A TOKYO MOVIE SHINSHA PRODUCTION
[ALARM RINGS]
Stop!
Dang!
Get the cars!
After them!
What are you doing?!
Hurry UP!
Keep up the good work!
[LAUGHTER]
There's 5 billion here
in non-sequential bills.
Here's a shower of money! Take that!
Whoa! Hot! Hot! Hot!
Steaming hot!
Bury me some more!
[HORNS HONK]
What's wrong, Lupin?
Let's dump it.
What?!
These are counterfeit.
Well-made, but still.
They are?!
They can't be...
We swiped these from the
vault of a state-run casino.
They're Gothic bills.
Gothic bills?
Those legendary counterfeits?
So, they're even showing up
at state-run casinos now, huh?
Jigen, that's it! That's our next job.
What do you say we party
hard to celebrate in advance?
Paaar-tay!
Damn it!
Stupid things! Damn it! Damn it!
[MOVIE THEME TREASURE
OF THE FLA ME PLAYS]
Lupin the Third
The Castle of Cagliostro
[SUNG IN JAPANESE]:
Searching out happiness
Is how I want to make my way
Even thorny paths and freezing cold nights
I want to traverse, the two of us together
The bleak heart of the traveler
Who will be there to embrace it?
Who will make those dreams come true?
A flame, it burns passionately
This love of mine
I want for you to understand, and you alone
Wrap me up in the bond we share
I've never heard of this
Principality of Cagliostro.
Population, 3,500.
It's the world's smallest state
to be a member of the UN.
And it's where the Gothic
bills are coming from, huh?
It's a famous legend
among those in the know.
The black hole of the
world of counterfeit bills.
Black hole?
The story goes that folks who
snoop around are never seen again.
JIGEN:
Huh. Scary.
It's scary, so I'm going to sleep.
[AIR RUSHES OUT]
HEY.
- LUPIN: [CHUCKLES]
- JIGEN: [DISGUSTED SOUND]
What the heck?
This spare is totally bald.
[BIRD CHIRPING]
Talk about peaceful.
[ENGINE ROARS]
What the...?
Get in!
[LUPIN THE THIRD
THEME MUSIC]
[TIRES SQUEALING]
- So, who do we side with?
- The woman!
Thoughtso!
The tires!
Got it!
[HORN HONKS]
- [PINGING]
- [MUSIC STOPS]
Dang! That's no ordinary car!
Yowch !
Now, this is getting interesting!
We're taking the lead!
[THEME MUSIC
RESUMES]
- [SMACKING]
- [BIRD CHIRPING]
Took it!
The next shot won't
be any ordinary slug.
Yes!
[HORN HONKS]
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
She's fainted.
That car's going to fall apart.
Take the wheel!
[TIRES SCREECH]
[CAR SPUTTERS]
Whoa...
Whoa, whoa, whoa... Whoa!
- No, let me go! - H-Hey! No! No, no!
Watch it! Down! Down! Down! Look down!
Look down, I said! Look down!
[GASPS]
[EXHALES]
Good, that's it.
Hold it right there.
[CRACKING]
- LUPIN: Whoops?!
- CLARISSE: [SCREAMS]
Hello?
Sir?!
LUPIN:
[GROANS]
Sir? Sir?
I'm sorry.
Hey!
Yo, Lupin.
Man, you're one sorry mess.
Uh, where'd my bride go?
Dear, oh, dear.
Damn it!
All that for one measly girl?
Who the heck were they?
[DRAMATIC CHORD]
It's a ring.
Hold on,
I've seen this somewhere bef--
What's gotten into you?!
You suddenly got all weird
after seeing the ring!
Ow!
[TIRES SCREECH]
[BIRDS CHIRPING]
Hey, Lupin, is there
something at this old castle?
It's the same crest as
the one on the ring...
Lupin.
It hasn't been too long since
this place was abandoned.
A fire...
MAN: Who's there?
LUPIN: Just passing through.
MAN: Tourists?
LUPIN: Well, yeah.
I thought this was supposed to be
His Highness, the Prince's palace.
It still is.
This place isn't for outsiders
to just come poking around.
You say this is the Prince's palace?
But it's an empty ruin.
Because of the big fire seven years ago.
MAN: Ever since the Prince
and his wife passed away,
MAN: it's been left to fall
apart, as you can see.
That's odd.
The Prince is basically the king, right?
So, there's no king now?
There's a regent,
so it's apparently not a problem.
Don't linger, you hear?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, Lupin.
[TOWER BELL RINGS]
[RINGING CONTINUES]
[RINGING STOPS]
You went and got all grown up...
What's up?
Don't play dumb.
[BONES CRACKING]
- Quit acting cool and keeping your problems to yourself!
Out with it! - No, no, no, no! You're choking me!
No! No!
[BONES CRACKING,
JIGEN GRUNTING]
Talk! You gonna talk?!
I'll talk, I'll talk, I'll talk, I'll talk...
JIGEN: [WHISTLES]
That's the castle of the regent,
the Count of Cagliostro.
Look there.
Lower.
On the other side of the aqueduct.
JIGEN: It's that boat from earlier!
So, the bride is inside that castle.
There's a sluice gate there.
It's exactly the same as it was back then.
You've snuck into that castle before?
It was over ten years ago.
I was gonna solve the
mystery of the Gothic bills.
I was just a punk,
still wet behind the ears.
And? How'd it go?
Oh, I got my butt kicked.
Turned tail and got out of there.
JIGEN: [SIGHS]
[BUZZING]
An autogyro, huh?
Talk about old-fashioned.
That's the Count.
- Huh? - Come on, let's go
look for an inn or something.
Hey...
Hey!
Jodot, that was careless.
My apologies, sir.
She was at a fitting
for her wedding attire
and the men were
not present at the time.
COUNT:
She's in the north tower now?
JODOT: Yes, sir. The drugs have
put her into a sound sleep.
Foreigners...
Yes, sir.
I am told that a pair of men
aided her during her escape.
Find them.
Dispose of them how you will.
[DOOR HUMS]
The ring is gone!
COUNT:
Get me Jodot!
[CROWD NOISES]
These letters are from the Gothic
alphabet that no one uses anymore.
The Gothic alphabet?
LUPIN: "With light and shadow as one
once more, it shall surely be restcred."
LUPIN:
1517.
The year is in Roman numerals.
So, this thing's 400 years old.
- Sorry for the wait!
- Ooh, looks tasty.
You seem awfully preoccupied.
What are you looking at?
Oh, I picked up this old ring
and I was wondering if it's valuable.
Oh, my! It's pretty!
This is the Lady Clarisse's crest.
Clarisse...
Look, that's her.
That photo up there.
WAITRESS:
That's of when she was little, though.
She returned from the convent yesterday.
I imagine she's grown
into a fine young lady.
The convent?
Oh, you don't know?
I thought you'd come to see the Lady
Clarisse and the Count's wedding, too.
Oh, so that's it!
I was thinking there
were a lot of tourists here.
But I feel sorry for the Lady Clarisse.
The Count is a notorious
womanizer, you know.
Oh, my! Just like me!
How does tonight sound?
- [GIGGLING] Oh, please!
- Well? Well?
LUPIN: A spy for the Count,
just like we thought.
JIGEN: His expression changed
the moment he saw the ring.
LUPIN:
Isn't the bride enough by herself?
JIGEN:
He wants the ring, too!
LUPIN:
Not if I can help it!
You knew that girl we saw today
was the Princess, didn't you?!
Oh, didn't I clue you in?
[QUIET FOOTSTEPS]
"With light and shadow as one once
more, it shall surely be restored," huh?
You think it'll be some
treasure that's restored?
[GAUNTLET CLICKS]
[DOOR HANDLE CLICKS]
Why you!
[WHOOSHES]
Wow, here comes the
whole kit and caboodle!
You creep!
[PINGING]
The Magnum doesn't work on them!
These guys are professional assassins.
[GRUNTING]
[LOUD HISSING]
Hurry!
[ACTION MUSIC]
[TIRES SQUEAL LOUDLY]
- Whew! That sure got my blood pumping.
- That was a full-blown attack.
This is one deep rabbit hole!
Yeah, this is getting interesting.
COUNT:
These didn't turn out well.
The quality has been on
a downward spiral lately.
My apologies, sir.
But if we continue to mass-produce
at our current pace...
Redo these.
And don't let the
delivery date slip, either.
Yes, sir.
Who's there?
I, Jodot, have never
blundered so greatly.
The rats got away.
Jodot, what's that piece
of paper on your back?
Th... Th-This is...
Lupin is on the scene
When did that get there?!
Lupin...
JODOT:
It is an advance notice from Lupin.
Read it.
Y-Yes, sir. Uh, but...
It's fine.
"To the Count of lust and greed,
I will be taking your bride.
"Expect me soon. Lupin the Third."
[CHUCKLES]
You should be happy
about this, Jodot.
Sir?
Let us wait then.
For this Lupin to come.
[HORSE CLOPPING]
BOX: Udon Noodles
with Deep Fried Tofu
Hey, you got here fast.
A job?
Goemon's here.
They're here, too.
Huh?
Take a peek.
Huh?!
That's a Japanese police car!
It's Zenigata.
What?!
LICENSE PLATE:
Saitama
COMMANDER:
All personnel, disembark!
Fall in!
And now, the cast is complete.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC]
ZENIGATA: Pardon me for
interrupting your meal.
I am Zenigata of the International
Criminal Police Organization.
It was reported that you received
an advance notice from Lupin
and that is why I am here.
COUNT:
Oh, you mean that petty thief
who's the third-generation
Arséne Lupin or whatever?
Is Interpol in the habit of disturbing
people's breakfasts for such things?
Your Excellency, Lupin is
not to be underestimated.
If he says he'll come,
he will, without fail.
There are five days until your nuptials.
I insist that you allow us
to patrol your castle.
[BELL muss]
We have police in this country,
too, you know.
Though, we refer to them
more elegantly as gendarmes.
You called, sir?
Gustav, cooperate
with this Japanese man.
You're dismissed.
Yes, sir!
One more thing, Your Excellency.
Please tell me why that scoundrel
Lupin would be after your bride.
Who knows?
Isn't investigating that
part of your job as well?
Please excuse me.
Are you sure about this, sir?
Allowing such a man
inside the castle would be...
I don't care.
I have lots of friends at Interpol, too.
I'm sure he'll have
to withdraw in no time.
LUPIN: There's Zenigata. Talk about
a child of the early Showa era.
He is one hard worker.
What is that?!
Don't go any farther.
What?
GUSTAV:
Watch.
[LASER ZINGS]
If you don't want to die,
don't go wandering around.
You let your men know that, too.
Inspector, we've detected
an antipersonnel radar as well.
I don't like this castle.
They've got too many preventative
measures for amateurs.
[LASER ZINGS]
A woman?
Hold on now, don't say you're out.
There's a woman mixed up in this,
but that's not the whole story.
Is there something
special about this ring?
Once we get the girl back from the
dirty ol' count, we'll know that, too.
After all, these are monsters
that the Magnum can't touch.
Between your blade
and this anti-tank rifle...
Hey, Lupin,
figured out how to get in yet?
Nope.
The place is incredible.
It's a nest full of lasers and radars.
I see.
We'll need a tank then...
So you called Zenigata.
What?
Is that true, Lupin?
Bingo! You've got good instincts.
So, you will fight fire with fire.
LUPIN: This is the
Castle of Cagliostro.
We're here.
This Roman aqueduct
is still in use today.
This is our only way in.
LUPIN: They use the Roman aqueduct to
draw water to the castle from the lake.
I see. And there won't
be any lasers underwater.
JIGEN:
Goemon, you're the lookout.
Watch out. There's a hole there.
[SURPRISED SHOUT]
Our first obstacle, huh?
[RUSHING WATER LOUDENS]
Here we go.
[SILENCE]
[RUSHING SOUNDS RESUME]
[GEARWORKS GRINDING]
[MACHINE SPUTTERING]
[WOOD CLACKING]
L-Lupin!
- [ZINGING]
- JIGEN: [GASPS]
00f, that's the machine room
of the clock tower.
I wonder if that son-of-a-gun
made it all right.
[CLASSICAL MUSIC]
[WINDMILL CREAKS]
What's that windmill?
According to Gustav,
it brings water up into the castle, sir.
Where does that water come out?
A fountain in the battery up above, sir.
- Come with me!
- Yes, sir!
Inspector!
Paris Headquarters has
ordered our withdrawal.
We are to return at once.
What?! What preposterous
nonsense is this?! I'm verifying this!
[SNEAKING MUSIC PLAYS]
What did you say?!
Lupin's advance notice...
So, the justification was...
Hm? The Count?
Police officers are
not bootlicking lackeys!
Whether he likes it or not...
[PHONE CLICKS]
Hello?
Hello?!
Dammit...
I'm taking this up with the Count!
And there's your personal
guide to the Count.
I want to see the Count immediately.
Did you hear me?! Let me through!
Give it up.
Only those deemed trustworthy
are permitted beyond this point.
What?! Are you saying that
the ICPO can't be trusted?!
I believe you have
been ordered to withdraw.
Please take your leave.
H-How did you know about that?
We can deal with the likes of Lupin
without the help of you Orientals.
Now, leave.
I see. I understand.
We'll pull out for now.
Yes, sir.
Did you just see me come here?!
What?
You blithering idiot! That was Lupin!
He disguised himself
as me and got inside!
All that brawn and you can't
even see through a disguise?!
- You good-for-nothing!
- Darn it!
Follow me!
LUPIN'S VOICE:
Don't let Lupin get away!
Stop right there!
Lupin!
Lupin?!
Stop this! Lupin is... Lupin is...
Help the Chief Inspector!
Attack!
[WEAPONS CLANKING]
Wow, look at them going at it!
Stop it! That's Lupin!
Darn it!
Get off my foot!
Lupin!
Whoa-oh!
[FRANTIC YELPS]
SERVANT:
It seems we caught something.
The idiot. He should have
gotten himself out of here.
SERVANT:
The gendarmes are gone, sir.
Gustav!
JODOT: Leaving his post?
What is he doing?
JODOT:
You stay here.
SERVANT:
Yes, sir.
Sorry, Pops.
You fool!
Call off this insanity at once!
Do you not see?!
You fell for Lupin's ruse,
hook, line, and sinker!
Darn it!
[CLICKING]
[SHOUTING]
JODOT:
Hey! Let go! Let go!
[CREAKING]
[LAUGHTER]
So, that Lupin finally made his way in.
I have no words to express my shame.
Tell the police force that their
inspector went ahead and left.
Mysterious disappearances
en route happen all the time.
Yes, sir.
[CLICKING]
MENACING VOICE:
Don't move.
Good evening, Fujicakes.
Lupin!
A woman engrossed in her
work is a beautiful sight.
You've gotten this far inside already?
We haven't seen each other
in a year and that's all I get?
I searched high and low, you know.
Lupin...
What you're searching for is where the bride is, right?
Oh, you knew?
I don't mind telling you, but promise
you won't get in the way of my work?
I won't, I won't! I never have!
I don't know about that.
The top of the tower on the north side.
Though, I imagine it'll be
impossible for you to get in.
Lupin...
[GRUNTING]
Dang. What an awful place
to lock someone up.
[COMICAL MUSIC CUE]
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
Got i-- Wha?
Whoa, whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Aaaaaaaah!
[DISTANT CREAKING]
Who are you?
I am a thief.
A thief, sir?
Good evening, Miss Bride.
You are that man from earlier,
aren't you?
You forgot this.
My!
You came all this way just for this?
When you would be killed if
the Count were to find you?
Oh, but it is in the nature of a
thief to target and be targeted.
I will leave once the job is done.
Thejob?
If only there were something
I could offer you, but...
I am a captive right now.
Oh...
Take this.
My target is a treasure
that an evil sorcerer locked
away at the top of a tall tower.
Please allow yourself to be
stolen away by this thief.
Me?
Rescuing jewels held prisoner in safes...
And releasing girls about
to be forced into marriage
to run free in green fields...
These are all jobs for a thief.
You would give me my freedom?
Thank you.
I really appreciate it.
But you do not know just how
terrible the House of Cagliostro is.
Please, just leave.
[SIGHS]
[MELODRAMATICALLY]
Oh, how could this be?
The girl believes in
the evil sorcerer's powers,
and yet, she would not try
to believe in the thief's powers.
If the girl would only believe,
the thief would be
capable of flying the skies
or even drinking the lake dry!
[QUIET GRUNTING]
[PAINED GRUNTING]
[POP]
My!
Right now, this is the best he can do.
[PANEL SLAMS SHUT]
[FEET SHUFFLE QUIETLY]
[METAL CLICKING]
[CLARISSE SQUEALS]
Sir Thief!
Hey!
Treat the lady with more respect!
Thank you for coming all this way
to deliver the ring, my dear Lupin.
I'm deeply touched by
the grand welcome, Count.
I hate to get right to it, but I'm
going to have you go away now.
Oh, but will you be able
to get rid of me so easily?
N-No!
You must not injure that man!
It'll be okay, missy. You have to
have faith in the thief's powers.
Monsieur!
Yes! The Monsieur is here!
He'll be right back, okay?
Now, what's the game going to be?
It would be easy to tear you apart,
but I hardly think we need
to sully the bride's room
with the blood of a petty thief.
You say that now...
You'll regret it later.
That will be the last
of your smart retorts.
[CLACKS OPEN]
[WHOOSHING]
[CHUCKLES]
That hole leads to a hell that
no one has ever crawled out of.
You look so sweet, and yet, you've
already attracted a man to your side.
The Cagliostro blood
always comes through.
[CHUCKUNG]
You are worthy of becoming my wife.
Murderer. You are not human.
Why, yes, my hands are covered in blood.
But so are yours.
Generation after generation,
my family has served as
the shadow to your family,
overseeing schemes and
assassinations to support this country.
Let go of me! You disgust me!
I won't have you telling me
that you didn't know.
You are of Cagliostro as well.
The same ancient blood of the Goths
that flows in my veins flows in yours.
Clarisse, after four hundred long years,
light and shadow, the two houses of
Cagliostro that have been divided,
are now about to become as one.
Take a look.
This is the gold goat that has
been passed down in my family.
- COUNT: When your...
- CLARISSE: [GASPS]
...ring with the silver goat comes
together to become one with it,
the hidden treasure of our
ancestors will be restored.
LUPIN [MUFFLED]: Ooh, I
heard that! I totally heard that!
LUPIN:
A marriage for treasure!
- It's him!
- LUPIN: The counterfeit-printing Count!
LUPIN: Everything he
says and does is a sham!
LUPIN: The girl is a very
kindhearted, wonderful young lady.
Monsieur? Monsieur?
LUPIN:
Yes! He's alive and well!
Thanks to the girl believing in him,
he can even fly the skies.
Sir Thief will come and
steal you away for sure,
so you just wait.
I will.
COUNT [MUFFLED]: Blast
it! So it's that ring?!
Give it here!
LUPIN: Hey, Count, you
listen and you listen good!
[SPRINGING]
LUPIN:
I've got the real ring!
You try and lay a finger on that girl,
LUPIN: and here's what I'll
do to your precious ring!
It was a fake!
[CHUCKLES]
[WATER RUSHING]
Well, crap!
Treat me like bodily wastes, will you?!
Well, pooh-pooh to that!
- Did he fall?
- Probably.
Make sure.
That is not a place fit
for the living to visit.
He is certain to die if
we leave him down there.
The weasel has the ring.
As you wish, sir.
You just wait!
I'll tear that petty
thief of yours to shreds!
[DOORS QUIETLY HUM]
[GENTLE MUSIC PLAYS]
[BONES CLATTER]
Four hundred years of
killing and more killing...
May you rest in peace. Hmm?
TEXT: 1904.3.14 Japanese Army Scout
Gennosuke Kawakami perished here. Avenge...
[DISTANT CLATTERING]
Lupin!
Why you! Surrender quietly!
Pops, I'm amazed you're all right.
Tell me! Where's the exit?!
Where'd you come in from?!
I got the shaft, too.
What?
By the looks of it, you've
been walking for quite a while.
Shut up!
I won't take pity from a thief!
Well, let's kick back and relax.
There's no way out anyway.
Make a little room for me there,
will you?
Pops, mind lending me a light?
Lupin, what in the world is the deal
with this horde of dead bodies?
It doesn't strike me as a gravesite.
Take a look at the wall there.
[LIGHTER IGNITES]
Th-This is...
May you rest in peace.
ZENIGATA:
I'd figured this was no ordinary castle,
but a secret worth
going this far to keep...
Hey, is that what you're after, too?
The one who's up to that is Fujicakes.
I just hope she doesn't end
up joining the dearly departed.
Anyway, making a fuss isn't
going to get us anywhere.
G'night, Pops.
[CLOCK RINGS]
JIGEN: [SHIVERING]
Man, it's cold.
Wow, look at the time.
How do things look?
No movement yet.
Guess we'll just have to wait.
[CLICKING]
[BONES CLATTER]
[GRUNTING, SLAMMING]
Gwahahahaha...
Take that!
Hup!
JODOT:
They're taking too long.
SERVANT:
Master Jodot!
Ah! Well done!
And, heave!
Curse you, Lupin!
This is a coffin!
Huh? Wha?
What the heck is this place?
These are 10,000-yen bills!
Goodness! And so are all these?!
These are sure well-made.
Pops, take a look.
West German 1000-mark bills!
Pounds. Dollars.
Francs! Rubles! Rupees!
Pesos! Crowns! Liras!
Whoa! There's even won!
LU PIN:
They've got the whole world covered.
P-Printing counterfeit bills!
Lupin,
so this is the castle's secret?!
That's right.
Gothic bills were once hailed as
being superior to even the real thing
and this is the heart of it all.
LUPIN:
Fake currency has played a shadowy part
in every upheaval in
Europe since the Middle Ages.
It brought down the Bourbon Dynasty
by sewing as a source
of funds for Napoleon.
And in 1927, it also
triggered the Great Depression.
The key player of the black
hole behind the scenes of history,
the Gothic bill.
And of those who tried to
get a peek at its source,
not a soul ever made it back out.
I'd heard the rumors,
but I never imagined that a
sovereign nation was behind it.
What'll you do, Pops?
Now that you've seen it,
there's no going back.
I know that. The police officer in
me is itching to get on the case.
LUPIN: [CHUCKLES]
Temporary truce
until we get out of here?
Fine. But I won't aid a thief.
Once we've escaped,
I'll arrest you without fail.
Fantastic.
Okay, then...
Let's shake on it!
I won't collude with you.
Well, now.
[SOFT THUMP]
Miss Fujiko.
I saw my opportunity,
so I've come to say goodbye.
What in the world are you...
Hired as the Lady
Clarisse's personal servant,
the one and only
woman inside the castle...
But the truth is,
I'm a female spy who came to
delve into this castle's secrets.
I was planning on sticking around a
little longer, but Lupin came, right?
It's going to become messy, so I'm leaving.
You know that gentleman?
Better than I wish I ever did.
Allies at times and enemies at others.
I suppose we might've been
lovers at one point, too.
He's a born womanizer.
Be careful.
He left you?
Certainly not.
I left him.
Smoke coming from the pitfall!
A fire...
It's coming from the basement.
Movement!
So, he's kicked things off!
[SIRENS WAIL SLOWLY]
[COUGHS] Bad news, sir! The fire's origin is
believed to be the basement workshop!
What?! Put it out right away!
Yes, sir!
Darn you! Shut that thing!
You all go, too!
Blasted Jodot.
Don't tell me he failed...
[FIRE CRACKLES]
Pops, hurry it up!
We're going to have visitors soon!
Proof! I need proof!
Curse you, Lupin!
Find him!
He should still be in here!
Don't let it scare you!
Get to it!
[GRUNTS]
There's Lupin! After him!
You put the fire out!
It's the chapel!
Monsieur!
Lupin! And Zenigata, too?!
They mean to steal the autogyro.
[LOUD WHACK]
You fool!
I will take my reprimand later.
He is going after the Lady Clarisse!
Please hurry!
Hurry UP!
[ENGINE SPUTTERS TO LIFE]
[RAMJET ENGINES IGNITE]
Darn it! Don't underestimate
the Metropolitan Police!
Pops, get on!
[ROTORS WHIRRING]
So long!
Pops, I'm going to
make a quick pit stop.
If this is a kidnapping for
ransom, I won't cooperate.
It's a non-business venture.
He's coming this way.
[EXERTIVE WHIMPERS]
[CRACKING]
[EXPLOSION]
It's bulletproof glass!
We can't open this! Please,
don't mind me and just go!
Pops, take the wheel.
Wh-Wh-What?! Hey, w-wait,
Lupin, I've never done this!
Whee! And here we are.
[CRACKS OPEN]
Clarisse?
Monsieur!
I have come to take you away!
Fujiko, rope!
Don't order me around!
[HURRIED FOOTSTEPS]
Miss Fujiko!
Go, quick!
Monsieur!
Okay, you're safe now.
[CLINKING, EXPLOSION]
Pops, over here!
Here, here, here!
Like it's that easy,
you blithering idiot!
All right, that's good!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
Hup, hup, hup, hup...
[GUNSHOT]
[EXPLOSION]
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
- Lupin!
- [MACHINEGUN FIRE]
Don't move, you she-rat!
Fujiko, I have a lot of
questions to put to you later.
Jodot, finish Lupin.
Yes, sir.
No!
You mustn't shoot him!
If you mean to kill him,
then I will die, too!
Fire.
Your attitude is commendable,
Clarisse.
Get the ring back and come here.
If you become my wife,
I'll spare Lupin's life.
Or you can both die now.
I'll let you choose as you will.
[GROANING]
Monsieur, the ring...
[WEAKLY] No, Clarisse.
You can't...
Under his collar.
Lupin always hides things there.
Damn you, Fujiko...
Here is the ring.
Spare this man and Miss Fujiko, or
else I will simply throw it in the lake.
Trust me. Put it on your finger
and come over here.
[QUIETLY] Shall I fire?
[QUIETLY] Wait until the ring gets here.
[AUTOGYRO LOU DENS]
Lupin!
[CRASHES]
Shoot them!
Don't let them get away!
You dirty coward!
You said you would spare them!
They'd seen the basement workshop.
You thought I'd let them leave alive?!
[PAINED WHIMPERING]
[SINISTER LAUGHTER]
I finally have it in my hands!
Lupin,
we'll say you owe me one for today.
Later.
And now,
we retreat without seeing any action?!
ZENIGATA:
Augh, we can't go much longer!
JIGEN:
Jump down!
[SHAMISEN CHORD]
Yet another worthless
object to fall prey to my blade.
Lupin, you better not kick the
bucket before I catch you!
[WHISPERING] Whatever the case,
this is certainly a problem.
[WHISPERING] A dark
plot is what this is.
[THUMP]
- [WHISPERING STOPS]
- Please order me to move against them!
We have all this indisputable evidence!
I saw it myself!
A whole row of
state-of-the-art printing presses...
I know that!
This is a highly political problem.
Ourjurisdiction here at Interpol
is limited to international crimes.
Secretary General,
it is clear that this is criminal!
FRENCH REPRESENTATIVE:
You just don't get it.
We're talking about a sovereign
state and a member of the UN.
Even Interpol cannot conduct
a compulsory investigation.
GERMAN REPRESENTATIVE: Not only that, but the
situation is exceedingly unfavorable for us.
Did you see this photo
that's on the front page of
every newspaper around the world?
The bravery of the Count,
who personally protected his bride.
"Lupin Fails to Abduct Princess Clarisse".
They also say, "Lupin's Accomplice
Disguised As Zenigata".
That was all me, the real McCoy.
That's problematic.
As an active duty police officer,
that was imprudent of you.
I believe I reported
what really happened!
The issue here is which
side the public will believe.
We stand no chance, surely.
The Count supposedly has a lot
of political friends in the West.
I imagine many countries would have
a problem if the truth were revealed.
Exactly! In point of fact,
there's proof that a certain country
ordered a massive quantity
of counterfeit US dollar bills!
- Humph! And these fake rubles weren't
ordered by your CIA?! - What?!
- Stop this!
- How dare you?!
SECRETARY GENERAL: You can't be bringing
up international disputes here!
UK REPRESENTATIVE: Precisely! We have
no choice but to have each country
come up with their own
countermeasures for the Gothic bills.
Inspector,
we are prepared to mobilize.
We can depart for the Principality
of Cagliostro at any time.
We won't be mobilizing.
Sir?
We'll be off the Lupin case as soon
as they find someone to replace us.
Everyone, prepare to return to Japan.
OLD MAN:
It's me.
Here's some food.
Much appreciated.
How is he?
JIGEN:
His fever seems to have gone down.
It's thanks to you operating on him.
If you want to thank someone,
thank that dog.
OLD MAN:
That old dog is friendly to no one,
but he won't budge from that man's side.
OLD MAN: Otherwise, I probably wouldn't
have offered you folks shelter.
Hey, Karl.
He's awake!
JIGEN:
Lupin, how're your wounds?
Jigen. Goemon. Long time no see.
Long time? What're you saying?
His memory is in temporary
disarray due to his injuries.
Karl,
you're not with your mistress today?
How do you know that dog's name?
Other than myself,
the only one left to know him as Karl
should be the Lady Clarisse.
Clarisse?
I see,
so your mistress's name is Clarisse...
Clarisse...
Lupin.
Jigen, what day is today?!
How many days has it been?!
Th-Th-Three days.
What? Then the ceremony's tomorrow.
No time to be...
Owowowowow...
Come on, don't push it.
You'll reopen your wounds.
Food. Bring me food.
Food? Like rice porridge?
I'm low on blood. Bring me
whatever. Just keep it coming.
Easy for you to say, but...
I'll handle it.
You idiot,
quit stuffing yourself like that.
Your stomach won't take it.
Shuddup! Even a jet airplane
can get fixed up in twelve hours!
See? What'd I tell you?
Need a wash basin?
[MUMBLES]
Huh?
What's that?
Says he'll sleep, now that he's eaten.
I had no idea.
All for the Lady Clarisse...
But with Lupin in this shape...
It sounds as though you have a great
deal of history with the Lady Clarisse.
I used to be the palace groundskeeper.
The Lady Clarisse loved
plants as a child.
When the Prince and his wife passed
away and she was to enter the convent,
she entrusted this dog to me.
So, he sniffed out the
Princess's scent on Lupin.
How did this man know the dog's name?
Who knows? This guy's
constantly falling in love, so...
It's nothing like that.
You were awake?
It was over ten years ago now.
I was a greenhorn, eager to set
out and make a name for myself.
Lupin
LUPIN:
I did crazy things,
and after making a real show of myself,
in the end,
I went after the Gothic bills.
[LIGHTS CLICK]
[RAPID GUNFIRE]
- [WHOOSH]
- LUPIN: [GROANS]
I managed to pull myself up
onto the shore somehow,
but I couldn't budge another inch.
Karl? What's wrong, Karl?
Looks like my time's
come to pay the piper.
Water...
She helped me drink the water,
her hands shaking...
And shining on her finger was that ring.
I'm ashamed to say,
I'd totally forgotten about it
until I saw the ring again.
[GROWLS]
[MOTORBIKE ENGINE REVS]
That's Fujiko's motorbike.
LUPIN:
It's a clipping from today's newspaper.
It says that tomorrow morning,
an archbishop is coming from
the Vatican for the ceremony.
Truth
[PHONE RINGS]
I'm quitting!
Fujiko?!
What?! Lupin's going to hit
the wedding?! Is this true?!
If you're pursuing Lupin,
you have full authority
to mobilize, right?
Right... I hadn't thought of that!
[HORN HONKING]
We're in a hurry!
Would you move aside?!
It's no use.
It's completely jammed up ahead.
WOMAN: They said there was a
landslide seven kilos down the road.
Is there no other way?
We're going to be late.
Right...
FARMER: By gosh, aren't ya
the fine lord archbishop?
Yep, just like I reckoned.
- Would ya be so kind as to bless
this li'l baby goat? - [GOAT BLEATS]
Oh, you're a local, right?
Aren't there any other ways to
get to the Castle of Cagliostro?
If ya don't mind country roads,
there's a way over there.
Thank goodness!
Would you show me the way?
Come on, get in. Get in.
Sure, sure. If it's for the fine
lord archbishop, then sure.
[GOAT BLEATS]
[GRUNTING, TIRES SQUEALING]
Keep it up, men!
One more hill and
we'll be at the border!
We have to get there
by dusk at the latest!
Heave-ho! Heave-ho!
[HORN HONKS]
GUSTAV:
Is this really all right?
Publicizing this on TV...
His Highness wishes to show the
world that this is a legitimate wedding.
JODOT:
Ah, His Grace, the Archbishop, has arrived.
Do you think Lupin will show up?
My Shadows will guard the bride.
All your men have to
do is guard the gate!
Yes, sir.
[CLOCK TOWER RINGS]
[RINGING CONTINUES IN DISTANCE]
[DOOR CREAKS]
[RINGING STOPS]
The time has come for light
and shadow to become as one.
Come, Clarisse.
[SWORDS CLINK]
[SOMBER ORGAN MUSIC]
ARCHBISHOP: The House of Cagliostro
is a noble family of ancient blood.
Bring here the proof that
you are their rightful heirs.
In accordance with the customs of old,
the exchange of rings shall
constitute your marriage vows.
Daughter of the Prince of
the Principality of Cagliostro,
Clarisse de Cagliostro,
do you consent to this marriage?
ARCHBISHIOP: If you do not object,
then respond with silence.
May God bless you...
[ORGAN MUSIC STOPS]
GHOSTLY ECHO: These marriage rites
are profoundly tainted by greed.
[FRIGHTENED YELPS]
[METALLIC CLANG]
[PANICKED SHOUTING]
[CRASHING, CLATTERING]
This is a curse!
No need to fuss.
So, that accursed rat has appeared.
[SMALL BELL CHIMES REPEATEDLY]
LUPIN [GHOSTLY ECHO]: I have come to speak on
behalf of the dead in the dungeon underground.
I want the bride.
- Oh, we cannot carry out the ceremony now.
- Get back.
This will be a fine bit of entertainment.
LUPIN [GHOSTLY ECHO]:
Clarisse, I've come for you.
CROWD:
It's a monster!
Something incredible has happened!
It's Lupin! Lupin's appeared!
SHADOW:
Stop the broadcast!
FUJIKO [ON TV]:
What are you doing?!
TEXT:
Please wait one moment.
Move out!
LUPIN [GHOSTLY ECHO]:
Clarisse.
Poor thing.
You've been drugged, haven't you?
Curse you, Count. You made it
so she couldn't speak, didn't you?
[PIERCING STABS]
[C LARISSE SC REAMS]
- CLARISSE: Monsieur! - ARCHBISHOP:
You mustn't. You mustn't get closer.
[LAUGHS]
That was foolish, Lupin!
Take care of those men as well!
LUPIN'S VOICE [QUIET]:
Clarisse. Don't cry, Clarisse.
LUPIN [GHOSTLY ECHO]:
I'll come to you now.
- [EXPLOSION]
- COUNT: [GRUNTS]
[GHOSTLY LAUGHTER]
What's going on here?!
LUPIN [GHOSTLY ECHO]: I wonder if this
gift will be to your liking, Count.
Highness!
LUPIN [GHOSTLY ECHO]: They're the
counterfeit bills you printed.
Take them as payment for the rings.
Blast it!
Find him!
He has to be in here somewhere!
Oh!
LUPIN:
I've definitely got them now.
Y-You're...
COUNT:
Lupin!
Monsieur!
Curse you!
Play me for a fool, will you?!
No burning up with jealousy now.
Or you'll get burned,
Lolita-loving Count.
[FIZZING]
[WHISTLING]
[BOOMING]
Take that!
[REPEATED CLANGS]
[THEME MUSIC PLAYS]
[POLICE SIRENS]
Lupin! Lupin! Lupin!
Take that!
Ladies and gentlemen,
pardon me for keeping you waiting.
We will now resume our broadcast.
The wedding hall is now in utter chaos!
[CHUCKLES]
Well, then... Buh-bye!
Die!
[WHOOSH]
[GUNFIRE]
After him!
Don't let him get away!
Lupin has fled! The Count is in
a rage and hot on his heels!
Oh, the police have come storming in!
Lupin is under the altar!
Make a hole! Attack!
Zenigata's men are pushing
hard towards the altar!
Oh, here's the gendarmerie!
In the lead is...
Gendarme Captain Gustav!
Secure our rear!
[CLANKING]
GENDARME:
Why you!
Give no quarter!
Justice is on our side!
The fighting is truly fierce!
What could possibly
be beneath the altar?
FUJIKO: Oh, it's a staircase!
There's a hole leading underground!
Could Lupin be inside that hole?
Let us follow with the camera!
ZENIGATA:
Darn you, Lupin!
ZENIGATA [ON TV]:
Lupin! Lupin!
FRENCH REPRESENTATIVE:
That idiot! What's he doing?!
He's ignoring his orders!
Call him off!
This is being broadcast via satellite!
It's too late!
[ACTING] Whoa!
What the heck is this place?!
This practically looks like
a national minting facility!
What's that over there?
Oh, wow!
These are Japanese bills!
Counterfeit bills!
Talk about hamming it up...
FUJIKO [ON TV]:
This is an incredible revelation!
Take a look!
They're counterfeit currency
from all over the world!
I've made a terrible discovery
during my pursuit of Lupin!
What should I do?!
[RATTLING]
[GUNFIRE]
First things first,
we're getting out of this castle.
I'm counting on you,
Jigen. Goemon.
Leave it to us.
We'll hold them off here.
Come on.
Gentlemen.
I beg of you to be careful.
And you, too, Noble Jigen.
Huh?
CLARISSE: Please make certain
that you return safely.
I will never forget this
debt of gratitude.
Now, you must go.
Clarisse, hurry.
Coming.
She called me Noble Jigen.
A lovely lady...
Let's get this started!
[SHOUTING, CLANGING,
SHAMISEN CHORD]
There is an extra keenness to
my Steelcleaver this evening.
Curse you, Lupin, this isn't over yet!
Leave matters within
the castle to me, sir.
Mm.
[BOTH BREATHE HEAVILY]
- Are your wounds causing you pain?
- Nah, they're nothing.
Now, let's get over this thing.
Two goats facing each other...
There are Gothic letters
carved along the seam.
LUPIN [SLOWLY]:
"Binding light and shadow..."
They're worn down and hard to read.
CLARISSE: "Binding light and shadow,
tolling the hours is the goat on high,
"into whose eyes, facing the
sun, I bid you place me."
Those words have been passed down
in my family since ancient times.
Does that help?
Yes, it helps!
Now I know the answer to the riddle!
[MOTOR CHUGGING]
- It's the Count. Come, this way.
- [GUNFIRE]
They're going inside the machine room
of the clock tower! Moor the boat!
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
There!
Ooh, here they come.
- [LASERS ZING]
- Hot, hot, hot, hot, hot, hot!
- Well, that's no good.
- [LASERS ZING]
Shut down the lasers.
The idiot. Does he think they
can get out of here?
[GUNFIRE]
Scared?
No.
Fantastic!
Here we go!
Don't let him get away!
Oh!
[SAILOR PANICS]
- Don't look!
- [SAILOR SCREAMS]
We can't go this way.
You men use the stairs!
Yes, sir!
Oof.
Stay here.
- I'm going to block the entrance.
- Be careful!
I'll be right back!
There!
[GUNFIRE CONTINUES]
[LOUD SMASHING]
[SOLDIERS SCREAM]
CLARISSE:
Monsieur! Behind you!
[WHOOSH]
Whoops! Hup, hup, hup...
Hey, there, Count!
Accursed rat! I'll run you through!
Looks like we've come to
the finale at last, Count.
[COUNT YELLS]
[SWISHING, CLANGING]
[CLANG]
[COUNT EXCLAIMS]
And one more!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
Hey, Count C,
I dare you to come get me!
[GEARWORKS
CLANK AND TURN]
Whoops!
Whoa, whoa, whoa... Whoa!
Whoa, whoa, whoa...
[LAUGHS]
Monsieur!
I'll start by taking care of you first!
Clarisse, run!
LUPIN:
I'm coming!
[WIND WHISTLES]
[COUNT LAUGHS]
How far do you think you're going?
Clarisse...
[COUNT LAUGHS]
Come on, come on. What's wrong?
Not running anymore? Eh?
This will be the end of
the Cagliostro bloodline.
Die, Clarisse.
Wait, Count!
Let's make a deal!
It's too late!
You can watch this woman die!
Listen to what I've got to say.
I'll tell you the secret to these rings.
You can do whatever you
want with the treasure.
But give up on the girl.
Let her go free.
Look at the Capricorn
on the clock face.
That's the goat that faces the
sun and tolls the hours.
It's got two holes in its eyes
to fit the rings into.
I'll let you have these rings,
but if you kill her, I'll throw
them in the lake and I'll kill you.
[WIND QUIETLY WHISTLES]
Ah-ah, that's far enough.
Let Clarisse go inside.
All right, fine.
- [HISSING]
- LUPIN: Ah!
[COUNT LAUGHS]
Lupin, you have to save
your trump cards for the end.
Come!
These are definitely the genuine
articles. The rings are mine now.
Here's your payment
for solving the riddle.
Let go!
Clarisse!
- COUNT: Let go!
- CLARISSE: [CRIES OUT]
[SWORD CLATTERS]
[STRAINS]
- [CLICKS]
- [CHUCKLES]
- [GRINDING]
- COUNT: Hm?
[GEARWORKS WHIR]
[COUNT GRUNTS, STRAINS]
[GRUNTING]
[SNAP]
[BELL RINGS
ERRATICALLY]
[RINGING CONTINUES]
The clock tower!
[EXPLOSIVE RUMBLE]
Your Highness...
[SPLASHING]
[RINGING FADES]
[WATER RUSHES]
What the heck is that?
[WATER ROARS]
Cagliostro is done for.
Cut me down.
I will not kill needlessly.
[PEACEFUL MUSIC]
[CLANK]
Monsieur...
Hey, can you stand?
Take a look.
[DRAMATIC MUSIC]
LUPIN:
The hidden treasure...
CLARISSE: I had no idea there was
a Roman city beneath the lake.
LUPIN: When the Romans were
driven from this land,
they built that floodgate
and submerged it.
And your ancestors
quietly inherited it.
LUPIN: Truly, a
treasure for all mankind.
It's too big for my pocket.
- [MUSIC STOPS]
- [ENGINES ROAR]
So, Interpol got their
lazy bums into gear.
CLARISSE:
Will you be leaving?
LUPIN:
Hm? Yeah.
LUPIN: A lot of scary men
just showed up, so...
[ROMANTIC MUSIC]
Take me with you.
I can't work as a thief yet,
but I'll learn, I promise!
I... I...
Please!
I want to go with you.
Clarisse.
Don't give me that silly talk.
You want to go back
into the darkness again?
It's taken you this
long to get into the sun.
Right? Your life is
only getting started here.
You can't become all grubby like me.
Oh, yeah! If you ever run into any
trouble, just call any time, okay?
Monsieur will come running, even if
it's from the other side of the globe.
[KARL BARKS]
Karl!
Oh, Karl! Karl!
Lady Clarisse.
Grandpa!
- [SLURPING]
- [LAUGHS]
[CLARISSE LAUGHS]
- Monsieur!
- Toodle-oo!
[TIRES SCREECH]
JIGEN:
Princess!
[ENGINE REVS]
Monsieur!
Clarisse, take care!
G'bye!
[KARL BARKS]
Thank you, everyone! Goodbye!
G'bye!
Dang it! One step too late!
That darn Lupin got away with his loot!
No, that man took nothing.
He honored me by fighting for my sake.
No, ma'am,
he ran off with a tremendous prize.
Your heart.
Yes.
Well, then, please excuse me!
[TREASURE OF THE FLA ME
PLAYS]
After Lupin! We follow him
to the ends of the earth!
Saitama Prefectural Police
[SIRENS WAIL]
What a refreshing bunch
of fellows they were.
I feel as though I have known that
gentleman since a long time ago.
Lupin...
I'm sure...
I'm sure we'll meet again.
She was a nice girl, wasn't she?
You could stay behind, you know.
[MOTORBIKE
ENGINE HUMS]
Oh? Fujicakes!
Lupin, take a look at what I scored!
Hey! Those are the master printing
plates for the counterfeit bills!
Wow! Wow! I'd love to be your friend!
So long!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa...
- [BIKE ENGINE LOUDENS, FADES]
H-H-H-H-Hey!
Hold on a second there!
[SIRENS WAILING]
Aw, crap,
here comes Pops again.
Lupin, you won't get away this time!
Fin