Tokuma Shoten, Japan Airlines, Nippon Network
Studio Ghibli (C) 1992
PORCO ROSSO
(Italian Tenor On Radio)
Yeah?
Mr.Rosso! We've got a job for you!
The Mamma Aiutos gang is on the move.
The Mamma Aiutos Gang?
I'm kinda busy here.
We need you to protect one of our
ships carring a fortune in Gold.
Is that all?
Well Uh...
There's a group of school girls on board too.
That is gonna cost you.
See here Bouty Hunter, no fight gauging!
We've got a contract with you!
Yeah. Yeah...yeah!I'm on it.
Stop the ship!
Stop the ship.Or we sink it!
Wow, pirates!
Pirates. Seaplane pirates!
Someday I'm get off my lazy butt
and give this thing an overhaul.
Are you seaplane pirates?
Yes. That's right!
So we're hostages?
That's right too.
Smells like you never bathe.
You're real sharp.
So cute!
Could use some love.
Hey!Hey! Cmon kids
we're in a hurry.
Boss do we have to
take all 15 of 'em?
Yeah it's not nice to seperate
them from their friends!
Ah! Looks like I'm late!
Aka Hearty! The Mama Auito gang has
taken the girls and the gold!
They went that way.
They went that...
No, not that way! That's wrong way.
Calm down. I know what I'm doin'
That Mama Aiuto gang is so cheap,they'll fly
just of out sight and hide on the nearest island.
Just to save money on gasoline.
Damn! Don't give out on me now!
Cmon Baby...cmon!
Yeah that's my girl!
That can't be good.
I better get this job done quick!
There they are!
What the heck is this? Site seeing plane?
This is Pirate country. They know
better than to be out here!
Porco Rosso!
Hey Girls! Get outta here. You get yourselves
kidnapped by these guys, sweethearts!
He's so cool!
What's this?
Looks like we're safe.
Hey look! We're flying!
What's goin' on down there?
Now girls! This is not a playground.
Hey! Can't you shut them up?
I told you, we shouldn't have taken them.
Aah! My nose!
Can we come up?
Yeah alright! Just don't let the boss know.
Ah! Great view!
Hey look! What a pretty red plane!
What! Where?
That was Porco!
Yeah!
Alright! Let's get this
thing over with.
He's back!
It is Porco!
I can't see!
That's not good!
Engine stopped.
We'll crash!
No we're not! We've got another engine.
Hey! Don't just sit there,shoot em'
Shoot em'
You keep missing him.
I think he's better than you!
Signal from the pig -
“Surrender now! You lose jerks!”
Never!
Here he comes! I'll get him this time
Where? Where did he go?
He is pretty!
We down. We're going to sink!
Let's get down from here.
We aren't gonna sink!.
This is a seaplane.
No! No! No
That's not good
We're sinking.
Hey! Stop em!They are valuable hostage!
Hey! Get back inside.
Girls! Out of the water!
It's dangerous!
Don't worry.
We all belong to a swimming club.
Watch this!
No! No! No. Don't do it.
Signal from the pig!
“He says - Hand over the Girls and the Gold...
and I'll let you keep some of the loot
so you can repair your ship"
I hate to put you jerks outta business!
We get to keep it?
That's generous!
Half?
We're not giving you anything!
You idiot!
Eat Lead!Come and get it Pig!
I dare ya!
Gotcha!
It jammed!
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Bye-bye! Bye bye Pirates!
See that went well!
He was nice enough not to kill us.
Show more ambition! You are a pirate!
Cmon on! Get me!
Hey! Get outta here!
Hey! Don't touch that!
Hey! Get down from there!
Put your pulls back on!
Hey! Get down!
Hey...don't touch that.
Another triumph for Porco Rosso!
It's a good thing, we pirate abandoned...
together right?
We gotta do somethin'
about that stupid Pig!
So you are an American
who can help us?
The pirates of the Adriatic, can't
have an American protection!
That's embarassing! No its not! Look at
him, his grandma's cousin  was Italian.
And besides Curtis is the only pilot
who can beat Porco. And for 10% ...
10% ? I'm not gonna pay that!
Shhh!
(Singing in French)
Beautiful.
Pig's here.
With his snout in the air as always.
Shh!
Mr. Porco Rosso? Congratulations on defeating...
the Mama Aiuto gang!
Did you know you took twice the
reward of Bounty Hunter this year?
And Sir, how does it feel to be the
top Bounty Hunter of the Adriatic?
And let me ask...Hey, eh!
What do you think you doing?
Get your hands off me!
Shutup and listen to the song!
Yes Sir..
She sure is incredible.
I just might have to take her back home with
me. I bet she can make it big in America.
Although she'll have to stop singing
in front of each everytime!
Hey Cowboy! Is that your plane upfront?
Yep. I don't mind saying she made me
bit of a celebrity in the racing world.
So you are the one who beat the
Italians in the Schneider Cup?
That's right! But what I'm best
at is Aerial combat.
These pirates tell me that you got a
pretty good reputation in the skies.
I'd be careful if you're planning on
making a deal with that Pirate Gangs.
Not only are they lying cheapstakes,
not a single one of them knows how to bathe.
That's for sure.
Wait! We heard that you stupid pig.
Hello.Look at this?
While you handsome pirate bosses are...
in one table, you are not here
to cause problems are you?
You know my rule,you eat in my
restaraunt..not fight.
Ofcourse, Gina. We would never fight
within 50 miles from your place.
We're even getting along with the pig.
Aren't we?
Be good boys.
Wish me luck.
May I help you?
Porco, tell me about your rescue?
Next time just the two of us.
Eating all alone here again.
So what do you think about the American
flyboy? He's something else, isn't he?
As soon as he saw me,
he asked me to marry him!
So I told him of the three
pilots I've married.
The first died in the war,second died in
the Atlantic, last one he died in Asia.
So you heard something?
I got the call last night.They found
his remains in some remote part of Bengal.
It's strange Marco. I've been waiting
to hear something for 3 years...
but now I can't even cry.
Just feel numb.
Maybe I've run out of tears.
Well yeah! The good guys always die.
Cheers. To a good man.
Marco I wanna thank you
for keeping an eye on me.
And my restaraunt all these years.
I can't tell you how much your
friendship means to me.
Well you know, its a great place...
except from that ugly photograph you
keep hanging in the wall up there.
Hey! That's my favorite picture. I can't
believe you scribbled over your face!
That's the only picture
left of you as a human.
How you ever going to break that
stupid curse on you,Marco?
Face it! I'm a pig.
That American's gonna be trouble.
Hey, that's Porco Rosso.
Let's alert the captain.
I envy you Mr.Rosso. I wish I
could make money way you do!
Here's this month's payment.
That the last you owe on the seaplane.
Let's see..How about buying some patriotic
bonds to help serve our nation?
Sorry I'm a pig. Leave
that to you humans.
Hey there,Mr.Rosso.
We got your gun ready.
Give me some ammo too,kid.
Yes Sir.
Lotta commotion in the street.
Sure is! Looks like our irons
are in for change in government.
If so you Bounty Hunters
will soon be outlaws.
Laws don't mean anything to a pig.
That's a good point. Won't mean
much to us weapons dealer either.
Here are the bullets! You
sure you want the usual?
We got the new armor piercing
that explode on contact!
Hey! Easy kid. I'm just a bounty hunter.
I'm not fighting a war.
Come again.
So whats the difference between
fighting a war and bounty hunting?
If you make money from war, you are scud...
but if you can't make money from
bounty hunting you are an idiot!
Ah! How in the whole world could
we be in debt.This is ridiculous!
We miscalculated!
We didn't take quite enough
money to cover our repairs!
Ah there! The pirates are here!
Man! This is embarassing. I can't believe
we have to work with these losers!
It's the stupid pig's fault boss!
Look at that. Those Mamma Aiutos
guy can't even afford paint?
Its embarassing to be seen with them.
Alright I guess we're all here.
Hey, you in the back. What
happened to Mr.America?
He's flying in the sun.
Typical American!
Sighted target: The Queen of the
Mediterranean at 10 'o' Clock.
That ship's kinda big, isn't?
That's why we doing this as a group.
Don't be such a sissy.
We're having engine trouble. You go on ahead.
We'll back you up.
Don't try to chicken out!
We stick to the plan.
We share the cost of repairs,
if one of us gets hit. Right?
No you babies! Everyones responsible
for his own expenses.
Even for the ammo? What do you think?
We're having engine trouble!
Shut up you sissies!
What guns are firing?
Attention all passengers!
We are now being attacked by seapirates.
Please do not be alarmed.
The Queen of the Mediterranean coastline
has anticipated this possibility.
And equipped our ship with
two top of the lines pilots!
Now launching from the main desk,
Lane#1 The Black Stallion, Sinor Valleta.
And from Lane#2 The Wolf of the Tiber,
captain Visconti.
Go get 'em boys!
I didn't know they had security.
Aw, they are panicking.
I've to win this thing myself!
Get off me! Help Curtiss!
Make ways, the American!
Hmm..alright I give up.
Guess I'll have to take this
baby to Milan for repairs.
With the help of American Donald Curtiss,airpirates shotdown Queen of the Mediterrean 2 security planes
after stealing all the valuables from the
ship,the pirates left the following message..
we're coming for ya!
Porco Rosso!
Repeat...
we're coming for you Porco Rosso!
Alright Ark! Get off me!
You really expect me to wait here?
Forget it! I'm off to Milan
Lucious feet, soft bed,
beautiful women.
There we go
Cmon baby. Just tour onto Milan
I don't like this weather.
I better duck below the clouds.
Cmon, girl, cmon on!
That's it. That's right!
Just stay with me baby!
Porco!
What?
Fight me pig! One on one!
No thanks Tex!
Kinda busy.
If you run away, I'll tell
everyone you are chicken!
Chicken,pig... what's the difference?
Wo! I'm out in the open.
Oh! Cmon baby!
I hit the pig!
You didn't hit anything.
My engine died you idiot.
He's down! I'm a bonafide celebrity.
Yahoo!
I need some evidence or no one
will believe me. Let's see..
Gotcha!
Obnoxious red paint!
That's proof.
I might just take it back to
Texas as a gift for mom.
Hurry, its an emergency!
Marco's been shot down!
Wait Ms.Gina!
There's a phone call for you.
Porco's alive. He's on the
phone right now.
You can take it at the front desk.
Hey! Wait!
Marco? Are you all right? I was just
about go search for you in my boat.
I'm fine! A tugboat gave me a lift.
Aah!
Thank God! And I've slimmed down.
On an island for two days.
So you look pretty good! Though
not sexy as that American flagway.
I'm sure he'll be stopping by your place.
So tell him we'll meet again!
Anyway, I'm in Milan to fix my plane.
You are in Italy?
You are an idiot! The Italians have
a warrant out for your arrest, remember?
Don't care how great your mechanic is
over there. You get back home you hear me?
Dont want to yell at you Marco. If you keep
acting so pigheaded,you gonna endup dead
Cant go to another pilot's funeral. Come home
Sorry Baby! Gotta fly.
You jerk!
Is Porco Rosso dead or alive?
Good question.
Hey Porco, I thought you would come
here tonight. So I waited up.
She really took a beating this time.
Looks like you are missing
half of the plane.
Wouldn't it be easier
to build a new one?
I'm attached to this one.
Ah!Alright. It's your money
Hey! Lookout, I'm gonna back her in.
Ok?
So tell me Piccolo, where did
you find the girl?
That's my granddaughter, from America.
Keep coming, keep coming.
Gorgeous fuselage, isn't Grandpa?
Great lines.
Not many workers around who can
do a job like that these days.
Well theres no resemblence.
Are you sure that girl
is your granddaughter, Piccolo?
Keep away from here.
Fio, you alright getting the
plane off the rig?
Sure. No problem.
I gotta outfly an American named Curtiss
and my business is in the toilet.
Curtiss? I got just the engine.
What do you think?
This would give me some extra kick.
Don't ask how I got it.
All I can say is that it came from an Italian sea
plane that lost the Schneider Cup to Curtiss in 1927.
But it wasn't the engine's fault.
The mechanic was an idiot.
I'll tune this up, just right.
But don't tune it up too delicately.I'm not
flying this thing in a race, you know.
You are talking to the God of
engine-work here. Trust me!
You plan on taking
all of my money?
Quit wining! These days money's barely
worth the paper it's printed on.
You coming up short! Give me the
money you got in your pocket.
I need that. I gotta pay for meals!
Hotel rooms, more meals.
You can stay here. Meals included,
I won't charge you much.
So Piccolo, haven't seen your sons
around. Are they alright?
They took off to find work.
They took off? Then whose
gonna design my plane?
Fio will do it.
Fio? That cute little girl?
Can't be such a pig.She's a talented
engineer. Even better than my sons.
No dice pack. I need a professional. I'm
taking my worth money somewhere else. Sorry
Wait!
Are you leaving because I'm a woman?
Or is it because I'm too young?
Actually its both kiddo.
Ok that's fair.
But tell me, what's you think
takes a pilot to be great?
Experience?
No. It's intuition.
Hmm I just knew you weren't
gonna say experience.
Grandpa said you flew solo in the first
week and you were a great pilot.
Right from the very start.
Isn't that true?
Hmm yeah that was
1910 when I was 17.
17! That's the same age I am!
I can't help being a woman,
but I gurantee you I have talent.
If I don't do a good job, you
don't have to pay. Okay, Grandpa?
She's my grand daughter,
she'll do fine.
Now with me, I was fixing
engines at the age of 12.
Why don't you sleep on it.
I'm off to bed. Breakfast is at 7.
Left you a clean towel in the bathroom.
Good night!
Still don't have enough.
But since you're a good friend,
I've decided to loan you the rest.
Good morning. Did you sleep well?
You up all night?
Here's a rough draft of the design.
So what do you think?
I tweaked the wing section that should make
the plane fly atleast five knots faster.
Look I dug up the original blueprints.
The design is really radical.Huh?
Wood monocco wings...
with extreme angles of incidence!
I've never seen anything like it.
Yeah they only made one. Then they
decided was too dangerous...
No pilot could fly. I found it
covered and dusted in a warehouse
With the wings like that I'm really surprised
that you can get it off the water.
Takeoffs and landings can be a little bit tricky.
But get it up to speed, she handles like a dream.
Why don't you try and increase the angle
of incidence by half a degree on the wing.
The rest looks fine.
So you're giving me the job?
Thank you! For trusting a woman!
Alright you got the job
but on one condition,Fiona...
No more staying up all night or
your work will start getting sloppy.
Also its truly bad for your complexion.
You got it.
To be honest, I couldn't sleep
last night because...
I was afraid you wouldn't give me the
job. I should sleep fine tonight
I'll go make some coffee and I'll get
back to work.This is so exciting!
I can't wait to start building!
Don't tell me she plans on building
the whole plane by herself!
This is my niece Monica.
Nice to meet you.
This is Ivana, my other niece
her four daughters, Sophia,
Laura, Constance and Valentina.
Fio's big sister Giliola. Sandra she's
my cousin. Marietta, good to see you.
My sons' wives Maria, Tina, Anna,
and the trio...showtime!
Porkalino!
Are you girls really still alive?
You pig! We thought we
get in on the action.
You are not here to
build my plane, are you?
Yeah, we need to get
some poker money.
So this is the crew, huh?
Don't you have any man relatives?
All the men are gone. They had
to look elsewhere for work.
This is work! Get them back...
You mean a grate?
Don't be such a pig.
You'll see, they're
very hard workers.
Yeah we're not baking a cake here!
Heavenly father, we give you thanks
for putting bread on our table...
and for giving us work when we
were at the brink of bankruptcy
Please forgive us for building a
fighter plane with the help of women.
Amen
Please eat and work
on making that cake.
Hear that? You gonna whip
pants off curtiss with this.
How do you think? Too delicate?
I think this might be
bad for your shed, Piccolo.
Yeah? Wait till we turn
it up to full speed.
Hmm, so you want to add a trim tab?
Yeah. Can I?
Hmm I dunno, this is going
to cost a lot of money.
It's a great idea but we already gone way
over budget. See what the client think.
Porco...
Would you stop looking at me like
that, Fio. Just do what's best.
That's great! I've already
talked to the manufacturers.
I'll can get the orders
filled right away!
I love you, Porco!
I give you three months
to pay the bill.
Maybe I should just
become an air pirate.
You like Fio, huh?
Don't touch her.
Don't worry. Just looking
at her makes me tired.
Ferrarin, look at you.
You are a major now.
Marco you crazy! What
you doing back in Italy?
I make a loot come
and go, as I please.
The secret police already know you
are in the country. Were you followed?
Yeah.
I gave em the slip
You gotta get outta Italy now. I've seen your
arrest warrant deserting the Italian Air force,
entering the country illegally,
being a blatantly unpatriotic pig
This is no time to laugh, Marco!
They got it in for you, they want
to confiscate your plane.
Man, this movie stinks.
Marco why don't you come back
to the Air Force? I got influence now
I can work something out.
Thanks for the offer. But I
rather be a pig than a Fascist.
Then you better keep
your plane off the skies.
The only way the Italians will let
you fly is if you fly for our country.
I only fly for myself.
You really are a pig, aren't you?
You realise if they can a pig,
they won't give you a fair trial.
I understand.Thanks Ferrarin.
Give my regards to the guys.
This movie is really great.
Alright I'll try to lookout for you.
But I can only do so much.
Sure. Well so long friend.
Hey Porco, need a ride?
Slide over.
I borrowed this truck so we can
take the seaplane to the lake..
We're ready to give
it a test flight.
No test flights. I'm gettin'
out of here today.
That's ridiculous! I refuse to give
you the plane without testing it.
Plus it will take atleast a day to take the
plane apart and transport it to the lake.
I don't have a choice. I want you to
take a good look behind this van.
Do it slowly.
Thats the Fascist Secret Police.
They're following us.
Following us? What for?
Because they like my pretty red plane.
Problem is they don't like me flying it.
Hey, are you a spy or something?
A spy?
That's the last thing I ever do
kid. I don't look after myself.
But you were a hero
during the war, right?
Well this is really strange if
you haven't done anything wrong!
Couldn't agree with you more.
Hold on!
How about we try
another direction?
Looks like you done this
kind of thing before.
Everytime I go to Milan kiddo.
The plane's ready than you were.
Two secret police are hiding out
back and three in the front.
This is so exciting!
Calm down woman, you rambling.
What?
Thanks
Take care.
I will
Fio, what do you think you doing?
I'm rigging up my seat. Just
give me about five seconds. Ok?
You are crazy if you think I'm
letting you fly along with me.
Shh! The secret police will hear you.
Fio!
There's a warrant out for my arrest, you realize?
This is not a joyride sweetheart,so if you...
Hold this a second please.
Thank you. Look at this. Tada!
I just wipped this together.
And it fits perfectly...
It's a bit of a tight
fit but it should do.
Would you hold this please?
Fio this is way too dangerous! I'll
be taking it from the canal out back
I don't even know if I can
get her off the water!
Eh,hmm. I know! That's why you need
to have the engineer with you.
So that I can make
adjustments to the plane
Don't you get it?
I'm off to fight Curtiss.
I'll have bullets flying over my head!
I can handle that. I'm responsible for this
plane and I wanna do my first job right!
Think about it. I'm a known womanizer, I
live on a deserted island in a small tent.
That's great. I love camping.
That's not the point.
Take her. I'll give you a good deal on the
salary. And I know she will come handy.
Besides I want you back in
business, so that I can get paid.
You are this girl's grandfather?
It'll be good for her. And I'll
install this so you two can chit chat.
So you are okay with turning
her into an outlaw?
Ehmm..Hmm I'm going along as your hostage.
See that way all my relatives can tell the
police that they had no choice but to help you!
So please Porco, let me come.
I can help you.
You better take out one of the machine guns.
What?
Theres not enough space even with
your tiny butt. Now take out a gun.
Thank you! And you know my butt is bigger than
it looks. I'll have to get out in 2 secs.
If we hang around here much longer,
you and the old ladies might come.
And that will cost
you a lotta mullah!
Grandma get out of the way!
Hey Fio, you bring back souvenirs.
I will.
Contact!
Open the door!
Go!
Get down!
Kidnapper! Give back our girl Fio!
Bring Fio back!
How's the steering, Porco?
It's crazy, just like you, Fio.
Its even harder than handle before!
Stop the plane.I'll
make some adjustments.
No we don't have time. I'll get
her up in the air somehow.
I can't get enough lift!
Porco there's a ship!
Get her up!
Come on, baby!
The eorons hitting the water.
Use the trim tabs.
The what?
It's the crate on your right.
Hurry!
Got it. Here we go.
Gorgeous! This is such
an incredible view!
Is that plane following us?
Its someone from the Italian Air force.
Hey! Looks like my old buddy
Ferrarin is here.
What's he saying?
He says the Air force has a trap for us up
ahead. Knows show how we can get outta here!
If we fly low all the way home,
we should stay outta their range.
Thank you very much, my friend!
Thank you!
Very funny!
What did he say?
He said "Cute girl, when did you
start babysitting"?
Alas! A solitary rose
blooms in the secret garden.
That's my favorite line
from a screenplay I wrote.
Mr.Curtiss, why are you
trespassing in my garden.
I've something special to show you.
It's from Hollywood.
“Dear Mr.Curtiss, In regards to the screenplay
you sent us...”
"We would love to produce it and we
would consider you for the lead"
The script's title is the
Rose of the Adriatic.
That sounds wonderful.
Really? Then it's settled.
Gina, come to Hollywood with me.
I've got great aspirations. I'm
already a big celebrity as a pilot!
Soon I'll be a Hollywood star.
And then...
There's more?
The President!
What's so funny? I'm serious!
Don't you wanna be the First Lady?
Gina!
I find your humility very charming.
So you come with me?
No I can't. I've a long
standing bet coming here!
I bet myself that if a certain
man comes to visit me when...
I'm out here in my garden,that
the two of us will fall in love.
But that fool only comes
to my restaurant at night.
He never stops and shows
his face in the daylight.
Porco? I thought he was dead!
You fool.
He left without landing.
My luck I lose again.
What? You chose that
stupid pig over me?
That's right.
Love is a little bit more complicated
here than it is in America.
Falling in love, happens to
you all the time
So have fun in Hollywood, little boy.
Little boy?
Hey! Watch it with the acrobatics.
You made me bump my head.
I'm just saying hi to a friend.
Gina of the Hotel Adriano?
She was the Lady in the white dress,
wasn't she? My grandfather told me...
that all seaplane pilots of the
Adriatic fall madly in love with Gina.
That's wonderful Fio.
So is Gina really your friend?
Or are you in love with her too?
It's time to refuel! Turn around, quit
yapping and get your butt in your seat.
What! Hey wait!
Hey! What's a girl doing
up Porco's plane?
Where's Porco?
He's having a serious
conversation with my dad.
Both the new government
and the old royalist...
have started striking deals
with seaplane pirates.
You are not gonna make a penny
hunting pirates these days, Porco.
There you go.
Thanks.
Well sounds like you are
out of a job Porco!
You should join up with
one of the two factions.
They pay good money for skills like yours.
You betcha.
Specially after Curtiss
goes back to America.
America? You're the ones who
should be going to America.
Farewell to the freedome in Adriatic
and to days in god abandon.
What is that? Shakespeare?
No, it's Porco. See you later.
So long.
The price of gas here is ridiculous. He's
charging us 3 times what we pay in Italy.
Don't be such a crook.
Be reasonable.
Here in the Adriatic Islands, we don't
dilute our gas like Italians do.
Can you please explain
that to her, Porco?
Just pay the kid, Fio.
Then plant your butt that looks bigger
than it looks back in the cubby hall.
We're taking off with my hat out.
Fine! The gas money is going
on your bill anyway!
So when do we fight Curtiss?
No need to now.
I'm outta a job, no ones hiring
bounty hunters these days!
What about your honor? You can't let Curtiss
run around acting like he shot you down .
I'm a pig! I don't fight for honor.
I fight for a paycheck.
It's beautiful!
What a fantastic hideout.
Agh! It's good to stretch my legs.
Ah! Looks like my hideout
isn't so hidden anyway.
Boss! We got the pig!
Get off me!
Out of the way!
You're finished, pig.
It's payback time.
We've got scores to settle.
A girl!
We got a girl here!
She's cute.
So what? Half the world
population is women. Idiot!
Hey Fio is no ordinary girl! She's
a first class seaplane engineer.
But she's so young.
And pretty!
A girl engineer?
Are you sure?
She redesigned my plane and
now it flies better than ever.
She's young, but she's a genius!
Wooh?
You really mean that?
Hey! I never lie about my seaplane, kid.
Treat her with respect. She came
along just to make sure I pay my bill.
So you're in debt, too?
It serves you right!
Hey what do you say, we smash his stupid red plane
to bits. And leave him here to rot and dead?
Smash it? You destroy a work of art?
It happens to be a one
of a kind Savoy-S21
We realize it's a nice plane...
but we have our reaons.
Yeah? What are they?
Well it's kinda complicated.
And you call yourselves seaplane pilots?
Step aside. Watch the shoes!
My grandpa has been telling me stories
of seaplane pirates ever since I was born.
He says seaplane pirates are the most honorable
and trustworthy fighters in the world!.
Everytime they fly both the ocean
and the sky purify their hearts.
So they're braver than
any pilot in the sky...
and they are mightier than
any sailor in the sea!.
Ms.Fio! Thank you, you make me
proud to be a seaplane pirate.
And you should be, I can tell it's not
about money or revenge. You are about honor!
Yeah! That's right, Fio! Yeah
To honor!
Now that girl is something else.
Ok Ms.Fio, we respect you so we'll
not destroy the plane that you made!
But we still hate that stinkin'
pig's gut and we want payback.
Slice that pig to bacon!
Yeah!
What are you morons talking about?
You can't gangup on a fellow sea
plane pilot! Where is your honor?
You ought to be completely
ashamed of yourselves!
A real seaplane pirate would never
fight in a pack like bunch of cowards!
Look at Porco, he just came back so that
we could have a re-match with Curtiss.
And defend his reputation
like a real sea pirate should.
So if you wanna fight Porco honorably
then you fight him in the sky!
One on one.
I would fight Porco...
but my plane has engine trouble.
You big liar! Quit makin' excuses.
What should we do, Boss?
She did make some good points.
Yeah!
We should pick someone who can fight
Porco. I think we should talk to Curtiss.
Wait a minute! Asking him
to fight the pig again?
Only Curtiss can beat him.
The contract with him
has already expired!
Howdy fellas!
What? It's Curtiss!
What's he doin' here?
I followed ya' all! I knew you
get into trouble without me!
Nice goin' Fio. Look at the
mess you got me into now.
Here..hold these.
So do you want me to challenge
for a rematch do you, pig?
Why should I give it to ya? I won once already
and my contract with these boys is expired.
Well give us a proposition?
What do you want?
Beautiful!
Tell you what, if I win
will you marry me darlin'?
That's what I want.
Fine with me! But if Porco beats you, then
you ought to pay the debt he owes me.
Don't do it, Fio!
Eh, backup!.
Ms.Fio are you quite
ceratin you wanna do this?
You should ask him not me.
These bills are kinda expensive.
No they're not!
Are you gonna fight or not?
I'll gladly fight for
the woman that I love!
Good!
Alright! The fight will take place
first thing tomorrow morning!.
Since Fio is doing such an
honorable thing, my gang will host!
Hey we like to host too!
Yeah! Yeah!
See you later, Ms.Fio!
This is ridiculous!
Don't forget to show up, pig!
Shut up, just go home already!
Ok!
What on Earth possessed you,
to make that deal?
Well I'm sorry, I guess I
shouldn't have been ameaned.
I'm just a stupid little girl!
Fio?
I should thank you for
saving my life back there!
You really put yourself on the line.
So thanks. It looks like we are
into this thing together now.
So you'll fight Curtiss?
He could win you know.
Hmm
You got more honor.
Honor? I hate that word, but somehow
when you say it doesn't sound so bad..
What's the matter with you?
Are you cold? Fio>
Oh Boy!.
I'm shaking allover. My heart's
pounding like crazy
I guess I was really scared .
I just didn't know you
would fight for me Porco!
Woah! What you doin'?
I need a swim.
Oh No!
What?
What's wrong?
I really lew it Porco.
I should have padded those bills!
Curtiss would have paid a lot more!
You're right!
Porco?
Can't you sleep?
I saw...
Maybe it was a dream.
Go back to sleep.
We gotta big day tomorrow.
Porco?
Yeah?
Why did you turn into a pig?
Hmm.. All middle aged men are pigs!
You know I've heard a lot about Capt.Marco
Rossolini. My father was in his fighter unit.
He told me that Marco once landed
a seaplane in raging sea...
to save the life of an enemy pilot.
I think that's amazing!
I got it! What if I kiss you Porco?
Yeah you heard the fairy tale where the girl kisses
the frog and turns him back to a handsome prince?
Cmon! You gotta save it for somebody
special. For crying out loud.
Don't you like me?
You're a great kid.
You know what Fio? Seeing you makes me
wish I shouldn't have given up being human.
Now go to sleep.
First tell me a story,
then I'll goto sleep.
Alright
Here's a winner!
It was the last summer
of the great war...
We were flying over the Adriatic, on a
routine survellience patrol heading to Istria.
My good buddy Berlini
was right beside me.
He had just gotten married
to Gina from the Hotel Adriana.
And I was his best man.
But the war called so he had to go
back to battle right after the ceremony.
Suddenly we were in the middle
of the worst dogfight in my life.
Friends and enemies were falling
around me like flies.
I had 3 planes trying
to chase me down.
And all I thought about was myself. Soon I
realised I was the only one left from my unit.
But the enemy never let up. I feel
my guts out trying to get away.
My hands and feet went numb. I could
feel myself starting to blackout.
I was sure I was gonna die then suddenly
everything around me turned white.
White?
Yeah, it was the strangest thing I ever seen.
A light that was so pure,
I figured I must be in heaven.
Then I realized that I had flown into
a cloud. I was so exhausted that...
I couldn't hold the stick to fly my plane.
But the plane just kept on flying.
Flew by itself?
Yeah it was perfectly quiet.
And the sky was beautiful...
then I saw this strange
white band high above me.
Berlini, I thought you were dead!
Come back here! Where do
you think you are going?
What about Gina?
You can't leave her alone.
Let me go instead!
Hold on!
When I came to, I was skimming
just above the sea, all alone.
God was telling you,
it wasn't your time yet.
You think? Seems to me, he was telling me maybe
I was a pig and I deserved to be all alone.
You can't believe that!
You're a good person!
No! The good ones are the ones who died.
Or maybe I'm dead, life as a pig.
It's the same thing as hell.
Now go to sleep.
That stupid kid, he sold
me rusted cartridges.
I think you are a great human being,
Porco. I'm glad you're still around.
Good night!
Place your bets here!
Box seats here!
Place your wager!
Buncha morons!
They'll turn this into a big party
Are all of these people air pirates?
No they are trash all over the Mediterranean.
Gangsters, smugglers, gamblers...
Yeah you might have a handful of
few respectful people but I doubt it.
Wow! Not only will I get a wife but
also will be getting more famous!
Ten minutes to start!
Listen up! This is a final bouter
between Porco Rosso and Donald Curtiss.
So if one of you fights dirty, you'll be
disrespected by seaplane pilots for eternity !
Cmon! No speeches, no speeches!
Quite down ! The next person
I hear whining is dead meat!
Why not drop a bomb?
Really gets them quite.
This fight will decides
the fate of Ms.Fio...
who you all love and respect!
So keep your mouth shut.
You got that? If you do
clap your hands, clap now!
Let's get started already!
Shut up pig! We're following
official procedures
Now both you place your
bets on these chairs!
Thank you.
Set it down, moron!
If both sides are satisfied, you should
shake hands or something like that!
Forget it. I like to keep my hands clean.
Shh! Alright! Let's just
get on with it.
We'll go to the church
as soon as this is over!
Ah! Don't worry Fio. Accordin' to
ma sweet mama it isn't love that counts! .
Fio, can we take a picture with you?
We took a bath!
Ok? Everybody ready?
Cheese! Smile!
Place your bets here!
Three mins to Curtiss in favor!
This is great! We should get
them to do this every month!
15 seconds to start.
Wow! I got chills.
Five seconds...
Four...
Three...
Two...
One...
Go! Go! Go
Curtiss is up first!
It looks like its gonna
be a one sided fight!
Gimme those!
Porco! What you doing?
Get some altitude!
He'll be eating bullets
if he climbs up now.
He being tricky.
It will be harder for Curtiss to
hit him if is closer to the water.
Aha! You are trying to make
me waste my bullets, aren't you?
Look at that! Porco gave him the loop.
Whats the loop?
The loop is what made Porco
the Ace of the Adriatic!
He's got me!
He's gonna shoot!
Look he's not shooting! What's
wrong? Is his machinegun jammed?
I think I know what's going on
here. Porco won't shoot a pilot!
He'll always shoot the plane!
Look, there he's in perfect position!
Cmon! Shoot!
No! He's not going for it!
Just as I thought!
If the pig shoots now,
he'll kill Curtiss.
I bet he plans to tire Curtiss out
and shoot his engine up instead.
What a show-off.
Porco...
Are you messin' with me?
Cmon shoot!
Ah! I bet your gun is jammed!
Isn't? Serves you right pig!
They are coming towards us!
So you wanna play games with me?
Is that it?
Don't kill us!
Kill each other!
Curtiss pulled away from the pig!
Jump! Jump!
Hey! Watch the money!
Amazing! The pig's leaving
a vapor trail!
Unbelievable! I haver never seen
a dogfight like this in my life!
They sure are crazy!
The fight's gonna be over!
What's taking her so long?
I dunno. She's in her
room with the door shut.
Boy! I really don't
wanna miss this fight!
Is she coming on not?
Gina, Italians know about the
fighting. Get the pig out of there!
Ferrarin.
Marco! I hope I'm not too late!
I cant believe that
can keep this up.
Looks like the pig's fading.
Go on, Porco hang in there!
You must quit!
I'm not handing Fio over
to a jerk like you!
He's got Curtiss's edge in sight!
It's over!
No! No! Don't jam now!
Gotcha!
What?
It can't be jammed!
It's not jammed. You used
up all your ammo, you idiot!
That's not good! And no sucking gun and
thanks to Fio's big butt!
I refuse to end this
fight with a draw!
You stupid cowboy! There's no way
you can hit me with that.
Oh yeah?
You think you can hit me from
there? Cmon give me a break.
You think that's funny?
you're not even cutting close!
Throw somethin' already!
You throw like a girl!
You don't even know
anything about girls!
Shut up, pig!
What's goin' on up there?
Cmon Porco!
They're coming in!
Wait! You're a bet! The
bets can't run off, Fio.
I go where the money goes!
Wait for me!
Why you crazy pig!
Come and get it cowboy!
Cmon put 'em up.
Fight with me, you weakling!
No, Porco!
Get up, Pig
You cheating!
Shut up!
Cmon Porco, Block.
Uppercut!
Yeah! Yeah!
Hit 'em.
Yes! Now we got a boxing match.
The bets are still open!
Taking bets! Taking bets!
Bring a bell up here!
Can't you fly this plane any faster?
Sorry maam, but I'm afraid
the engine will overheat.
Seaplane pilots are all idiots!
Het Fio! Did you see
that left hook I threw?
I'm gonna finish you
off in the next round.
This time I'm send
you to dreamland Curtiss.
Hit him!
I'll wade a pushway you!
Come on, big womanizer!
You're the one who is a womanizer!
You fall in love with
every woman you meet!
Your the one hoggin'
in all the girls...
Just pick one...Gina or Fio.
What are you talkin' about?
You gonna have one!
Gina says hi...
Don't say Gina like you know her!
Gina says she's been waitin' for ya!
For years now, she's been wanting to
meet her in that stupid garden of hers...
She loves you, Pig!
Porco!
The bell sounded the final countdown!
That's a knockout!
Stop!
Round is out! Back to your corner.
There they are!The Air Force
hasn't arrived yet.
End of round 6
Round 7
Gina does not want me, liar.
I'm not lying. Why would
I make that up?
So you want Gina?
You can't have Fio!
That's Gina's plane!
Hey its an emergency signal!
1..2..3
Who ever gets up first, wins!
4..5
Excuse me! Let me through please!
6..7
Gina, wait!
Marco. Marco, getup.
I don't wanna see breaking
anymore hearts! You hear me?
9.. Yeee!
Porco!
The winner!
Porco, Thank you!
Yeah, piece of cake.
Okay, listen up everybody. The Italian
Air Force is on its way here.
So anyone in trouble with the Italian
authority better move on out.
Come to the my place.
Drinks are on the house!
Ok gang! Lets squill!
Mr.Curtiss, the fight's over.
Hey Boss! Cmon hurry up!
I'm trying to be classy! You idiot!
You a great seaplane engineer.
Keep it up Ms.Fio.
Bye!
Thank you. And keep up the bathing!
And I want to say thanks
to you too, Mr. Curtiss!
Next time I'll propose
you formally and skip the bet.
Ok. But I already know my answer.
Fio! You're going with Gina.
No!
I'm going with you. You said
we are in on this together.
Gina, take her to her
respectable society please.
You always do this, Marco.
It's just not fair.
Sorry. Off you go.
Let's go.
Here come the Italian Air Force.
I'm gonna draw them from
the others. You wanna help?
Sure. Your face!
Hey wait up! Turn around!
Get away from me!
Cmon, let me see
Porco flew rings around Italian Air force
and they never caught up with him again.
I stayed with Gina for a while
and we became good friends.
But soon I decided, it was
time to go back to Milan.
Through the years there have
been a few wars and a...
good deal of turmoil, but my friendship
with Gina has remained strong.
I am now President of the Piccolo Co.,
and we are busy designing all sorts of...
radical new planes but I take time out
every summer to visit the Hotel  Adriana.
The old pirate gang still
hang out at Gina's Bar.
Mr.Curtiss does write to me sometimes,
although he's yet to become...
the President of the United States.
And he still fondly remembers the
summer in the Adriatic.
And as for how Gina's bet turned out...
well that's our secret!
Songs Performed by
Tokiko Kato
VOICES
PORCO ROSSO Shuichiro Moriyama
MADAME GINA Tokiko Kato
MASTER PICCOLO Sanshi Katsura
MAMMA AIUTO BOSS Tsunehiko Kamijo
Executive Producers
Yasuyoshi Tokuma
Matsuo Toshimitsu and Yoshio Sasaki
Original Story and Screenplay by
Hayao Miyazaki
Music by
Joe Hisaishi
English Translation by
Stephen Alpert, Haruyo Moriyoshi
Jim Hubbert and Ian MacDougall
A Studio Ghibli Film
Producer
Toshio Suzuki
Directed by
Hayao Miyazaki
The End