Who do you think
they are to each other?
Hm...
I don't know.
Yeah, this is a hard one.
I think...
the white guy
and the Asian girl
are a couple,
and the Asian guy...
is her brother.
Or the Asian girl
and the Asian guy
are a couple,
and the white guy
is their American friend.
They are not even talking
to the white guy.
Maybe they
are tourists,
and the white guy
is their tour guide.
Drinking at 4:00 a.m.?
Yeah, you're right,
that makes no sense.
Hm. Maybe they're
all just colleagues?
I have no idea.
Hm?
Ah,
I'm thinking two things...
I want you to draw a tree.
- Tree?
- Hm.
That's what
I'm good at.
A tree doesn't have feelers.
It looks all same to me.
- Black barks and white...
- What is it?
This is called "blue."
This is called "yellow".
- Hello.
My name is Nora,
what's your name?
My name is Michelle.
How are you,
Michelle?
I'm fine, and you?
I'm fine,
and you?
I'm fine, and you?
I'm...
Toronto Pearson
International Airport...
International...
This is from Korea.
This is our passport, and...
Whoa!
I mean,
there is so much in it
that I responded to.
But the one phrase that sticks
with me most...
Mm-hmm.
"The long journey...
"of rotting."
I liked it too.
We liked how you
used the long pauses.
Hm?
Hm...
Uh...
Um...
Oh, shit.
Hm.
Hey.
Huh?
Hm.
Whoa.
Oh...
Hm.
Hm-mm.
Hm...
Huh?
Mm.
Hm.
Hm...
Eternal Sunshine
of the Spotless Mind.
What did I do?
I love you so much.
I'll do anything to make
you happy.
Tell me what you want me
to do and I'll do it.
Have you
done your homework?
I haven't.
You have to do it
for graduation.
I got under
academic probation
last semester.
Hm-mm.
Class captain's
message.
Let me see
your homework.
Maybe next time.
Oh. Huh?
What's your plan
for weekend?
Playing games.
Are you okay?
We walked around a lot.
My leg is
a bit hurt, but I'm okay.
- This leg hurt?
- It's okay.
Rock, paper, scissor.
No, thanks.
Hi.
Hi! I'm Nora.
I'm Arthur.
Nice to meet you.
When'd you get in?
This morning.
You got
the worst room.
Right?
I know.
There is a word
in Korean.
In-Yun.
It means "providence."
Or... "fate".
But it's specifically
about relationships
between people.
I think it comes from...
Buddhism.
And...
reincarnation.
It's an "in-yun"
if two strangers even walk by
each other in the street
and their clothes
accidentally brush.
Because...
it means there must have been
something between them
in their past lives.
If two people get married...
they say it's because there
have been 8000 layers
of in-yun.
Over 8000 lifetimes.
You believe in that?
Believe what?
That...
You and I knew each other
in another life.
What, because
we are sitting here...
At the same table,
in the same city,
at the same time?
Mm-hmm.
Yeah, wouldn't
that make this...
In-yun?
Hm...
Mm-mm.
Mm.
That's just
something Koreans say
to seduce someone.
Hi.
Where you going?
New York City.
Why're you going there?
We live there.
What's your occupation?
Writers.
You're what?
We're writers.
How long
were you visiting Toronto?
Ten days.
What was the purpose
of your visit?
We were visiting
her family.
Are you two related?
We're married.
Thanks!
"If you bought
a ticket to see this show,
"took the subway or a cab
to be here,
"it cost you something
"and spend a couple hours
with these old women,
"that makes you
some kind of immigrant.
"And...
"all this cost me
something too.
"I crossed the Pacific Ocean
to be here.
"Some crossings
cost more than others.
"Some crossings...
"you pay for
with your whole life."
...sit most
of the day,
and in the end I...
And then
I started to write about...
After Dinner.
Um, yeah, I mean,
it's my kind of time.
Uh, but you're studying,
right?
Me, too.
I don't know.
You know
what I want?
What?
Chicken wings.
Holy shit.
Mm-hm. Yeah.
Oh, genius.
Mm-hmm.
Yes.
Chicken wings!
Hm...
What're you
thinking about?
Remember I told you
about Hae Sung?
Oh, yeah.
Is that this week?
Yeah.
Why is he
coming here again?
I think
vacation.
Uh, trunk? Trunk?
Hm.
Hmm?
Hmm.
Hi.
Hi, my love.
How was it?
You were right.
I was?
Yeah.
He came here to see me.
It's so crazy to see him
be this grown-up man
with a normal job
and a normal life.
He's so Korean.
He still lives
with his parents
which is really Korean.
And he has all these
really Korean views
about everything.
And I feel so not Korean
when I'm with him.
But also,
in some way, more Korean?
It's so weird.
I mean, I have Korean friends,
but he's not, like,
Korean-American.
He's Korean-Korean.
Is he attractive?
I think so.
He's really masculine
in this way
that I think is so Korean.
Are you attracted to him?
I don't think so.
I don't know, I mean...
He was just this kid
in my head
for such a long time.
And then he was
just this image on my laptop.
And now he's
a physical person.
It's really intense,
but I don't think
that that's attraction,
I think I just
missed him a lot.
I think I miss Seoul.
Did he miss you?
I think he missed
the 12-year-old crybaby
he knew a long time ago.
You were a crybaby?
Yeah.
Most of the time, he'd have to
just stand there and watch me.
When is he leaving, again?
The morning after tomorrow.
Mm-hmm.
Are you mad?
No.
It feels like you are.
I don't have
a right to be mad.
What do you mean?
Of course you do.
No, I...
That guy flew
13 hours to be here.
I'm not gonna tell you
that you can't see him
or something.
He's your childhood
sweetheart.
And it's not like you're gonna
run away with him.
Are you?
Definitely.
I'm gonna throw away
my life here and run away...
...with him to Seoul.
Do you even know me?
I'm not gonna miss
my rehearsals for some dude.
I know.
I know you.
What?
I was just thinking about
what a good story this is.
The story of Hae Sung and me?
Yeah.
I just can't compete.
What do you mean?
Childhood sweethearts
who reconnect 20 years later
only to realize they were
meant for each other.
We're not
I know.
In the story,
I would be the evil
white American husband
standing in the way
of destiny.
Shut up.
What do you not like about it?
Our story's just so boring.
We met at
an artists' residency.
Slept together because we both
happened to be single.
We realize
we both live in New York,
so we move in together
to save money on rent.
We got married so you could
get a green card. So...
Oh, you make it sound
so romantic.
Right, that's
what I'm saying.
I'm the guy
you leave in the story
when your ex-lover
comes to take you away.
He's not my ex-lover.
What if you met somebody else
at that residency?
What if there was
another writer from New York
who had also read
all the same books you had,
and watched
all the same movies,
could give you
useful notes on your plays,
and listen to you complain
about your rehearsals?
That's not how life works.
I know.
Yeah.
But wouldn't you be
laying here with him?
This is my life,
and I'm living it with you.
Are you happy with it?
Is this what you
imagined for yourself
when you left Seoul?
When I was a 12-year-old?
Yeah. Is this what
you pictured for yourself?
Laying in bed in some...
tiny apartment
in the East Village
with some Jewish guy
who writes books?
Is that what your parents
wanted for you?
You're asking me if you,
Arthur Zaturansky,
are the answer to
my family's immigrant dream?
Yeah.
Wow.
This is where we ended up.
This is where
I'm supposed to be.
Okay.
What?
It's just that you make
my life so much bigger.
And I'm wondering if I do
the same thing for you.
You do.
I'm just a girl from Korea,
you know?
Okay.
And you're forgetting the part
where I love you.
I don't forget that.
I have trouble
believing it sometimes.
Do you know
you only speak in Korean
when you talk in your sleep?
I do?
Yeah.
You never
sleep talk in English.
You only dream in Korean.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
You never told me that.
Well, sometimes
I think it's cute.
Sometimes, I don't know,
I guess I get scared.
Scared of what?
You dream in a language
that I can't understand.
It's like
there's this whole place
inside of you
where I can't go.
I think that's why I've been
trying to learn Korean,
even though I know
it's annoying for you.
You want to understand me
when I'm dreaming?
Yeah.
I'm sure I'm just
saying gibberish.
Hm?
Um...
Uh, hi.
Nice to meet you, also.
Uh...
Are you hungry?
Hm?
Oh...
Ah, oh. Yes.
Uh...
Pasta?
Pasta? Yeah.
You like pasta?
Yes.
Okay.
Let's get pasta.
Pasta.
What did you two do today?
Uh...
The Statue of Liberty.
You took the ferry.
Yes.
Yeah.
It's, um, nice.
I've never been.
What?
Really?
Yeah, I've never
actually been there.
Have we seriously
never been there together?
No.
When I was 24 year,
I, uh... Um...
Oh.
Yes.
Oh, military service.
Right.
You know how Korean men have
mandatory military service?
Yeah, your dad
talks about it.
How was it?
You like it?
No.
Uh, but military
and work, same.
Same?
Uh, you have, um...
You have a boss.
Hm.
There's no
overtime pay in Korea.
It's, uh, very hard.
Hmm. Uh, work. Work is hard.
Hard physically or mentally?
Uh, yes.
Uh, both.
Physical, very hard.
Uh, and, um...
Hm. Mentally.
Mentally, I'm strong.
Mm!
Mm.
Hm.
He's talking about you.
I'm sorry
we speak alone.
Uh, we will stop.
It's okay.
You haven't seen each other
in a long time.
I never thought I'd be
a part of something like this.
Hm?
Sitting here with you.
Do you know what in-yun?
Yeah. Nora told me about it
when we first met.
You and me.
Yeah. Yeah,
you and I are in-yun too.
Right?
I'm really glad
you came here.
It was
the right thing
to do.
Mm. I'm gonna
walk him to his Uber.
Okay.
Uh, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Uh, come visit me in Korea.
Definitely.
I'll be right back.
Okay.
Hm.
Hm?