Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org
Subtitles by 2003ad
Did you know there are more people with genius IQ's living in
China than there are people of any kind living in the US?
That can't possibly be true.
- It is.
What would account for that?
Well, first, an awful lot of people
live in China, but here's my question:
How do you distinguish yourself in a population
of people who all got 1600 on their SAT's?
I didn't know they take SAT's in China.
They don't. I wasn't talking about China
anymore, I was talking about me.
You got a 1600?
Yes. I could sing in an acapella group, but I can't sing.
- Does that mean you actually got nothing wrong?
I could row crew, or invent a $25 PC.
Or you get into a final club.
Or I get into a final club.
You know, from a woman's perspective sometimes
not singing in an acapella group is a good thing.
This is serious.
- On the other hand I do like guys who row crew.
Well, I can't do that.
I was kidding.
Yes, I got nothing wrong on the test.
Have you ever tried?
- I'm trying right now.
To row crew?
- To get into a final club.
To row crew? No.
Are you, whatever, delusional?
Maybe it's just sometimes you say two things at once
and I'm not sure which one I'm supposed to be aiming at.
But you've seen guys who row crew, right?
No.
OK, well, they're bigger than me.
They're world class athletes.
And a second ago you said you like guys who
row crew, so I assumed you had met one.
I guess I meant I liked the idea of it
in the way a girl likes cowboys.
OK.
Shall we get something to eat?
- Would you like to talk about something else?
No, it's just since the beginning of the conversation about
finals club, I think I may have missed a birthday.
There are really more people in China with
genius IQ's than the entire population of -
The Phoenix is the most diverse. The Fly Club...
Roosevelt punched the Porc.
Which one?
The Porcellian, the Porc, it's the best of the best.
Which Roosevelt?
- Theodore.
Is it true they send a bus around to pick up girls
who want to party with the next Fed chairman?
So you can see why it's so important to get in.
OK, well, which is the easiest to get into?
Why would you ask me that?
- I was just asking.
None of them, that's the point.
My friend Eduardo made $300,000
betting oil futures one summer...
...and Eduardo won't come close to getting in. The ability
to make money doesn't impress anybody around here.
Must be nice.
He made $300,000 in a summer?
He likes meteorology.
You said it was oil futures.
You can read the weather,
you can predict the price of heating oil.
I think you asked me that because you think the final club
that's the easiest to get into, is the one where I'll have the best chance.
I... what?
You asked me which one was the easiest to get into
because you think that that's the one where I have the best chance.
The one that's easiest to get into would be the one
where anybody has the best chance.
You didn't ask which one was the best one,
you asked me which one was the easiest.
I was honestly just asking, OK?
I was just asking to ask.
Mark, I'm not speaking in code.
Erica -
You're obsessed with finals clubs. You have finals clubs OCD.
You need to see someone about it who'll prescribe you medication.
You don't care if the side-effects may include blindness.
Final clubs.
Not finals clubs.
And there's a difference between being
obsessed and being motivated.
Yes...
...there is.
Well, you do. That was cryptic, so you do speak in code.
I didn't mean to be cryptic.
I'm just saying I need to do something substantial
in order to get the attention of the clubs.
Why?
Because they're exclusive.
And fun, and they lead to a better life.
Teddy Roosevelt didn't get elected for president
because he was a member of the Phoenix Club.
He was a member of the Porcellian, and yes, he did.
Well, why don't you concentrate on being
the best you, you can be.
Did you really just say that?
I was kidding.
Although just being straight
doesn't make it any less true.
I want to be straightforward and tell you
that I think you might want to be a little bit more supportive.
If I get in, I'll be taking you to the events and the gatherings,
and you'll be meeting people that you wouldn't normally get to meet.
You would do that for me?
We're dating.
OK.
Well, I'm gonna try and be straightforward with you
and let you know that we're not anymore.
What do you mean?
We're not dating anymore, I'm sorry.
Is this a joke?
- No, it's not.
You're breaking up with me?
You were going to introduce me to people
I wouldn't normally have the chance to meet.
What the f...
What is it supposed to mean?
Wait, settle down.
Erica, the reason we're able to sit here and drink
is 'cause you used to sleep with the door guy.
"The door guy"...his name is Bobby. I have not slept with
"the door guy", "the door guy" is a friend of mine.
And he is a perfectly good class of people.
And what part of Long Island are you from, Wimbledon?
Wait.
- I'm going back to my dorm room.
Wait, wait, is this real?
- Yes.
OK, then wait. I apologize, OK?
- I have to go study.
Erica.
- Yes?
I'm sorry, I mean it.
- I appreciate that, but I have to go study.
Come on, you don't have to study.
Let's just talk.
I can't.
- Why?
Because it's exhausting.
Dating you is like dating a stair master.
All I meant is that you're not likely to... currently.
I wasn't making a comment on your parents,
I was saying you go to BU. I was stating a fact, that's all...
...and if it seems rude, then of course I apologize.
- I have to go study.
You don't have to study.
- Why you keep saying I don't have to study?
Because you go to BU!
Want to get some food?
I'm sorry you're not sufficiently impressed with my education.
And I'm sorry I don't have a rowboat.
So we're even.
I think we should just be friends.
- I don't want friends.
I was just being polite,
I have no intention of being friends with you.
I'm under some pressure
right now from my OS class...
...and if we could just order
some food, I think we should -
OK, you're probably going to be
a very successful computer person.
But you're going to go through life thinking
that girls don't like you because you're a nerd.
And I want you to know from the bottom
of my heart, that that won't be true.
It will be, because you're an asshole.
Erica Albright's a bitch. Do you think that's
because her family changed their name from Albrecht?
Or do you think it's because
all BU girls are bitches?
For the record, she may look like a 34C.
but she's getting all kinds of help from our friends at Victoria's Secret.
She's a 34B, as in barely anything there.
False advertising.
The truth is, she has a nice face.
I need to do something to
take my mind off her.
Easy enough, except I need an idea.
I'm a little intoxicated, I'm not gonna lie.
So what if it's not even 10 P.M. and it's a Tuesday night?
The Kirkland facebook is open on my desktop
and some of these people have pretty horrendous facebook pics.
Billy Olson's sitting here had the idea of putting some of the pictures
next to pictures of farm animals, and have people vote on who's hotter.
Good call, Mr. Olson.
Yea, it's on.
I'm not gonna do the farm animals but
I like the idea of comparing two people together.
It gives the whole thing a very "Turing" feel since people's ratings
of the pictures will be more implicit than, say, choosing a number...
...to represent each person's hotness
like they do on hotornot.com.
The first thing we're going to need
is a lot of pictures.
Unfortunately, Harvard doesn't keep a public centralized facebook,
so I'm going to have to get all the images...
...from the individual houses that people are in.
Let the hacking begin.
First up is Kirkland. They keep everything open
and allow indexes in their Apache configuration...
...so a little WGET magic is all that's necessary
to download the entire Kirkland facebook.
Kid's stuff.
Next is Elliot. They're also open but
with no indexes on Apache.
I can run an empty search, and it returns
all of the images in the database in a single page.
Then I can save the page
and Mozilla will save all the images for me.
Excellent.
Moving right along.
Excuse me - everybody!
You're at one of the oldest,
one of the most exclusive clubs...
...not just at Harvard,
but in the world.
Now I want to welcome you all at
Phoenix' first party of the fall semester.
Lowell has some security.
They require a username/password combo...
...and I'm going going ahead and say they don't have access
to main FAS user database, so they have no way of detecting an intrusion.
Adams has no security, but limits
the number of results to twenty a page.
All I need to do is breakout the same script
I used on Lowell, and we're set.
Quincy has no online facebook, what a sham.
Nothing I can do about that.
Dunster is intense. Not only is there no public
directory, but there's no directory at all.
You have to do searches, and if your
search returns more then twenty matches...
...nothing gets returned.
Once you do get results, they don't link directly to the
images, they link to a php that redirects or something.
Weird. This may be difficult,
I'll come back later.
Hey, shark's week is on.
- What?
Great white, beautiful fish.
Leverett is a little better. They still use end search,
but you can do an empty search and get links to pages...
...with a every student's picture.
It's slightly obnoxious that they
let you view one picture at a time...
...and there's no way I'm going through five hundred pages,
to download pics one at a time.
So it's definitely necessary to break out Emacs
and modify that perl script.
Done.
Hey, what's goin' on?
Perfect timing. Eduardo's here,
and he's going to have the key ingredient.
Hey Mark.
- Eduardo.
You and Erica split up.
How did you know that?
It's on your blog.
Yeah.
Are you alright?
- I need you.
I'm here for you.
No, I need the algorithm you
used to rank chess players.
Are you okay?
We're ranking girls.
You mean other students.
Yeah.
You think this is such a good idea?
I need the algorithm.
Give each girl a base rating of 1400.
At any given time Girl A has a rating Ra...
...and Girl B has a rating Rb.
When any two girls are matched up, there's an expectation
of which will win based on their current rating, right?
Yeah.
- And those expectations are expressed this way.
Let's write it.
The one on the left.
On the right.
The right.
Who should we send it to first?
Dwyer.
Neal.
Who are you gonna send it to?
Just a couple of people.
Question is, who are they gonna send it to?
Hey guys, check this out.
The one on the left.
These girls...
Right or left?
Left.
Right or left.
That's my roommate.
All on the left.
This is pathetic.
Right.
Left.
Albright, he blogged about you.
You don't want to read it.
Erica, is this yours?
I stole it from a trainee.
Get the hell out of here.
That's an awful lot of traffic.
You think maybe we shouldn't shut
it down before we get into trouble?
Hello?
Wait, wait, wait.
What?
At four in the morning?
Well, there is a very unusual amount
of traffic to the switch of Kirkland.
You're saying it's unusual for four in the morning?
No, this would be unusual for halftime at the Super Bowl.
Alright.
I gotta go in.
What's going on?
Harvard's network is about to crash.
You don't think...
I do.
God save us every bodies.
Can't connect.
The network's down.
Unless it's a coincidence,
I'd think this is us.
It's not a coincidence.
Holy shit.
So you were called in front of the ad board.
That's not what happened.
You weren't called in front of
the administrative board?
No, back at the bar with Erica Albright.
She said all that?
Mark.
- That I said that stuff to her?
I was reading from the transcript of her deposition.
Why would you even need to depose her?
That's really for us to decide.
You think if I know she could make me look like a
jerk I'll be more likely to settle.
Mark.
Why don't we stretch our legs for
a minute, can we do that?
It's been almost three hours and frankly you did spend an awful lot of time
embarrassing Mr. Zuckerberg with the girl's testimony from the bar.
I am not embarrassed, she just made a lot of that up.
She was under oath.
Then I guess that would be the first time
somebody's lied under oath.
The site got twenty-two hundred hits within two hours?
Thousand.
What?
Twenty-two thousand.
These guys are just freaking' fast.
Is there any way to make this a fair fight?
Jump out and swim.
We'd have to jump out and drown.
You could row forward
and I could row backward.
We're genetically identical.
Science says we'd stay in one place.
Just row the damn boat.
You guys hear about this?
- What?
Two nights ago, a sophomore choked the network from a laptop of Kirkland.
At four A.M.
He set up a website where we vote
for the hotness of female undergrads.
What were we doing, that none of us heard about this.
I do not know, three hour low rate technical row before breakfast?
Full course load studying.
Another three hours in the tank, then studying.
I'm not sure how we missed it.
How much activity was on this thing.
Twenty-two thousand page requests.
Twenty-two thousand?
This stuff is half of facebook, seven houses.
He set up the whole website in one night,
and he did it while he was drunk.
Twenty-two thousand.
How you know he was drunk?
He was blogging, simultaneously.
You know what I think?
Way ahead of you.
This is our guy.
Cameron WINKLEVOSS.
Cameron spelled the usual way.
Tyler WINKLEVOSS. Tyler spelled the usual way,
and my last name is the same as my brother's.
Mr. Zuckerberg, this is an Administrative board hearing.
You're being accused of intentionally breaching security,
violating copyrights, violating individual privacy...
...by creating the website www.facemash.com.
You're also charged with being in violation of university
policy on distribution of digitized images.
Before we begin with our questioning, you're allowed
to make a statement. Would you like to do so?
You know, I've already apologized in
The Crimson, to the AVHW...
...to varsity Latina, and to any women at Harvard
who may have been insulted, as I take it that they were.
As for any charges stemming
from the breach of security...
...I believe I deserve some recognition from this board.
I'm sorry?
Yes.
I don't understand.
Which part?
You deserve recognition.
I believe I pointed out some pretty
gaping holes in your system.
Excuse me, may I?
Mr. Zuckerberg. I'm in charge of security
for all computers on the Harvard network...
...and I can assure you of its sophistication.
In fact, it was that level of sophistication,
that led us to you in less then four hours.
Four hours?
- Yes, sir.
That would be impressive, except if you'd known what you are looking
for you would've seen it written on my dorm room window.
So?
- Six months Academic probation.
Wow, they had to make an example out of you.
They had my blog.
I shouldn't have written nothing about the
farm animals, that was stupid.
But I was kidding for God's sakes,
doesn't anybody have a sense of humor?
I tried to stop you.
- I know.
How do you do this thing were you
manage to get all girls to hate us?
Why did I meet you?
You can't do that.
Eduardo, I said I know.
OK, let's look at a sample problem.
Suppose we're given a computer with a 16-bit
virtual address, and a page size of 256 bytes.
The system uses one-level page
tables that start at address 0x0400.
Maybe you want DMA on
your 16-bit system, who knows.
The first few pages are reserved
for hardware flags, et cetera.
Assume page table entries
have eight status bits.
The eight status bits would
then be... Anybody?
Ah, I see we have our first surrender.
Don't worry, Mr. Zuckerberg, brighter men
than you have tried and failed this class.
One valid bit, one modified bit,
one reference bit, five permission bits.
That is correct.
Does everybody see
how he got there?
Mark?
You Mark Zuckerberg?
Yea.
Cameron Winklevoss.
Hi.
Tyler Winklevoss.
Are you guys related?
That's good, funny, never heard that before.
So what can I do for you?
Did I insult your girlfriends?
No... actually... hang on.
- We never asked.
Maybe we should have.
- No.
We have an idea we want to talk to you about.
Got a minute?
You guys look like you guys
spend some time at the gym.
We have to.
Why?
We row crew.
Yeah, I've got a minute.
Great.
So you ever been inside the Porcellian?
No.
We're sorry. We can not take you past the
bike room 'cause you're not a member.
Want a sandwich, or something?
Uh, OK.
Mark, right?
Yea.
Mark, this is Divya Narendra, our partner.
- Hi.
We were really impressed with Facemash.
We checked you out, you also built Course Match.
Don't know no Course Match.
You can go online and see what
courses your friends are taking.
Really smart man.
Mark?
Yeah?
We were talking about Course Match.
It was kind of a no-brainer.
You invented something
in high school too, right?
An app for an MP3 player, that
recognizes your taste in music.
Any body try to buy it?
Microsoft.
How much?
- Didn't sell it, uploaded it for free.
For free?
- Yeah.
Why?
OK, we have something we have been working on for a while,
and we think it's great. It's called the Harvard Connection.
You can create your own page,
interests, bio, friends, pics.
Then people can go online
and see your bio...
Request you -
Yeah, how is that different
from MySpace and Friendster?
HARVARD.EDU
Harvard.edu is the most prestigious
e-mail address in the country.
And the whole site is based
on the idea that girls -
Not to put anything indelicately.
- Girls want to go with guys who go to Harvard.
See, my brother doesn't have
trouble putting things indelicately.
Main difference between what we're talking about and
MySpace or Friendster, or any of those other social networking sites -
- Is exclusivity.
Right?
Right.
Yeah, we'd love you to work with us, Mark.
We need a gifted programmer who is creative.
And we know you've been
taken to the shitters.
Women's groups are still
ready to declare a fatwa.
This could help rehabilitate your image.
Wow - you would do that for me.
We'd like to work with you.
Our first programmer graduated and went to work for Google.
Our second programmer just got
overwhelmed with school work.
We would need you to build the site,
write the code and we'll provide all -
I'm in.
What?
Awesome.
That's what you said?
It was three or four years ago,
I don't know what I said.
When did you come to Eduardo?
I don't understand that question.
Do you remember answering
in the affirmative?
The affirmative?
When I did you come to Eduardo with the idea for Facebook?
It was called TheFacebook then.
This doesn't need to be that difficult.
I'm currently in the middle of two different lawsuits.
Did you answer affirmatively when Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss
and Divya Narendra ask you to build Harvard Connection?
Did you say yes?
I said I'd help.
When did you approach Mr. Saverin
with the idea for TheFacebook?
I wouldn't say I approached him.
Sy?
You can answer the question.
At a party at Alpha Epsilon Pi.
What's that?
- The Jewish fraternity.
It was Caribbean night.
Is there something here that guys are generally attracted to Asian girls?
Because Asian girls generally are attracted to guys like me.
I'm developing an algorithm to define the
connection between Jewish guys and Asian girls.
I don't think it's that complicated - they're hot, they're smart.
They are not Jewish and they can dance.
Hey, Mark's here!
Mark!
I think I've come up with something.
Hang on, I've got to tell you
something you're not going to believe.
- What.
I got punched by the Phoenix.
Are you kidding?
- No, it's the first of a four-step process.
But they slipped the invitation
under my door tonight.
My first punch party tomorrow.
You got punched by the Phoenix.
Yea, it's probably just a diversity thing,
just ride that horse 'til...
What did you want to
talk to me about?
Mark, you said you've
come up with something.
Yeah, I've think I've come up
with something. Come outside.
It's twenty degrees outside.
I can't stare at that loop of Niagara Falls, which
has absolutely nothing to do with the Caribbean.
People came to Facemash in a stampede, right?
It wasn't because they saw pictures of hot girls.
You can go anywhere on the
internet and see pictures of hot girls.
Because they saw pictures of girls that they knew.
People want to go on the Internet and check out their friends, so
why not build a website that offers that: friends, pictures, profiles...
...whatever you can visit just browse around,
maybe someone you just met at a party.
But I'm not talking about a dating site.
I'm talking about taking the
entire social experience of college...
...and putting it online.
I can't feel my legs.
- I know.
I'm totally psyched about
this too, but Eduardo...
It would be exclusive.
You would have to know the people on
the site to get past your own page, like...
...getting punched.
- That's good.
Eduardo, it's like a Final Club,
except we're the president.
I told him I thought it sounded great.
It was a great idea.
There was nothing to hack. People were gonna
provide their own pictures, their own information.
And people had the ability to
invite or not invite their friends to join.
In a world were social
structure was everything...
...that was THE thing.
It was a big project, and he was going to have
to write tens of thousands of lines of code.
So I wondered why he was coming
to me and not his room mates.
Dustin Moskovitz and Chris Hughes,
they were programmers.
We're gonna need a little startup cash
to rent the servers and get it online.
So that was why.
Did he offer terms?
Well split it 70/30.
Seventy for me, thirty for you for putting up the thousand dollars,
and for handling everything on the business end.
You're CFO.
And you said?
I said, let's do it.
OK, did he add anything else?
- Yes.
It probably was a diversity thing.
But so what?
Why you think he said that?
Gretchen, excuse me for interrupting,
but whose discovery is this?
Sy, if you let me continue
with my line of questioning.
They're suggesting I was jealous of Eduardo for getting punched by the Phoenix,
and began a plan to screw him out of a company I hadn't even invented yet.
Were you?
- Gretchen!
Jealous of Eduardo!
- Stop typing, we're off the record.
Ma'am, I know you've done you're homework
and so you know money is not a big part of my life...
...but at the moment I could buy Mount Auburn street,
take the Phoenix club and turn it into my ping-pong room.
I'll let you know how the party is.
We recognize that you're a plaintiff in one suit
involving Facebook, and a witness in another.
Yes, sir.
At any time in the weeks prior
to Mark's telling you his idea...
...did he mention Tyler Winklevoss, Cameron Winklevoss,
Divya Narendra, or Harvard Connection?
Yes. He said they asked him
to work on their site.
But that he looked at what they had
and decided it wasn't worth his time.
He said even his most pathetic friends
knew more about getting people interested...
...in the website than these guys.
These guys, meaning my clients.
Yes.
Yes, he resented, Mark resented that...
...they, your clients that he thought that he
needed to rehabilitate his image after Facemash.
Mark didn't want to rehabilitate
anything. With Facemash...
...he hacked into the Harvard computers,
he thumbed his nose at the ad board.
He got a lot of notoriety. Facemash
did exactly what he wanted it to do.
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg was building
TheFacebook, he was also communicating with the plaintiffs?
Not at the time I wasn't.
It really did not have much to do
with the Winklevoss's dating site.
How would you know,
you weren't even there.
Were you aware that while Mr. Zuckerberg
was building TheFacebook...
...he was leading the plaintiffs to believe
he was building Harvard Connection?
You're offering a conclusion
not found in evidence.
We are about to find it in evidence.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler Winklevoss, November 30, 2003.
I read over all the stuff you sent me RE: HARVARD CONNECTION...
...and it seems like it shouldn't take to long to implement.
So we can talk about it after I get all
the basic functionality up tomorrow night.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Cameron Winklevoss, December 1, 2003.
Sorry I was unreachable tonight.
I just got about three of your missed calls,
I was working on a problem for my Systems class.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler and
Cameron Winklevoss, December 10, 2003.
This week has been pretty busy,
between Harvard, classes and work.
So I think it's probably best
to postpone the meeting.
I'm also really busy tomorrow.
OK, anybody else feel like
there is something up with this guy?
Tell him OK.
But we do have to make sure we
meet up before we go off for a break.
I know, I know.
Yeah, watch out.
Hey, Mark.
I need a dedicated Linux box
running Apache with a MYSQL backend
It's gonna cost a little more.
How much more?
About two hundred more.
Do we need it?
Gotta handle the traffic.
Do it.
I already did.
Hey, guess what.
I made the second cut.
That's good.
You should be proud of that right there,
don't worry if you don't make it any further.
I'll get out of here.
From Mark Zuckerberg to Tyler and Cameron Winklevoss...
… and Divya Nevendra.
Dec 15, 2003.
I have a CS problem set that I am just getting started with
and it should be about 15 hours of coding, so I'll be busy tomorrow night.
I won't really be free to meet
until next Wednesday afternoon.
I have to cancel Wednesday afternoon.
I've basically been in the lab this whole time.
And I also won't be able to do Saturday,
as I have to meet up with my parents.
As the plaque reads, this is John Harvard.
Founder of Harvard University in 1638.
It's also called the statue of three lies.
What are the three lies?
Mr. Dowd.
The three lies.
Shit.
Take your pants off.
I know.
Ah, Mr Saverin.
1 - Harvard was founded in 1636.
Not 1638.
2 - Harvard was not founded by John Harvard.
3 - That is not John Harvard.
Who is it?
Friend of the sculptor Daniel Chester.
Keep your jacket on.
Thirty-nine days after Mr. Zuckerberg's
initial meeting with my clients...
...and he still hadn't completed work
on Harvard Connection.
But on January 11, 2004...
...Mr. Zuckerberg registered the domain name
theFacebook, by Network Solutions.
To the best of your knowledge, had he
even begun work on Harvard Connection?
Not to my knowledge.
No.
Hey Cameron, I'm still a little skeptical that we have
enough functionality in the site to really draw the attention...
...and gain the critical mass necessary
to get a site like this to run.
We'll speak soon?
This is the first time he mentioned any problem.
Yes, it was.
You sent thirty-six e-mails...
...to Mr. Zuckerberg...
...and received sixteen e-mails in return...
...and this is the first time
he indicated he was not happy.
That's correct.
He had forty-two days to study our
system and get out ahead.
Do you see any of your code on Facebook?
- Sy, could you -
Did I use any of your code?
You stole our whole goddamn idea!
Fellas.
-  Match.com for Harvard guys?
- Can I continue with my deposition?
You know you really don't need a
forensics team to get to the bottom of this.
If you guys were the
inventors of Facebook...
...you would have invented Facebook.
I can't wait to stand over your shoulder
and watch you write us a check.
No shit.
Let's continue.
February 4, 2004.
Mark?
There is a girl in your art history class.
Her name is Stephanie Attis,
do you happen to know if she has a boyfriend?
Have you ever seen her with anyone?
And if not, do you happen to know if
she's looking to go out with me one night?
Dustin...
People don't walk around
with a sign on them that says, I'm...
Mark.
We were supposed to meet at nine.
Slept yet?
Have to add something.
What?
Shit, that looks good, really good.
Clean and simple, no Disneyland.
No live nude girls.
Watch.
What are you writing?
Relationship status
Interested in
This is what drives life at college:
Are you having sex, or aren't you...
...is why people take certain
classes and sit where they sit...
...and do what they do, and
add some center, you know...
...that's what TheFacebook will be
about. People are going to log on...
...because after all the cake and watermelon
there is a chance they're actually gonna -
- Gonna get laid?
- Meet a girl.
Yes.
- That is really good.
- And that was it.
- What do you mean?
- It's ready.
- It's ready, right now?
Yeah. Have a seat.
And here is the masthead.
- You made a masthead?
Yeah.
Eduardo Saverin, co-founder and CFO
You have no idea what that's
going to mean to my father.
Sure, I do.
So when is it going live?
Right now.
Get your laptop out.
What, why do we need my laptop?
Because you got e-mails of
everybody at the Phoenix.
I'm not sure if it's going to be
cool with them that I'm...
...gonna spam their -
This is not spam.
No, I know it's not spam.
If we send it to our friends, it's just
gonna bounce around our dorm.
I haven't got in yet.
These guys know people...
...and I need their e-mails.
Sure, good.
Give me the mailing list.
jabberwock12@listserver.harvard.edu
These guys.
They're literary geniuses 'cause of the
world's most obvious Lewis Carroll references.
They're not so bad.
- I'm just saying.
Yeah, you're right.
The site's live.
You know, let's go get
a drink and celebrate.
I'm buying.
Mark?
Mark, are you praying?
Whatever happened to Cole Porter
and Irving Berlin?
It's a Valentine's Day theme,
they're playing love songs.
Good point, 'cause Cole Porter and
Irving Berlin never wrote any love songs.
Honey, you should put your laptop away.
Just having different people
spam me the same link.
Casey...
What is it?
- I don't know...
I'm really hoping it's cats that look like Hitler,
'cause I can never get enough of that.
No, it's not.
Div?
What?
Hey, w-what is wrong?
It's fine.
Hey!
- Not now.
We need twenty minutes.
OK, I just want to let you know
that Zuckerberg stole our website.
Mark Zuckerberg.
He stole our website.
It's been live for more
than thirty-six hours.
Mr. Hotchkiss.
Ty, lawyer's on the phone with dad.
I'm here with my brother Tyler
and my business partner Divya.
"Welcome to TheFacebook.
TheFacebook is an online directory...
"...that connects people through
different social networks..."
"You must have a Harvard.edu
address to register..
That's right, yes sir.
I called earlier. I'm looking
for Mark Zuckerberg
Yes, sir he's actually quoted
a couple of times...
...I can read it to you.
"Everyone is talking a lot about
Universal Facebook within Harvard..."
He says, he meaning Mark.
"I think it's kind of silly that it would take
the university a couple of years to get around to it."
"I can do a classier job than they can.'
"And I did it..."
As of yesterday evening, Zuckerberg said over
650 students had registered to use Thefacebook.com...
He said he anticipated that nine hundred
students would join the site by this morning."
Yes, Divya was just reading that
650 students signed up for it on the first day.
God, if I was a drug dealer, I couldn't
give free drugs to 650 people in a day.
This guy doesn't have three
friends to rub together...
...to make a fourth.
Alright yes, that's what
we'll do Mr. Hotchkiss...
...we'll put it all together and well e-mail it to you.
You won't be able to go
on the website yourself.
Because you don't have a Harvard...
You know, it would just be
easier for us to e-mail it to you.
I'm sure you're right. He is a good guy, and
he's very bright and I'm sure he didn't mean to...
Wow.
What he did.
Thank you very much and dad...
I love you too.
This is a good guy?
We don't know that
he's not a good guy.
We know he stole our idea.
We know lied to our faces...
...for a month and a half.
No, he never lied to our faces.
OK, he never saw our faces, fine.
He lied to our e-mail accounts...
...and he gave himself a
forty-two day head start.
Because he knows what apparently you don't...
...which is that getting
there first, is everything.
I'm a competitive racer, Dave. I don't think you need
to school me on the importance of getting there first.
Thank you.
- Alright.
That was your father's lawyer?
- His in-house counsel.
He is going to look at all this, and if he thinks it's
appropriate, he's going to send a cease and desist letter.
What's that gonna do?
- What, you want to hire an IP lawyer and sue him?
No, I want to hire the Sopranos to beat
the shit out of him with a hammer.
We're not going to have to do that.
- That's right.
We can do that ourselves.
I'm 6'5'', 220, and there's two of me.
Whatever, I'm saying, let's calm down
until we know what we're talking about.
How much more information
are you waiting for?
We met with Mark three times,
we've exchanged fifty-two e-mails...
...we can prove that
he looked at the code.
What is that on the
bottom of the page?
A Mark Zuckerberg production
On the home page?
- On every page.
Shit, I need a second to let
that classiness waft over me.
They wrote Zuckerberg said he hoped the
privacy options would help restore his reputation...
...following student outrage over Facemash.com.
It's exactly what we said to him.
He's giving us the finger in The Crimson.
While we are waiting for dad's lawyer to look this stuff over
we can at least get something going in the paper.
- No.
- So people know that this is in dispute.
We're not starting a knife fight in The Crimson,
and we're not suing anybody.
Why not?
I don't understand, why not?
He's gonna say it's stupid.
Me?
Say it, why not?
Because we're gentlemen of Harvard.
This is Harvard, were you don't plant stories,
and you don't sue people.
You thought he was gonna be the
only one who thought that was stupid?
During the time when you
say you had this idea...
...did you know Tyler and Cameron
came from a family of means?
A family of means?
Did you know their father was wealthy?
I'm not sure why you're asking me that.
It's not important.
You be sure why I'm asking.
Not important to you.
Sy.
Did you know that they came from money?
I had no idea whether they
came from money or not.
In one of your e-mails to Mr. Narendra, you
referenced Howard Winklevoss's consulting firm.
If you say so.
Howard Winklevoss founded a firm
whose assets are in the hundreds of millions.
You also knew Tyler and Cameron were members
of a Harvard final club called The Percillian.
They pointed that out.
Excuse us for inviting you in.
To the bike room.
So it's safe to say you were
aware that my clients had money.
Yes.
Let me tell you why I'm asking, I'm wondering
why, if you needed a thousand dollars...
...for an internet venture you
didn't ask my clients for it.
They had demonstrated an interest
to you in that kind of thing.
I went to my friend for the money because
that's who I wanted to be partners with.
Eduardo was the President of the Harvard Investors
Association, and he was also my best friend.
Your best friend is suing you
for six hundred million dollars.
I didn't know that, tell me more.
Eduardo, what happened after the initial launch?
I'm sorry Sy, would you mind
addressing him as Mr. Saverin?
Gretchen, they're best friends.
- Not anymore.
We already went through this on the... never mind.
Mr. Saverin, what happened after the initial launch?
It exploded.
Everybody on campus was using it. Facebook me.
It was the common expression after two weeks.
And eh, Mark?
And Mark was the biggest thing on campus...
...that included nineteen Nobel laureates
and fifteen Pulitzer Prize winners,...
...two future Olympians,
and a movie star.
Who's the movie star?
Does it matter?
No.
Your friend. Is that Mark Zuckerberg?
Yeah.
He made Facebook?
Yeah. I mean,
it's both of ours, but...
Cool. I am a Chrisy, this is Alice.
Very nice to meet you.
Facebook me if you get home,
maybe we all can go out and grab a drink.
Certainly, can absolutely do that.
She said, Facebook me,
and we can all go for a drink.
Which is stunningly great
for two reasons.
One, she said Facebook me, right?
And the other -
- They want to have drinks later.
Yes, have you ever heard so many different good things
packed into one regular-sized sentence?
Excuse me, Mark?
Yeah.
I am Stewart Singer,
I'm in you're OS class.
Sure.
Awesome job with TheFacebook.
Awesome job.
Thanks.
I'm Bob.
How are you doing?
You know, I could swear
he was looking at you...
...when he said "the next Bill Gates
could be right in this room."
I doubt it.
I showed up late I didn't
even know who the speaker was.
It was Bill Gates.
Shit, that makes sense.
Alright, thanks guys.
You a moron?
- You medically stupid?
You don't recognize Bill Gates when
he's in front of you for an hour?
I get a Glock and kill you.
Time to monetize the thing.
What were their names?
Heard what I just said?
What?
I said it's time to monetize the site.
What does that mean?
It means, it's time for the website
to start generating revenue.
I know the word means,
I'm asking how you want to do it.
Advertising.
No.
Well, we got four thousand members.
Because TheFacebook is cool.
And if we start selling pop-ups for
Mountain Dew it's not gonna be cool -
- Well, I wasn't thinking Mountain Dew,
but at some point...
...I am talking as the business end of the company.
We don't even know what it is yet.
We don't know... what it is.
We don't know what it can be, we don't
know what it will be, we know that it is cool.
That is a priceless asset I'm not giving up.
So when will it be finished?
- It won't be finished.
That's the point, the way
fashion's never finished.
Fashion.
Fashion is never finished.
You're talking about fashion?
Really, you...
I'm talking about the idea of it,
and I'm saying that it's never finished.
OK, but they manage to make
money selling pants.
Mark, what is this?
A what.
This.
It's called a Cease and Desist letter.
What were their names?
Who?
- The girls.
When did you get this?
- About ten days ago, right after we launched the site.
They're saying the Winklevoss twins are saying
that you stole their idea.
I find that to be a little more then mildly annoying.
They find it to be intellectual property theft.
Why didn't you show this to me?
- It was addressed to me.
They're saying we stole TheFacebook
from Divya Narendra and the Winklevoss twins.
I know what it says.
- Did we?
Did we what?
Don't screw around with me now.
Look at me.
The letter says we could face legal action.
No, it says I could face legal action.
This is from a lawyer, Mark,
they must feel they have some grounds.
The lawyer is their father's house counsel.
- Do they have grounds?
The grounds are: our thing is cool, and popular,
and Harvard Connection is lame.
Eduardo, I didn't use any of their code.
I promise I didn't use anything.
Look, a guy who builds a nice chair doesn't owe money
to everyone who's ever built a a chair.
Look, they came to me with
an idea, I had a better one.
Why didn't you show me this letter?
I didn't think it was a big deal.
If there is something wrong...
If there is ever anything wrong...
...you can tell me.
I'm the guy that wants to help.
This is our thing.
Now, is there anything you need to tell me?
No.
What are we doing about this?
I went to 3L Student Legal Services,
and they told me to write them back.
And what did you say?
When we met in January, I expressed my doubts about the site.
Where it stood with graphics, how much
programming was left that I had not anticipated.
Lack of hardware, we had to deal with a site that lacked
promotion, then go on to successfully launch the website.
This was the first time to you raised
any of those concerns, right?
I'd raised concerns before.
Bullshit.
Not to us.
I'm talking about the meeting in
January to which this letter is referring.
Yeah.
Let me rephrase this.
You sent my client sixteen emails.
The first fifteen, you didn't raise any concerns.
Is that a question?
In the sixteenth e-mail you raised concerns
about the site's functionality.
Were you leading them on for six weeks?
- No.
Then why didn't you raise any
of these concerns before?
It's raining.
I'm sorry.
It just started raining.
Mr. Zuckerberg, do I have your full attention?
No.
Do you think I deserve it?
What?
Do you think I deserve your full attention?
I had to swear an oath before I began this deposition
and I don't want to perjure myself...
...so I have a legal obligation to say no.
OK, no.
You don't think I deserve your attention.
I think if your clients want to sit on my shoulders...
...and call themselves tall, they have a right to give it a try, but
there is no requirement that I enjoy sitting here, listening to people lie.
You have part of my attention, you have the minimum amount.
The rest of my attention is back at the offices of Facebook...
...where my colleagues and I are doing things that no one in this room,
including and especially your clients...
...are intellectually or creatively capable of doing.
Did I adequately answer your condescending question?
I have 12:45, why don't we say that's lunch.
Back at 2:30.
So, what are their names.
Their names were Christie and Alice.
And they want to have drinks, tonight.
I don't care.
Hey man, sorry.
A couple of girls are freshing up in there.
Sweet.
We have groupies.
I'll be right back.
Mark, where you going?
Erica?
Hi.
I saw you from over there,
I didn't know you came to this cupboard.
First time.
- Mine too, can I talk to you alone for a second?
I think I'm good right here
- I just...
I'd love to talk to you alone,
If we could go some place.
Right here is fine.
I don't know if you heard about this new website I launched?
- No.
TheFacebook?
- You called me a bitch on the Internet, Mark.
That's why I wanted to talk to you -
On the Internet -
That is why I came over -
Comparing women to farm animals?
I didn't end up doing that.
Didn't stop you from writing it.
As if every thought that tumbles
through your head is so clever...
...it would be a crime for it
not to be shared.
The Internet is not written in pencil, Mark...
...it's written in ink. And you published
that Erica Albright was a bitch...
...right before you made an ignorant
crack about my family's name...
...my bra size, then rated
women based on their hotness.
Erica, is there a problem?
No, there's no problem.
You write your snide bullshit from a dark room,
because that's what the angry do nowadays,
I was nice to you,
don't torture me for it.
If we could just go somewhere for a minute.
- I don't want to be rude to my friends.
OK.
- OK.
Good luck with your... video game.
Hey, that was great, that was the
right thing to do. You apologized, right?
We have to expand.
You want more?
Is he mad about something?
OK, we are expanding to
Yale and Columbia.
Dustin, I want you to show the coding work with me.
Chris, you are in charge of publicity and outreach...
...and you can start by getting us
a story in the BU newspaper...
...it's The Bridge.
They hate doing stories about Harvard.
Somebody at the newspaper will be a
computer science major, tell him.
Mark Zuckerberg will do
ten hours of free programming.
Why do you want a story
in the BU newspaper?
Because I do.
Now here's the arrangement:
Eduardo is CFO and owns
thirty percent of the company.
Dustin is a vice-president and head of programming,
and his five percent of the company will come from my end.
Chris is director of publicity, and his compensation
will depend on the amount of work he ends up doing.
Any questions?
Who are the girls?
Sorry, they are Christie and Alice.
Hi.
Hello.
Is there anything we can do?
No.
Nothing.
Yale and Columbia.
- And Stanford.
What?
- Stanford.
It is time for them to see this in Palo Alto.
You don't want any lunch?
No.
You're welcome to some salad.
No, thank you.
This must be hard.
Who are you?
I'm Marylin Delpy, I introduced myself
I mean what do you do?
I am a second year associate at the firm
My boss wanted me to sit in on the deposition case.
What are you doing?
Checking to see how it's going in Bosnia
Bosnia.
They have no roads but they have Facebook.
You must really hate the Winklevoss's?
I don't hate anybody.
The Winklevosses are suing me for intellectual property theft
They're suing me because for
the first time in their lives...
...things didn't work out the way
they were supposed to for them.
He is expanding.
What?
Yale, Columbia and Stanford.
It's gonna be in The Crimson tomorrow.
Really?
Yeah.
Well, it looked like the cease and desist order
really scared the shit out of him, huh.
- I want to hire a lawyer to file for injunctive releasing it, the site taken down now.
Every minute the site is up
Harvard Connection becomes less valuable.
I want an injunction, I want damages,
I want punitive relief.
I want him dead.
Yeah, I want those things too.
Then why aren't we doing anything about it?
Because we are gentlemen of Harvard?
- Because you're not thinking about how it's gonna look.
How's it gonna look?
Like my brother and I in skeleton costumes
chasing the karate kid around a high school gym.
Cam.
He has violated Massachusetts State law.
When he goes to Connecticut, New York
and California he will have violated federal law.
By the way, he's in violation of Harvard law.
There's no such thing as Harvard law.
Wait. Yeah...
There is.
Harvard student hand book.
Every freshman is issued one of these.
Somewhere in this book it says
you can't steal from another student.
This is what we need.
You can't get a meeting with Larry Summers.
My brother and I we pay tuition at this school.
We carry a 3.9 GPA.
We won trophies for this school.
And well be rowing in
the Olympics for this school.
I want a meeting with the
goddamn president of this school.
Why Stanford?
Why do you think?
Sorry, I'm late for bio-chem.
OK.
You don't know my name, do you?
Is it Stanford?
I should just kick your ass.
How do you go to a party?
Amelia Ritter,
but you prefer Amy.
You're from Olinda.
Your father's in commercial real estate
and your mother's ten years sober.
What's my major?
Trombone.
Really.
I remember something about a trombone.
Tu as fait l'amour à la jolie fille.
French, your major is French.
And yours?
Mine?
I don't have one.
You haven't declared?
I don't go to school.
- You're kidding.
No.
Where did you go to school?
William Taft Elementary,
for a little while.
Seriously...
...you're not like fifteen years
old or anything, are you?
You're not like fifteen, are you?
No.
So what do you do?
I am an entrepreneur.
You're unemployed.
I wouldn't say that.
What would you say?
That I'm an entrepreneur.
- Well, then what was your latest preneur?
Well, I founded an Internet company that let
folks download and share music for free.
Kind of like Napster?
Exactly like Napster.
What do you mean?
I founded Napster.
Sean Parker founded Napster.
Nice to meet you.
You're Sean Parker?
Uh huh, you see the shoes
on the other...
- Foot?
...table, which just turned.
I just slept with Sean Parker?
You just slept on Sean Parker.
You're a zillionaire.
Not technically.
What are you?
Broke.
There's not a lot of money in free music, even less when
you're being sued by anyone who's ever been to the Grammies.
This is blowing my mind.
I appreciate that.
I gotta hop in the shower
and get ready for class.
Bio-chem, even though you're
a French major whose name is Amy.
- You passed.
I'm a hard worker.
There's juice. Anything else
you can find, help yourself.
Mind if I check my e-mail?
Yeah, go ahead.
Amy.
Can you come out here?
Just a second.
There a snake in here, Amy.
What?
Where?
OK there is no snake but I need to ask you something.
Are you kidding me, I could have been killed.
How?
By running too fast,
and getting twisted in the curtain.
What do you need to ask me?
I went to check my e-mail
and there's a website open on your computer.
Yeah after you passed out last night
I went on TheFacebook for a little bit.
What's that?
TheFacebook?
Stanford had it for like two weeks now.
It's really awesome, except it's
freakishly addictive.
Seriously, I'm on the thing like five times a day.
Mind if I send myself an e-mail?
Yeah, is everything okay?
Everything's great.
I just need to find you, Mark Zuckerberg.
Ever been in this building before?
This building's a hundred years older then the country it's in.
So do be careful.
We're sitting in chairs.
Yes.
Very good.
You can go in now.
Catherine, I've got students now.
Students.
Undergrads.
Don't know, from the looks of it
they want to sell me a Brooks Brothers franchise.
Good morning.
Good morning, sir
I'm Cameron Winklevoss, this is my brother Tyler.
And you're here because?
Either of you can answer.
- I'm sorry sir, I thought you were reading the letter.
Read the letter.
Well, we came up with an idea for a website called Harvard Connection.
We've since changed the name to ConnectU...
...and Mark Zuckerberg stole that idea and -
I understand.
I'm asking what you want me to do about it?
Well, sir.
In the Harvard student handbook, which is distributed to each freshman...
...under the heading standards of conduct in the Harvard community...
...it says the college expects all the students to be honest...
...and forthcoming in their dealings with members in the community.
Students are required to respect public and private ownership...
...and instances of theft, misappropriation.
- Anne?
Yes, sir?
Punch me in the face, go ahead.
Or...
...unauthorized use will result in...
...disciplinary action...
...including required withdrawal from the college.
You memorized that instead of doing what?
What my brother and I came...
...here to ask you respectfully.
Sir, it's against university rules to steal from other students,
plain and simple.
You've spoken to your house master.
Yes, sir.
And the house master made a recommendation to the Ad board
but the Ad board won't hear us.
Have you tried dealing with the other student directly?
Mr. Zuckerberg hasn't been responding to any of our e-mails
and phone calls for the last two weeks.
He doesn't answer when we
knock on his door at Kirkland.
And the closest I've come to dealing with him face to face...
...was when I saw him on the quad
and chased him through Harvard Square.
- Chased him?
I, I, I saw him and I know he saw me, I went after him.
and he disappeared
I don't see this as a university issue.
Of course this is a university issue.
There's a code of ethics and an honor
code and he violated them both.
You enter into a code of ethics with the university,
not with each other.
I'm sorry president Summers,
what you just said makes no sense to me at all.
I'm devastated by that.
What my brother means is...
...Mark Zuckerberg walked into our dorm room
and stole our computer.
That would be a university issue.
I don't know this office doesn't handle petty larceny.
This isn't petty larceny.
This idea is potentially worth millions of dollars.
Millions!
Yes.
You might just be letting your
imaginations run away with you.
Sir...
I honestly don't think you're in
any position to make that call.
I was the US Treasury secretary.
I'm in some position to make that call.
Letting our imagination run away with us...
...is exactly what we were told
to do in your freshman address.
Well, then I would suggest that you let your imaginations...
...run away with you on a new project.
You would?
Everyone at Harvard's inventing something.
Harvard undergraduates believe that
inventing a job is better than finding a job.
So I suggest again that the two of
you come up with a new, new project.
I'm sorry, sir, but that's not the point.
Please...
...come right at the point.
You don't have to be a intellectual property expert
to understand the difference between right and wrong.
You're saying that I don't...
Of course I am not saying that, sir.
I'm saying that...
Really?
Sir.
Ann.
How did I get this appointment?
Colleagues of their father.
Let me tell you something, Mr. Winklevoss,
Mr Winklevoss...
Since you're on the subject of right and wrong.
This action, this meeting...
The two of you being here, is wrong.
It's not worthy of Harvard.
It's not what Harvard saw in you.
You don't get special treatment.
We never asked.
Just start another project.
Like were making a diorama for a science fair.
If you have a problem with that, Mr Winklevoss...
We never asked for special treatment.
The court's always at your disposal.
Is there anything else I can do for you?
Ty.
Thank you very much for your time, sir.
Oops.
I broke this 335 year old door knob.
Eduardo, spring break you and
Mr Zuckerberg took a trip to New York.
Yes.
What was the purpose of the trip?
Well, as CFO...
...I had set up some
meetings with potential advertisers...
Who paid for the trips?
It was paid for out of the thousand
dollar account I set up a few months earlier.
At this point your thousand dollars was the only
money that had been put into the company?
Yes.
How did you feel the meetings went?
They went terribly.
Why?
Mark was asleep.
I was not asleep.
Can I rephrase my answer?
I wish he'd been asleep.
So we're at 29 schools now
with over 75 000 members.
People who go on TheFacebook tend to stay on longer
then almost any other website.
Now here's the most impressive statistic:
Ninety-one percent of the people who try it
once, come back. Now, if you'll allow me...
Excuse me one second. What sound
is he making, is that like a tsk?
It wasn't a tsk...
...it was...
...like a gobble stop.
Almost a gag reflex.
Just what is this?
There was one more meeting
scheduled for the New York trip
Yes.
It was a dinner.
It was set up through
my girlfriend at the time.
Would you say that Mark
was excited about this meeting?
Yes.
Very.
They're not gonna card us.
Look around.
It will be embarrassing.
Tell him they're not gonna card us.
They're not gonna card us.
Mark.
Are you gonna talk about ads again
Unless you're the BALLET THEATER of HARTFORD,
the purpose of a business is to make a profit.
It isn't a business yet.
That's tough...
That's tough for me, cause my job...
Never mind.
He's twenty-five minutes late.
He founded Napster when he was nineteen.
He can be late.
He's not a God.
What is he?
He's twenty-five minutes late.
I think you're just jealous.
I honestly wasn't jealous.
I was nervous.
Why?
I didn't know him at all.
But I had done a search
and asked around and he...
...he struck me as a kind of a...
...a wild card.
Why?
He crashed out of two pretty big Internet companies in a
spectacular fashion, he's got a reputation with drugs.
He also founded the companies.
We don't need him.
He's here.
No, no, take your time.
And he does own a watch.
Stop it.
I'm Sean Parker.
How do you do?
You must be Eduardo.
And Christy, and Mark.
Nice to meet you.
You guys don't have anything
in front of you.
No.
Tori.
Hey, baby boy.
Could you bring out some things,
the lacquered pork with that ginger comfit.
Tuna tartar, and the lobster claws,
that'll get us started.
Christie,
...what do you like to drink?
An appletini.
Great.
Four of those.
From that point on,
it was a Sean-a-thon.
The question was what did you talk about.
He took us through his
episode with Napster.
I didn't want to spend my twenties
as a professional defender.
Who knew the music industry
doesn't have a sense of humor?
They tried to sell the company to pay the 35 million they said
we owed in royalties, but I guess to them that was a little like...
...selling a stolen car to pay for the stolen gas.
So we said screw it...
...and declared bankruptcy.
You made a name for yourself.
And you are dry.
Tori!
And then he went on to
his second business venture...
which was an online Rolodex
that he got thrown out of by his Case Equity.
And I wanted to do it nice this time. I put on a tie and shined my
shoes, but nobody wants to take orders from a kid.
So let me tell you what happens to a
twenty-year old on the top of a hot dot.com.
I'm not a psychiatrist, but...
- We got that on the record.
You're not a psychiatrist, but what...?
A psychiatrist would say that he was paranoid.
They'll hire private detectives
who'll follow you day and night.
You're a target for high-priced escorts.
I can't prove it, but I know they tapped my phones.
Whatever it is that's gonna trip you up,
you've done already.
Private behavior is a relic of a time gone by,
...and if somehow, someway, you've managed
to live your life like the Dalai Lama but...
...they'll make shit up because...
...they don't want you, they want your idea...
...and they want you to say thank you while you...
...excuse me,
...wipe your chin and walk away.
That's what happened to you?
And delusional.
Yes.
What?
There'll be payback at Case. It brought down the
record companies with Napster and...
...Case will suffer for their sins too.
Sorry, you didn't bring
down the record companies.
They won.
In court.
Yeah.
Do you want to buy a
Tower Records, Eduardo?
He told story after story about...
...life in SILICON VALLEY, parties at STANFORD...
...down in LA, friends who'd become millionaires..
...but mostly how Mark had to,
he had to come to California.
And then he cut around to TheFacebook.
So tell me about your progress.
Well, were in twenty-nine schools now.
We got over 75 000 members.
Tell me about the strategy you're using.
OK.
For instance we wanted Baylor in Texas,
but Baylor already had a social network on campus so...
...instead of going right after them, we made
a list of every school within a hundred miles.
Put TheFacebook on those campuses first.
Pretty soon all the Baylor kids were
seeing their friends on our site and we were in.
It's called the little bighorn, that's smart, Mark.
Thanks, that was mine.
- Easy.
Hey, you know what?
Settle an argument for us.
I say It's time to start making
money from TheFacebook.
But Mark doesn't want advertising.
Who's right?
Well, neither of you yet.
TheFacebook is cool, that's
what it's got going for it.
You don't want to ruin it with ads,
because ads aren't cool.
Exactly.
It's like you're throwing
the greatest party on campus...
...and someone's saying
it's gotta be over by 11.
You don't even know what the thing is yet.
How big it can get, how far it can go.
This is no time to take your chips down.
A million dollars isn't cool, you know what's cool.
You?
A billion dollars.
That shut everybody up.
And that's were you're headed.
A billion dollar evaluation.
Unless you take bad advice, in which case you may as
well have come up with a chain of very successful yogurt shops.
When you go fishing you
can catch a lot of fish.
Or you can catch a big fish.
You ever walk into a guy's den and see
a picture of him standing next to fourteen trout.
No, he's holding a three thousand pound marlin.
Yep.
That's a good analogy.
OK, we all know that marlins don't
really weigh 3 000 pounds, right?
Have you seen the big ones up close?
No I haven't. But looking at the guy holding
a marlin the size of a Range Rover.
Tat would be a really big fish
and a very strong guy.
You think you might be getting
away from the point.
I don't have a dog in this fight,
I just a fan and came to say hi.
He owned Mark after that dinner.
He picked up the check, he told
Mark that they'd talk together soon...
..and he was gone, but not before he made
his biggest contribution to the company.
Drop the The, just Facebook. It's cleaner.
That's gotta be some kind of
landspeed record for talking
You want to end the party at 11.
I'm trying to pay for the party
There won't be a party...
...unless it's cool.
What do you think?
Yeah sure, lets drop the The.
I meant catching the marlin
instead of the fourteen trout
Doesn't that sound good?
If you're a trout.
I'm going to enter this into the record,
incorporation papers for Facebook...
...an LLC registered in Florida.
Why Florida?
It's where my family lives.
And ask the respondents to stipulate that the
articles of incorporation state the ownership as follows:
65% for Mark Zuckerberg, 30% for Eduardo Saverin,
and 5% for Dustin Moskovitz.
We stipulate -
...and that was April 13, 2004.
You can mark it.
Do you have anything here
Yes, thank you.
Mr Saverin, have you ever done anything that might
be considered legitimate grounds for termination?
No.
You've never did anything to embarrass
the company, or even seriously jeopardize it?
No.
No?
No!
You were accused of animal cruelty.
You weren't?
This is not happening.
I have here an article from The Crimson.
Jesus Christ.
I can't have this, Eduardo.
Oh, come on man, this is bullshit.
This is another club playing a prank.
I'd gotten into the Phoenix.
I'd been accepted, and as part of
my initiation I had to, for one week...
...carry with me at all times,
and take care of, a chicken.
They identify you as one of the founders
of Facebook, Jr Eduardo Saverin.
I'm not the expert, but being connected to
torturing animals is probably bad for business.
I did not torture the chicken.
I don't torture chickens
Are you crazy?
No, now settle down, please.
I have here an article from The Crimson...
This is scathing.
I was having dinner at the Kirkland dining hall, with Mark
and I had the chicken with me, cause I had to have the chicken with me at all times.
This is college.
Somebody is going to have to answer for this.
The dining hall was serving chicken for dinner, so I had to feed my chicken,
so what I took little pieces of chicken, and I gave it to the chicken.
Someone must have seen cause the next thing
I knew, I was accused of forced cannibalism.
I didn't know...
...you couldn't do that.
I dealt with various animal rights groups.
I dealt with the associate dean at the college.
This was all resolved.
Someone from the Porc or the Fly must
have reported it, for all I know it was the Winklevosses.
Alright, let's just forget about it.
This is absurd.
I'm being accused of animal cruelty.
Next I'll be accused of necrophilia.
It is better to be accused of necrophilia.
I'm gonna have to explain this to my father,
I'm gonna have to explain this to everybody.
What is happening on that?
I have my final coming up for "Post War and Contemporary Art"
and I haven't been to class.
I'm supposed to write about those four paintings.
It's a Facebook page.
Yeah.
I put it under an ALIAS
I posted the paintings and asked people to comment.
Every once in a while I hop on and stir the pot to get a good debate going
Mr Zuckerberg was cheating on his final exam?
I'd rather not answer that question.
And why not?
Cause I'm not suing him for cheating on his final exam.
That's not what friends do.
Well, you just told us he was cheating.
Oops.
You told your lawyer I was torturing animals.
No he didn't tell us about it at all,
our litigators are capable of finding a Crimson article.
In fact, when we raised the subject, he defended you.
Oops.
993, we are so close.
Oh yeah, that reminds me...
We're gonna need more money, Eduardo.
I agree, more servers, more help.
I'm interviewing two interns to come to Palo Alto,
and we are going to have to pay them something
Sorry, what?
I already found a house for rent on a street two blocks from
the Stanford campus. It's perfect and it's got a pool.
When did you decide to go to California for the summer?
You mean, when did I actually decide?
Somewhere in the middle of the Sean Parker Variety Hour?
He was right, California is the place we've gotta be.
What, you're Jed Clampett?
I guess you guys have the Beverly Hillbillies in Brazil?
What is your problem with Sean?
He doesn't bring anything to the table.
Doesn't have money, Dustin's a better programmer.
He's got connections.
Got connections to VC's.
We need advertisers. I have connections with VC's.
They're real players, and as someone who's just
really embarrassed the company in a bad way -
It was the Winklevosses, Mark.
Hang on.
Hit refresh.
150. 000
150. 000 members
Eduardo.
Congratulations.
You don't think it was strange that
he was followed by private detectives.
Who came up with nothing.
Enough to get him out of the company.
The drugs, the girls.
We don't know if any of that's true.
Read about it.
And I can read about you torturing birds,
since when does reading about something.
Do fish eat other fish? The marlins and the trout?
What's he talking about?
I'm interviewing interns at 10 tomorrow night in the CS lab.
Get on board with this man, you know.
I don't really know what else to say.
What's going on?
They have 10 minutes to get root access to a python webserver,
expose its SSL encryption, then intercept all traffic over its secure port.
They're hacking.
All behind a PIX Firewall Emulator,
but here's the beauty.
You know I didn't understand
anything you just said, right?
I do know that.
So what's the beauty?
Every tenth line of code written, they have to take a shot.
And hacking is supposed to be stealth, so anytime the server
detects an intrusion, the candidate responsible has to take a shot.
I also have a program running that has a pop-up window
appear simultaneously on all five computers.
The last candidate to hit
the window has to take a shot.
Plus every three minutes,
they all have to take a shot.
Can I ask what part of the interns job
will they need to be able to do drunk?
You're right. A more relevant test might be seeing
if they can keep a chicken alive for a week.
That was mean.
Here.
What is this?
I opened a new account and put $18 000 in it.
Will that get you through the summer?
Welcome to Facebook
$18 000?
Yes.
In addition to the $1 000 you already put up.
A total of $19,000, then
Yes.
Just checking your math on that.
I got the same thing.
May I continue?
After expressing misgivings about Mr Zuckerberg
taking the company and moving it to California...
...for the summer, why did you put
$18,000 in an account for his use?
I figured we were partners.
I wanted to be a team player.
I figured Mark, Dustin and the new interns could work on
the site, while I was generating advertiser interest in New York.
But mostly I figured...
...how much could possibly
go wrong in three months?
OK, ready?
Sounds like an eight.
That was like a two.
He's better than that.
I'm OK.
Sure?
That's the doorbell.
I didn't know we had a doorbell
Hey Andrew, get the door.
No, he's wired in.
That's gonna cut into the security deposit.
Mark.
You live here?
Yeah.
We live right across the street, we saw the chimney.
Is anybody hurt?
You look...
We live across the street.
I'm Sharon.
This is my Sharon, she lives across the street...
...I was helping her move out, we saw the chimney.
Yeah, we had a little accident by the pool.
You came to California.
You made the right choice.
I'm so sorry.
No problem.
I didn't know you were gonna
No wait...
This house and this team are great.
It's exactly what it should be.
I'm Sean Parker.
Oh, he's wired in.
That's what I'm talkin' about.
Where's Eduardo?
He got a internship in New York.
Eduardo didn't come out.
I was crashing there for a little bit while taking care of some things, but
she's done for the summer, so she's back at her parents' place.
The homeless rockstar Palo Alto.
- Alright.
What's your plan for the summer?
I'm sorry, I was looking
at the architecture.
I asked what your plans for the -
A hundred schools by
the end of the summer.
Your date looks so familiar to me.
She looks familiar to a lot of people.
What do you mean?
A Stanford MBA named Roy Raymond
wants to buy his wife some lingerie...
...but he's too embarrassed to shop for
it in a department store.
Comes up with an idea for a high end
place that doesn't make you feel like a pervert.
He gets a $40 000 dollar bank loan,
borrows another $40 000 from his in-laws...
...opens a store and calls it Victoria's Secret.
Makes half a million dollars in the first year.
Starts a catalog, opens three more stores and after five years,
he sells the company to Leslie Wester unlimited for four million dollars.
Happy ending, right?
Except, two years later the company is worth $500,000,000
and Roy Raymond jumps off the Golden Gate Bridge.
Was that a parable?
My date's a Victoria Secret model,
that's why she looks familiar to you.
Don't be impressed by all this,
I read your blog.
You know why I started Napster?
The girl loved in High School was with
the co-captain of the varsity Lacrosse team.
And I wanted to take her from him.
So I decided to come up with the next big thing.
I didn't know that.
Napster wasn't a failure. I changed the
music industry for better and for always.
It may not have been good business
but it pissed a lot of people off.
And isn't that what your Facemash was about?
They're sacred of me pal,
and they're gonna be scared of you.
What the VC's want to say, good idea kid,
grown-ups are gonna take it from here.
But not this time, this is our time.
This time you gonna hand them a
business card that says I'm CEO, bitch
That's what I want for you.
So were the hell is Eduardo?
He's in New York.
Sucking up to ad execs.
He's got an internship.
The company's here, a
billion dollar company's here.
Do you live and breathe Facebook?
I know you do.
Eduardo wants to be a business man
and for all I know he'll be a good one, but...
...he shouldn't be in New York
kissing Madison Avenue's ass.
This is a once in a generation holy shit idea...
...and the water under the
Golden Gate is freezing cold.
Look at my face and tell me
I don't know what I'm talking about.
You ever think about that girl?
What girl?
T-the girl from high school, the Lacrosse team.
No.
You need to top up.
A hundred schools by the end of the summer?
Tell you what,a gesture of faith.
You get into hundred schools, I'll put you on two continents.
If you don't have a place to crash
I think you should definitely come live with us.
Let's line up some shots.
Excuse me.
You can take this away and bring back the 1942?
Absolutely, Mr. Parker.
Tyler.
Oh, and this is my brother Cameron.
His Royal Highness Prince Albert,
Your highness this is Taylor and Cameron Winklevoss.
Of course brilliant race.
I've never seen a race that close.
My grandfather Jack Kelly was one of the premier rowers.
I've been coming to Henley for thirty years,
and I've never seen a race that close.
Have you seen a race that close?
No, Your Highness. A mile and a half races are
more commonly won by a boat-length or two.
Yes, that's absolutely right.
Brutally close.
May I introduce my team mates?
I'm sorry, you have to excuse us.
We flew all the way out here to see that?
Wouldn't miss it, brother.
How's the royalty?
Ah, he just wanted to tell me
a couple of times how close the race was.
Brutally, brutally excruciating.
The guy's is the prince of a country the size of a Kentucky pie, it's fine.
Mr. Winklevoss.
- That was a tough beat.
I'm sorry dad, you and Mom
had to fly all the way to see this.
No son, don't apologize to me for loosing a race like that.
I'd never apologize to anyone
for losing a race like that.
Mr Kenright.
Dad, this is Mr Kenright, head of the host family this week.
Pleasure to meet you, Pleasure to meet you
I had a chat with my daughter.
She told me that she and her friends
already talking about the race...
...which they've just seen by their computers.
A new website called Facebook.
Do you have this in America?
I'm gonna find your mother.
Must be something wrong?
Your daughter doesn't go to school in the States.
No, no. Cambridge, majoring in French literature.
Though I wasn't aware there was such a thing.
They have Facebook at Cambridge?
And apparently Oxford, and the London School of Economics.
for the present
Good race boys, the bitter or the better, eh?
You watch my stuff.
This is online, I want to see it.
What are you doing?
Knock it off.
I don't mind that we lost to
the Dutch by less then a second...
...that was a good race...
...and that was a fair race,
and they'll see us again.
What I mind and what
you should mind...
...is showing up on Monday for a race
that was run on Sunday.
We tried talking to him ourselves,
we tried writing a letter, we'd tried the Ad board...
...and we tried talking to
the president of the university.
Now I am asking you
for the last time...
...let's take the considerable resources at
our disposal and sue him in federal court.
Come on.
I need a real drink.
Screw it.
Lets gut the friggin' nerd.
Talkin' about.
Check it out, I saw him today.
Manningham, Mitchell Manningham
Are you guys using spikes or ghostesses?
We don't know, we're just
shooting at each other
Use sweet kamikazes.
And that is?
I saw him getting into his Turbo Carrera
and he saw me too.
I know he did.
Don't, don't sweat it.
Does anybody hear that banging?
You don't hear anything,
you're writing code.
Somebody's at the door.
I'm gonna call you back.
What's up?
Mark was supposed to pick me up at the airport
an hour ago. I've been calling his cell.
He was on a 36 hour coding tear,
so he took a nap for a few hours.
What happened here?
Not happened, happening.
Next big thing.
Eduardo.
Hey man, back to work.
Sorry about it, It's the more wasted I get..
I meant the more...
We understand.
How old are they, Sean?
It's not polite to ask.
Sean, how old are they?
You think you know me, right?
I've read enough.
You know how much I've read about you?
Eduardo.
I waited an hour for you at the airport.
What time is it?
Midnight, it's 3 A.M. in New York
where I just came from.
You got to see some of the new stuff we got.
Dustin, show him the wall,
I'm just calling it the wall.
Forget about the wall,
tell him about the meeting I got set up.
You know Peter Thiel?
Nope.
No reason you should. He just runs a two billion
dollar hedge fund called Clarium Capital.
Why is he setting up meetings for you?
Thiel may want to make an angel investment
I don't care if he's an actual angel,
why is he setting up business meetings?
You've had a long flight.
No I had a long wait on the tarmac at JFK, then a long
wait at the passenger loading and unloading zone at SFO.
And in between there was a long flight.
I'm the business end of this company.
And he is a house guest
living here rent-free...
...on a very generous grant
from the Eduardo Saverin Foundation.
I heard about your big ticket Big Daddy Big Buys, Gary's Tuxedos -
Hey, man.
Harvard Bartending Course, you're just a small step away
from bagging Snookies Cookies. Can feel it.
Can I talk to you alone for a minute?
Sure.
Uh, bong hit.
I'm so high.
How's it going? How's the internship,
how's Christy?
How's the internship?
Mark, Jesus, I quit the internship, we talked about this
on the phone. I quit on my first day.
I do remember you saying that.
So how's Christy?
Christy's crazy.
Is that fun?
No.
Psychotic, she's insanely jealous,
she's irrational.
And I'm frightened of her.
Still it's nice you have a girlfriend.
I do not want that guy...
...representing himself as
part of this company.
You've got move out here Eduardo,
this is where it's all happening.
Did you here what I just said?
The connections, the energy.
Mark, Mark.
I'm afraid if you don't come out here,
you're going to be left behind.
I want, I want, I need you,
please don't tell me -
What did you just say?
It's moving faster then any of us
ever imagined it would.
It's moving fast and Sean thinks that we should -
Sean's not part of this company.
We have over three hundred thousand members,
we're in hundred sixty schools.
I'm aware.
Including five in Europe.
I'm aware of that - MARK.
MARK, I'm the CFO.
We need more programmers, and we need more
money and he set up the Thiel meeting.
He set up meetings all over town.
Set up other meetings.
Yes.
Without me knowing anything about it.
You're in New York.
I'm in in New York riding subways fourteen
hours a day, trying to find advertisers.
Yeah, and how is
it going it go so far?
What did you mean,
get left behind?
I'd like to freeze this bank account
and cancel all existing checks and lines of credit.
May I see some ID, please.
Yeah, sure.
Sean, he'll be right with you.
- No problem.
You know this is where they
filmed Towering Inferno?
That's comforting.
Hey guys, come on back.
Did she offer you some water?
Oh yeah, we're cool.
You must be Mark.
We took a look at everything
and congratulations.
We're gonna start you off with a
$500,000 investment.
Maurice is going to talk to you about
some corporate restructuring.
We'll file as a corporation in Delaware.
We've come up with a stark structure
that allows for new investors.
Now let me ask you something
Who's Eduardo Saverin?
When did you get back?
You scared me, I need you to knock.
I got back this afternoon.
And when were you gonna call me?
Jesus. it was kind of a bad trip.
And I was tired.
Or answer 1 of my 47 texts,
did you know I sent 47 texts?
I did and I thought that
was incredibly normal behavior
Are you mocking me?
I bought you a present.
Why does your status say single
on your Facebook page?
What?
Why does your relationship status say
single on your Facebook page?
I was single when I set up the page.
And you never bothered to change it?
What?
I don't know how.
Do I look stupid to you?
No, calm down.
You're asking me to believe that the CFO of Facebook
doesn't know how to change his relationship status on Facebook?
A little embarrassing...
...so you should take it as a sign of
trust that I would tell you that.
Go to hell.
Take it easy.
You didn't change it, so you could
screw those little Silicon Valley sluts -
That's not even remotely true and
I can promise you that the Silicon Valley...
...sluts don't care what any body's
relationship status is on Facebook.
Please open your present.
Your phone does work.
It's Mark.
Uh, open you present.
It's a scarf.
Have you ever seen me wear a scarf?
This'll be your first.
Yeah.
You froze our accounts.
I did.
You froze the accounts.
I had to get your attention, Mark.
Do you realize you jeopardize the entire company?
Do you realize your actions can permanently destroy...
...everything I've been working on?
WE have been working on.
Without money the site can't function.
Let me tell you the difference
between Facebook and everybody else.
We don't crash ever.
If the servers are down for even a day
our reputation is irreversibly destroyed.
Look -
Napster and Friendster have proven that. Even a few people
leaving would reverberate through the entire user base.
The users are interconnected, that's the whole point.
College kids are online because their friends are online, and
if one domino goes, the other domino goes, don't you get that?
I am not going back to the Caribbean night at A.E.Pi.
Holy shit.
What is wrong with you?
Did you like being nobody. Did you like
being a joke? You want to go back to that?
Hang on, hang on.
That was the act of a child, not a businessman.
Certainly not the act of a friend.
You know how embarrassed I was to cash
a check today? I am not going back to that life.
Maybe you were frustrated.
Yeah.
Maybe you were angry.
I was.
But I am willing to let bygones be bygones,
because Eduardo, I've got some good news,
I'm sorry, I was angry
and maybe it was childish.
But I had to get your attention.
I said I've got some good news
What is it?
Peter Thiel just made an angel
investment of half a million dollars.
Half a million dollars.
And he's setting us up in an office.
They want to re-incorporate the company.
They want to meet you, they need
your signature on some documents.
So you need to get your ass on the first
flight back to San Francisco. I need my CFO.
I'm on my way.
Eduardo.
- Yeah.
We did it.
Eduardo.
You're going back there already?
Yes.
Also I'm breaking up with you.
Four documents. The first two are
common stock agreement purchases...
...allowing you to buy stock in the newly re-incorporated
Facebook, as opposed to the old shares...
...which are now worthless.
The third is an exchange agreement allowing
you to exchange the old shares for new shares.
And finally the voter holding agreement.
How many shares of stock will I own?
1,328,334
- Jesus Christ.
That represents 34.4% ownership share.
Why the increase from
the original thirty percent?
Because you may dilute
to award shares to new investors.
I love working with business majors.
- Intelligent.
You should know that Mark has already taken
his percentage from sixty down to fifty-one.
Well, Mark doesn't care about
the money and he needs to be protected.
Dustin Moskovitz owns 6.81 percent,
Sean Parker 6.47 percent.
I can live with that.
And Peter Thiel seven percent.
Would you like to use my pen?
Eduardo.
Can you please repeat the question?
No, it was an outrageously lewd question
the first time and now you want us to hear it twice?
Yes, we do.
Read it back, please.
Go ahead.
Counsel, when you signed these documents, were you
aware you were signing your own death certificate?
No.
It was insanely stupid of me not to have
my own lawyers look over all these...
In all honesty, I thought
they were my lawyers.
I was your only friend.
You had one friend.
My father won't even look at me.
OK. Eduardo, did Mr Zuckerberg say
anything to you after you had signed the papers?
There was a lot of hand shaking,
a lot of congratulations.
He'd already told me he wouldn't be coming
back to school for at least a semester.
So we were saying goodbye for a while.
Before I left he said:
- But you gotta come back.
Somewhere around the end of
November, early December...
...Peter wants to throw us an amazing
party when we hit a million members.
It's gonna be out of control,
you gotta come back for it.
A million members?
Remember the algorithm?
On the window at Kirkland.
Yeah, I'll be here.
You sure about this?
You're twenty minutes late.
You're gonna walk in there, say you overslept
and you didn't have time to get dressed.
Their gonna pitch you. Case Equities is going
pitch you, Their gonna beg you take their money.
You're gonna nod, you're gonna nod...
...and then you're gonna say: which one of you
is David Roth? No, not Roth. Manningham.
Which one of you is Mitchell Manningham?
And he'll say, I am.
And then you'll say, Sean Parker
says 'Fuck You.'
And walk out.
OK.
In late November I got the e-mail from Mark telling
me to come out for the millionth member party.
What else did the e-mail say?
It said that we had to have a business meeting.
That Mark and Sean had played some
kind of revenge stunt on Case Equity.
And that Manningham was so impressed he was now
making an investment offer that was hard to turn down.
So I went to California and I
went straight to the new offices.
I didn't know weather to dress for
the party or the business meeting...
...so I kinda dressed for both.
But it didn't matter.
Why not?
Because I wasn't called out there for either one.
What were you called out there for?
An ambush.
Mr Saverin, please.
At first I thought he was joking.
Giving more contracts to sign.
But then I started reading.
What is this?
Well, as you know we
had some new investors that -
What is this?
Mark.
He's wired in.
- Sorry?
Is he?
- Yes.
How about now, you still wired in?
- Call security.
You issued twenty-four million
new shares of stock.
You were told that if
new investors came along -
How much were your shares diluted?
How much were his?
What was Mr. Zuckerbergs shares diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What were Mr Moscovitz's ownership
shares diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What were Sean Parkers
shares diluted down to?
It wasn't.
What were Peters Thiels ownership shares diluted down to?
And what was your ownership shares diluted down to?
.03 percent.
You signed the papers.
You set me up.
You're gonna blame because you were the business head of the
company, and you made a bad business deal with your own company.
It's gonna be like I'm not a part of Facebook.
Won't be like you're not a part of Facebook,
you're not a part of Facebook.
My name's on the masthead.
You may want to check again.
Because I froze the account?
You think we were gonna let you parade around in your
ridiculous suits and pretending you were running this company.
Sorry, my Prada's are at the cleaners.
Along with my hoodie and fuck-you flip flops.
You pretentious douchebag.
Security's here, you'll be leaving now.
I'm not signing those papers.
We'll get the signature.
Tell me this isn't about me getting into the Phoenix.
I knew you did it, you
planted that story about the chicken.
I didn't plant that story about the chicken.
What's he talking about?
You had me accused of animal cruelty.
Seriously, what the hell's the chicken?
What you hated most, was that they
identified me as a co-founder of Facebook.
Which I am.
You better lawyer up, asshole.
Cause I'm not coming back for thirty percent,
I'm coming back for everything.
Hang on.
I almost forgot.
Here's your nineteen thousand dollars.
I wouldn't cash it though, I drew it on the account you froze.
I like standing next to you, Sean.
Makes me look so tough.
That's it, that's our show for tonight, people.
I want to see everybody here geared up for a party.
We're going to walk into that club...
...like it's the Macy's parade, Mackie, put it up on the big
screen, we've gotta almost be there.
You alright?
You were kinda rough with him.
That's life in the NFL.
You know you didn't have to be that rough on him.
I'm putting together a party.
Sean.
You didn't have to be that rough on him.
He almost killed it.
I'll send flowers.
Speaking of flowers, I'm putting
together a party after the party...
...at Kappa Beta Sigma.
Ash is a sister.
Ashley.
- The intern.
I know who she is.
Are you guys..
Ashley? Me? No.
Well, a little bit.
Why?
Excuse me, Mark.
We were just talking about you.
Just that you're doing
a really good job.
Thanks, I appreciate that.
These came in for you.
Put it on my desk.
What's the package?
Nothing.
Mackie.
Yes, sir.
Refresh.
And you're not a hugger.
I know.
One million.
Who's got champagne?
I've got champagne.
The next transformative development of picture sharing application,
a place where you view pictures that coincide with your social life.
It is the true, the digitalization of your life.
You go through the party with a digital camera
and then your friends re-live the party online.
And tagging, the idea -
Would it be easier without the bra?
I spend hours watching what people do when they
log on. How they check their friends status updates.
That's weird, why did the music stop?
To see which one of their friends change
their profiles, change their photos and mostly-
Seriously, what happened to the music?
We lived on farms. And then we live
in cities, and now were going to live on the internet
Stop. I think something's
going on downstairs.
It's the cops.
Good to see you officer, what can I do for you?
What's going on?
Was the music too loud?
We were having a celebration.
Miss, I need you to button your blouse
I can tell them to turn the music down.
Not mine.
OK, we're going to need identification.
Keep your hands where we can see them.
You got anything else in your
pockets I should know about?
No, no, sir.
Don't be stupid now
- I don't, I don't.
What's this?
That's an EpiPen.
And this?
- That's my inhaler.
How old are you?
21.
I'm 21.
Lying makes it worse.
I'm sorry, I shouldn't have lied.
Listen, something has happened.
It's alright, it's gonna be alright.
I've posted bond, I wasn't doing anything.
I mean I got allergies.
Interns.
It was just a party.
This is gonna be news Sean,
it's gonna be online in a second.
I know.
You know with an intern.
It's cool, I have it under control.
I will get it under control.
I will call someone and see
what the next move is.
You don't think Eduardo was involved, do you?
You think?
- No.
Or Manningham. One of them, somebody sent
the coke 'cause it got in there.
You believe me? This is gonna be fine.
Go home, Sean.
Mark.
We're done for the day.
Yeah, I was just sitting.
What happened to Sean?
He still owns seven percent of the company.
All you had all day was that salad.
You want get something to eat?
I can't.
I'm not a bad guy.
I know that.
An emotional testimony I assume 85 percent of it is exaggeration
And the other fifteen
perjury
Creations the work mostly of the devil.
What happens now?
Sy and the others are having
a steak on university avenue.
Then they'll come back to the office and
work on a settlement deal to present to you.
They're gonna settle.
- Oh yeah.
And you're gonna have to pay a little extra.
Why?
So that these guys sign a non-disclosure agreement.
They say one unflattering word about you in public
and you're away from wife and kids.
I invented Facebook.
- I'm talking about a jury.
I specialize in voir dire jury selection.
What a jury sees when they look at a defendant.
Clothes, hair speaking style, likability.
Likability.
- I've been licensed to practice law for all of twenty months and..
...I could get a jury to believe you planted
the story about Eduardo and the chicken.
Watch what else.
Why weren't you at Sean's sorority party that night?
You think I'm the one who
called the police on him?
Doesn't matter. I asked the question,
now everybody's thinking about it.
You've lost your jury in the first ten minutes.
Farm animals.
- Yeah.
I was drunk, and angry,
and stupid.
And blogging.
- And blogging.
Pay them.
In the scheme of things, it's a speeding ticket.
That's what Sy will tell you tomorrow.
Do you think anybody would mind if I stayed
and used the computer for a minute?
I can imagine it would be a problem.
I appreciate your help today.
You're not an asshole, Mark.
You're just trying so hard to be.
Downloaded From www.AllSubs.org