Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
A WOMAN WITHOUT LOVE
CARLOS MONTERO
ANTIQUES OF ALL SORTS
Here it is.
It's a painting on a steel sheet.
From the beginning
ofthe 19th Century.
It's dated. Look.
The date doesn't mean
anything, Ma'am.
Yes. Montero Antique Store.
Yes? It's me.
There are many forgeries
in this business.
This seems to be from
the beginning of this century.
You are completely mistaken,
it's authentic.
What? Yes, yes, principal.
It's unbelievable.
I assure you that the little rogue
will be punished accordingly.
Yes, yes, Sir.
Good afternoon, principal.
It's 300 pesos, if you want it.
The most I would give you is $80.
No, that's impossible.
-Well, let's say $95.
-I'll handle this.
-The gentleman was offering me...
-Leave. Now.
As an expert, you will agree with me.
You are mistaken.
Besides, this picture is not for sale.
But the lady was asking me...
Here we sell, sir.
We don't steal.
Go to the flea market where
it's more expensive than the stores...
thanks to customers like you.
Come on, man.
With such a temper you'll have
very few customers, my friend.
What a stupid fool.
Why do you even
argue with those people?
But, Carlos. He was a customer.
A customer buys,
he doesn't bargain.
Carlos, please.
That telephone call upset you, right?
Remember, getting upset
is harmful for you.
And who gets me upset?
If it's not you, it's my son.
And when it's not my son, it's you.
So it must have been
the school, right?
Something happened to Carlitos?
Tell me.
If you didn't spoil him so much,
if you didn't always sidewith him
this wouldn't have happened.
For God's sake, what happened?
Simply, that at his age he has
the instincts of a thief...
and doesn't respect his teacher.
Are you still going to defend him?
That's all I need.
How embarrassing!
My son a thief!
I won't accuse him
without seeing him first.
He's at a difficult age
but he is a good kid.
I'll speak to him
and you'll see...
Yes! And you will cover up
for him as usual,
because all you care about
is getting your own way.
There is no other authority here
but yours, CarIos.
Since we got married I've had
to give up all my pleasures,
all my desires, all my opinions.
But now we are dealing
with Carlitos.
So you have sacrificed
yourself, right?
Before we got married it seemed
that I was always right...
and you treated me
with great respect.
But, of course, that was before.
In order to get out of your misery.
To get your parents out of that
rotten neighborhood they lived in.
I've kept my part of the bargain.
Do you lack anything?
You have been good to me.
If you wish, treat me as a maid,
but don't be unfair to your son.
Come here, Carlos.
Today you have tarnished your
father's name with shame.
Because your father
is an honest man, understand?
I didn't steal anything, father.
The teacher...
Shut up! Don't talk back to me!
You should listen to him.
And believe him if he tells the truth.
In the meantime, go to your room.
You will not come out or eat
until you tell me the truth.
-I don't want sons that lie or steal.
-It's not true! I'm not a thief!
That will teach you not to talk
back to your father!
-Come with me.
-Carlos, pIease.
When you grow up you'll say:
My father slapped me...
to always remind me that I should
not steal nor disobey!
Come on!
Get in there.
Isolation and hunger
are the best remedies for rebels.
If it was used more often
there would be fewer revolutionaries.
You have to learn
to behave like my son.
No, thank you.
You're not going to eat?
I'm not hungry.
It's your loss because
the tamales are delicious.
-Come on, eat one.
-I told you I didn't want any.
Come on.
What's the matter?
Every day the same thing.
Long faces, sighs,
ignoring the food.
Do you think it's free?
Look, if you're going to continue
sulking like this, leave the table,
because seeing you like this
makes me lose my appetite.
Carlitos, son,
are you already asleep?
Listen, I do believe you.
I know you are good,
that you never lie.
Carlitos!
My son...
Where are you, my boy?
He ran away.
Carlitos is not in the room
you locked him in.
-What are you saying?
-The boy has ran away, Carlos.
If anything should happen to him
it will be your fault.
He ran away? Impossible!
How could he have ran away
if I locked him in?
That doesn't matter now.
We must do something immediately.
Come on, Chole, perhaps
we'll catch him down the street.
Where are you going? Calm down.
He couldn't have gone far.
I'll catch up to you.
I'm going to call the police.
Oh, children! Children!
Man, that's strange.
-What happened, Gonzalez?
-Look, boss.
I thought it was something more.
Since when is it strange
to see a boy?
This boy is not from here, sir.
Let's see.
You are right.
He is... no.
Yes, he's crying.
He may be lost.
-Let's go and see.
-Come on, sir.
Don't run, boy.
We won't harm you.
Are you staying here
or just visiting?
Stay still. Don't be afraid.
I'm your friend.
Get back to work,
I'll catch up with you later.
Look, you will sit here with me
and tell me your name.
What, you won't tell me?
Then you are Don Juan
without a tongue.
Look, if you become my friend,
I'll take you to a river...
where you will find
the biggest trout in the world.
Would you like to catch one,
Juanito?
But I don't know how to fish.
No big deal. I'll teach you.
-Right now?
-Right now, my friend.
So we're already friends,
right, Juanito?
My name is not Juanito.
My name is
Carlitos Montero Jimenez.
So you have a name.
How did you get here?
-On a truck.
-Okay, Carlitos.
You'll now tell your friend Julio,
because my name is Julio,
why you ran away from home.
Well, at least here it doesn't
say anything.
The press doesn't say anything.
Anyway,
the police has been alerted...
and all we can do is wait.
Thank you for your concern.
I'll tell him.
Excuse me, miss.
I would like to speak to the owner.
My husband has not arrived.
Come back later.
Then you are the owner?
You're so young.
I wouldn't have believed it.
Well, Ma'am.
I'm sure you'll love to have
the piece of art I brought you.
I'm sorry, but I can't take care
of that right now.
Wait a moment.
My son!
You're fine! Are you alright?
Why did you go away? Where?
I bet you haven't eaten anything
since last night, right?
Yes I did, mother. I had breakfast
with my friend Julio.
Excuse me, but I'm so excited
that I haven't even thanked you.
It doesn't matter.
You don't know how I've suffered
these past days...
and when I was most desperate,
you show up with my son.
-How can I thank you for that?
-By drying those tears.
By seeing you happy
I feel well repaid.
Oh, son, how could you do it?
You didn't think
of your mother's suffering.
Sorry, mommy.
I swear I'll never do it again, ever.
Carlitos!
You think you behaved properly?
When I was little
and ran away from home,
I returned with my tail between
my legs and not smiling.
I should spank you.
Forgive me for leaving, father,
but I didn't steal anything.
It's alright. Alright.
Please forgive me, son.
Forgive me too,
but I have to leave.
-Carlos, Mister...
-Julio Mistral, at your service.
Mr. Mistral found Carlitos
and brought him to us.
-At your service, Mr. Montero.
-No formalities.
Allow me to embrace you and treat
you as my best friend from now on.
-Julio, right?
-Yes, sir.
Well then Julio, Carlos and Rosario.
Don't you think so, dear?
Of course. Without him think what
could have happened to Carlitos.
Ma'am, I'm delighted to have
met you. You too, Sir...
I mean, Carlos.
And till soon I hope, because
I intend to become a customer.
You can't leave without first
having a drink.
Carlos, the gentleman...
Keep quiet. What do you know
about men's stuff?
I bet you have never had
a cognac like this one.
Pure nectar.
I thank you for your kindness
but you must be anxious...
-to be alone with your son and...
-In due time, my friend Julio.
Rosario, what do you think
of inviting him to dinner...
to celebrate our meeting?
-It will be my pleasure.
-You heard it. Said and done.
That will teach you not
to go around being a do-gooder.
-To your health.
-Cheers.
Excellent wine, right?
Well, if I don't say it, who will?
We'll have coffee
in the living room, Rosario.
Coffee with a tad of cognac.
Well, more than a tad.
Come on in my friend, Julio.
Remember, no formalities.
-As long as you don't get bored.
-Please, don't say that.
Perhaps you like fun people.
The night life, night clubs.
You're young. I bet you are
a womanizer and a gambler.
Carlos, please. You are speaking
inappropriately to our friend.
You're mistaken, Don Carlos.
Gambling bores me
and easy women are not to my liking.
I'm crazy about my profession
and I would like to have a family.
You're a romantic.
Although I imagine
that in the forestry business,
a good engineer
with some political backing...
could get rich in no time.
By the way, do you smoke cigars?
Don't tell me you don't.
You'll smoke one today!
I have some cigars
that are delicious.
I'll bring them.
I'm taking advantage
of your hospitality, ma'am. I'll go.
No, please. Besides,
you heard my husband.
A very cordial man.
I'm sure that behind those rough
manners he hides a good heart...
and I believe he sees
me as a friend.
What I regret is that you don't.
Why do you say that?
I don't understand.
I'm under the impression that
my presence here bothers you and...
Not at all. From thevery
first moment I...
Thanks to you I recovered my son
and I will never forget it.
I'm happy to be mistaken, because
you seem admirable and, well...
Here they are.
You'll see
what great cigars these are.
Yes, they seem excellent.
The box is for you.
No, for God's sake,
that's too much. I beg you to...
No, no, this way each time
you smoke a cigar...
you'll remember
your friend Carlos.
Well, thank you very much.
In order to try to reciprocate
your hospitality...
I would like you to come and spend
a day with me in my woods.
They are not mine,
but I'm in love with them.
I assure you that you
won't be bored.
It wouldn't be a bad idea,
right, Rosario?
And where are those woods?
On the highway to Toluca
at kilometer 39.
Man, what a coincidence!
Tomorrow I have to go to Toluca.
I'll wait on the highway
around ten o'clock in the morning.
Sure. You can stay with the boy
in the fresh air and sun.
I'll continue on my way
and be back in time to eat.
Because I'm sure there will be
something to eat.
Of course, the best trout
in the country.
Not one more word.
We'll be there at ten o'clock.
How are you, Carlitos? Ma'am.
Dear friend,
you have British punctuality.
Punctuality is my middle name.
I won't tolerate informality;
neither my own nor that of others.
-Can I catch a trout?
-One? A dozen at least.
Yes, son, fish a lot,
your father's stomach will thank you.
Well, I'll leave now
so I can come back sooner.
Do you need anything from town?
No, nothing.
We have everything.
Wine, ham, cheese, trout...
Stop, otherwise I'll stay.
Thank you. Goodbye.
So long.
And let Rosario help
with the cooking.
She's an expert.
So long.
Mom, look what a big trout!
Look at my son. He is happy.
It must be marvelous living here.
Yes, especially for me since I love
the solitude and the mountains.
In these woods everything is pure,
until men and machines arrive.
They destroy everything.
Look at that tree, it is venerably old,
and to think they will make...
tables and chairs out of it
for vulgar people...
By the way, why is
your husband taking so long?
Why do you laugh?
You remembered him after
mentioning vulgar people.
Yes, why should I deny it?
You're so different,
I don't understand how...
you fell in love with him.
Fall in love?
Forgive me for being so indiscreet,
but I'm so interested...
in everything about you.
If you didn't love him
why did you marry him?
I was very young.
Almost a child and...
I'd rather not discuss that.
Mother, mother!
Look how many fish.
They are beautiful!
Why don't we eat them now?
I'm hungry.
It's almost three o'clock.
I can't understand
why he is so late.
Business is business.
I want to eat!
Well, then we'll eat.
We have waited long enough.
Very good! Come on!
He can eat alone when he returns.
What's the use of loving
With all your heart?
What's the use of suffering
Respecting love?
For me, there is only you...
He fell asleep,
it's past his bedtime.
It's almost 8 o'clock.
I don't understand
why Carlos is so late.
Does it bother you
to be alone with me?
Don't say that. I'm embarrassed
about my husband's behavior.
Why are you always so sad?
I don't know.
Perhaps it's the habit.
You don't know how sorry
I am to know you are unhappy.
Today I have been happy
for the first time in many years.
This afternoon you didn't
answer my question.
Why did you marry him?
Carlos was my parents' friend.
A good friend.
He was very rich and
we were very poor.
That's crazy.To condemn you
to not knowing what love is.
-And at your age.
-Really, I don't mind.
Some women don't have
a husband or son.
But they have love.
You're a very young woman
who spends her life...
beside a man she doesn't love
and who doesn't understand her.
A woman who lives a lonelier life
than these woods.
There is no loneliness
when one has a child.
That's not enough.
You have never loved anyone?
Rosario! Julio!
Where are you?
Carlitos.
You can't see anything
in this damn place.
You must be very angry with me,
but it was unavoidable.
Is there any trout left?
I didn't forget about that.
Finally.
I've been restless, desperate.
Why did you take so long?
You can imagine.
I'm not free, Julio.
Give me your coat.
I come for only a moment.
Forgive me.
I was so anxious to come here,
and you see, I can't stay long.
It's very late.
I spent all afternoon waiting for you.
Smoking like a fiend.
Worrying about what might
have happened to you...
if you weren't coming, after all.
I was tempted to call the store.
To go for you. I don't know.
Look, Julio, if it were up to me...
you know I would never
be away from you.
I swear that each time
our goodbyes seem harder.
I want to see you always.
Feel you near me every minute.
We can't go on like this, Rosario.
I don't want to share you
with him anymore.
Don't be cruel.
It is also terrible for me.
You wait, but you don't have
to live with another woman.
Nor do you have to lie, to pretend,
or to smile forcefully.
Nor hide whenever you
want to cry.
Forgive me, my darling,
but I love you so much...
I can't stand it any more either.
This is my house.
You are my world.
Each day I hate Carlos even more,
but lying is the worst part.
The shame, the humiliation
of having to lie is just unbearable.
Stop fighting it.
Get divorced and marry me.
I can't leave my son, Julio.
I have thought about it
thousands of times and I can't.
What if we run away together
and take your son with us?
We'll take the road
and when we are far away from here,
we'll write Carlos
telling him the truth.
Would you do it, my darling?
I want whatever you want.
Listen to me then.
Tomorrow at nightfall,
come here with Carlitos.
We'll immediately take a train
and go to any city to prepare our trip.
To Brazil where they have
offered me a marvelous job.
Say yes, my love.
Yes, my darling.
I'll go wherever you want.
I want to live my love by daylight.
I'll be back tomorrow.
Rosario.
Three first class tickets
to Vera Cruz.
-For when, sir?
-For tonight's train.
Rosario, thank God you are here!
It took you so long
I thought you weren't coming.
We have just enough time
to get to the train.
And the boy? What happened?
Answer me.
I can't go with you, Julio.
I came only to...
What? Explain yourself,
for heaven's sake!
We have to put our plan aside.
For now, at least.
-My husband...
-What? He knows something?
You told him about us
and he has taken the boy?
No, he suffered a heart attack
this morning. Angina pectoris.
I must return immediateIy.
I only came to tell you.
Is he very ill?
Rosario, I'll go with you
in case something is needed.
Let's go.
Julio, my Julio... My love...
Calm down.
We'll discuss it later. Come on.
Come in.
As soon as I found out what
happened I came to see you.
My good friend.
How is he, doctor?
Under the effect of medication.
He needs absolute rest.
Not the least bit of excitement.
I believe that for now
he is out of danger.
I'll be back in an hour.
In the meantime, lots of rest
and above all, no talking.
Leave the boy here.
I'll be at the clinic.
If something happens before
I come back, call me immediately.
He will be fine, doctor?
With the heart one never knows.
But if your husband
has no upsets or excitement,
he may recover soon
and live for many years.
-So long, ma'am.
-Thank you, doctor.
I wonder what triggered the attack.
Does he suspect anything?
No. I don't believe so.
He was in good spirits.
If it had happened after we'd left
it would have been my fault.
How could you know he was sick?
Who would blame you?
I'm afraid, Julio.
Calm down, I beg you.
You heard the doctor. He'll be okay.
It would be a crime
to leave him now.
We'll wait 10, 15 days,
whatever is necessary, and then...
nothing will break us apart.
What are you thinking about?
Imagine, the boy didn't want
to come with me today.
He has become very fond
of his father since his sickness,
and my husband of him.
It's natural.
They are father and son.
But answer the question I asked
before. When are we leaving?
Why don't you answer me?
Why don't you even
look at me, Rosario?
Your husband is well now,
the doctor has said so.
He can go backto his passion:
eating and drinking.
You don't have to feel guilty.
We can go with a clear conscience.
There is something you don't know.
Now that I see how much
he and the boy love each other...
I don't have the courage
to take him away.
Leaving could kill him
and I would never forgive myself.
I understand you don't love me
as much as I thought.
Please. If I didn't love you
I would not confide in you...
my most intimate thoughts.
I talk to you as if to myself.
You think I can abandon
my husband and rob him of his child?
Let's wait longer.
There must be a way out.
Away out?
If I go on like this, I'll explode...
and shout out everything
in your husband's presence.
Bring your son or leave him,
but come with me.
You are not the first woman
in my life, Rosario,
but you are the only one
I have loved.
The only one I will love
until I die.
The decision to come to Brazil
with me or not is in your hands.
Mom, look.
Look, my little boat broke.
It doesn't matter, dear.
I'll buy you another one.
For the last time, Rosario,
yes or no?
In that case...
Goodbye, Rosario.
ANTIQUES OF ALL SORTS
UNIVERSITY OF MEXICO
Well, what do you say now, Ma'am?
What can I tell you, Don Feliciano?
I'm happy.
I never thought Miguel
would graduate.
I'm not very old,
but I can die in peace...
because both my sons
are now doctors.
And it's not a joke, you can see
how badly distributed...
the riches are these days.
A family of doctors when there
are families of sick people.
Well, now... forget family
affairs and sentimentalities.
Everybody wants to drink,
starting with me.
Doctor, come on.
The girls want to dance.
And why are you standing there?
Take care of the guests.
Yes, I'm going. Come on, son.
Your father is right,
dance and enjoy yourseIf.
Come on. Come on.
Doctor, will you allow me
to care for your patient?
Your behavior shocks me,
young colleague.
Professional ethics
forbid a doctor...
from taking another
doctor's patient away.
I don't plan on taking her away.
It's simply a consultation.
Well, alright, I agree as long
as the patient doesn't object.
Well, my dear colleagues, even
though I admire the knowledge...
of Dr. Carlos, my friend
and teacher, I still recognize...
-the merits of the new doctor.
-So, you mean...
In case of an appendectomy,
I would choose you.
But when it pertains to dancing,
I choose our young doctor...
who is more of an expert.
Allow me, colleague.
Do you wish to dance, ma'am?
For heaven's sake, son,
I haven't danced in a long time.
Come on, mother, I want to teach
Miguel and his partner a lesson.
I want them to learn to dance
the waltz properly.
Are you going to deny him that?
Come on, dance!
Don't drink anymore,
I beg you.
But I drink  because the doctor
prescribed it, woman.
We're among doctors
and I'm sure they will approve.
Don't you agree?
And I drink to modern medicine
that prescribes whiskey...
for the aliments of the heart,
and therefore, I make a toast...
to the doctors who prescribe it.
And now, my friends,
we'll have a bite to eat.
Carlos, Miguel, come upstairs,
your father has something to tell you.
Boys, I want to tell you something
that will interest you.
I have been doing some inquiring
and it seems that a clinic...
is a great business, right?
That's for sure.
Why do you say that?
I'm not rich, but I'm on the verge
of closing a good business deal...
selling a few lots of land.
And I thought that instead of putting
the money under the mattress,
it would be a good idea
to invest it in a clinic.
That's a marvelous idea, father.
Can you imagine, Miguel?A clinic!
Our dream.
Everything sounds nice,
but is it a good business or not?
Because you know I don't...
Of course, father.
If you manage it well.
Carlos would be the director
and I the assistant.
And we could also have
a research laboratory.
Yes, son. I have also dreamed
of having you both settled...
and when your father had that idea
I was overjoyed.
Well, things being what they are,
it was her idea.
And she bothered me so much
she convinced me.
-You're a wonderful mother,
-The most beautiful.
-And as good as no other.
-Well, be quiet...
Well, so that's it.
Go find a house, but remember,
you have to pay me back.
-Ah, yes.
-Why didn't you tell us before?
It's beautiful, son. Beautiful.
I find it ideal,
very cheerful for a clinic.
A place like this and nobody will doubt we are good doctors, right?
Nevertheless,
I think the rent is too high.
I'll speak with your father who
knows a lot about this...
and you'll see how he gets
a good deal.
I think it is a steaI.
And by means of a long term loan
for which I will soon apply,
we'll be able to install
the most modern x-ray equipment.
But that costs a lot of money.
They are not inexpensive,
but here the clientele is very rich.
Let's see my office.
Yes, son.
How would you like this office
for yourself?
I love it, as I love
all your projects.
I'm so anxious for you to make
money so we can...
so you can dedicate yourself
to your research.
If you really want me to be
successful, why not...?
Why not what?
I don't know how to say it.
But instead of being
chief of nutrition,
why don't you become
the owner ofthis house?
With director and all.
Don't you like the idea?
I like it and I'm touched, Carlos.
You have been my colleague,
my teacher... but I don't know.
Right now it would
be impossible to think about that.
Why change friendship for love?
Don't make that face. Perhaps I
shouldn't give an answer yet.
Why don't we leave it pending
for some time?
If you wish, but you are for me
above all a woman, not a doctor.
Not a colleague, not even a pupil
as you claim.
I'll wait all the time necessary.
Now, let's talk about
something else.
Tomorrow you'll come
with me to the hospital.
I'll show you the new installation
ofthe bacteriological lab.
We have German microscopes.
Good morning, doctor.
Am I interrupting?
Rita! What are you doing here?
The same as you.
Dr. Manzano had also
cast an eye upon this house.
Do you know each other?
This is Dr. Sunsula.
The doctor is very well known.
They say that her method of feeding
children extends into adulthood.
What is your opinion, doctor?
I think...
As an adult, the doctor
thinks it is all nurses' gossip.
Isn't it so, Carlos?
-Yes, of course.
-See you soon, little doctor.
It's a pleasure to see you in such
professional and nutritious company.
What did she mean, Carlos?
Have you had anything
to do with that woman?
Absolutely nothing. But she thinks
all doctors and patients love her.
What is it with you two?
-Nothing. We were just talking.
-Come on, mother is waiting for us.
What a scoundrel!
What's the matter, Carlos?
Can you imagine him wanting
to cheat me at this point,
but since nobody robs me,
I cancelled the deal.
What are you saying?
That thief settled for only
130,000 pesos...
and today the land is worth
at least twice as much.
But you paid much less.
We just need to make some money
to settle Carlos in.
You don't know a thing about business.
You don't.
Remember when we
transferred the store,
we almost gave it away for nothing
because of your interference.
Forgive me,
but I take back everything.
You don't know how sorry I am.
But, father, I already made a deal
with the owner of the house...
and with the stores.
No, it's not definite.
I have to wait to sell at a good
price to an honest person.
Forgive me and don't worry.
Everything will be solved in time.
Father, Mr. Palafoz
is on his way here.
Don Nicolas Palafoz,
the notary public?
Yes, him.
Funny. He hasn't been in
this house for years.
He told me it was something
urgent and important.
Have you heard, Rosario?
Yes, and I wonder what
it could be.
Well, imagine.
When it comes to a notary...
It must involve an inheritance.
We would like that,
but from whom?
Could it be from your
Uncle Agustin?
He would leave only debts.
Don't worry.
I was thinking about your
Cousin Juana.
-Sure, that one is rich.
-Forget it.
She married again
and with a young man.
Where are you going?
You can keep guessing.
I'm going to my room.
But why? What's the matter?
After today's letdown, I'm not
in the mood for guessing games.
He's right.
Mr. Palafoz.
Come in, Don Nicolas. Come in.
It's been such a long time
since last we saw you.
What can I say, Don Carlos, Ma'am?
At your service.
How are you, Don Nicolas?
Not so bad, Doctor.
I already said hello
to Miguelito downstairs.
Won't you sit down?
And tell us what brings you here?
Care for a drink?
I'll sit down, yes, Ma'am.
And I'll tell you, Sir.
And for the moment, I won't
drink anything. Thank you.
Before I start I must tell you I'm
here as a notary, not as a friend.
In said capacity
I must give you bad news.
What can I say,
it's part of the job.
I've been notified by a Brazilian
colleague about the death...
of a  friend of yours.
It's about Mr. Mistral.
-Julio Mistral.
-Dead?
Julio Mistral, the engineer?
Exactly, ma'am. Yes, sir.
It happened over
a month ago in Sao Paulo, Brazil.
Who would have thought!
Such a kind friend, so refined.
I still remember how he took care
of me when I had my angina.
He was so thoughtful.
Do you remember, Rosario?
I haven't forgotten.
He was so fond of Carlitos.
You don't remember him, son?
He's the man that brought you
home when you ran away.
Yes, I had not made
the connection.
He taught me to fish trout.
I was very small.
-Did I know him, father?
-Let me see no.
You where born some months
after he went to Brazil,
to do his foresting.
That's so sad, dear God.
If you don't mind holding
your thoughts for a moment,
that engineer Mistral left a will
and if you allow me,
I will begin to read it.
Let's see.
"In the city of Sao Paulo, Brazil,
at the date of the month etc.
"I, Julio Mistral, being of sound
mind but ailing body,
"leave all my personal fortune
that amounts to...
"a million one hundred thousand
pesos, Mexican currency,
"to the son of my dear friends
Carlos and Rosario Montero,
"Miguel Montero Jimenez".
One million one hundred
thousand pesos to me?
Should the beneficiary hesitate,
or if his disappearance...
prevents him from receiving
the inheritance,
the money will then go
to the Muir foundation...
towards the help
of the destitute, etc. etc.
Well, I will now accept that
whiskey,
if you're so kind in order to drink
to the health of the young heir.
Nevertheless, what I can't
understand is why...
he remembered us after
all these years.
Do you understand it, woman?
Yes, he adored children,
was very kind,
as it seems he had nobody,
had not married...
But why did he leave it to me?
Perhaps because you are
the youngest.
Your son will have to declare
his acceptance formally.
Of course he accepts,
is it not so, Miguelito?
Tell me, Don Nicolas,
that money is free from all...
There are no debts, nor any
other heir that might contest...
Nothing, nothing. It's the most
simple and direct donation...
I have handled.
Thank you.
Then you accept, Don Miguel?
Well, of course we accept.
Does he have to sign anything now?
No. Tomorrow at 12 in my office.
To your health, then,
and congratulations.
That poor Julio was a true friend.
And he had a great heart.
Who would have thought I would
have a millionaire son.
How do you feel, Miguelito?
Frankly, father, a little stunned.
And why are you sad?
It hurts me to think he died
far away from his friends.
But remembering them.
I have to leave, but first I want
to congratulate you, Miguel.
-Thank you, Carlos.
-Where are you going, son?
Excuse me, mother, but I'm
on duty at the hospital.
But it is very early.
Won't you eat with us?
I'm sorry, but I have a headache
and would like to walk.
Leave him alone. I bet he's sad
about the death of his friend.
-See you tomorrow, mother.
-Goodbye, son.
Come here, Miguel.
You and I are going to drink to
the memory of the great friend Mistral...
and for your future and happiness.
Thank you very much, father.
To your health.
-Cheers.
Come in.
I have just heard the great news,
Congratulations, I hope we
celebrate it as it deserves.
Rita, please. I'm busy.
You jerk, you used to say
beautiful things about my lips.
Could it be on account
of the little doctor you go out with?
I don't like to hear nonsense,
forgive me.
What's the matter with you?
I came to hug you because I heard
you received an inheritance...
and you treat me like this?
-I haven't inherited anything.
-Then it's all a joke?
My brother Miguel
is the one who inherited it.
-Excuse me. Anyway I'm happy.
-Not more than I.
I can imagine. Some crazy aunt.
No, if you really must know,
it was an old friend of our parents...
who without even knowing him,
left him more than a million pesos.
Just like in the movies.
And nothing for you?
Nothing.
That's strange.
I don't think it's strange at all.
Each one is free to leave
his money to whomever he pleases.
Don't get mad, honey.
After all, you are the oldest and...
-What?
-Nothing.
But the reasonable thing
would have been to leave...
the money to the two of you.
Will you go away
and leave me alone?
Carlos, I can understand your bad
mood, but I'm your friend...
and I'm warning you this will create
a bad feeling among the staff.
-What the hell do you mean?
-Careful, you're hurting me!
You're very smart, little doctor.
Give it a little thought
and you'll understand.
Ah! Yes, yes, yes...
As far as I'm concerned,
I'd rather prefer to be shot.
I believed it might prove
more dangerous.
I don't see why.
Mom is right. The bullet
may only scratch you...
while the wine goes through
your stomach.
-So what?
-Nothing.
The wine only burns the stomach,
messes up the nervous system
and slows the digestion.
And at your age makes
you prone to apoplexy.
It's true that you don't
take care of yourself.
Today's doctors are all the same.
Don't drink, don't eat,
don't smoke, don't dance.
Well, you understand.
Foolishness.
Well, do what you want.
I already warned you.
Don't get mad, son.
You're nervous, irritable.
You don't want to spoil your
brother's party do you?
Of course not, mother.
Let's celebrate the return
of the prodigal son...
who didn't go on a trip.
I'll drink to Miguel's health.
Rigor in my father's prescription
and benevolence in your colleague.
-Very nice.
-That's the truth.
I have a license to prescribe
myself poison whenever I want.
-What will Don Feliciano do?
-Wait, Carlos.
One moment, please.
Dear friends, we have gathered
here in great friendship...
to celebrate the appearance
of reluctant lady luck to this home.
I toast to our dear Miguel hoping
he will make good use...
of the inheritance and that he
may live a long and happy life.
Miguel, give me a drop before
the attending doctor returns.
Aren't you going to reply
to Don Feliciano, Miguel?
I'm grateful for your words,
but you already know...
that speaking in public is not
one of my talents.
-I thought we were among family.
-At last we heard your voice.
We are indeed among relatives
and in a family that will soon...
increase its wealth.
Don't joke like that,
I don't like it.
-Forgive me, mother.
-Silence, Miguel is going to talk.
Above all, I want to thank
everybody for the good wishes...
and sincerity you show me
and then announce that...
I have decided to buy the house
in which Carlos and I...
had decided to establish a clinic.
Tomorrow I'll sign the deed.
I want to do everything
as you wanted, Carlos.
And just because I'm
the owner doesn't mean...
you won't be the director.
After all, it was your idea.
What do you say, Carlitos?
I'm very sorry, Miguel,
but I can't accept your offer.
It's not in my plans to accept charity,
and if some day I accomplish something...
it must be through my own effort,
and not...
-That's all.
-I didn't want to offend you. I'm sorry.
You are free to accept or refuse
what your brother offers you.
But you will apologize to him
and to all here for your rudeness.
Don't forget that you're
still in my house.
Forgive me everyone,
especially you, Miguel.
I didn't mean to offend you.
The conduct of that young man
has been deplorable,
and I'm not about to tolerate it.
He's young, his ambition was
the clinic and you spoiled it for him.
It's natural that he should be hurt.
And now you will side with him.
You know what I think?
It hurts me very much
because he is my son,
but he is jealous
of Miguel's inheritance.
Don't say that. Remember
he graduated 5 years ago...
and despite his efforts,
he's not been able to accomplish much.
Besides, he knows Miguel wants
to share everything with him.
Miguel is like me.
No wonder he's my son.
But that Carlos...
I better go talk to him,
tell him a thing or two.
No! Let me do it.
We mothers know how
to handle these matters.
And point out to him how
distasteful those outbursts are...
in front of strangers,
and not to forbid me to drink.
I do what I please.
Am I not his father?
Relax and sleep, Carlos.
I'll go to see him.
Are you awake, son?
Come in, mother.
What brings you here?
I couldn't have slept without
saying goodnight to you.
What's the matter, son?
Why are you in such a bad mood?
It's nothing.
Don't you think your mother
knows you well?
You behaved badly during dinner.
What's the matter?
I don't know. Nerves. My father
exasperates me so much sometimes.
-I don't really know.
-Are you sure that's all?
-You and your intuition, mother.
-Don't get mad at me.
But I thought that since
your plans failed,
and good fortune was on
your brother's side,
without him even looking for  it,
that had left you jealous.
Me, jealous?
You, my son.
You're with your mother which is
like being with yourself.
Tell me the truth.
I think you're right, mother.
What a shame!
Don't worry. That will pass
without leaving any trace.
You'll see. In the meantime,
try to bury those bad thoughts.
All my life I've wanted to be
someone, above all, for you.
Miguel is my brother,
but for him the career
is nothing but an ornament.
To me, research,
experimentation,
discovery is the great
ambition ofmy life.
You see. I lack the means.
Is that fair, mother?
It's useless to revolt against
what's already done.
But don't get depressed.
Continue as you have up to now.
Have faith.
In good fortune.
In everything.
In me,
who loves you so much.
In you, mother, yes. Yes.
Good night, son. Sleep well.
Carlos, I want to talk to you
for a moment.
Tell me.
Luisa is downstairs and we're meeting
mom to pick out furniture...
for the new house.
I would like you to join us.
Are you crazy?
I'm on duty all day.
-Manzano can cover for you.
-I don't like asking for favors.
I'll go tomorrow.
Didn't you want
to tell me something?
Yes, I've been meaning
to ask you something.
-I hope you understand and...
-What's it about?
Are you in love with Luisa?
Me? Where did you get
that idea?
I just thought so.
I wanted to ask you because...
I do love her.
-Well, tell her, not me.
-I already did.
-And she accepted.
-How do you know?
And how else could it be?
You're a distinguished,
charming young man,
and above all very rich.
You're pulling my leg, Carlos.
I'm serious. I love her.
But I also came to tell you that
if you love her, as I think you do,
I'll leave the coast clear for you.
A little late for that,
and besides, it's unnecessary.
Anyway, thank you, Miguel.
She must have said she's very
interested in her career,
that she's very fond of me
since I was her teacher, etc...
-But that's about it.
-And you?
Me?
I'm going to wash my hands.
Thank you, buddy.
See you tomorrow.
What are you doing here?
I was waiting for your brother
to leave to talk to you.
You too? And in the meantime
your patient is neglected.
What do you want?
Let go!
Do I have to call you "doctor" and treat you formally?
You must hear me out.
Lately I've been thinking about
how you enjoyed talking to me.
Remember how you used to take me
to the movies and to dinner?
Why did you change so much?
-You used to always come for me.
-I needed to kill time.
At least when there are no patients.
Seriously, you are always
in a bad mood, upset...
I know what it is,
but I want to help you forget.
Carlos, why don't you take me
dancing on Saturday?
-We could talk then.
-Are you insane?
You think I'll stroll around
with a... nurse?
You'd be embarrassed?!
Men are so odd. Really!
What should embarrass them
doesn't and...
-What do you mean?
-I know what I mean.
You're not leaving
without telling me.
Don't touch me!
Although I'm "just" a nurse,
I wouldn't have been embarrassed
going out with you.
Tell me what you have to say.
Don't think I'm jealous
of the lady doctor.
Everyone knows she's going out
with your rich brother.
What are you insinuating?
You should never offend a woman,
not even a nurse,
when you're your mother's son.
Take that back or I'll...
What do you mean?
You must be blind
or desperate for money...
to not see why your brother
inherited the money.
Bitch.
If you don't let go of me
I'll scream.
Until never, little doctor.
-What's the matter, Carlos?
-Nothing.
-Why did you leave so abruptly?
-I said it's nothing.
-Anything else?
-Nothing. Sleep well, son.
When will the house be ready?
I'm taking care of it, father.
I'll go there right after breakfast.
The decorators promised it will
all be ready tomorrow.
-Good morning, son.
-Good for some people.
I can wait for you to get dressed.
I'd like you to come with me
to see your new office.
I have a surprise for you.
You're very kind
and I'm very grateful,
but I don't think
I'll be able to use it.
-What? Didn't we agree...
-I'm thinking of leaving Mexico soon.
Without telling us, son?
Where to?
To the Tropics.
To the Tropics?
What are you talking about?
To the Tropics outside of Mexico.
I want to do some research.
If my request is granted
it will be very soon.
Well, I'll be damned.
Your brother wanted to help you
get established alongside him.
I know Miguel is wonderful
and I'm very grateful.
Worthy heir to such a generous
man as Mr. Mistral.
By the way, it's strange that although
he was favored so magnificently...
by our parents' friend, he has shown
no interest in seeing his face.
You're right,
I hadn't thought of that.
Now that you mention it,
I would like that.
Surely there must be a picture of him
around the house.
Right, mother?
I don't think so.
It's been so long that...
Yes, there is a picture.
I saw it recently, the day you were
cleaning out the hallway chest.
Your benefactor gave it to us because
I told him he looked like a movie star.
I hope you find it so Miguel can
put it in a gold frame at his clinic.
Go get it. Miguel would like to know
the face of his benefactor.
Mistral was kind and courteous.
All your gratitude is not enough,
Miguel, because he could have...
just as well left the money
for Carlos or myself.
He never met me,
so I can't understand why.
Actually, he did meet you.
We mailed him a card
regarding your baptism,
and later on your picture.
I believe it was the one
of your first communion.
Here you are.
He was not bad looking.
Distinguished, young...
Younger than you, right, dad?
Yes, fifteen years younger.
I don't know why he never married.
He always mentioned how much
he wanted a family.
Why are you standing?
Sit down.
I'm going to my room.
So many long faces.
And what's the matter with you?
Nothing. Talking about a dead man
reminds me of the troubles of life.
Ever since the inheritance,
you seem to be mourning someone.
I am mourning someone.
-I bet it's a woman.
-Yes, a woman.
Did you break up with her?
Worse even.
She died in my heart.
But there's really no reason
to be sad.
She was not worthy.
Rosario!
What is it, dear?
What is it?
Let's get her something, fast.
Carlos, what are you doing there?
Hurry up.
Her pulse is weak.
What do you think it is?
Prescribe her a sedative.
Something mild.
-What's wrong with her?
-Nothing serious.
And don't be concerned, she'll probably
have quite a few more of those.
Mom, calm down.
It was nothing,
you'll be fine soon.
But...
More. More. There.
That's perfect, don't you think?
I agree, but do you think the clinic's
success depends on this table?
Don't make fun of me.
Little things go a long way.
-What do you think?
-What a house!
And what a great business.
You took the best
Spanish chest I had.
You have good taste.
The clinic is fabulous.
A real treasure.
And what does the critic say?
I'm convinced. Yes.
It's not bad.
Don't trust him, Miguel.
He's a joker.
I'm leaving. I have a lot of work.
We'll see each other at dinner time.
What's the matter, father?
Nothing. Just some shortness
of breath once in a while.
"Don't blame anyone for my death",
said... whoever said it.
It's no one's fault I run around
all day Iong.
-Be careful.
-We'll walk you to the garden.
Let's go.
-How funny, how womanly.
-What?
Luisa. She feels she owns the house,
the owner, and the one million pesos.
Women are so sentimental
and indifferent.
Don't say  that about Luisa,
she's not like that.
-She has her own money, a career...
-You would defend her.
One never sees his mother as a woman,
but when you do...
you can find out surprising things.
You know what I'm thinking?
You defend Luisa, because
you would have done...
exactly the same thing.
How can you say that?
Howcan you even think that?
And you even laugh.
You're crazy!
I'm having fun and learning.
Look.
That kiss will cost Miguel
a million pesos.
I won't let you say that.
Luisa, is honesty in person
and you know it.
Yes, she personifies
the honesty of all women.
Interesting dilemma
proving a woman can be honest.
Very honest and still
cheat on her husband.
She will do it, and she won't
be the first or the last one.
You are so cruel!
You have no idea how cruel
and unfair you are being.
I'm sorry to say it, but I wasn't born
to be a husband, thank goodness!
What's the matter, mother.
Are you ill?
It's nothing. I'm just a bit dizzy again.
I'm fine now.
-Do you need anything?
-Don't worry. I'm fine.
-Are you sure?
-Sure, son.
Sit here, mother.
-Are you really feeling better?
-Yes, my son, I am.
Can you handle some good news?
-When is the wedding?
-You knew!
And you don't know how happy
I am.You'll be very happy.
-Really?
-Really.
Mother.
What an amazing ceremony!
I admit that when you put yourself to it,
you go all the way, my friend.
Yes, and it cost me a lot.
I didn't allow Miguel to pay
a cent for the banquet.
-Right, Miguelito?
-Be careful, Don Feliciano.
Starting today Luisa won't be
caring for you anymore.
-Right, Luisa?
-Let him eat. Today is a special day.
Look at your mother, she barely
even tasted the mushrooms.
Don't say that.
They served me too much.
-Are you happy?
-Immensely.
The day would be complete
if Carlos had come.
Here's to the couple!
Congratulations.
You show up now?
You think it's right to miss
your brother's wedding?
I'm a busy doctor, father.
The kind that works for a living.
-Don't argue now.
-You're right.
I want to make a toast.
Is there a glass for me?
Let me have this one.
Cheers, Miguel.
Cheers, Luisa.
This toast is to the alliance of science,
beauty and wealth.
And also to women's fidelity.
If you told us the joke,
we would laugh with you.
There is nothing fairer,
Don Feliciano.
I'm also toasting
Dr. Carlos Montero Jimenez, that's me.
A member of the Institute
of Tropical Diseases,
who will soon leave on a trip
without honey nor moon.
-Congratulations, man.
-You got it?
I also congratulate you
if that's what you want.
Thank you, dear people.
Nobody can imagine how happy
a man can be without money,
without a wife, without the danger
of losing the wife,
of losing the money...
Carlos, you have been drinking.
Stop being impertinent and
sit down and eat something.
Yes, I drank a little.
But you mustn't do it anymore.
I have warned you many times.
I propose a toast.
Luisa, Miguel, you have given me
the happiest day of my life.
A toast for my son Miguel who
is the one that has given me...
the most happiness.
He's rich, young, he has married
a marvelous girl,
and carries my name.
What more does one want?
And to toast them for
the happiness we are all here,
eating well, drinking even better,
because that's the reason
I spent my money.
Because if my son is splendid,
his father is more.
He's exactly like me.
He has all my qualities and none
of my faults, which are many.
And I toast to this son...
who today married
this angel, I...
-Carlos!
-Father!
Excuse me.
He's dead.
At least he died happy.
Death spared him from
many disappointments.
What's new, Carlos?
Leaving already?
The plane leaves at ten.
How's mother?
I think she needs a good rest.
It's not necessary.
Women have an incredible
amount of strength...
and great strength of character.
She has not shed one tear.
You know that people who don't
cry suffer the most.
That's what they say.
I'll go see her.
Carlos, I know this is not
the best time,
but since you're leaving,
I want to clarify a matter with you.
Go ahead.
We haven't talked since that day
at the clinic when you asked me...
Who is thinking about that now?
You are Miguel's wife.
It's my fault for believing
you were different.
You're mistaken, Carlos.
When you told me about your love
I didn't want to hurt you...
but I've been in love with Miguel
since way back.
I'm sorry, but I don't believe you.
The inheritance
made you change course.
You're like all the rest.
Vulgar, ambitious and capable
of selling yourself for...
Poor guy. You're sick
with jealousy and envy.
Jealousy? Envy?
Of my brother the imbecile?
Of the good deal you've done?
What I feel is repulsion, contempt.
Luisa, where are you going?
What happened?
Ask your brother.
I'm going back home.
What did you say to Luisa?
To the doctor? I was telling her
about the vulgarity of women.
First of all, don't call her
doctor in that tone of voice.
She's my wife, Carlos.
That's right.
You were the purchaser.
I order you to take back
what you just said.
You, ordering me?
You're crazy.
You want me to tell you
what I think?
It breaks my soul to say it,
but you are jealous. Envious.
I'm ashamed to be your brother.
Jealousy, right?
Of your great talent.
Would you have been able to write
your thesis without me?
Or do you think I'm jealous
because you married Luisa?
With money you can
buy everything.
Then it's my money you envy?
-Since I received the inheritance
-You had to bring up the money?
Shut up or I won't be responsible
for my actions.
For weeks you
haven't been able to say...
one word to my mother,
my father, Luisa or me.
You cowardly torture mother...
as if she was responsible
for my inheritance,
and I will not shut up!
Besides, I'm going to order you
to respect me.
Respect you, idiot?
You who has dishonored
us with your inheritance?
What did you say? Repeat it!
I say one cannot accept
the fortune of a man...
when one claims
he's the son of another.
Are you mad?
You're the son of the man
who left you his fortune.
You're not an honest man,
because an honest man,
doesn't accept the money
that stains one's mother.
Bastard!
If you come close, I'll...
Why did you make me tell you?
You should have kept quiet.
How can you say
that about mother?
How could you know?
The happy child. Pampered
and rich who never knew anything.
For many days I haven't slept,
eaten or known what I'm doing...
or what I'm saying because
I'm oppressed by shame and pain.
And my mother...
I should never
have told you anything.
Say it again to my face
or I'll kill you.
No, Miguel, no.
Tell me it isn't true, mother.
Tell me.
It's true Miguel.
Carlos told the truth.
No, it's not possible.
Yes, Miguel. The man who left
you that fortune was your father.
The only man I ever loved.
Then it's true.
You betrayed me, him and all.
I can say it.
You betrayed my father.
You have covered us with shame.
I will not allow you to insult me.
Mine was not a shameful affair,
only an impossible union.
In order not to abandon you
or your father who was sick,
I didn't go away
to live with him forever.
I don't ask you for forgiveness.
I'm not ashamed of those moments
of happiness an tenderness.
Nothing can pay for them
in this world.
To me, he was my real husband,
and that society in front of which
I have covered you with shame...
was the one that sacrificed
my life and my love.
Don't you feel shame either,
just as I do not feel it
for having loved your father.
Together with you two, he was
the only good thing life has given me.
My only love. Even today, being
dead, he is still alive in my heart.
Now you know everything.
If you're ashamed of me,
leave this house!
Forgive me, mother.
I'm the least likely to judge you.
Forgive me.
Come and live with us, mother,
with Luisa and myself.
Please say yes. I'll do whatever
possible to make you happy.
No, son. Leave me here
with my memories.
I'll be happy if you are happy.
You will always have me here
to hold you in my arms.
Forgive me too, mother.
I don't know what to say,
but I don't want to go,
leaving you like this.
-I'll stay here with you and...
-No, son.
I appear guiltier in your eyes.
You would again look at me,
like you have been doing lately.
I don't hold any grudge.
I'm your mother and I understand
you have suffered.
Go away, son,
and may God bless you.
Goodbye, mother.
I'll write to you.
Mother, tell me we'll see
each other every day.
If you need anything
you'll ask me for it.
Leave me alone now.
I need to be alone and rest.
Goodbye, Miguel.
I'm going to be away
for a long time...
and I hope you
don't hold any grudge.
You can leave in peace.
We will be like before. As always.
And don't worry about mother.
I'll take care of her.
-My brother.
-Carlos.
Let's go.
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS.org today