Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext
Dreams Travel
on Streetcars
Mexico
One of the great
cities of the world...
...is the setting of the most
varied and puzzling events...
... that are the pulse...
...of its daily life.
In spite of its transcendence,
millions of men
and women write,
hour after hour,
their brief and simple stories.
Their actions and words...
...always tend towards
the realization of a dream.
Of a wish... of a fantasy.
Together, they...
...give shape to the huge
swarm that is city life.
We will randomly focus
on a corner...
...of our great city.
Thus...
... this film is
but another anecdote,
simple and almost trivial,
of life in the working
...poverty-stricken
classes of the common people.
Those who travel
on streetcars.
All right, take her away.
Again.
I told you not to come in here.
You're so stubborn,
you're worse than mules.
Professor, there goes the train.
That's enough, already.
Hey, what's wrong with that guy?
He almost blew my head off.
I'm getting tired of him.
You're too old to play train.
Is your livelihood a game?
I never step over the line.
If you feel you're so smart,
take my post.
Not that smart, professor.
We owe everything we know to you.
Flatterer.
So, did you really fix it?
The problem was in the magnets.
Not bad, not bad.
But how could you finish
it so fast?
Let's notify the head of shop.
- Are you sure it's number 1 33?
- Sure.
- Nobody could've changed the number.
- Fine by me.
These boys' motives
seem reasonable enough.
Let's talk to the head of traffic.
Come with me.
There's a report on 1 33.
One week to be repaired.
It was supposed to be put back...
...to work exactly on Christmas Eve.
You are six days early.
- Who fixed it?
- Our buddy here.
And who are you?
Tobìas Hernàndez,
nick named "Tarrajas".
Let me explain, sir.
It was practically nothing.
What do you all have to say?
Two simple crew members...
...turned out to be more efficient...
...than our own
specialized mechanics.
They were my apprentices, sir.
What will we do with that train?
Give me the information I asked for.
Number 1 33's papers, sir,
and this memo.
Number 1 33 must be sent
to the yard, it's useless.
It will be replaced by
one of our new streetcars.
Why didn't I see this memo?
I haven't had time
to go over the mail yet.
No time, what an excuse.
Give the respective orders.
You heard him, sit down and listen.
Boss, what about us?
You may stay on at the company.
Otherwise, you'll get your pay.
We proved No. 1 33 isn't useless.
- We fixed it.
- Good afternoon, gentlemen.
Just a minute.
Don't any of you forget...
...that too much of anything
is detrimental.
Even efficiency.
Hey, where are you going?
- To break down No. 1 33?
- Stop joking around.
All right, men.
Patience, you will win
on some other day.
What about that scrap?
Let's take number 1 33
to the shops.
Leave it to me,
you get rid of the scrap.
See you.
We've had it, "Curls".
A crooked tree never straightens.
Tough luck.
You behave, and look at what happens.
Poor 1 33 is off to the graveyard.
And with it, our stable job.
It dried up, buddy.
What about those beer cartons?
It's for the streetcar
inaugural party.
I can't wait.
Neither can l,
I'm dying for a beer.
Why don't we go for it?
No, we have to take
the scrap to the yard.
Let's do it tomorrow,
it's already 5:00.
We're almost off, aren't we?
You've got to give your body
what it craves for.
WELL...SO WHAT?
Do you think we like your
stupid television so much?
It's not like we're
going to wear it off.
I've been thrown out
of better places.
Come on, we don't
need to beg anywhere.
- Why don't you stop?
- Come on, leave them alone.
No way, what are you
talking about?
Does anyone have a mirror?
Here, Lupita, right away.
You don't even need it.
You look beautiful.
Pablo, cut it off,
you're just teasing me.
When will you accept, Lupita?
You know my love
for you is true.
- Do you really want to know?
- My future's in your hands.
They day you drive your own car.
Isn't there a Ford in your future?
I thought you only
cared about true love.
Oh, don't listen to me.
I'm a joker, you take
things seriously.
You get upset right away.
Don't touch.
Tarrajas.
There's Lupe again,
with that damn Pablo.
You're her brother,
you should control her.
Don't you have any authority?
It's just fun and games.
That's how it always begins.
Don't you remember?
Don't get confused, I'm
in a class all by myself.
You know my
intentions are honorable.
- Why are you so late?
- What? What time is it?
Have you been drinking again?
Drinking, yes, I was.
- Blow into my eye.
- What?! The nerve.
You're shameless, and it's
all this perverter's fault.
You know, Lupita, today...
...Tarrajas and l
were greatly disappointed.
With great pain do we see
the injustice of the world.
You don't say! What happened?
Nothing, our lips are sealed.
You couple of busy bodies.
What about the Christmas play?
That's right, I forgot.
Shepherds, shepherds.
Boys change in number 7,
girls change in number 4.
You're not dressed,
what are you waiting for?
Go on, we're about to begin.
- Lupe.
- What do you want?
Why the long face?
You give me no
reason to be happy.
It's always me.
Somebody is bound
to cheer you up.
I'm not a bell to be
rung by anybody.
What an intimate conversation.
You're hinting,
and right in my face.
You're jealous, Pablo.
Me, jealous of that scoundrel?
If you could see envy...
He quit the union, he
can go anywhere in a car.
Look at him now, so fancy
and with all that dough.
Oh, he's just a flatterer.
No wonder they call him
the polisher.
Professor.
That's all I needed,
what are you doing here?
You should be dressed.
We were on our way.
You wanted to set an example,
like real actors.
Look at the state you're in.
Let's go, move.
That way.
Come Lupita, dance this
one with me, will you?
- Of course, Pablo.
- Come on.
I just came to have
a bit of punch, Mercedes...
...and I'm back at my post.
I left the shops all alone.
Put some spirit in it.
Gladly, and I'll make
it double just for you.
Thanks, Mechitas.
So, you left the shops unguarded?
What could possibly happen?
The tools...
...are kept under lock.
What else could they steal?
Who would ever take
a streetcar?
Come on, Mechitas.
Stop Lucifer, stop.
Among all the angels,
I am the Celestial captain
Gabriel and Michael, come forth.
May this be a lesson to you.
Take that thing away
and change the harness.
Since I've been thrown out
of the Catholic world...
...from this moment on they
shall be my diabolical resolve.
I will wear the mask.
And frighten with the tunic.
Come, plague, pour down, rain.
May they not reap wheat,
corn or beans.
May you all get diseased...
...and die of heat.
Don't spite me, evil Satan.
- Come on, Adam, where are you?
- Here, here I am.
Whatcha doing? I can't see you.
I'm in the middle of something.
Where's Eva?
Fixing me a drink.
Is there any fruit?
- She ate it with me.
- Come to my presence.
So, you're eating an apple.
You shall find out what
this evil deed brings.
Remember I forbade it?
- Yes, yes.
- I don't.
Then, get out of here.
Just a minute.
Who was the inciter?
His excellence over there.
Why, it is the traitor himself.
Before such defiance,
daughters of my entrails...
...come a whim of oppression.
You shall suffer
your original sin.
You wanted to know the science
of good and evil.
I'll send you a redeemer.
You, perfidious woman...
...shall bear your children in pain.
And you, Adam, for your disobedience...
...will have to support them
with your breath and sweat.
Grab the sword, Michael,
and quickly tend to him.
Stand up, brave woman,
I challenge you.
Here I am in person
ready to put you out.
My God.
Bravo.
INTERMlSSlON
5 MlNUTES
Meche, pour me another one,
for the road.
Well, how many roads
are you taking?
Mr. Braulio has many horses.
Strong horses that he forsook...
...to come to this feast.
Those strong horses, young man...
...are nobody's business
but mine.
So, what could happen to them?
Nothing, if we flatter
Mr. Braulio's taste.
Hey Mechita, do you
have two cold ones there?
Oh, I sold out a while ago.
Well, what a gloomy party.
After coming all the way over
here, there's nothing to drink.
We'll change our clothes
in a minute...
...and go fetch the carton
we saw in the afternoon.
The guard has a long
time to go, anyway.
Come on, wait over here.
If you knew this pain...
This pain that is
destroying my soul.
Our future, you understand?
We are smaller than dust.
I've got a knot in here,
a knot.
Look.
At who? I don't see anyone.
Nobody. I'm done talking
to you, that's it.
Let's see that carton,
you stone soul.
Stone soul, me? Over a carton.
Here, I've got my coat anyway.
Didn't I say stone?
Can't you see number 1 33?
Yes, I can. I see it
and don't want to remember.
Was there ever a streetcar
as dignified as that one?
Quiet, please don't say that.
Come on, be a man.
Go, don't just stay there.
Do something important, Curls.
Do something important,
that's true.
Don't just stay there, Curls.
And call me by my name,
you know my name.
Juan Godìnez, isn't it?
So, what's wrong with "Curls"?
Isn't that what everybody calls you?
Aren't you the cashier on the
streetcar collecting the coins?
Well, then it's Curls.
They call me that
out of sheer envy.
No offend intended.
Am I to blame for...
...having been born
with curly hair?
With decent features, huh?
Well, you're making me sick
with all your showing off.
Curls, I mean Godìnez.
Changing the subject,
you think I haven't noticed...
...that change my name around?
You call me "tall ajas"
instead of Tarrajas.
- Tall, me? How tall?
- No.
- Why, when?
Stop giving me nick names.
Tarrajas, Tarrajas.
My father, may he rest in peace,
left behind his work and energy...
...for the good of the
family name, that's why.
Sorry, buddy.
I'm sorry.
Look.
Here you go.
That's where we learned
the trade.
They call it "square-wheels"
because it's old.
Truck drivers
try to smash into it.
There's no need for that,
there's no need.
Professor, what happened
in the play?
You should refund the tickets.
- Calm down, relax.
- Don't give me that.
Miss, didn't I ask you
to look after them?
They got away, professor.
Writing for people like
that is a waste of time.
Where could they be?
They went to get some beer,
they'll be right back.
I'm not worried about the devil.
I could stand in for him,
but the other one...
That's what we get for giving
God's role to anyone.
Listen, Lupita.
Why don't we go out to look at
the car? Then, you can decide.
- Let's go.
- Let's.
Don't worry, Lupita.
They must be out on the town.
I'm not worried,
it's not like he's a child.
Get in. Isn't this
better than a streetcar?
- It is, but the deal is off.
- Why?
Come on, you know
I respect you.
I'll take you to a lovely
hill overlooking the city.
And we'll listen to the radio.
That's nice.
- In that case, yes.
- In that case, no.
We're young,
we'll find another job.
We could even start a business
together, always together.
Thanks, brother.
But nothing eases this
pain I feel inside.
Hey, Tarrajas.
Why don't we push it
so it gets some fresh air?
Swell, that's exactly what
I was going to say.
Tarrajas, why don't we
take it to the dance?
We'll take everyone for a ride.
You said it, man.
I'm already in a rut,
I might as well do something.
Whatever you say, driver.
- There.
- A little more.
So, it wasn't me, it was you.
Let's call it quits,
what if something happens?
I've been a watchman for 20 years,
nothing has ever happened.
Especially now with the
inflation, I won't go until...
- It's up to you.
- I'll be responsible.
You said it was the inflation.
There's a lot of money going round.
- What's wrong with that?
- What I mean...
...is that it's both
the cause and the effect.
About the money going round...
...being more than the
merchandise that's sold.
That's why prices
keep going up.
That's easy to see.
And since the workers'
salaries haven't increased...
...the result is a lower
real value of income.
It's the pits.
So, that's inflation for you.
It causes poverty among
common people...
...while industrialists
and businessmen...
...keep getting richer
and fancier.
It's grateful, it's working
better than ever.
Look, it's getting late.
Oh, my.
Stop here.
The light's off,
they seem to be closed.
- Mr. Braulio must be coming now.
- Braulio who?
- The watchman.
- Yes, but he must be pretty drunk.
Hey, what's with them?
Looks like they're
coming from a party.
Go find out.
Yes, sure. I'm always
the one doing the dirty work.
I'll go then, open up.
You're always the chicken.
Oh, well, if it isn't
Juanito and Tarrajas.
Where are you going?
To the play, where else?
You've got to be jesting.
Returning nonchalantly...
...after standing everybody up.
Leave all that to the
faithful, right Curls?
How come you're here
at this hour?
Won't you give us a lift?
There's no transportation.
Frankly, that's why we came.
Home delivery, now that we can.
- Right, Tarrajitas?
- Sure thing, get in.
- Thanks.
- Thanks a lot.
Hey, you're not fooling me.
I bet you got in trouble.
My buddy here will fill you
in, dear brother-in-law.
Just who are you calling
brother-in-law?
Oh, that's just our style,
don't take it seriously.
I don't take anything seriously.
Come on, they're
going to eat all the food.
Let me explain, Lupita.
It's an insignificant manifestation
of trust by the company.
They entrusted us with the pilot
service as a distinction.
Pilot service, what's that?
I'll explain it later,
we're taking you home now.
You can't take me anywhere
you want whenever you want.
Come on, are we going
to stay here all night?
Juanito, Tarrajitas, hurry,
there won't be any food left.
The passengers are complaining.
Come on, get in. Get in, sis.
And now, Lupita.
Let me explain to you
and to the rest...
...what this pilot service is about.
We're not charging for the service.
We're treating everyone
with the utmost courtesy.
That's the pilot service...
...which will forever...
...educate the streetcar employees...
...and the clients,
which will surely reciprocate.
Now, for example.
I haven't even
asked the musicians.
How far are you going?
To the corner of Peru and Argentina,
if you please.
Mechitas, do you still live
near the slaughterhouse?
I do, Juanito.
To the slaughterhouse, driver.
SLAUGHTERHOUSE
Philharmonic gentlemen.
It's just a manner of speech.
Why don't you play
a song for us all?
- We've got time to spare.
- Why, of course.
As soon as we're done eating.
Curls, after all you aren't...
...as bad as I thought you were.
Thanks a lot.
Sticky fingers.
- Lupita, kick, kick.
- Thank you.
Just a kick.
MEXlCO ClTY SLAUGHTERHOUSE
- Thanks a lot, Juanito.
- Thank you, Mrs. Mechita.
We'll be seeing each other, huh?
- See you tomorrow, Mechita.
- Yes.
See you tomorrow, Mechita.
Oh my, look at what's coming.
I'm not opening the door.
That's really cute.
I don't know, I have this feeling.
So, pilot service, huh?
- Take the streetcar back.
- No.
Yeah, too bad.
They're expecting the gondola
that picks them up daily.
They're going to tell on us.
- You must be kidding.
- Open up, let them in.
We aren't charging for the service.
They're taking us just
for the fun of it.
Besides, it's warmer than the gondola.
Thanks, may the Lord repay you.
- Thank you so much.
- Thanks.
- Can I come on with this?
- Go ahead.
Divine Providence sent a
streetcar instead of the gondola.
It's freezing,
lucky we're cozy in here.
Come on, Mrs. Panchita.
You have it all, you don't
know what it feels like.
But us...
Too bad, but if they
sold your tongue in pieces...
- What?
- The whole city would be poisoned.
Stop blurting those things out.
- Come on, we're leaving.
- Get on, get on.
Mr. Prudencio asked you to wait.
He's coming with his people.
- Yes, but he better hurry.
- Okay.
Heavens.
Who's he?
The Duke of Ordanto.
Oh, come on.
Let's see.
- Mister, mister.
- Huh?
- A little present.
- No thank you, madam.
Don't disdain me,
they're delicious.
No, it's not disdain, but...
Take it, it's sincere.
Yes, ma'am, thank you, but...
The lady over here wants some.
- You, girl?
- Sure, thank you very much.
Miss, take these bears as well.
Much obliged, ma'am.
No ma'am, we're not charging.
Thank you very much, thank you.
Look at it.
- Oh, it's so cute.
- It's the Lord of the Column.
- I'm so scared.
- What?
That's why I told you to
slowly uncover the crucifix.
Maybe that will
make them fear God.
The fact that it's free
seems pretty fishy.
Nowadays, nobody gives
anything for free.
And at this hour.
Maybe they'll try to mug
us come a lonely spot.
- Really?
- May the Lord help us.
Excuse me, where are
you taking your icon?
To be blessed at the church.
Why at this hour?
Because it was around this
time that I invoked him.
He granted me the grace
of healing this girl.
Poor thing, what was wrong?
A miscarriage.
We're poor, and don't have
any money to buy indulgences.
I had seen these ladies before...
...always with their little icon.
So what?
It's theirs, they can
do with it as they please.
It's their conscience, not mine.
I don't want any fat
guy meddling in this.
- It's your problem.
- What's it to you?
- Quiet, busy bodies.
- Busy body.
Butt out, I wasn't going to
give anything but now I will.
May God almighty give you more.
- Heretic.
- Thanks.
- lmagine that, what a fatso.
We're here gentlemen,
you can get off now.
Well it's about time.
Come on guys, it's cold.
Go on, hurry up.
Let's go.
Who sent this one?
Looks like a nut.
- Watch that gut.
- Whoa.
Come right back and
no more fun?
Go to sleep, I'll be right back.
I haven't forgiven your
toying with the neighbors.
- Good night Lupita.
- Good night.
Are you sure the watchman
is at the warehouse?
I'm certain of it.
- Where do we put it at this hour?
- Well...
-...I don't know.
- OK, I got it.
We'll put it up in the
storage room.
We'll take it to the
shop early.
When we figure
the boss has arrived.
That's it, we'll figure
when the boss arrives.
And when the boss has arrived...
What do we tell him?
That we were testing the car.
He'll be okay with that.
- Tarrajas, Tarrajas.
- What's up?
Ask the Lord to
bless my soul.
Guadalajara, Guadalajara.
- You smell like wet beer.
- Stop joking.
We need to return the streetcar.
- What streetcar?
- The one we took last night.
Heavens, what have we done?
- Don't you remember?
- Now I do.
I can't stand this hangover.
I was dressed like a devil.
- My horns still hurt.
- Come on.
If they notice it missing
they'll think we stole it.
Wait, I've always been honest.
Yeah?
Well, sort of honest, anyway.
Come on, hurry up.
Could we get fired?
They would put us in jail.
Oh no.
But we still have time
to get into the shops.
With the other cars.
I'll get him to give us
the day off today.
Forget it, we can't get in.
What do we do now?
We'll have to wait.
Back up anyway.
Well, let's see what happens.
Holy virgin Barbara...
...dear God, we're in
deep this time.
Twisted again.
We have to go the whole route.
Let's get off and leave it.
Let them find out.
They'd catch us right away.
Everyone we drove last
night will say we did it.
I'll put the Special sign on.
Then no one will get on.
SPEClAL
Let me drive, we may get lucky.
- Tarrajas.
- What?
Remember that escape route for
gondolas?
I was thinking about that.
What if we take that route?
And go back the other way.
Okay, give me the keys.
Make the sign of the cross.
Wait, wait.
He won't be long, kids.
Maybe it's Lorenzana.
You have good eye sight.
Try to read the sign there.
Yes, miss, it says special.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, miss.
Then that's the one.
Sir...
Will you stop the traffic
for the kids to cross?
Children.
Order.
Run, run.
We waited over 1 5 minutes.
Here's the order,
climb on children.
Yes, miss.
Get on children, but don't push.
We thought you weren't
coming. Read it.
Going to Xochimilco, huh?
Yes, we make this field
trip twice each year.
So, only twice a year?
Yes sir, always by streetcar.
Because it's a very
safe way to travel.
Excuse me.
I told you.
It'll be worse if you argue.
There's a cloud
over our heads.
Take off.
Good-bye, good-bye.
Have fun.
Behave, children.
Let's have some order.
You'll have to take
turns at the window.
Guys, shall we
sing our anthem?
Yes, yes, yes.
Alright, alright.
Ready?
Yes.
One, two, three.
Get up sleepyheads,
it's time...
...for work...
...which is also
the time....
...that the cuckoo
is singing.
Get up, get up, the
cuckoo is singing.
Cuckoo, cuckoo.
What do we do with them now?
Anything but go
to the terminal.
The supervisor might be there.
If he see us, we're done for.
We'll do it when you're ready.
Let's pretend it broke down.
Let's dump the
kids and beat it.
Go to the back
of the line.
Now you can't say
it's hard to see.
Everything is
expensive nowadays.
- Just a second.
- Don't rob me.
The days of looting are back.
Of course, the
lady is right.
You take advantage of us.
- How so?
- Don't you know...
...that prices are capped?
Don't you know this
is a free market?
You can sell it
for up to 20 cents.
- Doubling profits.
- So people assume.
Wholesalers charge
us high prices.
Don't gouge us in turn.
Then there's no
dough for you.
That can't be, it's not fair.
I need to talk to you.
What is it?
Car 1 33 was missing
this morning.
Turns out that Curls
and your brother stole it.
They made the pilot service run.
They were finishing.
Pilot run, my foot.
They drank and were playing.
I thought they were
making it up.
Just being mischievous.
Well I'm afraid I'll
have to report them.
Please don't,
they'll get fired.
You too, for
not doing your job.
Better not say anything more.
I'll get them and
bring them right over.
What if the company notices?
But supposing they don't.
Be a pal, I'll go get them.
The scoundrels.
- Lupita.
- I was looking for you.
- For me?
- Yes.
I need a big favor from you.
Done deal.
You'll take me
to find my brother?
Sure, where is he?
We have to find that out.
We'll find him, hop in.
I just know he's on number 1 33.
Sit down, children.
He has no parents.
How would you know?
'Cause no one visits him.
His name's Lorenzana.
There are many
Lorenzanas here.
All of the orphaned ones.
Hey Petingo, don't push.
What's your name, Corpse?
What's yours, Petingo?
I'll get you, Rigoleto...
...for being so nosy.
These kids are like
little demons.
Why are you fighting?
Get over here.
Now stay there.
Yes sir.
Watching kids is a
lot of responsibility.
Yes, I see that.
Sometimes they are too much.
Last year...
...on a field trip to Xochimilco...
...they told me that
a kid had gone down.
Did he drown?
Well imagine.
It was a struggle
to get him out.
But since bad news
travels so fast...
Where are you going, boy?
When do we reach
the hospice?
You should've seen it.
Hundreds of mothers.
Trying to see the child's face.
Naturally.
Fortunately he wasn't
any son of theirs.
He was a...
Lorenzana.
What is that for, sir?
Watch it, Chocolate.
You heard, Chocolate.
How much longer?
Less than before.
Hey, where are we?
Churubusco.
What time is it?
Time for you not
to ask questions.
Hey.
Where will you pretend
it broke down?
At the next stop.
Will you teach us how to drive?
- You again?
- Show us how.
- Go on now.
- Oh, please.
- Hey Lorenzana.
- What?
There's your mom.
Go, go.
What happened?
We need to stop, we
burned some fuses.
Just wait a while.
Here comes, here comes.
Order.
Can we get off
while you repair it?
The children would like that.
Sure, they can get off.
I'll tell you when.
- Oh.
- Come on, do it in order.
Yeah, huh? Come on.
Everybody out.
Silence please, this
is a delicate scene.
The actors are rehearsing.
Please hurry, miss.
What are you looking at, son?
Come one, come on, let's go.
Step on it.
Teacher, the
streetcar is leaving.
Let's go.
Hey.
Wait, wait.
They must be just maneuvering.
Silence, please.
We'll film this one.
Okay that's enough,
let me drive.
What's going on?
Do you see what I see?
Your sister Lupe with Pablo.
Let me.
Open the door, please.
I said open, can't you hear?
Open.
I would never have guessed.
How did you find us?
That doesn't matter.
I guess you're both happy?
You messed up.
Don't get wrapped
up in this.
Especially with strangers.
You ingrate.
- The watchman wants to tell.
- No way...
What are you staring at?
It's your fault, looking
at you makes me angry.
Who's denying it?
Do you want my brother
to get fired...
...or put in jail?
And to thank you
on top of that.
Hey don't even joke
about jail. Dingbat.
Hey, what are you doing?
Don't butt in, you intruder.
Stay there until you rot.
This isn't about you.
Well, anyway.
Get back before the noise starts.
I mean now.
Are you going back with him?
- If you'll let me.
- No.
No, how dare you?
Open up, I want to get off.
- Open, can't you hear?
- Pipe down.
Stop.
I said stop.
Cut them off.
What's wrong?
I don't get it
Don't be an idiot,
cut them off.
I can't understand.
You're deaf.
Cut them off, they're
taking me by force.
Oh.
Moron, look what
you did to my car.
See, see what you've done?
They will beat you
up for this.
Now we're really in for it.
- What?
- Look.
It's an inspector.
Run him over.
Is this the special
to Xochimilco?
Yes, sir.
So why are there passengers?
She's my sister, sir.
- How do you do, miss?
- My pleasure, sir.
There are orders for this car...
Take the Niño Perdido route.
At San Antonio Abad crossing.
Yes, sir.
I'll change the sign.
Wait until we reach
the intersection.
Don't mind me.
Whenever you're ready,
I'm going along.
Good luck, and good-bye miss.
Good-bye, sir.
Give me the keys again.
Thanks for helping us.
Me?
Sure, you distracted him.
I did it for you,
but that's enough.
I'm leaving, you're on your own.
As you like.
I'm leaving, it's up to you.
Don't go, Lupita.
- What?
- Sit down.
Please, Mr. Julio.
Please, Mr. Arcadio.
No way, I have change.
Thank you.
Don't pay, there's still time.
Excuse me?
You can pay upon arrival.
Why is that?
It just is, that's all.
If you'd rather pay
now, simply don't pay.
No.
Never saw anything like it.
They're paying, that's stealing.
Hello.
An American, that's
all we needed.
Don't pay, miss.
- Why not?
- Because it's free.
Smells like communism to me.
What'd she say?
Communism.
Me pay.
Don't pay, miss.
- Me pay.
Okay, okay, then pay.
What's the matter with you?
- See? They're paying.
- Well, tough.
We have to do something.
Get off right here, please.
I don't want you implicated.
Now I'm staying to the end.
I'll take whatever comes.
I have no change, sir.
So what am I supposed to do?
You can pay tomorrow.
What?
Don't worry sir,
I'll pay your fare.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Did you see Mr. Enrique?
Such lack of responsibility.
Giving away car fare
as if it were theirs.
Just like that.
With everything so expensive.
Sure since it's not theirs.
Like the rest of the country.
But salaries are
payable no matter what.
They can strike when they like.
That's why anything
labor related...
...is repulsive, I can't stand it.
Some say they'll
rule the earth.
I'd rather die first.
Don't worry, Mr. Arcadio.
That won't be in your time.
Is something wrong?
Nothing, thanks.
Do you feel ill, sir?
It's Daddy Pinillos.
The same.
This damned asthma again.
And who are you?
Sir, I am Tarrajas.
Yes, your face is familiar.
Are you new here?
I am, in this line.
Are you usurping the
title of driver?
Let me explain it to you.
Okay? You'll see.
Hey, who's the sour lemon?
Daddy Pinillos, a very sneaky guy.
He can get God into trouble
.
What if he's no longer
with the company?
Why not tell him to buzz off?
Do it the friendly way.
Alright.
Hello, friend.
Hello Daddy Pinillos.
You don't drive well.
You didn't close that
when you drove through.
No matter, there was
hardly any traffic.
Regardless, regulations require it.
Train number 830.
Since when do you
have a conductor badge?
Well...
Why are you nervous?
Me?
Yes you; you seem scared.
Heh, heh, heh.
Back to your post so I can drive.
This also has its downs.
Especially for people like you...
...who haven't been
drivers for long.
Can't pull that on me.
All right.
Traffic, Pinillos speaking.
Oh, it's you boss?
Sorry to bother you.
But it's really important.
Two company guys and a woman.
They're driving a streetcar
behind our back.
It's number 1 33, sir.
1 33?
Just a moment.
Mister Benìtez.
This is serious, he's
calling the company.
Let's go.
I took care of
this yesterday.
Number 1 33 was sent
to be dismantled.
It's out of service for good.
Thank you Mr. Benìtez.
Pinillos, you're meddling...
...in things where
you shouldn't.
You're no longer an employee.
Your ongoing impertinence...
...is a waste of our time.
Pinillos.
He says a
streetcar was stolen.
I think his age is
affecting his brain.
What is it, "daddy" Pinillos?
Nothing son, nothing.
After dedicating my
life to the company...
...they retired me,
claiming my health...
...puts passengers at risk.
And now that I look
after the company...
...they say I'm meddlesome.
They'll see I'm
not an old fool.
Bye, Panchito.
Please, "daddy" Pinillos.
Where are we going now?
To a closed off street.
It's the only safe way.
Tell them they must get off.
And that this car is finished.
I tell them?
If you don't, who will?
You're a bad conductor.
I never spoke in public before.
Go on.
Hey.
Well, now what?
- What?
- Don't get nervous.
- Relax.
- Don't get nervous?
Ladies and gents, everyone off.
No, young man.
It's beyond our control.
Let's go to the depot.
And as you know, at the depot...
...they'll have to help us.
They can't just ignore
the public interest.
- I won't get off.
- Nor l.
This is impossible.
Same old thing.
Calm down now.
There's another car behind us.
Wait at the intersection.
Who will replace our down time?
It's not our fault.
- Nothing we can do.
- Step off now.
I told you we shouldn't
take a streetcar!
- Will it be a long wait?
- I don't know, ma'am.
What happened?
Come on, talk.
Wait.
Nothing so far.
- I spoke to the watchman.
- And?
He's more scared than you are.
So he hasn't told yet.
Not a word.
The company knows nothing.
But old Pinillos telephoned.
Maybe, but all is calm there.
Are we just going
to stay here?
We're safe here.
When the watchman arrives
we'll be at work.
No problem.
Hi, "daddy" Pinillos.
What is it?
Something of interest
for the company.
Have you seen 1 33
pass through here?
I don't think so.
No, it hasn't. What' up?
Something incredible.
That car is
operating irregularly.
I have to find it.
An irregular streetcar.
What's that?
None of your business.
And the terminals?
No, it won't go there.
There are dispatchers there.
Might be switching tracks.
I have to find it.
I have to find it. See you.
Okay, good luck.
- What are you doing?
- What Lupita?
- Me?
- Watch those hands.
- Abusive.
- Don't offend me.
I'll tell your brother.
So, you'll talk to my brother.
Why, you coward?
I'm not made of stone.
If you think that,
I can't face him.
If I break his trust, it's over.
Curls, you're exaggerating.
It's just that me being a woman...
I'm sorry Lupita.
Where are you going?
- But I thought...
- Sit here with me.
You're not mad?
I wasn't angry.
Just nervous...
...about what might happen.
Lupe, Lupita.
I'm sorry.
- Light, anyone?
- Here.
- No.
Okay then.
Evening, boss.
Let's unload. Why's that there?
It's been there for hours.
Bad stuff.
I think we're being tricked.
Unload anyway.
Start, boys.
Do you have a light?
I'm out and can't find one.
Strange for it to be here, huh?
This track is not in use.
Oh. We're just waiting.
For what?
Actually, we're taking
a little break.
Work can get you tired at times.
Thanks for the light.
Hold up pal, what's the hurry?
Weren't you taking a break?
Don't leave, let's party.
Really? Hey, thanks.
Big load, huh?
They must be heavy hitters.
What's in the cargo?
Can't you read? What's it say?
Oh, I hadn't noticed.
- Well, thanks.
- Careful.
It's corn.
Go on in, buddy.
Let's talk in private.
- But I have to go.
- I said go in.
Pick it up.
Go ahead, friend.
Hey, not so fast, buddy.
Trying to pull a fast one?
How so, sir?
Come on, don't pretend.
He thinks we're as stupid as he is.
- What?
- I've no time to argue.
- There's two of you right?
- Right.
How shall we resolve this?
As friends or not?
Definitely as friends.
- Hey, let go.
- Leave that corn.
- Let go.
- You think it's for free?
You looking for a fight?
You want to fight, creep?
Why are you getting in there?
Let her go.
Get out of here, go on, beat it.
Don't push me.
Run, the cops'll be here soon.
Bad luck.
Things were going well.
Where to now?
I'm tired of being on the move.
You think I like it?
We can't go on like this.
Seven o'clock is not far.
Half an hour isn't bad.
The fuzz is after us.
We're done for.
Let's make it count.
Come on.
So you thought you'd
get rid of me?
You're in for it.
No need to be angry.
No need?
Who said you could take it?
It was stolen.
We're getting tired
of you, old man.
You're not an employee.
You're just making trouble.
Holy Virgin of Guadalupe.
Boys, don't be dumb.
Respect his white hair.
His white hair.
I can handle this pair.
You gangsters.
Gangsters?
Enough already, do it for me.
Cowards.
Thank the lady.
Take the car.
But no more arguing.
I'll take it, son.
With us inside.
There's no stolen train.
You'll pay dearly for this.
We're going to the company.
For the love of the Lord.
Are you okay?
See, "daddy" Pinillos?
Come on over here.
It's okay, it's okay.
Let go.
Somebody drive.
But straight to the depot.
Please help me.
What'll the company do for you?
All the guys will
single you out.
For being a snitch.
Come on, please.
Stop begging him.
Looks like his mind is made up.
Then let's let things
take their course.
Don't worry.
I took it, I'm to blame.
Are you nuts?
Think I'll let you take the rap?
We both did it.
Stop and open the door.
Sorry gramps, this is our stop.
I drove streetcars
before you were born.
- Bums.
- A century ago.
We can carry you if need be.
Thought you could beat an old man?
Straight to the compa...
Pinillos, don't do this.
- He's cold.
- Are you sure?
God, what do we do now?
Hey, come here.
- What is it?
- He's hurt.
What's going on?
This passenger got ill.
He got ill, or did you make him?
Let's see.
Any contusions?
When I saw him I felt...
...something bad would
happen to him.
- He was pale.
- As a sheet.
Still breathing.
To the drugstore.
He needs a doctor.
Hold on.
You wait here.
And what if a car comes?
Let them wait.
Curls, what if the old man dies?
It's up to God.
We didn't kill him.
But, what if?
While they investigate.
What happened?
Streetcar accident.
Let's see.
Do we have to pay?
- Any family with him?
- None.
He's alone, maybe just fainted.
Let's see what we can do.
I'll call the Red Cross.
I don't think you need to.
I'll try to revive him.
He'll react to this right away.
Hey, look.
Must be in a hurry.
If he can run...
...we're out of here.
Thank God he's okay.
We thought he was a goner.
"Daddy" Pinillos will bury us all.
Shall I see you home?
No, leave me, go away.
I'm warning you as gentlemen.
This isn't over yet, you'll see.
Taxi.
The streetcar depot in lndianilla.
Here you are, sir.
Okay.
Mr. Pinillos has
waited a long time.
Let him wait or leave.
- Hold on.
- Thanks.
- Good bye Mr. Manuel.
- Good bye.
The meeting is over at one.
- Hope to see you.
- I'll be there.
Mr. Manuel.
Pinillos.
I forgot about you.
Forgive my insistence.
This is a grave matter.
Can it wait until tomorrow?
It must be now, sir.
A streetcar was stolen.
You don't say!
I do say, and I have the details.
- Come in.
- After you, Mr. Manuel.
Did you hear?
He's nuts, how can that happen?
- He said it.
- Wait.
Can our company...
...be so easily fooled?
No sir, but I was
on that streetcar.
And the crooks confessed.
This is absurd.
I mean no harm.
I'm protecting the company.
I swear this is all true.
To make you stop this...
...I'll show you
we make no mistakes.
Come along.
You'll see that 1 1 3
is in its place.
You did say 1 1 3, right?
Yes sir, exactly: 1 1 3.
- There you have it.
- Huh?
What do you say?
They must've just brought it.
These are the crooks.
May I help you, sir?
Glad you're here.
Has it left today?
No, it hasn't moved from here.
Do you think we'd dare to...
And the company's so organized.
How can a car leave unknown?
I totally agree.
You agree, sir?
Don't you?
- No sir.
- Look, Pinillos.
A streetcar cannot be stolen.
They travel on rails...
...belonging to the company.
Stealing means taking away.
But I know they took it.
Excuse me, Pinillos.
Who knows more than Management?
But we appreciate your interest.
Stop by the cashier tomorrow.
Good night, Pinillos.
Mr. Manager, sir.
I'm not looking for a handout.
But now everyone, from...
...managers down to employees...
...watchmen and workers all hide...
...their tracks and incompetence.
Not another word, sir.
You don't want it known.
You've no right to meddle
in the company.
You're not an employee.
But you do receive a pension.
A pension.
I will not allow your insults.
Braulio.
- Sir.
- Escort him please.
This was the story.
For some, uneventful.
Ignored by the majority,
but memorable to its stars
who return to the simple
rhythm of their lives
as their steps fade
into the streets.
They have so often walked
ever deeper
into their still unknown future.
Meanwhile,
the city continues to
spawn and create
thousands of different stories.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS.org