Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS.org today
Ascent to Heaven
The only agricultural
exploitation of this town,
which we will call San Jeronimito,
located on the coast
of the state of Guerrero,
are coconut trees.
Oil is extracted from
the white coconut pith,
which is then used by
several industries.
The occupants of these
humble dwellings
are almost all wealthy
owners of several
hundred palm trees.
The people of the coast maintain,
with their exaggerated charm,
that a coconut tree yields
as much as a milk cow.
There is no church in the village.
Thus, the inhabitants
preserve their tradition
of celebrating weddings
with a trip
to a heavenly island
situated one mile off the coast.
Spending the night
on this deserted island...
... consecrates the newlywed's union...
... who must then be forgiven
by the bride's mother...
... before embarking on the trip.
Let's see the daily
arrival of the vehicle...
... that brings news from the world...
... to this isolated corner.
Careful, don't touch that garment.
It has to be white.
Take care of it, Mrs. Linda.
Don't worry, Silvestre.
I'll take it.
Look, such lovely
organdie endives.
It looks just like the dress...
...worn by Gen. Mendez's daughter.
Yes, but you'd rather your
daughter had worn a...
...rough cotton dress instead...
...of eloping.
Go ahead, Mrs. Linda.
Albina must be dressed by now.
If you're in such a hurry, go ahead.
I'll pick up the train.
- Hurrah for the newlyweds.
- Hurrah.
Hurrah!
- Hurrah for the newlyweds.
- Hurrah.
Hurrah for the newlyweds.
- Hurrah for the newlyweds.
- Hurrah.
Hurrah for the newlyweds.
Hurrah.
I have a mind to keep
you here all day.
If you think we're happy,
you're mistaken.
I doubt you can support yourself,
let alone a wife.
You're both so young.
Come on, Mrs. Clara,
forgive them.
- Yes, yes.
- Forgive them.
Forgive them.
The food's getting cold,
we're hungry.
Let them get up, woman.
Oliverio's mother is ill.
I could keep them here
until they grow roots.
But...
You should thank God.
You can get up now.
Mother, I'm so happy.
I know Albina is your whole life.
I'll try to be
a worthy son to you.
I know you'll be happy,
you have our blessings.
Go on, go. Go let the people in.
Come in, she forgave me.
Hurrah for the newlyweds!
Hurrah for the newlyweds.
Are you happy?
I am, Oliverio. I wouldn't
trade places with anybody.
But a wedding in Mexico City
would have been nice.
And spending our honeymoon
at your mother's house...
...in Portales.
Will it ever be ours?
- Who knows.
- To have such a large house.
And spend our wedding night
on a desert island.
That's the custom.
- I'm anxious to go.
- What about me?
With you, the island
is like a palace.
Get ready for the worst.
It's Felipe, my brother.
Mother got worse.
I said you shouldn't
have gotten married today.
It was mother,
she asked me to.
Thanks to that you
may not see her alive.
Tie the boat and come.
If something terrible happens...
...we'll have to decide
about the property.
Don't say that now.
It's got to be said sometime.
I won't give up my share.
Your soul is poisoned.
Making plans...
...while mother is ill.
Don't insult me.
I'm the eldest, I'll decide.
She's still here to decide.
What if she gives
it all to the boy?
We'll do what she decides.
It's her call, isn't it?
All right, Chuchito, all right.
Go play, go on. Go play.
Are you feeling better, mother?
I won't make it this time.
You have many years ahead.
But if something should happen...
...God forbid, God forbid...
...trust me to settle the property.
Did you think I'd fall that easy?
I didn't think anything, mother.
It's just in case.
You know I'm the son
who loves you the most.
Yes, I know. I know you.
You're closing in.
I just want to fix things.
To solve this.
The big coconut tree field
can go to Felipe.
It's fair to give Oliverio...
...the boats and the refrigerator...
...since he just got married.
The other field is for Chuchito.
I'll settle for the
little house in Portales.
Not because of what it's worth.
I have aspirations
and want to move to the city.
Mother.
Mother, are you feeling worse?
No, but leave me alone.
Give that to me, how dare you.
Look. Such a straight face.
Get out, you'll wake mother up.
And don't come here anymore.
Oliverio, my son.
He's getting married, forget him.
Not quite, here I am.
Thank God you're here, son.
Juan, go do your chores.
You too, Felipe.
Albina... go look
for Chuchito.
Leave me alone with Oliverio.
Yes, Mrs. Ester.
I'm sorry, son. I interrupted...
...your wedding night.
But I'm not feeling well.
Don't say that,
you've been worse.
You know I won't make it.
Come closer.
I know only you are fond of Chuchito...
...and you won't let
those thugs hurt him.
I want the house in Portales...
...to be his.
He must go to school in the city.
- Be somebody.
- Yes, mother.
Do it in memory of your sister...
...who died giving birth to him.
I'll do it for you and for Chucho.
I love him as if he were my son.
But you should put it in writing.
My siblings won't respect words.
Go fetch the delegate
to dictate my will.
I'm on it, mother.
Chuchito.
- Where are you going?
- I'll be right back.
What will it be, Mr. Esteban?
I don't mean to snub you, but...
...a delegate shouldn't
drink too much.
One for the road. Come on.
To drown our woes.
A mother cannot be replaced.
Don't be a vulture, brother.
God willing, mother will survive.
I've always been strong.
Darling mother.
I can still see her
at the San Jose fair.
In such good health.
Hey, have you seen Eladio?
He was in my pocket a minute ago.
Not anymore. Look, he's gone.
You're hilarious.
He's had me waiting for an hour.
A girl like you shouldn't wait.
- Shall I help?
- Leave me alone.
Look who's here. Where's the bride?
- Hello, Raquel.
- A sight for sore eyes.
- Oliverio.
- Buddy, have a drink.
- It's no time to party.
- Mr. Esteban...
My mother wants a word with
you. Please, come.
What are you up to, evil son?
Disturbing her for your greed?
No brotherly quarrels.
You shouldn't disturb her now.
I never evaded a lady's call.
It's my duty.
You're not going.
Go away, take your wife with you.
You didn't hesitate
to get married now.
- Are you going or not?
- He isn't.
- No.
- Quiet.
I'm the authority, I'll decide.
You're the eldest, right?
- You don't want me to go.
- No.
Then, I won't. I'm staying.
You'll be responsible
if anything happens.
Sure, I'll be responsible.
What could happen?
Hey, Oliverio.
- What do you want?
- To talk.
Oliverio.
You took so long.
Isn't Mr. Esteban coming?
I couldn't find him.
He's out of town for the week.
I feel terrible.
Now you look yellow.
Please Albina, the spoon.
Look, Oliverio.
Why wait for delegate Esteban?
Go to Petatlan...
...and bring Counselor Figueroa
to draw up will.
Why go so far, mother?
Counselor Ocaña is in Acapulco.
It's not the same.
Counselor Figueroa...
...took charge since your father.
And in the meantime?
Don't worry.
I'll be strong enough to wait.
Go, and don't tell your siblings.
All right, mother.
The bus leaves at six.
Take a nap, son.
I also want to get some rest.
Yes, Oliverio.
Go to sleep. I'll wake you up.
Let's go to Petatlan together.
Stay and take care of mother.
What if something happens?
Nothing will happen,
I'll be back as soon as I can.
Oliverio.
What?
Take my mirror.
Don't break it...
...it's bad luck.
- It's safe here.
- Let's see if it's true.
A cigarette, doll.
Yes, Congressman. Thank you.
Come here.
Oh, boy.
Now me, Silvestre, now me.
You're acting like a child.
I can't play with you
the same way.
Careful, don't hurt the lady.
- Hey, Silvestre.
- Well, well.
It's about time.
When is the baby due?
I'm going to Petatlan...
...to see Dr. Martinez.
- Yes, sir.
He's one of the best.
- Are you traveling, too?
- Yes.
You shouldn't, should you, Feliza?
After what happened
to your sister Jacinta.
I'm here if you need anything.
- Thanks.
- Careful, careful.
I'm going with your mother.
Wait until the bus leaves.
It won't until it fills up.
When one's in a hurry, things stall.
Don't worry, I'll look after her.
Good-bye, my dear.
You're so corny, Oli.
Is that envy or a compliment?
Envy? I have them by the dozen.
Influential, like me.
Ha.
I like ripe fruit, not rotten.
Your influence just wilted.
You'll see.
I want to see my granddaughter.
Can I pay when I get back?
You know I always say yes, Mr. Nemesio.
Everything's on paper.
When justice is finally done in Mexico...
...and I get my land back...
...you'll get every penny.
- Much obliged, Mr. Nemesio.
- Thanks, boy.
Does it have to be full to leave?
Well, I have to make a profit.
We're all in a hurry.
- Fine, Congressman.
- Good bye.
How much?
Four tickets will be enough.
Give me the change.
- Fine, Mr. Eladio.
- Come on, Congressman.
You first. Go ahead.
That's okay.
- Hurrah for Mr. Eladio.
- Hurrah, hurrah.
Your change, Congressman.
Thanks, Silvestre.
- Sit over there.
- Get moving.
- Ready?
- Let's go.
- Step on it, man.
- Step on it.
Well, I'll be darned.
We have a flat.
You said it loud enough.
We're not deaf.
- Where's the spare?
- On top.
Come on.
Things can't go on
like this forever, and...
...when my situation changes...
...if there's anything
I can do for you...
I heard you'll be appointed judge.
In a matter of days.
Despite my forlorn appearance...
...the governor is a friend of mine...
...and the president studied
with a friend's friend.
Oh, that's good.
Here, let me light it for you.
Why let a cigarette go out?
To get some courtesy back, doll.
Do you want to put it out?
Patience, you'll be back in time.
Perhaps, but it's so slow.
A slow stride is
better than a tiring one.
- If I were the driver...
- You'd crash the bus.
Look at those curves, you
always lose control there.
Since when?
I'm not a handle.
It's all I can hold on to.
You're used to being supported.
Slopes frighten me, you see.
Back off, back off.
Buy yourself a scapular.
The fog looks like cotton.
Look.
The Congressman feels
safer beside Silvestre.
You don't feel well, do you?
I'm already sick.
Look out for that pothole.
You think I'm not looking.
That rock!
I told you, you fool.
Don't bother me, it's distracting.
Too many people in the kitchen
spoil the pan of chicken.
If it weren't for this wooden leg...
...I would be walking by now.
And the little angels
are so quiet.
Such innocence.
Move your arm, I can't drive.
Careful, please be careful.
You'd better stop
until the fog clears up.
We'd lose more time.
Others are in a hurry, too.
He keeps bothering me!
We all need to get there fast.
It hurts a lot, doesn't it?
I feel terrible.
You should have come sooner.
I think it's close.
Calm down, calm down.
Now we're in for it,
here comes another car.
Almonds, sugar coated peanuts,
candy and chewing gum.
- Like this, mother?
- Be quiet.
- Watch out.
- I couldn't be more careful.
Please, back up.
We're in a hurry.
Hey buddy, back up.
Let's go.
I'd like to sir, but I can't.
- My reverse doesn't work.
- What?
Back up or I'll make you.
This junk couldn't even be towed.
Let's see.
All right, let's go.
Pull.
Harder on reverse.
Harder, man.
We need a pulley.
Yes, Congressman.
I'm familiar with this.
Back up, and it'll be solved.
Look, Mr. Eladio.
Fidencio, wait. Let's get off.
No, I don't want to. Stop it.
You pig. You're always sniffling...
...but never blow your nose. Creep.
Gross, snot.
Oh, my, what happened?
Silvestre, get off and take the kids.
Call some women to help with Feliza.
Go on, hurry.
Turn around, don't look.
Women! I need two.
Hurry, quickly.
- They're coming.
- Hurry.
Come on, I'll take you.
What do you need?
Get in, no questions.
Come on.
This happened to
me years ago...
...on a boat, and I'm fine.
Hurry. Don't just stand there.
And don't let any men in here.
- Move, I'm going in.
- You can't.
It's the honey,
I need to wash it down.
I need my bottle.
No, you son of a...
- Oh, Oliverio, Oliverio.
- What?
Look...
- Really?
- Yes.
I'm sorry. I'll see what I can do.
Do you know what's going on?
We don't have a place for the show.
Too bad, find a way.
We made the trip, it's too late.
Ma'am, everything is fine.
- Do you want to come?
- Heavens.
Mother, let me see it.
Stay right here, girl.
- Stay here.
- Oh, child.
What are you up to,
pretty little bud?
I'm taking this to Feliza.
Don't let her mistreat you.
Don't get burnt.
- What if I do?
- You'll burn me, too.
You've got experience, child.
Experience?
You bet. Do you want to try?
I'm burning for you,
and you're so evasive.
Put some time aside for me.
Those squeaking doors.
Get someone to oil them.
- I think it was a boy.
- A boy?
It's a boy, it's a boy.
It's about time, so many girls.
I'm going to cry my eyes out.
Hospitals with all their staff...
...can't pick flowers like this.
- How's the mother?
- Just fine.
She just wants to go home.
Tell the men to climb on board...
...to help her get off.
He sure is cute, look at that...
He's so cute.
He's cute, isn't he?
Silvestre, I'm helping too.
- She's heavy.
- Come on, come on.
- Help me, Silvestre.
- Yes, Oliverio, let's see.
Be careful. Get a good
grip on her shoulders.
- Slowly.
- I'll hold her legs.
- Come on.
- Careful.
We'll take her.
We'll try to make her
as comfortable as possible.
Marta, Marta, get out
so the lady is comfortable.
The baby's father will be thrilled...
...when he gets back from the mine.
Imagine when Albina
surprises you like this?
Bring me my son.
- Mrs. Linda, bring me the boy.
- My son.
Cover him up, he'll get sick.
Give him to his mother.
Congratulations.
Give me those boxes, girl.
Where's the blanket?
Let's see that smile.
Congratulations.
I'd love to be his godfather.
I have lots of godchildren.
But he will be my favorite.
I want to see the cutie.
Move. Don't pester the lady.
- He has hair, look.
- Thanks.
Isn't he just like his father?
Tough luck. You're
as ugly as him.
Let's go, it's getting late.
Take care of him, he's lovely.
- Shut the door.
- I'm going to cover him.
Yes.
Get in, it's getting late.
What did I say?
See how fluid it is now?
Yes, but you can't deny
there was an accident.
Sure, but in exchange
of a new life.
Huh, boy.
Cheer up, everything will be fine.
The rain didn't fill the river.
We'll never get ahead like this.
Animals and people together.
- How nice.
- This is a drag.
Civilization. I don't understand.
We have a right to use
public services no matter what.
It's mine.
- Hit him, get him.
- It's mine.
Enough, stop fighting.
Get out of here.
Damn it.
Stay still, you're acting
like chili peppers.
Now you're really going to get it.
What if you had broken my leg?
- So what?
- I'd be worse off.
Well, you could buy another one.
Settle down, settle down.
Let's see what your
godfather brought you.
Godfather.
Again, compadre.
That's what we're here for.
What happened?
It's like with the slippers.
They get their feet wet
before the dance.
Why won't it start?
I'll take a look, must be the rocks.
Come on, Mr. Pedro.
Help that man who fell.
You're filthy,
you need a bath.
Let's take a dip in that pond.
I think I could use it, I'm coming.
Don't worry.
We'll get the bus out
thanks to my compadre.
This darn bus is like a pig
it loves mud.
Don't get mad.
Let's take a dip, you'll relax.
I understand that you're sad.
Poor thing.
Married and single.
I don't need your pity.
Sure. Albina is very pretty...
...but she isn't with you.
That's why I want to go back.
Come on, don't play hard to get.
Come on.
... has skinny legs...
Lorenza
... but pull the bus out first.
Animal traction is obsolete.
We're an industrialized country.
Look over there.
My train of oxen can
pull it out, Mr. Eladio.
Why go so far?
You're all so close-minded.
- Enemies of progress.
- Yes, Mr. Eladio.
- The oxen are too slow.
- Yeah, but they're sure.
- I'll get the tractor.
- Go on.
Tell me, do you dislike me?
No, why?
Because you act
like you don't know me.
I'm treating you as always.
Yeah, but now we're not as always.
Oh, you're so faithful.
Poor Albina, she has no
idea who she married.
It seems you don't either.
What's wrong with her?
It's not about her.
It's about you.
Pull that.
Up.
- Pull.
- Harder.
Pull that.
Come on, you bum, push.
Stop loafing around.
You do it, if you're so savvy.
I'll be dog-gone.
Now Mr. Eladio's really done it.
Second gear, to your left.
Leave me alone,
I know what I'm doing.
Not by the edge.
Not by the edge, you dunce.
I told you to move
to the left, stupid.
All right, to the left it is.
This politician is a show-off.
Always fussing about.
Back up.
I'll be damned, man.
If those are his speeches,
he's sure to win.
Thought it was easy to
do two things at a time.
We're stuck.
Look at the bus.
She manipulates others
besides her father.
Give me those cheeks.
That's why I'm your godfather.
Close-minded nitwits.
The animal traction
got tired and left.
Let's go, Silvestre.
Please, it's late.
Let's all go.
Hey.
Don't forget about me.
It had to be you.
Did you want to leave me here?
Oh, you're such a nuisance,
what a pest.
Not a pest.
- More like a plant.
- No wonder you want to grow roots.
Were you thinking of me?
Pay up, Rosalio.
I may have dough, but
I'm not your relative.
What?
I'll ask you when
I hang my hat on them.
You think everyone's like you.
The guy at the wheel.
To the crossroads.
Are you selling chickens?
Not ordinary livestock.
I only deal Legore...
...Rhode Island...
...and others from my catalogue.
Tell me when you have
feathers for my mattress.
Silvestre, it's late, let's go.
Come on, let's.
Let's all climb on the bus.
Mother, at least give me some bread.
- I knew you had some.
- Stop pestering.
- Do you want a bite?
- No, thanks.
Well.
- You sound like a...
- Spaniard, from Madrid. Mr...
Nemesio Alvarez y Villalbazo,
at your service.
- Miguel Suarez, at your service.
- Pleasure.
- What do you do?
- I sell hens.
- Where are they?
- Here.
Right here?
It's cheaper than cages.
Those are some nice looking hens.
Are they expensive?
Well, they yield a lot.
There's no better business
than a hen farm.
If you're interested.
As long as I'm not done
justice and recover my land...
...I can't think of it.
Oh, man.
They may think I'm lazy.
If I don't get some sleep,
we'll be dead.
Don't worry,
I'll sleep on the luggage.
Stop loafing around.
I have to be in Petatlan early.
You said we'd make it on time...
...to catch the bus
to Chilpancingo.
I can't stand it anymore.
Let me drive, I'm not sleepy.
Whatever.
I'm going to sleep.
If it weren't for you...
...what a country this would be.
Everybody doing their own will.
No wonder we don't get ahead.
I'm going to file a complaint.
This man here is the
complaining kind.
And he hasn't confronted
real problems yet.
Always among hens, all he
does is cluck and complain.
Yes, but like a rooster.
People like you are our doom.
Mom, look at him snore.
He even whistles.
Like a train, huh?
Yes, son. Come here.
Good morning.
Look at her twisting
like a caterpillar.
Move. Give me that.
If you broke my mirror...
...with all that bouncing around...
...you won't live to tell about it.
Heavenly Jesus.
What a life, brother.
They pay you for sleeping.
Would you like your chocolate, sir?
I can see Petatlan.
Who said we're going to Petatlan?
Aren't we going to Petatlan?
Yes, we are.
But first, we'll drop by my...
...mother's ranch in time
to serenade her.
Today's her birthday.
Everyone's invited.
- Thank you.
Happy birthday to you...
... happy birthday to you...
... we've come to sing...
... to beautiful girls like you.
Wake up, dear, wake up
- The sun has risen.
- Sorry, man.
But what would you do if...
...it were your mother's birthday?
I don't know, my mother is dying.
Don't get depressed.
Even if you arrive early, you...
...can't return to San Jeronimito today.
Besides, the lawyer
won't even be up yet.
There's a motorcycle waiting for me.
Just a few yards
from my mother's house.
I hope nobody leaves
without toasting for her.
We'll be delighted.
What's your mother like?
She's a true beauty.
Happy birthday to you...
... happy birthday to you...
You know I wish for
you the best, mother.
Thank you, dear.
Did you hear, mother?
Get up, today's a great day.
The only day I can't get up early.
... wake up, dear...
There's Silvestre.
I have to pretend I'm asleep.
... the birds are chirping...
... and the moon has risen.
What a beautiful morning...
Open up, here is my
loving mother's son...
- Come on.
- Oh, Silvestre, my son.
Heavens. Oh.
You're tearing me apart, boy.
I'm starving.
As idle and glutton as always.
Mother.
My passengers are
going to accompany us.
Come here. Come in.
Ma'am, accept my most
sincere congratulations.
Pleased to meet you...
...and honored by the invitation.
Mother, Mr. Eladio...
...is our candidate for Congress.
Thank you so much.
The table is served. Come in.
- Sit down.
- Thank you, ma'am.
You better behave.
- Grandfather.
- My darling.
You must be dying to be together...
...after so many days apart.
- How have you been, Mr. Nemesio?
- Fine, Mrs. Tita.
Many happy returns.
With our best wishes.
- Thank you.
- Chocolate, Mr. Nemesio.
Don't trouble yourselves, Justina.
Don't be shy, don't be shy.
Tend to them, Justina.
A table for you and your girl.
Come, this way.
Have a nice day, Mrs. Sixta.
Thank you, sonny.
- How's your mother?
- Very ill when I left.
I may not see her alive again.
God willing, you will...
...and she will soon get well, son.
The chocolate is getting cold.
- Please sit down.
- Yes, please sit.
Please sit down.
Sit down, son.
- Will you come here?
- Sit there.
Move that hat.
Thank you, but this chair
is too low for me.
I'd rather sit between two thorns.
Don't compare me.
I'm thorn enough to poke
whoever bothers you, love.
- You took the biggest one.
- It's mine.
Did I teach you those manners?
Calm down, there's more.
I'll be.
Carmelita...
...I asked you to behave.
Don't dip it.
We're among family, granddaddy.
That's precisely why.
Out of respect to this house
and their kindness...
...I want you to behave.
Don't take this.
Oh, thanks.
Where are you.
Quiet. We want to hear
the congressman speak.
- Speak.
- Yes, speak.
In the history of all peoples...
...mothers have always
occupied the first place.
Nobody knows who came first.
The chicken or the egg.
The agent can tell us that.
Young man...
...just because I sell them...
...it doesn't mean I'm a chicken.
I'm serious.
Excuse the interruption.
Continue, madam.
It's moving to see this example...
...which should be the reflection
of every good child.
So, in memory of my beloved mother...
...and of yours, if you'll allow me...
...as well as in honor
of the birthday girl...
...Id like to pick the
petals of the anthology...
...threaded by the lucid
and distinguished conception...
...of this great bard,
Pepe Radilla...
...tireless glory of
contemporary literature...
...and radiant sun of our state.
This is getting sour.
If I weren't decent and didn't
respect where I am...
...and the date we're celebrating,
my dear cripple...
...Id be stirring your
curdled milk by now.
San Marcos is famous
For its beautiful women
Acapulco also has its share
of different little faces
Beloved woman of San Marcos
Come on, come on, come on
Bravo.
Come on, come on. Everybody
Hurry up, hurry up. Come on.
The whole crowd. Come
on, everybody.
Now, ladies and gentlemen.
We have a sight.
This beautiful Mexican ranch,
as you see.
Won't you speak to us in Spanish?
Alright Mr. Canvas,
alright.
Look, gentlemen.
There you can see...
...a typical little Mexican ranch.
Poor, but clean.
And very joyful.
We got here just in time.
You can use your half-hour rest...
...to witness a typical fiesta.
A typical fiesta.
Magnificent, magnificent.
Wonderful.
Don't get into trouble,
no English spoken.
Ok, let's go. Come
on, everybody.
Come on.
Beloved woman of San Marcos,
lovely woman of San Marcos
What's up, Raquel?
Aren't you happy with Jeronimito?
I'll bet my name on it.
All right, people.
Tough luck.
- Make yourselves at home.
- Thank you.
Excuse me.
Make yourselves at home.
Mr. Johns, come on.
I'm not from San Marcos
I'm from San Jeronimito
Tell me, any one of you
If you've seen prettier eyes
Beloved woman of San Marcos,
lovely woman of san Marcos
Mr. Eladio...
Keep an eye on your little chick.
Somebody may steal her away.
They would if they could.
Here comes my trine.
Not only the women of San Marcos
Are pretty and lovely
Carmelita, take your
elbows off the table.
And eat slowly.
Don't stuff your face,
it's bad manners.
Were you well tended, Mr. Nemesio?
Service was great, Mrs. Sixta.
Just like every time I come.
Do you know when Silvestre
is returning?
Tomorrow, I suppose. Today...
That's too bad.
Today is the last day
of Carmelita's vacation.
Look, amigo.
Would you like to sell my hat?
How could I? Sell it yourself.
You don't have a nice hat.
Here, buy mine.
Ten pesos.
I don't want your hat.
I want this.
You wear a bonnet, I wear a hat.
Don't pester me, mister.
Excuse me?
I don't deserve to have
the mother I do, Mrs. Linda.
She suffered so much
since she became a widow.
To handle a lost soul like me.
Come, come now.
Who is your mother's pride?
No, no, no.
She would say that out of kindness.
She will go straight to Heaven...
...fully dressed to her shoes.
Where are you going in
that state, Silvestre?
I'm a man, mom.
To keep my promise.
I have a debt.
A debt? Who do you owe?
My friend.
I have to take him to Petatlan.
You will stay right here.
Look, Silvestre.
You know my hurry.
Lend me your truck.
If you ask for my life...
...my life I would give to you.
Take it.
It's all yours.
Will you look at that.
Candidate. It's ten o'clock.
Ten?
Damn, the motorcycle isn't here yet.
Who told me to act like a priest...
...snooping in none of my business?
I thought this would
happen, Congressman.
That's what you think.
I've got the victory.
Except the rally won't
be the same without me.
Hey.
Raquel, where are you going?
I'm spending the night
in Petatlan, bye.
You've been warned.
They stole her from you, Congressman.
Ascent to Heaven port
Leave me alone.
Come on.
I've always liked you, Oliverio.
But now you're electrifying me.
Simmer down.
Oh. I like them better gruff.
Stop horsing around,
we're going to lose control.
That's what I want, to lose control.
I'm in no mood for jokes.
Hey, don't get so jumpy.
Can't you see you're not alone?
You're reckless.
Sure.
I'm worth nothing to you,
you don't care if you kill me.
After humiliating me for so long.
What woman would risk so much?
Say something, you sissy.
All because of this rain.
Yeah, blame the rain.
Stop playing the fool.
Let go.
What a brute.
It's all your fault, you tramp.
When the baker is no good,
he blames the flour.
Don't give me that nonsense.
You're right to be mad, darling.
Do with me whatever you want.
When we get to the top
I'm going to teach you...
If you were a man...
...you would have done that already.
You'll see soon enough.
We're at the top. Now what?
Weren't you going to teach me,
little jasmine flower?
I'm going to teach you
to respect me.
Shameless tramp.
Come on.
It was fate.
I was so wrong in
throwing myself at you.
Hit me.
Is Mr. Eladio Gonzalez here?
- Who? The candidate?
- Yes.
- I need to see him.
- You'll find him at that house.
Thank you very much.
Your junk won't make it back.
Oliverio is one of the
best drivers around.
Perhaps, but with all the thunder
and dynamite he's carrying...
You'll have to collect
his body with a shovel.
Don't be so gloomy, Mr. Gonzalez.
Why, Mr. Nemesio?
Poor Silvestre.
Is it allowed to take
dynamite on buses?
We travel with children, and...
It's a manner of speech.
I see.
Hi, Pedro.
Just a minute, please.
Who would know that Eladio...
...the son of a simple water carrier...
...would consider being
Father of the Homeland?
Buckets are like...
...like...
Life is like the buckets
of a water-wheel...
...my dear Mr. Nemesio.
My committee wants me to go to
Petatlan instead of Chilpancingo.
I'm a fortunate man, aren't I?
Say good-bye to the family for me.
Good-bye, doll.
- Raquel.
- Yes?
Where are you going? I'll take you.
Wherever you're staying.
I can take you anywhere.
In that case, take me to the
Golden Palm, it's 5 blocks away.
A. Figueroa y Lezama
Lawyer
No, son, no.
At my age, I wouldn't
go to San Jeronimito...
...for all the gold in the world.
Risk crossing that
Ascent to Heaven?
Don't even think of it.
But, Mr. Counselor...
Don't worry, man, don't fret.
I know how to fix this
without risking my life.
Just leave it to me, you'll see.
Mother must dictate her will.
Forget the will.
Listen.
Do you know somebody trustworthy
enough to say that...
...your mother owes
that person money?
Well...
My father-in-law, Mr. Lucilo Peña.
Excellent.
I have a means to solve all this.
See?
I'm going to fill in these papers.
Then, your mother over there...
...needs to put her finger
print on them. Here.
Under each bill of debt.
I'll write them in
your father-in-law's name.
Then, Mr. Lucilo must...
...impound the house in Portales...
...and write it off
in your nephew's name.
These documents are legally valid.
Your siblings can't dispute them.
I hope not.
You don't know how greedy they are.
Who knows what they're scheming now.
In complete use of her
mental faculties...
...declares...
...to be the owner of a property...
...called The Large Coconut Grove.
The boats and the fishing gear.
We said those are for Oliverio.
It shall be clearly stated.
So.
In the presence of Mr. Juan
and Mr. Felipe Grajales...
The house in Portales, Mexico City.
We said it was mine.
Put it in writing.
Words are like feathers in the wind.
That's why we're making this document.
You have to decide.
Let's do it.
By right, the house is mine.
In that case, it's rightfully
mine, I'm the eldest.
Are you giving in?
Me, give in? Never.
Then, you have to play.
One match.
Play it.
- Come on.
You first.
See? I'm even giving
you a head start.
Anyway, the house in
Portales is for me.
Luck will settle it.
Two fives.
Black is your fate.
Two sixes.
See?
It's God's will.
What did I tell you?
The house in Portales will
be inherited by...
...the individual
Juan Grajales.
Quiet, your grandmother's asleep.
Mother.
How are you, mother?
Slightly better.
We made out your will with
the Municipal authority.
Yes, mother.
To spare you the trouble.
Why don't you let her rest?
- Come later.
- Be quiet, you dummy.
You have no say in this.
Why not?
- She's my daughter-in-law.
- Felipe.
I think she's right.
If you don't mind, Albina.
Will you bring the pen
so mother can sign?
You know I can't write.
You don't have to write, mother.
Look, here.
You just need to make an "x"...
...under the written part.
I can't move this hand.
It's heavy.
That doesn't matter.
Let's try with your left.
I'll guide your hand.
Why with the left hand...
...if she just said she's better?
Give me that.
You won't refuse, will you?
Make an "x".
I won't do anything
until Oliverio returns.
Where is he?
Yeah, where is he?
Golden Palm
guesthouse
Good-bye, Raquel.
- Are you going back?
- Yes, do you need anything?
Not me.
In case you wanted something.
I got what I wanted.
Well then, good-bye.
Good-bye, and good luck, baby.
Here so soon, Congressman?
What a surprise.
Keep your distance, girl.
Try your tricks on someone else.
Heavens, you can't take a joke.
Of course.
I was convincing in my
taste for young boys.
I said, behave yourself.
Stay around, we'll talk later.
Don't try so hard to be a man.
So handsome and such a good catch.
Here come my people.
Go away, this is a serious matter.
They've come for the shepherd
who will keep them united.
Leave me alone.
Friends.
Here is the cowardly Eladio.
Hurrah for the people's candidate!
- Hurrah!
He's here to steal from us.
Get rid of him...
Death to him
- Death.
Death to him.
Calm down.
This nation is free and democratic.
We fight for principles...
...not for men.
Every Mexican has a right
to vote and be voted.
Suffrage is free.
Mr. Eladio Gonzalez...
...a political adversary
is not a personal enemy.
Let me shake that hand.
With pleasure.
I am deeply pleased to
have you as an adversary.
There are still
some moral men left.
That's what I say.
Your words honor me.
Ballot boxes...
...not insults...
...will give us the victory.
That's what I expect, my friend.
Good-bye, my friend.
Let the march continue.
Actions Not Words
Sanchez Coello
Hurrah for the People's Candidate
My poor Congressman.
Look at what they did.
Come, I'll wash you.
Go back to your chores.
This is not a matter for women.
Please go away.
Forget the past.
Come so I can wash you.
Leave me alone, madam.
Compadre Chema,
what's the matter?
Just life, compadre.
Eusebita, your goddaughter.
She's left us.
No, what do you mean?
We just saw her yesterday.
It was very quick, compadre.
A snake bit her, and...
You know.
Mr. Chema.
- I share your pain.
- Thank you.
Chema...
I can't find the words, you know...
My goddaughter.
Be strong, compadre.
I share your pain.
Thank you.
Let's go.
- I feel your loss.
- Thank you, Mr. Nemesio.
Who would have known?
Some go and others arrive.
The day before yesterday
a little angel was born.
Today another one took flight.
Poor thing.
Poor us...
...who have endure such
disorderly times.
May I see her face, Mr. Chema?
Yes, dear.
Look at her.
Wasn't my little girl pretty?
Yes, Mr. Chema.
She looks like she's asleep.
Too bad the earth
has to eat her.
Silvestre...
...I feel so bad for Mr. Chema.
But you know I have to go.
Since you have to be with him...
...I'll walk.
Man, there's always a solution.
I'll stay for the burial.
You take the car. That easy.
Thank you, Silvestre.
Look after your luggage.
I'll be right back.
I can't believe this guy.
He runs and leaves us here.
Who will be responsible
if something is missing?
I'll unload the top.
Albina.
- Your mother.
- No.
You barely missed her.
I got what I wanted.
Where are my brothers?
They left this morning.
Where is Chucho?
I left him asleep at the patch.
Go to the door...
...and tell me if anyone comes.
Here come your brothers.
Thy will be done on Earth
as it is in Heaven...
Come with me.
This is the moment.
Blessed Mary, mother of God,
pray for us...
We couldn't tell you before...
Mother dictated her final will...
...which is on this paper.
Yes, Oliverio.
It's all there, poor mother.
Her final moments were harder
because you weren't here.
This isn't valid. It isn't signed.
What proof do you want?
Isn't our word enough?
We'll talk some other day.
When we're calmer.
This isn't the right time.
Oliverio is right.
Let's not rush.
Besides...
...we have to respect
the loss we are grieving.
Albina...
...come.
Hail Mary!
Full of grace...
Did you hear?
You won't get your way.
Bottomless ditch...
...scoundrels.
Save the bills of credit.
My mother's will shall prevail...
The house in Portales
will be Chucho's.
He'll go to school...
...and have everything he needs.
THE END
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS.org today