Nazarín is part of the collections
of the Fundación Televisa A.C.
This version is a product of the
joint project for the preservation
of Mexican cinema by the Cineteca
Nacional and the Fundación Televisa.
The digitization and
restoration was carried out by
the Cineteca Nacional
Digital Restoration Laboratory
from a 35 mm acetate
negative for image
and from a 35 mm interpositive
for sound.
The acetate negative has a very prominent vertical
line at the bottom.
To remove it, it was
necessary to replace the scene
with frames taken from
a composite positive copy.
A total of 135,761 frames were restored.
Hats, shoes, bottles...
...or used clothes
you want to sell.
Hats, shoes, bottles or used
clothes you want to sell.
Birds for sale.
Tamales, get your
hot tamales.
Come get your hot tamales.
Heroes Hostel
Camella is not a thief.
Why is her mother in jail, then?
- She took my buttons.
- Made of shells.
You showed them to me yourself.
Shells?
I took them off
chácharas old coat.
Tell it to her face,
get it off your back.
Do you think I'm scared of her?
If I see her I'll make her...
...swallow them and pull
them out of her stomach.
The wires should be on the front.
Yes, that would be more practical.
The blueprints of the project...
...will be ready this week, Mr. Pablo.
Excuse me, sir.
Is there going to be
electricity here?
Will they charge for it?
They're bringing it
for free, you fool.
I can't afford candles,
how can I buy bulbs?
Electricity is a public utility.
There is no such thing here.
This is a poor neighborhood.
Let's get it, it's on the table.
First come, first serve.
Get out.
Nobody comes in my kitchen.
Mrs. Chanfa.
Come up, please.
Now what happened
to the blessed soul?
Mrs. Chanfa!
Stop shouting, I’m not deaf.
I'm coming.
You!
You've got to do something.
You must react.
If you don't pay me tonight,
you'll lose your house.
Mrs. Chanfa, guess what.
Anything, coming from you.
What disease is it this time?
Well, look here.
The fact is, I was robbed.
All the clothes from the trunk.
Look.
I have nothing to wear
but the cloak.
And only because I had it on.
Plus...
...the little bit of food
there was in the kitchen.
What more did you want?
The alms from yesterday's mass.
I curse your moment of birth,
I am tired of you.
What will it be, you big fool?
A piece of bread...
...or some tortillas
to keep me on my feet.
The rest doesn't matter.
If you can spare it,
may god repay you.
What if I can't...
...or don't want to?
Then, I won't eat.
It wouldn't be a first.
Anyway, who was the wretch
who stole from you?
Chona, no doubt about it.
She came in to clean
house and make coffee.
I thanked her,
and when I remembered...
...there was nothing...
did you hear?
They called your cousin a thief.
Who?
The priest up there.
People walk in
and out of his home.
Be they thieves...
...or whatever...
where are you going, doll?
Even manure smells better
than that woman's perfume.
I'd better go.
Look who dared spread poison.
That rotten priest.
He said she stole from him.
Chona may be a street
walker like us...
...but she's better than her mother!
What did they steal,
vinegar face?
Not your bones, I presume.
Look at that.
The almighty bishop.
Even flies refuse to
stand on his skin.
The sacred grave of
11 thousand virgins.
That's what chona took.
Wash your mouth out before...
...you talk to honest people.
Out, you've said enough.
But he insulted my cousin.
Get out, the three of you.
Don't you dare bother the priest.
Don't yell,
I’m not your sister.
Come on.
I'm leaving.
Because I feel like it...
...you damned slave drivers.
Because we're poor.
Stop running, they won't bite.
Pretending to be so good.
Damnation.
Let's go.
Thank you very much, sir.
You're welcome, father.
Should I report the theft?
I don't have the habit.
The habit?
You've been robbed so many times?
Yes sir, many.
Always.
Excuse me.
Sorry, father.
May I ask you some questions?
Sure, certainly.
Come right in...
...make yourself at home.
There's a staircase.
Everybody comes in and out.
If you like, come in.
Come in.
We hope we're not interrupting.
Not at all.
Make yourselves at home.
I heard you are not
troubled by the thefts.
I don't keep anything, see?
I don't know what keys are.
Besides, my few possessions...
...that I had, rather...
...aren't worth the
effort of locking up.
But please, sit down.
Are you an orthodox priest?
No, sir.
I am roman catholic and apostolic.
I profess my ideas with conviction...
...as I do my faith in Christ our lord.
Things don't belong to anybody.
They are for whomever need them.
I'm surprised to see a
priest living in this hostel.
My neighbors are poor.
So am I.
That's why I live among them.
Oh, sorry, father.
I've come to trouble you.
What do you need, woman?
The boys broke the pot,
I came to get yours.
- Take it.
- Thank you.
You aren't Mexican, are you?
My parents were Spaniards...
...and I went to school in Spain.
Where do you preach?
I rarely step into the pulpit.
I speak low and familiarly
to those who want to listen.
And to whoever is close by...
...I speak my mind.
How do you support yourself?
From paid masses.
When there are any.
I'm taking this wood, father.
You're not using it, anyway.
Fine, woman.
No offense, but your
life seems very precarious.
Quite so.
But due to my conformity
I am not bitter.
So...
...you challenge outrage...
...hunger, poverty...
...persecution and slandering.
I do not challenge them.
I withstand them.
From what you've said...
...I presume you won't
improve your condition...
...or ask your superiors for anything.
That is correct, I do not intend...
...and I do not ask.
You eat when you need to,
if not, you don't.
Exactly, I do not eat.
And if it is necessary,
I ask for charity.
Don't you think that the
dignity of a priest...
...cannot be reduced
to asking for charity?
Oh no, sir.
Charity does not
degrade the recipient.
Nor does it affect dignity.
But, sirs...
...haven't we spoken
enough about me?
If we, moved by your
sad situation were to...
...place some coins
in your hands...
...would you take them?
It was a pleasure, father.
Likewise, sir.
At your service.
Thank you very much, sir.
If you want to die,
use the beam.
That won't crack.
Stay still, mule.
Even if you really
want to die...
...he doesn't deserve
such a favor.
Leave me alone.
I don't feel like it.
Now, you listen to me.
I don't want
stories in my house.
If you want to be in the newspaper...
...jump in front of a train,
the audience is bigger.
You'd better get to work
and stop thinking...
...things you shouldn't.
He's back, isn't he?
No, but he said he would
pay me what you owe.
Come on, woman.
Cheer up, and come
help me in the kitchen.
Take father Nazario's
breakfast upstairs.
He might give you good advice.
You want one?
Eat, woman.
Why don't you eat? That's
why you get those attacks.
Want some?
No.
Don't eat, go ahead and die.
Good morning.
God bless you, father.
May he repay you.
I'm fine this time.
Wait.
Take some of this.
God bless you,
and may he give you more.
Not so much, or else...
thank you very much.
What's wrong?
Who are you?
Oh, I know.
You live beneath this room.
Why are you crying?
You yelled in your sleep.
Bad dreams.
You've been deceived, right?
Go back to your town...
...to your people.
Why did you return, pinto?
Where are the clothes to wash?
Your burner.
Well.
- Will you return?
- No.
Are you leaving forever?
Didn't you know?
Celery.
A mixed one for me.
Half.
One liter, lime.
Have a drink, cheer up.
Come on, it's celery spirits.
I can't hold it.
Why do you think we drink?
To get drunk.
I'm glad you looked for me.
We're from the same town.
What you have to do now...
...is come live with me.
I considered being a maid.
Look...
see who's coming in,
look at her blouse.
Good evening.
Greet me.
How dare you greet me, you thief?
Where did you get those buttons?
At a store.
I bought them.
My drawer is not a store.
Come here, I’ll teach you.
So, the sows are
feeling brave this morning.
What am I, disabled?
- Whore.
- Madame.
You're going to get it...
...you hussy.
Up front, don't be a...
let me go, I’m going to kill her.
Let her go.
You'll see.
Let me go
let me go.
Let me go.
You wretch, scoundrel.
You tramp...
leave her to me.
Leave this one to me.
Kill her.
I'll kill her.
What are you doing here?
I can't be apart from you.
Hussy.
You're so pretty.
You've taken over my thoughts.
This is how I wanted to see you.
Begging for what I won't give.
You always want the same thing.
I'm going to bleed you,
and then I’ll go.
I'll go to others who
are worth more than you.
You like me, don't you?
I've robbed your will...
you can't leave me
even if you wanted to.
Pig.
Good evening, Father, it's Andara.
What do you want at this hour?
Which Andara are you?
The one who insulted
you this morning...
...and said the dirtiest things.
Oh, you're one of the three...
exactly.
I'm telling you that my
cousin chona is a thief.
And you're a saint.
Well, I’ll be.
What are you doing here?
They're following me.
I have taken a life.
Heavens!
Why did you come here to hide?
Because they won't
find me here.
I haven't said
I’ll let you stay.
I'm wounded.
Just look at you.
You poor soul.
How much blood have you lost?
Let me fix that wound.
Who did this to you?
That damned camella...
...with a knife she was hiding.
Anyway, why do you
want to know?
To tum me in?
Tell me how it happened.
I'll decide if I should
help you or tum you in.
All because of some buttons
that tramp stole from me.
When I confronted her she
reacted, and I cut her face.
Then she called me a whore,
and I took it.
Oh, but then she called
me a drunk and a madame...
...and I couldn't take that.
She pulled out a knife...
...and cut me right here.
I took it from her...
...and stabbed her over here.
Excuse me.
And over here.
That must have made her mad.
If I didn't kill her
I came real close because...
...she hollered like a pig
when they took her.
You fool.
Do you realize what you've done?
Sure I do.
I may be a street walker,
but I’ve got my pride.
Oh, heavens.
Shut that infamous mouth.
You talk about pride after you...
...committed the sin of homicide?
You should worry about your guilt...
...before it's too late.
Don't say that, father.
Oh, mother, it hurts so much.
Do you have vinegar
for the wound?
vinegar...
where do you think you are?
I have no such luxuries.
Do something...
...because it's getting very bad.
Why am I seeing black?
Why don't we let some air in?
Don't tum me in, father.
I'd rather die.
You are good, I am evil.
Don't tum me in.
I won't tum you in.
If you are not found,
it's up to god.
As long as you're here,
I will help you.
But it they should ask...
I cannot lie.
Go on, father. Make a broth.
Put some herbs in it.
Forget the herbs, you poor wretch.
Think of your sins.
Your conscience must
be very heavy.
Put your fate in god's
and the virgin Mary’s hands.
I am here to help you.
If you think of more
serious things...
...than camella...
your dignity...
...and herbs.
Et tibi pater: Quia peccavi nimis
cogitatione verbo, et opere...
mea culpa
mea maxima culpa
let go of my son.
Nobody lays a hand on him...
...except me.
He mustn't steal my sugar.
Take him away, he's had dessert.
Is the girl yours?
No, she's your mother's.
Hey, don't get mad...
one-eye.
A cup of coffee,
make it strong.
Father Nazario.
Let's go, uncle, he is not in.
I must go.
I'm going to give him
the alms for today's mass.
Next week I may
have something more.
Thank you so much, Mr. Angel.
You are always very helpful.
You deserve it, Mr. Nazario.
Here you are.
I could use some broth, father...
...but above all, some tequila.
It's good for inner
and outer wounds.
Go get it and come back soon.
If you want something, ask.
This is not a hostel
for criminals...
...and I don't take orders from you.
I'll go if I want to.
And I’ll do as I please.
I have a coin in my pocket.
Take it.
I don't need your coin.
If I did, I would ask you for it.
Get the tequila at a distant bar.
Not at Chato's. You're too innocent,
and he's too talkative.
They would throw me out.
Save your advice,
I know where to go.
Try not to make noise.
Oh, st. Anthony.
They may ask the blessed priest...
...to tell them everything.
Don't let them find me...
...and I’ll light a candle
for you on Tuesdays.
Don't get mad if I say...
...that I don't believe in hell.
Tripas told me...
...and he has read a lot.
Pick between Mr. Tripas' opinion...
...and mine.
No, no father.
You are more knowledgeable.
Where does it end?
When you're lying on a mat
do you know you're dead?
Your soul knows it,
and it's immortal.
I have some more questions.
Well. Maybe since you
know so much...
...you can teach me.
How are people born?
Why do chicks hatch from eggs
looking like chickens?
Why are three buzzards bad
luck, and two are good?
How come mice, small as
they are, are so cunning...
...while rats are big and stupid?
Something else...
why are souls released
from purgatory...
...when you give priests money?
Come on, tell me.
Your head is full
of confusion, child.
And superstition.
Alas...
...since there is nothing to do...
...I will answer your questions.
One by one.
I'll begin my clearing
up the first...
...which is the easiest,
yet most mysterious.
Why are we born?
You really got ahead.
Don't come in, I’m bathing.
Wait, I’ll be done in a minute.
Why are you so late?
I've been worried sick.
You had to be a man.
I have no reason to explain
my actions to you.
You filled the house
of your perfume.
Don't you like it?
I prefer the smell
of wild flowers, child.
You cannot come in, father.
What is it?
Why do you cover your face?
Tell me, what happened?
I'm ashamed of you seeing me.
You should have been
more ashamed before.
This is who you should be.
Not the other one.
I'm almost out of pain, father.
I can go now.
I'm not throwing you out.
But if you're cured, you should go.
It isn't right to have
a woman in my room.
Do you think I don't know that?
You won't have to see me tomorrow.
You'll never see me again.
Tamales, hot tamales.
Tamales, father.
Tamales, get your hot tamales.
I just found out where she is.
And she's really close, too.
Pay me to keep quiet.
I will not.
You Judas.
You'll sell a friend
out for money?
Friend...
I want money,
I’ve had enough lectures.
So, will you pay me?
No.
I'm going straight to the police.
Each will fight for his own life
what evil has Andara done you?
You will never set
foot in my house again.
Cinnamon.
Cinnamon, come here.
Andara.
Open up, for Christ’s sake.
Father nazario, open up.
Wait.
What for?
Cinnamon turned her in.
The police will be here soon.
If they find her with you
they'll take you in, too.
Come with me now that it's dark.
You can hide in my room.
They'd find her there, too.
Let them.
Let them take me in, too.
I hope they hang me.
That's all I’m good for.
What's wrong with you, Mrs. Chanfa?
The farce is over.
I threw you out the day before
yesterday because of the smell.
I didn't say anything
on account of the priest.
Go, they shan't catch you
in this house.
Use the other staircase.
What will they do to the priest?
Go on, now.
Wash the floor you stepped on so...
...they don't smell you were here.
And you, you must leave right away.
They will come around asking
if we saw you...
...and we still have to scrub
all this and you're in the way.
I was on my way to angel's
house to discuss...
so, go over there now.
Lend me the sponge...
...and bring some water.
Lend me a sponge.
You are going to help me.
Bring all the petroleum you can.
Hurry up.
I'll be in the kitchen
like nothing happened.
What are you doing?
The smell that was here...
...it'll go away with fire.
Fire!
How's the manufacture coming along?
Good morning, Mr. Ángel.
Do these suit you?
They're fine, thank you.
Look, Mr. Nazario.
The friendlier, the clearer.
Do you know where I’ve been?
To see the judge.
And do you know what he said?
That you are nuts.
How could you admit
you knew about the fight...
...and that you hid that woman?
There is only one way
of telling the truth.
Telling it.
Now they're saying you had
a scandalous, dishonest...
...and dirty relationship
with that woman.
Slander.
Plain slander.
I know you wouldn't dare.
Besides, if you were to
succumb to such a demon...
...it wouldn't be
with that ugly creature.
Here's the chocolate.
Sit down, Mr. Nazario,
I have more to say.
To top things off, they are...
...implicating you in the
fire that destroyed the hostel.
In the fire?
Me?
Yes, sir. You.
So, what are you going to do?
God is my tribunal.
I submit to him.
I will accept in resignation...
...the pain that human evil...
...may afflict upon me.
The bishop is aware.
There may even be
an investigation.
That will cost you
your preaching.
What do you say to that?
That I shall obey with resignation...
...my boss's determination.
But if you are relieved of your...
...license while in this house,
it would be...
...very painful for my mother.
She cares deeply for you, and...
...I would prefer to
spare her the pain...
...and that vendetta.
You are right.
I have to spare that lady...
...who has been so kind
as to put me up...
...in her home such sorrow.
I shall leave at
this precise moment.
Fortunately, everything I possess...
...is on me.
So...
...after expressing to you
my utmost gratitude...
heavens, Mr. Nazario,
this is not a game.
Sit down and
drink your chocolate.
Do you know where you're going?
If they are taking my license...
...I shall do what I always wanted.
Move to the countryside.
Where I will feel close to god.
All right.
But how will you support yourself?
I'll beg.
What?
A priest, begging?
Don't forget priestly dignity.
Don't worry.
Nobody will notice...
...that I am a priest.
Good afternoon, sir.
Would you give me charity
in the form of food?
We don't feed bums here.
I can work in exchange.
Now, that's different.
Wait.
Hey, you.
Give him a cart.
Thank you.
They denied my
cousin work yesterday.
Of course.
He demanded a salary.
He wouldn't work for food.
There are ten men in town
waiting their tum.
What shall we tell this one?
Leave it to me.
All right.
You know.
What is it?
Where are you going?
I'm sorry, sir.
I am on my way.
Pretty good, huh?
What did they say?
Who was the brave man
who threw you out?
If you can, answer me.
I'm the one who threw him out.
Working for food
is bad for all of us.
- Of course it is.
- That's why.
And that's just in the meantime.
What a scoundrel.
Careful, his hand.
A coin, for the love of god.
May god repay you.
Father nazario.
Hello, Beatriz.
It's a miracle I should find you.
Why, child?
It's a big world.
What happened,
why are you like this?
I am on a pilgrimage.
Barefoot?
I spent the night
with a poor family.
I gave my boots to the
eldest, who was ill.
And the rest of the things?
You must have had something.
A man with the venerable
look of a priest...
...took my bag and my blanket.
It wasn't worth a dime anyway.
What are you doing here?
I live with my widowed sister.
Andara is also with us.
In god's name.
So that fool is here?
It was good seeing you.
God be with you.
My house is close by.
- Come with me, father.
- Sorry.
I must beg for a blanket and food.
- Some other day.
- We will give it to you.
My sister has her husband's clothes.
Help us, father.
Help us.
My niece is terribly ill.
Andara says over and over...
"if blessed father nazario
were here, he would cure her."
To the point where my sister...
...wanted to go look for you.
You believe that crazy woman?
Please, father.
My sister is suffering.
Please come and comfort her.
All right.
I cannot refuse
saying some words of comfort...
...and praying to god for her.
Not a word about anything else.
Josefa.
Here comes father nazario.
Father nazario.
Our lady of Guadalupe.
I don't want him to see me.
Well.
Put that on the girl.
God called you to
this house, father.
- I know you're a saint.
- Don't say that.
So, how is your daughter?
She's slipping away, father.
If you don't do something,
she won't see tomorrow.
Only god and science
can help her.
Come father, sit down.
What ails the girl?
High fevers are devouring her.
The day she fell ill...
...I felt something bad approaching...
...because an owl chirped all night.
And when I went out...
...three dogs howled.
One after the other.
- Has a doctor seen her?
- Yes, father.
He sent her this.
She's already taken two bottles.
They gave her a cleansing,
but it didn't work.
Oh, father.
I have prayed so.
Follow the doctor's orders.
You must have resignation
and trust in god.
Only a miracle can save her.
God began by bringing
you to this town.
You arrived barefoot...
...just like our lord Jesus Christ.
Save my daughter, father, save her.
If I didn't see the pain
impairing you...
...I would leave right now.
How can I do that
which science cannot?
I know that you can perform miracles.
You can.
Yes, it's obvious
that you're a saint.
Say the consecration
prayer, and she shall heal.
Do it, father.
What this poor mother has to say.
A miracle.
- Perform a miracle.
- Blasphemy, ignorant.
A miracle, me?
Yes, sir. A miracle.
If you refuse, it'll only...
...be because you don't want to.
It had to be you, you fool.
Who do you take me for?
Am I an impostor?
Do I try to deceive people?
Don't mention miracles,
don't tease me.
Have compassion on me.
Help my sister.
- Doesn't it pain you to see her?
- Quiet.
I am not a healer.
If god chooses to take her,
it is best for her soul.
That is manifested by pain.
I can only pray with you.
Where is she?
Over here, father.
Lord, restore this
innocent soul's health.
I offer you in tum
my health and my life...
...and I humbly accept all
obstacles and calamities...
...all diseases and pain...
...that may afflict a man.
Help us, our lord of Chalma.
Aid us, lord, aid us.
Go away, devil, respect this house.
Out with you Satan,
there is nothing for you here.
Help us on the holy cross,
Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
Do not forsake us, protect us.
Do not leave us.
Help us.
On heaven as it is on earth...
free us.
Holy, holy, holy.
Our father who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
Forgive our trespasses
as we forgive...
...those who trespass against us.
Lead us not into temptation.
Deliver us from evil. Amen.
Our father who are in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us our daily bread...
father nazario...
...the girl is well.
At dawn she was dying...
...and suddenly she
asked me for food.
I touched her forehead,
it was no longer burning.
Don't go, father.
The news has spread.
They want to touch her.
All right, all right.
You don't need to talk
nonsense.
Get up woman,
stop thinking tall tales.
I said you wouldn't convince him.
It's a miracle. A miracle.
I'm leaving, you're insane.
Devote your prayers...
...to giving thanks for
the grace you were granted...
...and to god.
Where are you going?
Wherever you go, father...
...we will follow...
...because we want
to be pilgrims, too.
And as good and saintly as you.
I admire your intention...
...but do me a favor
and be saintly on your own.
Do you think I’m mad enough
to take you along?
Just look...
...at what was upon me.
It must have broken a leg.
That damned beast.
Patience, colonel.
I told you not to use this one.
That's all we needed.
But these animals think
they're smarter than us.
It chose a hell of a time
to get a cramp.
Good morning, gentlemen.
May I help you?
Go ahead.
Take the head,
I’ll take this side.
Hey you, donkey.
What's wrong with you?
Don't you know a colonel
and especially a priest...
...should always be greeted?
You won't believe it, boss.
I was figuring out
how much I sold...
...and I wasn't looking.
Well, so you learn to look...
...walk by again and greet us.
Let's go!
- Good morning, boss.
- Good morning.
Sir...
...you may think of me as you please...
...but I believe that such treatment...
...is anti-christian and rude.
This is a man, not an animal.
A son of god, as much as you.
And he has his dignity
in spite of any...
...past, present or future despot.
After relieving my conscience so...
...I will go.
What kind of scoundrel is that?
Forget it, colonel.
He's a heretic.
One of those eccentric preachers...
...they send from the north.
Forget him and arrange the horse.
We've been here over an hour.
Why are you following me?
The road belongs to everybody.
We want to do penance
and learn good things from you.
I said, if you want to do penance...
...to do it on your own.
Each to his own conscience.
Each to his own solitude.
We will not get in the way.
Well!
We truly are fond of him...
...and he pays us in this manner.
If you abandon us who
knows what will happen.
All right.
Come along.
But you must promise
to act decently.
To be obedient...
...and leave me alone.
I believe in god the
father almighty.
Creator of heaven and earth.
Means that I believe...
...without a doubt,
in the lord our father...
...the first person
of the holy trinity.
Who...
...through his virtue of
omnipotence...
...created from nothing.
That is...
...where there was nothing...
...the earth and everything in it.
Is god everywhere?
Yes, everywhere.
Is he here, too?
Yes.
Then, eating this is
like communion, isn't it?
No, child.
When the priest consecrates...
...the lord descends into the bread.
Just as you would.
Father...
...if I take communion,
will the demons get out?
What demons would those be?
The ones she has inside.
The poor thing is full of them.
My sister says I have
heart spasms.
That's a curse.
Somebody who wishes you evil.
How many times must I tell you...
...that those are only superstitions?
When I felt short of breath, I felt...
...a ball of fire in my stomach.
And I felt like killing.
That's not witchcraft or demons.
It's a well known illness.
It stems from imagination.
And the cure comes
from imagination.
Plus...
...a healthy life...
...and exercise.
Reject sorrow.
Pray.
You'll get over it.
I think they are demons.
What's wrong?
Why are you fleeing?
Listen.
Why?
What are you doing, father?
Beatriz.
Andara, come here.
Don't touch him.
Don't touch him, Mr. Nazario,
it's the plague.
Everybody is leaving town,
it is infected.
Let's go back.
Run, father.
Please.
Could you show us to
town hall, sir?
I am the municipal authority.
And I order you to go away.
We cannot support beggars.
We haven't come to beg, sir.
We just want to help.
Caring for the sick,
burying the dead.
Cleaning.
In that case, you can stay.
We need a lot of help.
Where shall we begin?
Go to any house.
You'll be needed.
Help me.
Andara, open that window.
Did you hear me?
Beatriz, come here.
Here.
Take the child.
Andara...
go look for milk.
- Where?
- Anywhere.
Juan...
what about the government support?
Is it coming or not?
I saw them from the hill.
It was about time.
Where's Lucia?
Somebody's caring for her.
Hey, how many are coming?
Wait, Juan!
...sed pro tua pietate
prosit mihi ad...
...tutamentum mentis et corporis,
et ad medelam percipiendam:
Qui vivis et regnas deus, per omnia
saecula saeculorum. Amen.
Think that this life...
...is only a road.
Withstand your pain...
...and prepare your soul
for the joy...
...of being in god's presence.
Not heaven.
Juan.
Leave the passions
of this world behind, child.
The lord has given you time...
...to examine your conscience.
Think of heaven that awaits you.
Not heaven.
As a priest I tell you...
...that you can save
yourself if you repent.
Juan.
We've come to help.
Lucia.
Lucia, it's me.
I am here again.
I won't leave anymore.
Help is here,
they will cure you.
Soon you will be fine.
You can go now.
- You are no longer needed.
- I'm a priest.
I beg you to let me help
you through these times.
Juan.
Tell them to go away.
Didn't you hear?
They must go!
I have failed, child.
May the lord have
pity on the soul.
I wanted that, too.
There is nothing
for us to do here.
Look at what a delicious avocado.
The legs are short.
Let's break the pinata.
Lower it, I can't reach.
Now take it, you thieves.
Whoever touches it will be sorry.
Mr. Saban.
They want to rob and kill me.
Don't let them, Ujo.
Don't let them.
Thank you.
Thank you, Mr. Saban.
Charitable souls...
won't you give me something?
What a stingy old woman.
She won't give a glass of water.
I'll mark the best
doors for you, Andara.
But I don't want to
trouble you, shorty.
No trouble.
I am fond of you, Andara.
This is...
- what did you bring?
- Lots of stuff.
I have more at home.
Do you want to go over?
Let's sit in the street
to avoid gossip.
Would you like me to carry you?
You're ugly.
Ugly, but I’m fond of you, Andara.
Since I saw you at the
church yesterday.
Nobody loves...
...that ugly woman.
She must be for me.
So, if you...
do you think you're pretty?
A legless tadpole.
That's what you are.
Say what you will, I am fond
of you and want to help.
Sit down, we have to talk.
Good morning.
I'm going to wash these clothes.
Wait here, we will go
up the hill together.
She sure is good-looking.
She hasn't worked the streets.
Hey, you repugnant shorty.
Relax, no insult intended.
I don't care if you're public,
I want you at my side.
But listen.
You should beat it,
get out of town.
What, Ujo?
Pinto...
Mr. Sabas' cousin,
is spreading stuff about you.
Pinto is here?
He came to buy some horses.
He said the feds are after you,
you're criminals.
I tell you he's seven years old.
I don't want him, he's eight.
No he's not.
I'm not deceiving you, pinto.
I saw when he was born.
He's gentle, does no tricks.
Try him out.
I knew you were around here.
Garbage.
A priest's lover, no doubt.
You brag about being
a pilgrim apostle.
But I know you,
I know what you are.
You big hussy.
Wait.
Even if it's just courtesy,
listen to me.
Had you forgotten me?
I hadn't forgotten you, either.
Although you're not worth it.
I saw you with
that sanctimonious bum.
I want you to leave him.
You hear?
He's good, I will not leave him.
Now you know.
Remember I have a bad temper.
Tomorrow at eleven
I’m leaving for your town.
From there, to the capital.
You're coming with me.
I'm thirsty.
Give me some water.
Now, come.
Come where we can talk.
Leave me alone pinto,
for the love of god.
If it's an order I’ll go,
but I don't want to.
I want to be good.
Let me be good, pinto.
Stop pinto, I won't go.
I won't.
All right, woman.
Tomorrow, then.
I'll wait for you
at the town exit.
You're advised.
Don't fail me, or else...
oh, get out.
Get out!
Because night carries
yesterday's sorrow...
...and the hope and joy
of a new day.
That's what death is like.
Joyous and sorrowful.
Joyous because it frees
us of life's chains.
And sorrowful...
...because we love our flesh...
...and it hurts us to leave it.
What's wrong, Beatriz?
You had a bad encounter.
Didn't you, child?
Did you see us, father?
Then, how can you guess?
That's not guessing.
It's knowing.
You are always the most pious.
Today you were distracted
at prayer.
Distant.
The squalls of passion
are difficult to hide.
I know you're struggling
against Satan.
When he looks at me, I obey.
I was about to go with him.
And I don't want to, father.
Can you explain that?
It's a bad passion, child.
Mortal flesh avoids domination.
What can I do to kill
that weed, father?
Love.
And not only one thing...
...or one single human being.
But all of god's creation.
Is that how you love, father?
Is that how you love Andara...
...and I?
Yes, like that.
God knows...
...how can we flee, father?
Climbing down the hill...
...nobody will see or hear us.
Flee?
Thieves flee.
Not those who give
everything to people in need.
I know that due to our
humble condition...
...human justice will
not care for us.
But the divine...
...will not forsake us.
A while ago I got a
bad feeling in my head.
A premonition?
Oh, father.
I think we're going
to have hard times.
I think so, too.
We will suffer much.
When that happens, I only
hope I am at your side.
If I can carry your load
on my back...
...I certainly would, because...
...that's how much I trust you.
I am fond of you, too.
If you should get lost like sheep...
...I would search for you.
Promise me whatever happens...
...you won't make me leave your side.
I am very tired, father.
What is it, Andara?
What's wrong?
Come here.
Come.
Sit down.
Tell me what it is.
She has her pride...
...and doesn't like a
"nobody" offending her.
And you...
you love Beatriz more.
And it isn't fair.
I love you two the same.
No, sir.
You say nice things
to Beatriz...
...and to me...
...since I am such a dunce...
you just call me a fool.
Don't say that, child.
I love you both the same.
And stop thinking those things.
- Andara.
- Ujo, a tamale.
Your body fell off today.
You've only brought your head.
I came to tell you
that I am going with you.
Because I care for you.
Because you have robbed...
...my heart and put it
in my mouth, honey pie.
Beatriz...
...Ujo is coming with us.
He says he cares for me.
Love is the prettiest thing.
Do you truly love her, Ujo?
Yes, I do.
You, ugly.
You, public.
I had never cared for anyone.
But as soon as I saw you...
what a love.
See?
He is my sweetheart.
There they are.
We caught them together.
Ujo, you'll lose your girl.
Who are you looking for?
You, a hussy and a renegade.
Stop teaching bad habits.
If you've come to arrest us...
...we will not resist.
No need for such an upheaval...
...to catch 3 harmless people.
It's against you, and a certain...
...Ana de Ara, I have a
warrant for your arrest.
Let's go.
One woman is not enough.
Now you have two.
We are christian.
Bully.
Coward, you wretch.
Don't you see he has no defense?
Grab her.
Here, make more fire.
Stronger.
Beat him.
Let me go.
You've beaten my sweetheart.
Sure.
- Did they hurt you, father?
- It doesn't matter.
Let me go, stop it.
Andara.
I said let go.
You see.
Because you didn't obey me.
Get out of here, you dirty frog.
Calm down, Andara.
You have done wrong.
Apologize to your victim
for god's forgiveness.
Scumbag, sorry, damn it.
Come on, let's go.
Stay here, Beatriz.
They only want us.
Careful.
Sergeant.
Don't you remember me?
Yes.
From your village.
What will they do to us?
Soon, in a moment, a rope
of prisoners...
...will parade down
your own village.
- You'd better go alone.
- Sergeant.
Let father nazario escape.
You should be ashamed of yourself.
He's done nothing,
I swear he's a saint.
Andara.
Ujo.
You behaved very poorly.
You sure kicked me there.
But, in spite of your cruelty...
...I care for you.
That's why I’m here.
I kicked you?
Forgive me, shorty,
I care for you too.
I got carried away
and didn't see what I was doing.
When you hit the
man with the pole...
I couldn't believe it was you.
You were spitting fire,
but you looked pretty to me.
You are so ugly...
...but you looked pretty.
Look, my little snail.
Get down, midget.
Let me go, let me go.
Get some rest.
Here, for the girls.
What about me?
There is nothing for the men.
Listen, corporal.
Untie our hands for a while.
Let's see, give us some
water, we're dry.
Do you have a cigarette?
A cigarette, please.
Let me have one, come on...
whoever catches it first.
Quiet, there's enough for all.
Here.
- Stay still.
- Water.
Water.
You have it in there.
You dunce, now do you see why...
...I told you to come with me?
Don't make that face.
I have a horse outside.
Hurry, we're leaving.
- Where to?
- Wherever I decide.
Be grateful I even
searched for you.
What are you waiting for?
Where are you going?
I'm not going with you,
I’m staying.
Listen, don't try my patience.
I won't leave him, kill me.
If he's insulted, so am I.
If he's hungry, so am I.
If they hurt him,
I hope I get beat, too.
If I can't be in jail with him...
...I'll wait at the gate
until that saint gets out.
I'm going to kick that
devotion out of you.
I will be in your town tonight.
I'll talk to your mother.
If she can't talk you
into going with me...
you will be sorry.
Well, let's go.
All right.
See you there.
She is stubborn.
Leave her to me.
Everybody ready?
Come on, what's the hurry?
Stop complaining, it's useless.
Shut your mouth.
Andara.
I thought you didn't
want to say good-bye.
Hurray for the couple.
What are you laughing at?
You are making do with
so little, doll.
Go ahead, laugh.
I care for you, Andara.
Forward.
March.
Come on, out.
Good-bye, Ujo.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, shorty.
Sergeant.
Somebody take this girl.
Let's see, the priest.
Go on.
Let's go!
Why are you taking her so?
The old man is her grandfather.
The sergeant says he kidnapped her.
They are going to drop her off.
Hey.
If you're a priest, hear their
confession so we know their sins.
Hear your mother's confession!
Sergeant.
This woman is disrespecting me!
Hand me the newest one,
naughty priest.
Sergeant.
Aren't you sick to see
him treated that way?
Hand some over, you're tired.
Come on, man.
Give us a little taste.
Save some for the poor.
That's enough rudeness.
You will be quiet.
Get up.
Forward... march.
We'll meet later.
What will you get
for being so stingy?
Go on inside.
Women over here.
Don't cry, mother.
How? You're a prisoner.
I am not a prisoner.
I chose to be here.
They have nothing against me.
What about the shame of...
...seeing you parade
with criminals?
We were always honest people.
Death is better
than seeing this.
Humiliation is good
for the soul.
What are you talking about?
That is what the priest says.
Forgive me, honey...
...but a priest who
travels with women...
...is no saint.
Well, yes he is.
You should have seen him.
He cured the girl
just by touching her.
And those who had the plague.
He lead them to heaven.
How else could it be?
His angelical voice
dives into your bones.
If he touches your clothes...
...you start shaking
as if you wanted to die...
...and go to heaven
to be with him forever.
Oh, darling.
You love that man.
You love him like a man.
Liar!
It's a lie!
- Oh, no.
- Pinto!
Take her away, she's ill.
I'm dying.
No, don't see.
Lie, it's a lie.
You are worse than a dog.
Oh, I am so ashamed
I could die.
I'm dying.
Don't believe it, father.
It isn't true,
don't believe it.
Don't believe it.
I said we'd meet later.
Come, I’ll teach you
another rosary.
Punch his mouth so
he preaches better.
Hey you, what's worse?
Being a whore or a madame?
He can say what he pleases.
And he will say it here.
Father, give some holy bread.
Go on, give your communion.
You scoundrels.
You're blind.
Insult me, not the
sanctity of mass.
Cowards.
Abuse your strength, but don't
offend the majesty...
...of the lord, your creator.
We'll see who's a coward.
You wimp.
Go on, give him his communion.
I thought the priest could
fight, but he's chicken.
For the first time in my life...
...it's hard for me to forgive.
And I forgive you,
it is my christian duty.
I forgive you.
But I also scorn you.
And I feel guilty about
not knowing how...
...to separate scorn...
...from forgiveness.
Keep your forgiveness.
Now, a little stroll.
He'll need bandages
for Sunday mass.
Stop.
He's not defending himself.
Who asked you?
It's not manly to
beat someone that way.
What, did you get cold feet?
Who didn't like it?
Let's stop here.
Thank you.
You are good.
Me, good?
No, I’m quite the opposite.
Have you committed many crimes?
I don't know.
Only two.
And burglarized many churches.
Don't you felt pain sometimes...
...about what you did?
When I’m alone.
But then my friends come, and...
do you have any relatives?
I might as well not.
My mother is in jail.
Go with god.
Would you like to be good?
Yes...
...but how?
All you have to do is say:
"I want to be good".
And be truly determined
to be good.
You'd like to change your life.
Would you like to change yours?
How?
Look, all...
all I do are bad deeds.
And...
...what good is your life?
You, on the good side,
and me on the bad side.
Neither of us are
much good at all.
Do you have any money?
I'll keep it for myself.
You don't need it.
Attention.
Get your things, we're
leaving in five minutes.
Line up outside.
Sergeant.
Where is father nazario?
Isn't he coming with us?
Where is he?
The bishop, made an agreement
with civil authorities.
You will not be on the rope.
You'll be taken separately.
Alone, by a man out of uniform.
That was all they could do.
No doubt it will spare shame.
Don't you want to know
the status of your case?
At least you'll admit
to your recklessness.
All your madness.
No wonder they say you
are unresigned.
A rebel spirit.
It will be difficult
to adjust to reality.
To make you see that your habits
contradict those of priests.
Your ways confront the church...
...which you claim
to love and obey
do you need anything?
Father!
Father.
What did they do to you?
Who hurt you?
Where are you taking him?
Good-bye, child.
Sergeant.
I want to go where he goes.
Take them away.
- Let's go.
- Father!
No, let me go with him. Father.
Don't leave me alone, father.
Father.
That fat frog-eyes
was the one who beat him.
And skinny bones
defended him.
May god bless you
and grant you all graces.
And to you, frog...
...may your children rot
before they are born.
May your throat choke in pus...
...and may you die
a long, painful death.
Is he arrested?
Give me another apple.
Can I give you something?
Take this charity,
and may god be with you.
Take it.
No.
May god repay you, ma'am.