Invest in www.caseway.ai
to change the legal industry!
Being the third son of a good family
and not educated to any trade...
my head began to be filled early with
thoughts of leaving England to see the world.
And thus against the will, nay the commands
of my father, I broke loose and went to sea.
How true my father's prophecy of disaster.
For not long after, being in the
latitude of 12 degrees, 18 minutes...
bound for Africa to buy Negro slaves
for my fellow planters in the Brazils...
a violent tornado came
upon us which carried us westward.
Far out of the way of all human commerce.
My only possession, my only weapon.
I woke refreshed
and half perished with hunger.
Thirsty, without provisions, with little hope
of survival, I set out to survey my fate.
No other land in sight, I was on
an island and barren by the sea.
The wreck of our ship,
stranded during the night.
Sam.
She might slip from the rock, I must contrive
a raft and try to save her precious supplies.
I plundered from the wreck...
many chests with all manner of clothes,
tallow, gunpowder, the carpenter tools...
and scores of other must useful articles,
not to forget that fellow survivor, Sam.
Gold, yet, what use to me.
However, on second thoughts.
Tinder, steel, flint...
fire, fire, worth more to me
than all the gold in the world.
How often I'd seen my servants do this.
Yet I, a master of servants,
couldn't even build my own fire
Rex. Ah, Rex.
You're alive, you're alive too.
Rex.
What was that Rex?
What is it?
She was gone, that fearful sound
had been the death cry of our poor ship.
I regretted all iron work, cables
and lead that had gone down with her.
Rats, the only things from
the ship I did not want ashore.
No ship will sail by without my knowledge.
I kept dry branches ready
to flame into a mighty beacon.
Most urgent of all was to secure myself
against both wild beasts and savages.
Meanwhile the rains approached and
needing store room for all my supplies...
I found a place where the earth was
easiest and started to dig up a cave.
As I had never before so much as handled
an ax or for that matter any kind of tool...
I was but a very sorry workman
and all this cost me a great deal of time.
I became a possibly good
shot and with good cause...
for my constant hard manual labor
gave me a most voracious appetite.
The green coconut and its milk I found to
be most wholesome, cool and refreshing.
My eleventh month.
Days passed in
hunting wild foul, preparing food...
trips to my lookout
hill to search for sight of ships.
One day much like another, uneventful and...
I am sick...
chills, fever, getting worse.
Help, help me.
In this second sleep
I had this terrible dream.
You here, father?
Yes, here, here, here, here, here, here.
Not there, but here.
Where else would I be? Are you not here?
Why do you get here?
My boy, you should not
leave your native country.
At my house, with your dear mother and me,
you had the very best of all possible worlds.
Yes, yes, I remember all you told me, a lot.
- Give me water.
- At home you are well off...
and saved the miseries of labor
and hardships of mankind's lower state.
Though yet embarrassed by the pride, envy...
luxury and ambition of its upper state.
Water father, give me water.
Ours is the middle station
of life my boy, the middle station.
Even kings would've envied you,
admit that now, you admit it?
Will you not help me? I want water.
Why did you ling
yourself into this stupid adventure?
Did you not know that
your mother and I were praying that...
God would not separate us from you?
And...
- you were always wayward.
- Water, bring me water.
Your mother and I
will forgive you, but remember...
God, will not forgive you.
He will not forgive you.
You will die like a dog, you will die.
I will die I will die.
I woke weak, yet clear of head.
Whether I had slept for one whole
day or more I could never be certain.
My first thought was for water.
Did not the Brazilians have some
physic to prevent recurrence of fevers?
In that chest I found
a cure for both, body and soul.
Come to me in the day
of trouble and I will deliver thee.
And thou shall glorify me.
Yes, it's true.
Only He can deliver me out of this place.
I now respect to the Sabbath and so,
mark that day differently from all others.
The last of it Rex.
Now I've been denied the staff of life.
I recalled a grass I had
observed to sprout and start to grow.
Grain, that which in England we call
corn and in the new world they call wheat.
Some few seeds must've
come ashore with me from the ship.
With the Lord's help,
I could try to raise a crop.
Meanwhile I set out to make a
more perfect discover of my domain.
I found great amounts of coco, orange and
lemon trees, sugar cane, tobacco and banana.
I discovered the turtle, which
furnishes an abundance of savory flesh.
Great quantities of most useful shell.
And even turtle eggs.
Also that other sea beast, the octopus...
which they say some
people lack the fortitude to eat.
Parrots, which were known to me.
And other birds, which were foreign.
Animals I did not recognize,
And those I did, goats
goats.
It was a most unusual clear day.
Land, could I not
hack out a canoe, sail to it?
I hewed out a tiny sailing canoe,
was swept out to sea by some great current.
Thanks only a sudden Gail wind,
was I even fortunate to get back to shore.
In other ventures I was more successful.
Come Rex, here Rex, come here Rex, come.
Tell me only this, where did you
find their father? Do you know?
The one mystery of the island I never solved.
Due to sowing during dry season,
first half of seed complete loss.
It's just as it may
seem the best would come to pass...
and that I might finally
triumph over the sun, the rain...
I was threatened by a new enemy, the birds.
They came down on my field
like a plague, a ruthless devouring army.
I fought for wheat as though it'll my life,
used every weapon to frighten and kill.
Hungry Rex?
You can wave your
tail, but you cannot talk to me.
Five years, the fifth
anniversary of the day I landed.
Time to celebrate.
♪ I care not I or
nobody and nobody cares or me. ♪
Do you or do you not? You don't, I do.
I did.
This is a day, a day...
What a day this is?
I have nothing further to say.
My friends, my old friends.
I care for nobody and nobody cares or me.
I remember you all.
- Hooray for friendship.
- Hooray.
Hip Hip Hooray. Hip Hip Hooray.
And here the lowly Keg is dead.
They'll keep us together,
stuck, one to another...
until the resurrection.
Tom, you're at,
Morton, for you and for you Campbell.
At last, a full harvest.
Now it could be truly said,
I worked for my bread.
Have a cake, have a cake,
bake me a cake as fast as you can.
Be patient Rex.
Sing for your supper Poll.
Coarse, burnt...
and most delicious meal of my life.
I built a bower, so that I fancied
now, I was Lord of the whole manor.
And had my country house
and my seacoast house too.
I perfected myself in all tasks
and was forced to learn new ones.
In short, I learned to master
everything in my island...
except myself.
Sometimes in the midst of my work...
the anguish of my soul and my loneliness
would break out upon me like a storm.
Escape.
No matter the dangers I must
do something to escape this tomb...
this prison.
My heart died within me. Alone.
Alone.
Forever alone.
I was a prisoner, locked up by the
eternal bars and bolts of the ocean.
Days became weeks, weeks
became months, months became years.
I quite gave up looking to see for
ships, in time my linen clothes rotted,
my cats all ran wild, my
faithful dog weaken by age...
could no longer keep up
with the hunt he so dearly loved.
Rex, Rex.
Whats wrong? Rex...
Come on boy, eat Rex, eat.
Poor Rex, poor boy.
Would you like a tasty?
A dove? A pigeons egg, eh?
Now you just wait there or me.
Now truly alone.
Starved for the sound
of another voice, any voice.
I would rush to my valley of the echo.
The Lord is my shepherd.
I shalt not want,
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures.
He leadeth me besides still waters.
He restoreth my soul.
My soul.
Dreadful fantasies possess
my mind, I fought to save my sanity.
Lay down in green pastures, he leadeth me
besides still waters, he restoreth my soul.
Green pastures, green pastures.
The scriptures came meaningless to my eyes.
The world seemed but a whirling ball,
it's oceans and continents a green scum,
And myself, but no purpose and no meaning.
Help, help.
Had anyone in England met such an odd
creature as I was in my 18 year of solitude.
It must either have frightened them
or cause a great deal of laughter.
Ah, my little friends.
Yes.
I don't know what to call you but
you are my little friends, aren't you?
Eh?
Ah, just you wait there in your
homes and I will feed you.
You're hungry too, aren't you? Yeah.
Yes.
Here's a morsel for you, eh?
There.
Go on, get him, get him, get him.
Well, good bye.
Good bye.
Condemned to all those years of loneliness...
now trembling in the very
apprehension of seeing another human.
How mad men are possessed by fear.
I even scattered my 10 cattle
so it won't betray my presence.
Hello Robin, hello.
Men eaters.
From that very land I
had once thought to sail to.
I bolted horrified.
All that night I observed the
cannibals at their ghastly entertainment.
They left on the morning tide, but
how soon a tide would bring them back?
How many times have they come and gone while
I unknowing was on my side of the island?
I was in a murdering humor,
I even thought to lure them
into my castle and from ambush...
slaughter 20 or 30 of the naked wretches.
I knew no peace for months and months.
A 100 times I was just
about to let fly at them in my sleep.
I contrived what I called my bomb.
Now I had my bomb, I had a vision.
I imagined how easy I might set a trap
and these monsters might be destroyed.>
After passion, hatred.
I realized I had no heaven sent right
to be judge and executor on these people...
who had done me no injury.
I would leave them to God's justice.
I would not interfere
with them unless they attack me first.
I moved about my
island with the greatest of caution...
never knowing when their attack might come.
They had 2 victims.
While they strung one up for slaughter, I
saw that the second tried to make his escape.
Here, here. No, no, no, no. Here, here, here.
Up, up, up now.
Up, up, I shall not harm you.
Here, up, up. Here, up, up.
Him, him, you. Underground, underground.
Out of sight, come on.
Him, him.
Him.
Him, under.
You, up, up, up, up.
What is your name? What is your name?
You name? Name.
Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday.
Come here, come here, come here.
You Friday,
You Friday, Friday,
- Fraday.
- No, Friday,
Fraday.
Master, Master.
Master.
Friday, Master, friends.
- Friends.
Eat. Eat.
No, no eat man, wrong, wrong.
Friday, this good, eat.
I dare not sleep, if the cannibals fail to
come for me before morning, he might.
The cannibals had departed.
Fortunately for me, without so much
as a search for their missing companions.
I would not let him handle any weapon.
I used my musket to ensure
his continued fear and respect of me.
I put a strong door to my cave
so he could not take me unaware at night.
How reassuring it was to
see him eat the flesh of animals...
knowing the only source for that other
meat he so relished would be myself.
Master...
Someday if you are
good, I'll teach you to smoke.
How pleasant it was,
once more to have a servant.
- Friday, what is this?
- Milk.
- And this?
- Bread.
No, no Friday, use the fork.
- Friday, what's this?
- Plate.
- This Friday?
- Meat.
Good Friday, very good.
- What you see?
- Inside, black line.
- Is your land, your nation.
- Inside?
No, there.
Though this, it appear near.
There is your nation, your people.
Oh happy, there see my nation, my people.
Why do you always come here, to this island?
God says, only good place after kill here.
And you would like to go back to your nation?
Yes. Oh yes, like go back Friday.
- Friday happy there see my people.
- I understand,
Suppose a whole lot of his
countrymen were to visit the island.
Would he not, forgetting
all obligation to me.
Either return
with them to his native country...
or worse still, lead them to
plunder my precious possessions.
And even join in a feast upon myself.
Friday.
Why are you here Friday, what you want?
Smoke, good for Master, good for Friday,
Go.
I you want something again, ask me first.
Had he truly remembered my
promise that he might smoke?
No...
I could not trust him through another night.
- Go to bed now.
- Not finished work.
Do you hear me, go to bed.
So long ago, I had intended these for slaves.
Sit up.
Give me your ankles, the legs.
Why you tie Friday?
I am your Master, I shall do as pleases me.
You force me to this,
now at least I can sleep.
- Take of quickly, Friday foot hurts.
- You had decided.
Did you not tell me the other day you wanted
to go away, go back to your own nation?
- That you want to go to your people.
- Yes.
Go with you, only with you.
- They'd kill me.
- I tell you save life, you friend.
- They'd still kill me.
- No, no kill.
My people obey Friday,
Friday love Master always.
Friday, sit down.
I cannot hold you here by choice.
Perhaps it will be better if you go back.
You beg, kill Friday.
- What must I kill you for?
- Take.
Kill Friday, no send Friday away.
Friday, Friday...
Forgive me, Friday forgive me.
I want you to be my
friend, I will never leave you.
If you want to go, do so.
Friday, over there, wild pig..
How wrong I had been, Friday was as
loyal a friend as any man could want.
With his many different skills
he enriched my life on the island.
We found that two working together could
do far more than two working separately.
Friday, you like? You know what it is?
Beautiful, beautiful present from god.
Better say from the devil, eh?
No, no you would not understand Friday.
Will Master give Friday 1, 2, 3?
You take them all, amuse yourself.
I you get tired of them,
throw them into the sea.
Master, look at Friday.
Beautiful clothe for war.
Take that of.
These were the happiest years
of all the life I made in my island.
Sit down Friday.
You understand Friday?
Devil is Gods enemy in the hearts of men.
He uses all his malice and skill
to destroy the kingdom of Christ.
But Master say god is so strong, so great.
- Is he not much more strong than devil?
- Yes, yes god is stronger than the devil.
He's above the
devil, therefore we pray to God.
But if god is much more strong as devil...
why God no kill devil
so make him no more wicked?
What's it Friday? What's it?
If God the most strong,
why he not kill devil? Kill him.
Well you see Friday...
without the devil there
be no temptation and no sin.
The devil must be there for us to
have a chance to choose sin or resist it.
Is God let devil tempt us?
- Oh, yes.
- Then, why God mad when we sin?
You understand, don't you Poll?
Friday cant get these things into his head.
You understand, don't you, eh?
28 years on the island.
The desire to escape still burns within me.
And now counting on
Friday's skill and knowledge...
I contemplated the manufacture of a craft...
large enough to carry us to Spanish country
which Friday told me lay to the north.
We devoted weeks to selecting a proper tree.
This would be my last chance to
see my native England before I died.
- Where did he come from, eh?
- There.
Take it out of sight, there must be others.
- Master...
- Look.
Come on.
Now, rehearsal for the last time.
There they are, here we are behind the trees.
Now, well see.
- Boom.
No, no, no, tinder, tinder.
White man like Master, friends?
Come on.
Move now.
Tie them to those trees, will come back
for you when we've got water for the ship.
- White men eat prisoners too?
- Eat them, no Friday.
- But murder them, yes.
- Move now.
Rope Master, the rope.
In spite of my appearance
I'm not something that lives in trees,
I'm a man.
Captain Oberzo.
- Now we can talk.
- But to whom do I speak?
- Who are you? Where have you come from?
- What is your case? Tell me.
Mutiny sir, engineered by my mate,
aided by those you saw him lead ashore.
My bosen here and most of
those aboard are loyal.
It's the mutineers
who control the firearms sir.
And your ship?
As fine as ever for sail, beyond the
reef, waiting only for the next tide.
They anchored here to
take on water and abandon us...
- when they surprised and killed the savages.
- Fernandez...
Should they return to the ship we're lost.
We prevent their return...
you think it possible, armed of course,
to reassert your command?
Nothing could prevent me.
- On 2 conditions then.
- Agreed.
First, while you are upon this island
you will be governed by my orders.
Accepted, second.
Second, if we recover your
ship, you will carry me...
and my man to England, passage free.
Or your home in China, India,
three times around the world.
Fernandez.
- Mate?
- Yes, lead of the mutiny.
Fernandez.
They're going to escape.
Unless I've forgotten the ways of civilization
Captain, they'll not be putting back yet.
Hey, what's that?
Kill him.
- I'll cut his throat.
- Wait.
Gold.
Where you find this?
- There?
- Let's get it, take your arms.
Which way? Come on.
You, take a look.
- Nobody here.
- Over we go.
Come here.
Drop arms, in the name of the
governor of this island, drop arms.
Drop arms or I blow your head of.
No, was I that young?
Master, the boat
arrived, the captain is waiting.
Thank you Friday.
I didn't expect it yet.
The proof of the pudding, so the
people cannot say that Crusoe is mad.
These are presents for our friends outside.
You commanded the Captain to punish us
harshly for our sins, did you not Governor?
Nothing of the sort, I asked the Captain
to grant your request to remain here...
rather than return to the gallows.
Started ill, but you'll live
to regret your sacrilegious waste.
What I have here are instructions for you.
Time of planting, care of livestock...
places of concealment of weapons and powder.
Information also as to the savages.
Who do, on occasion, visit this place.
Whether or not you learn the lessons I
have learned and survive I cannot foresee.
You have something
which I for years did not have,
Something for which I wept, for
which my soul shriveled and starved.
You have others of you're
own kind, you have companions.
You have man.
You can sever the ropes that bind you,
it should cost you an hour of painful work.
By then we shall have set sail.
From what you saw today Friday...
Are you not a little afraid of
coming back with me to the civilization?
If Master is not, Friday is not.
And thus, I left the island
after I had been on it...
eight and twenty years,
two months and Nineteen days.
Invest in www.caseway.ai
to change the legal industry!