1
00:00:39,890 --> 00:00:43,516
THAT OBSCURE OBJECT OF DESIRE

2
00:02:09,939 --> 00:02:12,906
I'd like a 1st-class sleeper
on the Seville-Paris tonight

3
00:02:13,039 --> 00:02:14,301
and a couchette.

4
00:02:15,039 --> 00:02:16,336
I have nothing for tonight.

5
00:02:17,173 --> 00:02:19,196
There are no sleepers
on the Seville-Paris.

6
00:02:20,141 --> 00:02:25,006
But I can give you two seats
as far as Madrid tomorrow night,

7
00:02:25,141 --> 00:02:27,767
then a sleeper
and a couchette to Paris.

8
00:02:30,376 --> 00:02:33,570
All right. I have a trunk
and three suitcases.

9
00:02:33,943 --> 00:02:36,876
Can you have them picked up
and forwarded to Paris?

10
00:02:37,477 --> 00:02:39,500
No problem. I'll take care of it.

11
00:02:45,077 --> 00:02:46,442
First-class, you said.

12
00:03:18,284 --> 00:03:21,079
- Where is she?
- Gone, sir.

13
00:03:21,217 --> 00:03:23,615
- When?
- Barely 5 minutes ago.

14
00:03:23,751 --> 00:03:24,649
Come with me.

15
00:03:47,522 --> 00:03:50,353
- She was bleeding.
- It's nothing. Just her nose.

16
00:03:51,155 --> 00:03:52,179
Burn it.

17
00:04:03,391 --> 00:04:06,222
- She left barefoot.
- Get rid of all that.

18
00:04:06,492 --> 00:04:07,480
Very good.

19
00:04:12,593 --> 00:04:16,117
- A pair of panties, sir.
- Burn it.

20
00:04:16,260 --> 00:04:18,317
It's all wet.
She must have been afraid.

21
00:04:18,894 --> 00:04:21,359
We return to Paris tomorrow.
See to the packing.

22
00:04:21,527 --> 00:04:24,085
Gladly, sir. I was tired
of steaks cooked in oil.

23
00:04:24,862 --> 00:04:27,090
I used to work in a restaurant.

24
00:04:27,228 --> 00:04:29,457
One regular, an elderly German,

25
00:04:29,596 --> 00:04:32,824
always used to quote
one of their philosophers:

26
00:04:32,963 --> 00:04:35,191
"lf you go with women,
carry a big stick."

27
00:04:35,963 --> 00:04:37,123
That's not funny.

28
00:05:02,468 --> 00:05:03,455
To the bank.

29
00:05:38,174 --> 00:05:40,732
Damn it! Here, as well.

30
00:05:42,341 --> 00:05:43,568
Another terrorist attack.

31
00:05:45,641 --> 00:05:47,971
Quick, turn around.
We'll be late.

32
00:06:16,213 --> 00:06:18,441
This is your car.
I'll see you in Madrid.

33
00:06:53,520 --> 00:06:55,679
Excuse me, sir.
Are you going to Paris?

34
00:06:56,853 --> 00:06:58,843
We must live in the same area.

35
00:06:59,288 --> 00:07:01,083
I've passed you in the street.

36
00:07:01,554 --> 00:07:04,146
I live on Rue Rembrandt.

37
00:07:04,288 --> 00:07:06,345
- Me, Rue Murillo.
- lndeed.

38
00:07:07,622 --> 00:07:08,554
It's a long trip.

39
00:07:08,690 --> 00:07:11,248
But I simply cannot get used
to flying.

40
00:07:12,423 --> 00:07:15,322
These days, if you take
a plane to Brussels,

41
00:07:15,456 --> 00:07:19,288
thanks to two very nice young
people, you wind up in the desert.

42
00:07:23,891 --> 00:07:26,154
Excuse me, I'm afraid
you're in my seat.

43
00:07:26,559 --> 00:07:29,253
- I'm so sorry...
- Please, stay where you are.

44
00:07:29,559 --> 00:07:31,185
- You don't mind?
- Not at all.

45
00:07:32,560 --> 00:07:35,720
I need to sit facing forward
or I get nauseous.

46
00:07:36,527 --> 00:07:38,959
- Going home to Paris?
- With my daughter.

47
00:07:39,094 --> 00:07:40,219
- You, too?
- Yes.

48
00:07:41,062 --> 00:07:44,654
Didn't we meet at the Law Courts,
in my cousin's office?

49
00:07:44,796 --> 00:07:46,785
Quite possible. I'm a judge.

50
00:07:46,929 --> 00:07:49,622
- Your cousin's name?
- Edouard Foucade.

51
00:07:50,330 --> 00:07:53,229
I know him well.
An outstanding mind.

52
00:07:53,364 --> 00:07:55,989
- I'm Vincent d'Olargues.
- Mathieu Fabert.

53
00:07:56,130 --> 00:07:58,392
Delighted.
He's often spoken of you.

54
00:08:10,132 --> 00:08:12,758
No, thank you. There's no need.

55
00:08:20,601 --> 00:08:21,827
Are you French, too?

56
00:08:22,435 --> 00:08:24,458
Yes. I live in Paris.

57
00:08:25,635 --> 00:08:27,692
Weren't you at the bullfights
Sunday?

58
00:08:28,169 --> 00:08:31,398
Yes. There's no mistaking me
for anyone else.

59
00:08:34,637 --> 00:08:37,229
- Care to see the newspaper?
- No, thank you. I've read it.

60
00:08:41,471 --> 00:08:42,937
Already three minutes late.

61
00:08:43,971 --> 00:08:45,198
That often happens.

62
00:10:00,584 --> 00:10:04,176
You can't leave like this!
You don't understand. Don't go.

63
00:10:05,752 --> 00:10:07,446
You can't do this.

64
00:11:00,627 --> 00:11:02,059
Care for something to read?

65
00:11:10,196 --> 00:11:11,685
Going straight on to Paris?

66
00:11:11,930 --> 00:11:15,760
No, I'll spend three
or four days in Madrid.

67
00:11:18,731 --> 00:11:22,255
Mister, why did you throw
water on the lady?

68
00:11:22,565 --> 00:11:23,792
Hush, lsabelle.

69
00:11:24,431 --> 00:11:26,330
It's impolite to ask questions.

70
00:11:26,632 --> 00:11:29,757
No, madam, she's right to ask.

71
00:11:30,132 --> 00:11:32,190
After all, it's not a very
common act.

72
00:11:32,934 --> 00:11:34,194
Isn't that so, Mr. d'Olargues?

73
00:11:35,234 --> 00:11:36,756
Well, I must say...

74
00:11:37,167 --> 00:11:39,156
No, indeed, it's not very common.

75
00:11:39,568 --> 00:11:42,534
Even if there's no law against it.
But I think...

76
00:11:42,668 --> 00:11:44,635
Let me just assure you,
I'm not a lunatic.

77
00:11:45,335 --> 00:11:47,393
You have absolutely nothing
to fear.

78
00:11:48,802 --> 00:11:50,598
I don't mean to be indiscreet,

79
00:11:51,269 --> 00:11:55,668
but I'd give something to know
why you did what you did.

80
00:11:56,471 --> 00:11:57,959
You're quite curious, sir.

81
00:11:58,504 --> 00:12:00,493
I'm a psychology professor.

82
00:12:01,238 --> 00:12:03,795
Do you teach at the Sorbonne?

83
00:12:04,071 --> 00:12:06,970
No, I give private lessons.

84
00:12:07,905 --> 00:12:09,167
I understand.

85
00:12:10,039 --> 00:12:11,199
Mr. Fabert...

86
00:12:11,873 --> 00:12:13,771
You seem like a normal person.

87
00:12:14,107 --> 00:12:15,697
Your cousin Edouard is a friend.

88
00:12:16,140 --> 00:12:19,732
So I think your act has an
explanation, even if it is unusual.

89
00:12:20,975 --> 00:12:24,270
Isn't it better to drench
than to kill someone?

90
00:12:26,409 --> 00:12:27,636
Probably.

91
00:12:29,477 --> 00:12:32,739
That woman was the dregs.
The worst woman on earth.

92
00:12:33,276 --> 00:12:36,265
My only consolation is to think
that when she dies,

93
00:12:36,844 --> 00:12:38,606
God won't forgive her.

94
00:12:38,978 --> 00:12:41,706
Personally, I find your case
highly interesting.

95
00:12:42,244 --> 00:12:43,801
So do l. Sincerely.

96
00:12:44,212 --> 00:12:47,475
If you wish, I can try
to tell you what happened.

97
00:12:51,214 --> 00:12:54,805
A terrorist group was on trial.
I forget their names.

98
00:12:55,780 --> 00:12:59,179
I came to wait for my cousin,
as I often do,

99
00:12:59,648 --> 00:13:01,546
at the end of the session.

100
00:13:04,682 --> 00:13:07,114
Hello, how are you?

101
00:13:07,249 --> 00:13:08,340
Fine.

102
00:13:11,916 --> 00:13:15,008
- Coffee, sir?
- No, thank you, child.

103
00:13:15,151 --> 00:13:17,014
So? Did they get the death penalty?

104
00:13:17,151 --> 00:13:21,175
Hardly. The priest got 8 years
and the others 3. It's pathetic.

105
00:13:22,017 --> 00:13:25,041
I think the jury received
death threats.

106
00:13:25,185 --> 00:13:28,743
- From whom?
- The R.A.B.J., obviously.

107
00:13:30,819 --> 00:13:35,378
R-A-B-J. "Revolutionary Army
of the Baby Jesus."

108
00:13:36,054 --> 00:13:40,214
The ones behind
the Saint Damian's bombing.

109
00:13:40,354 --> 00:13:42,718
That's right.
15 people were killed.

110
00:13:43,589 --> 00:13:46,680
So, are we lunching at your place?

111
00:13:46,889 --> 00:13:48,684
- It's all ready.
- Let's go, then.

112
00:14:16,360 --> 00:14:17,917
So, what's cooking?

113
00:14:18,061 --> 00:14:19,687
Scrambled eggs with truffles,
to start.

114
00:14:19,827 --> 00:14:20,987
Superb.

115
00:14:21,129 --> 00:14:25,061
- Then, chicken with lobster.
- I'm sure I'm going to love it.

116
00:14:25,195 --> 00:14:28,025
May I peek? I like to see
my meals beforehand.

117
00:14:28,162 --> 00:14:29,356
I'll come with you.

118
00:14:46,999 --> 00:14:50,454
- You're the new chambermaid?
- Yes, sir. I began this morning.

119
00:14:50,600 --> 00:14:52,657
- What's your name?
- Conchita.

120
00:14:52,800 --> 00:14:53,959
You're Spanish?

121
00:14:55,300 --> 00:14:56,664
You speak French well.

122
00:14:57,367 --> 00:15:00,458
I've been living here for 10 years.
Excuse me.

123
00:15:03,502 --> 00:15:06,935
The young lady didn't seem
like a very experienced servant.

124
00:15:08,703 --> 00:15:12,658
I'll bet she was the girl
you drenched.

125
00:15:12,870 --> 00:15:14,461
Yes, it was.

126
00:15:14,737 --> 00:15:15,997
Nice work.

127
00:15:16,737 --> 00:15:17,930
It was easy enough.

128
00:15:18,604 --> 00:15:20,730
A child of five could have guessed.

129
00:15:26,239 --> 00:15:28,705
Today's terrorists are clearly
fascinated by danger.

130
00:15:29,140 --> 00:15:32,004
Some may be politically motivated,

131
00:15:32,140 --> 00:15:34,163
but most are in it for the risk,
the exploit.

132
00:15:34,974 --> 00:15:38,168
Just you wait, they'll be
on the sports page soon.

133
00:15:41,075 --> 00:15:44,633
The other glass for red wine.

134
00:15:45,176 --> 00:15:47,142
That's fine, miss. Thanks.

135
00:15:49,276 --> 00:15:50,936
Excuse me, I'm still learning.

136
00:15:51,277 --> 00:15:54,606
The Bonnot Gang is history.
They had an ideal, at least.

137
00:15:55,177 --> 00:15:59,634
They used revolvers
to terrorize Paris for days.

138
00:16:00,011 --> 00:16:01,807
They were unselfish, generous.

139
00:16:01,944 --> 00:16:03,843
Sure, but they were still gangsters.

140
00:16:10,946 --> 00:16:13,105
She's obviously never worked
with her hands.

141
00:16:13,714 --> 00:16:15,305
Notice how delicate they are?

142
00:16:28,716 --> 00:16:30,148
You rang, sir?

143
00:16:30,883 --> 00:16:33,679
Tell Conchita to bring me
a glass of chartreuse.

144
00:16:34,150 --> 00:16:35,674
Yellow or green?

145
00:16:36,017 --> 00:16:37,950
Green. It's more stimulating.

146
00:16:38,651 --> 00:16:40,480
And slightly aphrodisiac.

147
00:16:41,185 --> 00:16:43,708
- You're very cultivated, Martin.
- Thank you, sir.

148
00:17:19,958 --> 00:17:22,719
No, don't go just yet. Shut the door.

149
00:17:25,926 --> 00:17:26,914
Come here.

150
00:17:28,192 --> 00:17:29,420
Closer.

151
00:17:30,626 --> 00:17:33,458
I meant to ask you...
What did you do before?

152
00:17:33,860 --> 00:17:36,587
I worked in an office,
on the switchboard.

153
00:17:36,860 --> 00:17:38,520
Then in the cloakroom
in a small town bar.

154
00:17:39,462 --> 00:17:40,927
- But I quit.
- Why?

155
00:17:41,595 --> 00:17:43,026
The atmosphere.

156
00:17:43,662 --> 00:17:46,719
I had a strict upbringing.
I'll turn down the bed.

157
00:17:51,297 --> 00:17:54,354
- Which region are you from?
- Andalusia. From Seville.

158
00:17:54,696 --> 00:17:56,356
I know Andalusia. I like it a lot.

159
00:17:56,898 --> 00:17:59,626
- What does your father do?
- My father's dead.

160
00:18:01,832 --> 00:18:03,389
Never mind that. Come here.

161
00:18:03,865 --> 00:18:06,491
I don't intend to treat you
like a servant.

162
00:18:06,732 --> 00:18:09,427
Besides, you're not a servant.
As you can see.

163
00:18:10,232 --> 00:18:11,494
Please sit down.

164
00:18:13,367 --> 00:18:15,856
- Your mother lives in Paris?
- Yes, in the suburbs.

165
00:18:16,167 --> 00:18:18,225
At times I feel utterly lost,
you know.

166
00:18:19,201 --> 00:18:20,929
I can't get used to it.

167
00:18:22,501 --> 00:18:23,934
Get used to what?

168
00:18:24,069 --> 00:18:26,466
To everything. To people,
to what's going on.

169
00:18:26,803 --> 00:18:28,359
It's really hard for me.

170
00:18:28,769 --> 00:18:31,201
- Besides, I don't like working.
- Really?

171
00:18:32,403 --> 00:18:35,199
I work to help my mother,
who's always in church.

172
00:18:36,137 --> 00:18:40,502
Apart from that, the only thing
I like to do is dance.

173
00:18:41,305 --> 00:18:42,601
You're a dancer?

174
00:18:43,205 --> 00:18:45,069
Unfortunately, it's not a living.

175
00:18:46,205 --> 00:18:48,365
- How old are you?
- 18.

176
00:18:48,672 --> 00:18:49,934
What do you think of me?

177
00:18:50,840 --> 00:18:52,135
I hardly know you.

178
00:18:53,841 --> 00:18:56,671
- Your hair is like silk.
- You think so?

179
00:18:59,875 --> 00:19:01,067
I'm going to bed.

180
00:19:01,975 --> 00:19:05,408
Don't go. I have something
serious to tell you.

181
00:19:35,481 --> 00:19:37,242
Where's Conchita?

182
00:19:38,448 --> 00:19:41,847
- She's gone, sir.
- Gone? How, gone?

183
00:19:42,482 --> 00:19:45,880
Early this morning. Without her
wages, without any explanation.

184
00:19:47,249 --> 00:19:49,306
- You have her address?
- No, sir.

185
00:19:49,450 --> 00:19:50,711
Why not?

186
00:19:50,850 --> 00:19:54,248
I found her through the want ads.
She turned up two days ago.

187
00:19:59,051 --> 00:20:00,278
A pity.

188
00:20:16,154 --> 00:20:17,882
What happened next?

189
00:20:18,887 --> 00:20:21,719
- I'm not boring you?
- On the contrary.

190
00:20:22,354 --> 00:20:25,014
About three months later,

191
00:20:25,422 --> 00:20:27,685
I was in Switzerland on business,

192
00:20:27,823 --> 00:20:30,688
staying at a hotel
where I go occasionally...

193
00:21:13,030 --> 00:21:14,258
A light, please.

194
00:21:18,199 --> 00:21:20,892
No, not a light, I want money.

195
00:21:21,466 --> 00:21:22,829
But I have none.

196
00:21:25,132 --> 00:21:26,723
We need money.

197
00:21:31,200 --> 00:21:33,258
No, just 800 francs.

198
00:22:26,243 --> 00:22:28,106
Your papers, sir.

199
00:23:13,217 --> 00:23:14,377
What are you doing here?

200
00:23:15,017 --> 00:23:16,915
- Returning your 800 francs.
- What?

201
00:23:17,551 --> 00:23:21,780
We spotted you at the hotel.
Those young men are my friends.

202
00:23:22,485 --> 00:23:24,951
We were on tour. Our manager
left with the receipts.

203
00:23:27,587 --> 00:23:28,609
Keep the money.

204
00:23:29,720 --> 00:23:32,686
I insist. Keep it.

205
00:23:33,621 --> 00:23:34,950
I'll pay you back when I can.

206
00:23:36,355 --> 00:23:38,684
- Why did you walk out?
- Because of you.

207
00:23:39,322 --> 00:23:40,514
What did I do?

208
00:23:40,654 --> 00:23:44,179
You were too affectionate.
I felt it. I preferred to leave.

209
00:23:45,857 --> 00:23:47,618
I'll be here a few more days.

210
00:23:49,223 --> 00:23:50,621
Won't you stay with me?

211
00:23:51,824 --> 00:23:53,756
I'd like to, but I must go home.

212
00:23:54,091 --> 00:23:56,250
- So soon?
- My mother's waiting.

213
00:23:56,991 --> 00:23:59,981
She has no money.
I have to go. Thanks.

214
00:24:01,291 --> 00:24:02,621
Where do you live?

215
00:24:02,792 --> 00:24:05,418
56B, rue Louis Blanc,
in Courbevoie.

216
00:25:21,272 --> 00:25:24,330
Do two Spanish women live here?

217
00:25:24,540 --> 00:25:25,869
That door, there.

218
00:25:43,375 --> 00:25:44,932
Is Conchita here?

219
00:25:50,210 --> 00:25:52,108
Hello. Come in.

220
00:25:52,544 --> 00:25:54,374
It's the man who lent us the money.

221
00:25:54,512 --> 00:25:55,636
How nice.

222
00:25:55,777 --> 00:25:58,006
- Am I disturbing?
- Not at all.

223
00:25:58,711 --> 00:25:59,803
On the contrary.

224
00:26:05,813 --> 00:26:07,335
Let me have your coat.

225
00:26:13,413 --> 00:26:16,278
We were about to have coffee.
Care for some?

226
00:26:16,481 --> 00:26:17,640
With pleasure.

227
00:26:18,249 --> 00:26:20,408
- Are you well, Conchita?
- Yes, just fine.

228
00:26:21,048 --> 00:26:22,139
I can tell.

229
00:26:22,282 --> 00:26:25,942
I'll pay you back for Conchita's
ticket as soon as I can.

230
00:26:26,083 --> 00:26:28,311
The others promised they would,
too.

231
00:26:28,849 --> 00:26:32,214
Unfortunately, I have no money
right now. Neither do they.

232
00:26:32,584 --> 00:26:34,016
There's no hurry, madam.

233
00:26:34,518 --> 00:26:37,450
- You made it home all right?
- Yes, thanks to you.

234
00:26:38,085 --> 00:26:40,517
My friends are grateful and so am l.

235
00:26:40,684 --> 00:26:43,207
Don't mention it. It was
the most pleasant of holdups.

236
00:26:46,186 --> 00:26:47,243
Your father?

237
00:26:49,253 --> 00:26:52,879
Yes, he died six years ago.
He committed suicide.

238
00:26:54,421 --> 00:26:55,408
How awful.

239
00:26:55,821 --> 00:26:58,787
A good man, but he left me
nothing but debts.

240
00:26:59,455 --> 00:27:03,388
I have no pension, nothing,
and I have no skills.

241
00:27:04,023 --> 00:27:06,853
It's the problem
of well bred women.

242
00:27:07,856 --> 00:27:09,584
She spends her days in church.

243
00:27:10,290 --> 00:27:13,313
I have to pray
for my husband's poor soul.

244
00:27:14,991 --> 00:27:18,924
I was offered a job as concierge,
but I've too much pride for that.

245
00:27:19,491 --> 00:27:23,151
I'd rather kiss church steps
then sweep doorsteps.

246
00:27:24,893 --> 00:27:28,326
My daughter helps me
but I don't want her to work.

247
00:27:28,560 --> 00:27:29,526
Why not?

248
00:27:30,094 --> 00:27:33,219
Because of the bad influences.
The things you hear!

249
00:27:35,761 --> 00:27:37,556
If she'd heeded them,

250
00:27:38,028 --> 00:27:40,018
she'd have been gone long ago.

251
00:27:40,794 --> 00:27:43,023
Don't worry about the money.

252
00:27:43,395 --> 00:27:44,861
I'll pay you back as soon as I can.

253
00:27:47,997 --> 00:27:50,156
It's really of no importance.

254
00:27:50,997 --> 00:27:53,190
And if you're a bit short right now...

255
00:27:53,330 --> 00:27:55,796
Please accept this.

256
00:27:56,632 --> 00:27:58,291
Gladly, sir.

257
00:27:58,931 --> 00:28:01,363
This is a difficult time for us.

258
00:28:01,498 --> 00:28:02,794
I'm happy to be of help.

259
00:28:03,766 --> 00:28:05,095
I have to go out.

260
00:28:05,399 --> 00:28:08,628
Thank you again.
You can stay, if you like.

261
00:28:19,801 --> 00:28:21,358
Not afraid of me anymore?

262
00:28:25,203 --> 00:28:26,464
Come with me.

263
00:28:36,071 --> 00:28:37,593
I'm not that kind of a girl.

264
00:28:38,205 --> 00:28:41,467
If that's what you're after,
then leave and don't come back.

265
00:28:43,805 --> 00:28:45,169
I understand you.

266
00:28:47,439 --> 00:28:50,270
Is dancing all you really know
how to do?

267
00:28:50,873 --> 00:28:54,363
I don't like sewing. I can't cook.
What am I supposed to do?

268
00:28:55,574 --> 00:28:57,666
Don't you get out?

269
00:28:58,441 --> 00:29:00,431
It's stupid to stroll idly.

270
00:29:00,809 --> 00:29:04,139
Especially if you can't shop.
I'd rather stay in bed.

271
00:29:06,443 --> 00:29:08,466
Hand me that box on the mantel?

272
00:29:25,146 --> 00:29:26,373
Would you like a candy?

273
00:29:36,115 --> 00:29:39,479
You may not believe this,
but I was captivated.

274
00:29:40,549 --> 00:29:42,641
- I went back there for a month.
- What?

275
00:29:43,216 --> 00:29:46,842
- I went back nearly every day.
- What did you say?

276
00:29:47,483 --> 00:29:49,245
Let's wait a moment.

277
00:30:37,591 --> 00:30:39,615
It's you.

278
00:30:39,759 --> 00:30:40,951
Bravo, Conchita.

279
00:30:42,459 --> 00:30:43,788
You're perspiring.

280
00:30:44,693 --> 00:30:46,319
We've been working
for half an hour.

281
00:30:46,927 --> 00:30:50,758
I brought you some coffee
and cookies.

282
00:30:50,894 --> 00:30:52,155
That's lovely.

283
00:30:55,361 --> 00:30:56,657
He's a friend. El Morenito.

284
00:30:57,194 --> 00:30:59,023
We've already met.

285
00:30:59,728 --> 00:31:01,660
Yes, sir, in Lausanne.

286
00:31:05,362 --> 00:31:06,351
See you tomorrow.

287
00:31:07,163 --> 00:31:08,026
Goodnight.

288
00:31:08,463 --> 00:31:10,089
We're rehearsing a number.

289
00:31:10,564 --> 00:31:12,861
I'm drenched in sweat.
Excuse me.

290
00:31:14,965 --> 00:31:16,124
Your mother's not in?

291
00:31:31,567 --> 00:31:32,534
This is for you.

292
00:31:33,301 --> 00:31:34,359
What is it?

293
00:31:36,135 --> 00:31:37,465
Would you open it?

294
00:31:40,303 --> 00:31:41,632
It's so beautiful.

295
00:31:42,469 --> 00:31:45,299
Give it to my mother,
it'll make her happy.

296
00:31:54,672 --> 00:31:57,035
I feel so good like this.

297
00:31:58,939 --> 00:32:01,598
Come sit down. I'll sing you a song.

298
00:32:01,905 --> 00:32:02,997
Here?

299
00:32:09,473 --> 00:32:10,632
Sit here.

300
00:32:28,344 --> 00:32:29,707
Did you understand?

301
00:32:31,244 --> 00:32:32,471
Sit here.

302
00:32:37,312 --> 00:32:38,403
It means...

303
00:32:38,979 --> 00:32:40,945
"ls anyone listening? - No.

304
00:32:41,078 --> 00:32:43,204
"Shall I tell you? - Tell me.

305
00:32:43,346 --> 00:32:45,403
"Do you have another lover? - No.

306
00:32:45,546 --> 00:32:47,273
"Shall I be your lover? - Yes."

307
00:32:48,781 --> 00:32:52,544
- And it's true?
- It's a song. The words aren't mine.

308
00:32:53,447 --> 00:32:56,471
- I never stop thinking of you.
- Neither do l.

309
00:33:12,418 --> 00:33:15,350
What are you doing?
What's got into you?

310
00:33:15,518 --> 00:33:18,610
But, Conchita, you came
and sat in my lap.

311
00:33:19,552 --> 00:33:20,813
You kissed me.

312
00:33:21,086 --> 00:33:24,314
I kissed you to thank you.
And because I like you.

313
00:33:25,652 --> 00:33:27,915
- You kiss me but don't love me.
- Me?

314
00:33:28,820 --> 00:33:30,377
I know what you're after.

315
00:33:31,088 --> 00:33:34,612
I amuse you, you like me.
But that's all.

316
00:33:36,655 --> 00:33:38,780
Do as you like with other girls.

317
00:33:39,322 --> 00:33:43,278
I can give you some names,
if you want. But I'm me.

318
00:33:46,290 --> 00:33:48,654
- What I want is quite different.
- Tell me what.

319
00:33:50,657 --> 00:33:55,454
The first time we met,
do you remember?

320
00:33:57,525 --> 00:33:59,388
I was struck by your eyes.

321
00:34:01,526 --> 00:34:03,152
I found them kind.

322
00:34:05,060 --> 00:34:07,084
I'm sure I wasn't wrong.

323
00:34:08,760 --> 00:34:10,249
Every day, I ask myself:

324
00:34:10,860 --> 00:34:12,326
What can I do for her?

325
00:34:13,461 --> 00:34:14,859
And all I can think of...

326
00:34:16,462 --> 00:34:17,620
is this.

327
00:34:25,097 --> 00:34:27,585
Hello. Been here long?

328
00:34:27,863 --> 00:34:30,329
Less than five minutes.
Hello, madam.

329
00:34:30,764 --> 00:34:32,127
Don't get up.

330
00:34:32,931 --> 00:34:34,329
What's this?

331
00:34:34,831 --> 00:34:37,729
More coffee and cakes!

332
00:34:38,131 --> 00:34:39,620
You're really spoiling us.

333
00:34:40,533 --> 00:34:42,465
I'll go prepare all this.

334
00:34:43,732 --> 00:34:46,858
Oh, sir, two women alone
are so vulnerable.

335
00:34:47,499 --> 00:34:51,194
We'd be rich now, had we got off
on the wrong track.

336
00:34:51,667 --> 00:34:52,997
But once thing is sure:

337
00:34:53,300 --> 00:34:55,858
Sin has never spent the night here.

338
00:34:56,234 --> 00:34:59,099
Our souls are straighter
than St John's finger.

339
00:35:01,603 --> 00:35:04,627
Sometimes I'm glad
Conchita doesn't work.

340
00:35:04,836 --> 00:35:05,995
Why is that?

341
00:35:06,136 --> 00:35:08,068
The language you hear
in the street!

342
00:35:08,470 --> 00:35:10,834
Young girls are led astray

343
00:35:10,971 --> 00:35:12,665
more by the advice of women
than of men.

344
00:35:14,071 --> 00:35:16,334
I know girls with a rosary
in their hand

345
00:35:16,672 --> 00:35:18,729
and the devil under their skirts.

346
00:35:19,672 --> 00:35:21,070
Come over here.

347
00:35:25,906 --> 00:35:27,066
Do you have a lover?

348
00:35:28,107 --> 00:35:30,300
- Is that true?
- Of course.

349
00:35:31,008 --> 00:35:32,439
Why are you like that?

350
00:35:33,307 --> 00:35:35,137
Afraid to commit a sin?

351
00:35:35,407 --> 00:35:37,068
No, that doesn't bother me.

352
00:35:37,408 --> 00:35:38,874
Are you frigid?

353
00:35:39,976 --> 00:35:41,874
There's so much I can't ask you.

354
00:35:42,543 --> 00:35:44,475
But if there's a reason, tell me.

355
00:35:44,610 --> 00:35:47,542
- I was sure you wouldn't guess.
- What is it, then?

356
00:35:50,611 --> 00:35:51,975
I'm mozita.

357
00:35:53,044 --> 00:35:54,442
Mozita?

358
00:35:55,944 --> 00:35:56,933
What does that mean?

359
00:35:58,045 --> 00:36:00,705
I've never been with a man.

360
00:36:28,284 --> 00:36:32,080
Excuse me.
Mr. Fabert would like to see you.

361
00:36:33,018 --> 00:36:35,779
- I'll meet you back at the house.
- All right.

362
00:36:36,051 --> 00:36:37,949
He asked me to bring you
to his home.

363
00:36:38,085 --> 00:36:39,211
Very well.

364
00:37:04,590 --> 00:37:07,113
- Sir, that lady is here.
- Show her in.

365
00:37:15,725 --> 00:37:17,123
Please sit down.

366
00:37:21,959 --> 00:37:25,551
I think you know me well enough
by now.

367
00:37:27,327 --> 00:37:28,884
And I'm sure of one thing, madam:

368
00:37:29,827 --> 00:37:31,817
I love your daughter. Very much.

369
00:37:32,527 --> 00:37:35,652
I wish to unite my life with hers.
You understand?

370
00:37:36,695 --> 00:37:38,024
You want to marry her?

371
00:37:41,629 --> 00:37:43,153
I can't, for the moment.

372
00:37:45,030 --> 00:37:46,428
Later, perhaps.

373
00:37:46,797 --> 00:37:48,490
But here's what I propose...

374
00:37:51,365 --> 00:37:52,626
Take a look.

375
00:37:54,865 --> 00:37:57,456
I propose to have her live here
with me.

376
00:37:58,699 --> 00:38:01,494
I'll do everything I can for her.
Understand?

377
00:38:02,899 --> 00:38:05,592
No more rambling
around the house.

378
00:38:06,934 --> 00:38:09,593
Naturally, I'll look after you, too.

379
00:38:10,568 --> 00:38:13,830
Never again will either of you
have to work.

380
00:38:14,801 --> 00:38:16,768
Take this in the meantime.

381
00:38:17,968 --> 00:38:20,025
But I count on you for one thing.

382
00:38:21,802 --> 00:38:25,962
I'd like you to help me.
I want you to bring her here.

383
00:38:26,470 --> 00:38:28,460
- Can you do that?
- I think so.

384
00:38:28,771 --> 00:38:32,294
The day after tomorrow,
around 5 p.m. Come with her.

385
00:38:32,704 --> 00:38:35,693
And reassure her.
Tell her I'm sincere.

386
00:38:35,838 --> 00:38:37,305
Fine.

387
00:38:37,572 --> 00:38:38,902
I'm counting on you.

388
00:38:58,142 --> 00:38:59,369
Whose is that?

389
00:38:59,508 --> 00:39:01,907
- It's my TV set, sir.
- What's it for?

390
00:39:02,743 --> 00:39:04,676
To lend to the young lady.

391
00:39:04,810 --> 00:39:07,504
They say it deadens the mind,
but if you're alone....

392
00:39:07,644 --> 00:39:10,076
- Take it away.
- Very well, sir.

393
00:39:13,212 --> 00:39:15,405
Wait. It's her.

394
00:39:32,881 --> 00:39:34,973
You again. Come in.

395
00:39:37,349 --> 00:39:38,678
What is it?

396
00:39:39,049 --> 00:39:40,515
A letter for you.

397
00:39:50,617 --> 00:39:52,709
"l wanted to give myself to you.

398
00:39:52,852 --> 00:39:55,410
"You tried to buy me
from my mother.

399
00:39:55,552 --> 00:39:58,541
"You'll never see me again."

400
00:40:00,486 --> 00:40:03,611
Stop the decorating.
There's no point now.

401
00:40:04,020 --> 00:40:06,953
- I'm not surprised, sir.
- How's that?

402
00:40:07,221 --> 00:40:10,710
Never wait for a woman
at the first rendezvous.

403
00:40:10,888 --> 00:40:12,911
- Why not?
- Because she won't show up.

404
00:40:52,328 --> 00:40:53,453
Concierge!

405
00:40:56,461 --> 00:40:58,724
- They left?
- Yes, this morning.

406
00:40:58,863 --> 00:41:01,852
- Were they alone?
- I think so.

407
00:41:01,996 --> 00:41:04,360
They didn't leave anything for me?

408
00:41:04,497 --> 00:41:05,860
Not with me.

409
00:41:05,996 --> 00:41:07,486
Will they be back?

410
00:41:07,631 --> 00:41:08,994
It would surprise me.

411
00:41:12,531 --> 00:41:16,521
Won't they have to come back
for the furniture?

412
00:41:16,666 --> 00:41:18,325
No, it's a furnished place.

413
00:41:18,766 --> 00:41:21,891
They took their belongings.
Who knows where?

414
00:41:53,737 --> 00:41:55,500
What are you going to do now?

415
00:41:56,672 --> 00:41:57,661
Answer me.

416
00:41:58,372 --> 00:41:59,962
Nothing. I don't want a thing.

417
00:42:01,040 --> 00:42:04,302
Pull yourself together. Do some
traveling. This is unlike you.

418
00:42:05,839 --> 00:42:07,636
These have been a disastrous
two months.

419
00:42:09,007 --> 00:42:12,235
Find someone else.
There are plenty around.

420
00:42:14,175 --> 00:42:15,471
I've no desire to.

421
00:42:16,642 --> 00:42:20,040
I respect love too much to settle
for shoddy goods.

422
00:42:20,676 --> 00:42:24,131
I've rarely possessed a woman
I didn't love passionately.

423
00:42:24,977 --> 00:42:28,239
The rest I can count on the fingers
of one hand.

424
00:42:38,578 --> 00:42:41,806
A fly! I've been chasing this one
for days.

425
00:42:42,279 --> 00:42:45,269
It had to drop into your glass.
I'll change it.

426
00:42:47,114 --> 00:42:48,272
One fly less.

427
00:42:49,947 --> 00:42:52,937
If she came back now,
I'd ask nothing of her.

428
00:42:53,615 --> 00:42:57,309
I'd stay with her, without so much
as moving, as long as I could.

429
00:42:58,149 --> 00:43:01,207
You know, she may have been
after your money.

430
00:43:02,016 --> 00:43:04,278
Nonsense! Had it been my money,

431
00:43:04,850 --> 00:43:07,839
she could have taken me
for much more and she knew it.

432
00:43:10,117 --> 00:43:12,140
Let's go have lunch.

433
00:43:12,284 --> 00:43:13,841
I'll take care of it.

434
00:43:29,255 --> 00:43:30,811
Thank you. My hat, too.

435
00:43:36,088 --> 00:43:39,613
Excuse me, miss,
but haven't we met?

436
00:43:40,122 --> 00:43:41,520
Yes, sir, I think so.

437
00:43:48,824 --> 00:43:50,188
See you tomorrow, then.

438
00:43:50,457 --> 00:43:53,549
- What did you say?
- For our lunch tomorrow.

439
00:43:54,324 --> 00:43:55,881
What's got into you?

440
00:43:56,025 --> 00:43:57,548
Good bye, miss.

441
00:44:04,326 --> 00:44:05,519
You were here?

442
00:44:05,660 --> 00:44:07,593
I just came in. I start at noon.

443
00:44:08,560 --> 00:44:10,857
- How long have you worked here?
- 4 days.

444
00:44:12,294 --> 00:44:14,227
Why did you disappear like that,

445
00:44:14,995 --> 00:44:17,893
without leaving an address
or a message?

446
00:44:18,429 --> 00:44:19,361
You know very well why.

447
00:44:19,496 --> 00:44:22,462
I don't, you owe me an explanation.

448
00:44:22,596 --> 00:44:24,323
There's nothing to explain.

449
00:44:24,530 --> 00:44:26,258
Excuse me, sir...

450
00:44:27,897 --> 00:44:29,988
Don't chat with the customers.
People are waiting.

451
00:44:46,400 --> 00:44:49,060
This will be my last warning.

452
00:44:49,468 --> 00:44:53,491
I won't have you chatting
with the customers.

453
00:45:04,937 --> 00:45:07,096
- That's it, I'm free.
- Free, how?

454
00:45:07,237 --> 00:45:09,635
I just resigned.
I don't work here anymore.

455
00:45:09,771 --> 00:45:11,101
Fine.

456
00:45:11,238 --> 00:45:12,999
- Shall we have a drink?
- Yes, where?

457
00:45:13,138 --> 00:45:15,400
- Here.
- Let's go.

458
00:45:16,472 --> 00:45:18,097
Why make my mother
that proposition?

459
00:45:18,238 --> 00:45:20,796
- What?
- What do you mean, what?

460
00:45:20,939 --> 00:45:22,303
That she bring me to you.

461
00:45:22,740 --> 00:45:25,229
You tried to buy me
like a piece of furniture.

462
00:45:26,640 --> 00:45:29,164
And I was about to give
myself to you.

463
00:45:29,808 --> 00:45:32,240
You reacted so stupidly.

464
00:45:32,941 --> 00:45:36,430
You might have come and said:
I won't be bought.

465
00:45:36,809 --> 00:45:39,173
What do you do instead?
You run away.

466
00:45:39,676 --> 00:45:42,073
Had you said, this is what I want,

467
00:45:43,343 --> 00:45:45,002
I'd surely have given it to you.

468
00:45:46,777 --> 00:45:48,174
Let's sit down.

469
00:45:57,112 --> 00:45:59,476
Where were you?
How do you get by?

470
00:46:00,312 --> 00:46:03,211
I worked a little.
Modeled for a magazine.

471
00:46:03,780 --> 00:46:07,110
We stayed with a friend for a while.
And we had your money.

472
00:46:07,981 --> 00:46:09,071
And after that?

473
00:46:09,748 --> 00:46:11,078
After that?

474
00:46:11,881 --> 00:46:13,575
You think I couldn't make out?

475
00:46:14,648 --> 00:46:17,615
That I can't live without you?
I don't want your money.

476
00:46:19,316 --> 00:46:21,714
I can get by on nothing. Unlike you.

477
00:46:25,184 --> 00:46:26,706
- What will you have?
- Coffee.

478
00:46:26,850 --> 00:46:28,077
A brandy for me.

479
00:46:29,351 --> 00:46:31,408
- We won't serve the young lady.
- What?

480
00:46:31,552 --> 00:46:33,279
Sorry, sir, we won't serve
the young lady.

481
00:46:40,219 --> 00:46:42,185
Let's go.

482
00:47:00,956 --> 00:47:01,854
It's funny.

483
00:47:03,023 --> 00:47:05,149
I was angry with you
these two months,

484
00:47:05,291 --> 00:47:06,551
I didn't want to see you again.

485
00:47:07,324 --> 00:47:09,153
But seeing you now
makes me feel good.

486
00:47:10,224 --> 00:47:11,588
I have a house in the country.

487
00:47:12,424 --> 00:47:14,323
I'd like to take you there one day.

488
00:47:14,958 --> 00:47:15,856
Where is it?

489
00:47:15,992 --> 00:47:18,890
Not far from Paris.
I hardly ever use it.

490
00:47:19,893 --> 00:47:20,949
Mathieu...

491
00:47:22,393 --> 00:47:24,154
I'll be your mistress there.

492
00:47:24,827 --> 00:47:26,588
When? Today?

493
00:47:27,394 --> 00:47:28,917
No, the day after tomorrow.

494
00:47:54,998 --> 00:47:57,521
What is it? A power failure?

495
00:47:57,733 --> 00:48:00,494
Yes, sir, the power station blew up.

496
00:48:00,966 --> 00:48:03,159
- An accident?
- No, sabotage.

497
00:48:36,772 --> 00:48:37,704
Hello, Adrienne.

498
00:48:40,107 --> 00:48:42,231
I set out some candles.
I hope they'll do.

499
00:48:42,573 --> 00:48:43,665
I'm sure they will.

500
00:48:44,074 --> 00:48:47,199
- Shall I prepare some food?
- Don't bother. We ate on the way.

501
00:48:48,141 --> 00:48:50,300
- Is the room ready?
- Of course, sir.

502
00:49:04,577 --> 00:49:05,736
Put them there.

503
00:49:10,745 --> 00:49:13,109
- Will you be needing anything?
- No. Goodnight.

504
00:49:23,214 --> 00:49:24,338
Who's that?

505
00:49:26,314 --> 00:49:29,008
- My wife.
- I didn't know you...

506
00:49:29,148 --> 00:49:31,774
She died seven years ago.
I loved her very much.

507
00:49:32,515 --> 00:49:34,811
- This was her room?
- Of course.

508
00:49:35,982 --> 00:49:37,539
Then I don't want to be here.

509
00:49:43,550 --> 00:49:46,311
- lsn't there another bedroom?
- It's not made up.

510
00:49:46,584 --> 00:49:47,811
Then have it made up.

511
00:49:48,484 --> 00:49:49,576
All right.

512
00:50:00,919 --> 00:50:02,317
Prepare the room down the hall.

513
00:50:03,153 --> 00:50:04,483
Right away, sir.

514
00:50:05,654 --> 00:50:08,586
You told your mother
you were leaving?

515
00:50:09,187 --> 00:50:10,778
No, why?

516
00:50:11,489 --> 00:50:14,047
She might worry, or get angry.

517
00:50:14,388 --> 00:50:15,479
My mother?

518
00:50:15,622 --> 00:50:17,555
If she saw me streetwalking,
she'd say:

519
00:50:17,690 --> 00:50:20,917
"Qué gracia!
Isn't she a charmer!"

520
00:50:23,324 --> 00:50:25,347
- It will be ready in five minutes.
- Fine.

521
00:50:27,357 --> 00:50:28,721
Doesn't your mother matter?

522
00:50:29,425 --> 00:50:31,653
Not in the least.

523
00:50:31,892 --> 00:50:36,018
I raised myself and I do exactly
as I please, all the time.

524
00:50:36,525 --> 00:50:37,651
That's how it is!

525
00:50:38,127 --> 00:50:39,683
Oh, Mateo...

526
00:50:45,594 --> 00:50:46,924
Mi amor.

527
00:50:57,062 --> 00:50:58,460
I think I'm going to faint.

528
00:51:01,230 --> 00:51:02,423
Sit down.

529
00:51:04,964 --> 00:51:06,191
Sit here.

530
00:51:07,898 --> 00:51:10,091
I love you but I almost passed out.

531
00:51:12,598 --> 00:51:14,996
Lie down. Want a glass of water?

532
00:51:15,132 --> 00:51:16,996
No, stay with me.

533
00:51:19,867 --> 00:51:22,197
- Will you love me for a long time?
- Of course.

534
00:51:23,200 --> 00:51:27,656
Even when I'm old and gray,
will you still love me?

535
00:51:29,301 --> 00:51:32,994
Say it, even if it's not true,
to give me strength.

536
00:51:33,835 --> 00:51:36,301
I'll love you until the very end.

537
00:51:37,269 --> 00:51:39,201
After you, I'll never love
anyone else.

538
00:51:39,870 --> 00:51:41,769
If you leave me, I'm as good
as dead.

539
00:51:43,570 --> 00:51:44,865
You know, Mateo,

540
00:51:45,003 --> 00:51:48,334
I promised for tonight,
but I haven't the strength.

541
00:51:54,205 --> 00:51:56,603
- The room is ready.
- Thank you, Adrienne.

542
00:51:56,739 --> 00:51:58,171
I'll take the bags.

543
00:52:02,473 --> 00:52:03,564
Come.

544
00:52:24,077 --> 00:52:25,941
Good night.

545
00:52:26,078 --> 00:52:28,408
Goodnight, Adrienne.
I won't disturb you again.

546
00:52:35,246 --> 00:52:36,337
Take this off.

547
00:52:43,714 --> 00:52:46,237
- Can I go and change?
- Yes, in there.

548
00:53:41,056 --> 00:53:42,681
I'll be right out.

549
00:53:55,959 --> 00:53:57,857
- The window...
- What?

550
00:53:58,326 --> 00:53:59,587
Close the window.

551
00:53:59,860 --> 00:54:02,326
- No one can see us.
- It doesn't matter.

552
00:54:18,429 --> 00:54:19,725
See how beautiful I am?

553
00:54:23,230 --> 00:54:25,253
- Do you like me?
- Oh, yes, I like you.

554
00:54:25,397 --> 00:54:27,989
- You like me a lot?
- Yes, why ask?

555
00:54:29,298 --> 00:54:30,786
No. Later.

556
00:54:31,865 --> 00:54:33,455
I'm not in the mood now, that's all.

557
00:54:34,132 --> 00:54:35,359
Not in the mood!

558
00:54:35,666 --> 00:54:36,926
No, not now.

559
00:54:41,100 --> 00:54:43,396
It's been too long. I've had enough.

560
00:54:44,101 --> 00:54:46,090
I've been more patient
than a man could be.

561
00:54:46,867 --> 00:54:48,424
- I didn't promise you anything.
- What?

562
00:54:49,134 --> 00:54:51,123
I don't owe you a thing.

563
00:54:51,501 --> 00:54:55,730
Watch out, Conchita. I could grow
tired of being teased.

564
00:54:55,869 --> 00:54:56,857
Grow tired?

565
00:54:57,003 --> 00:54:59,128
I won't stand for this behavior
forever.

566
00:54:59,770 --> 00:55:00,826
You won't?

567
00:55:01,804 --> 00:55:03,633
I won't be your lover tonight.

568
00:55:04,437 --> 00:55:05,733
Not tonight, not tomorrow.

569
00:55:10,405 --> 00:55:12,462
Enough! Take off your nightgown!

570
00:55:15,006 --> 00:55:16,233
Put out the candles!

571
00:55:21,339 --> 00:55:22,499
Please!

572
00:55:41,544 --> 00:55:43,942
Come into my arms, don't be afraid.

573
00:55:45,644 --> 00:55:50,078
You kept me waiting so long,
but now...

574
00:55:50,678 --> 00:55:52,474
Don't cry victory too fast.

575
00:55:53,312 --> 00:55:56,643
Your skin is so smooth,
and your belly...

576
00:55:58,246 --> 00:56:00,076
- What's this?
- What?

577
00:56:00,712 --> 00:56:02,077
What's this I feel?

578
00:56:03,346 --> 00:56:04,608
What are you wearing?

579
00:56:16,216 --> 00:56:17,113
Take that off!

580
00:56:19,116 --> 00:56:20,980
I'll tear it off, you'll see.

581
00:56:21,983 --> 00:56:24,177
Leave me alone, you won't do it.

582
00:56:31,685 --> 00:56:34,243
What in Christ's name is this?

583
00:56:34,718 --> 00:56:35,810
Leave me alone.

584
00:56:37,019 --> 00:56:39,850
I tore at it for 10 minutes,
I struggled.

585
00:56:40,387 --> 00:56:43,842
What with all the knots and laces,
and Conchita's resistance...

586
00:56:44,054 --> 00:56:46,918
Nothing doing!
Impossible to tear the thing off.

587
00:56:47,721 --> 00:56:50,517
Isabelle, go play outside
with the little boy.

588
00:56:50,656 --> 00:56:53,178
- But, Mommy, I want to hear.
- Go and play!

589
00:56:57,756 --> 00:56:59,780
I think I've been very proper.

590
00:57:00,124 --> 00:57:02,420
Nothing I said was likely to...

591
00:57:02,558 --> 00:57:05,718
True, but children today,
you know...

592
00:57:05,858 --> 00:57:07,824
Do go on.

593
00:57:21,160 --> 00:57:23,683
I don't like what I'm doing either.

594
00:57:26,428 --> 00:57:29,724
You want what I won't give you.
It's not me you want.

595
00:57:31,161 --> 00:57:33,320
You'll just have to wait.

596
00:57:34,396 --> 00:57:36,987
It will happen, little by little.

597
00:57:38,963 --> 00:57:42,521
You know I'm yours alone,
what more can you ask?

598
00:57:47,198 --> 00:57:48,391
Tell me...

599
00:57:49,531 --> 00:57:51,122
You want me to come live
with you?

600
00:58:06,970 --> 00:58:08,164
Keep the change.

601
00:58:08,904 --> 00:58:10,802
She's 10 minutes late.

602
00:58:10,937 --> 00:58:13,301
She'll be here.
She went to see her mother.

603
00:58:14,372 --> 00:58:16,395
How are things with the mother?

604
00:58:16,539 --> 00:58:18,868
I send her some money
but I never see her.

605
00:58:20,006 --> 00:58:21,733
You like things as they are?

606
00:58:21,873 --> 00:58:24,033
No. I want to possess her, naturally,

607
00:58:24,174 --> 00:58:29,072
but when she's with me, I'm
overjoyed. That's all I ask for.

608
00:58:29,908 --> 00:58:32,101
You really can't live without her?

609
00:58:33,941 --> 00:58:36,135
Everyone knows you're living
together.

610
00:58:36,276 --> 00:58:37,536
So why don't you marry her?

611
00:58:37,909 --> 00:58:40,932
If I married her,
I'd be entirely defenseless.

612
00:58:47,144 --> 00:58:48,270
Sit down.

613
00:58:48,411 --> 00:58:50,344
How are things?

614
00:58:50,478 --> 00:58:52,239
- Fine.
- What will you have?

615
00:58:53,478 --> 00:58:55,706
The young lady is here...

616
00:59:01,813 --> 00:59:05,405
Delighted to see you again, miss.
May I offer you some champagne?

617
00:59:07,814 --> 00:59:08,871
Excuse me.

618
00:59:31,051 --> 00:59:33,143
Would you buy me a 16mm camera?

619
00:59:33,318 --> 00:59:35,944
We'll look at some nice ones later.
Come on.

620
00:59:47,154 --> 00:59:49,279
- I'd like to ask you something.
- Go ahead.

621
00:59:49,721 --> 00:59:51,778
Why do you insist we make love?

622
00:59:51,921 --> 00:59:54,581
To be closer to you, because
I love you.

623
00:59:55,121 --> 00:59:58,452
I love you, too. But I don't feel
like making love with you.

624
00:59:59,723 --> 01:00:00,983
We're together.

625
01:00:01,489 --> 01:00:04,217
You hold me in your arms,
I caress you,

626
01:00:04,357 --> 01:00:07,221
you have my legs, my mouth,
my breasts.

627
01:00:07,957 --> 01:00:09,650
So why make love, too?

628
01:00:09,791 --> 01:00:11,621
Because it's normal. It's natural.

629
01:00:12,192 --> 01:00:14,590
All people in love do it.

630
01:00:14,992 --> 01:00:17,550
Then you think I'm not normal.

631
01:00:19,059 --> 01:00:20,754
Let's go.

632
01:00:36,529 --> 01:00:41,485
HIJACKED JUMBO JET EXPLODES:
290 DEAD

633
01:01:08,668 --> 01:01:10,634
Wait, I'll just wash up.

634
01:01:11,201 --> 01:01:13,633
- You're not tired?
- On the contrary.

635
01:01:13,935 --> 01:01:15,696
I feel in form tonight.

636
01:01:16,436 --> 01:01:17,800
We'll see.

637
01:01:50,341 --> 01:01:51,170
Come quick.

638
01:01:52,308 --> 01:01:54,502
You didn't forget? Like every night.

639
01:01:54,642 --> 01:01:57,802
No, I didn't forget. Come on.
I won't do anything.

640
01:01:58,342 --> 01:01:59,899
- You promise?
- Of course.

641
01:02:00,043 --> 01:02:02,339
- Otherwise, I'll leave right now.
- Come here.

642
01:02:10,678 --> 01:02:12,644
Must I wait much longer?

643
01:02:13,411 --> 01:02:16,105
If I gave you what you want,
you'd stop loving me.

644
01:02:24,448 --> 01:02:26,311
You only stay for my money.

645
01:02:26,915 --> 01:02:28,574
For the comfort I provide you.

646
01:02:29,114 --> 01:02:33,048
Unlike you, money means nothing
to me. I know where to find it.

647
01:02:33,182 --> 01:02:35,410
Perhaps I'm too old for you.

648
01:02:37,049 --> 01:02:38,106
You?

649
01:02:38,917 --> 01:02:40,143
Certainly not.

650
01:02:40,683 --> 01:02:43,171
I hate young people.
They're such idiots.

651
01:02:43,850 --> 01:02:47,079
I love people who've lived.
Like you.

652
01:02:55,785 --> 01:02:57,013
But, Conchita...

653
01:02:59,519 --> 01:03:00,508
What?

654
01:03:01,719 --> 01:03:04,515
There are several ways
to make a man happy...

655
01:03:05,187 --> 01:03:07,983
- What do you mean?
- And still remain a virgin.

656
01:03:08,354 --> 01:03:10,286
Oh, no! Who do you think I am?

657
01:03:17,989 --> 01:03:19,784
What if I die before you do?

658
01:03:20,690 --> 01:03:21,985
That can't happen.

659
01:03:23,156 --> 01:03:26,385
Why not? I think I have a weak
heart, like my father.

660
01:03:26,958 --> 01:03:28,321
Don't talk nonsense.

661
01:03:29,291 --> 01:03:32,690
Anyway, watch out,
if you take another woman,

662
01:03:32,826 --> 01:03:35,257
I'll come plague you every night.

663
01:03:38,526 --> 01:03:39,889
What was that?

664
01:03:58,663 --> 01:04:00,856
- See anything?
- Not very well.

665
01:04:01,763 --> 01:04:04,286
A demolished car, someone
lying on the ground.

666
01:04:05,164 --> 01:04:07,391
Get away! Don't stand there.

667
01:04:08,465 --> 01:04:11,625
- What is it?
- Terrorists or a gang killing.

668
01:04:11,932 --> 01:04:13,227
We'll find out tomorrow.

669
01:04:13,531 --> 01:04:16,054
That was scary.
I don't feel like staying now.

670
01:04:17,599 --> 01:04:19,190
You stayed longer yesterday.

671
01:04:19,332 --> 01:04:21,697
That was yesterday, this is today!

672
01:04:29,968 --> 01:04:31,934
Give me time to get used to you.

673
01:04:32,869 --> 01:04:34,198
No, get out!

674
01:05:18,210 --> 01:05:20,039
Conchita, open up!

675
01:05:23,777 --> 01:05:25,333
Open up, I said!

676
01:05:25,777 --> 01:05:27,403
I'm drying myself.

677
01:05:40,980 --> 01:05:42,469
One more minute!

678
01:06:18,820 --> 01:06:19,978
What are you doing here?

679
01:06:21,487 --> 01:06:22,885
I let him in.

680
01:06:23,820 --> 01:06:25,479
He got thrown out of his hotel.

681
01:06:25,887 --> 01:06:27,751
He's slept here for
the past 3 nights.

682
01:06:27,887 --> 01:06:31,321
Relax, we sleep back to back.

683
01:06:31,454 --> 01:06:33,081
Just like you and I do.

684
01:06:33,489 --> 01:06:35,580
- Go on, get out!
- Leave him alone.

685
01:06:35,722 --> 01:06:36,881
Out! Get lost!

686
01:06:37,022 --> 01:06:38,386
Leave him alone!

687
01:06:41,157 --> 01:06:42,384
Take your things.

688
01:06:44,457 --> 01:06:46,889
I've known it since the day
I met you.

689
01:06:47,058 --> 01:06:51,014
Deep down, you're cold and
heartless. If he goes, I go.

690
01:06:51,192 --> 01:06:53,714
Sure, go on, get out!

691
01:06:54,359 --> 01:06:55,847
Get out, the two of you!

692
01:06:56,326 --> 01:06:59,350
I'll give you ten minutes.
Then I call the police.

693
01:06:59,960 --> 01:07:01,392
I'll wait for you outside.

694
01:07:03,328 --> 01:07:06,385
I've had enough of you, too.
Ten minutes, you hear?

695
01:07:06,528 --> 01:07:08,494
I'll be gone before that, gladly!

696
01:07:08,628 --> 01:07:12,117
But don't come running after me.
I'll never come back.

697
01:07:12,262 --> 01:07:14,194
May God be your witness!

698
01:07:14,829 --> 01:07:17,727
I never want to see you again.
Hear me? Never!

699
01:07:34,132 --> 01:07:35,360
I can't take it anymore.

700
01:07:36,032 --> 01:07:37,588
One of these days, I'll go see her.

701
01:07:39,434 --> 01:07:41,558
- How humiliating!
- I don't care.

702
01:07:41,900 --> 01:07:45,334
I can't sleep or do anything.
Give me an idea.

703
01:07:46,000 --> 01:07:49,195
I told you: Take a trip, go to Brazil.
Or China.

704
01:07:50,435 --> 01:07:51,924
Wherever you want.

705
01:07:52,068 --> 01:07:54,126
I want someone to prevent me
from seeing her.

706
01:07:54,669 --> 01:07:55,895
You, for instance.

707
01:07:56,936 --> 01:07:58,265
Can't you do anything?

708
01:07:58,703 --> 01:08:02,796
I don't see how. And if I did,
you'd never forgive me.

709
01:08:02,937 --> 01:08:04,334
Don't worry.

710
01:08:05,471 --> 01:08:07,629
- Are you sure?
- Absolutely.

711
01:08:11,805 --> 01:08:13,362
I'll see what I can do.

712
01:08:38,610 --> 01:08:40,041
Coming.

713
01:08:46,444 --> 01:08:48,240
- Who is it?
- Police, open up.

714
01:09:02,680 --> 01:09:04,407
Don't be afraid, ma'am.
We're friends.

715
01:09:05,281 --> 01:09:06,474
May l?

716
01:09:18,817 --> 01:09:20,214
Would you come here, please?

717
01:09:31,318 --> 01:09:33,580
You are lncarnación Perez?

718
01:09:35,186 --> 01:09:37,175
This is your daughter, Concepción?

719
01:09:38,786 --> 01:09:40,581
You have 24 hours to leave
the country.

720
01:09:42,154 --> 01:09:43,744
Here is the expulsion order.

721
01:09:43,887 --> 01:09:46,081
You've been declared
undesirable aliens.

722
01:09:46,587 --> 01:09:48,417
But what have we done?

723
01:09:48,722 --> 01:09:51,314
That's not my business.
I'm just carrying out orders.

724
01:09:53,022 --> 01:09:56,113
You have till tomorrow morning.

725
01:10:16,325 --> 01:10:18,554
How long will you be away, sir?

726
01:10:18,760 --> 01:10:21,625
I don't know. Perhaps a week,
or a year or two.

727
01:10:21,760 --> 01:10:23,624
But you'll come with me, Martin.

728
01:10:23,994 --> 01:10:26,620
- Where are you going?
- We'll find out right now.

729
01:10:27,128 --> 01:10:28,957
I'll close my eyes.

730
01:10:29,462 --> 01:10:32,155
Spin me around a few times.

731
01:10:37,929 --> 01:10:40,725
- Where's the map?
- Right in front of you, sir.

732
01:10:47,964 --> 01:10:51,090
Fine, we're going to Singapore.
Start packing.

733
01:10:51,299 --> 01:10:53,197
What's the weather like there?

734
01:10:53,566 --> 01:10:54,862
Who the hell cares?

735
01:10:55,000 --> 01:10:57,523
What will we do in Singapore
at 3 p.m., sir?

736
01:10:57,900 --> 01:10:58,991
Have a nap.

737
01:11:03,067 --> 01:11:05,794
- But you didn't go to Singapore.
- No, but...

738
01:11:05,934 --> 01:11:09,026
- You went to Seville.
- You amaze me!

739
01:11:09,269 --> 01:11:11,928
Not at all. You knew
she was from Seville.

740
01:11:12,769 --> 01:11:14,758
You changed your mind,
it's quite human.

741
01:11:16,435 --> 01:11:19,596
Subconsciously, we know
there's no such thing as chance.

742
01:11:20,470 --> 01:11:23,562
You're right, I went to Seville.

743
01:11:45,774 --> 01:11:47,206
Whenever you wish, sir.

744
01:11:47,341 --> 01:11:48,705
I'm coming.

745
01:12:25,947 --> 01:12:30,005
A beautiful woman loves you
but you don't treat her right.

746
01:12:30,148 --> 01:12:31,512
You're very rich but you're mean.

747
01:12:40,683 --> 01:12:42,616
For both of you.

748
01:12:53,619 --> 01:12:54,676
Superb, isn't it?

749
01:12:55,619 --> 01:12:58,312
Frankly, sir, architecture
isn't my strong point.

750
01:13:01,654 --> 01:13:03,120
By the way, Martin...

751
01:13:03,887 --> 01:13:06,445
You've been with me
for several years

752
01:13:06,588 --> 01:13:10,316
yet I don't know a thing about you,
about your private life.

753
01:13:11,022 --> 01:13:12,852
There's nothing to know.

754
01:13:13,123 --> 01:13:14,486
What's your opinion on women?

755
01:13:15,123 --> 01:13:16,850
My opinion is of no importance.

756
01:13:20,590 --> 01:13:22,056
It's important to me.

757
01:13:22,690 --> 01:13:24,554
In that case, sir...

758
01:13:24,691 --> 01:13:27,180
I have a friend who loves
women very much,

759
01:13:27,325 --> 01:13:30,382
but he claims they're sacks
of excrement.

760
01:13:31,392 --> 01:13:32,949
Why say such a thing?

761
01:13:33,326 --> 01:13:34,814
It's not me who says it.

762
01:13:35,959 --> 01:13:37,585
You can go, Martin.

763
01:13:37,992 --> 01:13:39,721
I have a dinner invitation
for tonight.

764
01:13:54,496 --> 01:13:56,962
You're forgetting your sack.

765
01:13:57,830 --> 01:14:00,387
I'll have it picked up.

766
01:14:59,674 --> 01:15:01,106
I don't believe this!

767
01:15:01,241 --> 01:15:02,433
Is it really you?

768
01:15:02,941 --> 01:15:04,271
Running into you like this!

769
01:15:05,007 --> 01:15:06,439
It's incredible!

770
01:15:06,841 --> 01:15:08,602
- You knew I was here?
- Not at all!

771
01:15:08,741 --> 01:15:12,037
How I've missed you! I thought
you didn't love me anymore.

772
01:15:12,175 --> 01:15:14,004
Let me look at you.

773
01:15:16,709 --> 01:15:19,835
- Have you been here long?
- Several days.

774
01:15:20,109 --> 01:15:23,565
What misfortune we've had.
We were expelled from France.

775
01:15:23,744 --> 01:15:26,574
- Expelled?
- By the police. Just like that!

776
01:15:27,178 --> 01:15:30,235
3 days to get here from the border!
Without a cent.

777
01:15:30,745 --> 01:15:32,836
Luckily, Conchita found a job.

778
01:15:34,845 --> 01:15:37,676
I won't bother you two.
You must have lots to say.

779
01:15:38,046 --> 01:15:39,104
See you soon, Don Mateo.

780
01:15:43,048 --> 01:15:45,105
- Where are you staying?
- I rented a house.

781
01:15:46,248 --> 01:15:49,238
You were cruel, throwing me out
in the middle of the night.

782
01:15:51,049 --> 01:15:52,481
So you have a job?

783
01:15:52,882 --> 01:15:57,009
Yes, just around the corner.
In a club called the Gurugu.

784
01:15:58,783 --> 01:16:01,716
Come see me dance, tonight.

785
01:16:02,617 --> 01:16:04,106
Will you?

786
01:16:06,251 --> 01:16:07,683
Mi amor.

787
01:16:08,284 --> 01:16:09,649
Mi alma.

788
01:16:09,886 --> 01:16:10,908
Let me kiss you!

789
01:16:11,519 --> 01:16:13,145
- Después.
- What?

790
01:16:14,019 --> 01:16:15,246
Later.

791
01:16:16,453 --> 01:16:18,419
All I can give you for now is this.

792
01:17:59,103 --> 01:18:00,797
- You like this life?
- Very much.

793
01:18:01,571 --> 01:18:03,264
Anyway, it's the only one I have.

794
01:18:04,138 --> 01:18:07,536
What if I asked you to live with me,
forget about all this.

795
01:18:07,671 --> 01:18:08,830
Are you serious?

796
01:18:09,939 --> 01:18:11,427
I'd leave right away, Mateo.

797
01:18:12,172 --> 01:18:14,162
I'm so happy that you came back.

798
01:18:15,073 --> 01:18:18,506
Before, I didn't trust you.
But I've changed a lot, you know.

799
01:18:19,040 --> 01:18:21,632
I'm not the same. You'll see.

800
01:18:23,808 --> 01:18:27,172
I used to be a bit unpredictable.
I know.

801
01:18:28,109 --> 01:18:29,540
But I've calmed down.

802
01:18:30,942 --> 01:18:33,738
Me too, I've thought things over.

803
01:18:33,876 --> 01:18:35,501
You must see me dance every night.

804
01:18:35,643 --> 01:18:38,438
Now that we're together again,
we stay together.

805
01:18:42,011 --> 01:18:43,943
I'm going, I'm going.

806
01:18:44,078 --> 01:18:45,203
Going where?

807
01:18:45,345 --> 01:18:48,073
Upstairs.
They make us take half-hour naps.

808
01:18:48,378 --> 01:18:50,072
If not, we daydream on stage.

809
01:18:50,511 --> 01:18:51,500
Wait for me.

810
01:19:42,188 --> 01:19:43,211
That's me.

811
01:19:45,421 --> 01:19:47,683
Conchita's told me so much
about you.

812
01:19:48,788 --> 01:19:50,845
How do you do? Sit down.

813
01:19:55,056 --> 01:19:56,487
Care for a drink?

814
01:19:57,390 --> 01:20:01,118
- You're a friend of Conchita's?
- I adore her. She's an angel.

815
01:20:02,690 --> 01:20:04,589
You're not as old as she said.

816
01:20:05,224 --> 01:20:07,952
- She said I'm very old?
- So-so.

817
01:20:08,324 --> 01:20:10,019
Also that you're very kind.

818
01:20:10,692 --> 01:20:12,521
And maybe a little naive.

819
01:20:13,260 --> 01:20:15,783
She told you she went to rest up?

820
01:20:15,927 --> 01:20:17,916
Yes, she's taking a rest.

821
01:20:19,594 --> 01:20:20,616
What's so funny?

822
01:20:20,760 --> 01:20:22,590
- You are.
- Why?

823
01:20:23,628 --> 01:20:25,788
Want to know how she's resting?

824
01:20:26,161 --> 01:20:30,321
Go straight up those stairs

825
01:20:30,462 --> 01:20:33,827
and you'll find the room
she's resting in.

826
01:20:34,596 --> 01:20:35,721
Good luck.

827
01:21:41,907 --> 01:21:42,964
What are you doing here?

828
01:21:43,675 --> 01:21:44,833
Get out, all of you!

829
01:21:45,808 --> 01:21:46,932
Get out!

830
01:21:47,808 --> 01:21:49,741
Get the hell out!

831
01:21:50,475 --> 01:21:51,499
Move it!

832
01:21:52,442 --> 01:21:54,102
Out, all of you!

833
01:21:54,410 --> 01:21:57,103
You, too! Get the hell out!

834
01:22:11,379 --> 01:22:12,868
Come with me!

835
01:22:13,013 --> 01:22:14,569
I'm not leaving
and don't you touch me.

836
01:22:21,914 --> 01:22:26,438
What's your excuse now?
You're such a good liar!

837
01:22:27,148 --> 01:22:30,945
Are you accusing me?
You break in, chase everyone out...!

838
01:22:31,082 --> 01:22:31,548
Shut up!

839
01:22:31,683 --> 01:22:34,241
You may get me fired
but I'm to blame!

840
01:22:34,916 --> 01:22:38,212
You're so stupid!

841
01:22:39,651 --> 01:22:41,844
- So this is your job?
- You knew it was.

842
01:22:41,984 --> 01:22:43,280
- I did?
- So innocent!

843
01:22:43,418 --> 01:22:46,509
We dance nude for tourists.
Even kids know that.

844
01:22:46,718 --> 01:22:48,513
Don't tell me you didn't know!

845
01:22:48,652 --> 01:22:50,312
No, I didn't.

846
01:22:52,086 --> 01:22:54,551
Idiot!
You only act of out jealousy.

847
01:22:54,686 --> 01:22:57,619
What right have you!
You're not my father

848
01:22:57,754 --> 01:23:00,743
and you're not my lover.

849
01:23:02,288 --> 01:23:04,050
If you belong to someone, tell me.

850
01:23:06,255 --> 01:23:08,118
I swear I'll leave Seville tomorrow.

851
01:23:09,255 --> 01:23:12,551
I belong to no one but myself,
and I'll stay my own.

852
01:23:12,689 --> 01:23:15,053
I've nothing more precious
than myself.

853
01:23:15,189 --> 01:23:17,781
- And those men?
- I don't even know them.

854
01:23:17,923 --> 01:23:21,947
They came with a guide.
They're on their way to Tangier.

855
01:23:22,091 --> 01:23:23,454
That's all I know.

856
01:23:23,791 --> 01:23:26,019
Look around you.
Does this resemble a bedroom?

857
01:23:27,225 --> 01:23:29,191
Look, where do you see a bed?

858
01:23:35,059 --> 01:23:36,855
I can't go on living like this.

859
01:23:37,927 --> 01:23:39,688
You have to be honest with me.

860
01:23:41,327 --> 01:23:42,918
Even if it's for the last time.

861
01:23:44,594 --> 01:23:46,993
If you stay one more day
in this place,

862
01:23:47,828 --> 01:23:49,158
it's over between us.

863
01:23:50,595 --> 01:23:52,358
You've never understood me.

864
01:23:52,796 --> 01:23:56,626
You think you're chasing me
and that I won't have you.

865
01:23:56,763 --> 01:23:58,355
It's the opposite.

866
01:23:58,498 --> 01:24:01,362
I'm the one who loves you,
who wants you for life.

867
01:24:01,698 --> 01:24:03,527
I've never loved anyone but you.

868
01:24:05,564 --> 01:24:07,190
First, because you're handsome.

869
01:24:07,932 --> 01:24:10,194
You have such gentle, shining eyes.

870
01:24:12,999 --> 01:24:17,023
The nights I've thought of your
eyes! It drove me crazy.

871
01:24:17,366 --> 01:24:20,299
I love happiness
and I know you'll make me happy.

872
01:24:26,601 --> 01:24:29,659
I'll give you everything.
You need only ask for it.

873
01:24:31,002 --> 01:24:32,797
I don't want much, you know.

874
01:24:33,369 --> 01:24:35,494
A little house of my own,

875
01:24:36,270 --> 01:24:38,202
some money if I stop dancing.

876
01:24:38,470 --> 01:24:39,629
In Seville?

877
01:24:40,837 --> 01:24:43,167
It's yours. Just say when.

878
01:24:45,938 --> 01:24:48,598
All I can do is love you madly,

879
01:24:49,072 --> 01:24:50,935
and stay intact for you.

880
01:25:40,881 --> 01:25:42,142
You look so lovely today.

881
01:25:42,714 --> 01:25:44,271
You don't know how happy I am.

882
01:25:55,450 --> 01:25:56,710
It's all yours now.

883
01:26:07,152 --> 01:26:09,846
- Afraid of burglars?
- I'm afraid of no one.

884
01:26:10,553 --> 01:26:11,984
Not even you, Mateo.

885
01:26:13,386 --> 01:26:14,511
Come see upstairs.

886
01:26:14,952 --> 01:26:18,283
Is your mother moving in with you?
In which room?

887
01:26:18,421 --> 01:26:20,183
My mother? She'll never live here.

888
01:26:21,254 --> 01:26:22,482
Just you and me.

889
01:26:23,121 --> 01:26:24,519
Take this, too.

890
01:26:24,921 --> 01:26:27,217
- What is it?
- The deed to the house.

891
01:26:28,589 --> 01:26:33,248
It's all I wanted.
Nothing can come between us now.

892
01:26:34,823 --> 01:26:38,449
And I can entertain you in secret
at midnight.

893
01:26:38,590 --> 01:26:39,681
Tonight!

894
01:26:39,824 --> 01:26:41,585
Don't hold your breath.

895
01:26:41,724 --> 01:26:42,883
What?

896
01:26:44,957 --> 01:26:48,391
Tomorrow night, at midnight.

897
01:27:20,698 --> 01:27:23,562
Good, you're on time.
I was waiting for you.

898
01:27:28,099 --> 01:27:29,224
Kiss my hand.

899
01:27:31,399 --> 01:27:33,365
Kiss the hem of my dress
and my foot.

900
01:27:36,966 --> 01:27:38,728
There. That's good.

901
01:27:39,300 --> 01:27:40,460
Now go away.

902
01:27:40,735 --> 01:27:41,859
What did you say?

903
01:27:42,401 --> 01:27:43,799
I said, now go away.

904
01:27:46,569 --> 01:27:47,659
You're laughing?

905
01:27:48,102 --> 01:27:49,830
You make me laugh!

906
01:27:55,203 --> 01:27:57,795
It's just too much. Look at me,
Mateo.

907
01:27:58,404 --> 01:28:00,165
Look how happy I am.

908
01:28:04,105 --> 01:28:08,435
I'm free of you. Free for
the rest of my life, understand?

909
01:28:10,206 --> 01:28:11,466
Open this gate!

910
01:28:11,772 --> 01:28:14,762
Open it with your teeth.

911
01:28:18,674 --> 01:28:21,640
Don't go just yet.
I still have a lot to say to you.

912
01:28:22,342 --> 01:28:26,036
I can't stand you!

913
01:28:26,642 --> 01:28:30,131
Your slightest touch makes me sick.
I feel like throwing up.

914
01:28:30,443 --> 01:28:33,967
I try to run away but you always
catch up with me,

915
01:28:34,110 --> 01:28:36,940
and your hands touch me again,
you take me in your arms,

916
01:28:37,077 --> 01:28:38,873
you kiss me with your mouth.

917
01:28:41,477 --> 01:28:44,603
The things I felt when you
forced me into your bed!

918
01:28:45,011 --> 01:28:47,944
At night, I'd spit after each
of your kisses!

919
01:28:48,379 --> 01:28:52,437
I prayed to God that you'd die
after I'd ruined you.

920
01:28:53,146 --> 01:28:55,612
I've said it all, you can go now.

921
01:28:55,980 --> 01:28:57,206
Go on, go away!

922
01:28:57,780 --> 01:28:59,303
Go away, Mateo!

923
01:29:00,114 --> 01:29:01,239
You won't go?

924
01:29:01,915 --> 01:29:03,505
Then stay here and watch!

925
01:29:22,452 --> 01:29:26,112
Here he is, here's my lover.
He's handsome, and young.

926
01:29:31,419 --> 01:29:32,578
Come on.

927
01:29:34,053 --> 01:29:37,110
Take this.

928
01:29:38,388 --> 01:29:39,614
You want to stay?

929
01:29:42,121 --> 01:29:44,281
If you want to watch...

930
01:29:45,488 --> 01:29:46,614
watch!

931
01:30:50,666 --> 01:30:52,064
I knew you'd be back.

932
01:30:52,834 --> 01:30:54,026
Good night.

933
01:30:58,868 --> 01:31:02,766
My guitar is mine.
I'll play it for whom I please.

934
01:32:44,285 --> 01:32:48,081
The previous day's fighting
claimed 200-300 casualties,

935
01:32:48,219 --> 01:32:49,947
mostly among civilians.

936
01:32:50,320 --> 01:32:52,980
The BTX virus is approaching
Barcelona

937
01:32:53,121 --> 01:32:55,177
where emergency measures
have been taken.

938
01:32:55,487 --> 01:32:58,977
No antidote has been found
to neutralize the virus...

939
01:32:59,122 --> 01:33:01,145
No, thanks. Turn off the radio.

940
01:33:32,460 --> 01:33:34,983
After what happened last night,

941
01:33:35,128 --> 01:33:36,923
I came to see if you were dead.

942
01:33:42,194 --> 01:33:43,353
Already cold.

943
01:33:44,229 --> 01:33:47,627
I thought you loved me enough
to go off and kill yourself.

944
01:33:48,596 --> 01:33:50,392
I have something to say,
but not here.

945
01:34:12,900 --> 01:34:16,298
Let me explain what happened
last night.

946
01:34:18,801 --> 01:34:19,994
Where are you going?

947
01:34:27,568 --> 01:34:30,330
You just don't understand women.

948
01:34:31,270 --> 01:34:34,668
You think that by giving me
a house, you own me.

949
01:34:36,036 --> 01:34:37,400
But you don't.

950
01:34:39,804 --> 01:34:41,203
You're not listening to me?

951
01:34:47,039 --> 01:34:48,504
You'll never have me.

952
01:34:55,074 --> 01:34:56,335
Listen to me.

953
01:34:58,641 --> 01:35:00,732
That scene last night
was all a charade.

954
01:35:01,641 --> 01:35:03,073
I won't tell you.

955
01:35:08,610 --> 01:35:09,870
Listen to me!

956
01:35:10,243 --> 01:35:13,641
El Morenito isn't my lover!
He doesn't even like women!

957
01:35:13,777 --> 01:35:16,642
We were both play-acting.
Nothing more!

958
01:35:26,112 --> 01:35:29,045
Now I know you love me.

959
01:35:31,147 --> 01:35:33,942
Mateo, I'm still a virgin.

960
01:35:44,749 --> 01:35:46,442
They're having a fight.

961
01:36:04,919 --> 01:36:06,009
Here.

962
01:36:10,853 --> 01:36:11,977
The key.

963
01:36:12,720 --> 01:36:15,880
For you. You can come whenever
you want.

964
01:36:32,323 --> 01:36:35,381
You have to admit she had
that licking coming.

965
01:36:36,323 --> 01:36:37,755
That was yesterday morning.

966
01:36:38,358 --> 01:36:41,325
That's it. It's all over now.

967
01:36:52,493 --> 01:36:56,449
That's the story. You can see
why I spoke of killing her.

968
01:36:56,761 --> 01:36:57,783
Certainly.

969
01:39:33,487 --> 01:39:35,953
An announcement
about a strange alliance:

970
01:39:37,054 --> 01:39:41,078
Several extreme-left groups,
known to the public,

971
01:39:41,222 --> 01:39:44,677
the P.O.P., the P.R.I.Q.U.E.,
the C.L.A.W. and the R.U.T.,

972
01:39:44,823 --> 01:39:48,550
have suddenly joined forces
in a vast campaign of bombings,

973
01:39:48,689 --> 01:39:51,349
under the direction of the R.A.B.J.

974
01:39:51,490 --> 01:39:53,649
"Revolutionary Army
of the Baby Jesus."

975
01:39:54,323 --> 01:39:57,290
These wanton
and incomprehensible bombings

976
01:39:57,424 --> 01:39:59,720
are designed to disrupt our society

977
01:39:59,858 --> 01:40:01,381
and spread total confusion.

978
01:40:01,925 --> 01:40:04,687
A number of far-right
terrorist groups,

979
01:40:04,826 --> 01:40:07,588
notably the P.A.F. and the S.T.I.C.,

980
01:40:07,725 --> 01:40:10,123
say they'll meet the challenge
of the extreme left

981
01:40:10,259 --> 01:40:15,454
and contribute to this operation
of total subversion.

982
01:40:16,894 --> 01:40:20,019
The Archbishop of Sienna
is still in a coma

983
01:40:20,161 --> 01:40:23,219
after a bullet in last week's attack

984
01:40:23,362 --> 01:40:26,055
struck his carotid artery.
What is most serious

985
01:40:26,196 --> 01:40:30,129
is that though he still breathes
normally through the windpipe,

986
01:40:30,262 --> 01:40:32,195
he is virtually brain-dead.

987
01:40:32,964 --> 01:40:36,021
Msgr Fiossole could remain
in this vegetable state for months.

988
01:40:36,597 --> 01:40:40,792
The reaction of the Roman Curia
has had a considerable effect

989
01:40:40,932 --> 01:40:43,398
and even the Communist Party
has published

990
01:40:43,532 --> 01:40:45,963
a statement condemning
this vile attack.

991
01:40:46,699 --> 01:40:50,530
And now, for a change of mood,
let's listen to some music...

