Subtitle Ripped by: Shovon Khan
https://www.facebook.com/shovon.1994
Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS today
THE EXTERMINATING ANGEL
PROVIDENCE STREET
- Where are you going?
- For a quick walk.
We have 20 guests arriving.
How could you go now?
I didn't think of that.
Maybe you're right.
I'll be back as soon as I can.
You're not leaving.
Please, let me go.
Fine, then. Go.
But never set foot
in this house again.
Lucas just left.
What got into him?
Did he quarrel with one of you?
Not with us.
He didn't even mention he was leaving.
We got along just fine.
He's a good fellow.
Well, if he didn't like it here,
good riddance.
There's plenty of others
like him around.
Probably chasing some skirt.
You never know.
- Camila?
- What?
- What are we gonna do?
- Whatever you want.
But make it soon.
I can't wait to get out of here.
Same here.
But where can we go at this hour?
Yes, it's late,
and it's a nasty night out.
A friend would let us stay at her place.
I can drop you somewhere.
I'm going quite a ways out by cab.
You're staying and waiting for me.
Haven't you set out the caviar?
No, that comes later.
Madam wants the main course
served first.
And she asked me to do it.
'Cause you're such a clown.
That's odd. Lucas isn't here.
They'll take our coats upstairs.
Please go on up.
Hear anything?
They must be upstairs by now.
Taking off like this
really isn't right.
You should have thought of that before.
Stay if you like.
Let's go.
That's odd. Lucas isn't here.
They'll take our coats upstairs.
Please go on up.
No, I've never tried it.
So the youngest colonel in the army
claims to be neither honorable nor heroic.
Blanca, I can't stand
the roar of cannons.
What about the fatherland?
The fatherland is a string of rivers
that flow into the sea.
Which is death.
Yes. Death for the fatherland.
Alvaro, Edmundo
has something to say.
To the delightful evening
our friend Silvia provided us,
and to her wonderful creation
of the “Virgin Bride of Lammermoor.”
“Bride” I can accept.
But virgin?
The virgin part would have suited
the Valkyrie better.
The Valkyrie?
Yes, Leticia.
I call her that because she's ferocious
and a virgin.
A virgin? You think so?
They say she's holding on
to that object.
Perhaps it's some kind of perversion.
To the delightful evening
our friend Silvia provided us,
and to her wonderful creation
of the “Virgin Bride of Lammermoor.”
Forgive me if I change
the usual order of the menu.
We'll start with a Maltese dish
traditionally served on the island
as an hors d'oeuvre.
It stimulates the appetite.
Liver, honey and almonds
in a very spicy sauce.
It's delicious.
I had it in Capri, where I conducted
a concert years ago.
Just like in the theater - right on cue.
Delicious, Lucia.
And quite unexpected.
Lucia has a style all her own.
Not everyone can pull off
a surprise like that.
I didn't find it funny in the least.
I caught you in time.
Don't let him out, Julio.
Mr. Russel doesn't like jokes.
Take him back out to the garden.
I'm relieved to hear that.
There are serious matters
that require your urgent attention.
- Is something wrong?
- Strange things are going on.
If madam would accompany me.
What about the sheep?
- To the garden as well.
Where are you going?
What's the meaning of this?
Are you leaving?
Yes, ma'am. I have to see my sister.
Poor girl just -
Enough! ls she sick or what?
She didn't feel well this morning and -
This is madness! An outrage!
How can you leave
just as my guests sit down to dinner?
Forgive us, madam,
but everything is ready to serve.
God grant me patience.
Are you unhappy here?
On the contrary, ma'am.
I have only fond memories
of five years in your service.
Well then?
Please forgive me.
And where are you going?
With Pablo to see his sister,
but we'll both be back
first thing in the morning.
Don't bother.
Leave now and you're fired.
I'd give anything
to make madam happy.
Please forgive us.
They planned this together.
But why?
Domestic help grows
more impertinent by the day, madam.
I trust you and the two waiters
will manage to serve.
We should take our things.
No, we're in a hurry.
We'll come for them tomorrow.
They won't let us set foot
in the house tomorrow.
I'll just take a moment to pack.
Wait for me outside.
Some Jew passing by.
No, it was the Valkyrie.
What an interesting woman.
What's your name?
Beatriz. And yours?
Eduardo.
- Age?
- Thirty.
Profession?
Architect.
Single?
Until Saturday... just like yourself.
Just five more days.
I feel wonderful tonight, Doctor.
I ate with real relish.
Your treatment has worked wonders.
I deserve no credit.
Your ailment was really quite minor.
- Do you dance, Doctor?
- I've never tried.
What a shame.
I hoped you'd take me in your arms.
I'm flattered my patient
feels so amiably toward me, but-
Transference.
I've longed to satisfy that desire
for some time now.
Did you bring your pills?
What's wrong?
Oh, it's nothing, Doctor.
I told you.
You mustn't eat so much, Cristian.
An ulcer is unforgiving.
Cristian, permit me to introduce
my good friend, newly arrived in our city.
Leandro Gómez, Cristian Ugalde.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Likewise.
Will you excuse me?
- Of course.
Aren't you going in to hear Blanca?
In just a moment, Cono.
What was that about?
Why that passionate kiss?
Poor Leonora.
Is there any hope for her cancer?
Unfortunately, none.
In three months
she'll be completely bald.
She's got a nice head.
- Leandro!
- My dear friend Cristian.
I'm so happy to see you!
I thought you two were in New York,
as always.
Well, here we are.
You'll have to make the best of it.
We'll have to see a lot of each other.
Absolutely.
In fact, come by tomorrow.
I have a little box to give you.
Careful. We're not alone.
Allow me to introduce you
to Mr. Sergio Russel.
Don't bother.
You two continue catching up.
I've got no stomach for mumbo jumbo.
Excuse me.
- That Russell is an eccentric.
- A tough cookie. But that's his problem.
Let's go and listen to Blanca.
Very nice!
Magnificent, as always.
A delightful performance.
Pity there was no harpsichord.
It would have sounded wonderful.
Please play some Scarlatti for us.
You'll have to forgive me.
lt's late and I'm tired.
Late?
This is the most intimate and pleasant
hour of the whole evening.
That was marvelous, Blanca.
That was by Paradisi, wasn't it?
That was exquisite.
Who'd have guessed the world-renowned
orchestral conductor was -
I'm very pleased to meet you
under such fraternal circumstances.
- What lodge?
- Dawn 21.
Sublime column. Grade.
Maestro, I'd love to hear your opinion
of the “pizzicato” we just heard.
It was a sonata, sir.
Allow me to introduce Mr. Ugalde.
And your name is?
Leandro Gómez.
Pleased to meet you.
- Do you plan to stay long in the city?
- Do you?
- You tell me first.
- No, you.
I live here.
I expected as much.
- Get the coats ready.
- Yes, sir.
Forgive him.
He felt rejuvenated tonight.
He hasn't had wine in a while.
Between that and the fatigue...
Alberto's stamina is admirable.
You only have to watch him conduct.
How can he endure hours
of such tension and activity?
When we retire to bed
after a concert,
he still tries -
I have no complaints
in that department.
On the contrary,
I have to hold him off.
Let him rest, then.
We wouldn't want him to try -
Heavens no, Edmundo!
I'm sure he wouldn't dare here.
No, of course not.
I didn't express myself well.
She's just a bit tired.
In her condition, it's natural.
Rita's sleepiness is a good sign.
Congratulations.
This is the fourth, isn't it?
Actually, I've lost track, ma'am.
Are you sure of the father?
I mean -
You should ask her.
Science will tell.
Blanca, I thought you'd already left.
I was delayed for a moment.
Raul was telling us
that the fauna in Romania -
Due to the climate extremes.
But enough talk for now.
I must be leaving.
Where could my shawl be?
Just a moment.
Why don't they leave?
It's almost 4:00.
Any minute now.
You can sneak off to my bedroom
during all the good-byes.
What about Edmundo?
If he comes in, I'll say
I was showing you the incunabula.
Good idea.
Thank you.
Everything was perfect, Lucia,
despite -
At this hour,
even lipstick begins to fade.
The problem now
is how to take care of our friends.
They must be uncomfortable.
I love the spontaneity of this situation.
If you'd like to spend the night,
we'll make up
as many rooms as needed.
I'm pleased to see the old spirit
of improvisation is alive and well.
You're the perfect host, Edmundo.
But I wouldn't wish
to impose on your kind hospitality.
I'm afraid I have a rehearsal
tomorrow afternoon.
And I have an appointment
just four hours from now, so -
This is getting serious.
They're turning out the lights.
The moment has come to decide.
We should leave right now.
If the others are drunk or crazy,
let them stay.
This is outrageous.
If it weren't for the respect due our hosts,
I'd like to teach that boor a lesson!
These stiff clothes
are for statues, not men.
Especially at 5:00 in the morning.
Aren't they going a bit far,
taking off their tuxedo jackets?
Don't forget Leandro lives
in the United States.
Besides, this is the time
when the body's most relaxed,
and with the pleasant
temperature in here -
I'm sure they'll feel ashamed
when they look back on their behavior.
I'm sure they will.
And I'd like to spare them
that embarrassment.
Let's meet them on their level
to make their Faux pas less obvious.
Please, Lucia, take my spot.
Our first night together.
What are we doing here?
Why didn't we leave?
Everyone decided to stay.
Does that seem normal to you?
Life is amusing...
and strange.
I can't stand up another minute.
Come.
Let's go to sleep.
Good morning, Rita.
Did you sleep well?
I didn't wake up even once.
I was just the opposite.
What a night!
I haven't been in such torment since
the train to Nice went off the tracks.
You've gone off the tracks before?
How interesting!
You should see yourself in a mirror.
I'm confused.
What's going on here?
I don't know
how we got to this point,
but there's a limit to everything.
What can I say? For now
we have to offer them breakfast.
I'm sure they'll go home after that.
Of course.
I trust in their discretion.
I ran all over the place,
out of my mind.
A third-class car full of village folk
was squashed like an accordion.
What a slaughterhouse it was inside!
I must be unfeeling. The misery
of those wretches didn't move me.
I'm hungry-
Unfeeling? You fainted on viewing
the body of Prince Lurca in state.
You mustn't compare the two.
How could anyone be indifferent
before the majesty
of that admirable prince, our friend.
That noble profile!
Don't they eat breakfast here?
I think the lower classes
are less sensitive to pain.
Have you ever seen a wounded bull?
Not a trace of emotion.
I'm going to freshen up a bit.
We all look a fright.
This is so much fun.
Did you sleep well?
Why do you look at me like that, sister?
I must look awful.
You look more interesting than ever.
The disheveled look suits you.
Why do you look at me like that?
I must look awful.
You're more interesting than ever.
The disheveled look suits you.
What a set of ears.
It happened during the night.
He lost consciousness at dawn
but then came to a bit.
Why didn't you alert us immediately?
We must put him to bed upstairs.
Best not to move him right now.
We'll see what we can do.
Keep him covered up.
He looked a bit strange during dinner.
It may be nothing.
He's had a few of these incidents.
What do you think, Doctor?
Within a few hours
he'll be completely bald.
I don't understand.
I mean he has just a few hours to live.
That's awful.
Your predictions are never off.
I don't feel very well either.
Nonsense.
Do what you can to set out
a nice breakfast for our guests.
But, ma'am, it's so early.
The groceries haven't even arrived.
- Not even the milkman?
- No, and that's strange indeed.
Bring out the meat left over from dinner
and some hot coffee.
Lucia, dear,
where could we freshen up a bit?
I'm sorry I didn't see to that earlier.
Shall we go to my dressing room?
I bet they don't leave this room.
You see?
What do you make of this?
I honestly don't know.
It seems unreal...
or perhaps too normal.
I find it odd
no one but us is concerned.
Why didn't you and your Fiancée
leave last night?
I don't know.
Like everyone else.
What about you?
I don't know.
And that's what worries me.
After last night's party,
none of us made
the slightest effort to go home.
Why?
Was it normal for us to spend
the night in this room,
violating the most basic precepts
of good etiquette?
We turned this room
into a gypsy campground.
I find it very original.
I love when things deviate from the routine.
I saw what was happening,
and I didn't like it.
I kept quiet out of courtesy.
Come now, gentlemen.
No need to blow things out of proportion.
We were all under the spell
of the music, the friendly
conversation, the good cheer.
Nothing to be surprised at.
My feet have swollen.
For example, dear Lucia,
why did you have the butler
serve us breakfast here
and not in the dining room?
I don't know, Doctor.
I thought since
we're already gathered in here -
lt's clear the doctor likes
to play Sherlock Holmes.
Don't you think?
I have to get home.
My husband and children
must be worried. I'm leaving.
We'll go with you. I should say!
This is absurd! Let's go.
- Are you coming, Rita?
- No, not yet.
What would we do out at this hour?
For God's sake, you have children
in school just like me.
My children have a tutor at home:
Deacon Sampson.
A very cultured man
of great refinement.
Forgive me if I exaggerate,
but I think he may well be a saint,
though Cristian thinks -
Right, Cristian?
This is no time for talk of deacons.
What do we care about your -
Let's go.
Excuse me.
You know,
a cup of coffee wouldn't hurt.
I can't have my cigarette
on an empty stomach.
I'd like some too.
Will you join us, Blanca?
I think they're being hysterical,
getting so alarmed over this.
It's not the first time the morning's
found me at a party like this.
Excuse me, Lucia,
but there are no spoons for the sugar.
Forgive me.
Poor Julio has his hands full.
Julio, bring some small spoons.
Wouldn't you gentlemen like
some coffee or cold cuts?
Nothing, Julio.
Go do as you were told.
I think I'd better wait
to clear the dishes first.
Didn't you hear me?
I asked you to bring spoons.
- I took the liberty of asking -
- Enough. Do as I tell you.
What's wrong?
Don't you feel well?
Blanca, what's wrong?
Can I help you?
What do you think
about what just happened?
The butler's strange resistance
to carrying out his orders
confirms my observations.
Since last night, not one of us,
try as we might,
has been able to leave this room.
What's going on here,
Aranda, my friend?
There's a very sick man.
How is he, Doctor?
No use hiding the truth.
He's slipping into a coma.
If I only had some Coramine
or oil of camphor.
Cristian, out of simple humanity,
you must make an effort
to shatter this lethargy.
We must get Russel to where
he can receive appropriate care.
Dr. Conde is right.
We have to make an effort.
Which of you will try?
Why don't you try yourselves?
We'll be right behind you.
It's no use.
We're doomed!
Sister, why did you bring me here?
Don't be cruel.
It was you who made me come.
Calm down.
There's no more water.
A little coffee?
I'm dying of thirst.
Forgive me, but there's not
a single drop left.
This water smells a bit,
but it can't be bad.
Some lemon will take away
the bad taste.
No, thank you, Eduardo.
I prefer to wait.
I just don't get it.
There's got to be a solution.
We haven't all gone crazy, have we?
We've been here 24 hours,
yet no one's come for us.
They've forgotten about us.
The attitude of those outside
concerns me more than our situation.
What's going on with them?
They should have tried -
Unless they've all died
and we're the only survivors.
Why don't they come for us?
Calm down.
Don't lose your head.
Come now, gentlemen.
- Was I talking to you?
- Let's not get hysterical!
Shut up!
- I'll break a window.
- Don't bother. The door's right there.
This has something to do with the servants
running off. Why did they leave?
Gentlemen, I beg of you.
There's no need
for alarming hypotheses.
I'm sure the servants
had their reasons for leaving.
Yes, the same reasons
rats flee a sinking ship.
If you'll allow me,
they didn't even seem to know
why they were leaving.
An hour before everyone arrived,
they were fine.
So there's no explication for anything.
This is just great!
The most important thing
is to keep our heads.
There's nothing worse than panic.
This situation can't go on indefinitely.
We're not under some spell.
This isn't some sorcerer's castle.
Only by dispassionate analysis
can we get to the bottom
of our inaction.
Here's what I propose.
Let's have a moment of silence
and make a supreme effort,
a firm act of will demonstrating
our resolve to leave here -
Shut up, Nóbile.
That's the best thing you can do.
You led us into this trap.
You've made us the butt
of this cruel joke.
I have, my friend?
By inviting you to dinner?
By opening my doors to you?
Exactly.
You called us one by one
to come for dinner after the opera.
Such a cordial invitation.
“I'd be honored if you would - ”
Et Cetera.
We could have been sound asleep at home
or in some brothel, instead of here.
Tell me, what prompted
that untimely invitation?
Untimely? Why?
You were all delighted.
You yourself expressed pleasure
at such a warm reception.
Well, I take it back
and hereby state
that the only one responsible
for this degrading situation
is you.
Me?
I think you've lost your mind, Raul.
Edmundo's right.
You're a fool.
If you weren't a lady -
Look at the butler.
The water tastes fine to him.
My head aches.
What are the men here
doing about this?
Gabbing like streetwalkers.
Silvia, think of something
to get us all out of here.
I'll never set foot in this brothel again.
Don't be alarmed by his nervousness.
He's as sensitive as a little girl.
This is affecting him
more than the rest of us.
Don't upset me more
than I already am!
Can't you see how nervous I am?
I don't want to hear or see anyone.
I'm happy
that I won't see the extermination.
I wouldn't mind dying either.
But not like this,
surrounded by people,
unable to be alone with you.
That's my great torment:
the fact we can't be alone.
Actually, there is a way
to get away from the others.
It can't be. How?
I'll tell you when they're all asleep,
if indeed they decide to sleep.
When I lifted the lid,
I saw a steep cliff,
and a rushing stream far below.
And before I sat down,
an eagle flew by 40 feet below me.
The wind blew
a gust of dry leaves in my face.
I'm cold.
Consummatum est.
Really?
Just what we needed.
Our bodies should evaporate
when we die.
They'll lose heart
when they see him in the morning.
Roco could have gone in his place.
After all, what's one less conductor?
What shall we do?
- Did they see you?
- Yes. I don't know.
It doesn't matter.
Here it flows into the sea.
I can?!
Come further down!
Your Rictus! Horrible!
My love!
MY death!
Back into the fold!
- Nothing, sir.
- What would you like us to do?
I don't know,
but we can't go on like this forever.
Four days ago, the mayor felt
it most important
to establish communication
with those cut off inside.
He told me to install loudspeakers
so that those inside - if they're alive -
could hear and follow our instructions.
But he gave up the idea
when he realized how absurd it was.
Absurd? Why?
Seems very workable to me.
It would be even easier
to walk in the front door,
since nothing's stopping us,
yet no one has gone in yet.
That's absolutely right.
We sent in a fully equipped
team of men yesterday afternoon.
By 9:00 p.m.,
they were back in the barracks.
Not one of them
had gotten in the house.
But did they really try to get in?
No, that's the worst part.
We want to see what's going on inside.
We 're not dogs! Let us by!
One.
Two.
Three.
Four.
Why are you taking so long?
lt's so easy!
What is it?
- Let me go ahead. I've got a fever.
- So do I. Wait your turn.
You stepped on my foot!
Must people wear
their damned shoes everywhere?
Why is it taking so long?
Let's hope they haven't cut off
the water from outside.
228, 229...
Go help them!
Excuse me.
Get away! Women first!
Get back!
Let the ladies go first!
Didn't you hear him?
Stop pushing!
Form a line! One cup to start!
Later you can have all you want!
Drinking too quickly is dangerous,
especially when you're ill.
Use moderation.
Didn't you hear?
Women first! Get in line!
Here. Drink.
I won't allow you
to abuse my brother.
It's so nice and cold.
I'm hungry-
Don't eat.
Don't leave me alone!
He hasn't spoken in two days,
his eyes closed,
cut off from everyone,
including me.
And you say it's nothing.
I'll say it again, Alicia.
He's suffering
from the same thing we all are,
though perhaps, due to his age,
it's affected him more.
My hands are like dry branches.
We'd have been
better off not finding water.
We're only prolonging the end.
Then don't drink.
What are you eating?
Paper, miss.
Not very appetizing,
but it deceives the stomach.
If it didn't disgust me -
The taste isn't unpleasant,
Miss Beatriz.
My friends and I
ate it when we were kids.
Maybe 'cause we were bored in class.
I went to a Jesuit school.
Good people.
We were bored, like most kids are.
Paper is good.
They say it's made from leaves
and tender tree bark,
so it can't be harmful.
If you'd like to try -
Julio, come here.
Excuse me.
Hold this rag there.
Don't go! Don't leave me alone!
O prince, save me!
Our pact.
I can't take any more, Ana!
I can't stand seeing that monster
comb half her hair!
I hate her.
I prefer hunger and thirst
over putting up with her.
Why don't you comb it the right way?
Like this.
All the way down.
We won't put up
with your strange quirks.
Excuse me, Beatriz.
Did you happen to see a silver box
with some white capsules inside?
A box?
No, Rita. I'm sorry.
It's Cristian's medicine.
We guarded it like gold,
but we're all a bit-
I'll look around for it.
I'm hungry-
The dinner set on the table -
isn't there a lump of sugar left?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
There's been nothing for days.
Are you feeling better?
Try to hold on. lt'll turn up.
I'm sure someone found the box
and hid it again so I'd croak.
Don't say that.
You know what?
I do nothing but wonder,
“What are they doing now?”
I can't forget
my poor children either.
But I'm consoled knowing the deacon
will care for them as we would.
The deacon!
That's what bothers me most:
Our children are in that hypocrite's hands!
Don't be unfair.
Don't deny he was wooing you,
to use a euphemism.
But I'd best keep my mouth shut.
- No, speak!
Is our conversation that interesting?
I don't give a damn about you
and your pathetic marital problems.
You're an insolent boor,
and I've treated you as such
since we came here.
I couldn't care less.
I've despised you
since long before that.
Gentlemen, your attitudes -
We're all in the same boat.
It wouldn't hurt
to be polite to each other.
You should keep your mouth shut.
I agree.
You have to be a real cynic
to give advice to your victims.
My victims?
Why, Raul?
Tell me.
L'll feel better
if you give me a good reason.
I'm tired of explaining.
Edmundo, come with me.
Don't say any more.
Don't get them any more worked up.
Have a seat.
Please sit with me, Alvaro.
You're my friend.
I swear I'd give my life
to put an end to this -
to this situation.
Suffering horrifies me.
I've always tried to relieve it
wherever I could.
How could they believe that I -
lt's all right.
Calm down.
I'm hungry-
Think of a way to get us
out of this nightmare!
Only a miracle will get us out of here.
Why don't we organize a rosary?
Edmundo and I have promised
with all our hearts
to offer a solemn mass
if divine providence delivers us
from this captivity.
That unbearable stench!
It's horrible!
We're trying to get rid of it.
Don't go! Don't leave me alone!
I'm cold.
Blanca, your hair.
Remember what I told you.
- Doctor.
What can we do?
The poor thing is suffering terribly.
I can't take it anymore, Doctor.
Why don't you just kill me?
Don't talk nonsense.
You got through last night quite well.
Painkillers are as vital now
as food itself.
We don't even have an aspirin!
Don't leave me. I'm begging you.
Your presence comforts me.
If we get out of here, if I'm cured,
I want to go to Lourdes with you.
Promise me you'll go.
You will, won't you?
I promise.
We'll prostrate ourselves
at the feet of the Virgin,
because she's the one
who'll get us out of here.
Don't talk too much.
Don't excite yourself.
It can do you serious harm.
When we get to Lourdes,
I want you to buy me
one of those washable plastic Virgins.
You will, won't you?
Where did you get this?
We used to call this room
our “Theban paradise.”
We'd gather some friends
once in a while
and spend a few unforgettable hours.
Why didn't you tell me
you had this earlier?
Under the present circumstances,
imagine if the others should find out.
What once provided pleasure
can now serve to alleviate pain.
This contains Laudanine,
codeine and morphine.
Morphine? Where?
- What was that about?
- What's it to you?
What?
What are they hiding?
You'll see when everyone's asleep.
- I'm hungry.
- Quiet.
This is too much.
Have some consideration.
You smell like a hyena.
What did you say?
I said you smell like a hyena.
How dare you!
Why do you insult me?
You should be ashamed
to bring up things
the rest of us overlook
out of dignity.
Why are you afraid of the truth?
She smells bad.
So do you, and I and everybody.
We're living like pigs in a pigsty.
You disgust me, all of you!
I hate you!
Pay no attention to him.
He's on edge.
This will end very badly, my dear.
Everything I've most hated
since I was a child -
rudeness, violence, filth -
are now our inseparable companions.
Death is preferable to this anarchy!
What did she do?
Don't you see?
We should tie her hands.
- Get her out of here this minute!
- Sure, call an ambulance.
She's got a high fever.
Use cold compresses
and change them every five minutes.
Don't cry, Alicia. lt's over now.
They'll watch so that nothing
like that happens again.
Will it make me nauseous?
Yes, but it'll ease your pain.
You'll sleep well tonight.
What day is today?
What?
How long have we been here?
Over a month, isn't it?
Not that long.
We couldn't have lasted
that long without food.
It feels like we've always been here.
I have the same feeling.
And we'll be here forever.
Unless -
What?
Unless we escape together,
lose ourselves in the shadows.
You don't answer?
Wherever you go,
I'll go too, Eduardo.
Look.
Just as we thought.
What's that?
- What is it now?
- Quiet.
Who stepped on my hand?
- What happened?
- I don't know. I must've been dreaming.
I'm not blind, sir.
- What the hell are you saying?
- You're no gentlemen. You're an incubus!
Cristian, please.
You're making a fool of yourself.
You'd better watch your tongue.
Calm down, gentlemen.
What's happened, gentlemen?
The colonel sneaks around
in the dark like a thief.
You swine!
Let's settle this once and for all.
I challenge you to a duel.
I accept.
What a madhouse.
No one can get any sleep.
Look at him.
Another mess N6bile's gotten us into.
Don't you understand he has an ulcer?
This is madness!
Calm down first.
Then you can talk.
Just don't come to blows.
This is below us.
Gentlemen, remember your upbringing.
I'd like to know
if Nóbile started this.
We have to show him
that he can't mess with us.
I prefer not to answer.
Fine - until we run out of patience.
Try to calm him down.
Talk to him.
I can never forgive him for this.
He's shamed me.
Stop fighting
and find us something to eat!
Leave me alone!
Alvaro, how could you?
Even the best among us
are losing their heads.
Please have pity on me!
I apologize, to you and everyone.
I don't how I could have done that.
I wasn't myself.
Once again, I apologize.
Allow me to make a suggestion
that I hope will be satisfactory.
To avoid unfortunate
incidents like this,
I suggest
the women sleep on one side of the room
and the men on the other.
Excuse me, but you're speaking
to gentlemen.
Forget him. He's a degenerate.
He insists on insulting us.
Edmundo's right.
I just thought, for everyone's sake -
Don't say any more.
Don't you understand -
There you go.
Now, remember:
Keep your wits about you.
Let's go.
Hey, where are you going?
This is Don Cristian's family
just here for a look,
so the children can see the house
where their parents are.
Go ahead.
I know I can go in
and speak to them -
if they're still alive -
then come back out and give
an account of the situation.
Are you sure?
- Try me.
- Over here.
You won't accept my proposal?
I'll go to the press,
to the powers that be.
I must be heard.
I'm certain I can solve this problem.
Another lunatic.
Go on. Don't just stand there.
- Why do you stop?
- Keep walking.
The important thing
is that he keep walking.
Go on!
- Go on, boy!
Go in!
Why didn't you keep going?
You know how kids are.
- Go on. Try it again.
No. Let's go.
If we don't want to sink
into utter debasement,
we must maintain rigorous hygiene
and strict order during our stay here.
Today we'll organize a cleaning team.
How are you feeling?
Fine.
My head's a little -
Poor man.
If it weren't for you and Leticia -
They're savages.
I can't thank those two enough
for standing up for you.
It was a premonition.
Before going to the opera that night,
I heard an insistent voice telling me,
“Take the keys with you.”
The keys?
In Kabbalah we use the word “keys”
for the magical objects that can unlock
the doors to the unknown.
Take this, Blanca.
Hold it tight.
Like this.
And Silvia.
You hold this the opposite way.
Like this.
Victim!
I'm not feeling anything.
I need the blood of an innocent.
We'll have to wait
for the last lamb to be sacrificed.
What is it?
Look!
In the closet.
Friends.
What's wrong?
That's it.
Doctor, in there.
What's going on?
Leandro, Colonel, help me.
Keep everyone back.
Alvaro, let me see.
- How did they do it?
- That doesn't matter.
Please stay back.
What's wrong with you?
I was thinking...
of the look on your face
if I pushed you
into the salon.
Try it and I'll kill you.
What does that mean?
They've probably lost
the few wits they had left.
It's the Masonic cry for help.
Any Mason in hearing distance
is supposed to come to his aid.
But in this case,
unless the bear's a Mason...
Cristian, the time has come.
The unpronounceable word.
H.
- l.
- H.
- O.
Help!
Quick, close the windows!
It's every man for himself!?
There'll be millions of people
in the room any minute.
I13 very late, my son.
Come to bed.
I'm not sleepy.
What a multitude!
He died in a state of mortal sin.
My beloved son!
I'll never see you again!
Look there.
Up on the peak! See him?
The pope.
Yes, it's him.
Full of majesty and power,
like a warrior.
I'll adjust the pillow for you.
Good night, son.
- Good night, Mom.
Nothing. Same as before.
Quiet as a tomb.
And that yellow flag?
They've quarantined the house
like in an epidemic.
I'd prefer typhus.
Pablo!
Well, well, what wind
blew you this way?
The same as you, chef.
Any news?
- None. Unless they've all croaked.
- You think so?
They say foul odors
reach as far as the street.
Maybe everything
we left in the kitchen rotted.
Don't shoot!
Don't kill him, please!
He's very tame.
I'm a servant in this house.
Did you tell the cook
and the maids we were coming?
Me? I didn't say a word.
- Then what are they doing here?
- Beats me.
Let's go find out.
Maybe there's some news.
Raul said all this will end
when Nóbile dies.
When the spider dies,
the web unravels.
If he had any decency,
he'd know what to do.
He and Leticia
have hidden themselves away.
I order you to be quiet.
lt's the decent thing to do.
And you gentlemen, speak openly.
Let us all know what you're plotting.
We want to put an end to him.
Put an end to him?
Have you gone mad?
This is absurd.
Completely unreasonable.
We don't want reason.
We want out of here.
If you want a fight, you'll have one!
Alvaro, step aside.
Our quarrel's not with you or the doctor.
Necessity justifies our actions.
- Kill him!
- Once and for all!
First hear me out.
Kill the doctor too.
He stands in our way.
Consider the terrible consequences
of your actions.
This vile act of aggression
does not stand alone.
It means the very end of human dignity
and reverting to savage animals.
Step aside, Doctor,
or I won't be responsible
for my actions.
Enough talking! Get him!
Enough, Raul!
Don't complicate matters more!
I told you to stay out of this!
Look, it's Nóbile!
There's no need for violence.
No use fighting over something
so easily achieved.
Thank you, Leticia.
Edmundo, wait.
Stay where you are.
What is it, Leticia?
I don't know.
Actually, I do.
It's so... extraordinary.
How long have we been here?
I don't know. I've lost track.
But think how many times
each of us has changed places...
during this horrible eternity here.
Like pieces on a chess board,
moved thousands of times.
Even the furniture.
We've moved it around
a hundred times.
But look now.
Right now all of us -
people and furniture -
are exactly where we were that night.
Or am I hallucinating again?
Tell me, Alvaro.
Tell me, all of you!
It's true.
I was right here.
Weren't you at my side?
And to my left -
- Me, just like I am now.
And we were on this sofa.
I held your hand in mine.
Who can remember?
After dinner, I sat down at the piano,
where I am now.
And you were there.
That's right.
Fine.
But what difference
does any of this make?
Blanca, do you remember
the piece you were playing?
Perfectly well.
The last piece I played
was a sonata by Paradisi.
Play it now.
Just the ending.
You hear me? Play it.
Play it.
You were standing behind me.
Stand up.
You all applauded.
You stepped down from the piano.
Some of your friends approached.
Who spoke first?
Try to remember!
You must remember!
A delightful performance.
Answer her, Blanca.
What would you have said?
Pity there was no harpsichord.
It would have sounded perfect.
Please play some Scarlatti for us.
It's too late to play
any more, isn't it?
It's 3:00 in the morning.
You'll have to forgive me.
It's late, and I'm tired.
Exactly. We're all tired.
It's very late,
and we must be going.
Let's go!
Follow me, everybody!
Come on! Follow me!
This way!
It's good. ls it from inside?
I've only got two bottles left.
Look! A light!
Camila, come here!
Look, a light!
It's them.
- Holy Virgin!
- Let's go in.
- You first.
Why don't we wait
until after the faithful have left?
After? Why?
Well...
Father.
Somethings wrong.
We should let
everyone else leave first.
That's what I told you.
I forgot my prayer book.
- Why don't they leave?
- Let me by.
Let me explain.
- You first.
- There's no rush.
This is too much. Come on.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from MY-SUBS