From the 11th century,
throughout the Middle Ages
the city of Santiago de Compostela
in Spain
was the goal of a great pilgrimage
which still exists today.
Every year, more than 500,000 pilgrims
started out on foot.
They came from all over Europe.
They came to worship
at the tomb of the apostle James.
At the end of the 16th century
at the time of the wars of religion,
the Bishop of Santiago
had the remains of the apostle concealed.
They were rediscovered by chance
at the end of the 19th century.
The Papacy hesitated
before authenticating them.
In the 7th century A.D.
- according to legend -
a star led shepherds
to the place where the body was.
Hence the name Compostela.
Campus Stellae, the Field of the Star.
In the West
the Milky Way is also called
"The Way of St James".
THE MILKY WAY
- Did you think those bastards would stop?
- Forget it.
- I'm knackered.
- And I'm hungry.
- Got any bread?
- You know I haven't.
Alms...
Alms, sir...
- Do you have money?
- No, sir.
Then you shall have none.
- And you?
- Me?
Yes, I have a little.
Then you shall have much.
- Are you going on a pilgrimage?
- Yes, sir.
To Spain? To Santiago de Compostela?
Who told you?
Go, take a whore for a wife.
And bear children of that whore.
Name the first: "Ye are not my people"
and the second: "No more mercy".
You understand?
Look!
- Where did he come from?
- Must have been under his cloak.
- How'd he know where we're going?
- What do you care? It's the bill that counts.
- I should have shown him my money.
- Why did he give it to me?
He liked your beard.
It inspires confidence.
I guess so...
Reminds me
of what my mother used to say.
You're dirty...
Go play with your brothers.
Don't shave, my son.
A beard suits you.
Wise woman, your mother.
Can you sell me a cigarette?
Take one.
- The bill is for both of us.
- I appreciate it.
What are you doing here?
What happened?
You've got blood on your hands.
And there, look.
There too.
What's your name?
You on your own?
Where are your parents?
Cat got your tongue? Here.
A drop of wine will do you good.
Pierre, come on, let's go.
You should go home.
Shall we take you back to the village?
We can't do anything.
Don't bother, they won't stop.
Get in! What are you waiting for?
- Going far?
- To Spain, sir.
That's lucky,
I am going to the border.
- Do you mind driving at night?
- Not in the least.
- This is a bed fit for a queen.
- It's really comfortable.
God Almighty. God Almighty...
- You want some?
- No, thank you.
- You from around here?
- Yes. Nearby...
- I'll drop you off...
- Thanks, but I like walking at night.
In any case
the miracles of Christ have nothing
miraculous about them.
- They are quite commonplace.
- Oh really?
These days, science explains everything.
Miracles are natural phenomena,
whether you like it or not.
I think science is more than ever
in accord with scripture.
That's why the whole world
is Catholic these days.
- How do you mean, Catholic?
- Yes, the whole world.
- What about the Muslims?
- They're certainly Catholic.
- And the Jews?
- Even more so.
What do you want?
Do you have any leftovers?
We have money.
All right, wait.
Good day to you all...
Hello.
Invite them in, it's cold outside.
- I didn't want to disturb you.
- Of course not.
Come in.
- Thank you, sir.
- Sit down there.
You will never make me believe, Father,
that the body of Christ
can be contained in a piece of bread.
Be careful.
His body is not "contained".
In the sacrament of Eucharist,
the wafer is the body of Christ.
There is transubstantiation,
which is altogether different.
I would like to understand, but I don't.
It's beyond me.
The Host is the body of Christ, that's all.
You must not believe it
to be merely a symbol...
of the body of Christ.
That was the belief of the Albigensians,
the Calvinists - and others.
It is a grave error.
I say Christ is in the Host
like the hare is in this pâté.
- What?
- Yes.
It's hare and, at the same time,
it's a pâté.
You've understood nothing!
You speak like 16th-century heretics
known as Pateliers.
No, you must believe
Christ's words to the letter.
It's something I just can't conceive of.
All the more reason:
"Credo quia absurdum."
Religion without mystery
is no religion.
To sum up...
Heresies which attack a mystery
may seduce superficial spirits
but they will never succeed
in obscuring the truth.
- Father, I have a question.
- Yes?
What becomes of Christ
once in our stomach?
What are you doing here?
- Where are your papers?
- Here.
Dupont...
Duval...
Get out of here!
We've had enough of you.
Good night.
Imbeciles.
Not even a crust of bread?
A little charity, sergeant.
You can't enforce the law
and be charitable.
- It's strange...
- What is?
I have the feeling the Pateliers were right.
It's a revelation.
I feel that the body of Christ is in the Host
like the hare in this pâté.
I'm absolutely sure of it.
- But you just said the opposite.
- Me?
Yes, you!
Out for a walk again, Father?
You promised to be good.
- We're going to have to lock you up.
- I wanted a breath of air.
No, don't bother. I promise, I'll be good...
- You know me...
- That's just it!
If you insist...
Strange, he seemed normal enough.
- Is he really a priest?
- Yes, of course.
He was a priest in Chevilly
until last year, then...
- You must have contradicted him.
- Perhaps.
I knew it.
Touch my hand.
Cold hands, warm heart...
A warm heart...
- How old are you?
- Fifty nine.
And... you still can?
At my age...
- The first thing when I get to Santiago...
- OK, OK.
Do you hear that?
Sounds like people talking.
Do you reckon?
Tu ergo nil intelleges.
Regiam incipit.
- What's he saying?
- I don't know.
Quisnam est tu?
Undenam venis?
Quicquam quaesis pax tibi?
Venite, attamen,
deusque videbis,
nec verbum dicere tibi recepit.
- Who is he then?
- No idea.
A shepherd who talks like a priest.
I'm going to sleep.
Good night.
Brethren...
Good tidings from Rome.
The Emperor Gratian
has restored Priscillian
to the bishopric of Avila.
So, we are justified.
The heretic is not I
but he who sits on the throne of St Peter
and who has taken the title of Pope.
Our doctrine is justified
and soon we will proclaim it
in broad daylight, to the whole world.
Let us give thanks unto God.
Our soul is of divine essence.
Like the angels it was created by God
and placed beneath the sway of the stars.
In punishment for sin,
it was united to a body...
This body is the work of the devil
who exists from the beginning
like God himself.
Matter so unworthy and base
as our body,
God cannot have created.
The body is the prison of the soul.
The soul, in order to free itself...
must gradually become detached from it.
The body must be humiliated, despised...
unceasingly submitted
to the pleasure of the flesh.
In order that the purified soul
may return after death
to its celestial abode.
Swear never to betray this secret.
We swear.
It is not I who have harvested thee,
nor ground thee.
It is not I who have kneaded thee
nor put thee in the oven.
I am innocent
of all your sufferings.
And I wish that those
who have inflicted them
may know the same agony.
What's that?
You scared?
- I don't like storms.
- That won't protect you.
How do you know?
- You believe in God?
- You know I do.
Watch this...
Where are you going?
Hey! You hear me?
If you exist, go ahead!
You fool! Right between the eyes!
One, two, three...
See?
It didn't get me!
Imbecile, do you think God's
at your disposal?
- As I was saying earlier...
- What?
- Everyone ought to believe in God.
- Yes.
There have always been atheists,
but they're mad.
- Or they're not real atheists.
- How so?
Because a reasonable man
cannot believe there is no God.
- And why not?
- Why not?
The proof is in the Bible.
Psalms 13, verse 1...
"It is the fool who hath said in his heart:
'There is no God'"
- Well that settles it.
- Yes, it is very convincing.
There is no God.
All religions are based
on a false premise, Thérèse:
the necessity of God the Creator.
But this Creator does not exit.
All religions bear the emblem
of imposture and stupidity.
But if one especially deserves
our contempt and hatred,
it is the barbarous law
of Christianity,
in which we were both born.
You rely on an avenging God.
Don't be a fool, Thérèse.
Such a god is merely a chimera...
to be found in the fantasies of madmen.
He is a phantom invented by
the wickedness of men
whose only purpose is to deceive us
or raise us up against each other.
If this Lord existed,
considering the imperfections of His works,
could we do anything but despise Him
or outrage Him?
If there were a God,
there would be less evil on earth.
Look, your ear is still bleeding.
Is it a crime to depict the bizarre inclinations
with which Nature inspires us?
No, Thérèse, there is no God,
Nature is sufficient to herself.
This godlike phantom
is nothing but a revolting platitude
which does not deserve
a moment's consideration.
A pitiful extravagance
which the mind rejects
and the heart rebels at,
which should've emerged from darkness
only to re-enter it forever!
If your God exists, I hate Him!
Yes, God exists! God exists!
Only sons of bitches don't believe in God.
If debauchees deny God,
it's to satisfy their passions
for who can deny the obvious?
What I don't get is how Christ
could be both God and man.
It is difficult, I admit...
But when the Devil takes the shape
of a wolf, for instance,
he is a wolf, but he's still the Devil.
- It's somewhat the same with Christ.
- But...
- Clean up the cloakroom, it's getting late.
- Right away, sir.
If Jesus was God,
how could He be born and die?
It's a fundamental question.
How could He born and die?
How many heresies have been
on this subject!
Some have said Christ was only God.
That His human form was an illusion.
- So didn't He eat?
- No, He only pretended to.
He didn't suffer - or die.
Marcion was of this opinion.
- Nestorius, too, wasn't he?
- He was.
They even said Christ watched
His own death on the cross,
Simon having taken his shape.
Other heretics maintained the contrary,
that Christ was not God but man.
Get rid of this, it's rotten.
But He could laugh and cough, couldn't He?
They always show Him so dignified.
Walking slowly, his hands like this.
He must have walked
like anyone else.
We're late. What time is it?
- Almost the 6th hour.
- I'm hungry.
- Master!
- What?
The guests have arrived
and your mother and brethren also.
Behold - my mother and my brethren.
For whosoever shall do the will,
of my father,
the same is my brother,
my sister and my mother!
If He was a man, He was
like the rest of us, wasn't He?
At the beginning...
I didn't dare to believe...
but afterwards I was very happy.
He is marvellous.
Just a moment...
Once a rich man learned
that his steward...
was wasting his wealth.
So he said unto him...
"Thou mayst no longer care for my goods."
The steward said to himself:
"What shall I do?
"I'm not strong enough to dig.
And to beg I am ashamed
"Ah, I know what to do
"so that others may receive me."
And?
One moment.
He summoned his master's debtors
and said to the first: "What dost thou owe?"
"100 measures of oil."
"Set down 50," said the steward.
And to another he said:
"What dost thou owe?"
"100 measures of wheat."
"Set down 80," the steward commanded.
And the master praised his dishonest
steward for his shrewdness.
For the children of this world are
wiser among themselves
than the children of light.
Come.
- They have no wine...
- What has it to do with thee and I?
Mine hour is not yet come!
Whatsoever he sayeth unto you, do it.
Fill the water pots with water and serve it.
They shall have wine.
No doubt about it,
he was a man like the rest.
In the 4th century, after the Council of Nicea,
many Christians fought and died
in order to prove whether Christ was like
unto the Father, or consubstantial...
Good day, madam, sir...
This way, please.
Thank you.
Do you mind if I ask
what you were speaking about?
- Oh, about one thing and another,
- But about what?
We were speaking of Christ
of His double nature.
You've studied for the priesthood?
No, but the subject interests me.
And we were wondering how it was that
although there were so many healers
and prophets at the time
like Simon the Sorcerer for example,
Christ was the only one
who succeeded finally.
- Why, because only He was God!
- Quite so, Madame Garnier.
- The oysters are splendid today.
- Oysters, why not?
Excuse me.
Who gave you permission?
Sir, we were just going to ask
if you have some...
All we wanted was...
Out! Go on, get a move on.
Worth a try.
Excuse me, ladies and gentlemen,
this is Jean, I'm Pierre.
Could you spare a little...
- Pass me the chicken.
- Thank you.
Thanks a lot.
Going far?
- To Spain, madam.
- On foot?
- Sometimes on foot, sometimes walking!
- Do you want a drop of wine?
I won't say no.
Puts a little fire in your belly.
- Ladies and gentlemen, to your health!
- And to yours!
My dear friends...
I am very happy to present
our little yearly performance
that we prepared for you
and I ask your kind indulgence.
As you all know,
this year has been a difficult one.
Violence is everywhere, these days,
but thanks be to God,
our classes have been undisturbed.
In a few moments,
the older girls will present a witty comedy
written especially for us
by Mr Pontier, our young pharmacist.
Before that, you will hear a recital
by years 10 and 11
from the works of our great poets:
Racine, Lamartine and Henri de Régnier.
But first, to show that in
the young hearts confided to our care
religion is a living reality,
here is a brief prologue by our young girls.
Go on...
Brigitte.
If anyone holds it permissible for
a Christian to have several wives...
and that having several wives is not
forbidden by divine law...
Anathema upon him!
If anyone holds that the sacrifice of the Mass
is a blasphemy against the sacrifice
of Christ who died upon the cross...
Anathema upon him!
If anyone holds that God's
commandments are impossible to keep
even for one who is justified
and in a state of grace...
Anathema upon him!
Aim...
Fire!
Is there a shooting-range near here?
No, it's me. I was imagining
they were shooting a Pope.
What?
You will certainly see a lot of things
but never the shooting of a Pope.
If anyone holds that God hates
the new-born baby...
and that He punishes him
for the sin of Adam...
Anathema upon him!
Many Christians
wonder why God permits
innocent animals to suffer...
Many also wonder
why God did not make man herbivorous
like the sheep and the giraffe.
Well, little Sylvie, the first in her class,
will give you the answer.
If anyone holds that meats
God has given us are unclean
and except from a desire
for self-mortification
abstains from eating them...
Anathema upon him!
Where did that originate?
At the Council of Nicea...
At the Council of Braga, in 567 AD.
I say and I maintain
that Purgatory is never mentioned
in the scriptures,
that confirmation and Extreme Unction
were not instituted by Christ!
Anathema!
You shall die
for you have relapsed into your errors.
But you have one chance of escaping Hell.
Say "I recant" and your soul shall be saved.
I cannot.
I would like to, but I cannot.
I cannot...
Take him away.
- Father?
- Yes, my son.
- One thing troubles me.
- Yes?
The burning of heretics
may it not go against
the will of the Holy Spirit?
It is the secular justice of men
that punishes them.
Not because they are heretics
but for their sedition.
But then, those whose brothers
have been burnt
will burn others, and so on.
Each one believing he possesses the truth.
Why these millions of deaths?
Do you know what you are saying?
I am not sure.
Yet you persist?
No...
I submit, Father.
What's the matter?
Thought I'd sit down,
my feet are killing me.
Let me see.
I'll fix that.
- They'll never make it.
- It's better than nothing.
Go on. Hope you crash, you bastard!
- Think he's still alive?
- No. Not a chance.
What shall we do now?
We better call the police.
I wouldn't...
They'll hold you up for hours.
Just leave.
Where did you come from?
I don't understand a thing.
- Are you hurt?
- I got in when you hoped he'd crash.
I always get in at the last moment.
- What about us?
- Go away!
I already told you.
Who are you?
A labourer...
A labourer who is never out of work.
There are millions of us down there.
Down where?
There were tears are of no avail
and repentance no succour.
Where prayers go unheeded
and good resolutions are rejected.
Where no time is given for repentance.
For once under the veil of death,
it is too late to repent.
One day we shall be saved.
On Judgement Day,
God will have mercy on us.
You with the sore feet...
Look.
He won't be needing them.
Be careful.
They'll see that your shoes are new.
I'll fix that for you.
Don't move.
My daughter, I beg of you...
- Renounce.
- No, Mother.
I will suffer like our saviour.
Look, the Earl, our benefactor,
has come to dissuade you.
Are you in pain?
No. I feel nothing. Now the other hand.
My daughter,
Christ does not require this of you.
It's closed, you can't go in.
What were you going to do in there?
- Who us?
- Yes, you.
- We wanted to visit the chapel.
- Do you know why it's closed?
No...
This convent is contaminated by
the last of the Jansenists...
They commit the most fearful
sacrilege in there.
There are convulsionaries, fanatics.
Don't go in!
How do you feel, my daughter?
Very well...
Now go. All of you.
Don't you want anything?
I wish to be alone.
A word, sir...
Who are you?
I am Father Billuard,
of the Company of Jesus.
Isn't it at night that Jesuits
come out, like rats?
What language!
It serves the likes of you!
Now, I'm in a hurry...
I know where you come from,
what goes on in this holy place.
I also know that you still deny
the true doctrine of Grace.
In the fallen state of nature
inward grace is irresistible.
Do you dare repeat that
in a more retired spot?
Sir, I am at your disposal.
Follow me.
Gentlemen, will you act as our witnesses?
What for?
In a duel.
We don't know anything about it!
You will judge according
to your conscience.
Come.
Now do you dare repeat that?
Yes! In the fallen state of nature
inward grace is irresistible.
Grace does not always
obtain its object.
One moment, please.
Can you deny that one of the elect
has grace sufficient
- for the accomplishment of good?
- Yes, I deny it.
The will is submitted
to preponderant delectation.
To deserve and not deserve
in the corrupted state of nature
it is not necessary for man to have free will
exempt from necessity.
To deserve and not deserve
in the corrupted state of nature
man must be delivered from all necessity,
absolute and even relative.
It is a semi-Pelagian error
to hold that Jesus Christ dies for all men.
You blaspheme
against Divine Goodness.
He died so that all might be saved.
Antecedent will is mere wishful thinking.
I have no control
over my thought and free will.
My free will is an illusion.
What does "free will" mean?
It means that between two actions,
a good and a bad one, you can choose.
Yes, but God knows everything, doesn't He?
If I choose the bad,
He knows it beforehand.
Yes, He has always known.
How am I free if what I am going to do
is fixed ahead of time?
That's free will.
God's grace helps
you to choose the good.
But He decided I would do evil.
He decided, not me!
Why did He choose evil?
God's designs are impenetrable.
Hey, look.
We're for it if they want our passports.
- For the French, an identity card is enough.
- We'll see.
La Concha de San Sebastian -
what does that mean?
San Sebastian's shell, isn't it?
- I prefer the Riviera.
- Ever been there?
- No, but I've heard.
- It's strictly for the rich.
Come on or we'll never get to Santiago.
Where are you going?
Straight ahead.
- If you don't mind...
- What?
There's an inn over there.
Take the donkey and wait for us.
- Till when?
- Tonight. We're going to the village.
Here, we're in a hurry.
- It's gold!
- Of course.
- What if you don't come?
- We will.
- Won't we?
- Of course.
If we don't, keep everything.
Here. Until tonight.
Thou didst die in the order of sanctity,
having received the last sacrament.
Thou wert for us already one of the blessed.
Alas.
After thy death, all thy errors were
discovered in this manuscript.
Many believed thee.
Blood flowed, be it on thy head.
May God whose mercy is infinite
take pity on the soul.
Remove him.
Hear me...
This is the dogma, the sole truth.
There is only one God, in Trinity:
Father, Son and Holy Spirit.
The Father is neither created
nor engendered,
the Son is not created but engendered,
the Holy Spirit is neither
created nor engendered
but proceedeth from the Father and Son.
The Son and the Holy Spirit exist
from all eternity like the Father.
Whosoever strays from this dogma
shall be declared a heretic.
God is one.
Listen, all of you!
They are deceiving you!
The one God cannot be divided in Three.
Father, Son and Holy Spirit
are only names we give to Him.
It was the Father made flesh
who suffered.
The Father who died on the cross!
The Son and the Holy Spirit
are coeternal with the Father
by an immanent and necessary
operation of the Father.
The Father is the only God!
The Holy Spirit is merely an archangel.
Seize them!
Let me do this,
I know this door.
Let's see.
- Did you get it?
- No.
What was it?
Something stretched out, with no paws.
I heard there were sleepwalkers
in the forest.
I haven't seen them yet.
They only come out
under a full moon.
- What's that?
- Let's see.
- Know what it is?
- It's like what the blind make.
It's a rosary. It's what the Papists
use to pray the Virgin.
Is that right?
Get ready.
Give me a light.
- What time is it?
- Quarter to seven.
Time flies.
Seems like yesterday.
We have inherited the fruit
of their travail.
The day of trial approaches.
We cannot any longer
await a miracle.
Your hear that?
There! Look!
What is it?
- You see her?
- Yes, but...
Look, she's moving!
It was her! I'm sure of it!
You're tired. It was a hallucination.
And that?
- How's things?
- Fine.
What will it be?
I don't know... Some chorizo.
Same for me.
And a pitcher of red.
- Did you sell the tractor?
- Are you kidding? They still use mules!
- And they're right.
- You sound like my grandpa.
It's just my opinion.
- Want a taste?
- With pleasure.
Here. Tell me what you think.
- Delicious! Do you cure it?
- Of course.
- A little more?
- No, thank you.
Good evening, everybody.
- Everything all right?
- Everything's fine, thank you.
Seems two suspicious-looking
characters came in here.
Do you have your papers?
- Yes, sir.
- Let's see.
I don't want to see you
here tomorrow morning
- Father... Bit chilly this evening.
- Indeed. I came in to warm up.
- A little ham and wine?
- It's very tempting.
It's excellent, I recommend it.
I heard you were promoted to Sergeant.
Not bad, at your age.
- It was expected. I've earned it.
- Quite a career.
- So you're to be a father again soon?
- We're not rich.
Here they are.
We'd given up on you!
- We saw the donkey outside.
- Put him in the stable?
Yes, he must be hungry.
Gentlemen...
- Good hunting?
- No. Nothing all day.
That's unusual.
Have you got your permits?
- Of course.
- Let's have a look.
All in order.
Right. Shall we go?
- Thanks for everything.
- Don't mention it.
See you. Goodbye. Father...
Evening, all.
- Do you want to eat?
- No, just a room.
Fine.
- Good evening, Father.
- Good evening.
What's the matter with you?
You're crying?
Can I help you?
You should tell him...
- Father...
- Be quiet.
- Do you see this rosary?
- Yes, of course.
- The Virgin Mary just gave it to me.
- The Blessed Virgin?
- Yes.
- When?
A half-hour ago.
I saw her. She appeared to me.
I scorned her, I was insulting her.
Faith does not come to us
by reason, Father,
but by the heart.
Of course. Here, keep it.
A miracle is always very moving.
But you must not let yourself
get in such a state.
The Blessed Virgin has appeared
thousands of times.
All over the world.
She has performed countless miracles.
Shall I tell you one?
Oh, yes.
Come, if it interests you...
You too, come. All of you.
Gather around.
Now listen carefully.
A very long time ago
not very far from here,
at a Carmelite convent,
there was a young sister,
very good and very trustworthy,
the Treasurer of the convent, so to speak.
She was very orderly, very responsible
and profoundly devoted
to the Blessed Virgin.
Now listen carefully.
Unfortunately
one day, a young man seduced her.
Some say it was the Devil.
But that hasn't been established.
She fell madly in love with him
and decided to flee from the convent.
Are you all with me?
Just before her departure, one night,
the poor girl, in tears,
flung herself down
at the altar of the Virgin,
begging for forgiveness
in a passionate prayer.
She placed at the feet of the statue
the key of the convent safe.
Then she fled.
Now listen carefully.
She lived for a long time
- excuse me - with her seducer.
For years.
They had children
- sons and daughters -
but in the depths of her heart
she was unhappy.
One morning, she decided
to return to the convent.
She was ready to accept her punishment.
She arrived without warning,
it was morning,
and going through the chapel,
she looked at the statue of the Virgin.
Now listen carefully.
The key to the safe was still there!
Then she went in, full of trepidation.
But the nuns didn't even look
surprised to see her.
As if she had never left.
She went back to her chores
and no one ever said anything to her.
Do you know why?
Because, during her absence,
the Virgin had taken her shape
and had fulfilled all her obligations.
A most beautiful miracle.
That's a wonderful tale.
Really, Father, it is beautiful.
There are even more beautiful ones.
I could go on all night.
There is no mystery sweeter
or more profound
than that of the Virgin Mary.
It's getting late. I must go.
- Good night.
- Good night, Father.
Follow me, please.
Coming...
What are you doing?
One does not place a candle
under a bushel
but on a candlestick to give light.
No, your room is just opposite.
- There's room for two.
- No!
- Why not?
- If you don't like it, you can go.
Here.
Gentlemen...
A word of advice.
If anyone knocks, don't open the door.
- Why not?
- Just don't open it.
To anyone.
Even me.
Good night.
Good evening.
Good evening, miss.
Please don't let me disturb you.
Thank you.
You're very beautiful.
You're very kind, thank you.
You seem puzzled.
- Your name?
- Rodolphe.
Have you come far?
Yes. On foot.
Have a rest.
It's quiet here.
You will like it.
Who is it?
- Me... Open the door please!
- No!
- Just a second.
- Out of the question.
Listen, the Father is here.
He came back just to speak to you.
- Open up.
- No!
It's me again, my child.
Excuse me for bothering you so late. But...
When we spoke about the Blessed Virgin,
I forgot several important points.
- Open up. I won't be long.
- No. You can speak from where you are.
- But why?
- Because...
As you wish.
The chair, please.
Thank you.
You cannot conceive the richness
of mysteries concerning the Virgin.
Think about it...
First, the Immaculate Conception.
She was conceived without original sin.
Then the birth of Christ
commanded by the operation
of the Holy Spirit
and the precious virginity of Mary!
Imagine... Do you follow me?
- Yes, Father.
- We do. With great attention.
Then listen carefully...
Imagine that she remained a virgin,
before, during
and after the birth of Our Saviour.
Certain heretics have denied it.
Photin and Cleobule, for example.
But dogma must be believed.
Christ was born of His mother
without breaking her virginity.
Do you comprehend that?
Yes, as thought springs
from the brain without breaking the skull.
As a sunbeam
traverses a pane of glass.
Very good.
Finally, imagine her Assumption.
She rose into heaven,
in flesh and blood, borne by angels,
and from on high she acts
on behalf of sinners.
Amazing.
The dogma of the Assumption
is perhaps the most beautiful.
A glass of water, please.
Well, remember,
if you want her to love you
that nothing is so repugnant to God
as the sin of impurity.
Why is it that Jesus did not reply to Herod
or even raise His eyes?
Because Herod was a Fornicator
and Jesus didn't wish to look at him.
Very good, my daughter.
Avoid lechers
as you would the plague.
Remember the odious sects
of the Adamites, the Nicolaites
who held their wives in common
and delivered themselves up to debauchery.
It is written: " The house
of the impure woman
"is the house of the dead."
Yes, my children.
- Now open the door.
- You're wasting you time, Father.
Very well!
- Father?
- Yes?
Suppose we decide to get married?
- Married?
- Yes.
That would be quite different.
But hear the words of the Apostle Paul:
"It is good if a man takes no wife."
You see?
Furthermore you must know
that certain theologians,
St Thomas, for instance,
have sustained that even in wedlock
carnal union is venal sin.
I am a virgin, Father,
and therefore, perhaps, without sin.
Don't say that!
My child, no one is without sin.
Not even the Holy Virgin?
Of course. She was
incapable of committing sin.
But do you know that Origen,
St Basil and St John Chrysostom
- maintained that she had certain faults?
- Which ones?
A little vanity perhaps,
the desire to be esteemed.
Perhaps at the Annunciation
she doubted the words of the angel.
And finally at the foot of the Cross,
her faith weakened slightly.
Well, now I will let you sleep.
- Good night, miss.
- Good night.
- My son, do you hear me?
- Yes...
- Open the door, I must speak to you.
- It's unnecessary, I heard everything.
- Open up. Just five minutes.
- I said no and I mean it.
Well, let you friend come out then.
He doesn't want to. Go away.
Oh yes, the sword. Thank you.
My hatred of science
and my horror of technology
will lead me one day
to an absurd belief in God...
Funny meeting you here...
Up already? On you way?
Why such a hurry?
Stay a few moments.
What are you hiding?
Well, well, a ham.
It's ham from the inn.
- We tasted some, remember?
- You're right, it's the same.
- Where is this from?
- We...
Did you buy it?
- As a matter of fact, yes.
- From the innkeeper.
Did you really buy it?
- And it was not very expensive, either.
- That's right.
Why didn't you say so before?
On your way.
- Do you want a bit?
- We've even got wine.
No thanks, really, not now.
- You want some?
- No thanks.
Some other time. Bon voyage.
Good night.
- Look! Santiago!
- At last!
- About time, I was getting fed up.
- Me too.
Come here!
- What does the lady want?
- Let's go and see.
Where are you two going
in such a hurry?
To Santiago.
- Pilgrims?
- No, for a little break.
No need to hurry, nobody's there.
- What?
- Nobody.
In the four squares around the cathedral
there used to be thousands of pilgrims.
Now they're all empty. Not a soul.
Same thing in the hotels.
How come?
Seems somebody discovered
it wasn't St James' body
but a fellow without a head
named Priscillian.
They cut off his head a long time ago.
An unorthodox character, it seems.
What are we going to do?
Not in such a hurry, eh?
Want to go frolic in the grass?
- Sure.
- Let's go.
- Got any money?
- Gold, in fact.
Let's see.
Here.
- It's beautiful!
- Easy does it. We'll settle that later.
- Well, are we going or not?
- Come on.
- Wait, I have something to tell you.
- Go on.
Well?
- I desire a child of you.
- Why?
I'd call him: "Ye are not my people".
"Ye are not my people..."
And what if we had one?
I'd call him: "No more mercy".
"No more mercy..."
Come on.
He's there.
I hear Him. He's approaching.
Lord, where are you?
- Stop. Hear me!
- I hear Him. He is very close.
Lord! Are you there, Lord?
- Forget not what I told ye.
- No, Lord, Thou canst not die.
Get thee behind me, Satan.
For thy thought is not the thought of God
but that of men.
Lord, we are here.
What do ye want of me?
- Have pity on us, son of David.
- Pity, Lord.
- Believe ye that I am able to do this?
- Yes, Lord.
According to thy faith be it unto thee.
I see people.
Like trees walking!
A miracle, Lord!
I see grass, trees.
A miracle, Lord! I see You.
See that no man know it.
Why not?
Why is it that we may not
tell Thy miracles?
At Capharnaum,
Thou performedst many in public.
Thou multipliedst
the loaves and fishes.
Before thousands.
Think not I come
to bring peace on earth.
I come not to bring peace but a sword.
Lord, a bird! I recognised it by
the sound of its wings.
I am come to set man against father,
daughter against mother,
step-daughter against mother-in-law.
Verily, verily.
Man's foes shall be
in his own household.
Son of David, show me
the colours white and black.
He that loveth his parents
more than me is not worthy of me.
He that loveth his children
Everything about Catholic dogma
and its attitude to heresy is exact.
Texts and quotations are drawn
directly from the scriptures
or from ancient and modern works of
theology and ecclesiastical history.