The characters depicted in this film
are entirely fictitious,
any similarity to actual persons,
living or dead,
is purely coincidental.
THE PHANTOM OF LIBERTY
The film begins in Toledo, in 1808,
during the city's occupation
by Napoleon's army.
It is inspired by a story
written by Gustavo A. Bécquer,
the Spanish romantic poet.
Platoon, halt!
Right!
Prisoners against the wall.
First row, kneel.
Platoon, ready, aim...
Down with liberty!
Death to the traitors!
...fire!
First row, kneel.
Platoon, ready, aim,
fire!
I'm hungry.
Come.
Despite his wound.
and to get revenge against the knight.
the captain bet his fellow officers
that he would have Doña Elvira's
mortal remains brought to his bed.
Nothing could deter him from his intent.
and one night
he carried out his macabre plan.
"The ineffable hand of death
had spared her face.
"which had remained as fresh
and delicate as a rose.
"They found her beneath her tombstone
amid her vile paraphernalia..."
- What is that?
- What?
Paraphernalia.
- Is it a nice smelling herb?
- No.
- Is it a rosary?
- Not that either.
Paraphernalia is a legal term
for a married woman's personal property.
But in English, "paraphernalia"
took on a much broader meaning.
It refers to any accessories,
belongings, personal items,
even fishing gear or a sewing kit.
- Where were you?
- We went biking over the bridge.
- Now we're going to the slide.
- Go, but we're leaving soon.
- We'll come get you.
- Okay.
That was a good slide.
- I think I know you. What's your name?
- Véronique.
- And you?
- Valérie.
Yes, of course.
Since you are both so sweet,
I'm going to give you a nice gift.
- Come with me, we'll go...
- We can't. Our bikes are that way.
Well, let's go.
Now, I'm going to show you
some very pretty pictures.
But you can't show them to anyone.
If you want them, you have to promise.
Look.
They're yours.
Show them to all your little friends.
But not to grownups. Don't forget.
I'm sick of symmetry.
Harry?
Back already?
What are you talking about?
I never went out.
Don't you feel well?
I don't know what's wrong with me.
I'm nervous, tired.
That's true. I've noticed recently.
We could take advantage of
Véronique's vacation
to go to the seashore.
Why the sea? The sea's no longer the sea.
- Hello, Mum.
- Hello.
Look what someone gave me.
- What is it?
- Hi, Dad.
I passed you on the street yesterday,
and you didn't even recognise me.
I've been sleeping so badly these days.
I haven't told you,
but sometimes I lie awake all night.
You should get a check-up,
at least you'd be reassured.
Why do you say "check-up"?
"General examination" is the French word.
It's too long. "General examination".
"Check-up" is much quicker.
What's the hurry?
Françoise!
Come here.
- Where did you get these?
- A nice man gave them to me.
So, you let her talk to strangers?
I didn't see anything. I didn't know.
The man seemed very nice.
He even offered us sweets.
- Yes, sweets.
- I've warned you before.
If you ever accept anything
from a stranger again,
there will be trouble.
- Time for her snack.
- Yes, madam.
- Disgraceful.
- Let me see.
- Can you imagine?
- Disgusting, but what can you do?
I don't know what to do.
I can't always keep an eye on her.
Look at this.
- Remember? In Milan.
- Oh, yes.
- At your parents' house.
- Yes.
We were still too young.
But it was great. And you didn't want to...
Véronique might hear us.
It's incredible.
It's revolting.
- Sickening!
- What can you expect nowadays?
- This one could pass.
- I guess.
This one is obscene.
That may be okay for old fogies,
but not for me.
No, not this!
- Let me see.
- What good would it do?
- Why not?
- No!
Let me see it.
You're right. This is going too far.
- Call the maid.
- Yes.
Françoise.
- Françoise.
- Yes, madam.
I think I'm going to skip dinner tonight
and go to bed early.
You should see a doctor. I insist.
- Here, you can keep them.
- Thanks, Daddy.
- May I trade them for some spider pictures?
- If you like.
You called, madam?
After today's incident, it's best you leave us.
But I had nothing to do with it.
I didn't know...
I don't want to discuss it right now.
Settle things with my wife, then get out.
I'm sorry, but under the circumstances,
there's nothing I can do.
- But, madam...
- Of course, you can stay the night.
Come. Let's work out what we owe you.
- This one's a water spider.
- Very good, darling.
I drew that one. It's a wolf spider.
No, darling, it's a trapdoor spider.
A species you won't
find in France, unfortunately.
Hélène.
That's enough.
That really is enough.
I'm sorry, Mr Foucauld,
but this isn't my specialty.
We're both wasting our time.
So what should I do?
Physically, there's nothing wrong with you.
If you want to discuss your dreams,
see a psychoanalyst.
He'll listen to you for months,
even years if necessary.
Doctor, it wasn't a dream.
I have the postman's letter.
- Here, look.
- The letter?
- Doctor?
- What is it?
May I see you a moment?
- Can't it wait?
- It's rather urgent.
Excuse me.
My father is very sick.
- What's wrong with him?
- He's already had two attacks. He's old.
- I'd very much like to go see him.
- We're very busy right now.
Will you be away long?
A day or two,
I'll be back as soon as possible.
- All right, then, go.
- Thank you, Doctor.
Excuse me,
did you see any foxes on the road?
Foxes? No.
- No foxes crossing the road?
- I didn't see a thing.
What did I tell you?
There are no foxes around here. Never were!
I had first-hand information, sir.
Maybe it's the storm.
- And we still have 30 miles to go.
- We've wasted enough time! Let's go.
Excuse me, are you going toward Argenton?
Yes, sir.
Be careful. I think there was a landslide
and the road may be out.
- Goodbye, madam. Thank you.
- Goodbye.
Move out!
- Good evening, madam.
- Good evening, may I use your phone?
- The line's down because of the floods.
- What will I do now?
- Do you have a room?
- Of course. Front or back?
It doesn't matter. I'm leaving early.
- Would you like supper?
- No, just some milk and fruit.
I'll just be a minute. Go and dry off.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, madam.
- What hellish weather!
- Apparently the road to Argenton is out.
Have a seat, madam.
We're stranded here, too.
- Are you from around here?
- My family is. And you?
We're from Saint Joseph's Monastery.
You must know it.
I've been there with my father.
I'm going to see him. He's very sick.
Who knows if I'll find him alive.
What's wrong with him?
- I'm afraid for him.
- The heart. The disease of our times.
The bustle, the anxiety, the travelling.
My father runs a small farm.
He never travels.
He doesn't read the papers.
He doesn't have a phone.
If everybody prayed to Saint Joseph
and took 30 minutes a day to meditate,
- we'd all be perfectly relaxed.
- Surely.
Whenever you're ready.
- Good night.
- Good night, madam.
Good night.
This way, please.
Excuse me, madam.
Would you like an extra blanket?
It's very humid.
No, I sleep with the windows closed.
- Is there hot water?
- Of course.
- Shall I wake you in the morning?
- That won't be necessary.
- Then good night, madam.
- Good night.
Who is it?
It's Father Gabriel.
I'd like a word with you, please.
Just a moment.
Good evening, madam. May I?
- Do you know what this is?
- Yes. It's an image.
A miraculous image of Saint Joseph.
It can have surprising effects on the sick.
- Really?
- I'm thinking of your father.
Faith can sometimes triumph
where science has failed.
We just saw the Marquise de la Pomarède.
Yesterday she was near death.
We brought her the image.
We prayed.
This morning when we left the castle...
- She was cured?
- She felt a little better.
You play cards, madam?
Sometimes, when I'm alone.
- I play solitaire.
- So do I. It's very relaxing.
That must be the fathers.
- Good evening, madam.
- Good evening.
And now, with your permission,
we shall pray for your father.
I don't know how to thank you.
I'm deeply touched.
Madam, would you like a rosary?
Yes, thank you.
In the name of the Father, the Son
and the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Let us meditate tonight
on the sorrowful mystery
of Christ's agony on the Mount of Olives.
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
thy will be done on earth as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread.
And forgive us our trespasses,
as we forgive those trespass against us.
And lead us not into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace.
The Lord is with thee.
Blessed art thou amongst women,
and blessed is the fruit of thy womb, Jesus.
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us sinners
now and at the hour of our death. Amen.
- I'm in.
- Raise you 10.
- Pass.
- I'll see you and raise you a scapular.
I open.
- How many cards?
- Two.
- None.
Virgins are 10
and sacred hearts are 25, right?
Yes, and scapulars are 50.
I open with a virgin.
- I'll see you.
I'll see you.
Full house, jacks over eights.
Didn't you say your father once lived
in the colonies?
No. He never left these parts. Why?
Oh, nothing.
Place your bets.
- She was so mischievous.
- Who?
A pious lady who used to visit us.
Her husband was a military man.
- And?
- Nothing, nothing.
- Father Gabriel.
- I didn't say anything unusual.
Those must be the late guests
I was expecting.
If you'll excuse me.
- Which is higher, a flush or a straight?
- A flush.
Then I raise you 10.
- Is our room ready?
- Yes. It's very nice.
You have a view of the mountain.
Very quiet. You'll see.
It's late, but if you want dinner,
a snack or a sandwich...
No, thank you. The lady is tired.
We'll get some rest.
Take their luggage up.
Come.
- What time would you like breakfast?
- We'll come down.
Would madam like anything?
A bottle of mineral water?
Nothing, thank you.
Good night.
- What do you mean?
- That this is wonderful.
Come sit next to me. Come on.
- The things you make me do.
- Don't be nervous.
You heard the man. It's very quiet here.
- Too quiet.
- Sit down.
Take off your glasses.
What's wrong?
You seemed so happy about coming.
- I shouldn't have listened to you.
- How I've waited for this.
Please, François, take me home.
- Why did you come then?
- Because I can't refuse you anything.
For once we're alone,
without my mother, my brothers, my sisters.
It had become unbearable,
having you near me, always having to lie.
For me as well, François.
But how can we avoid lying?
- Sit down here. Come.
- François.
Come on.
All my life, I've felt you close to me.
Your perfume, your presence.
The times I held you on my lap
when you were a child.
When I think of a woman,
it's always you I see.
Of all my nephews,
I've always loved you the best.
Remember that Holy Thursday,
sitting side by side
in the dim light of the church?
Your hand was resting on the pew.
Gently, I put my hand on yours
and squeezed it.
I felt your fingers close around mine.
I didn't dare believe it.
I waited for a moment, then I looked at you.
You looked at me and leaned toward me,
and we kissed for the first time.
We couldn't help ourselves.
No.
I won't touch you.
But there's one thing I want
more than anything.
- What?
- To see you naked.
Impossible.
- I won't leave here until I do.
- I couldn't.
I've never been naked in front of a man.
No man has ever touched me.
Take off your clothes.
If you refuse, you know I'll stop at nothing.
Damn.
Take off your clothes.
- You promise you won't touch me?
- Yes.
Lock the door.
Turn around.
It's no use. I can't do it.
- But you said...
- I said nothing!
François, what's got into you?
François, stop it! Stop it!
- You swear you won't touch me?
- I swear.
Turn around.
What must they be thinking at home?
They'll be waiting for us.
You know your mother.
She's so easily worried.
They may think we had an accident,
what with the phone lines down and all.
Well, too bad. We'll see.
- Are you ready?
- You can turn around if you want.
For pity's sake, François.
Don't be frightened. Let me.
- You swore.
- Yes.
One second.
It's better like this, isn't it?
- No.
- What?
Let go of me or I'll scream!
Help!
Excuse me.
I'll light the way for you.
Just light a candle
and the power comes back.
- Going downstairs?
- To the bar.
The bar is closed.
Come to my room.
We were just about to open some port.
- No, that's all right.
- Yes, come in. Just for a minute. Please do.
Do come in.
- My dear, allow me to introduce Mr...
- François de Richemont.
- Miss Rosenblum.
- Pleased to meet you.
- The pleasure's mine.
- My name is Jean Bermans.
Please, sit.
- Are you from Paris?
- Yes. Are you?
No, I'm a hatter from Nîmes.
Miss Rosenblum is my associate.
Thank you.
Are you in business, too?
- No, I'm a student.
- Oh, what are you studying?
- I'm graduating high school.
- Lucky young fellow.
I have fond memories of my student days.
If only I could have gone to college.
But in Ostend, you know...
- Are you here alone?
- No, I'm with...
With my mother.
Perhaps she'd care to join us.
I don't think so. She's not feeling well.
One moment.
I'm sorry, but I heard voices.
I'm looking for matches.
Come in. Sit down for a minute.
Yes, but I'm with four gentlemen.
- Four gentlemen?
- We might invite them in, too.
That would be lovely.
Will you show me to your room?
- Yes, but...
- Come.
- Which door?
- That one.
She didn't tell me the gentlemen were...
But it's no problem. On the contrary.
Jean Bermans.
Gentlemen, I'd be honoured if you came
for some port in my room.
What do you mean in your room?
- That's very kind of you, but...
- I'd be so pleased.
It's late. We were going to bed.
We must celebrate the chance
that brought us together.
- Celebrate what?
- Chance. Come along.
Come along, please.
This way.
After you, miss.
Please go in.
You must be Dominicans.
- No, Carmelites.
- Oh, good.
My dear Edith, isn't this a stroke of luck?
This is Miss Rosenblum.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Likewise.
Edith, pour us some port, will you?
- Mr de Richemont, will you give me a hand?
- Of course.
It's a bit cramped in here, but no matter.
We love these impromptu parties.
Thank you very much.
We're going to have a charming time,
if you have no objections.
Excuse me.
Mr Bermans, haven't we met before?
I don't think so.
You never lived in the Congo?
- In the Congo?
- The Belgian Congo.
- I've never been to Africa. Why?
- No reason.
- The weather's improving.
- Good.
Personally, I love Africa.
Saint Christopher was never any help to me.
- Naturally, madam.
- Why's that?
He's no longer a saint.
Nor are Saint George and some others.
The church has become very strict
about sainthood.
- But isn't that damaging to the faith?
- On the contrary. It reinforces it.
Sainthood isn't like some badge.
You've no doubt heard of Savonarola?
- Wasn't he a Dominican?
- Indeed, and an illustrious one.
Savonarola was tried
and condemned as a heretic.
He's completely rehabilitated now.
Soon he may even be sanctified.
While other saints will disappear?
Yes, it appears
that Saint Thérèse de Lisieux...
Saint Thérèse?
- How could they?
- That's the rumour going around Rome.
We now know that Thérèse's parents
had a hereditary disease
when she and her many brothers and sisters
were conceived.
- What will become of the basilica?
- A church like all the others.
What about the Virgin of Lourdes?
Same thing?
No. There never was a real miracle
at Lisieux, whereas in Lourdes...
Go on, beat me, you old slut!
Harder! Again! That's it!
Harder! Yes!
I'm swine! I'm garbage!
Beat me, you filthy trollop! Beat me!
I'm rotten!
A leper!
Again! No, wait! Don't go!
Let the monks stay, at least!
Go on. Again! Yes!
- Leave him to me, madam.
- Yes, take him.
Thank you for your hospitality.
He likes getting hit, I'll hit him.
Calm down, Father. Calm down.
You must rest.
This way.
Come.
Do whatever you want.
Good morning. You're the first one up.
- Good morning. Is the phone working?
- Not yet. But the road to Argenton is open.
- Is my bill ready?
- Of course.
- Excuse me. Are you going to Argenton?
- Yes.
Can you give me a lift?
The bus isn't due for two hours.
- I'd be glad to.
- Thank you.
Here you are.
Thank you. Do you need the bill?
Allow me.
Goodbye.
- I'll tell you where to drop me off.
- Of course.
Thank you very much.
Here he comes.
Look out, he's coming. Take your seats.
Attention!
Be seated.
THE COLONEL IS A CUCKOLD
THE CAPTAIN IS A PANSY
Who wrote that?
You won't answer?
Then I'll have to report it.
It's incredible. Honestly.
At your age, you still act like children.
Duval, erase that.
And close the door, please.
Last class, we were discussing,
the notion of laws and misdemeanours.
We saw how the aim of laws
is to maintain social order.
Naturally, they're subject to change
from one country to another,
from one age to another.
In fact, they are merely conventions.
The same goes for customs and morals.
Take polygamy, for example.
Target practice! Group 3!
As I was saying,
morals are subject to change,
like laws.
So, polygamy,
which is the norm in some societies,
is taboo in ours.
On this subject,
I refer you to the works of Margaret Mead.
Take it down. I repeat, Mead, M-E-A-D,
on sexual practices in Melanesia.
These books...
I'm not starting over for latecomers.
I was talking about the works
of Margaret Mead
on sexual practices in Melanesia.
I was saying that these works...
Accident on Highway 787.
With all these comings and goings,
I lost the thread.
Right, I was saying that these works,
which are in the barracks library,
will help you better understand
the relativity of customs
and, consequently, of laws.
When you compare one culture to another,
it's all a question of viewpoint.
Everyone is always
someone else's barbarian.
What's more,
as far as the relativity
of customs and laws is concerned...
The gasworks just blew up. General alert!
Aren't you going with the others?
- We're on arctal ructive duty.
- On what?
Arctal ructive duty.
I see. And you?
- Me, too.
- Very well.
With all these interruptions,
I've forgotten what I was saying.
Oh, yes.
I think that everything
I just explained to you
will help you better understand the relativity
of customs and laws.
You're well aware that it's often
a question of changing the laws.
We also hear a lot about an evolution
that is leading to changes in customs
and morals.
Hey, look at this.
RED
WORKERS SOUND THE ALARM!
Attention!
- Colonel.
- Go ahead.
Excuse me.
I was told the class was a bit restless today.
We'll see about that.
Sit down.
Please, carry on.
There's a good deal of talk
about changing our morals.
Some people are even calling
for a general upheaval.
But the consequences of such a disturbance
could prove unacceptable,
even horrifying.
I'll pick an example at random.
My wife and I are invited over
to some friends...
- We thought you'd never make it.
- You can't imagine the traffic.
We nearly began without you.
- You should have.
- Don't be silly.
Why, here's Sophie!
Hello, my dear, how are you?
How you've grown.
- Everything fine at school?
- Yes.
You know Mrs Calmette.
- Good day, madam.
- Good day.
- Hello, nice to meet you.
- Hello.
If you'll just follow me... This way.
Let's see. Mrs Calmette, you sit there.
Elizabeth, here.
You, Professor, on my right.
Charles, between Elizabeth
and Mrs Calmette.
And you, Sophie darling, come here.
Here on my left.
Do sit down.
We went to see Tristan and Isolde
at the opera the other day.
- Was it good?
- Splendid.
Carlotta Igellicci was heartrending.
What a voice! What presence!
It's a shame she's put on weight.
Care for a cigarette?
I'd love one, thanks.
- How was your trip to Spain?
- Interesting.
- But...
- But what?
We had to come home early.
Madrid was filled with the stench of,
pardon my language,
food.
It was indecent.
What will our planet be like in 20 years
with the current population explosion?
It makes you think.
What are you referring to?
Consider the quantity of toxic products
we dump into our rivers.
Insecticides, detergents,
all the industrial residue.
- Not to mention bodily wastes.
- Of course.
There are almost four billion people
on Earth.
In 20 years, there'll be seven billion of us.
Seven billion!
Yes, and how much bodily waste
do you think a person discharges daily?
I don't know. Half a pound, maybe?
Much more.
Urine is heavier than water.
All told, I'd say at least three pounds.
Multiplied by four billion, that makes
more than 12 billion pounds a day.
In 20 years, more than 22 billion pounds.
- Ten million tons of excrement a day?
- Exactly.
My word.
That's really alarming.
Yes?
How many tons did you say?
More than 10 million tons a day.
And such waste is extremely toxic.
Its damaging effects are increased
by the presence of chemicals.
Just try peeing into your fish tank every day
and you'll see what I mean.
Mum, I'm really hungry.
Sophie, it's bad manners to talk like that
at the table.
Excuse me a moment.
- Where's the dining room, please?
- Last door on the right.
Thank you.
- It's occupied!
- Sorry!
- What is it?
- Colonel, we go on duty at 11:00 a.m.
Go ahead then.
Driver's license and registration.
- Don't you know the speed limit?
- I was doing under 40.
Really?
- And the seat belt is compulsory.
- I know. I wasn't thinking.
- Have you seen your tyres?
- No.
You're not only endangering your own life
but that of other drivers.
I have a doctor's appointment in Paris.
Are you kidding me?
Consider yourself lucky
I don't impound your car.
- Richard, how are you feeling, old man?
- No better, no worse.
- And your wife and little girl?
- Fine, thank you.
You must come over for dinner
some evening.
- We'd like that. Thank you.
- Come in.
Sit down.
- Did you bring the test results?
- Yes.
Let's have a look.
Glucose, 130, good.
Cholesterol, fine.
Uric acid... Urea...
Good.
Yes.
Very good.
Your results are better than mine.
Now for the electrocardiogram.
Well, it's normal.
- You smoke a lot?
- A pack a day.
Too much.
And you lead a hectic life.
Keep it up and in three or four years
you'll end up in a wheelchair.
Let's look at the x-rays.
This area here is clear, see?
There's a small spot here.
We could take another x-ray to be sure.
And those white spots?
Oh, nothing.
Catherine met your wife the other day.
So you're not going
to the coast this summer?
Depends. If I'm not feeling well,
we'll stay in Paris.
All right. Well?
One thing. I'd like to make a small incision.
Sheer medical curiosity.
- Big?
- No, this long.
- Is it an operation?
- Just to see.
- When?
- Whenever you want. When you have time.
Is tomorrow okay with you?
Tomorrow? Is it that urgent?
It's always best to do these things
as soon as possible.
- What's wrong?
- It's up to you,
but personally, I'd like to have a look.
Look, Pierre, I'm not a child anymore.
If it's something serious, you can tell me.
I like patients like you.
You have a neoplasm.
I see.
- What's that?
- A growth of new tissue.
Or, if you prefer, cancer.
What?
You have cancer of the liver.
Cancer, me?
At a fairly advanced stage.
But nowadays, you know, these things...
Cigarette?
What did Dr Pasolini say?
It's nothing.
Oh, good. That's a relief.
I was a bit worried, you know.
- Did he start you on a treatment?
- No, nothing.
Isn't Aliette here?
She's at school now.
Hello? Yes, speaking.
What did you say?
When? How?
That's impossible.
We'll be right over.
- What is it?
- Aliette's disappeared.
- What?
- She's disappeared from school.
Don't panic. There must be an explanation.
Did the nanny take her?
Yes. She just got back.
She didn't say a thing.
Brigitte!
Exactly what happened?
I don't know. We don't understand it.
- You're sure she's disappeared?
- I don't know.
What makes it so odd
is that she and the others
were under constant supervision.
And she was always there.
Come with me. I'll show you.
"Will we see him
"come back?"
This is Mr and Mrs Legendre,
Aliette's parents.
Pleased to meet you.
When the children came into class,
the teacher counted them.
There were 22 of them, as usual.
Five minutes later,
she noticed Aliette wasn't there.
She called me right away.
- Could she have run away?
- Impossible.
The concierge is certain that no student left.
It's unbelievable.
Isn't anyone in charge around here?
Sit down.
I counted them, too.
- I took the enrolment list and called the roll.
- Mum.
I've lost faith in this school.
- Be quiet. What do you want?
I'm here.
Be quiet when the headmistress is talking.
- Understand?
- Yes.
Now go back to your seat. Go.
I'll do the roll call again for you. You'll see.
- Al Fariq, Juliette.
- Here.
- Lantelle, Sophie.
- Loiron, Claire.
- Here.
- Legendre, Aliette.
You see? She's there.
- And all the others are there?
- All of them. I checked.
- You looked everywhere?
- We searched the entire school. Nothing.
Good Lord!
What could have happened to her?
If you think we'll accept
your feeble explanation, you're wrong.
- But, sir...
- We must notify the police at once.
- Where's your coat?
- In the hall.
Come on.
- Show them in.
- Yes.
Please come in.
Do sit down.
- You are Mr Legendre?
- Yes. Thanks for seeing us so quickly.
Not at all. What can I do for you?
- Our daughter has disappeared.
- When?
About an hour ago, when she got to school.
The nanny took her as usual.
When the teacher called the roll,
she was there.
They searched the entire school,
but obviously they didn't find her.
Do you have any enemies?
Anyone who would wish you harm?
I don't think so.
You're a man who's fairly...
I mean, if it's a kidnapping,
do you have the means to pay a ransom?
Yes, of course.
I see. Is there a witness?
The nanny.
You took this child to school?
Yes, sir. But I don't know a thing.
It wasn't me.
I left her at the gate, like I always do.
Didn't I, Aliette?
That's right. It was like every day.
She left me at the gate.
You'll speak when you're questioned.
First, we'll fill out a missing persons form.
You did well to bring her. It helps.
Come here, child.
Now, then, we were saying...
- Legendre. What is your first name?
- Aliette.
Race, white.
- Age?
- Eight and a half.
Marital status, single.
Brown eyes.
Brown hair.
Height?
3'8".
Weight?
Fifty-five pounds.
Wearing a blue coat,
black shoes, white socks.
Ask the sergeant to come in, please.
Sergeant, please.
Issue an all-points bulletin for Paris.
We must find this child.
Yes, sir.
- This her?
- Yes, why?
- Can't we take her along?
- No need.
Just take a good look at her,
then get to work.
Yes, sir.
Sergeant, your shoes are far from spotless.
You're right. I didn't have time to...
Fine, fine, go.
So there's no need to worry.
Everything is taken care of.
Contact us if you hear anything,
even if you're warned against it.
- I assure you, we will.
- Thank you, Inspector.
Don't mention it.
- Thank you.
Goodbye.
- Sir.
- Good day.
- A fine-looking dog you have.
- Yes.
- You keep him tied up all day?
- I let him out from time to time.
- With all this traffic?
- He's used to it.
- What's his name?
- Chico.
Chico. Good boy!
The bastards who mistreat animals
should be drowned.
That's right.
That's what the Gospel says.
Well, more or less.
What's the matter?
There he is!
I see him. It's him.
The open window on the top floor.
I'll call in.
Court is in session.
The defendant will rise.
All right, all right.
Here are the judgments on the charges
and the verdict.
On the charge of first-degree murder
the jury replied guilty,
by a majority of at least eight votes.
As to extenuating circumstances,
the jury did not find any,
by a majority of at least eight votes.
Under Articles 295, 298, 297, 302 and 304,
and Article 12 of the Penal Code, the court,
having deliberated
in accordance with the law,
sentences Bernard Levasseur
to death.
Court is adjourned.
May I have your autograph?
- Me, too.
- Me, too, please.
The trial of the Killer Poet lasted 14 months.
Meanwhile. the search
for the little girl continued.
Until one day...
Commissioner, Mr Legendre is here.
Show him in.
Sir.
- Commissioner.
- Have a seat.
After all this time,
you may have started losing hope.
I have good news for you at last.
- You did it? I don't believe it.
- Yes.
Bring her in.
Please sit, madam.
Excuse me. Where were you?
I waited until 11:00.
It couldn't be helped.
- You could've phoned.
- I didn't know where you were.
Commissioner, I don't know
how to thank you.
Was she well treated?
She had everything she needed, didn't she?
Everything. As usual. You know it.
How did you find her?
I have the written statement. I'll read it.
It's a rather unusual story.
"On the night of February 7 or 8,
the population of Lisieux
"was awakened by a deafening explosion.
"When rescue workers arrived,
they were amazed to find..."
What is it?
It's already 1:30?
I'm sorry. I have an urgent appointment.
Go ahead.
My secretary will read it to you.
Do you mind, Jacqueline?
Goodbye and excuse me.
"Written statement.
"On the night of February 7 or 8,
"the population of Lisieux was awakened
by a deafening explosion.
"When rescue workers arrived,
they were amazed to find..."
Shall I wait, sir?
No, you may go. Thank you.
- Good afternoon, sir.
- Good afternoon, Georges.
What? They're not here yet?
No, sir.
But the appointment was for 1:30.
Listen, turn off that music, will you?
You can't go into a bar or restaurant
without hearing canned music.
- Turn it off, will you?
- Yes, sir.
The usual?
Of course.
- Good afternoon, madam.
- Good afternoon.
- Will you sit at the bar?
- No, I'll sit over there.
Fine.
- I'll have some port.
- Yes, madam.
I'm sorry to disturb you, but...
Don't be afraid.
I'm the police commissioner.
Pleased to meet you.
- Do you mind if I sit with you for a minute?
- Please do.
- Your port, madam.
- Thank you.
- Your drink is at your table, sir.
- Thank you. Leave it there.
- You come here often?
- This is my first time.
I was troubled when I saw you come in.
- Shall I tell you why?
- If you wish.
Today is the fourth anniversary
of my sister's death.
I loved her very much.
She looked exactly like you.
I thought you were her.
Same face, same voice, same walk.
Her name was Marguerite.
My name is Estelle.
One summer afternoon
it was unbearably hot.
- You still here?
- Yes.
- Didn't you have an appointment at 3:00?
- It's too hot. I didn't want to go.
Too hot! I've told you before,
you'll never amount to anything!
I don't think I'll go to Toulouse.
I'm going to tell Mother.
She'll be furious, but you're right.
The family dinners, the aunts and cousins...
So boring.
I know.
What would I do in Toulouse at 3:00 p.m?
Take a nap.
Do me a favour. Play Brahms' Rhapsody.
If you like.
She never did go to Toulouse.
She died a few days later.
- Do you play piano, too?
- Yes, a little.
- You're not French?
- I was born in Italy.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
May I?
What did your sister die of?
Miserere colic.
What is that?
It's horrible, especially in the final stages.
You end up vomiting...
- Excuse me.
- How awful.
Horrible.
I must be going,
but it was extraordinary
meeting you like this.
I'd like to see you again,
invite you to the Policemen's Ball.
I'd love to go.
A call for you, sir.
- Is it Marcel saying he's late?
- I don't think so.
No one else knows I'm here.
Shall I say I haven't seen you?
No. Ask who's calling.
Never a moment's peace.
Would you mind giving me
your name and address?
It's your sister, Marguerite, sir.
- What?
- She says she must speak to you.
Georges, tell her to go screw herself.
Excuse me, madam.
This must be a sick joke.
My sister's been dead for four years.
But, sir...
She insists.
She wants to see you tonight
in the family vault.
She says the key
is in your right-hand desk drawer.
Why, that's true.
Ask her what I requested she play
one hot summer day
when I went in her room.
The commissioner wants to know what
he asked you to play one hot summer day
when he went in your room.
Brahms' Rhapsody, sir.
Give me that.
Hello.
Yes, speaking. Who are you?
Learn the true mystery
of death tonight? But...
Hello? Hello?
- What do you want?
- I want to come in.
It's closed at this hour.
I'm Mr Richepin.
My family vault is here. Let me in.
You need a special authorisation.
I'm the police commissioner.
Go in, then. Shall I go with you?
No need. Stay here.
Hello.
That's him!
- What are you doing? Let go!
- Take him away!
Don't you know who I am?
Hands off! I'm the police commissioner!
- Explain it at the station.
- Let go, I said.
Stand at attention
and give me your badge numbers.
Yes?
- The commissioner.
- Send him in.
Sit down.
You should know that I've been treated
in a most shameful manner.
I couldn't even call home.
You were found last night at the cemetery,
desecrating a crypt.
When arrested, you claimed you were
the police commissioner.
You know full well I am.
I order you to return my belongings at once.
And take me to my office.
You'll hear about this.
Of course.
As we were saying, desecration of a crypt.
- It was my sister's casket.
- Your sister?
Yes. I went to see my sister.
She phoned me.
Put him back in his cell.
Get me the police commissioner. It's urgent.
Hello, Commissioner?
Sorry to disturb you.
This is Inspector Dupuis.
We've arrested a fellow
who claims to be the police commissioner.
Claims to be the police commissioner?
How strange.
Does he look like me?
Is he pleasant?
Not at all.
I see.
Bring him here right away.
Superintendent,
the commissioner will see you now.
This way, please.
There you are. Come in. How are you?
- Fine, and you?
- Fine, thanks.
- That will be all, Inspector. Thank you.
- Thank you.
Won't you have a seat over there?
I'm fine here.
Very well. You there, and me here.
Two glasses of scotch.
- You've put on weight.
- So have you.
- All those official dinners.
- Always eating and drinking.
- We ought to refuse.
- Not easy.
What are you doing this morning?
- This morning, you know...
- Ah, yes, the zoo. At noon.
I fear that there may be some trouble,
but I've taken precautions.
I've stationed 12 vehicles
of riot police nearby.
But not grouped together.
Spread them out, some here, some there.
We mustn't alarm people.
The main thing is to keep them
from reaching the cages.
The locks have been carefully checked.
And anyway, if some animals are killed,
tough luck.
The lives of our men are more valuable
than a zebra's.
- Cheers.
Down with liberty!
- Charge.
- And let them have it.