Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext
WUTHERING HEIGHTS
This picture is based on
Wuthering Heights,
Its characters are
at the mercy of
their own instincts and passions.
They are unique beings for whom
the social conventions do not exist.
Alejandro's love for Catalina
is fierce and inhuman.
It can only be fulfilled
through death.
Above all,
this picture tries to remain true
to the spirit of
Emily Brontë's novel.
- Who fired that shot?
- Your wife.
She killed some buzzards.
Just to play a bad joke on me.
You're two little girls.
Eduardo, tell her to leave me alone.
- She doesn't listen to me.
- To me neither.
- Eduardo, don't do that.
- Don't do what?
Don't kill that animal.
Can't you see how it sufers?
Don't be ridiculous.
This keeps it from sufering.
It's the way to keep them intact.
Isabel wishes you'd dissect
butterflies in a less cruel way.
I don't like to see animals sufer.
I don't make them sufer.
I kill them with one shot.
They go to death's liberty
painlessly.
You are much crueller, Eduardo.
Well, release that bird or kill it.
Why have it in a cage?
Because I love it.
Enough for you not to mind
being locked up, right?
Why is that dog barking?
It must be the buzzards again.
Beware! They may
come through that door.
You can poke fun at me.
You're not scared of anything.
As I know I'll have a short life,
I must like the things …
- that frighten people.
- You're incorrigible.
Because I say what I feel?
Don't you realize
that such misgivings explain …
many things about my life?
- Take the meat to the larder.
- The ham as well?
- Good evening, Maria.
- Alejandro!
I want to see Catalina.
Go back the way you came.
We've had enough of trouble here.
I want to see Catalina.
Not at this hour!
Come back tomorrow...
No, don't ever come back.
Are you still afraid of me?
You have the devil in you.
We never had a moment's peace
with you.
Leave us alone!
Tell your mistress I'm here.
- What was that?
- Must have been the wind.
- It came from the kitchen.
- I'll go see.
What broke, Maria?
What happened, Maria?
It's Alejandro, sir.
Alejandro has returned.
What?
- Where are you going?
- Leave me alone. I'm going to greet him.
You stay here.
Ask him to come in, Maria.
He was your parents' servant!
- Let him come here.
- Alejandro is not a servant.
my father adopted him
and we were raised together.
To me he is more than a brother.
Don't forget that you are my wife.
Behave accordingly.
-Catalina!
-Alejandro!
Eduardo, it's him!
He's back.
We thought you would never
come back again, Alejandro.
I was sure he would.
How could you have left me so long
without hearing from you?
- Where have you been?
- In many places. Far away.
Yes, some days it felt like I had
a lead weight in my heart.
You were then so far
I couldn't reach you.
I had moments of fatigue
during my work.
You were then lying in the sun
in despondency.
I shivered with cold
in the height of summer.
You were then in a snowy country.
I have always kept you here.
A minute after you left, you were
already back with me for good.
- Catalina, come here.
- Your lips are bigger now.
How many women
will you have kissed? Silly!
I know you have
and it's been in vain.
Catalina.
Look at him, Eduardo.
He's so self-confident now!
He must have got rich.
Yes, I have become rich.
Does that bother you?
That doesn't mean anything to us.
Right, Eduardo?
Come. Look at Isabel.
She's changed so much, hasn't she?
- You remember her?
- I do. I remember everything.
Everything!
Alejandro!
Will you really let him go out
in a night like this?
If he wants to stay the night,
he must say so.
I'd rather die than spend one night
under this roof.
You're still as wild as you were.
Where are you going?
- I'll live with your brother on the farm.
- You think he'll let you in?
I don't intend to ask his permission.
Now the farm is almost mine.
Is that true about my brother?
Your brother has lost a fortune
gambling.
That scoundrel must have taken
advantage of the situation.
And to think that my brother
treated him worse than a dog.
Alejandro used to say that one day
everything would be his.
How can you talk like that,
Catalina?
I admire people
who get what they want.
You wouldn't have done that.
Would you, Eduardo?
Don't compare me with that swine.
- Can I tell you something?
- What?
You will never love me
half as much as Alejandro does.
Don't listen to her.
You know what she's like.
- Have you finished?
- In a minute.
What's wrong with your brother?
He won't understand.
Why don't you try to understand him?
I'm a good wife,
I'll give him a child.
- What more does he want?
- He wants to be able to live in peace.
If you've always loved Alejandro
and he's always loved you,
why didn't you marry him?
Because my brother Ricardo
hated him.
Eduardo hated him.
- Everybody has always hated him.
- I have never hated him.
You despised him like the rest.
If we had gotten married,
you would have made beggars of us.
I thought that to someone in love,
tribulations didn't matter.
You're a romantic fool
who repeats the nonsense you hear.
Alejandro means more to me
than my soul.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph!
You have the devil in you.
You sound crazy sometimes.
See how you can't understand me?
Leave me alone.
You shouldn't act this way, Eduardo.
I've always told you the truth.
When you married me you knew
I'd never stop loving him.
Leave me alone!
I have been so stupid.
I had stopped thinking about him.
I even hoped that he had died.
How can you love a servant so much?
Who turned him into one?
Ricardo. He treated him
like a slave when my father died
and made him live in the stable.
You never liked him either,
always showing of your wealth.
He had plenty of reasons
to hate you all.
If you love him so much,
why did you marry me?
Are you going to be jealous now?
Don't worry, I've never wanted
to cheat on you with him.
That's not enough. I know
you won't go find him in his room.
But you cheat on me in thought.
Why did you marry me?
Because he was gone
and I thought forever.
Because I loved you.
Not the same way, but I loved you.
Besides, I needed to have a child.
Your love and mine
will end with death.
My love for Alejandro is inhuman.
- What if I killed him?
- It wouldn't do you any good.
I would love him the same
after his death.
Evil has come into this house.
Throw it out, Lord,
and let us live in Your company
for the good of our souls.
Amen.
We go to take away this.
What are you doing here, you beast?
You want to stink up the house?
Go to the kitchen
and put that out at once!
And I'll pull your ears.
You know I don't like to see you here.
How many times must I tell you
I want no shouting in this house?
How dare you speak to me like that?
Are you the owner of the farm?
If you can't pay me in a month,
I am!
In the meantime,
I don't want to be disturbed.
Of course, you can win it all back
by gambling.
If you ask him for more money,
you're done for.
Dirty devil!
You should have left him
in the street, where you found him.
You are the master here.
Throw him in the street!
You're to blame for this!
Let us be!
Remember when you used to feed me
the leftovers in the stable?
Now I can throw you out
whenever I please.
Good morning, everyone.
Fine, I get up at dawn,
ride five leagues on horseback
and you welcome me with long faces.
If our visit bothers you,
we'll leave.
Good morning, Jorgito.
Where are you going?
Don't you remember me?
- You don't say hello, Jorge?
- Or your aunt Catalina?
It's a shame the way
your son behaves, Ricardo.
He's a complete savage.
You're here to see your beloved, right?
You're fit for each other. You nauseate me.
- Are you drunk this early?
- Leave me alone.
Good morning, Alejandro.
I couldn't sleep a wink,
knowing I'd see you today.
We must see all the places …
we used to hide when
we were little. Coming?
- Where are you going?
- With you two.
No, you stay here.
We'll go to places you don't know.
They're our places.
only ours.
Catalina and I will have a row.
You'd better stay here this time.
- Is it still here?
- I don't think anyone's been here.
Remember? We wanted to get away.
To sail away on a boat.
Sailboats still exist.
Here it is! Look.
My knife.
The ropes.
Look, the lantern!
You remember? You broke it
the day you threw it at me.
With reason.
You were angry
and refused to talk to me.
You know something, Catalina?
When I came back, I had only
one thing in mind: To get revenge.
From me as well?
From everyone who made me sufer.
I wanted to take everything
and whip them away …
- to stay alone with you.
- And you changed your mind?
I must wait.
You mean more to me
than my hate for them.
Come on, Catalina. Right now.
It is time to escape again.
I'm going to have Eduardo's child.
I don't give a damn!
We'll send it to him after its birth,
but you stay with me.
It's too late, Alejandro.
Stay here. All I need
is to have you close by.
I want you only for myself.
Would you like to be with a woman
who's always looking back?
Catalina, come with me,
or I swear you'll be sorry.
We've often threatened each other
in vain.
This time I'll do something
that will hurt you.
You won't tell me what it is?
No.
Look.
- What's the matter?
- You've been spying on us.
Do I interest you that much?
You're not
the one that interests me.
Why are you looking at me like that?
Leave me alone.
Catalina!
I didn't expect that.
You're in love with Alejandro.
Ah, that was it.
You shouldn't have bothered to guess.
I'm in love with Alejandro.
You want more details?
Sorry, Isabel.
I didn't want to make fun of you.
But how is it possible
that in such a short time?
That's the way it is.
I'm in love with him.
And I love him at least
as much as you love Eduardo.
I feel sorry for you.
You don't know him.
I'm the only one who does.
He's a savage
who only acts by instinct.
- And you love him!
- I always have.
But that doesn't blind me.
He'll play with you.
He'll make you
sufer like a poor devil.
Don't you realize that Alejandro
can only love me?
- That's what you think.
- You think I'm jealous, right?
No, Isabel. I'm giving you advice
as I would to a sister.
Forget that man
before it's too late.
Thank you for the advice, but I know
very well what I have to do.
Listen to her.
She knows that man better than me
and I've always known him.
How did he get rich?
Honest people
don't need to hide their lives.
And why does he live with a man
he'd rather see six feet under?
Who asked you anything?
This is none of your business.
Alejandro, Come!
I knew you'd be taking that path.
Running away from me.
And I knew ...
you would come,
but not once did I look up here.
You were furious, weren't you?
- Yes.
- So was I.
Do you like them, Alejandro?
Don't they suit me?
Don't waste you time, Isabel.
Alejandro doesn't like those things.
You really don't like them?
Say something, Alejandro.
Don't you know she loves you?
Why do you say that?
Leave me alone.
You confessed
you were crazy for him!
She loves you more
than I do Eduardo.
Let go of me!
Do you dare deny it?
My sister-in-law is broken-hearted.
By the moonlight and in her dreams,
she pronounces your name.
And she hasn't eaten in three days
because of you.
Look!
She's worse than a tiger!
Be careful, Alejandro. She will bite you too,
if you marry her.
If she did,
I'd pull her teeth out one by one.
Why do you torture her so?
That can't be true.
I swear it is.
She's crazy about you.
All that seems ridiculous.
I'm going after her.
Let me go!
Is it true that you love me?
Mr. Ricardo, sir.
You don't have to announce me
when I come to my brother's house.
Find something
to warm my stomach up.
I believe it is already warm enough.
You don't need to drink any more.
You think I'm drunk?
I didn't come here to argue.
I was on my way to town,
and it started to rain,
so I decided to come in.
You weren't going to town
and didn't come in by chance.
You were coming here,
and I know exactly why.
Well then...
Some time ago I said I would
never give you another penny.
This time it's serious.
If I don't pay the mortgage,
that scoundrel will keep the farm.
I don't care about the farm.
You know I hate that house.
And having a neighbour like him
wouldn't bother you, either?
I would try to keep him
away from here.
Your wife goes to see him often.
They go out together.
Where they go and
what they do, only they know.
I trust Catalina. How dare you speak
that way about your sister?
I'll speak the same way about yours.
That dog is after both of them.
Won't you lend me the money?
- No.
- Then let the devil take you all!
They told me you were here.
Is something wrong, Ricardo?
Why did he come?
What's the matter, Eduardo?
Is it true you have gone to see him?
Why have you hidden it from me?
You know I haven't.
You've always known where I was going.
Didn't you, Eduardo?
Yes, I did.
If I could only be sure
you still love me.
Don't see him anymore, Catalina.
I'm sufering very much.
Promise you won't see him again.
I promise
I won't look for him again.
Where are you going?
IsabeI! IsabeI!
You must think I'm a beast.
I know you aren't. It's not
your fault that you are as you are.
Everybody has always maltreated you.
You need tenderness.
- Your tenderness?
- Yes. Mine.
And if you couldn't make me change?
I'm sure I can.
And if I didn't dare to ask you
to go out with me?
I would.
- You love me that much?
- That much.
Alejandro! Come here!
Wait for me. I'll be right back.
Well? Where are we going?
Alejandro, I've told you
to leave Isabel alone many times.
It hurts you when I kiss her.
If Eduardo finds out,
we'll never see each other again.
Put your dirty mouth anywhere,
but leave Isabel alone.
Is it possible to be jealous
of a wax doll?
She has the same eyes
as your husband. I hate them.
Besides, you married the brother.
Why can't I marry the sister?
Because you're not in love. I can't
allow you to make her unhappy.
I want to marry her
only to hurt you.
And if I didn't care?
If you didn't care I could cut
my throat this very minute.
Here! Cut your throat,
because it doesn't bother me a bit.
Listen well. I don't care!
Catalina, you've always treated me badly,
I don't hold any grudge against you.
But I have to hurt those …
who kept me from you.
I will not allow you
to bring any harm to Eduardo.
Will you defend
that repulsive worm now?
Sooner or later he will have to pay.
Too bad if it hurts you.
I give you three minutes
to leave this house,
if you don't want my servants
to throw you out.
Is this what you call dignity?
Why don't you throw
this scoundrel out?
I see you devote your time
to eavesdropping.
You can be proud of this individual.
He dares to threaten me, and look...
there you have him, trembling like a scared rabbit.
And you chose that bastard.
- I will never forgive you.
- I was defending your own sister.
You'd deserve to be beaten up by Alejandro
for doubting my integrity.
But I can't even touch him.
He's scared to death.
Hit him, Eduardo!
I bet you don't dare!
You heard it.
Hit me! Hit me!
Go away, Alejandro.
You've hurt me, but I don't …
want anything to happen to you.
Let me kill him.
I won't rest until I do.
If you kill him,
what will happen to you? To me?
Get away.
If you love me, Alejandro!
go away.
If I leave, I will do something
that will hurt more.
Go away, Alejandro!
Go get him!
You must choose right now
between him and me forever.
When you listen behind closed doors,
you hear everything.
I called Alejandro to forbid him
to see Isabel again.
You can't be his friend and my wife.
For God's sake!
Leave me alone. I'm going crazy.
I don't want to wait anymore.
You must definitely choose!
Go away! Leave me!
Can't you see how I am?
Don't come near me!
I should never have said anything.
It was you!
Spy! Traitor!
God knows what you've told him.
I want to die!
You'll never see me again!
Don't go now.
It would be useless, sir.
What will she do?
The usual.
Lock herself up and cry a while.
I'll go see.
She won't want it.
Anyway, I'll go see.
Mistress.
Mistress, open up, please.
You haven't eaten all day.
Your dinner's here.
Open up, Mistress!
I'm leaving your dinner here.
IsabeI, Come here!
I told you
not to see Alejandro anymore,
and this morning you were with him.
You're to blame
for what happened today.
Why did you see him again?
Answer me!
You will force me to lock you
in the house
to defend you against yourself.
That man can only do you harm.
Eduardo, you have always been good to everyone,
I've never seen you hurt anybody.
Why are you so cruel to him?
Because he doesn't deserve kindness.
Much less from me.
What similarities are there
between him and you?
What have you seen in him
to make you lose your dignity?
Alejandro is so unhappy.
He's a beast …
to whom
nothing respectable exists.
He'll ignore even what's most sacred
to follow his instincts.
And I don't want to carry on arguing.
I forbid you to see him again.
If you do, I swear you'll be sorry.
Maria, how is she?
Go away.
You're responsible for all this.
- How is she?
- I don't know.
She's locked herself up
and won't see anyone.
Go away or I'll call someone.
- Maria.
- Yes, sir?
- What time is it?
- It must be nine o'clock.
- Is she still there?
- Yes.
She doesn't even open the door
to get her food.
She hasn't eaten a bite
since yesterday morning.
Go away.
I'll go up later.
You little rascal!
come here!
I'll show you!
Where is that damn boy?
I'll show him not to run away
from his father.
Good night.
Has she any reasons
to behave this way?
Didn't she ofend me?
You know her.
She will soon come to you
for forgiveness.
I don't want her to ask for
my forgiveness. I want to see her.
Have patience.
It will be okay.
But don't spend
another sleepless night.
- Will you go to bed?
- I don't know...
Open the door, Catalina.
I can't stand it any longer.
I want to speak to you.
I forgive you everything, but open the door.
-IsabeI?
- What do you want?
She won't open the door.
She doesn't answer me.
Nor me...
Just a little while ago,
Maria and I begged her to open.
Tomorrow, I'll break down the door
if necessary.
We must end this situation
once and for all.
What are you doing here?
Leave right now, Alejandro!
I want to talk to you, Isabel.
If you don't get out, I'll scream.
Do it.
Scream.
Leave me, Alejandro!
Don't touch me.
Why don't you scream?
Don't you dare?
Now I know why you've come.
If I scream,
they will find you here
and Catalina will know
you've been in my room.
You only want to make her jealous,
but she won't come.
She's locked in
and won't see anybody.
- I came to see you.
- You're lying.
I'm telling you I came to see you.
- I cannot believe you
- Why?
Because you only love her.
I loved her, but
I also hated her.
I can't stand this Ioneliness.
You've shown me something else.
I wish I could believe you.
But you want to forget her with me.
Forget her!
She's forgotten.
I swear, Isabel.
Sir, come upstairs right away!
It's Mistress!
- Catalina, what's the matter?
- I want to die!
Help me with her.
I'll go anyway!
- Why didn't you say she was ill?
- I didn't know it.
I came to see how she was
and found her lying on the floor.
- Your gossip started all this!
- It's all right.
If that man comes here
to woo your wife and you sister,
I won't breathe a word!
It's me, Catalina.
I didn't know that you were sick.
Send for the doctor.
Hurry!
That's the best you can do.
Sir!
Come a second.
- She eloped with him.
- You'll bring her back.
No. Nobody can deal with him.
She'll pay a high price for this.
She will not set foot
in this house again! Understand!
For me, she's dead.
Will you let her
stay with that man?
She chose it.
Come on, Maria.
You alone will help me
take care of her.
- What's the matter?
- I'm very happy, Alejandro.
This is no time for kissing.
- Alejandro, do you love me?
- Very much. Come on.
Be happy and have many children.
May you be very lucky
and healthy.
We have good hearts and need help.
Let's go.
- How are you, sir?
- Fine.
- How is everything here?
- Everything is fine.
- Is it all right?
- Very well, boss.
Come on, get down.
Jorgito, come here!
How's everything?
Thank God and the Blessed Virgin,
everything is peaceful these days.
I told you not to put that bench
there. It doesn't belong here.
Jorgito!
One can't even work in peace.
- Take this.
- Jorgito, give me a kiss.
Don't come near me!
What are you doing here?
Come on!
You won't be sleeping here.
José will show you to your room.
Go!
Go ahead.
All that peace couldn't last.
I don't know what is going to happen
with that devil in the house.
As the saying goes: "To the blind dog,
everything seems like flies."
Where the hell are you going?
This way.
And try not to talk too much.
Master doesn't like it.
Thank you, I don't want any.
As if you were a princess.
You can't be dificult here.
You must learn to eat whatever there is.
Where are you going, Ricardo?
What do you want?
Idiot! Where are you going?
It has nothing to do with you.
Let's leave this house.
I don't want to stay here!
Leave me alone.
What have I done
for you to treat me this way?
You've brought me here
where nobody likes me.
If you still have any love for me,
take me away from this house.
Love for you?
Have you seen spiders under a rock?
You step on it and crush them.
That's what I'll do to you.
But I still love you, Alejandro.
I've never done you any harm.
I hate you simply because you are.
You have his blood.
If you don't love me anymore,
let me go.
You'll never hear from me again.
You wanted to be my wife
and so it shall be.
You'll remain here ...
to cook for me
and wash my clothes.
And you won't leave this house
until I say so.
You let yourself get trapped, idiot.
You'd deserve
to be beaten to a pulp by him.
I don't like you,
but I feel sorry for you.
Don't be afraid.
I won't eat you up.
We can finish this business
once and for all.
What will you do?
Every night I go up to his room
and the door is locked.
Well locked …
but one of these days
he'll forget it.
Perhaps tonight...
For heaven's sake, don't!
Why don't you kill him?
You must hate him more than I do.
Isabel! Idiot!
Where are you?
I need you.
IsabeI, The state you're in!
What's the matter?
I walked all night.
I want to see my brother.
He's out. Besides,
I don't know if he wants to see you.
You know him.
Then I'll see Catalina.
Wait! She's very ill.
I must speak to her, Maria.
I must talk to someone.
Come.
- Catalina!
- How are you, Isabel?
As you can see.
I'm not surprised to see you
like this. I can imagine it all.
Sit down.
I'll watch for Master.
You must speak to Eduardo, Catalina.
He must allow me to come back here.
I can't stay on the farm.
If you knew all I've been through.
I've told you
I can imagine all of it.
Then you'll speak to Eduardo?
Will you tell him...
I won't tell him a thing.
It would be useless.
But I'm his sister,
he has to protect me.
We warned you in time,
but you wouldn't listen.
How could I know?
I thought you opposed to our relationship
because you were jealous.
Jealous of whom?
I can't be jealous of him.
It would be like being jealous of myself.
The advice I gave you was impartial.
Alejandro has never loved you.
I know it. That's why I don't want
to go back to him.
Please, speak to my brother.
He'll listen to you. Speak to him.
How are you, Cathy?
You're looking better.
Tell me that you feel perfectly well.
- What's the matter?
- Isabel is back.
Isabel has come back?
She's waiting for you
in Maria's room.
Poor Miss Isabel.
You are the best one, after all.
Until he came, we were in peace,
then everyone turned evil.
Everyone is selfish just like him.
The carriage will soon be ready.
You must return to the farm right away.
Eduardo.
I wasn't the one who made you marry him.
A married woman belongs with her husband.
When you see me like this,
don't you realize I can't stay there?
Leave!
You shouldn't have come.
You knew he's the man
I hate most in the world.
But you still eloped with him.
Why didn't you think twice?
Why did you deceive me?
If I let you come back to this house,
he'll come for you...
And I don't want to see him again.
So now you know.
Eduardo, I beg you.
I know I was wrong.
For the sake of our parents' memory,
let me come to you again.
It's useless, Isabel.
I'll leave now.
But let me tell you one thing.
He'll wind up stealing her from you,
dead or alive.
That will be your punishment!
Sir, forgive her,
she's only a child.
I don't want anybody
to mention her to me again.
Maria, Catalina has fainted.
Let's take her inside.
Where's that wine?
Hunting on Sunday: The one who kills
the youngest pays a fine.
Yesterday we killed 28 rabbits
and none of them was pregnant.
I'm not like you.
I go out everyday
and shoot whatever jumps.
Alejandro, I need more money.
I have to make up for my losses.
You don't have any collateral left.
You're a thief!
Give me a little.
Just a little, that's all.
What are you doing there?
You'll get indigestion and then,
I will pay for the consequences.
Don't worry, pretty one,
we never shoot females.
Leave her alone!
You think she's a maid!
Get out, all of you!
You have taken away everything.
There is nothing left.
Out!
Be careful, Ricardo.
You're drunk, but so am I.
No fights. Let's leave
and never set foot here again.
Leave right now!
You are in my house. You hear?
No more card games.
I don't want you to come back ever.
Serves us right.
We shouldn't come
play in certain places.
I can assure you I will never
set foot in this house again.
Neither will I.
Thank you for defending me, Ricardo.
Leave me alone.
I'm not your defender.
Go and open the door.
Sir, you know my brother.
Don't tell him you've seen me like this.
Don't worry.
Besides, I couldn't,
he's always with his wife.
- How is Catalina?
- Very bad.
What did you say?
I said that woman has
very little time left to live.
Come here.
What are you waiting for?
Come on!
Don Mariano, you can tell me the truth.
I saw her at birth.
I'm like a second mother to her.
Will she live?
She's very weak.
It all depends on how the birth goes.
Anyway, send for me immediately
if anything changes.
I'm very happy.
You heard the doctor.
- Everything will be alright.
- I don't like it when you lie to me.
You are all lying to me.
I know I won't survive
the birth of my child,
but I'm not afraid.
Why do you insist on torturing me?
Why don't you ask
why I insist on having black hair
or on being a woman.
I can't help it.
When the time comes,
don't be sorry.
If you leave me, I won't bear it.
I'm cold.
Maria, I want to see Catalina
for the last time.
- Tell her I want to see her.
- I won't.
Then I'll come in the house by force.
Who are you to stop me?
Nobody has ever loved her like I.
I must see her before she dies.
For weeks nobody has wanted
to tell me anything about her.
Master never leaves her.
Find a way to get rid of him.
You must help me see her!
Leave the doors open.
Go tell her,
I want her to be warned.
- Where is Master?
- I convinced him to sleep a few hours.
He hasn't slept too many nights.
Catalina,
someone is coming to see you.
Alejandro!
Why didn't you tell me sooner?
You did it on purpose!
You're always against me.
Hurry, bring my vanity case.
I want to do myself up.
I must be very pale.
Go away, Maria!
Leave us alone.
My darling.
Why have you come back this late?
Catalina!
I've come to never leave you again.
We have little time left.
I would like to hold you like this
until we both die.
How long do you intend to live
after I'm gone?
How long until you forget me?
Don't torment me, Catalina.
You are responsible for my death.
I don't pity you if you stay alone.
I know it makes you happy to think
that I'll writhe in a horrible hell
while you'll be resting in peace.
I won't be able to rest in peace.
In the ground,
I'll sufer as much as you.
You have done me great harm.
I'll never forgive you.
I've been to blame for loving you
so much. You love me that way too.
But I don't care. I'll take
the Alejandro I love with me.
Why have you been so cruel?
You've done what no one else
was able to do: Destroy our love.
You abandoned me
and I don't blame you.
My love,
I want to die with you.
-Alejandro!
-Catalina!
Don't go, my love.
Don't leave me ever again.
Just take care of her now.
You can find me
whenever you wish.
Maria!
Sir, she needs you.
The moment has come.
What are you doing there?
Go get the doctor immediately!
Dry your tears
because she won't need them.
Let the devil take us all.
- How did she die?
- After her child was born.
- A handsome boy.
- Never mind the boy.
Did she say my name
before she died?
She never regained consciousness.
I hope she wakes up in glory.
I hope she wakes up in hell!
Catalina,
I'm going to say a prayer for you
until my tongue goes dry.
Catalina, I hope you don't have
any peace while I live.
You said that I killed you
and the dead haunt their assassins.
Haunt me.
Make me crazy.
But don't leave me alone.
Don't leave me in this abyss.
Catalina, show yourself.
Come back to curse me.
Catalina!
"For the ungodly have said,
reasoning with themselves but not right.
"The time of our life is short
and tedious
"and in the end of a man,
there is no remedy,
"and no man hath been known
"to have returned from hell
"or from the other world.
"For we are born from nothing
"and after this,
"we shall be as if we had not been.
"For the breath in our nostrils
"is smoke,
"and speech a spark
to move our heart,
"which being put out,
our body shall be ashes
"and our spirit shall be
poured abroad as soft air,
"and our life shall pass away
as the trace of a cloud
"and be dispersed as mist, which is
driven away by the sun beams,
"and overpowered with the heat.
"And our name in time
shall be forgotten,
"and no man shall have
any remembrance of our works."
Drop your bloody book now!
And take that one to bed!
We want to be alone.
One can't even read the Lord's Book.
And poor Mistress didn't have
a prayer said for her in this house.
Son, wake up.
Her soul will call for amends to be made.
May the Lord forgive her
and forgive us all.
He has to come back sometime
or perhaps the earth swallowed him?
He's been away for 3 days
without eating or sleeping.
He has been seen from afar.
He must have gone crazy.
Or perhaps he went to lay on her tomb
like a faithful dog.
Let him come, to beat us all up,
or shoot himself in his room...
But let him come!
You're afraid of him.
You don't want to confess it.
But you're afraid of him.
And you're not afraid of him.
I don't know...
If he should come tonight,
he might break his neck in the ravine.
Everything would be over
and we would rest once and for all.
We can kill him when he comes here.
I have the key to his room.
He forgot it.
He'll go with Catalina.
It will rain on their bodies.
That will be the end of it all.
I've already told you, idiot.
I'm sure he cheats on you on her tomb.
You're nothing. Your husband
cheats on you with a dead woman!
A dry shot to the heart.
No.
A black hole between his eyes.
Will you help me, Isabel?
What do you want?
How shall I help you?
We'll kill him together.
I'll never be able to do it alone.
We have to put an end to him.
You must hate him more than I do.
I'll explain what we must do.
No, I don't want to.
He's stronger.
When he finds out
you want to kill him...
IsabeI, José!
Open up, you wretched!
Open up!
Now or never.
Open up.
That scoundrel knocks
as if he owned the place.
You'd better open.
Then we'll be rid of him in a second.
José, Open it now!
I don't want you to kill him.
He's my husband.
You're repulsive!
Don't change your mind.
Go away, Alejandro!
Your life depends on it.
You'd better open up, you bitch!
And still you insult me.
You are a brute without a heart.
Go back to her now.
Shoot yourself over her tomb.
Open it, Isabel!
I won't open.
I told you Ricardo wants to kill you.
Don't Alejandro. Please!
No, Alejandro, don't!
"These things they thought
and were deceived,
"for their own malice blinded them."
Don't you know how to eat?
Why didn't you put the bib on?
Is she already gone?
I'm talking to you.
I took her in the carriage myself.
And her brother took her in.
Sure, they're the same.
They held each other crying.
She will be alright there.
Better than in this house of the devil.
May everything be
through God's grace.
He stayed in his room all day,
crying and calling for her out loud.
Then he left through that door
looking like a doomed man.
God save us from him.
"Let none of us
go without his part in luxury
"and let us everywhere
leave tokens of joy
"for this is our portion
and our lot.
"And they knew not
the secrets of God,
"who created man incorruptible
and to the image of his likeness made him.
"But by the envy of the devil,
death came into the world.
"And they follow him
that are of his side."
Alejandro!
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm