BROKEN EMBRACES
What's your name?
Harry Caine.
I used to be called Mateo
and I was a film director.
I was always tempted by the idea
of being someone else,
as well as myself.
Living one life wasn't enough,
so I invented a pseudonym,
Harry Caine,
an adventurer who, as fate would
have it, became a writer.
I had him sign all the
scripts and stories I wrote.
For years,
Mateo Blanco and Harry Caine
shared the same body,
mine.
But a moment came
when suddenly I could
only be Harry Caine.
I became my pseudonym.
A self-made writer
made by himself.
There was just one
unforeseen detail.
Harry Caine would
be a blind writer.
Ernesto Martel's dead!
Who?
Ernesto Martel.
I know his granddaughter.
So he's dead.
Yes. Did you know him?
No.
What are you interested in?
Politics,
finance, culture...
I'm interested in you.
What are you like?
Do you mind describing yourself?
What do you want to know?
Your measurements, for example.
36", 26", 36".
What color are your eyes?
Green,
and in summer kind of bluish.
And your hair?
And how are you dressed?
I'm blonde,
with long, straight hair.
I'm wearing
a purple tank top,
tight jeans...
Tight?
Yes, tight.
And high heels.
How high?
Very high.
Let's see.
Blonde hair,
long.
Let's see, your eyes.
Green eyes,
in summer kind of blue.
And your skin...
What beautiful skin!
And your lips
are full.
May I use the bathroom?
Of course.
At the end of the hall.
Sorry, I thought you were alone.
- May I come in, or is there an encore?
- No, come in. We've finished.
She helped me cross the road, and
I asked her to read me the paper.
Yeah.
The place is in a mess.
- What are you looking for?
- My shirt.
Here.
Your shirt.
- Thanks.
- Anything else?
Your socks?
Yes, thanks.
Here.
Thanks.
Hello.
Well, Harry, I'll be off.
- Thanks for helping me cross.
- You're welcome.
- You're standing on my foot.
- I'm sorry!
Sorry.
- It was a pleasure.
- Likewise.
- Thank you.
- Not at all.
Well, I have to go.
I hope we meet again.
Yes.
You can't come home with the first
person to help you cross the road!
Something'll happen to you.
Everything's already
happened to me.
All that's left
is to enjoy life.
Diego told me you finished
the script yesterday.
I'd like to add a
final epilogue.
I was to give it to the producer
and the director today.
You'll have it tomorrow.
Ernesto Martel's dead.
He was very ill.
We haven't talked
about him in years.
That's true.
Hello.
You look awful.
I ran here.
This is Monday.
Don't run for my sake, Diego.
We aren't in a hurry.
I am. I gave my word.
You'll have it tonight.
We're changing the ending.
- Now?
- Yes.
Think about the next script.
Something with fantasy
or terror for brats.
It's what sells best.
I don't know if I can.
I'd thought about
working on a story based
on Arthur Miller's son.
- The writer who married Marilyn?
- Yes.
It appeared in Vanity Fair,
and I read it in El Pais.
After Marilyn, he married the
photographer Inge Morath,
and they had a son.
He was born with Down's syndrome,
and Miller hid him away.
He doesn't even mention
him in his memoirs,
and he never wanted to see him.
Despite his wife's pleas,
he would never see him.
That's awful!
But one day they met by chance.
Miller was giving a lecture
in defense of a mental retard
who'd been sentenced to death
after making a forced confession.
His son with Down's syndrome
was in the audience.
After the lecture, the son went up
to the stage and hugged his father.
Miller didn't know how
to get free of that man,
but then the stranger
let go of him and said,
"I'm your son Daniel, and I'm
very proud of you, Dad."
We'd have to ask the
family for the rights.
We'll change the names.
It isn't about the
writer's shabbiness,
it's about the strength
of the son who survives
without any grudge against the
father who'd ignored him.
It's very interesting,
but years ago, when you
started writing again
and I sold your scripts,
you said you'd never do
remakes, sequels or biopics.
I remember clearly because I
was surprised by the biopics.
This wouldn't be a biopic,
it's about overcoming the odds
- and about natural goodness.
- Yeah. I'll get the door.
I brought yogurts, but
he's out of cleaning stuff
and juice, too.
And pick up the dry cleaning.
- I'm off, guys.
- Okay, fine.
We'll talk about that later.
Okay, Judit.
- How are you?
- Fine, and you?
Fine. Got that session?
Freshly downloaded.
Great.
Hey,
you want a bit of crystal?
Nah, I need to sleep
occasionally.
Hide me.
Be more discreet.
There's hardly anyone.
Hey,
buy me a drink.
Whatever you want.
You want anything?
No.
To browse, use the arrows...
Personalize applications.
Explore Internet...
Obituary.
The financier of Chilean origin,
Ernesto Martel, died yesterday
in his home in Madrid.
Martel was one of the leading
businessmen in the '90s.
Ermar Capital, the empire
he created in the '80s,
helped finance important public
works in South American countries.
Twice married, with two sons,
he faded from public
life in recent years
after being implicated
in the Apresto scandal
and accused of fraud
and tax evasion.
In 2002, he was sentenced
to three years in prison
but only served...
I've just spoken to the
Minister of Transport
and it's all under way.
We're building the
Caracas subway.
Sure, there's a lot of money.
Well, at least five years.
Listen,
I'm looking for a qualified
company and I'd thought of you.
Of course.
It'll all go through me.
The President himself told me.
I'll call you later, okay?
Yes, Mr. Martel?
Lena, would you come
to my office, please?
I want to dictate a letter.
Yes, right away.
Hello.
Good morning.
The letter is for the
Minister of Industry.
"Dear Antonio, I'm delighted..."
I'm sorry.
- Are you all right?
- Yes.
"I'm delighted to
inform you that shortly
"I'll be meeting with a
Venezuelan committee..."
Sorry.
Why not tell me what's wrong?
I'm sure I can help you.
My father's very ill.
He's being discharged today
and I'd like to be there.
Of course. What's
wrong with him?
Stomach cancer, and it's spread.
Lord!
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
Where's Dad?
He's inside, waiting.
I can't believe they left you here,
put out on the street like dogs.
Wasn't the doctor to
operate this week?
He was supposed to.
This morning he told us
they were discharging him.
I asked what that meant.
He said, "It's simple, it's
July, I'm going on vacation."
On vacation?
I said, "Are you putting
us on the street?"
"No, ma'am, I'm
sending him home."
"But what can I do
with him at home?"
"That's your problem," he said.
"I'm going on vacation."
"He's dying," I said.
"He can die peacefully
at home," he answered.
They can't torture him for 20
days with tests and then do this.
Girls,
have you forgotten about me?
- Really, Dad!
- No one could forget you.
Sweetheart...
Take it slowly.
Isn't it nice to get out?
I'll put the bags in.
You'll be comfortable here.
I'll bring your pills.
Try to rest.
I'm leaving now, I've
got a lot to do.
You can call me at any time.
I'll come by in the morning.
Bye, Mom.
Take care.
Madame Mylene? Hello,
it's Severine.
Severine! It's been a long time.
How nice to hear you.
I need money.
When?
Now! I'm free at the weekend.
During the week I'm busy.
I'll see what I can do.
Can I call you tonight
if I've got anything?
Of course. I'll be waiting.
Yes?
Severine?
Who is this?
I'm calling on behalf
of Madame Mylene.
You're mistaken. There's
no Severine here.
I must have misdialed.
Forgive me.
- The rails, ma'am.
- Thank you.
Hello? Has he called you?
Who?
The client, who else?
- How dare you give him my number!
- I couldn't refuse.
That's not how it's done!
Have you gone crazy?
He knows all about you.
I didn't tell him, he
found out himself.
He knows that you tried
your hand at acting
and that at times you've
"performed" for me.
Months ago he made me promise
that if you contacted
me again, I'd call him.
I couldn't refuse,
he's my best client.
Yes?
Magdalena, love!
- Mom, how's Dad?
- Awful!
We had a terrible night.
He's been vomiting
blood and everything,
it's like he'd burst inside!
- I don't know what to do!
- I'm on my way.
Yes?
Mr. Martel? It's Lena.
Good morning.
I'm sorry to bother you.
You never bother me.
I'm calling because
my father is dying.
He has to be hospitalized,
but I don't know where.
They sent him home yesterday,
and we don't know what to do.
Don't worry.
We'll take him to
a private clinic.
I'll see to everything.
Don't worry, Dr. Blasco is the
best digestive surgeon in Europe.
How's the patient?
He arrived in a very bad condition.
I think you know that.
Can you save him?
I'm Ernesto Martel.
We'll do all that's possible,
but right now we can't operate.
And tomorrow?
Tomorrow, perhaps. We're
feeding him parenterally
and he'll need a blood
transfusion to recover.
Do the impossible to save him.
Of course, that's my duty.
I'll keep you
informed of progress.
May I stay, Doctor?
Of course, you can stay with
him as long as you wish.
Thank you.
I can't thank you enough.
I'm at your disposal, ma'am.
Mom, shall I stay with you?
No, go on, love,
you've done enough.
Shall I get you some food?
No, don't bother, I'll
get something later.
I'll call you.
Who is it?
I'm Ray X.
Ray X? No one's called that.
It's a nickname. At one time
I did a lot of ecstasy.
What do you want?
I want to write a script with
you and direct it myself.
Are you a director?
I made a very good
documentary 14 years ago.
This would be my
first fiction film.
Call Judit Garcia, my
agent, and talk to her.
She can fix an appointment.
And now I'd like to shower. You
got me out of the bathroom.
Are you going to
stay there all day?
You didn't give me
Judit Garcia's number.
Look it up. She's a well-known
production manager.
I'm leaving.
Yes, go on.
- Yes?
- Hello, Harry, it's me.
Hello, Judit.
A young director rang me.
His name's Ray X and he wants
to write a script with you.
- You know about it?
- Yes.
He wants to see you
this afternoon
or tomorrow.
I asked for an advance
and he's agreed,
but I can't go with you, I'm
busy with the Americans.
Okay, I'll see him and
tell you all about it.
I hope you like him, he
seems to be well-heeled.
- Have you seen him?
- No, from his voice,
and from the check I'll ask
for as soon as I hang up.
I'll send Diego so you're not alone.
Ciao.
Hello.
- I'm here to see Harry Caine.
- Yes, he's in his office.
Hello.
I'm Ray X.
How are you?
Sit down.
I'm listening.
I really like your work.
I've seen all of it.
Thank you.
Let's get to the point.
What kind of story do
you want to write?
Well...
Yes?
I'd like to write a story about
a son's revenge on
his father's memory.
Why does the son want revenge?
The father destroyed him
and ruined his life.
How?
The father is a violent
man, a homophobe,
unscrupulous and very powerful.
But the son is a sensitive boy,
with artistic interests,
but he's got lots of
complexes and he's weak.
He always tries to
please his father.
He's a homosexual, but he got
married twice, like his father.
And he separated, like he did.
He's got a son, who hates him
as much as he hated his father.
When the father dies,
the son can finally
rebuild his life.
That's his salvation,
his revenge,
and the story I want to tell.
I fear I'm not the writer
you're looking for.
You are.
More than you know.
I'll pay whatever you ask.
It's too personal.
Make it your own.
Thank you, but no.
Now, if you don't mind... Diego!
I'll leave you my number.
Come along.
In case you change your mind.
- Come along!
- Leave me alone!
I'm sure we'll see
each other again.
In my case, it would
be a miracle.
- Please, come with me.
- I'm coming!
Goodbye.
Son of a bitch!
- He was talking about himself, right?
- I guess.
Look in the top drawer.
Look through the photos
of the '94 shoot.
He may be in one of them.
Keep looking.
Here he is!
Describe the photo.
He's with you on the shoot.
He's got long, straight hair and
he's holding a video camera.
I was almost certain.
Who is he?
Ernesto Martel's son.
What can he want now?
Put the photos away
and close the drawer.
Hello, it's me.
We have to talk about our son.
I can't talk now, Rosana.
I caught him trying
on my dresses.
It's your fault. You made him
effeminate to humiliate me.
I'm sending him to you. After
all, you're his father.
If I haven't been a good father for
19 years, I doubt I'll learn now.
I have to go.
And tell him if he wants to talk
to me, he can ring me himself.
Don't be so hard on them.
They're blackmailers!
- Help me with my necklace.
- Of course.
Why not invite your son
here for a few days?
That's what his
mother just said.
But it's best not to
involve you with them.
He'd keep me company.
Does he like the
cinema or the theater?
Very much, I think.
His mother says he's
a bit of a fairy.
If I invite him, I'd like
you to tell me if it's true
and if you think
it can be fixed.
How should I know?
- I'm not asking you to screw him.
- Thanks a lot!
But you pretty girls
know those things.
Call him, but I won't do that.
It's disgraceful, Ernesto. I won't
say a thing about our separation,
but I don't like you
living with a man.
What'll your children think?
That their father is homosexual,
he's got good taste
and he's very lucky.
If they love me and you don't turn
them against me, they'll accept it.
You should've told me
before we got married!
If you'd stopped thinking
about my father's fortune,
- you'd have realized.
- What do you mean?
I'm hanging up. Pain in the ass!
I've got another call.
I hope it's not
your other ex-wife.
I hope not.
Never get married.
I'm not planning to right now.
This is Judit Garcia.
Hello, Judit. Did
you get the money?
I don't want it.
I've just sent it
back to you, Ernesto.
Won't you call me Ray?
That's my artistic name.
Artistic?
What are you trying to do?
Erase my father's name.
What's that got
to do with Harry?
I've wanted to see him for ages.
And it's true I want to make a film
and have him write the script.
I've got the male lead.
You're not a director.
If you saw my documentary,
you'd change your mind.
Ernesto,
forget about us.
Don't be scared of me.
I'm not my father.
Stay away from Harry.
If you try to see him again,
I'll report you for harassment!
I really don't want to
scout for locations
but the Americans are
paying me a fortune
and we need the money.
Go on, don't worry about me.
Give me Tonino Guerra's book.
I'm worried about Harry, too.
Look after him while I'm gone.
I'm busy, I can't spend
all day with him.
It's just two weeks!
Harry's fine on his own.
It's because of Ernesto Junior.
I'd like you to keep an eye out
so if he turns up again or calls,
you can let me know right away.
Why are you so worried?
He's crazy. I don't trust him.
Why?
- It's a long story.
- Give me a summary.
This isn't the time.
For you, it never is!
If you really mind
looking after Harry,
I'll just stay in Madrid,
or I'll hire someone.
I don't mind keeping him company,
but I'm sick of all the secrecy.
When is your mother back?
I'm not sure. In
ten days, I think.
What are you looking at?
A poster that says "Give blood".
And you want to give yours?
No, no.
I liked the sound of it.
It would be a great
title for a film.
Yes, it sounds good.
Like a vampire film.
That's true.
Imagine that behind the ad
there's a group of vampires
who work in various
donor centers,
they keep the blood
that's donated
and use it themselves.
Your mother would like that story.
We'll write it.
Give Blood.
The vampires live
like the Chinese,
as part of Spanish society but
without attracting attention,
and like the Chinese they also
control several industries.
Sunglasses, for example.
And late night bars,
discos, after-hours...
They don't need drugs to stay awake
so they're the best night workers.
And the sun cream business.
They're sensitive to climate
change and to holes in the ozone.
Their sun creams are the
best on the market.
That's good.
It must be a very thick cream, like
armor, to protect them all day.
That's how the story begins.
A very beautiful
girl, totally naked,
covering her body with
a really thick cream
before going to work
in a donor center.
Her body has a beautiful,
velvety pallor.
What a great beginning!
We need a love story.
A mixed love story,
between the young vampire
girl and a normal boy.
She works in one of those
blood donor centers
where they use the
blood themselves.
He goes there to give blood.
They instantly like each other.
After she puts the needle in his
vein, she gets really aroused.
They start dating.
But she doesn't want him
to become a vampire.
Those vampires don't proselytize.
They don't bite people
unless it's really necessary.
But they like sex, right?
Sure.
That'll be one of the problems
because we need some tension.
They really desire each other
but when it comes to
screwing she holds back.
Why?
In case she loses control and bites
his jugular when she's aroused.
When they're randy, she
lets him do everything,
in front, behind, whatever,
except kiss her on the mouth.
And her breasts?
That's a high risk area.
When he kisses her breasts
she has to cover her face
with the pillow and she rips
it apart with her teeth!
And when she eats his dick?
No blowjobs. She'd tear
it off right away.
And how does he feel about that?
You can do without kisses,
but it's tough when they
won't eat your dick.
He's so in love he accepts it.
When they know each other
better, she'll wear a muzzle,
to protect both of them.
When she gets excited, she has
a kind of dental erection
and her mouth grows out,
like she was a wolf.
I really like your story.
You'll sign this one.
I'll be your sparring partner,
like you've always been for me.
The music you play
is fucking great.
And I really like you.
Did he tell you?
I want us to be great friends, and
you have to tell me everything.
Let me work.
You have to tell me everything.
I need liquid.
Sorry, he's blasted on GHB.
I don't like being felt up.
You want a bit of MDMA?
Just a bit.
I'm working tomorrow.
We're doing a great
vampire script.
Yeah?
Want some GHB?
I've had some MDMA.
- I think your friend likes me.
- What's up?
Diego! What's up?
What is it?
- Is that yours?
- Coca Cola with GHB.
Asshole! Why did you put
it beside his drink?
Take it easy.
He's wasted.
Get some ice. Call an ambulance.
- Yes?
- Diego?
No, I'm a friend of his.
Diego's sick.
We're taking him to Emergency.
Why? What's happened?
Can I speak to him?
No, it's...
Where are you taking him?
- Where are you taking him?
- Quiron Hospital.
Quiron Hospital.
Come on, get in.
He's coming.
That's his jacket.
Okay.
- Excuse me, do you need help?
- Yes, please.
I have to hang up. You
want the hospital?
- Yes, I do.
- I'll go with you.
I'll hold on to you.
- You want Reception?
- Yes.
How are you?
I don't know. Shocked.
Did you speak to my mother?
Yes.
- Did you tell her about the coma?
- No! Are you crazy?
Anyway, it was only six hours.
If you ever tell her,
say you fainted.
Or whatever.
I told her you ate something
that disagreed with you.
Did she believe you?
I don't know.
She wanted to rush back, but
I persuaded her not to.
Are you asleep?
No, I'm not sleepy anymore.
- You want to talk?
- No.
You want me to talk?
I don't know. If you want to...
I mean, to distract you.
Before I went into films
I was very good at
telling stories.
Then will you tell me why my mother
is so afraid of Ernesto Junior?
Is she?
She made me promise
I'd keep an eye out
in case he reappeared.
She didn't explain why?
She never explains anything.
It's a long story.
That's what she says.
How did you meet him?
We met him fourteen years ago.
In an office we'd rented
to prepare my latest film.
After writing and
directing five dramas,
I'd finally written a comedy,
or so I thought
I wanted to change genres
and take a risk.
And I certainly did.
Take a risk, I mean.
Mateo...
There's a girl here.
She doesn't have an appointment.
What's she like?
Too pretty to be funny.
Really?
She's the financier Ernesto
Martel's mistress.
She's here with his son.
Is she an actress?
If she's been with that man
for two years, she must be.
But come out and say
hello, just to be polite.
You have to be nice
to important men.
- You never know.
- Okay.
GIRLS AND SUITCASES
Hello.
- Lena.
- I'm Mateo.
I'm Ernesto Martel, Junior.
How are you?
I apologize for
turning up like this.
I heard you were holding
auditions for your next film.
- Yes.
- I'd love to audition.
I can come another day.
Now that you're here,
we'll read something.
Okay.
The reading didn't work.
We were both too nervous.
The first meeting only
served to show me
that the mere presence of
that woman disturbed me.
Where were you this morning?
Didn't Ernesto tell you?
I didn't ask him.
We went to see a film director
to do an audition.
An audition? Why?
I want to work.
Weren't you going to
redecorate the house?
You have to change the
furniture, carpets, lamps...
I don't know how to do that.
Get in a decorator.
Even if I do, you'll
have to guide him.
That way, you'll learn.
I want to be an actress.
I always have.
You tried before, and
look how you ended up.
That was below the belt.
I'm sorry, my love, forgive me.
I'm going upstairs.
Lena, please.
Don't get angry,
darling, I beg you.
In any case, don't worry.
I was no good.
I was very nervous.
Telephone. It's Mr.
Mateo Blanco.
Come in!
He says it's important.
Yes?
Yes.
Of course.
Very well.
Thank you.
That was the director.
The audition wasn't enough,
he wants to see me again.
What are you going to do?
Go and see him, no?
I need to do something.
- I've always wanted to be an actress.
- And what about me?
This is Magdalena Rivero. I want
to cancel my massage tomorrow.
I'll call you another time.
Thank you.
They still haven't
given me the part.
They will.
If they do, it won't
change anything,
except that I'll be
working too, like you.
And at night we'll tell
each other what we've done.
Why don't we get married?
What?
I'm asking you to marry me.
Haven't you got married and
divorced enough times?
With you, it would
be the first time.
We've been living
together two years.
We're fine like this,
don't you think?
It seems you don't.
Martel offered to produce the film.
Your mother didn't want that.
We were waiting for a subsidy
from the Ministry...
Can't I help?
No, I want to give
you a demonstration.
...and a television pre-sale.
But that would take months,
and I was in a real hurry
to start shooting.
Just like Audrey.
Spot on, faggot.
- Totally Audrey!
- Yes, it's true.
This guy's a pain!
Move closer to the mirror.
Light up your face.
Now look at me in profile
with an exaggerated
smile, like the model.
Okay. Like that one?
Yes. Come on.
Now.
More of a smile in your eyes
and close your mouth more.
Come on. Now.
Very good. Again.
Open your mouth a little more.
Now.
Wonderful, very good.
Again.
That's it. Great.
- Art!
- Totally!
Great.
Now I'd like to try
something much more daring.
A platinum blonde wig.
Something very pop.
I've got one!
I've got a Goldie Hawn
type with much more volume
- that'll look fabulous.
- But she mustn't look like a poodle.
- No?
- No.
- If she isn't a poodle, she isn't Goldie.
- Then forget it.
I told you he wouldn't
like Goldie, faggot.
He wears it when
he gets dressed.
- So, platinum blonde.
- Yes.
I'll change your make up.
Get out of the way!
Look, the wig's false,
it's really bad.
It's Kanecalon fiber,
but it looks fabulous.
Okay, let's have a look.
You'll flip out.
Put on these earrings.
Judit, can you
move to your left?
Are you tired?
No.
Don't smile.
The wig is false enough.
That's it.
Wonderful.
From the start, Judit
didn't like Lena.
But I liked her more every day.
And Ernesto Junior liked me
and I intended to use that.
His father had asked him to make
a documentary about the shoot.
As for Ernesto Senior,
I'd never met a man so
obsessed by a woman.
He was producing the film
in a desperate attempt
not to lose Lena.
This is shit! It's
incomprehensible!
Action!
In the midst of that
emotional panorama,
we started shooting.
Now think of all the times
you've made gazpacho for Ivan
and how he enjoyed it.
And that really hurts you.
We'll do the first time
you come back home
after a photo session.
As soon as you open the door, you
look over at the answer phone.
Okay.
If it's flashing,
it may be Ivan.
"'If it isn't flashing, it'll
be another day of despair
"'because you've been looking
for him for two days.'
"'All right, okay, okay.
"'Listen, did you like the
bit with the tomatoes?'
"'Yes, a lot, it moved me.'
"'Me, too. It really moved me.'
"'It's amazing that you could
be moved by tomatoes.'
"'It wasn't the tomatoes,
"'it was the nice things
you were saying to me."'
Do you think they
like each other?
Me?
I don't know anything.
I just look at their lips.
"'Samples?'
"'What do you think?"'
- Cut!
- Very good. Print it.
- Are you going to do anything?
- No, you can go.
I don't mind staying.
You should go. I'm going
to check some wigs.
Wigs? I love that!
No, you don't.
You've filmed hours of wigs.
This is more of the same.
And Lena?
Lena?
After we've tried the new
wigs she wants a massage.
She's got a cramp.
I haven't got any cramps.
Couldn't I tape it?
Ernesto, please, don't be such a pain.
Go away!
Bye.
- Edurne...
- Yes?
I'm going to speak to Lena. I
don't want to be interrupted.
Don't worry, I'll see to it.
I'll be your watchdog.
Wait! Is his son out there?
No, I sent him home.
Edurne's keeping watch.
Mateo, this is crazy.
Hello.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Waiting for you.
I didn't think film making
was such hard work.
Yes, it is. It doesn't stop.
It's very absorbing.
Aren't you tired?
Chocolate gives me energy.
I love bitter orange
with chocolate.
I meant the shoot,
not the chocolate.
Oh, very.
At the end of the week, I'm
very tired, but I'm happy.
I thought we could take a break,
a weekend, just you and I,
in the house on Ibiza.
We rehearse on weekends.
Don't you rehearse
during the shoot?
Yes.
Do you spend the whole
day rehearsing?
- That's how you make a film.
- What about other people?
You can't just leave
them aside for months.
The film sets the rules.
No, I set them.
I'm the producer.
- Is there a problem?
- Yes.
It's completely impersonal.
I asked for a graphic set,
but this is totally dead!
- Shall I speak to Antxon?
- No, I'll do it.
What's wrong with you?
You look awful.
It's Diego.
He could hardly breathe all night.
Neither of us got any sleep.
You still don't know what it is?
Some doctors say it's asthma,
others that he's allergic,
but we don't know to what.
They're still investigating,
but we're desperate.
Take all the time you need.
Right now, your son
is what matters.
Thank you.
Another thing.
- I was talking to the producer.
- And?
He's complaining that Lena's
too absorbed by the shooting.
How does he think
films are made?
Ernesto is a businessman,
not an artist.
No one asked him to
become a producer!
It's too late to
argue about that.
He's taking her to
Ibiza this weekend
so you can't rehearse.
Son of a bitch!
Get rid of the lamps, the
table, the chairs...
I wanted a graphic set,
but it should be alive.
God, I look awful!
You get scared when I touch you,
but not when you see me dead?
I didn't think you were dead.
I thought you were asleep.
I usually snore.
If I'd thought you were dead, I
wouldn't have got made up for you.
Any man of my age could
have a heart attack
after screwing six times.
You're not a man of your age.
I wouldn't mind dying
after fucking with you
for days, weeks, months,
years, centuries.
I'm crazy about you,
you drive me crazy.
I guess you know that.
Yes.
I think I do.
Action!
Look at what I found on the sidewalk.
They fell off your terrace.
They were gifts from
Ivan, I threw them out.
You can't do that, Miss Pina.
You could kill someone.
In Naples, on New Year's Eve,
they even throw out furniture.
My grandpa was Neapolitan,
and it's in my blood.
But this isn't Naples and
today isn't New Year's Eve.
I was nervous, throwing things
out relaxes me. You keep them.
They'll come in handy.
"Love."
You say "love," I say "sex."
Cut!
- Shall we print it?
- Like hell!
I'll fix your make-up
after, okay?
You're not on form today.
I know.
What's wrong?
I'll tell you later.
- We'll have a sandwich break.
- 30 minutes?
Yeah.
We'll take a 30 minute
sandwich break.
Let's clear this a
bit and go outside.
No lips.
"I've had a horrible weekend."
"But we didn't rehearse
so that you could rest."
"Rest?"
"I had that son of a bitch
on top of me for 48 hours."
"He didn't let up for a second."
"The bastard."
"I'm living on tranks."
No lips.
"No, no. I'll get over
it and I'll do it."
"Are you sure?"
"Yes."
"You have to be
witty and light."
"Of course."
"Light."
You don't know what it's like
having that monster on
top of you for 48 hours.
It makes me sick.
"It's best if you don't
think about it."
"It's best if you and I
never talk about Ernesto."
"It's best not to open
that can of worms."
What do you do with
your notebooks?
I fill them.
And then?
I burn them.
I'd rather the
notebooks slept here.
Slept?
Leave them here. You'll
get them back tomorrow.
When you finish, I'll keep them.
Very well. Whatever you say.
What time tomorrow?
I'll call you when the
material is ready.
I presume you are aware of the total
confidentiality of your work.
Of course.
Goodbye.
Hello, Lena.
Hi.
My father was asking why I
don't go with you to yoga.
- He always asks.
- Tell him that I'm grown up and free,
and that I've forbidden
you to follow me.
I can't tell him that.
Try it. It would do you good.
I can't.
Do what you like, but
don't come with me.
You're such a pain!
What are you doing?
Working.
Turn that off! Didn't Mateo forbid
you to tape us off the shoot?
My father told me to ignore that.
He wants to see everything.
Neither of you has any scruples!
Fucking leave me alone!
Remember I'm taping you.
Stop, I said.
Stop!
I told you to stop! Give
me the fucking camera!
- You're crazy!
- Just leave me alone!
Let go! My camera!
Focus on me!
Ernesto,
listen carefully.
Yes, I'm talking to you.
I've just been with
the man I love
and I'm happier
than I've ever been
because that man loves me too,
a lot.
Don't worry, I'll leave
you in peace very soon.
You needn't spy on us anymore.
There's nothing to hide now.
I don't know if you got back a
little late or a little early.
- It was raining, we couldn't shoot.
- Where are you going?
I'm leaving you.
Shouldn't we talk first?
I've said all I had
to say to you.
Lena, please!
Please, Lena!
Goodbye.
Listen to me.
Let go.
Turn over, my love.
I'll help you.
Let me do it.
Relax, I'll help you.
You could have broken something.
I'll take off your shoes.
You'll be more comfortable.
I'll see to everything. Come on!
Help me.
My love, be careful.
Sit down, but be careful.
My darling.
That's it.
I'll take you to the hospital.
My wife fell down the stairs.
Be very careful, please.
Let's see, be careful.
Her head.
Easy does it.
Be careful with my legs.
Take her to Trauma.
Can I make a call?
Not in here. In the
doctor's office.
- It's urgent.
- We'll take you there right away.
Mateo?
Yes.
What's wrong? Aren't you coming?
No, not tonight.
Has something happened?
Something came up unexpectedly,
but don't worry,
everything's fine.
Tomorrow it's an evening shoot.
Shall I see you before?
No, I can't make it.
I've got a lot to do. I'll
see you at the studio.
You sound odd. There's
really nothing wrong?
No.
I'll see you tomorrow.
There they are.
Ask no questions.
How are you, ma'am?
Fine.
Can I help you?
No, I'm all right, thank you.
It was nothing.
You go on ahead and
open the door.
Thank you for your discretion.
Can you take off your
glasses, please?
What should I do?
What can I do so
you'll forgive me?
Take me to the studio.
You shouldn't move.
If you don't, I'll drag
myself there if I have to.
What'll you say?
How will you explain the
cast and the bruises?
It depends on you.
On me?
I'll do what you want if you
promise to stay with me.
I'll stay with you
if you let Mateo finish the
film however he wishes.
He'll interrogate
you, he isn't stupid.
I'll say I tripped.
How can you work
if you can't walk?
He'll decide that,
but I want to be sure you'll
respect his decision,
no matter what it costs
or the time it takes.
Understood?
I live there.
That's everything.
Ernesto will back
whatever you decide.
Decide what?
I can't go from a shot
of you walking normally
to one of you in a cast!
When can you take it off?
In three weeks.
May I speak to Lena alone?
Tell me the truth.
People don't fall down stairs.
That only happens in films.
Keep your voice down!
We have to finish shooting
as soon as we can.
- Until then I can't leave Ernesto.
- Why?
He's a psychopath. What
more proof do you need?
My God!
I can't leave!
I promised to stay with him if
he lets you finish the film
under your conditions.
There must be another solution.
What is it?
The only solution is that I stay
with him until you're finished.
What have you promised exactly?
To live under the same roof,
in separate bedrooms.
He's got no rights.
Do you think he'll accept that?
I don't know,
but the sooner we
finish the better.
We mustn't stop now!
We just have one
scene on the stairs.
We'd have to repeat the ending.
Retake 23. One, first.
Action!
So you're Ivan's ex-wife,
the one who's been in a
mental hospital for 20 years.
Yes, but I'm not in a
mental hospital now.
I'm here with you,
going down the stairs.
From the note, it seems
you're anxious to see him.
Yes, but you go first.
You're the one in a hurry.
I've been waiting 20 years.
Go on.
As I was saying,
after I split up with my husband
I went out on the street
and there was a guy
eyeing me, good-looking,
his ass...
His feet...
I brought him home and
screwed him several times.
I'm very interested in
sex as a social matter.
- How was it?
- In bed?
Divine, a virtuoso. I've
never seen anything like it.
This is the good take.
His big toe!
Every morning, Lena arrived
at the shoot exhausted.
By sheer repetition,
there was always a take in which
she managed to do it well.
Living with Martel
had become hell.
Lena didn't say anything,
but it was obvious.
When shooting finished I
begged her to leave him,
but she was scared for the film.
She didn't want to leave him
at least until I'd chosen
all the good takes.
Yes?
- It's Magdalena.
- ls anything wrong?
No, I'm down below. I've
got no money for the taxi.
I'm coming down.
I'll be right back.
She's in the washroom.
What happened?
We had a terrible fight.
He tore off my clothes and
threw me out on the road.
Give the taxi driver a tip. He
lent me his jacket, otherwise...
Son of a bitch!
We'll report him to
the police right now.
Take me far away
from here, please.
Yes, of course.
Whatever you want.
Give me the camera.
What are you writing?
The secret of Golfo Beach.
When I took the photo I didn't
see the couple kissing.
And what's the secret?
I don't know. I have to
write it to find out.
We're that couple.
Two people, just
like when they died.
A man and a woman.
They died together.
Before we knew, a
month had passed.
I knew that sooner or later
we'd have to go back,
but we kept putting it off.
I was only worried about
your mother and you.
I hadn't even said
goodbye to you,
and you had all those
allergies when we left.
OPENING SOON
GIRLS AND SUITCASES
I was wondering
when he'd turn up.
But they can't open the
film so soon, can they?
He's doing it to annoy us. It's
a trick so you'll go back.
All the ad needed was
the word "Wanted".
What'll we do?
Nothing. Screw him!
PREMIERE TONIGHT
DISASTER
What does it say?
That the only intelligent thing we
did was not to go to the premiere.
Bastards!
Judit?
It's me. I have to
speak to you urgently.
Call me, please.
I'll give you the number.
845132...
28...
Sorry, 28845132.
And ask for Harry Caine. I'm
registered under that name.
Are you there?
I'll be expecting your call.
Mom didn't call back?
No.
Why?
She was angry, I guess.
Even so, she should've told
you what was happening.
But she didn't, and we've
never talked about it.
Weren't you curious?
Me? I was dying of curiosity!
For two days I kept calling
your mother and the editor,
but neither answered.
So I decided to
go back to Madrid
and see with my own eyes
what was happening.
It's the first time
we've been apart.
I'll be back at the weekend.
But if you're worried,
come with me.
No, I'm better off here.
Madrid scares me.
Magdalena's death didn't surprise
us locked in an embrace,
as we'd dreamed,
but sitting in separate seats.
It even surprised me
by leaving me alive.
Say something.
Mateo is dead.
Don't say that.
We address him by his name,
but he refuses to answer.
He insists that Mateo is dead.
His work revolves around images.
I guess that for him living
in the dark is death.
- Is there any chance that he'll see?
- None.
He has what we call
cortical blindness
and it's irreversible.
That's very good,
very good.
There are some steps
to the right.
But not here.
You have to go
forward a bit more.
I'll guide you until
we reach the edge.
Come on.
That's it.
We're almost there.
Now there are a few
steps down to the car.
We'll take them carefully,
they're very high.
They're 10 inches, I
measured them earlier.
Wait, I'll put down your bag.
Come on.
The first is the hardest,
but I'm holding on to you.
Yes, slide your feet along.
That's it, let's go.
Very good.
Come on.
Now, the second one.
That's right.
A little more.
There.
That's it, no more steps.
Did you go to see Lena's
mother in the village?
Yes.
What did she say?
She was very grateful to Ernesto
for taking care of everything.
- Is she there?
- Yes.
They buried her with her father.
Did you see the grave?
Yes.
What's it like?
Simple.
Her mother didn't
want anything fancy.
Look, mom, the sea!
We're in Famara.
Stop, please. I'll get out here.
No, wait a minute.
How can you get out?
Go to Reception and do
what you have to do.
I'll wait for you on the beach.
- I want to get out here too.
- How can you get out in this wind?
- I don't mind the wind.
- Be quiet, Diego.
Stop the car, please.
Mom, please, let me stay.
It's the first time
I've seen the sea.
- Please.
- All right.
- Wrap up well.
- Okay.
And don't go to near the water.
Give him your hand.
Don't let go of him, please.
You wrap up, too.
Oh, Lord.
That's it.
Careful, there's a step.
Let's go.
Wait here, please.
Good morning.
Harry!
Harry Caine!
We're here!
We have to go, Harry.
Come on, Diego.
Give me your hand.
Can't we stay a bit longer?
No, you have to
obey your mother.
You've had enough
wind for today.
I'm here, Harry.
Careful you don't trip.
Do you remember Famara?
Perfectly. It was the
first time I saw the sea.
I remember the kites and
a dog that was barking.
I remember the dog barking, too.
What are you doing?
I'm trying to reconstruct
some of your photos.
I've got one that's
almost complete.
What do you want to
see to cheer you up?
I'd like to hear
Jeanne Moreau's voice.
I don't have her number.
Look for Elevator to the
Gallows, by Louis Malle.
Okay.
Fritz Lang,
Jules Dassin, Nicholas Ray...
Look up above.
Fanny and Alexander,
Eight and a Half,
Magnificent Obsession,
Elevator... Here it is.
I've never seen it.
I hope you like it.
How can I throw it out?
The police have to find it...
Leave that! It's
Girls and Suitcases.
I don't understand.
It's obvious, babe!
If the police find 30 pounds
of uncut cocaine in my house,
they could arrest me.
But I don't understand how that
suitcase appeared in your house,
like that, all of a sudden.
Doesn't it sound odd?
As I was saying, after I
split up with my husband
I went out on the street and
there was a guy eyeing me,
good-looking, his ass...
His feet...
I brought him home and
screwed him several times.
They're completely off key.
In bed? A virtuoso.
Look, my hairs are
standing on end.
How could I have chosen those takes?
They're both terrible.
What do you want to do today?
I have to go home.
Mom left a message that
she's coming back today,
to celebrate your birthday.
It's my birthday?
That's what she says.
If Judit says so...
Happy birthday!
I'll have to take
you out to dinner.
Anyone at home?
Yes.
Love,
I was dying to see you!
What's up?
Do they show a lot?
Yeah.
Today I didn't even have
time to wipe my ass.
Don't look at me like that. I
thought you'd be used to it.
Yes, I'm sorry.
You're so handsome!
Are you all right? I
was worried about you.
I'm fine.
Mateo looked after
me day and night.
Mateo?
Don't you call him
Harry anymore?
Yes.
We have to buy him a
birthday present.
What have you been
doing all this time?
Nothing.
Watching films
and talking.
Talking?
Yes.
About what?
Mom, for God's sake!
And what was wrong with you?
I don't know if I believe
the gastroenteritis.
You used it as an
excuse in a script.
I had an accident, but I'd
rather not talk about it now.
An accident?
What kind of accident?
It's hard to explain.
Try it, I'm not so dumb.
We'll leave it for another day.
I'm fine now.
I'm going to buy
some DVDs for Mateo.
I don't know what you've
talked about all these days,
but I do know what I haven't
told you in all these years.
I never asked you.
But you'll have asked
yourself a thousand times.
This is your birthday present.
It's for you too, Diego.
After you two disappeared,
Ernesto Senior only
wanted revenge.
- Forget it.
- No.
- You've had a bad day today.
- That's why.
I'd like to end it better.
He had a crazy plan to
get his revenge on you,
but to carry it out
he had to bribe us,
at least, me and
Luis, the editor.
Even though it was crazy,
there was no problem.
We both sold out
without any objection.
Luis and I.
With me,
he was courteous enough to
provide me with an alibi.
He suggested I go to the U.S. for
six weeks, to the Mayo Clinic
so Diego could be cured
of his aspergillosis.
That way, I wouldn't
be present while he
destroyed your film.
Because that was his plan.
To reduce the film to rubble.
I preferred to stay in Madrid
and have Diego cured here.
I wanted to witness everything.
If I was going to betray you,
I wanted to suffer the
price I had to pay.
It was torture
seeing how Ernesto chose
all the worst takes
and how Luis edited them,
turning your film
into a monster.
The only way to bear all
that was to suffer more.
I sold myself to Ernesto
out of pain and jealousy.
I couldn't bear or forgive
that you left with Lena
without saying a word.
With my treachery, I got my revenge
on you, on her and on myself.
The only innocent one was Diego.
Forgive me, love,
for how bitter I've
been all these years.
No one deserves to
grow up with that.
Another gin and tonic, please.
Don't look at me like that.
Thank you.
Don't go on. It isn't necessary.
Yes.
Now that you're calling yourself
Mateo again, I've got no excuse.
You've told us everything.
No, not everything.
No one knew where you were.
We had no idea.
Ernesto organized all that,
the premiere, all that
fuss, so that you'd react.
His revenge was meaningless
if neither of you responded.
He asked me constantly
about your whereabouts
but I knew nothing
either, which was true.
That's why I didn't want to call you,
so as not to complicate your life.
He hired various detectives
to look for you,
but before they could find you
you called me,
two days after the premiere.
I was too ashamed to answer
and too dazed.
I still am.
When Ernesto asked
me about you again,
I don't know why,
I gave him the number in Famara.
He sent his son to look
for you on Lanzarote.
It was Ernesto Junior who
found you after the accident
and called the hospital.
Did he have anything to
do with the accident?
No!
But I keep thinking
that if I hadn't given
that number to his father
perhaps nothing would
have happened.
Why do you think that?
I don't know.
A guilty conscience, I guess.
Well, that's enough!
14 years with a guilty
conscience is sufficient.
Wait, I'll help you down.
No, thank you.
Good night.
Call if you need anything.
Diego isn't answering.
Leave a message.
Hello, Diego. It's Mateo.
I'm sorry to call so early.
Tell your mother to
call me when she can.
Thanks.
- Harry, why so early?
- I couldn't sleep.
That's too bad!
Coffee and toast?
Yes, but first would you
call this number for me?
Ray X?
- Here.
- Thanks.
I'll get your coffee.
Ernesto?
Who is this?
I'm sorry to bother you.
This is Mateo Blanco.
Look at this!
You have to start the day well.
How do you feel?
A bit hung over, but I'm fine.
I think the catharsis
last night did me good.
Let me help you.
No, sit down.
Sit down.
Diego,
yesterday I had one
more thing to tell you.
Tell me later. We'll
have breakfast now.
If I don't tell you now,
I may never tell you.
At the end of the '80s,
Mateo and I had a love affair.
I thought so, even before
the catharsis last night.
You did?
It's obvious!
The same curtains in
your bedroom and in his,
souvenirs of Mexico and the Caribbean
in both houses, the crosses...
Right.
There's something else I
think you don't know.
Mateo is your father.
He's my father?
Yes.
And the fleeting lover,
my supposed biological father?
Did you make him up?
I can hide things,
but I'm incapable of
making things up.
The fleeting lover existed.
We had an affair. He was gay
and the affair was very brief.
Does Mateo know?
Are you crazy?
At the time he asked me and
I denied it, of course.
I didn't want to pressure him.
I didn't want that to
change our relationship.
And I'd never asked him if
he wanted to be a father.
Fuck!
So Mateo's my father.
By the way, he rang
early this morning.
Mateo? What did he want?
You're to call him when you can.
Why didn't you waken me?
Because after last night
you needed to rest
and he didn't say it was urgent.
Pass me the phone.
- Yes?
- Hello.
Diego told me you rang. Are you okay?
Do you need anything?
No, I'm not okay,
and, yes, I do need something.
The 40,000 meters of negative we
shot in my last film, to edit it.
I'm at Ernesto Junior's house,
and I've found out that the
material was destroyed in '94.
I imagined something like that,
but I didn't think
they'd do it so soon.
- Why are you in Ernesto's house?
- I think I'll blackmail him.
We need money, and he's
got lots to spare.
I don't want Diego going
back to that damn bar.
I want to pay him a salary.
Don't be crazy.
There's no one else to
accuse of Magdalena's death.
Oh, God!
Wait, I've got
something to tell you.
Last night you said enough.
Listen to me!
I was production
manager on the film,
the only person with access
to the lab and the material.
After giving Ernesto's order to
destroy it, I intercepted it
and I kept it. I've
got it all at home.
You're lying.
I didn't tell you last night because
I didn't know you wanted to edit it.
I took it all,
the double takes, the interneg,
the sound tapes, everything!
You can have it all.
That changes everything.
Get out of there
and leave Ernesto in peace. He's
got nothing to do with this.
He still has to tell me
why he was in Lanzarote.
Bye, I'll call you later.
Ernesto and his camera.
You remind me of Peeping Tom.
Yes, but I never
wanted to kill you.
I'm not so sure.
This copy of The Making
of will prove it.
Why do I want it?
I can't see it.
Someone you trust can see
it and tell you. Excuse me.
These are the final images of the
documentary on Mateo Blanco,
also known as Harry Caine.
How's the documentary,
as Ernesto calls it?
Very interesting.
What are you seeing now?
The last night, coming
back from the restaurant.
How could he tape us?
It was very dark.
His car headlights and the
lighting on the mobile sculpture
were enough to see
what happened.
And he's retouched it digitally.
Ernesto didn't cause
the accident,
and, as well, he was
the first to help you.
How could he tape and
drive at the same time?
I don't know.
Anything else I should know?
What are you watching now?
When you were waiting
at the roundabout
for a car to pass on your left,
Lena and you kissed.
We kissed? I don't
remember that.
It's a normal kiss,
the kind couples give
each other out of habit.
The last kiss.
Yes.
Lena didn't die in your
arms like you'd dreamed,
but the last sensation
she took from this world
was the taste of your mouth.
Is it here?
Yes.
Play it frame by frame,
so that it lasts longer.
14 years after shooting it,
I could finally edit
Girls and Suitcases.
- It's you...
- I left you 1,000 messages.
1,000 from you and
none from Ivan.
What's that suitcase?
It's Ivan's. He's leaving me.
And the crutches?
His ex-wife, the lunatic,
pushed me down the stairs.
I've split up with
my husband, too.
I'm sorry.
I've made coffee, do
you mind pouring it?
I was looking for
Ivan all night.
Then I had a photo session,
and I still haven't slept.
Neither have I.
- When did you two split up?
- Four days ago.
Sugar?
I saw it coming.
But after we broke up, I
went out on the street
and saw a guy looking at me.
Gazpacho! I'll have some.
No!
I put in a whole box
of sleeping pills.
Why?
In case Ivan came.
He loves gazpacho.
Really, Pina!
That's nothing. As he didn't
call, I tore out the phone.
I tripped over it,
but I didn't ask because I don't
want to be inquisitive...
The bed...
ls that smoke?
I dropped a match and it went on fire.
I didn't want to put it out.
Fire purifies.
Get your coffee.
Were you telling me something?
Oh, yes!
I was telling you
that I've got a
suitcase at home, too.
Your husband's?
No.
A suitcase with 30 pounds of
top quality, uncut cocaine.
Are you a dealer now?
No! I'm still a Councillor
for Social Affairs.
The suitcase appeared
in my closet,
all of a sudden.
I have to get rid of those
30 pounds right away.
There's a lot of drugs in
politics, because of the hours.
Between the party
and the Council,
I could shift five
pounds, but the rest?
Throw it away!
Are you crazy?
I have to make sure the police
don't find it in my house.
I don't understand...
It's obvious!
If they catch me with all that
cocaine, they'll arrest me.
Yes, but I don't understand how
the case appeared in your closet.
As I was saying, after I
split up with my husband
I went out on the street and
there was a guy eyeing me,
good-looking,
his ass...
His feet...
I brought him home and
screwed him several times.
I'm very interested in
sex as a social matter.
How was it?
In bed? A virtuoso.
I've never seen
anything like it.
What a big toe!
Look, my hairs are
standing on end.
Then what happened?
After we screwed,
he asked if he could stay
with me for a few days.
- Got any muffins?
- Yes, on the shelf.
- And there's creme caramel.
- I'll have that afterwards.
So, he asked if he could
stay and I said all right,
but I wasn't promising anything.
I didn't want him to think
I was an easy woman.
Anyway, he turned up with
a suitcase and moved in.
Last night, on TV,
I saw he'd been arrested
in a drugs bust.
He's one of the biggest drug
traffickers in the country.
What?
So, kind of suspicious,
I open the suitcase
and I see it's full
of bags of cocaine.
I took one,
went out on the street and
haven't been back since.
What a story!
I was surprised he
screwed so well.
For men who live at
that level of risk,
it's like every screw is the last.
And there's no comparison.
Look at those goose bumps!
Yeah, I saw it before.
You've got a talent...
And the suitcase?
The suitcase?
Well,
I was going to ask if I
could bring it here.
- You hear?
- Yes.
I'll bring it here.
If they find it in my house, it's
not for what could happen to me,
although it's not ideal for a
councillor for social affairs,
but the mayor would be so
upset, and my party...
It couldn't take
another scandal.
Don't shout.
The police!
How could it be? No one
knows you're here.
I've been very striking
since I was a child.
Act like you've come for coffee.
That's what we've got re-edited.
Do you think it's
worth carrying on,
or is it crazy?
What? I pissed myself laughing.
I'm dying to see what happens.
It's wonderful, Mateo!
It's hilarious. You
have to re-release it.
No, what matters
is to finish it.
Films have to be finished,
even if you do it blindly.
[  anoXmous   @
https://thepiratebay. sx/user/[qusawa]