Sit down and start undressing.
There's no hurry.
Like that.
Keep your underpants on for now.
Don't look at me.
Don't look at me!
Remember, you're alone.
There's a mirror on your left.
See it?
Stand up and get near it.
Watch yourself in the mirror.
Kiss your own lips.
Go on.
Again.
Think it's me you're kissing
and you like it.
Rub your cock against the glass.
More.
You love it... that's right.
Now go back to the bed.
Caress yourself with your fingertips,
wherever you like.
Take your cock and caress it
over your pants.
Do it for real.
You should be getting randy.
Take your underpants off.
Take them off.
Turn round.
Support yourself on your knees.
Touch your buttocks.
Not your legs,
between your buttocks.
That's it.
You're getting randy.
Now... ask me to fuck you.
Don't look at me.
I'm not over here.
I'm next to you and you want me to
fuck you. Come on, ask me to.
- But didn't we...?
- Just ask me.
Come on, don't be afraid.
Just say it.
Fuck me.
I want you to feel me inside you.
I want you to enjoy it.
Go on, don't stop.
Tell me when you're going
to come.
Do you feel me inside you?
Yes...
- I think I'm coming.
- Me too.
You did well. You may leave
after you shower.
Freeze the image and "The End".
THE LAW OF DESIRE
Hear the applause?
It's a great film. Fantastic.
Fuck me.
I'll stay if you want me to.
It's hot. Go to the seaside
and help your sister.
- Will you visit me?
- I don't know.
I must start rehearsals
straight away.
- Take a week's rest.
- I don't need to rest.
This line is for you.
Will you direct "The Human Voice"
for the stage?
What other plans do you have?
Right now, to get drunk...
...and get high.
And you, Tina?
I have theatre, film and TV offers,
and even a soap.
But I can't talk till
the contracts are signed.
Hey, Tina!
Don't take my double chin.
Is it true you've become
a lesbian?
With men like you, even I
would be a lesbian.
- And so would you, I guess.
- We already are.
- Why can't they leave us alone?
- Forget it.
- What happened?
- Nothing.
Must go. I left the girl alone.
- Any news from her mother?
- She's still in Tokyo.
I'm very proud of you.
- Bye.
- Want a ride?
No, you stay and enjoy
the party.
I've seen all your films.
Today I saw all three showings of
"The Mussel's Paradigm".
You liked it?
The second time I did, but less than
the first time I saw "Remake".
And the fifth time you saw
"Shitface"?
Less than the third time
I saw "Halitosis".
Which is your own favourite?
I like making films,
not watching them.
- What did you talk about?
- Cinema.
- And what did he tell you?
- Things.
- Where are you going?
- Home.
- Can I come with you?
- OK. Can you drive?
Yes. Where's your car?
- I'd like to steal this.
- A Vespino? What for?
Belongs to a friend who's leaving
tomorrow. I'd like it as a fetish.
Got some coke?
See if there's any left.
Come in.
I'm a model, but I'd much rather
be in films.
Excuse me, I'm going to throw up.
The Human Voice
They should ban premieres.
- What's your next play?
- "The Human Voice".
- Is there a role for me?
- It's a female monologue.
Can't a guy do it?
No. Look, just go.
Sorry, I'm very tired.
- Don't you want me to stay?
- No, not tonight.
You didn't say goodbye
and it's my last night.
I thought you had scored
with that girl.
I would have told you.
We can't get it together, Pablo.
It's not your fault if
you don't love me.
And it's not my fault
if I love you.
That's why I'm glad you're leaving.
I'll get over it sooner.
I don't want you to get over it.
Let's not talk about it.
It's late, let's go to bed.
Promise you'll come and see me.
There's a beautiful beach and
a lighthouse to die for.
- Still haven't fixed this?
- I will one day.
I bet. I'll come back in September
and it still won't be fixed.
That'll give you an excuse
to come back.
Mind if we don't make love?
Don't worry, we won't do anything.
- And if you can't sleep?
- I'll take a pill.
You take one, too.
I'll take a couple.
- Is it OK with beer?
- After all you've taken tonight?
- Very nice.
- Like it, don't you?
Try it on.
Amazing, it's your size.
You should buy it.
- I've no money.
- Pay me tomorrow.
I'm going on holiday.
Take it. When you come back,
bring me what you have.
- Thanks. See you.
- God bless.
What would you ask from
the loved one?
Not to accompany me to parties,
wait at home for the gossip.
Let me type in peace.
Read the same books,
know about medicine...
...law, plumbing, electricity...
In short, to adore me.
Not to nag me, and...
to accept I'm useless.
Anyone would do that for you.
Don't be so sure.
- Bet they would.
- Don't be so sure.
Tell me, what do you most
love and hate in love?
Same thing.
Love absorbs you
24 hours a day.
You can't concentrate.
That's what I most love
and hate.
Really?
Dear Pablo, this is the lighthouse.
It'd make a wonderful location.
I come here at dawn.
How are you? Write to me.
Big kiss, Juan
Dear Juan, I got your letter.
It's nice, but not what I expected.
I'll send you a typed letter.
Please sign it and
send it back.
I long for you as ever. Pablo
How did the interview go?
Terrible. Know what they offered
me? A porno movie... with her.
I kept my cool. Said I was too old
to show my arse. Bastards!
- Nothing wrong with your arse.
- I use it less than you, that's why.
- You can be so crude, darling.
- Sorry, Pablo. I'm sick of it all.
- What would you like to drink?
- Coca-Cola.
Come outside.
Be patient, Ada. She can be rude,
but she doesn't mean it.
She got a letter from my mum.
Didn't let me read it, but I think
mum's staying longer in Tokyo.
Slagging me off?
The sink's full of dishes.
The cleaner comes tomorrow.
This looks like a junkie's house.
- What's a junkie?
- Nothing, nosey!
- A sportsman.
- Never heard of ice junkie?
- That's hockey.
Well, a junkie is...
a very messy person.
Then I'm a bit of a junkie, too.
Silly! Let me talk to Tina.
Her mother is staying in Tokyo
with some photographer.
What are you going to do?
Cry till I run out of tears.
I'll send you a typed letter.
Please sign it and send it back.
I long for you as ever. Pablo
Sado-masochist comic book.
What will you do with Ada?
First she must finish school.
And then...
...I'll have to keep her.
She hates her grandparents.
- Want me to do the ironing?
- No, let the cleaner do it.
- What's this, Ada?
- A comic. Can I have it?
No, you've got to study.
Her grades are appalling.
You like the harmonica? You can
have that, but promise you'll study.
- I can't concentrate.
- Why's that?
She's in love with you.
It's a loan.
- You promised not to tell.
- Shut up.
We're off, you've a lot to do.
- You've two more mouths to feed.
- Three.
If you get bored, give me a call.
Bye now. - Bye.
Thank you, darling.
I didn't leave to forget you.
If I ever did, as you said I should,
I'd end up empty inside.
Tell me what you're up to.
What books you're reading.
What films you've seen. What records
you've bought. Have you got a cold?
I want to share everything
with you.
Except if you've met someone
you fancy. I couldn't share that.
I want to see you. You decide when.
I adore you.
- Pablo is in love.
- With you?
I doubt it.
- He could be your father.
- If only!
Forget it, he's very selfish.
Selfish? He gave us a cheque
and a harmonica.
I don't mean that.
Look, Ada!
Ramiro de Maeztu School.
127, Serrano Street.
I studied here as a child.
Want to go inside the chapel?
They still haven't fixed the gap.
The times I must have
jerked off in here.
O Lady, more pure than a lily
and a rose.
O Mother, more beautiful
than the glowing sun.
Attend to my prayer,
listen to my song.
Wipe away my tears
of bitter pain.
Attend to my prayer,
listen to my song.
Wipe away my tears
of bitter pain.
I was a soloist when I was young.
It's the only thing I miss
from that time.
You remind me of an old pupil.
He used to sing in the choir, too.
Father Constantino, it's me.
You? It can't be.
Yes, it can.
You've changed so much.
Not really. I'm still the same
deep down.
- And that girl?
- She's... my daughter.
Are you married?
No, I'm condemned to solitude.
You can never say that.
I can. There have been
only two men in my life.
One was you...
...my spiritual mentor.
The other was my father.
Both abandoned me.
I don't trust any other.
Put your trust in God.
He'll never abandon you.
Maybe you're right.
I'd like to sing in
the choir again.
- Not here, please.
- Why not?
If it's God you're after,
go to any church.
He's in all of them.
But my memories are here.
Banish them, as I have done.
My memories are all I have left.
What's that?
The May Cross. It gives us solace,
remember?
Get a man, it's more hygienic.
No men, or women. Let's not talk
about it, not in front of her.
Need any help? What's wrong?
Are you angry with me?
No, she's taken a vow of obedience,
chastity and silence.
Well, not obedience.
And the silence is driving me mad.
"Chas...
"... ti...
"... ty...
"No!"
That's a relief!
She's taking First Communion.
Are you? I'll get you a dress
worthy of a saint.
I'm starting to rehearse
"The Human Voice".
- And who's the lucky girl?
- You, I hope.
It worked!
We asked the Virgin for work.
I'll take another vow.
Don't be greedy. Sit down, love.
You serious? You're not
taking pity on me?
Can I be in it?
I asked for work too.
We'll see. But it'll be
hard for you.
Why?
The show will bring you
painful memories.
Better than showing my arse
in a nightclub.
Much better.
- Is it because I'm your sister?
- No way!
Or because I'm broke?
Eat up, love. I'll never
eat again.
A face-lift!
I can't do it, Pablo.
I won't spoil the show for you.
My skin is awful for that role.
What's so funny, sweetie?
When her lover left her,
Laura ran after him.
She fell and broke her ankle.
Then cut her leg off saying she had
gangrene, to make him feel guilty.
But her thirst for revenge
remained unquenched.
Dear Pablo, I didn't leave
to forget you.
If I ever did, as you said I should.
I'd end up empty inside.
Tell me what you're up to.
What books you're reading.
Have you got a cold?
Given up snow?
I want to share everything
with you.
Got an extra ticket for the show?
- Got any spare tickets?
- No, sorry.
Excuse me, sir. Got any
spare tickets?
I don't suppose you've got
a ticket?
I'm off, it's too hot in here.
We're staying, it's been
a tough night.
OK, but don't get drunk.
See you tomorrow.
You're Pablo Quintero, aren't you?
- I really wanted to talk to you.
- Well, here I am.
I'm going home.
Want to come with me?
I don't sleep with men.
Bye, then. Nice to meet you.
You win.
- I'm going with you.
- This isn't a contest.
It is, and I've just lost.
But I don't care, come on.
I couldn't get a ticket.
I'll leave one at the box office
tomorrow.
- Leave that. Want a beer?
- OK.
Don't touch anything.
Laura P.
Who is Laura P.?
The lead in my next film.
Don't touch, they're just notes.
Is it true your sister
is a transsexual?
What's it to you?
I'll help you tidy up.
- You do this often?
- All the time.
It's a miracle the place
hasn't caught fire yet.
Cool it, OK?
You don't kiss as if you're
unblocking the sink.
- Then you teach me how.
- With pleasure.
How was that?
Listen, you don't have any
venereal diseases?
Why do you ask me that now?
You're so promiscuous...
No. Don't worry.
I've never had anything,
not even crabs.
I hate that kind of disease.
Look, why don't we just
forget it?
- You want to?
- If you keep asking questions, yes.
I won't ask anything else,
I promise.
Listen... one last question.
Last one.
Only one, OK?
You want to fuck me, don't you?
Ever since I saw you
at the disco.
I've never done it before.
Dear Pablo,
Tell me what you're up to.
What books you're reading.
What films you've seen.
Given up snow?
I want to share everything
with you.
Except if you've met someone
you fancy. I coudn't share that.
I adore you. Juan
Shit!
You're a pig.
If I were 16, I'd report you
for being a child molester.
- Who is it?
- Antonio.
What a surprise!
Come in, don't be shy.
I wanted to see you
before I go.
You shouldn't provoke
a child molester.
Let's go to bed.
- Good morning! About time.
- Don't shout.
- I fixed the switch in the hall.
- So I see. Thanks.
You're hopeless. Someone
should take care of you.
I've heard that one before.
When this dries, one coat of paint
and it'll be as good as new.
You've done enough for today.
Don't worry about it.
Antonio, darling. You may think so,
but I'm not in love with you.
I'm touched by your tenderness.
But don't fall in love with me.
I'm too selfish, I coudn't share
my life. Thank you and good luck.
- Pablo, wake up.
- What time is your train?
- In two hours.
- Then let me sleep a bit more.
- A massage will wake you.
- Stop it, I'm getting up.
You need a shower.
Get into the bathroom.
I don't want you going out
with other guys.
And stop taking coke.
When I tell you, you'll come and
see me. We'll go sailing together.
You need a healthier life.
Aren't you a bit reactionary?
And quite right, too.
Who is the boy in the letter?
That Juan?
You've read it?
How dare you?
I can't help it. I want to know
everything about you.
Don't do it again.
He seems very much in love
with you.
He isn't. That letter is a joke.
Love is never a joke. I hope
you're not in love with him.
Let's drop it, OK?
Don't lie to me, Pablo.
Don't cheat on me.
Hold on! I never promised anything.
I told you not to trust me.
Stop pretending.
I'm not a press.
You love me, I can tell.
But you play at being frivolous.
I am frivolous.
- You're screaming for affection.
- Maybe. But not at any price.
You're better than you think.
But you don't lead a healthy life.
I'll take care of that.
Since I can't get you to listen,
I've written you a letter.
Ah, yes, the letter.
I tore it up.
I did read it.
But you shoudn't have written it.
But that's in the past.
Breakfast?
I'll write when I get there.
- Promise, you'll write back.
- All right.
I don't want anyone to know
about us.
Listen, if you've been spying
on me...
...which seems likely, you'll know
I never talk about my private life.
I'm thinking of my family. They don't
read my letters, but best be cautious.
Write under a girl's name.
So my mother doesn't know
you're a guy. Get it?
Come off it, man.
- I'm sure she won't read them.
- She won't read what?
- The letters.
- What letters?
Yours.
Just in case. My mother is German
and likes being a spy.
Take care, and have a good trip.
Hurry, you'll miss your train.
Hello?
Mum, you're back!
Ada, my darling.
I've missed you so much.
Mind my make-up.
I'm on at the end.
Aren't you glad to see me?
Yes, you look lovely.
- What's this?
- My First Communion dress.
I told you not to, Ada.
You and I are atheists.
Have you forgotten?
You may be an atheist, but Tina
and I are great believers.
We have a May Cross at home.
But it's June!
We've found a Virgin
who works miracles.
You two are bonkers.
Have you seen Tina? - Yes.
- She's a great actress, and so am I.
- Ada, come here, we need to talk.
- We are talking.
Don't be stubborn. Sit down.
Look at these filthy hands.
I've come for you.
I live in Milan now.
It's a beautiful industrial city.
You'll love it.
I don't speak Italian, and
I don't care about industry.
Anyway, you'll go off. I'm staying
with Tina, she won't leave me.
- How do you know?
- She doesn't like men like you do.
Ada, this time I've found
what I was looking for.
I don't want to go with you.
This girl drives me crazy.
I've broken two nails.
Yes, my love. I know I shoudn't
get my hopes up.
But until now, whenever
we've had problems...
...we've always talked things
through.
And made up with a simple glance.
But it's not the same on the phone.
On the phone it's final.
Wait!
Me? Why would I think
you want to hang up?
That would be too cruel.
And you... have never been cruel.
How silly of me.
I was about to say, until now.
Yes, it'd be better
if you hang up.
Goodbye, my love.
Yes, I'll be brave. I will!
Now hurry and hang up, please.
Hang up, please.
I love you more than my own life.
More than my own life.
Aren't you hungry?
It's disgusting.
God, it's hot! How can you
stand that jacket?
Go on, don't by shy.
Hose me down!
It's so hot!
I can't take the heat tonight.
Come on, no more hydrotherapy.
That was amazing! I've always
dreamt of doing that.
I didn't think it'd be so powerful,
but it was great.
Let's get drunk.
You two were great tonight.
You were bloody awful,
especially you.
You really overacted.
- Sorry, I'm not a machine.
- Neither am I.
I'm a drug addict too, you know.
Don't ever say I overacted
in front of other people.
It's the truth.
- But no one needs to know.
- You're right, I'm sorry.
So you don't like my acting?
Don't be a drag. I like you and the
public likes you, can't you tell?
- Yes, but...
- But what? You should be happy.
I am, but the show gets me down
sometimes.
I warned you.
I love all the drama.
All the crying and talking
on the phone.
What I hate is having to
dress like a slob.
I shouldn't have said that.
You'll never give me work again.
You're wrong. You're the lead
in my next film.
More coke!
With your paranoia, I'd better
warn you before you read it.
- So you don't get cross.
- Why? What's the film about?
See? You're pissed off already.
- Tell me, or I really will be.
- Tomorrow.
Look, it's not that the role
is inspired by you.
But it has... a certain affinity.
I need another line.
How much of an affinity?
Regarding your problems with men.
I don't have any problems with men.
They mean nothing to me any more.
And that's not a problem?
- You think I'm a freak, too?
- I didn't say that.
Talk about your own problems
and leave me alone.
Will you listen?
Leave my life out of it. I may be
ridiculous, but I have my self-respect.
- Who says you're ridiculous?
- I know I am.
- Will you listen to me?
- OK, I will.
My problems with men mean more
than a storyline.
No one's going to play with them.
Get out of here!
- No one's playing with them.
- They're mine, you hear?
You keep them, if it
makes you happy.
It doesn't, you bastard.
But I've paid for my failures.
And now they're all I've got.
Your milk.
Will I have tits like yours
one day?
Of course you will. At your age,
I was as flat as a board.
Does Pablo like tits?
I don't know. Some men
don't appreciate them.
No more questions.
Drink your milk.
She took everything, didn't she?
Good. We'll have more room now.
I'll never leave you, Tina. I told
her that and she slapped me.
Bitch! But never forget
she's your mother.
- I love you.
- How much?
- Can I sleep with you tonight?
- Of course, sweetheart.
Can I ask the Virgin
something first?
At this hour? The poor Virgin
must be sick of it. Go on, then.
- Morocco.
- Finished.
What did you ask?
That Pablo never leaves us
like mum did.
Let's go to bed, sweetheart.
Thank you, Virgin.
God, it's hot!
- Here.
- What is it?
Photos of when we were kids.
I thought I had them all.
When you asked for them,
mum and I kept these.
Do what you like with them.
I want you to trust me, Tina.
I promised not to ask questions, and
I've kept my bargain over the years.
But your past is part of mine.
Don't take it out on me, Pablo.
I'm very vulnerable,
and very imperfect.
Hi, Pablo. It's Juan.
Hello, Juan. How are you?
Terrible. Why don't you
answer my letters?
Because...
...I'm trying to forget you. And
when you do that, you can't write.
Pablo, I'll give you what you want,
but you must teach me how.
You can't teach that.
Give me another chance. Come to
see me so I can try.
OK. I'll come and check
that lighthouse.
You'll love it. Write to me,
I miss you so much.
OK, I'll write to you now.
Pablo... I love you.
Pablo, are you there?
- Pick up the phone, I'm sick of this.
- Yes, I'm here.
I've been calling for days.
I've been out. Did you get
my letters?
Yes, and I don't like them.
I'm sick of Laura P.
It was your idea to use
a girl's name.
Well, I was wrong. You must
come and see me, Pablo.
- Are you avoiding me?
- Antonio, I've told you...
Must go. If you don't come,
I'll come to see you.
Antonio, I don't love you.
I'm still in love with Juan.
I won't come to see you.
I'm going to see Juan.
Forget me. Dont fool yourself.
I never lied to you, Laura P.
- Nearly done?
- Not quite.
- You go, I'll clear up here.
- Thanks!
But tomorrow it's your turn.
It's closed.
- But if you want something...
- A bottle of whisky.
- What brand?
- This one.
- You must be Juan, right?
- Yes, and who are you?
I'm Pablo's friend.
- Pablo is coming tomorrow.
- Not any more.
He sent me to tell you.
- Why doesn't he tell me himself?
- He doesn't want to see you.
- That's his shirt, isn't it?
- Yes, he gave it to me.
You still love him?
In my own way. But Pablo needs
more, and I was willing to give it.
Don't bother. He's found what
he wanted in me.
I wanted to show him
the lighthouse.
I'll tell him all about it.
Stop playing with the torch.
Here, drink.
I often come here to watch
the dawn.
What are you doing?
- You'd kiss him, wouldn't you?
- What's it to you?
Leave me alone!
- What the hell do you want?
- To possess you.
You're crazy.
I love Pablo. I want everything
that is his.
I belong to no one. No one.
Sorry, I'm a bit drunk.
I didn't mean to.
I don't understand you.
I don't know what's going on.
Let go of me!
Are you Pablo Quintero?
What's happened?
He fell, or was pushed
over the cliff.
Near the Trafalgar lighthouse?
- You know the place?
- Juan sent me a photo.
- Where were you last night?
- In the theatre with my sister.
I left Madrid around 8
this morning.
I suppose we can check it out.
How well did you know Juan?
We were good friends.
- How good?
- We weren't lovers.
- Is that clear?
- No, it isn't.
- Juan loved you.
- How do you know?
We grew up together.
He told me everything.
Stay the night. You're in
no shape to travel.
No, no, thanks. That's kind of you.
I'm going to Jerez
to see a friend.
Let's go to the cliffs.
Dear Juan,
The more generous you are
with me...
...the more I realise I've made you
do things against your will.
I won't touch you again,
even if you ask me to.
I want you to desire me,
even if you don't love me.
But you can't force things.
I want you to show me
the lighthouse at dawn...
...and hear the waves
against the cliffs.
I love you more than ever.
I can't help it, Pablo
It's like the shirt
he was wearing.
Did you see if a pocket
was missing?
Let's go after him.
The pocket.
What a mess!
- Antonio?
- I'm in the bathroom.
I'm practising for the
grape harvest.
- Come with me?
- You go alone.
Is something burning?
I can smell smoke.
- It's a cigarette.
- But you don't smoke.
It's not a joint, is it?
Open the door.
What are you doing?
Where were you last night?
Nowhere. Stop shouting,
everyone can hear you.
Let them, I'm in my own house.
What do you want?
- Sorry, I rang the bell.
- The maid's out.
- Who are you?
- I'm Pablo.
A friend of Laura's.
Can't that woman leave us alone?
Don't worry. She won't
bother you again.
Remember me?
Laura introduced us.
Of course I remember.
You're the film director.
You'll be late, mum.
I'll open the side door for you.
- Where were you last night?
- I didn't go out.
- I heard the bike.
- Mum, you've got to help me.
How can I? You don't tell me
anything. It's that slag's fault.
- She was here last night.
- I knew something was wrong.
And him? He's got a shirt
like yours.
I never had a shirt like that, OK?
I'm worried about you, son.
Between your father and his politics
and you... it'll be the death of me.
Let's go to the roof,
we'll be alone.
What's wrong? Aren't you
happy to see me?
Juan has been found dead near
the Trafalgar lighthouse.
Can't say I'm sorry.
He really hurt me.
I can still remember his letter
word for word.
What did you do last night?
Why did you ask your mother
to lie?
You know very well where I was
and what I did.
- I did it for us.
- Don't touch me, murderer!
It was your fault.
You lied when you said
the letter was a joke.
And when you said Juan and you
weren't lovers.
I told you not to lie,
but you wouldn't listen.
Anyway, it doesn't matter now.
This death will unite us for ever.
What's happened?
Did he do that?
Let's go inside, I'm naked.
How did it happen?
He came asking after a girl.
I said she wasn't here.
He got angry and bit me.
Is he a friend?
No way. This girl Laura
introduced us. I was seeing her.
She wrote to say she was coming,
but she changed her mind.
He thought she was here.
What's going on?
- Nothing.
- Is Laura OK?
- What have they done to you, son?
- Nothing.
- What do you mean?
- It's just a bite.
Who was it? That film director?
Can I talk to you or your husband?
My husband is at one of those
parliament sessions.
Go and disinfect that wound.
Cannibal!
- I hope you're on the case.
- Don't worry, we'll get him.
He's a very bad driver.
Please sit down and tell me
what happened.
A young man's been murdered
near the lighthouse.
He was a friend of Pablo Quintero,
who came to see your son.
My son's not involved with that
pervert. What's the victim's name?
Juan. He worked at a beach bar
near the lighthouse.
Your son says Pablo Quintero
came here...
...looking for a mutual friend, a girl
called Laura. Do you know her?
I've heard the name. I fear my son
might be in love with her.
Here's proof.
I don't want anyone to hear of this,
especially not my husband.
He's got enought to worry about.
Being a politician's wife
is like being a widow.
- You do understand, don't you?
- Of course, I do.
Have you discovered something?
- Where was your son last night?
- He stayed at home.
- Don't tell me he's a suspect.
- No, we suspect the girl.
Good heavens!
- Let us know if she gets in touch.
- Certainly. You too.
- Will he pull through?
- Yes.
He's badly bruised and has broken
a leg. But the worst is his head.
- The head?
- Yes, but he'll recover.
- Can I see him?
- Not yet.
I advise you to go to your brother's
place and check it out.
Why?
The police will search his place.
- He was here during the murder.
- No matter, they'll hassle him.
Thanks. I'll be back tomorrow.
Remove anything suspicious -
photos, postcards, drugs, notes...
- You know what I mean.
- Yeah, I do.
Same typeface. The two letters and
the script were typed on this.
Here he refers to Laura P.
as "Bitter Heel".
Look what I've found.
A quarter of coke.
Not enough for a conviction.
But enough for two lines.
How about it?
That's your loss.
This bitch is a knockout.
- Wouldn't you like to lay her?
- Me? No.
And you?
Right here on this table.
At my age, if it weren't for
these little vices...
...you wouldn't survive the job.
I hope you find out sooner than I did.
At your age I'll be Chief Inspector,
not a detective like you.
I don't know why you became a cop.
With your look, you should be
a model. You'd make more.
- Look who's here!
- What are you doing here?
Searching.
Not me, he was. I was reading.
Put that script down.
This isn't a public library.
Seems interesting.
He can read!
Do you know Laura P.?
- Who is she?
- "Expressive eyes...
"... honey-coloured. Average height,
but attractive.
"With a lovely smile.
"Laura is around 40.
"And dreams of having a face-lift.
"She has a wooden leg and
lives in a lighthouse.
"She retired there to
seek revenge.
"But doesn't realise that she's
the victim of that revenge. "
Are you going to read it all?
It's your brother's description
of Laura P.
- She doesn't exist.
- The lighthouse does.
Then get your information
from it.
We've got information.
These two letters were typed
on this machine.
One signed by your brother,
the other by her.
This is absurd. Laura is a fictitious
character invented by my brother.
Who wrote that letter, then?
What colour are your eyes?
"Expressive eyes, honey-coloured. "
- You're of average height.
- "But attractive. "
And I bet you have
a lovely smile.
- Why don't you smile for us?
- Laura P.
Get your fucking mother
to smile for you.
- People like you should be dead.
- Hands off!
People like you shouldn't hit
a defenceless woman.
You're not a woman.
Bet you'll charge me with
hitting a cop.
Your mother wasn't worth
fighting for.
Queers! You'll pay for this.
They must be on holiday.
Let's go.
- At last!
- Where am I?
You've had an accident.
An accident?
- I don't remember anything.
- Nothing at all?
Touch anything in his home, and I'll
report you. I've called a lawyer...
He's awake, doctor.
But he's lost his memory.
- We'll come with you.
- No, you won't.
- We'll help him recover his memory.
- We've got other methods.
Careful. A cover-up is
also a crime.
And torturing a patient
is an act of charity?
We'll wait outside. You're not
a Chief Inspector yet.
- Leave us alone.
- Yes. Excuse me.
So you don't remember anything?
Who am I?
Why are those men there?
They're police. Your name's Pablo.
A friend of yours was murdered.
" Mysterious death in the lighthouse. "
Did I kill him?
No. They suspect
a friend of yours, Laura.
- Laura.
- Yes. So they want to question you.
I've called a lawyer.
Remember him?
Rest. You need to recover.
- What used I to do?
- Films.
- How were they?
- Marvellous.
Get better soon so
you can do more.
Amnesia will buy us a month,
at most.
And if he gets cataleptic?
That's different. If he can't talk,
they can't question him.
- Hello.
- Hello, Tina. - Hello.
- Guzmán Morales, Pablo's lawyer.
- Nice to meet you.
- We'll talk later.
- OK, thanks. How is he?
- He's awake.
- Yeah?
- But...
- But what?
- He's lost his memory.
- I must see him.
- She looks like a real woman.
- Of course.
- Who are you?
- Your sister, Tina Quintero.
My God, you don't remember
anything.
I'll have to fill you in.
- The doctor's told me a few things.
- Did he tell you about me?
- Mum?
- Yes.
- Will she come to see me?
- No, we're orphans.
Our father's is alive,
but he's in New York.
He hasn't written for years.
Our parents separated...
...when we were very young.
You stayed with mum here
in Madrid. This is Madrid.
I went with dad to Morocco.
He's a painter, and he had
a studio there.
There are things we've
never talked about.
It was my fault our parents
separated.
I was involved with dad.
One day...
...Mum caught us out.
And... well, you can imagine.
So you went to Morocco.
We lived there a few years
and we were happy.
Until he left me...
for another woman.
I never forgave him.
He hurt me so much, I haven't
been with another man since.
- Did I know about it?
- You really don't remember?
Your amnesia leaves me
without a past.
I'll go mad if you don't recover
your memory. Look, the two of us.
That's you, and that one is me.
What do you mean?
At first I was a boy.
But when I arrived in Morocco
with dad, I changed my sex.
We had decided before leaving.
- Did you decide, or did he?
- What does it matter?
He liked the idea.
And I was crazy about him.
- Would you have done it anyway?
- Probably.
- Don't judge me now, you never did.
- I won't. But I need to know.
He's my father too, I suppose.
I don't regret it. I'd have given
my life for him if he'd asked me.
I understand.
What happened then?
After he left me, I got
a false passport...
...and I went to Paris.
I couldn't face you or mum.
I only came back for
her funeral.
That's when you and I
were reunited.
We were both so lonely.
And we still loved each other
after so many years.
You didn't hold a grudge
against me, and that...
I could never thank you enough.
That's why I stayed with you.
You're all I've got.
Come here. Give me a hug.
I can't.
I'm glad you're my sister.
So that nothing happens to Pablo
and he's protected from the police.
The Sorrowful Mysteries.
First Mystery: Jesus praying
in the Garden.
Our Father, who art in Heaven,
hallowed be Thy name...
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses.
After three weeks
he's still the same.
Leave this case to me, father.
Want to pension me off?
I've still got two months to go.
Look who's here.
I don't want you to go
on a downer.
Leave the dirty work to me.
You're too scrupulous.
And you're too clumsy.
You'll go far.
I feel great today. Here,
split it between yourselves.
- And the cocaine?
- Naughty boy. Tomorrow.
- And the bag?
- That's for my brother. Bye now.
You make me so happy.
Watch those two.
There's nothing like charity.
What's the typewriter for?
Leave her alone.
She knows nothing.
Go for the brother.
He knows everything.
I'll make him talk today.
I'll show you who's clumsy.
Don't take me seriously, son.
To be a good cop, being
unscrupulous is not enough.
You need a sense of humour, too.
I thought I wasn't going to make it.
I've brought you all sorts of stuff.
- Here.
- What are we celebrating?
Something marvellous.
I've got a boyfriend.
I met him when I was picking up
your mail. We screwed in your bed.
I didn't dare take him home.
I hope you don't mind.
No, no, of course not.
- I wanted to be sure before I told you.
Are you happy? - Yes, very much.
- You don't look it.
- Tina...
- I've something to tell you too.
- What is it?
- I've recovered my memory.
- Really?
- Just wait till I tell Ada.
- Don't. I don't want anyone to know.
- Why not?
- I'm happy here.
The police won't leave us alone
until you talk.
- They think I'm Laura P.
- That woman doesn't exist.
- And the letters?
- Tina, keep out of this.
All right.
Up to you. I've brought
your typewriter.
- In case you feel like writing.
- No, take it away.
Pablo, what's going on?
Don't look like that. Main thing is
you're in love, and happy.
I won't be happy until you're back
at work. But if you don't talk...
I'll talk in a few days.
I'm not strong enough yet.
I have enough strength
for the two of us.
That's how I like it.
- Want me here for the questioning?
- No, I'll get the doctor to call you.
Tina, I'm so happy for you.
This time will be different.
I can feel it.
- Isn't that a bit heavy for you?
- Don't worry, I'm very strong.
So I see. Don't lose it, OK?
We might want to confiscate it.
- Aren't you hot in that jacket?
- Yes, but I feel good in it.
How's your brother?
The same, or worse.
Don't question him yet.
A man has been murdered and it's
our job to find the murderer.
How many murderers
have you caught?
Don't be unfair. The boy's
just starting.
Why don't you leave us alone?
- The lawyer isn't here.
- We just want to talk about Laura.
No one with that name
has come to see me.
Think she's out there?
On the roof maybe?
Could be a pseudonym.
You seem to know her
better than I do.
Does Antonio Benítez ring a bell?
- They both know you.
- I seem to be famous.
And that means you don't
have to talk?
If a murder's been committed,
you should find the murderer.
Not a poor amnesiac.
The letters.
Both written on your typewriter.
How do you explain that?
You tell me.
These letters are not
the only proof.
- You're late.
- I went to the boutique.
It's closed.
It opened today. A shirt like Pablo's
was sold to Antonio Benítez.
- He and his mother deny it.
- And you believe them.
We've got the boy
under surveillance.
He's going out with his sister.
What?
He's been comforting your sister.
Didn't she tell you?
I should have guessed.
- Why didn't I? - What is it, Pablo?
- I need a phone. She's off today.
Let's go to my office.
Go on without me.
The Glorious Mysteries.
First Mystery: The Resurrection.
- Yes?
- Tina.
Say yes or no and don't mention
my name. Are you alone? - No.
- What's wrong?
- Is Antonio Benítez with you?
- How do you know his name?
- Listen to me.
He murdered Juan.
He's not a bad guy,
but he's crazy.
It can't be.
There's a cop outside. Don't look.
Don't let Antonio see him. Tina...
Just keep calm.
We'll be there in
a few minutes.
It was too good to be true.
- Forget that now.
- And think about what?
You're in danger,
don't you understand?
Act normal. Bet he's looking at you.
Find an excuse to leave the house.
Say you've got to testify.
And bring the girl with you.
- All right?
- All right.
- The hospital? What did they say?
- Pablo is dead.
He jumped out of the window while
he was being questioned.
You must bring him back to life.
He's mine! Pablo is mine.
- He wanted to save me.
- What do you mean?
Nothing.
We must go to the hospital.
You wait here.
Wait, wait.
- I'm going with you.
- No need.
How can you be so calm knowing
your brother is dead?
And why are you so concerned?
You don't even know him.
Why is that policeman
out there?
Let us go.
Who phoned you? How could your
brother jump with a leg in plaster?
Maybe the police pushed him.
Let us go.
Run, Ada, run.
You go, Ada! Don't touch me,
you scum!
- Go up. He wants to kill Tina.
- Who?
- A man.
- Calm down.
Up there. Please help her.
- Where's Tina?
- She fought with Antonio.
- Did you see policeman? - I don't know.
- He was down here. - Yes.
- Where's he?
- He went up.
- And he hasn't come down? - No.
- Antonio might be armed.
- Don't move.
- Let go of me.
- Give yourself up.
- He's got a gun.
- Turn the spotlight off!
- Antonio, come out with Tina.
- Turn it off.
Anyone moves, and I'll shoot her.
- Antonio, is our colleague there?
- Yes, he's up here.
Stay calm. Let them go and
nothing will happen to you.
Think I'm stupid?
I want to negotiate first.
There's nothing to negotiate.
Put that gun down!
What do you want?
I want Pablo to come up.
I'll only talk to him.
- Antonio, will you let Tina go if I do?
- And the policeman?
I will if you come up.
I'll throw you the keys.
Where are they?
- What do you want?
- I wanted to see you.
Here I am. Untie her.
I can't. Do you mind?
- Is he dead?
- No, I just hit him.
- Try to bring him round.
- I will.
- You didn't need to come up.
- Shut up.
- Take him away, Tina.
- No.
Go! I created this situation
and I have to deal with it.
You've been fooling me, you two.
I hate you.
Go now. Go!
I'll be back in a second.
Bloody typewriter!
Pablo, get away from there.
Wait a minute.
No one shoot.
I'm coming out to talk.
- Give me the gun.
- Learn to use it first.
But you never let me use it.
What a waste of taxpayers' money!
No one come near the door.
Wait there, in the middle
of the road.
Come on, move away.
- And Pablo?
- He's fine.
Listen to me. I want an hour...
...to negotiate with Pablo.
Any interruptions...
...and I kill everyone.
I'm crazy enough.
OK, you've got an hour.
One hour.
I needed to see you at any price.
I doubt you'll ever love me...
...the way I love you.
I doubt you'll ever find
as pure a love...
...as the one you'll find in me.
You'll have a thousand adventures
without love.
But at the end of it all...
...you'll find only pain.
You'll be ecstatic with pleasure.
But you will never find
as pure an illusion...
...as the one I made you feel.
Loving you this way is a crime.
But I'm willing to pay the price.
I knew it when I picked you up
at the disco.
I knew it'd be a very high price.
But I have no regrets.
I don't care what happens
in a hour.
And you shouldn't think
about it either.
How am I doing?
You taught me how.
Thank you very much.
Cover up, it's cold.
I'll get your crutch
and help you dress.
Antonio.
- Antonio!
- Stay there.
Who will wipe from your life
the memory of me...
...and make you forget
my love?
Poor love, made of
blood and pain.
This love, that saw
both of us crying...
...also made us dream and live.
How did it cease to exist?