"A STATE OF EMERGENCY
HAS BEEN DECLARED...
THROUGHOUT THE COUNTRY.
THE ARTICLES AFFECTING...
FREEDOM OF SPEECH...
FREEDOM OF RESIDENCE...
FREEDOM OF ASSOCIATION...
AND HABEAS CORPUS...
HAVE BEEN SUSPENDED."
"MADRID,JANUARY 1970."
Move your ass!
Minority actions,
systematically carried out...
in order to disturb
public order in Spain...
have been occurring
in recent months...
and are obviously...
part of an international plot.
The defense of peace
and progress in Spain...
and of the rights of Spaniards...
as desired by all sectors
of society...
obliges the government
to take urgent measures...
which will put an end
to these outbreaks.
Therefore, invoking
the powers set out by law...
in particular those contained...
in the following articles-
Doña Centro, what's up?
You get back to work.
I'll see to it.
Centro!
Isabel, don't shout.
You'll wake up the neighborhood.
I feel awful!
Like my guts are scrambled.
Don't exaggerate.
Christ!
- What?
- Nothing.
You weren't exaggerating.
Far from it.
Get up, love. You're in labor.
We have to get you dressed.
Isabelita, you really fooled me.
When you came to this house,
you weren't exactly alone.
Be careful.
Come on. That's it.
Wait! I have to close the door!
Take it slowly.
Going into labor tonight!
You might have warned me.
- How was I to know, Centro?
- Well, if you didn't-
But I can't count.
Ignorance- What a terrible thing!
Stop! Stop!
Bastard!
Come on. Lean here.
Careful.
Stop!
Centro, for God's sake!
Stop, damn it!
Fucking hell!
Now, don't worry.
Come on, love. Hurry, hurry.
Are you crazy or what?
I could have killed you!
These high heels will kill me.
You can't get on.
I'm going back to the depot.
My friend's in labor.
What do you want me to do?
I told you not to get on.
Sit down there, love.
Don't do this. Please get off.
You don't have to adopt the baby!
Just get us to a hospital!
But I'm off duty.
Don't you understand?
Ma'am, it isn't my bus.
Take it easy! Hang on!
Close your legs!
Breathe!
Fuck! 30,000 drivers in Madrid
and it happens to me.
Now, don't cry!
If idiots like us didn't decide
to give birth occasionally...
the world would be empty
or full of old people.
See, the cologne cools you down.
- It's falling.
- Press your legs together.
I mean the angel.
It looks like it's going to jump.
As if the poor thing
wanted to kill itself.
I've wet myself.
No, it isn't that, love.
You've broken your waters.
Stop, please!
My friend's broken her waters!
I'll park where
we won't be in the way!
Put your legs up here.
That's it. Now the other one.
Take it easy. Come on.
Don't worry. I'm with you.
Let's go for it.
Come on. That's it.
Push, push, push!
Keep going!
That's good!
Very good! Keep going!
Good!
Push, push, push!
Driver! Come and help me!
Push!
Keep going!
That's it! There it is!
It's a boy!
And he's real rowdy, eh?
Just what we need!
First of all,
we have to tie the cord.
Have you got anything
to tie the umbilical cord?
I know. Your shoelaces.
Give them to me.
You did really well.
Does he have everything?
Everything?
The kid's got it all.
Your other shoelace.
And now we have to cut the cord.
Have you got scissors?
Anything to cut with?
God, you've got nothing!
I know.
I'll cut it with my teeth.
This doesn't hurt.
Give me a cloth for the baby.
- Poor little thing.
- Here, take this.
My baby!
There he is now!
There's your baby!
My baby! Aren't you beautiful!
Aren't you beautiful.
- Now where do we go?
- To the hospital.
She's in no shape
to come home with me.
Hold him tight.
You're very weak.
Don't drop him.
You mustn't fall asleep.
Careful, we're moving.
You can't go to sleep.
Look at how beautiful he is.
The pains have started again.
That's the placenta.
Give me the baby.
You have to push again.
- Again?
- Again.
You have to get it all out.
Come on, love. Push.
Hurry up! This woman's bleeding!
We're on our way!
Rest for a while.
You couldn't wait, could you?
You were in a big hurry to get
to Madrid, and here you are.
What are you going to call him?
Victor.
Look, Victor.
Madrid.
LIVE FLESH
In the heart of Madrid...
defying the harsh weather...
a young woman
has given birth...
inside a city bus.
The news of this
unexpected birth...
has been greeted with delight.
The mayor presented the baby
with his first layette...
and named him
an honorary citizen.
The director of
the City Transport Company...
was not to be outdone...
and, accompanied by
the chief councillor...
and their respective wives...
presented the mother and son...
with lifetime passes...
which entitle them
to free use...
of the bus service
anytime they wish.
With such enviable prospects...
we can assure
the impatient young man...
a "life on wheels. "
"20 YEARS LATER"
Down in the Coto Doñana
they've killed
They've killed my dog
A deer among the green rockrose
he was following
Throughout all of Andalusia
You'll never find
another dog like my dog
Dogs! That's how they treat us
and that's what we are.
Dogs.
Look at the lambs
we have to protect.
He was so happy when he returned
He took such care
Bringing my flock back to me
He was the key to my farm
and the guardian of my flocks
There wasn't a wolf
that would come near
The lambs on the river bank
He was the bravest of the brave
Look at them.
Stealing, scheming...
betraying and corrupting
each other.
There'll never be
another dog like my dog
We're the guardians
of a sick flock.
Here, have a drink
to celebrate it.
No, thanks. You drink enough
for both of us.
Hi, it's me.
- What are you doing?
- Watering plants.
Are you angry?
Not angry, bruised.
Forgive me.
I'm sorry I left like I did.
Do you forgive me?
Sancho, I don't like
discussing this on the phone.
Well, we'll talk later, all right?
I'll be home as soon as I can.
So long, my darling.
My wife's cheating on me.
What?
Clara's sleeping with someone.
Come on, Sancho.
Don't talk rubbish.
- I don't know what to do.
- Try drinking less.
Non-drinkers think not drinking
solves everything.
I really don't think
alcohol helps you at all.
If I don't drink, I'll kill her.
Quit talking shit!
It's the only way
a woman won't cheat.
Of course, I could kill him.
But I don't know who he is.
Could it be one of them?
To think that any of those creeps
could go screw my wife...
while I'm working.
Just the thought makes me sick.
Beautiful!
No, my father isn't here.
You can come over.
Learn to wait?
I don't give a fuck
what Lou Reed says!
If you aren't here
in 15 minutes...
I'll call the Pirate.
Yeah, she sells shit,
but at least it's something.
Bring me some candy bars too.
It'll save me going down.
"HOSPITALS: STATE OF EMERGENCY"
- Elena?
- Yes? Who is it?
- It's Victor.
- Victor who?
The guy from last Saturday.
What guy?
The one you screwed
in the toilets, remember?
I was very high.
We arranged to meet tonight.
I'm about to go out.
Where?
With a friend.
Call another day.
A friend?
But you arranged to meet me!
I told you, I forgot!
But I've brought you a pizza.
You said you'd liked them.
- This guy's dumb!
- It's still warm.
Then you eat it!
I've changed my mind.
Don't call me again.
"REHEARSAL OF A CRIME"
Hey.
Next stop's Eduarto Dato.
We've done a full circuit
of Madrid.
I know.
Aren't you getting out?
- No, I'm going on.
- Where to?
I don't know. Nowhere.
Nowhere? This isn't a hotel.
You must be going somewhere.
I'm not. So what?
Going to stay here all night?
- I'll get off.
- When?
Later.
It better be soon. And watch it.
Fucker!
She had to go out, huh? Liar!
How long ago did he leave?
Tell me the truth,
or I'll go somewhere else.
There he is!
About fucking time!
Come up!
Wait in the sitting room.
But don't touch anything.
What are you doing here?
- You let me in.
- Me?
I thought you were
somebody else.
Well, it's me.
We made a date a week ago.
Who do you think you are, anyway?
- You were expecting a dealer?
- What is it to you, asshole?
- Get out!
- Watch it.
I wasn't rude to you.
I'll go when I get
an explanation.
Fuck, don't take it that way.
I just wanted to talk
for a while.
I met you a week ago.
We had a really great fuck.
It was my first time.
You know what that is?
And it's the first time
I've stolen from a pizzeria.
I did it to be with you.
Get out.
Can't you see
I'm pointing a gun at you?
Get out of here!
Just because you came between
my legs the other night...
you think you can sneak in here
demanding explanations?
What is this, you shit?
Don't insult me!
A great fuck? Jerk-off,
you didn't even stick it in!
You've got a lot to learn!
Shut up!
At that moment, I was sure that
it was I who killed the woman.
And I assure you
that this morbid thought...
gave me a certain pleasure.
A woman has reported...
hearing what may be
a shot in her building.
umber 18, Eduardo Dato St.
The caller lives
on the second floor.
That's near here.
- Night K to H 50.
- Go ahead, Night K.
We heard your message.
We're on Eduardo Dato Bridge.
We'll check it out.
Very well.
The caller didn't seem too sure.
When you've finished,
call in your report.
We'll do that. Over.
You still here?
I wasn't going to leave you
here unconscious.
Who do you take me for?
It really hurts.
You cut my head.
Get out, or I'll call the cops.
Oh, God, I need a fix!
Someone called downstairs.
I said you weren't in.
He was pissed off.
He had some candy bars for you.
Are you crazy?
You want me to hit you again?
There's number 18.
- Who is it?
- Police. We got a call.
Yes, that was me.
My friend here says I'm crazy,
but I swear I heard a shot.
- It was the TV.
- It wasn't the TV!
Can you let us in, ma'am?
The lady of the house
is away at present.
- We're the domestic staff.
-Just open the fucking door!
There's an armed lunatic
about to rape your neighbor!
- A rapist?
- That's all you think of.
Let's go.
Give me the radio.
Lay off!
I'll go first. You cover me.
But, Sancho, we need backup.
This is a rat hole!
You want to wait till that girl
is raped and killed?
Of course I don't,
but this isn't the way.
Scared shitless isn't either.
I'm scared because I haven't drunk
two bottles of whiskey...
and no one's screwing my wife!
What was that?
Never mention Clara again!
Cool it, Sancho! Shit!
There's the door.
Now what do we do?
How do we get in?
Give me the radio.
We'll call a squad car.
- We have to get in.
- How do we do that?
We knock.
Don't take the gun.
It's my father's.
There's your fucking gun.
Police! Open up!
Open up!
Don't move, or I'll shoot!
Take it easy! Let the girl go!
Why are you here?
I haven't done anything!
Tell them it's a mistake.
- It's your mistake, asshole.
- Sancho!
I haven't done anything!
And that cut on her face?
What cut?
I'm sorry. Did I hurt you?
It must have happened now!
Let her go,
or I'll rip your balls off!
Sancho, don't provoke him!
Don't you provoke me!
What's your name?
Victor. Victor Plaza.
I know there's
an explanation for all this.
Put down the gun.
Let me have the girl,
then you can explain it all.
Deal?
All right, but tell him
to stop aiming at my balls.
Let her go, or I'll bounce them
off the wall!
Stop! Give me your gun!
What are you doing?
You've flipped.
You're aiming at a superior!
I am aiming at a lunatic
and a drunk.
Give me your gun.
Victor, here's the deal.
My partner will give me his gun.
Then you put down yours.
Let me have- What's your name?
Elena, pleased to meet you.
All right?
- Yeah. Well-
- All right.
Sancho, give me
your fucking gun!
Let me go!
Victor, take it easy, all right?
We made a deal.
Now it's your turn.
Yeah, but what'll happen to me?
Nothing at all.
Put down the gun.
Put down the gun, please.
Slowly.
That's the way. Miss-
Put down the gun.
Drop the gun!
Sancho, drop the gun!
Sancho, please! Fuck!
What are you doing?
Get out of here!
Go! Get out!
At the Barcelona '92
Paralympics...
Spain has won a medal
in wheelchair basketball.
The Spanish team beat
Argentina 56 to 52.
The ball is passed
to number 5, David de Paz...
undoubtedly the best
in the game.
De Paz holds out against
the Argentine defense and shoots.
In the stands,
a special spectator...
celebrates the decisive shot.
It's Elena Benedetti,
his wife.
David de Paz, an ex-policeman
paralyzed by a bullet...
in the line of duty...
has had an excellent tournament,
averaging-
What I want
is for you to suffer...
the way I suffer.
And I'll learn to pray
To make it happen
What I want
Is for you to feel
As useless
As an empty whiskey glass
in one's hands
And I want the heart
in your breast
To feel as if it belonged
to someone else
And it hurt
I wish you death
Wherever you are
And I'll learn to pray
To make it happen
Dear son, I've got cancer.
I won't last until
you get out of jail.
I'm leaving you the house,
if it isn't demolished first...
and my savings, if this disease
doesn't eat them up.
I know I wasn't a good mother.
Whatever I had
I shared with you...
but all I got from the street
was misery.
I'm sending the photo
and the news clipping-
Mother, you'll be glad to know
I'm not on drugs.
or have I contracted AIDS.
I study a lot.
I spend the day going
to classes on education...
metal work, handicrafts,
and even theology.
That way I reduce my sentence,
and learn as well.
A Bulgarian inmate
is teaching me Bulgarian.
I'm reading the Bible too.
Right now, I'm into Genesis.
You must think I'm cracked,
but if I don't want to go mad...
I must keep my mind busy-
not think.
"4 YEARS LATER"
Bastard!
Hello, Mother.
I got out two days ago.
I've been cleaning
the house since then.
It was a mess!
I went to the bank today.
For my inheritance.
150,000 pesetas.
On my way here,
I was trying to work out...
how many tricks
you had to turn...
to save 150,000 pesetas.
At the very least...
a thousand tricks.
I've got the same amount
without ever having fucked.
It isn't fair.
However you look at it,
it isn't fair!
- I'm sorry, Elena.
- Thank you.
Ma'am, I'm a friend of David's.
Elena, I'm very sorry.
I'm very close to you.
I'm very sorry.
Ma'am...
I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
Who's that?
I'm Ana.
I work with Elena
at El Fontanar.
Ma'am, my deepest sympathy.
- You need more?
- No, that's enough.
- Chief?
- What is it?
May I take some flowers
for my mother's grave?
Take all you want.
Mr. Benedetti won't mind much.
- Thanks a lot.
- You're welcome.
We're just about finished.
- You need any more?
-Just a bit.
"El Fontanar
Children's Shelter."
"Be brave, Elena.
We love you and need you.
From all of us."
Is this the funeral
for Mr. Benedetti?
This is the grave,
but his family left ages ago.
I've been wandering
around here like a zombie.
It was really dull and quick.
They all went off
in a terrible hurry.
I was disappointed.
Are you a friend
of the family?
Of Elena's, really. All I know...
is that her father was
an Italian diplomat with a gun.
- And you?
- Actually, I know David best.
You think they're happy?
The dead?
Perhaps.
I wonder that too.
No, I meant David and Elena.
- I don't know! Ask them!
- This way.
Do you know her?
- Or rather, did you know her?
- Not very well.
She was my mother.
Thank you.
I left my car at one
of the cemetery gates.
If you help me find it,
I'll give you a lift.
It's a deal.
Honestly, I've got absolutely
no sense of direction.
I'd get lost
in my own back yard.
Can you remember
the car model and color?
Come on! I'm not that loopy!
My God, this looks
like Sarajevo!
It's going to be expropriated.
Really? When?
I don't know. They're going
to build a big avenue.
"The Prince of Asturias."
Can I offer you a drink?
To be honest, a drink
would help warm me up.
I just moved.
The furniture's coming.
- Maybe we should leave it-
- But I can buy you a drink.
- Look, 150,000 pesetas.
- No, another day.
Listen, I didn't steal it.
This is an inheritance.
An inheritance, get it?
What's the matter?
My name's Clara.
And don't get angry.
We'll meet another day.
All right. I'm sorry.
My name's Victor.
Bye, Victor. See you again.
I'm very close to you.
What did you say?
Cool, dude.
Even cooler.
Up you go.
I saw Victor Plaza
at the funeral.
Victor?
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
I didn't see him.
You had your back to him.
You were going
to the car with Sancho.
Fucking son of a bitch!
- Did he say anything?
- He sympathized with me.
He's a psychopath.
How did he know
about the funeral?
I don't know.
Maybe he followed you.
We have to tell the police.
No, David. Don't do anything.
I'm not going to let that madman
follow you around.
We can't report him
for expressing his sympathy.
People think charity
is giving away...
the worst things you have.
And it isn't that.
Sure, we get lots
of worn out t-shirts...
but what about anoraks?
We'll have to hit Elena
for money again.
You know this is illegal entry?
I don't give a fuck.
Why were you in the cemetery
the other day, spying on my wife?
I wasn't spying on anyone.
My mother died
while I was inside.
I just happened to be near
your fucking funeral.
You always happen to be
where you shouldn't.
That's true.
I'm not as lucky as you.
You always win,
even in the worst moments.
If you go near my wife again...
I'll crack your skull.
How?
What a goal!
What a fucking goal!
Look, look, look!
Did you see that dribble?
Caminero's a knockout!
You're fucking great!
Well, Victor.
I've warned you.
Help me. I've brought you
something.
Great!
We put it like this.
See how good it looks?
- Now it's a sofa.
- Great!
And it opens into a bed.
Thanks a lot.
- Here, read this.
- A Bible.
Yes, it's my Bible.
- What's this?
- Read it.
Go on, read it.
"Tonsillectomy in childhood."
- "No toxic addictions."
- Not one.
- Hemoglobin. Hemato- What?
- Hematocrits.
"Iron."
"Anti-HIV, negative."
So, I'm real healthy.
Yes, you are.
I didn't tell you before...
I just got out of jail.
- Hot, isn't it?
- Nice.
What does that mean?
What is that?
Bulgarian.
It means if you want,
we can open the futon.
Stop looking.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Me neither.
Come here.
Here I go.
How was it?
- I didn't even notice.
- I don't have much experience.
- Why don't you teach me?
- You can't teach that.
You can teach anything.
And I learn fast. Real fast.
I want to become
the best lover in the world.
Tell me the things
you like to do...
what you think about
when you masturbate.
I've got time to learn.
Look, Victor. You've treated me
like a hen's ass.
Christ, what a put-down!
First of all, don't dive
at my pussy so fast.
I mustn't dive at it.
Not to eat it...
or stick it in.
You have to prepare it first.
And don't worry.
It'll tell you when it's ready.
How will it tell me?
- It'll tell you. It'll notice.
- I hope so.
That's the first lesson.
Making love involves two people.
Great! And the second?
- Hi, Clemen. How are things?
- A mess.
I had to send Josep home
before he gave us all the flu.
- How are the kids?
- Fine. A volunteer showed up.
- Does he have references?
- He knows a lot about boilers.
- Has he fixed ours?
- He has.
- Great, but who is he?
- Well, he studied education.
He's promised to stay
the whole year.
- I took a real shine to him.
- I can see that!
When he saw
that I was so busy...
he offered to help
with the kids.
They're having a ball.
They're just crazy about him!
Mr. Wolf! Come over here!
Victor, this is Elena.
She's the big boss.
Miguel, you're obsessed
with legs.
- Let go!
- Pleased to meet you.
- What are you doing, Victor?
- Me? I'm helping.
By following me
like a psychopath?
I'm not following you.
Since you got out,
I see you everywhere.
I'm sorry, but we live
in the same city.
- I don't think you can stay.
- Why not?
Clemen said that
my teaching diploma was acceptable.
Your diploma!
When did you study teaching?
In jail, by correspondence.
Did you tell Clemen
that you were in jail?
What's up?
I can't stay because I've been
in jail? It was your fault.
What is this?
An NGO or a ministry?
This is a shelter for 12 children
who have suffered enough.
I don't want our problems
to affect them.
"You will be damned
in the town...
and in the country.
Damned will be
the fruit of your body...
the produce of your soul.
You will be damned
coming in and going out."
Deuteronomy.
Chapter 28.
Moses was thinking of me
when he wrote it.
Lesson number 11.
What's it to be today?
Whatever you want.
Not whatever I want.
Lesson number 11.
The greatest pleasure
for a woman in love...
is pleasing her man.
Clara, don't fall
in love with me.
You should have
warned me before.
"WELCOME"
What are you doing here?
I live here.
I married you long before
you got Alzheimer's.
- Where were you?
- I was at a class all morning.
Dance class?
Yeah, dance class.
What are you cooking, bull's tail?
Bull's tail in brandy.
Are we celebrating something?
Our 12th anniversary.
I took the afternoon off.
Sancho!
God, I'd completely forgotten!
- I'm sorry.
- I can see that.
Go inside. I'll see to this.
Will you fix me a drink?
You lie down like a guy
to watch TV.
I never knew that only men
lie on the sofa.
So now you know.
I'm tired.
Well, you've been busting
your ass dancing.
You quit seven years ago.
Why start again now?
Maybe I'll go back to dancing.
I need to be busy.
Then take care of us.
Sancho,
why don't we separate?
Why don't we separate?
As long as I love you,
you're not leaving me!
One day I'll stop
being afraid of you, Sancho.
I feel that day
isn't too far off.
I have to get back
to the kitchen.
And never hit me again!
It hurts me more
than it does you.
All the more reason!
You stay here.
I'll set the table.
Forgive me.
Even though
you may not believe it
As God is my witness
This will be our last meeting
You will understand.
That even if you pretend
To be in terrible pain
You're not going to die
But abandon now
That illusion
To no one in the world
Shall I give my heart
Return my love so I may kill it
Return the tenderness I showed
You don't deserve to keep it
You mean nothing to me now
Give me back
my mother's rosary
Everything else you may keep
Your things I'll send you
any evening
For you are not
to see me anymore
I'd do anything for the kids,
but you owe me two months.
The council is slow
in paying us.
That Italian woman's loaded.
She can fork out.
Really, Rosa.
Clemen, we're going
to the dentist.
If he mentions the bill,
get him to call me.
400,000 pesetas.
- Hello.
- David, what a surprise.
- Is my wife here?
- Shall I get her?
No, it's all right.
Thanks.
Come on.
Just give me two days.
Well, go and buy them
this afternoon.
Thanks, Elena.
- Hello, David.
- Hello.
You look awful.
Are you all right?
I saw Victor come in here.
He works as a volunteer.
What?
David, please,
don't make a scene.
How could you accept him?
I didn't. I came in one day
and he was here.
I don't understand.
David, this isn't the army.
I can't countermand the offers
without giving a reason.
And Victor's a good worker.
- Fuck that!
- What can I do?
Victor, can't you see I'm busy?
Excuse me.
I'd like a word before you go.
Yes, I'd like that too.
Would you mind leaving us alone?
Yes, I'd mind a lot!
Don't worry, my love.
Nothing will happen.
This is the last place
where you should have met.
Victor, let's talk clearly.
The woman who just left
through that door is my wife.
I'm crazy about her.
I'd do anything to defend her,
because she's all I have.
And like all cripples,
I've got a filthy temper.
I'm sure you love your wife
and have a filthy temper.
But it's not my business.
It is a bit, I think.
Before I met you, I looked up
at the sun, the stars, the moon.
Since I met you,
I have to look down...
at dog shit
so I don't stain my hands...
at curbs so I don't
crack my skull!
You condemned me to look down!
I didn't condemn you
to anything!
I don't give a shit
if you fired by accident.
It wasn't an accident!
- You did it on purpose?
- It wasn't me who shot you!
It was Sancho!
Clara told me.
How could he have shot me?
You had the gun.
Get off!
Victor, get off!
Let me go, please!
Victor, please!
I didn't want
to press the trigger!
- Take the gun!
- What are you doing?
Put your finger on the trigger,
but don't press it.
I pressed the trigger,
but Sancho pressed my finger.
He did it because
you were screwing his wife.
Clara wanted
to leave him for you.
He knew that.
That's why he shot you.
I spoke to Messengers of Peace.
They have a house
for children with AIDS.
I'm seeing them tomorrow.
If they accept me,
I'll leave El Fontanar.
I've already told the others.
How can you leave?
This way, Victor will have
no excuse to see me.
I thought you'd be pleased.
No, and I don't like you
being a martyr.
They can let you leave?
You set up that house.
I'm not abandoning them.
I'll still help financially.
What about the kids?
Your kids.
I don't know
how I'll leave them.
But I can't think
about myself.
Come here, Elena.
Come on. We'll smoke a joint
and relax a bit, all right?
We've both had...
a tough day.
- You look pretty relaxed to me.
- I've already smoked one.
What did you and Victor
talk about?
Didn't he tell you?
I didn't ask him.
I'm asking you.
So what did you talk about?
Here.
About the shooting.
Victor says it wasn't him.
But he had the gun.
I don't understand.
There are things
I never told you.
They happened before I met you.
I was very close to Sancho...
and also to Clara.
Especially to Clara.
Let it out.
Insult me if you want.
Do whatever you want,
but say something.
Say something.
Go to sleep, Aitor.
Be careful.
You'll catch cold.
I needed some air.
David told me about the shooting.
And?
I can imagine how
you must have hated me...
how you still hate me.
How could I hate you?
Do I look like I hate you now?
Until recently, all I wanted
was to get revenge on you two.
I even had a plan.
- A plan of revenge?
- Yes.
A ridiculous plan.
Of all that happened that night...
what hurt me most was that
you called me jerk-off...
and said I couldn't fuck.
I swore I'd make you
eat those words some day.
Worst of all, it was true.
So I decided that
when I got out of jail...
I'd become the world's best lover.
My plan was to spend
a whole night with you.
During that night,
I'd fuck you nonstop...
until I split you in two.
I'd give you more pleasure
than you'd ever dreamed of.
And naturally,
you would fall for me.
But I'd dump you...
and I'd never go back to you,
not even if you begged me.
That was my revenge.
That was my plan.
Good-bye, Victor.
Don't go so quickly.
I'm leaving in a few days.
I suppose we won't meet again.
In order to forget Elena...
I got a job and started
reading the Bible again...
as I did in jail.
On the first day, God created the night
so that lovers couldn't sleep.
He created water so that
it would drip constantly...
from market roofs.
And He created fish,
not to fill the seas with them...
but so that I could
unload them before dawn...
and, in that way,
not think about Elena...
and not go insane.
What a fright, baby.
Give me a kiss.
Give me a kiss!
Squeeze me.
Come on.
Where were you these two weeks?
In Portugal.
You smell different.
It's fish.
What were you doing?
- Tourism, and a cure.
- Tourism.
Didn't you get my card?
I couldn't tell you before.
Sancho suspects something...
so he's reforming
to try to win me back.
We even went to a clinic.
The bastard's stopped drinking.
And you?
I'm drinking even more,
can't you see?
I'm going to take a shower.
Anything wrong?
No, nothing.
I'm tired.
I'm working at the market now,
as well as at the Shelter.
Unloading crates.
Why are you working so hard?
What do you mean, why?
I can't leech off you forever.
- Why not?
- The things you say.
Wait.
We must stop meeting.
Don't tell me that.
I don't want anything from you.
Just to see you occasionally.
We both have
to sort out our lives...
but we must do it separately.
But why?
I'm not asking you
to love me!
I love you enough
for both of us.
Clara, do you notice
an odd smell?
Clara, I smell something odd.
Christ, the frying pan!
Are you crazy?
What's up with you?
Christ! Shit!
Fucking hell!
I thought you weren't coming.
I had a problem at home.
They're asleep.
It's all been done.
Great.
Thanks a lot.
Go see your girl.
And happy birthday!
Kiss her for me.
"THE SONG OF SOLOMON"
I didn't know you were here.
I came to get my things
from the office.
Don't go.
If anyone has to go, it's me.
Be quiet.
Promise that
you won't look for me...
and we won't meet again.
- Promise me.
- Yes, I promise.
We are in an impossible dream
Seeking the night
To forget in its shadows
the world and all else
We, in our daydream
Painful and beloved
Two leaves that the wind
Brought together in autumn
We are two beings in one
who, loving each other, die
To keep the secret
of their love
But what will life matter
When we are separated
We are two teardrops
in a song
But what will life matter
Dawn's breaking.
We are two teardrops
in a song
Nothing more
Are we
- David?
- Yes. Did I wake you?
I didn't expect you so soon.
I came back on my own
from Seville in a taxi.
I didn't wait for the team.
Go to sleep.
You must be exhausted.
No, I'm not tired.
What's up?
Not in the mood?
It isn't that.
It hurts.
It hurts?
How come?
I was fucking all night.
- What are you doing?
- I'm leaving.
To go where?
Far away.
Clara, don't start.
Give me an Alka-Seltzer.
My head's exploding.
Let me past.
Why not forget last night?
Take it easy, Clara.
Give me the keys and let me go.
We deserve another chance.
We've had too many.
Get out of the way.
I can change.
I proved it last week,
didn't I?
- Fuck. Forgive me!
- I forgive you.
Who was it?
Knowing that won't help you.
You doing it hasn't helped me.
It was Victor.
Bastard! I knew it!
It was my fault.
It won't happen again.
Why should I believe you?
I never lie, David.
That's true.
Yes, you're offensively honest.
What will you do now?
Stay with you,
if you don't throw me out.
- Didn't you enjoy it?
- I didn't say that.
Then why the fuck
stay with me?
You need me more than he does.
Right. I'll keep exploiting
your guilt complex.
David!
David, open the door!
What are you doing?
So long.
Please, open the door!
- Where are you going?
- Training.
Are you sure?
Of course I'm sure.
Who are you worried about,
me or him?
The three of us.
Who did he speak to?
Yes?
Clara, is that you?
Clara, answer me.
Wherever you hide,
I swear I'll find you.
This time you've had
a serious row.
No, not at all.
We were doing really well.
I'd stopped drinking.
But she flipped out...
and belted me
with her beauty case.
Is that a bullet wound?
She didn't mean to hit me.
It's just a scratch.
If you'd had your back to her,
you could've ended up like me.
I wouldn't mind ending up
in a wheelchair...
if I could get Clara back.
You stupid bastard.
- What?
- Nothing.
- You got any coke?
- Coke?
No. Why do you want it?
I don't want to cry.
Cocaine drys up your tears.
It cools you down.
Let me help you.
Come on.
Fuck!
Give me that.
Thanks, David.
What did you want to tell me?
- Clara sent you, right?
- No.
- Really?
- Clara hasn't seen me in ages.
But I've seen her.
Look.
You love Crispies.
Why won't you eat them?
And what's up with you?
You're big enough
to feed yourself.
Oh, he didn't like that at all.
- Yes?
- Hello, Clemen.
- This is Elena.
- Hi, Elena. What's up?
Is Victor there?
No, he isn't.
Where is he?
Listen, Elena. You said
you didn't want to see him.
It's important.
You said that if he asked
for your address...
we weren't to give it,
and now-
Now I'm asking for his.
What is it?
Really, I can't believe this.
Don't think that
because you fund us...
you have the right
to boss us around.
Don't torture me.
I've tortured myself enough.
Don't get like that.
Victor lives in La Ventilla,
in one of the pre-fabs.
Not only did she
fix up his house.
He's been screwing her
since he got out of jail.
Where does he live?
My boy!
Dear Victor...
I'd like you to keep this note
among the pages of your Bible...
along with the things
you most love.
When you read this,
I will be dead or running away.
You mustn't feel responsible
or pity me.
When I came to your door...
I knew I'd end up
like this neighborhood...
expropriated and destroyed.
But I have no regrets,
nor do I blame you, my love.
Before I met you, I was already
condemned to disappear.
I'm leaving your key
and some money.
I couldn't get any more because
I'm running away from Sancho.
Get out of Madrid.
I know you have more reason
than ever to stay now...
but Elena will understand too.
Keep away from Sancho.
It would be pointless
to confront him.
People like you and me
weren't born to kill.
We may hurt others...
I would even say we have
a special gift for that...
but we don't kill them.
There he is.
I'm sure it's him.
I know the way
he hammers on doors.
Good-bye, Victor.
Where's Victor?
He's gone.
He doesn't live here anymore.
Where does he live?
I don't know.
What are we going to do now?
Shoot each other?
Tell me another way
to settle it.
That depends on you.
This sums up my life.
Dragging myself along
to be near you.
I should have ripped
your balls off that night.
Shoot!
What's keeping you?
Will I have to shoot
for you again?
You stole six years of my life.
You stole much more from me.
Clara didn't belong to you.
Your life didn't belong to you.
No one ever owns his youth...
or the woman he loves.
It can't be!
David!
What are you doing here?
Elena, I'm in Miami.
I'm spending the holiday here
with some friends.
It's my first Christmas
in the sun...
and the first in six years
without you.
Although it hurts me
to admit it...
I understand you more than ever.
I understand your lack ofjoy...
why I so rarely saw you laugh.
Don't feel guilty about anything.
I'm to blame for what happened
in Eduardo Dato...
and for the massacre
in La Ventilla.
Look on this declaration
of guilt...
as a declaration of love...
and as my Christmas gift.
- Victor!
- Yes?
Is it time?
Come on!
Good-bye!
-Josep!
- What?
- Hurry!
- Which way do I go?
- The fastest way!
- Where's that?
- Through the center.
- No, we'll never make it.
Everyone's watching
the big soccer game.
We'll make it.
Come on, breathe.
Hang on, my love.
And you, don't be so impatient.
Come on, love.
Do the seal.
Come on,Josep.
The seal!
The contractions!
Don't be so impatient.
Hang on.
I'll try to convince him.
I know exactly how you feel.
I was in the same situation
26 years ago, about to be born.
But you're much luckier
than I was.
It's so different now.
Look at the sidewalk
full of people.
When I was born,
there wasn't a soul on the street.
People were shut up at home,
scared shitless.
Fortunately for you, son...
in Spain we stopped being scared
a long time ago.