Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
I couldn't hear anything with the music.
What is it?
I'm a policeman.
Didn't you see my ID?
I'm short-sighted.
I'm not.
Live opposite one of those windows..
I couldn't help noticing your plants.
- Pretty, Aren't they?
- Don't try to be clever with me.
It 's drugs.
You must think I'm soft in the head.
Talking of head,
how do you like my little pussy?
From here it looks...
scrumptious.
Saul sold his first-born
for a plate of lentils
Wouldn't you turn a blind eye
for a taste of this?
Let's see.
It doesn't come free.
OK.
I'll keep my mouth shut,
and you move the plants.
All right.
Don't go all tight on me.
Can we do it from behind?
I'm used to it that way.
Pervert!
I'm a virgin.
I'm not ready to lose my virtue.
Shut your mouth, doll.
I do things face to face.
Fuck! I never would have believed
you were a virgin!.
PEPI WAS HUNGRY FOR REVENGE
- The chorus should be higher.
- What's wrong with it?
- Like egg whites.
- Hi.
- How's it going, Pepi?
- I'm fine.
I've got a proposition for you.
An American tour. I can see it now..
Shut up.
I've got a problem you can help me with.
And what are you offering in return?
- All of my hash plants.
- It's a deal.
- OK, guys?
- Of course.
Give him a good kicking,
but don't go too far.
We don't want anyone to die,
now is not the time.
No problem, girl.
The only elastic is in my garter.
He's here. Go on.
Sing, so he doesn't suspect anything.
Not in the balls!
What's going on?
Why me? What have I done?
Great. You'll be in a sorry state.
You bastards!
Why are you beating me up?
Stand in line. I'll pass them down.
Here we go.
Careful you don't get the lift dirty.
It's so sad to see them go.
That was some going-over you gave him.
This one's crap.
You liked giving a policeman
a good kicking, didn't you?
- It's your kind of thing.
- Let's go.
- Shall we leave you that one?
- Why not?
Are you Matilde...? No, Kleenex. Hi.
- Hi Pilar. Just a minute.
- Yes, OK.
Wait. It's Kleenex
who signed the letter.
ETA STABILISES SOUTHERN FRONT
It's bad enough having
a brother who's a policeman.
but when he's your twin,
it's the bitter end.
I'm always the one who gets beaten up.
With so much democracy in this country,
where will it end?
Those Communists need to be
taught a lesson. Leave it to me.
Listen... I'm...
I'm the victim here
and I don't want publicity.
Thanks, but don't bother.
If it happened to me, I'd take my gun
and shower them with bullets.
Do you know what you should do,
to make sure
this never happens to me again?
Move out of here.
I don't know why you bought
that house in Parque de Lisboa.
We'll move when we're good and ready.
We've all the same right to be here,
me, you and Luci. Get it?
Thanks. I didn't expect
anything better from you.
Have you forgotten
who's been paying for your bills?
You know what? I'm leaving.
- Right now.
- Juan, don't be upset.
Sorry Luci.
It's nothing to do with you.
You've got enough problems,
married to him.
You haven't drunk your coffee.
Do you think I can?
I'll get a transfer to the Canaries.
No one knows you there. I'll be safe.
He's right. We should leave him alone.
I don't know why we bought that flat.
Shut up. this is man's business.
- I'm taking a taxi.
- Wait, we'll take a taxi.
Do you think I came here to do that?
I'm a singer and a model, not a whore.
A holiday in Morocco...
- A Moroccan brothel?
- Of course not.
I'll report you
for white slave trafficking.
I didn't leave my village for that.
I've got talent.
As a singer and model, not as a whore.
I know...
The business you're talking about,
I can just stand on the corner.
- You have to eat.
- I don't need a pimp to take my money.
Take your money?
I'm just trying to get you a job.
You guys are all the same. Taxi!
- Wait a minute.
- Taxi!
You'll see. Just let me explain...
- I'm going right now.
- Wait until five o'clock.
There isn't a mark on him.
We'll see about that.
- How's things?
- Fine.
Going to the market?
I've just been.
The price of potatoes has gone up again.
Be quiet.
That's bad news on a bad day.
You look terrible. What's happened?
- It's a terrible thing.
- Tell me what happened.
My husband and my brother-in-law
had a terrible fight.
- And?
- So Juan left the house.
What a shame!
Did he leave me a message?
- Quiet!
- No...
I can't let her get away.
I have to say something.
But how can I start speaking to her?
Yes... The jersey.
Of course he'll phone.
Can you ask him to call me?
When he calls, I'll say
you were asking after him.
- Ask him to leave a number.
- Yes, of course.
Luci, do you think
your brother-in-law likes me?
I don't know. Men are so weird.
What a lovely jersey you're wearing!
I made it myself.
That's amazing.
You could teach me to knit.
- I never thought of that.
- Well, think about it.
I live round here.
I'd pay you plenty.
- I don't know.
- You could make a living from it.
NEXT MORNING, PEPI
HAS HER FIRST LESSON
Look, help me.
I put the needle in,
put the wool round,
and there's the stitch.
No, not like that.
What do you mean?
You were doing it to the right
and you're going backwards.
What does it matter
if it's only practice?
If you know how to do it,
why are you doing it backwards?
You're ruining my knitting.
- No, you're doing it all wrong.
- Some teacher!
I'm not a teacher,
you're not paying attention.
Every time I make a mistake, I'll hit you.
That way, I'll learn.
You're right. I need a good slap.
Well!
That's your kind of thing.
How did you guess?
Your eyes are shining, you dirty bitch.
Some things you have to accept.
That's why I married him.
I thought that as a cop,
he'd treat me like a dog.
Some hope.
He respects me like his mother.
- You shouldn't trust him.
- I'm furious.
Don't worry.
As long as we do our knitting classes,
you'll get your slaps just the way
you like it, you crazy, dirty bitch.
- I'm all wet just thinking about it.
- Lucky you, you bitch.
So what do you do?
I'm an heiress, but my parents
are sick of giving me money.
They've told me to fend for myself.
What will you do now?
I thought about selling my virginity,
but I was raped so that's no good.
Well, at least you had some fun.
I'd have had much more fun
with the 60,000 ptas I'd have sold it for.
One woman's meat is another's poison.
I just want revenge on the guy who raped me.
Why should I lie to you?
It was your husband.
My husband?
Bastard! I should be so lucky.
- Who's this?
- My knitting teacher.
Forty-something and nice and tender.
Just the way I like them.
- I'm dying for a piss.
- Wait.
Piss on her.
She's hot. It'll cool her down.
It won't be easy.
but it'll be worth it.
Definitely. I'll help you.
Just relax.
Stand on the chair.
Lift your leg.
You like it, don't you?
I'm not a cow, you know.
Well...
Finished. No more.
That's it.
- Where are you from?
- Murcia.
We're going to be good friends.
You're invited to Toni's party,
at his cousin's house.
- It's gonna be fucking brilliant.
- Where'd he get the money?
Turning tricks with a queen, apparently.
I'll be there.
- Will you come?
- I don't know.
I've got to go.
- It was lovely to meet you.
- Make sure you come.
I'll expect you at the same time.
- Where have you been?
- Teaching knitting.
- Knitting?
- Yes.
- Why didn't you tell me last night?
- You were working.
Why is your shirt wet?
It was a glass of water, it got split.
- Have you been in a bar?
- No, my pupil did it by mistake.
Does she pay well?
- Yes.
- Is she a neighbour?
- You don't know her.
- All right.
Anyway, you know
I don't like independent women.
I believe that women have to find fulfilment.
And I get bored here at home.
Look, here's something
that will fulfil you.
So there is.
Amuse yourself by getting the food ready.
It's late and I'm hungry.
Why do you wear those trousers?
You know I hate them.
If your cousin comes home
in the middle of the party...
Stop nagging. I've told you,
they're away on their summer holidays.
Won't those people
complain about the music?
I've told you. They're away on holiday.
You're driving me nuts.
Stop being so paranoid.
All right.
I won't be quiet.
Why shouldn't I speak my mind?
Because I love you? You love me too
and you say what you want.
Do you think your silence makes you
loveable? It's driving me to despair.
When you don't talk, it drives me mad.
I think terrible thoughts about you.
your drinking, for example.
You're nice, sensitive, and intelligent.
People like that drink a lot.
But you started drinking on the day
that Oscar, your best friend,
decided to stop pretending and get
a boyfriend, which is what he wanted.
You think you're so liberal, how can you
be so old-fashioned as to hate queers?
People are free to do what they want
with their bodies. But not you.
He was your best friend
and you couldn't forgive him.
It's as if you were jealous.
so you married me to get your own back
and you started drinking.
Some revenge!
Hey, Toni. How's it going?
What's up, Moncho?
Have you won the lottery, or what?
'Course not. Got myself a client.
I'm looking for something like that too
because living with my parents is...
Listen, I know someone.
But he's a real old queen
and you might not like him.
Yeah, man, you know I love old queens.
He might not like you, anyway.
They usually like exotic types like me,
and you, to be honest...
You can try, anyway.
How much did you get?
20 grand.
Just for...
...for sleeping with him?
I'll tell you.
But keep your mouth shout.
He's a really weird guy.
He's my cousin's neighbour
and I often come to see him.
The other day I was in the street
and he cam up to me with some dough.
He said, why don't you organise a party?
And that was it.
Is he coming?
I don't think so. He's weird.
That's his window up there.
I bet you he's looking out.
I know you want me and you need me,
whatever you say.
But knowing isn't enough.
It's been 40 days and 40 nights
since we last had a fuck.
and I'm about to explode.
I'm like a cat on a hot tin roof.
I deserve better.
I've no reason to despise myself
just because I've got facial hair.
You taught me that having a beard
isn't so bad, and I'm grateful.
If that's not proof that you love me...
The problem lies in the way we live.
If I wasn't so rich and we had to work,
I'm sure our problems would unite us.
But I'm not going to leave you, believe me.
I'll be with you always, no matter what.
I can put up with anything.
- Here.
- No, thanks.
I said, eat it.
You little tart.
You know how to make me horny.
Give it to me, it's mine.
- 100 ptas and it's yours.
- Go to hell.
Let's see.
I'd like to keep it as a souvenir.
That pain in the arse
is taking photos again.
Give it here.
Interesting.
- How much?
- 100 ptas.
I'll take it.
Now I can blackmail your husband.
- Good idea.
- You don't mind, do you?
'Course not. He deserves it.
By the way, Pepi.
What were you saying the other day,
I know a woman
who can do your mending.
- Do what?
- Your mending.
Where?
Down there.
I'll let you know.
I'd rather carry on using it for now.
You can't say I poke my nose
into your affairs.
Did I say anything yesterday,
when you said you'd lost 20,000 ptas?
I thought you'd probably
spent them on a prostitute.
I did think it,
but I didn't say anything.
I know I'm very possessive,
and very jealous.
I should give you more freedom.
But what can I do? I am the way I am.
And deep down I'm sure
that you like me the way I am.
And now, our competition:
"General erections".
Tonight's big surprise.
In "Erections", the guy
with the biggest dick,
the most slender, enormous, perfect dick,
will be named King for the night,
and can do whatever he wants,
however he wants,
and with whoever he wants.
Does everyone agree?
The result will be announced
by our hostess, Pepi.
A round of applause for Pepi!
The result will also be decided
by multiplying the length by the thickness.
Pepi, with her calculator,
will give us the results.
Ready, guys?
Are those bodies ready?
Pepi, are you ready?
Fantastic. Then let's begin
"General Erections"!
- Where are you going?
- To shave.
- That's a shame. It suits you.
- Not that you'd notice.
Eighteen...
...by six...
One hundred and eight!
Toni...
Fifteen by...
...five...
Seventy-five!
Sixteen and a half...
...by six...
Ninety!
What's this?
Am I dreaming?
Delirious?
Is this reality I see before me,
or is it an illusion?
Help me, I can hardly breathe.
Moncho...
Twenty...
...by nine...
Two hundred and twenty points!
Ladies and gentlemen...
I give you...
I give you tonight's winner...
Moncho!
I knew that if I just
fixed myself up a little bit...
And now, the prize giving.
What do you want to do, and with whom?
Your desires are our to fulfil.
I want Luci to suck it.
It won't bite you.
Go on. Eat before it gets cold.
That's enough! Some of us want to sleep!
Don't stop. No one can ear you.
PEPI, LUCI AND BOM
Shit, I'm useless.
If I want to be a writer,
I'll have to learn.
- Yes?
- Pepi?
- Hi, Dad.
- Speak up, I can't hear you.
I've got a face mask on,
so I can't move my face.
I was going to call.
I haven't had my cheque.
That's what I wanted to tell you.
I'll send a cheque to cover
your rent and bills, but no more.
It's for your own good. You're old
enough to make your own living.
I am. I'm writing stories.
And loads more you don't know about.
I mean something more practical.
I've spoken to Sr Velasquez. He says
you can work for him if you want.
I told you, I don't want to be a secretary.
And anyway...
- I've got a job.
- Really? What is it?
GIRLS WITH IMAGINATION
ADVERTISING AGENCY
- A creative in an adverting agency.
- What's that?
I have to... come up with advertisements.
It's well paid and it suits me.
You're not lying to me again?
Me? Didn't you say
I had a lot of imagination?
Well, now I'm making a living from it.
You can't go on like this.
Listen, we've talked long enough.
Sorry, Dad, goodbye.
Work...
And a change. It's obvious.
I'd prepared everything so that
the afternoon would be perfect
He brought champagne
to celebrate our meeting.
Then something terrible
ad unexpected happened.
Is something wrong?
- I really need to fart.
- Go right ahead.
PUTON panties contain a substance
which transforms the smell of your fart
into an elegant perfume.
What delicious perfume you're wearing.
What's it called?
It's a woman's secret.
- Can I help you, miss?
- I'm in a terrible hurry.
Tell me what's wrong. Maybe I can help.
I need to pee so badly I could die.
Really?
Every time I enter a lift
or a phone box, I need to pee.
- Does it happen to you?
- Sometimes, but it's no great tragedy.
PUTON panties are made from fibres
which completely absorb your urine
and change their colour,
as though you'd put on a new pair.
There are times when solitude
is our greatest enemy.
PUTON panties, carefully rolled,
acquire a consistency which,
in the absence of anything better,
can fulfil the role
of a passionate companion.
PUTON panties
FOR ALL EVENTUALITIES
It's not because it's mine,
but I love it.
- It's just the way you wanted it.
- Exactly.
- Let's see what the client says.
- I'll deal with that.
- She's a bit of a dolly bird.
- She's perfect for this.
- But the guy couldn't be better.
- True.
I loved it. It's beautiful.
And the plants are gorgeous.
This is our audience.
It's a shame the panties don't work,
since I'm constantly peeing.
- Luci knows all about that.
- Oh, yes!
Bom, we should be going.
I'll come with you.
I've got an interview next door.
- See you later.
- Bye.
Advertising's your thing.
You think so?
I have an interview with a capitalist.
Is it about manufacturing dolls
with pussies and periods?
If it goes well,
I'll produce your record.
That would be fantastic.
The dolls are a brilliant idea.
Let's hope they think so too.
They're hard nuts to crack
and I need to persuade them.
- When are you going to Cuenca?
- This afternoon.
- What are you doing?
- She's coming with us, of course.
I'm going home to get my clothes.
I don't know what I'll do
if my husband's there.
Make a scene. Tell him
you're leaving because he raped me.
I'm annoyed we thought
your brother-in-law was him.
I'm still a bit mad with him.
He's a coward.
I don't think he'll dare do anything
if I say I'm leaving.
- Well, my capitalist lives over there.
- Good luck.
Remember to write down everything,
real and imagined.
and take photos, for my story.
Don't worry.
- Bye.
- See you later.
Silly!
Girl!
- Bye, Pepi!
- Come on.
I told you to stop those knitting classes
or I'll tie you to the bed.
Not a bad idea,
but I don't give a shit what you say.
What sort of language is that?
What would my poor mother say?
And another thing. Where's the money?
Or do you do it for free?
- I'm paying a debt of yours.
- Mine?
Yes! You should know that
my pupil is the girl you raped.
She wanted to sell her virginity
but since you ruined her plans,
I'm helping her to make jerseys
so she can make money on the market.
You're crazy. Someone's
filled your head with nonsense.
Don't you realise you're a victim?
Yes, a victim of the wave of eroticism
sweeping the country.
So what?
Eroticism?
- What have you done?
- All sorts.
I'm going on tour with Bomitoni Group.
I'm their groupie.
You're a groupie
for that bunch of degenerates?
You don't know me.
Pity I didn't get to know you earlier.
Luciana,
if you go out that door,
I'll bang you all up.
You'd be doing me a favour.
You've got to have fun in life
and apparently,
life in prison can be very lively.
- I'm going to get my things.
- You're not taking anything.
Fine. It'll be a weight off my shoulders.
But isn't there any way I can
force my wife to come back home?
It's quite clear.
There's no law to stop
a woman married to a policeman
becoming a groupie overnight.
OK.
If you go to court, you'll have every
feminist in the country on your back.
I'm sorry, but that's the way it is.
Thanks.
THE POLICEMAN
ALSO KNEW HOW IT FELT
TO BE HUNGRY FOR REVENGE
- Arrested!
- Don't shout. I'm not deaf.
Can I ask why I'm being arrested?
What about the plant?
You, get the plant.
It's there as a decoration.
I didn't know it was a crime.
- It's plastic.
- It cost me 15,000 ptas.
Plastic? Bring it here!
Don't you know it's forbidden
to make fun of the police?
Don't you know that
plastic plants are fashionable?
Let's go.
They're always on the go.
They go swimming, sailing,
they go to discotheques,
they hardly sleep.
The usual thing for young people.
Lots of free time,
and lots of wonderful energy.
Ana Lorenz, let's see now.
What about people
who stay in the city?
All the restaurants have the "Closed
for Holidays" sign in the window.
It can be a big problem, can't it?
Yes. I think it will be less
of a problem this year, because...
- Hello. Is Luci in?
- No.
I haven't seen her for days.
She's not ill, is she?
No, no.
She moved to Parque de Lisboa.
The new flat?
You're confusing me
with my brother. I'm Juan.
Juan?
I didn't realise.
- Come in.
- Silly me!
How lovely.
Aren't I an idiot?
Of course, since I'm wearing
his dressing gown.
Oh, yes.
Luci didn't even say goodbye.
You know what her husband's like.
He probably wouldn't let her.
Luci and I are very good friends.
I'm very sad she's gone.
- I'm not.
- No?
- No.
- Why?
I'm a bachelor.
And bachelors have other needs.
- Are you going to stay here?
- Yes.
Didn't Luci say anything?
She was supposed to ask you to call me.
No. But so what?
I've thought a lot about you.
- Really?
- Charito...
Angel... Darling...
- I like you very much, you know.
- No, please, no.
Afterwards, you won't respect me.
You'll say I'm like all the rest.
Look what you've done to me.
Wait a minute.
You'll see.
No, please.
You won't feel a thing.
- Don't take my clothes off.
- OK, I won't.
But let me feel your legs.
Even if it's only your legs.
Let me.
- I've got 30 ptas. What have you got?
- I've got 50.
Not even 100 ptas.
- If someone comes...
- They're playing tonight.
My friend Pepi is coming.
I really want to see her.
Lot's of my friends are coming.
Don't you understand what I'm saying?
- Why doesn't someone come?
- Here are some girls.
Girls never give you anything.
They keep it for themselves.
Let's see if a boy comes.
- Yes! Look!
- Here's a boy coming!
Come here, boy. Come here.
Can you give us some money?
I'm going over there to have a beer.
We just need enough for a ticket.
How much have you got? Perfect!
Bomitoni!
You're a friend of Toni's, aren't you?
He's told me a lot about you.
Sick it up, nobody will notice.
I'm his cousin's neighbour.
I've been drinking and smoking.
I'm on a real downer.
Let's go for a walk. It'll do you good.
OK.
You must be happy.
I'm so grateful to you
for introducing me to her.
- I'm a new person.
- You look younger.
I love you because you're dirty
Filthy, slutty and servile
You're Murcia's most obscene
And you're all mine
I love you because you're dirty
Filthy, slutty and servile
You're Murcia's most obscene
And you're all mine
I only think of you
Murcia girl!
Because you are...
...a slag!
I put my finger in your crack
I give you a couple of slaps
Force you to make me come
I'm worse than a terrorist
I only think of you...
Murcia girl!
Because you are...
...a slag!
That big poof is from my village.
Toni, how's it going?
He's lovely. He's got a different style.
I'm a model. I suppose you realised.
My agent told me that I might
have a chance. I probably will...
Would you give me your phone number?
My phone number? Who do you think I am?
And take your hand off.
See? They're all the same.
I fit you just like a glove
You get off when we make love
If I fart into your mouth
You give me a round of applause
You belong to me
Murcia girl!
Because...
...that's what I want!
It's disgusting, but so what?
You get dolls that suck milk bottles,
that pee, that poo, everything.
None of them sweat and bleed
and that's the doll for this Christmas.
NO FILMING ON SUNDAYS
We're going to the country on Sunday
so you can use the camera.
I'm a month behind and I need
a definite answer as soon as possible.
That's the way we do business, quickly.
Just a minute.
I can't make out all the corrections.
The boy says, "I want Luci to suck it".
And Bom says,
"Go on, eat before it gets cold."
- Thanks.
- That was my secretary.
Listen, we can take the angle of
bisexual education and personal hygiene.
Some people think children
are mentally retarded.
But some of them aren't.
If you like the idea, maybe you
can persuade your colleagues...?
I'm going to look for funding elsewhere
I don't think I can rely on you.
Well, call me whenever you want. Bye...
The detergent people don't like
the reference to bridal purity.
What a day.
Paco says he wants to discuss it.
Not today. Tell him tomorrow.
- Say I've gone out to do something.
- OK.
If I stay here any longer
I'll have a nervous breakdown.
I'm not surprised.
- Is this OK now?
- Great.
If there's anything urgent then...
I wonder who that is.
- Surprise!
- What are you doing here?
- Pepi! How are you?
- I'm fine.
- I bought you a present.
- You shouldn't have.
You deserve it.
And I think you'll like it.
I think I'm going to love it.
- Hi everyone.
- Hi, Pepi.
Wow, they're so big.
- You like them?
- They're fantastic.
- Very good.
- They're so pretty.
This really achieves a certain...
What can I say?
You know what I mean, don't you?
This is a real success.
I can help you through the agency.
You're all sweaty.
- How's the boxing?
- It keeps me fit.
Why does she bother? It's exhausting.
- She's at it all day. What about me?
- Shut up, stupid.
Can I have a drink? I'm thirsty.
- Luci?
- I'll get it.
She's under your thumb. Come on.
- I've got some coke. Want some?
- I don't feel like it.
What are you like?
I'll keep some for Luci, she'll want it.
I've got the agency's cameras
so we can shoot the video this weekend.
Are you serious about filming us?
Of course. Now I've got the cameras,
I'd better use them.
Pepi, what gorgeous women
you've brought me.
- I knew it.
- My God.
I've never seen anything like it.
Careful.
Look at her.
Happy as a kid in a sweet shop.
Do you want a line? Here you are.
You never say no, do you?
I was just telling Bom, we're
going to film our story this weekend.
- You want me to be into it too?
- Of course.
I'm not sure...
I've never done it before.
Don't worry,
I'll make sure you'll do it right.
You're only playing yourselves, after all.
I'm looking forward to it.
You'll have to do what I say.
As well as being yourselves, you have to act.
What do you mean?
You can't just go like this
to the camera.
As well as being yourselves,
you'll have to represent your characters,
and representation is always artificial.
I don't understand.
For example, you're a forty something
housewife, married to a cop...
- Are you listening to me?
- I'm putting a comb on the angel.
So, you're a housewife
but you really like to party.
So you have to show that.
I've seen you being slapped
and eating snot without turning a hair.
I don't know.
- And you like it?
- I love it.
We have to show that. You eat snot
like it was a slice of bread.
- That's how I am.
- Of course.
But cinema isn't life,
cinema is falsehood.
They use a machine to make rain,
because real rain can't be photographed.
I'm including the scene where Bom
pisses on you, just as it happened.
Do you remember? It was brilliant.
So when she pisses on you,
you have to moan with pleasure.
Yes! Listen, like this...
Yes, that's is more or less.
We'll rehearse, don't worry.
If we don't do it,
people won't believe you're a masochist.
You know I love to obey,
so I'll do whatever you say.
You just need to exaggerate a little.
And you too. Because you're...
- You're 15.
- 16.
You look much older. But what's funny
is if you look at your age,
because you're
a forty something policeman's wife
and you're a 16- year-old punk singer.
- It's itchy.
- Here we go again.
You're crazy.
I know you're violent
and perverted and so on,
but you don't look like a sadist
so much as just unfriendly.
If I'm no good, find someone else
and leave me in peace.
Don't be upset. It's supposed to be fun.
If it doesn't work it doesn't matter.
Why don't we rehearse a bit?
Hey, Bom, hit me.
Leave me in peace.
- Shall we go out?
- Let's go clubbing.
I'd rather stay here and watch TV.
- Lighten up, girl.
- You and I can go.
- You're always up for everything.
- Shall we get dressed up?
Let's go!
Is your brother-in-law still in the Canaries?
I suppose so. He called before he left
but I haven't heard from him since.
Is that waiter never going to come?
Luci...
- What?
- Get some beers.
All right.
How are you?
- Is this the guy you told me about?
- No, a different one.
- We've just got married.
- Really?
- Quique, Pepi.
- Pleased to meet you.
- He doesn't say much.
- He's mute.
- He's good-looking though.
- True.
Enjoy yourself.
Did you see...?
You never join in, do you?
It's so boring in here.
Have you seen the people?
I never get bored.
I love watching everything.
- You can get blood from a stone.
- A what?
A stone!
- Are you Bom, from Bomitoni group?
- Another pain in the neck.
Don't come the star with me, twat.
She loves being recognised.
Have a drink with us.
- Yeah?
- I said to bring beers.
I thought you said Coca-Cola. I got confused.
- Where are the guys from the band?
- They're on military service.
- I come from the same place as Toni.
- Really?
- I'm an artist, too.
- What do you do?
I'm a singer. Not like you,
a different style.
Flamenco rock.
- What?
- Flamenco rock.
What's that?
It's kind of like a ballad,
but international.
- Is it hard?
- Well...
Are you working anywhere?
Let me speak. Are you working?
I'm working in a bar to pay the rent,
but just serving drinks.
- What did she say?
- She's working in a bar.
- Just serving drinks.
- No one suggested anything else.
My agent's promised me
a tour in the north.
Bilbao, San Sebastian, all around there.
I'll probably make a record.
I might be able to help you.
I've got an agency.
- Really?
- It's mine.
Really? I'm a model.
You might not have the sparkle
to be a model.
What do you mean?
Look at my hair. Think what an advert
I could make with that.
- Maybe...
- What?
- All right!
- Go on...
Give me one of your cards.
Here you are, twat.
She's so refined!
I'll call you.
- Who's that?
- I don't know. Who is it?
- She's gone.
- Go and fetch her.
- What shall I say?
- Whatever you like.
And buy me some fags. I've run out.
All right.
- Who's the dimwit?
- Her girlfriend.
Some laugh.
- Anyway... I'll call you.
- Sure.
I want to get out of that bar.
Those guys get the wrong idea.
I'm not old-fashioned. They can
touch my belly-button. But that's it.
- The girlfriend?
- The girlfriend.
Mine.
- Anyway, I'll call you.
- Of course, whatever you like.
OK.
There you are!
I told you to wait in the theatre bar.
I'm going to lock you in my dressing-room
until the performance is over.
If you escape again... You little devil.
What am I to do with you?
The theatre'll throw me out.
- I've got him.
- Thanks.
Some friends of mine want to see you.
- Me? What for?
- They like you.
- Me?
- Yes, very much.
- They're in a bar near here.
- Is it nearby?
- Just here.
- OK. Let's go.
- Don't hit him on the head.
- If he was yours...
You women go too far.
I wish he'd hurry and grow up.
In you go, little one... After you.
Here she is.
Are these your friends?
- Hello.
- So?
We were bored and we saw you
dressed up like that.
Stay with us.
- I'm due on stage in five minutes.
- What play are you in?
- The Lady of Camellias.
- Not Scarlett O'Hara?
Are you bored? You look terrible!
I'll leave my son here to entertain you
and pick him up after the show.
- I'm not bored.
- We can have a drink and talk.
- Don't leave him here.
- Behave yourself.
He's a charming boy. Look after him.
Don't worry. Leave him here.
- I want a sandwich.
- Just what we need.
They don't do sandwiches.
Have a "Cuba Libre".
- OK, a "Cuba Libre".
- Child!
Some night this has turned out to be.
- Have a look, sweetie.
- What now?
- And my cigarettes?
- I forgot.
- Well, go and get them.
- Enjoy yourself.
Out into the street again. All right...
Look, an artist,
and the son of an artist.
- What's up, kid?
- Leave me alone.
- Why the hurry?
- What's it to you?
Are you forgetting I'm a policeman?
I could arrest you right now.
- I'm scared! Try it.
- OK. Let me see your papers.
I haven't got any.
Under the law, if you don't have papers
you can be fined 4,000 ptas.
I'll shove that law up my hole.
Really?
Tell me that down at the station.
- Why?
- To the station!
Coward!
A proper husband doesn't need laws
to treat his wife the way he should.
You know how good I am
at dealing out justice...
- ...with my hands.
- You're all talk.
That's why I left you.
Really? You can forget all that
because you're coming with me.
- OK?
- Where?
Parque de Lisboa. No one knows us there.
You'll have to kidnap me.
What a good idea.
You'll spend the rest of your life
tied to the bed.
If only you had the balls.
Shut up, you whore!
You don't know what a whore
I am, you bastard.
Tonight you'll pay for everything
you've put me through.
Yes, I deserve it.
- Communist!
- Fucking communist!
Take that!
- You like it, don't you? Take that!
- I like it!
I'm going to strangle you!
She's not coming.
If she's gone back home,
I'll teach her a lesson.
She's trying to provoke you. You haven't
been giving her enough recently.
Her little trick will backfire on her.
I'll come round to your house.
Fine with me.
You could move in.
I'm starving.
Let's get something to eat.
It's a bit late to eat out,
but I can make you something at home.
Where has that bitch got to?
Don't think about her anymore.
I used to like her, but recently
she's been a pain in the arse.
This cod I'm making
is gong to be delicious.
- Have you got the water?
- Pour it in very slowly.
- Will you stir it?
- Of course.
- I'm so tired.
- Me too, I'm dead.
- I'm going to get a spoon.
- And the water goes in?
Pour it in bit by bit, not all at once.
- That's the secret.
- You're wonderful.
I thought you might make me
an omelette or something,
but cod with chillies and garlic,
my favourite dish...
I'm really hungry too.
I can't stop thinking about
how Luci left me standing there.
She's got more of a hold on you
than you think.
It's not that.
With masochists,
you never know what to expect.
She's probably having a great time suffering
because I'm not at home yet.
I've told you, she's not right
for you. And you know it.
- I've got used to her.
- That's the problem.
In bed... it's incredible.
That's what I don't get.
She looks like a mosquito, but...
That's got nothing to do with it.
If you didn't have such weird tastes,
you'd soon find a replacement.
My tastes change as time goes by.
When I was small, I used
to like women of over 50.
Last year, I was into forty somethings.
And now I wouldn't say no
to a woman of 35.
If you go on like that,
next year you'll be into 10-year-olds.
Talking about replacements, if I leave Luci
what will you do about the film?
I doubt that'll happen, but I'll replace her.
I don't think she was an actress.
Have you thought about
the end of the film?
- Well...
- Tell me.
You and Luci got married, both in white,
and I had a child by the policeman.
You come and see me at the hospital
and I give you the baby,
because you've set up home together.
What an imagination you have.
I had to have something.
But I don't know.
I'd like something more realistic.
Anyway, I'm waiting to see
what happens between you two.
How can we be such good friends,
and yet so different?
I never wonder about things like that.
Give me a kiss.
- Look out.
- I'll spill it.
- Are you embarrassed?
- That's why it was a quick one.
- I'll clean it for you later.
- Clean it now.
No, later.
This transvestite's been all around Europe.
- He's a star.
- Something like that...
"I'm a hermaphrodite.
I was born with both sexes."
I'm just the same.
I'm bored and feel like going out.
- I'll be there in an hour and a half.
- That sounds great.
Someone's at the door.
I'm going to see if it's Luci.
Your favourite Avon lady's here.
The sales lady with spunk,
all my clients are hunks.
Well, hello, Francisco.
I'm never so greedy
for a woman of breeding!
Let's see, how are we doing?
Some place you've got.
- What have you brought?
- The very best in cosmetics.
It's the best. Look what I've got.
A face mask made from
mixed vegetables, it's scandalous.
What else have I got?
The best cocaine, heroin and acid.
- It's not Luci.
- Who is it?
Roxy, speeding as usual,
with cocaine for the boys.
Ask her to keep me a gram.
I don't even want to speak to her.
They're getting on my tits.
I wish they'd leave me in peace.
I'll have to move out.
- You have to stop being depressed.
- I'm worried about Luci.
It's been two days.
I haven't heard from her.
- She'll have found someone.
- I wouldn't be surprised.
All we shared recently was a packet
of fags. But she could have called me.
the doorbell. This time it'll be Luci.
I'll have such a go at her!
A uniform! Come in, darling!
How are you? I'm a Cinderella at heart.
An ordinary woman.
Who's this woman?
Wait, where should I start?
- Can you sign, please?
- I'll sign for you right now.
- Thank you.
- Signed and sealed.
Don't you have
a little teleprinter somewhere?
It's a telegram from Luci.
Wait, I'll read it.
"I'm well. I'm in hospital.
Come and see me. Luci."
Something horrible must have happened.
Don't worry, I'm coming over
No, don't. I have to go and see her at once.
Wait, I'll be there in half an hour.
- All right.
- Keep calm.
But hurry, please.
Shit.
- Stay with me.
- I'm on duty.
Please, don't go!
- Please, don't go!
- I'll call the police.
- I need you
- Seorita!
Come here, come inside.
Come on, come and sit down.
No, please, no.
What's he like?
What am I like?
Try this new...
...schizophrenic pussy.
Schizophrenic pussy. Try it, darling.
It's amphetamines, try it, baby.
Luci, you've got so many medicines.
- Have you taken any today?
- None.
Shall I help you
to take a tranquilliser?
No. Leave it.
But you haven't taken any at all.
I don't want to make a habit
of taking pills.
I'd rather be in pain.
She's so long-suffering.
See what they've done to her
and she hasn't said a word.
But you were very lucky, Luci.
- At least they didn't rape you.
- No, that's true.
If that ever happens to me,
they can hit me as much
as they want, I don't care,
as long as they don't rape me.
Imagine,
you spend your life keeping men at bay,
which isn't easy,
and then some yobs come along
and it's all for nothing. What a joke.
It just shows the state this country is in.
No one cares what happens to an
honest woman walking down the street.
Have you told the police?
No. Unfortunately, Luci didn't see
the faces of any of the attackers.
No?
- I'd better go.
- Of course.
If Juan comes, remember to tell him
I was asking after him.
I haven't seen him for a few days.
Goodbye, Luci. Look after yourself.
- Thanks for coming to see me.
- The stitches won't leave a scar.
Bye. Don't forget to tell Juan.
She's so innocent.
She was born a fool.
It was bad of you to take advantage
of her while I was away.
I didn't think you were such a bastard.
I was worried in case
she met the others here.
Did you put the right address
on the telegram?
Yes, don't worry.
This must be them.
Luci, what's happened to you?
Nothing. You can see.
What do you mean, nothing?
You look like a mummy.
My husband. He kidnapped me and took me
to our new flat to persuade me...
Tell him to go.
We want to talk to you in private.
In your dreams, little girl.
Call me that again,
and I'll scratch your eyes out.
You should leave.
You won't like what we have to say.
Don't worry.
I'm sick of dealing with sluts.
- Tell him to go.
- I can't. He's a monster.
You seem dazed. I think the beating
has affected your head.
- what's wrong? You seem different.
- Nothing's wrong.
You don't know me well enough yet.
Don't push me, or I'll get mad.
Keep calm.
I'm much more of a slut than you think.
And you're not as evil as you think you are.
You couldn't give me what I deserved.
Lately you'd been
treating me like your maid.
I'm not complaining,
but I think I deserved
something much worse.
But look...
He nearly killed me.
You hear her, little girl.
There's nothing you can do.
Choose between him and me.
This is your last chance.
When I married him,
I'd already made that choice.
Don't trust him, he'll go back
to treating you like his mother.
He hates me with all his soul,
and he can't forgive me for what
I've done to him these last months.
I'd be crazy to pass up
an opportunity like this.
- Stupid!
- Quiet, this is a hospital.
- Let's go.
- Anyway...
I want to thank you
for everything you've done for me.
Save your thanks.
If it weren't for you,
he'd never treat me like this.
- Be quiet, you've said enough.
- Let's go.
- This is beginning to stink.
- Thanks for the presents.
No problem.
I'll be coming round
to get my wife's things.
You can collect them tonight,
from the rubbish bin.
That's the end of it.
What fucks me off is seeing
that policeman laughing at us.
Forget about it.
They deserve each other.
- What will you do now?
- I don't know. I feel disorientated.
Why don't you leave those painters
like you were saying,
and move in with me?
- Are you serious?
- Of course.
I'm a girl living alone.
I need someone to protect me.
With your boxing,
you could be my bodyguard.
I'd be delighted to protect you.
Let's get your things right now.
You're an angel.
What's wrong now? Come on, cheer up!
If I move in with you
I'm not going to sponge off you.
I can't have a woman supporting me.
- I need to get money from somewhere.
- You've got your music.
Music? I don't have a band anymore,
they've all left. I've got nothing.
Pop's gone out of fashion.
I need a different style,
I don't know what.
I've already thought of that.
Why not sing boleros?
- Boleros?
- Yes.
- Like Olga Guillot?
- Exactly!
- I'd love to.
- That's decided then.
Do you think I can do it?
You've got soul,
and that's what's important.
I'll take care of the rest
and choose the songs for you.
So many changes in just one day.
Yes... Cheer up.
A new life is opening up before you.
And for you, too.
I hope so.
# by lyliakar #
Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext