1
00:00:22,789 --> 00:00:25,895
[♪♪♪]

2
00:00:37,003 --> 00:00:38,141
MAN:
Here's your key.

3
00:00:40,607 --> 00:00:41,711
[DOOR CLOSES]

4
00:00:58,291 --> 00:00:59,736
Hello.

5
00:01:00,493 --> 00:01:01,995
[TRAVIS WHISTLES]

6
00:01:09,903 --> 00:01:10,938
Oh. Uh...

7
00:01:11,104 --> 00:01:13,243
My bad. They gave me
the wrong key.

8
00:01:13,406 --> 00:01:15,852
Not your bad.
We stay a little long.

9
00:01:16,009 --> 00:01:17,682
We're now leaving soon.

10
00:01:19,179 --> 00:01:20,715
Okay.

11
00:01:21,614 --> 00:01:24,424
What the fuck, guy?
ANKA: It's okay, Viktor.

12
00:01:24,584 --> 00:01:25,927
He's here for the room.

13
00:01:26,086 --> 00:01:27,258
TRAVIS:
Yeah.

14
00:01:29,022 --> 00:01:30,296
Yeah.

15
00:01:30,457 --> 00:01:31,697
You're on vacation.

16
00:01:32,358 --> 00:01:34,065
Uh, yeah.

17
00:01:34,227 --> 00:01:37,834
I've actually never
been here before. It's--
It's a pretty cool town.

18
00:01:38,398 --> 00:01:40,378
Where are you guys from?

19
00:01:41,734 --> 00:01:44,305
Ukraine.
Cool.

20
00:01:44,471 --> 00:01:47,782
Now that he kidnapped me I don't
know where we're gonna end up.

21
00:01:47,941 --> 00:01:50,217
You're so dirty. Ha-ha-ha.

22
00:01:54,547 --> 00:01:56,390
[ANKA MOANS]

23
00:01:57,016 --> 00:02:00,156
Enough. You're gonna
wear me out.

24
00:02:01,955 --> 00:02:03,525
Come.

25
00:02:03,690 --> 00:02:04,828
Have a drink with us.

26
00:02:05,625 --> 00:02:07,127
Uh...

27
00:02:07,794 --> 00:02:09,899
[♪♪♪]

28
00:02:11,664 --> 00:02:13,666
It's vodka, man.
Don't be shy. I

29
00:02:15,735 --> 00:02:17,476
Come on, man.

30
00:02:17,904 --> 00:02:19,713
TRAVIS:
Yeah. You know, it's--

31
00:02:20,740 --> 00:02:23,983
Well, actually I've got some beer.
Do you guys drink beer?

32
00:02:24,144 --> 00:02:25,248
It's still cold.

33
00:02:25,578 --> 00:02:27,148
[BACKPACK UNZIPS]

34
00:02:27,380 --> 00:02:29,018
VIKTOR:
Beer, huh?

35
00:02:31,017 --> 00:02:32,360
TRAVIS:
Yeah.

36
00:02:37,290 --> 00:02:38,735
I like this guy.

37
00:02:38,892 --> 00:02:40,565
He brings party with him, huh?

38
00:02:42,095 --> 00:02:43,472
Come.

39
00:02:47,834 --> 00:02:49,336
There you go.

40
00:02:54,007 --> 00:02:55,577
There we go.
We do a cheers now, huh?

41
00:02:55,742 --> 00:02:57,949
Sure.
Nazdrovia.

42
00:02:58,344 --> 00:03:00,017
Nazdrovia.
ANKA: Nazdrovia.

43
00:03:03,950 --> 00:03:07,727
Okay. I go take shower,
then we go.

44
00:03:17,564 --> 00:03:18,599
Oh, shit.

45
00:03:20,266 --> 00:03:22,610
Fuck. I'm sorry, man.
I didn't mean to--

46
00:03:22,769 --> 00:03:23,804
No. For what?

47
00:03:24,270 --> 00:03:25,908
Never mind. It's human nature.

48
00:03:26,072 --> 00:03:28,109
I'm looking everything that moves.
Right.

49
00:03:28,608 --> 00:03:30,281
Okay.
She's hot, right?

50
00:03:31,678 --> 00:03:33,316
Yeah, she's pretty hot.
Yeah.

51
00:03:33,479 --> 00:03:34,981
Yeah.

52
00:03:36,382 --> 00:03:39,989
Hey, we were in this club,
crazy chicks. You go there,
you're gonna score.

53
00:03:40,153 --> 00:03:41,962
I have club card for you.
Oh, no.

54
00:03:42,121 --> 00:03:45,534
No, no, no. You're gonna go
in there, man. Connection.

55
00:03:46,125 --> 00:03:48,162
Anka, I need that club's card.

56
00:03:48,828 --> 00:03:50,705
Oh, hold on. I lose it.
Okay.

57
00:03:50,863 --> 00:03:52,433
Baby, I need
the club card.

58
00:03:52,599 --> 00:03:53,907
[SHOWER RUNNING]

59
00:03:54,067 --> 00:03:55,478
Anka!

60
00:03:55,902 --> 00:03:58,746
Shit. Something's
fucking wrong?

61
00:03:58,905 --> 00:04:01,010
What the fuck? Anka!

62
00:04:01,174 --> 00:04:03,984
Hey, get in here!
We got a problem, man.

63
00:04:04,143 --> 00:04:05,383
Anka.

64
00:04:05,545 --> 00:04:07,149
Talk. Talk.

65
00:04:07,313 --> 00:04:09,589
Hey, get in here, man.
Come on!

66
00:04:10,450 --> 00:04:13,863
I think she's having a heart attack
or something. Talk to me!

67
00:04:14,520 --> 00:04:16,796
What the fuck you doing, man?
Get in here!

68
00:04:16,956 --> 00:04:18,401
Anka, talk to me.

69
00:04:18,558 --> 00:04:21,732
Come on, man.
We gotta get her to a doctor.

70
00:04:21,928 --> 00:04:23,999
Help me, man.
Call a fucking doctor!

71
00:04:24,397 --> 00:04:26,707
Hey! Come on, man!
What the fuck? Help me!

72
00:04:27,200 --> 00:04:30,306
Call the fucking doctor!
What the fuck you standing there?

73
00:04:30,470 --> 00:04:33,508
What the fuck you doing, man?
Get in here!

74
00:04:36,009 --> 00:04:37,488
What--?

75
00:04:38,544 --> 00:04:40,285
[GRUNTING]

76
00:04:40,446 --> 00:04:42,448
[♪♪♪]

77
00:04:47,720 --> 00:04:49,290
What is going on?

78
00:04:54,694 --> 00:04:56,332
Anka.

79
00:05:16,849 --> 00:05:17,919
[SIGHS]

80
00:05:18,084 --> 00:05:19,324
[CELL PHONE BEEPS]

81
00:05:23,389 --> 00:05:25,096
Yeah, we're good to go.

82
00:05:38,037 --> 00:05:39,072
Here.

83
00:05:39,439 --> 00:05:42,511
Keep her dry. If she gets sick,
we'll have to discount her.

84
00:05:44,110 --> 00:05:46,784
[♪♪♪]

85
00:06:43,569 --> 00:06:45,571
[♪♪♪]

86
00:07:07,193 --> 00:07:08,365
Come on.

87
00:07:08,528 --> 00:07:10,701
Save that shit for
the honeymoon, please.

88
00:07:11,397 --> 00:07:12,933
Oh, the best man.

89
00:07:13,099 --> 00:07:17,104
You know,
since I am the best man,
which clearly I am,

90
00:07:17,270 --> 00:07:20,114
you know, why is it that
she's marrying you?

91
00:07:20,273 --> 00:07:22,116
You had your chance
freshman year.

92
00:07:22,275 --> 00:07:24,152
What ever happened?
SCOTT: I don't know.

93
00:07:24,310 --> 00:07:25,846
You were a man-whore?

94
00:07:26,012 --> 00:07:29,118
Not in front of her.
Thanks for that.

95
00:07:30,082 --> 00:07:31,755
Come on, let's go.

96
00:07:36,489 --> 00:07:37,934
Again. More of this.

97
00:07:38,090 --> 00:07:41,037
You get to kiss this jackhole
for the rest of our life.

98
00:07:41,194 --> 00:07:43,071
This weekend, he's mine.

99
00:07:43,329 --> 00:07:46,242
Such a dick.
Don't let him bang any strippers.

100
00:07:46,399 --> 00:07:47,434
SCOTT:
What?

101
00:07:47,733 --> 00:07:50,441
There are no strippers
in Palm Springs.

102
00:07:50,603 --> 00:07:53,880
Well, there's no decent strippers
in Palm Springs, all right.

103
00:07:54,040 --> 00:07:55,951
Once I get him out on the course,

104
00:07:56,108 --> 00:07:59,248
the only thing he's gonna
be banging is five irons, Ames.

105
00:07:59,512 --> 00:08:01,185
Okay.

106
00:08:02,448 --> 00:08:04,587
I'll call you from the hotel.
Be safe.

107
00:08:04,750 --> 00:08:06,320
All right.

108
00:08:15,828 --> 00:08:19,207
A little breakfast?
No. I'm good. It's a little early.

109
00:08:19,365 --> 00:08:21,606
Even for you.
This is nothing, man.

110
00:08:22,835 --> 00:08:25,543
In a couple of hours,
you are gonna be doing blow

111
00:08:25,705 --> 00:08:27,343
off some hot stripper's ass.

112
00:08:28,975 --> 00:08:31,785
You said there were no good
strippers in Palm Springs.

113
00:08:31,944 --> 00:08:33,287
There aren't.

114
00:08:34,947 --> 00:08:37,188
We're not going to Palm Springs,
are we?

115
00:08:38,584 --> 00:08:40,495
[CHUCKLING]

116
00:08:41,354 --> 00:08:43,595
[LOUDER'S "DON'T LET UP"
PLAYING]

117
00:08:43,756 --> 00:08:47,033
♪ Crank that system up ♪

118
00:08:47,193 --> 00:08:50,868
♪ I wanna be on top
So don't let up ♪

119
00:08:51,030 --> 00:08:54,170
♪ Crank that system out ♪

120
00:08:54,333 --> 00:08:57,906
♪ I wanna hear that shout
So don't let up ♪

121
00:09:05,111 --> 00:09:09,423
♪ If tonight's the night
Come on, let's do it right ♪

122
00:09:09,582 --> 00:09:12,222
♪ So don't, so don't let up ♪

123
00:09:12,385 --> 00:09:16,390
♪ If tonight's the night
Come on, let's do it right ♪

124
00:09:16,556 --> 00:09:19,469
♪ So don't, so don't let up ♪♪

125
00:09:27,934 --> 00:09:29,470
[CLANKING IN DISTANCE]

126
00:09:30,670 --> 00:09:32,377
Holy shit.

127
00:09:32,572 --> 00:09:33,710
Holy shit.

128
00:09:33,873 --> 00:09:36,149
What the fuck is this?

129
00:09:43,616 --> 00:09:45,095
Anka.

130
00:09:45,551 --> 00:09:46,928
Anka.

131
00:09:47,086 --> 00:09:48,531
Anka.

132
00:09:48,688 --> 00:09:49,723
Get up!

133
00:09:49,889 --> 00:09:50,993
Anka!

134
00:09:51,157 --> 00:09:54,161
Hey! Who the fuck
are you guys?

135
00:09:54,327 --> 00:09:56,068
What the fuck you doing?

136
00:09:56,228 --> 00:09:58,071
What the fuck you want
with us?

137
00:09:58,230 --> 00:09:59,436
Anka!

138
00:09:59,599 --> 00:10:01,408
Hey!

139
00:10:02,001 --> 00:10:03,708
Come to me!

140
00:10:03,869 --> 00:10:05,940
You motherfuckers, don't touch her!
Aah! Aah!

141
00:10:06,105 --> 00:10:08,244
VIKTOR: Don't touch her!
Aah! Aah!

142
00:10:08,407 --> 00:10:09,442
VIKTOR:
Come to me!

143
00:10:09,609 --> 00:10:10,986
Come to me, motherfuckers!

144
00:10:11,143 --> 00:10:12,588
Who are you? Where--?

145
00:10:12,745 --> 00:10:14,053
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]

146
00:10:14,213 --> 00:10:15,954
Where the fuck are you taking her?

147
00:10:16,115 --> 00:10:18,026
Aah! I don't wanna die!

148
00:10:18,184 --> 00:10:19,754
Anka! I'm gonna come for you!

149
00:10:19,919 --> 00:10:21,091
ANKA:
Let go!

150
00:10:21,253 --> 00:10:22,288
Let go!

151
00:10:22,455 --> 00:10:23,490
No!

152
00:10:23,656 --> 00:10:24,726
VIKTOR:
Anka!

153
00:10:24,890 --> 00:10:26,631
Anka, I'm gonna come
for you!

154
00:10:26,792 --> 00:10:28,669
All you motherfuckers
are gonna die!

155
00:10:28,828 --> 00:10:30,637
ANKA:
No!

156
00:10:30,796 --> 00:10:33,072
[KOVAS' "READY" PLAYING]

157
00:10:33,232 --> 00:10:36,702
♪ I hope you ready, ready
I hope you fee! it ♪

158
00:10:36,869 --> 00:10:40,715
♪ I hope you ready, ready
No, no, don't be sweet ♪

159
00:10:40,873 --> 00:10:45,344
♪ I hope you ready, ready
Ready, ready, ready, ready ♪

160
00:10:52,618 --> 00:10:53,995
♪ Tonight is the night ♪

161
00:10:54,153 --> 00:10:57,691
♪ I hope you ready, ready
I hope you feel it ♪

162
00:10:57,857 --> 00:11:01,771
♪ I hope you ready, ready
No, no, don't be sweet ♪

163
00:11:01,927 --> 00:11:05,704
♪ I hope you ready, ready
Ready, ready, ready, ready ♪

164
00:11:05,865 --> 00:11:10,075
♪ I hope you ready, ready
Ready, ready, ready, ready ♪

165
00:11:18,744 --> 00:11:19,779
Ha, ha!

166
00:11:19,945 --> 00:11:22,013
♪ Here comes the bride ♪♪

167
00:11:22,014 --> 00:11:24,016
[MIKE & SCOTT LAUGHING]

168
00:11:24,183 --> 00:11:25,662
What's up?
CARTER: How's the leg?

169
00:11:25,818 --> 00:11:27,058
JUSTIN: It's okay.
Carter.

170
00:11:27,219 --> 00:11:29,665
How are you, Mike?
I'm glad you made it.

171
00:11:29,822 --> 00:11:30,857
Good to be here.

172
00:11:31,023 --> 00:11:34,527
How you doing? Thanks for coming.
Wouldn't miss it.

173
00:11:34,694 --> 00:11:36,970
We're not here for you.
We're here for this.

174
00:11:37,129 --> 00:11:39,439
Bounce it.
Up and down, north to south.

175
00:11:39,598 --> 00:11:42,044
How great is this?
Tits and ass at your table.

176
00:11:42,201 --> 00:11:44,545
I could get
all the stripper action I want,

177
00:11:44,704 --> 00:11:47,913
look my wife in the face
and say I never went
to the club. Genius.

178
00:11:48,074 --> 00:11:50,145
Sit down. Let's do some damage.
Okay. Cool.

179
00:11:50,309 --> 00:11:52,084
♪ I hope you ready, ready ♪

180
00:11:52,244 --> 00:11:56,158
MIKE:
Ha-ha-ha! Look at that.
Spade and neutered. What's up?

181
00:11:57,650 --> 00:12:00,290
♪ I hope you ready, ready
Ready, ready ♪

182
00:12:00,453 --> 00:12:04,595
MIKE:
Yeah. Dude, some come for
the free booze, I come not to lose.

183
00:12:05,725 --> 00:12:07,261
Pay me, motherfucker.

184
00:12:07,426 --> 00:12:08,905
[LAUGHING]

185
00:12:09,595 --> 00:12:12,735
MIKE:
Oh, yeah. Winner, winner,
chicken dinner, bitches.

186
00:12:13,966 --> 00:12:15,309
♪ I hope you ready ♪♪

187
00:12:19,205 --> 00:12:21,185
JUSTIN:
This whole place
is a lab experiment.

188
00:12:21,340 --> 00:12:23,684
Look. Look at it.
There are no windows.

189
00:12:23,843 --> 00:12:26,517
There are no clocks on the walls.

190
00:12:26,679 --> 00:12:29,023
They pump oxygen in here
to keep you awake.

191
00:12:29,181 --> 00:12:32,253
They give you free booze
to keep you drunk.

192
00:12:32,418 --> 00:12:35,058
They parade women
in front of you on top of that.

193
00:12:35,221 --> 00:12:38,930
It's all just to take your money.
Man, this place is evil incarnate.

194
00:12:39,091 --> 00:12:41,799
Yeah, maybe so,
but not when you're winning.

195
00:12:42,628 --> 00:12:45,268
Mikey, you're looking
a little light over there.

196
00:12:45,431 --> 00:12:47,877
Oh, me? I'm golden.
It's you I'm worried about.

197
00:12:48,033 --> 00:12:49,774
Oh, God. Don't start this shit.

198
00:12:50,803 --> 00:12:52,043
Wait, what shit?

199
00:12:52,204 --> 00:12:55,185
His "don't do it" speech.
I've heard every version of it.

200
00:12:55,341 --> 00:12:58,686
You're gonna tell him
not to get married.
You don't want him to.

201
00:12:58,844 --> 00:13:01,620
You're married, you know that, right?
Yeah. I know.

202
00:13:01,781 --> 00:13:04,261
And it's a living hell, Carter.
Seriously.

203
00:13:04,416 --> 00:13:06,896
Marriage is nothing
but a three-ring circus.

204
00:13:07,052 --> 00:13:11,159
Engagement ring, wedding ring,
suffering. You'll see.

205
00:13:11,824 --> 00:13:14,168
Yeah, but it's gonna be
different for Scotty.

206
00:13:14,326 --> 00:13:17,068
Really? Interesting.
How exactly?

207
00:13:17,730 --> 00:13:19,573
Because he's not
marrying a bitch.

208
00:13:19,732 --> 00:13:22,713
Oh, see, there it is.
He comes in with a:

209
00:13:22,868 --> 00:13:25,906
I am getting married
in one week, and you
and your lovely wife

210
00:13:26,071 --> 00:13:29,143
are gonna be there.
My lovely fat wife. Yes, we will.

211
00:13:29,308 --> 00:13:32,846
Okay, time to go.
What? What are you doing? I'm hot.

212
00:13:33,012 --> 00:13:36,221
That's why they sent over
the cooler. Asians are bad luck.

213
00:13:36,382 --> 00:13:38,658
You make good
firecrackers, though.

214
00:13:38,818 --> 00:13:40,456
That is just some racist bullshit.

215
00:13:40,619 --> 00:13:42,565
I'm sorry, man.
He did not mean that.

216
00:13:42,721 --> 00:13:44,166
All right. So, what now?

217
00:13:44,323 --> 00:13:45,802
JUSTIN:
Got Cirque du Soleil tickets.

218
00:13:45,958 --> 00:13:48,495
Oh, so you're not only disabled,
you're also gay.

219
00:13:48,661 --> 00:13:49,833
Sometimes.

220
00:13:49,995 --> 00:13:51,804
But it's not gonna matter too much

221
00:13:51,964 --> 00:13:55,537
because Scotty is getting
seriously eye fucked

222
00:13:55,701 --> 00:13:58,375
by the girls at the progressive slots.
See them?

223
00:13:58,537 --> 00:14:01,746
Dude, they are hot.
And I bet you they
hate their fathers.

224
00:14:01,907 --> 00:14:04,683
JUSTIN: Yes.
What are you doing? Don't start.

225
00:14:04,844 --> 00:14:07,950
I'm not doing anything.
Justin, do your thing.
Limp on over.

226
00:14:08,113 --> 00:14:10,024
Nothing wets a pussy
like this hardware, huh?

227
00:14:10,182 --> 00:14:11,752
Pity fuck is still a fuck.

228
00:14:11,917 --> 00:14:13,521
That's true.

229
00:14:16,522 --> 00:14:18,229
Hey, guys.

230
00:14:18,657 --> 00:14:20,728
I'm Kendra.
I'm Nikki.

231
00:14:20,893 --> 00:14:25,137
Hi. I'm Scott.
This is Carter, Mike and Justin.

232
00:14:25,631 --> 00:14:28,441
Mike.
So you girls wanna join the party?

233
00:14:28,601 --> 00:14:29,773
Not much of a party.

234
00:14:30,903 --> 00:14:33,884
We're just kind of getting started.
We have a Jacuzzi.

235
00:14:34,039 --> 00:14:36,918
It's in our room,
if you guys wanted
to head up there.

236
00:14:37,076 --> 00:14:38,316
Smooth.

237
00:14:38,477 --> 00:14:40,388
You guys have
any better ideas?

238
00:14:42,381 --> 00:14:46,056
We know a place,
but it's off the Strip.

239
00:14:46,218 --> 00:14:48,824
Yeah, it's way off the Strip.

240
00:14:52,892 --> 00:14:56,738
I don't know, it might be
too much for some nice
boys from the suburbs.

241
00:14:56,896 --> 00:14:58,466
NIKKI:
It's a little freaky.

242
00:14:58,931 --> 00:15:00,467
Do you like freaky?

243
00:15:00,633 --> 00:15:04,206
We like freaky.
We've always been
into that sort of thing.

244
00:15:06,472 --> 00:15:07,644
What about you?

245
00:15:08,040 --> 00:15:09,314
Um...

246
00:15:09,642 --> 00:15:10,916
KENDRA:
Do you like freaky?

247
00:15:11,076 --> 00:15:12,453
Yeah.

248
00:15:12,611 --> 00:15:13,646
Yeah, sure.

249
00:15:14,847 --> 00:15:16,918
[♪♪♪]

250
00:15:29,795 --> 00:15:32,571
[MIDDLE EASTERN MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO]

251
00:15:33,165 --> 00:15:35,111
Hey, listen, on the radio here,

252
00:15:35,267 --> 00:15:37,474
I love this guy.
I have his records.

253
00:15:37,636 --> 00:15:41,049
But do you think you could turn
it down a couple of notches

254
00:15:41,206 --> 00:15:42,879
so we can hear ourselves?

255
00:15:48,480 --> 00:15:49,515
Thank you.

256
00:15:49,682 --> 00:15:52,026
Yeah. Do you think
that those girls are pros?

257
00:15:52,184 --> 00:15:54,061
What, hookers? Pfft.
No, tennis pros.

258
00:15:54,219 --> 00:15:57,723
Who cares? I wanna poke them
in their vaginas with Justin's crutch.

259
00:15:57,890 --> 00:16:00,598
Go check their oil with my tongue.
Know what I mean?

260
00:16:00,759 --> 00:16:03,069
A little low down there?
You need a fill-up?

261
00:16:03,896 --> 00:16:06,342
Hey, you know your meter's
not working, man.

262
00:16:07,533 --> 00:16:10,878
You high rollers pay me 20 bucks,
I call it even.

263
00:16:11,036 --> 00:16:13,038
[♪♪♪]

264
00:16:13,839 --> 00:16:16,718
SCOTT: You sure this is right?
CARTER: I think that's it back there.

265
00:16:16,875 --> 00:16:19,651
The GPS shows
it should be right here.

266
00:16:19,812 --> 00:16:21,723
You see a club?
I don't see a club.

267
00:16:21,880 --> 00:16:23,757
All I see is a bacon factory.

268
00:16:25,818 --> 00:16:29,231
What are you afraid of?
Think I'm gonna drive
you to the alley

269
00:16:29,388 --> 00:16:32,528
where my friends steal your money
and cut your heads off?

270
00:16:36,395 --> 00:16:37,635
CARTER:
Okay, time to go.

271
00:16:37,796 --> 00:16:39,935
JUSTIN: All right.
MIKE: Okay.

272
00:16:45,671 --> 00:16:48,743
SCOTT:
That is way off the Strip, all right.

273
00:16:49,308 --> 00:16:52,517
MIKE: Are you sure this is it?
JUSTIN: It's the address she gave us.

274
00:16:52,678 --> 00:16:55,420
SCOTT:
Those girls were right.
This place is pretty freaky.

275
00:17:01,420 --> 00:17:02,455
What you want?

276
00:17:03,922 --> 00:17:05,299
We're here for the party.

277
00:17:05,457 --> 00:17:07,562
You on the list?

278
00:17:07,726 --> 00:17:09,763
Yeah. Nikki and Kendra sent us?

279
00:17:10,863 --> 00:17:12,240
Oh.

280
00:17:12,398 --> 00:17:13,741
So you're that deal?

281
00:17:14,400 --> 00:17:15,777
What does that mean?

282
00:17:16,635 --> 00:17:20,481
It means
you're gonna have a nice time.

283
00:17:20,639 --> 00:17:22,619
Come on in. Down the hall.

284
00:17:37,489 --> 00:17:39,628
[♪♪♪]

285
00:17:46,298 --> 00:17:48,403
JUSTIN:
Dude, this place feels fucked.

286
00:17:48,567 --> 00:17:49,671
I think we should go.

287
00:17:49,835 --> 00:17:52,714
What, go check out Cirque du Soleil?
Sure.

288
00:17:52,871 --> 00:17:54,441
Your vagina's hanging out.

289
00:17:54,606 --> 00:17:55,641
What?
Yeah.

290
00:17:55,808 --> 00:17:57,685
How did that get out?
Second time.

291
00:17:57,843 --> 00:17:59,686
My goodness.

292
00:17:59,945 --> 00:18:04,087
Well, we're here.
Might as well see
what it's all about.

293
00:18:04,249 --> 00:18:06,160
"Might as well see
what it's all about."

294
00:18:06,318 --> 00:18:08,195
Dude, we're not going
anywhere.

295
00:18:08,654 --> 00:18:09,758
[CELL PHONE RINGING]

296
00:18:09,922 --> 00:18:11,959
Oh, fuck.
That's me.

297
00:18:12,124 --> 00:18:14,400
Fuck, dude.
It's Amy.

298
00:18:14,560 --> 00:18:16,301
You probably
wanna take that.

299
00:18:16,462 --> 00:18:18,999
You're practically married.
Guess what I do.

300
00:18:19,164 --> 00:18:23,271
When I'm away from my wife,
I turn off my phone.
She can't call, can't text,

301
00:18:23,435 --> 00:18:27,042
can't make me send
a photo of where I'm at
because she's insecure.

302
00:18:27,206 --> 00:18:30,744
That's why your marriage sucks.
She put on 30 pounds, so...

303
00:18:30,909 --> 00:18:32,445
Amy, hey.

304
00:18:32,611 --> 00:18:35,217
You said you would call
when you got tothe hotel.

305
00:18:35,380 --> 00:18:36,450
I know, l'm sorry.

306
00:18:36,615 --> 00:18:41,689
Um, look, we're just walking in
somewhere, so I'm-- I gotta go.

307
00:18:41,854 --> 00:18:44,698
So l'll call you when I get back
to the hotel tonight?

308
00:18:44,857 --> 00:18:47,667
Scott.
Yeah?

309
00:18:48,026 --> 00:18:50,233
Should I be worried
about you?

310
00:18:51,029 --> 00:18:52,235
No.

311
00:18:52,397 --> 00:18:53,899
Please don't do this.

312
00:18:54,066 --> 00:18:57,980
You have nothing to worry about,
okay? I love you.

313
00:18:58,137 --> 00:18:59,411
Okay.

314
00:18:59,571 --> 00:19:01,209
I love you.

315
00:19:03,075 --> 00:19:05,385
[♪♪♪]

316
00:19:13,352 --> 00:19:14,922
Guys?

317
00:19:16,922 --> 00:19:18,424
Very funny.

318
00:19:22,995 --> 00:19:24,531
Hello?

319
00:19:27,432 --> 00:19:29,002
Hello?

320
00:19:33,539 --> 00:19:35,348
[DOOR CLOSES IN DISTANCE]

321
00:19:47,953 --> 00:19:49,899
SCOTT:
What the fuck?
What are you doing?

322
00:19:50,055 --> 00:19:51,864
Stop it! I can't fucking breathe!

323
00:19:53,492 --> 00:19:55,836
Where the fuck are you taking me?

324
00:19:57,229 --> 00:20:00,108
Ugh! Let me go!

325
00:20:01,366 --> 00:20:03,812
[GASPING]

326
00:20:09,474 --> 00:20:11,249
[SCOTT COUGHING]

327
00:20:24,556 --> 00:20:25,591
What the fuck?

328
00:20:28,293 --> 00:20:30,796
[CROWD CHEERING]

329
00:20:30,963 --> 00:20:32,533
[OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ DJ, turn it up ♪

330
00:20:32,698 --> 00:20:34,439
♪ Turn, turn, turn
Turn, turn it up ♪

331
00:20:34,600 --> 00:20:36,409
Now, that's a bachelor party.

332
00:20:38,270 --> 00:20:40,272
Ah! You fuckers!

333
00:20:40,806 --> 00:20:42,547
Ah! You assholes!

334
00:20:42,708 --> 00:20:44,915
♪ That's when she dances
Like them girls ♪

335
00:20:45,077 --> 00:20:46,215
♪ In the nightclub ♪

336
00:20:46,378 --> 00:20:48,517
♪ That's when she dances
Like them girls ♪

337
00:20:48,680 --> 00:20:50,125
♪ In the nightclub ♪

338
00:20:50,282 --> 00:20:52,125
I'm gonna kill you.
I'm gonna kill you.

339
00:20:52,284 --> 00:20:54,628
Are you in on it?
I had no idea.

340
00:20:54,920 --> 00:20:57,560
♪ She drops to the floor
Brings it back up slow ♪

341
00:20:57,723 --> 00:21:01,364
♪ Like a stripper
That girl puts on a show ♪

342
00:21:01,526 --> 00:21:03,870
♪ So I swear
Just fell in love ♪

343
00:21:04,029 --> 00:21:06,339
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Scott! Scott! Scott!

344
00:21:06,898 --> 00:21:09,208
♪ Up in this club ♪

345
00:21:09,368 --> 00:21:11,939
Scott! Scott! Scott!

346
00:21:12,404 --> 00:21:13,883
♪ DJ, turn it up ♪

347
00:21:14,039 --> 00:21:16,144
♪ Turn, turn, turn, turn
Turn, turn it up ♪

348
00:21:16,308 --> 00:21:18,049
♪ Let me hear that beat drop ♪

349
00:21:18,210 --> 00:21:19,780
♪ Beat drop, beat drop ♪

350
00:21:19,945 --> 00:21:21,447
♪ To her favorite part ♪

351
00:21:21,613 --> 00:21:22,853
♪ Part, part, part ♪

352
00:21:23,015 --> 00:21:26,258
They won't put their clothes on.
They just won't do it.

353
00:21:26,418 --> 00:21:28,864
♪ In the night club ♪
♪ That's when she dances ♪

354
00:21:29,021 --> 00:21:31,023
Are you mad?
Uh...

355
00:21:31,189 --> 00:21:32,566
Maybe.

356
00:21:32,724 --> 00:21:34,397
♪ And dances and dances ♪♪

357
00:21:34,559 --> 00:21:36,197
You guys set me up
pretty good.

358
00:21:36,361 --> 00:21:38,568
Hey, it's what they paid us
to do.

359
00:21:39,398 --> 00:21:41,207
So you're a...?

360
00:21:42,000 --> 00:21:43,377
What do they
call you now?

361
00:21:43,535 --> 00:21:46,744
Oh, this week, "escorts."

362
00:21:48,040 --> 00:21:49,542
Are you disappointed?

363
00:21:50,842 --> 00:21:52,014
No.

364
00:21:52,611 --> 00:21:53,988
Good.

365
00:21:55,414 --> 00:21:56,825
Let's go.

366
00:21:57,582 --> 00:21:58,652
Where?

367
00:21:58,817 --> 00:22:00,797
The champagne room.

368
00:22:02,587 --> 00:22:05,227
SCOTT:
You are gonna get me
in so much trouble.

369
00:22:06,825 --> 00:22:09,237
WOMAN:
Hey, I'm Angela.

370
00:22:09,828 --> 00:22:11,273
Hey.

371
00:22:12,164 --> 00:22:14,007
I'm, uh-- I'm Justin.

372
00:22:15,701 --> 00:22:16,736
I'm sorry.

373
00:22:16,902 --> 00:22:18,779
Gotta get back to my friend.
Sure.

374
00:22:18,937 --> 00:22:22,111
Just so you know, darling,
this thing stays hard all night.

375
00:22:23,175 --> 00:22:24,882
Who lit the fuse on her tampon?

376
00:22:25,043 --> 00:22:26,647
MIKE:
Tampon.

377
00:22:27,779 --> 00:22:29,884
What is wrong with your friend?

378
00:22:30,882 --> 00:22:32,589
A lot.

379
00:22:32,984 --> 00:22:34,861
You're too sweet for her.

380
00:22:35,020 --> 00:22:36,260
[MIKE BELCHES]

381
00:22:36,822 --> 00:22:39,962
So why don't you stay here?

382
00:22:40,125 --> 00:22:41,604
I want you to wait for me

383
00:22:42,527 --> 00:22:46,168
because I don't know how long
your friend's gonna be, okay?

384
00:22:46,331 --> 00:22:47,708
You ready?
Mm-hm.

385
00:22:48,200 --> 00:22:50,180
I just came
in my pants.

386
00:22:50,335 --> 00:22:51,405
That's not my wife.

387
00:22:51,970 --> 00:22:54,246
That's not my wife.

388
00:22:54,639 --> 00:22:57,848
Shh. Don't tell anyone.
Keep a secret.

389
00:22:58,110 --> 00:22:59,714
[OVER SPEAKERS]
♪ Heart track ♪

390
00:22:59,878 --> 00:23:01,551
♪ Hit back ♪

391
00:23:01,713 --> 00:23:03,386
♪ Whole smack ♪

392
00:23:03,548 --> 00:23:05,152
♪ Grinds me ♪

393
00:23:05,317 --> 00:23:06,921
♪ l'm on your ♪

394
00:23:07,085 --> 00:23:08,723
♪ Heart track ♪

395
00:23:08,887 --> 00:23:11,629
♪ Hard snatch, winds me ♪♪

396
00:23:11,790 --> 00:23:15,135
[AMBIENT ELECTRONIC MUSIC
PLAYING OVER SPEAKERS]

397
00:23:30,942 --> 00:23:32,285
Mmm.

398
00:23:33,245 --> 00:23:35,122
Yeah. Oh.

399
00:23:38,116 --> 00:23:40,187
No. No, no. Can we--?
Can we just--?

400
00:23:40,352 --> 00:23:42,229
Slow down, slow down,
slow down.

401
00:23:42,387 --> 00:23:43,661
Slow is cool.

402
00:23:43,822 --> 00:23:45,824
We've got the room for an hour.
Yeah.

403
00:23:45,991 --> 00:23:47,937
No, no. Um...

404
00:23:48,093 --> 00:23:51,506
No. I'm just thinking
maybe we could just talk.

405
00:23:51,663 --> 00:23:54,007
Talk?
Yeah.

406
00:23:54,332 --> 00:23:55,811
Yeah. Yeah.

407
00:23:55,967 --> 00:23:59,346
Like, um, are you from Vegas?

408
00:23:59,504 --> 00:24:00,744
[LAUGHS]

409
00:24:00,939 --> 00:24:02,748
Is that what
you wanna talk about?

410
00:24:02,908 --> 00:24:05,411
No, no. It's just that, um...

411
00:24:07,879 --> 00:24:09,825
No. It's just that, uh...

412
00:24:09,981 --> 00:24:13,326
Oh. Oh. Is--?
Is this your first time?

413
00:24:13,485 --> 00:24:15,226
No. I'm--

414
00:24:15,620 --> 00:24:16,826
I'm getting married.

415
00:24:17,756 --> 00:24:18,860
Not tonight.

416
00:24:19,024 --> 00:24:21,231
Not tonight.
No, not tonight.

417
00:24:21,393 --> 00:24:23,168
Please, Kendra. Kendra.
Wait.

418
00:24:23,328 --> 00:24:26,241
Just relax, okay?

419
00:24:26,598 --> 00:24:29,477
Nobody's gonna know anything.

420
00:24:29,634 --> 00:24:30,772
Yeah. I know, I know.

421
00:24:30,936 --> 00:24:36,614
No, but look--
Look. Look, I was--
I was unfaithful last year.

422
00:24:36,775 --> 00:24:39,585
All right, my fiancée found out
and I almost lost her.

423
00:24:39,978 --> 00:24:43,755
All right, I realize how fucking lame
this sounds, I do, but I just...

424
00:24:44,182 --> 00:24:47,652
I told myself that I wasn't gonna
be that guy anymore.

425
00:24:48,787 --> 00:24:50,733
Hey, I get it.

426
00:24:51,356 --> 00:24:54,462
It's cool.
Nothing has to happen.

427
00:24:54,626 --> 00:24:56,902
We can just hang out.

428
00:24:57,929 --> 00:24:59,875
At least, here.

429
00:25:00,098 --> 00:25:01,941
Have another drink.

430
00:25:03,768 --> 00:25:05,008
MIKE:
Ahh.

431
00:25:05,437 --> 00:25:08,680
Scotty. I just found out
who killed JFK.
You wanna know?

432
00:25:08,840 --> 00:25:12,515
You still have your clothes on.
You are slow, you little bitch.

433
00:25:12,677 --> 00:25:13,849
What's up?

434
00:25:14,012 --> 00:25:17,186
Somebody threw up in our room so--
Somebody?

435
00:25:17,349 --> 00:25:18,384
Yeah.

436
00:25:18,550 --> 00:25:20,962
Yeah, you did.
Hey, you can't keep a secret.

437
00:25:21,119 --> 00:25:25,124
Close your mouth, open your legs.
Close your mouth, open your legs.
Ha-ha-ha.

438
00:25:25,290 --> 00:25:27,065
Are you okay?
No.

439
00:25:27,225 --> 00:25:30,263
No. I need to get some air.

440
00:25:30,428 --> 00:25:31,463
KENDRA:
Okay.

441
00:25:31,997 --> 00:25:34,409
Air is good. Air is good.
Get some H2O.

442
00:25:34,566 --> 00:25:36,603
No, that's water.
Hey. What are you doing?

443
00:25:36,768 --> 00:25:39,112
Great.
You're hot, but I need you to leave.

444
00:25:39,271 --> 00:25:42,650
You're hotter. Hi, Nikki.

445
00:25:42,807 --> 00:25:44,343
[MIKE LAUGHING]

446
00:25:45,443 --> 00:25:47,582
[MIMICS CAR ENGINE
REVVING]

447
00:25:50,515 --> 00:25:52,085
Indy 500.

448
00:25:52,250 --> 00:25:54,992
Ah! One more, one more.

449
00:25:55,153 --> 00:25:57,155
[♪♪♪]

450
00:25:57,322 --> 00:25:59,324
[PANTING]

451
00:26:24,282 --> 00:26:26,125
[♪♪♪]

452
00:26:40,465 --> 00:26:42,376
Open up!

453
00:26:48,673 --> 00:26:50,209
[POUNDING ON DOOR]

454
00:26:50,775 --> 00:26:51,879
[COUGHING]

455
00:26:56,147 --> 00:26:59,060
SCOTT:
Come on. Is anybody in there?

456
00:27:03,154 --> 00:27:05,065
Please!

457
00:27:07,892 --> 00:27:10,031
Open the fucking door.

458
00:27:33,485 --> 00:27:36,125
[♪♪♪]

459
00:28:11,423 --> 00:28:12,993
[WHIRRING]

460
00:28:13,425 --> 00:28:14,495
[GATE BEEPS]

461
00:28:34,979 --> 00:28:36,253
[DOOR CLOSES]

462
00:28:36,414 --> 00:28:38,553
[FOOTSTEPS]

463
00:28:39,217 --> 00:28:42,198
[MAN WHISTLING]

464
00:28:43,321 --> 00:28:45,858
[MOTOR WHIRRING]

465
00:28:47,592 --> 00:28:49,538
[LIQUID SLOSHING]

466
00:28:56,101 --> 00:28:57,876
[SCOTT COUGHING]

467
00:29:02,240 --> 00:29:04,151
Bachelor boy
finally woke up, huh?

468
00:29:04,309 --> 00:29:07,449
JUSTIN:
Yeah. I think the warm piss
in his pants did it.

469
00:29:08,012 --> 00:29:09,685
CARTER:
We thought you were dead.

470
00:29:09,848 --> 00:29:11,919
SCOTT:
Just dead drunk.

471
00:29:12,717 --> 00:29:14,663
Ugh. God.

472
00:29:14,819 --> 00:29:16,321
[CHUCKLING]

473
00:29:23,495 --> 00:29:25,771
You know, I would have
carried you to bed,

474
00:29:25,930 --> 00:29:29,434
but you're fucking
huge and I've got
a gimpy leg, so...

475
00:29:29,601 --> 00:29:34,812
Heh. Last thing I remember,
I was throwing up and
got locked out of the club.

476
00:29:35,073 --> 00:29:39,215
How did you get back here?
You were here when we got in.

477
00:29:41,079 --> 00:29:42,251
Um...

478
00:29:42,413 --> 00:29:45,485
The cabbie.
The cabbie with the broken meter.

479
00:29:46,718 --> 00:29:50,791
Oh. Did you at least get laid?
No. But she was a cutie.

480
00:29:50,955 --> 00:29:55,961
That pisses me off because
I paid that whore good money
to rock your world. In advance.

481
00:29:57,862 --> 00:30:01,537
SCOTT:
Where's Mike? Did he pass out
in the tub covered in his puke again?

482
00:30:01,699 --> 00:30:07,081
Yeah, probably. But not here.
He went home with that, uh,
Nikki girl.

483
00:30:07,238 --> 00:30:08,376
He hasn't resurfaced.

484
00:30:08,540 --> 00:30:10,144
Did you try calling him?

485
00:30:10,642 --> 00:30:13,282
Dude, his phone's
in the sex dead zone.

486
00:30:13,444 --> 00:30:15,549
He's miles from home.
Remember?

487
00:30:15,713 --> 00:30:18,319
It's not gonna be on
until we get back to Phoenix.

488
00:30:18,483 --> 00:30:20,224
MIKE: You've reached Mike.
Voice mail.

489
00:30:20,385 --> 00:30:23,457
I'm in Vegas. Leave me alone!
Hey, Mikey, it's Scott.

490
00:30:23,621 --> 00:30:26,227
Turn your phone on, man.
We're looking for you.

491
00:30:26,925 --> 00:30:30,873
I wouldn't worry too much
about Mike. He knows
what time our flight is.

492
00:30:31,029 --> 00:30:35,705
It's the spell of Vegas, man.
Like I said, it is pure evil.

493
00:30:35,867 --> 00:30:39,576
Looks like Mikey was
getting the bachelor party
you were supposed to.

494
00:30:39,737 --> 00:30:41,273
SCOTT:
Yeah.

495
00:30:44,175 --> 00:30:46,678
[COUGHING]

496
00:30:48,546 --> 00:30:50,548
[♪♪♪]

497
00:30:55,320 --> 00:30:56,765
What the fuck is this?

498
00:30:56,921 --> 00:30:59,458
What the fuck did you guys
put in that champagne?

499
00:30:59,624 --> 00:31:02,127
It's got a nasty aftertaste.

500
00:31:04,395 --> 00:31:07,001
I know I ate some fucking pussy.
What is this?

501
00:31:07,165 --> 00:31:11,204
All right, I get it. I got you, Scott.
Now you got me. Ha, ha.

502
00:31:12,403 --> 00:31:14,781
Come on, guys.
What the fuck?

503
00:31:14,939 --> 00:31:17,283
Shit.
VIKTOR: Yeah.

504
00:31:17,442 --> 00:31:19,786
You are in the shit.
Who the fuck are you?

505
00:31:21,913 --> 00:31:24,484
What are you doing?
What does it look like?

506
00:31:24,649 --> 00:31:27,721
I'm not gonna die in here.
Who said anything about dying?

507
00:31:27,886 --> 00:31:30,298
Come to me, motherfucker!
What is going on?

508
00:31:30,455 --> 00:31:31,957
Come on, you motherfucker.

509
00:31:32,123 --> 00:31:34,262
Argh!
MIKE: What is he doing to him?

510
00:31:35,193 --> 00:31:36,831
Oh, my God!
Oh, my fucking God!

511
00:31:36,995 --> 00:31:38,406
Get the fuck away from me!

512
00:31:38,563 --> 00:31:41,669
Scott! Justin!
What the fuck is going on?

513
00:31:41,833 --> 00:31:43,676
There's our snaky
motherfucker!

514
00:31:43,835 --> 00:31:46,543
MIKE:
Oh, my fucking God. Get the--

515
00:31:46,771 --> 00:31:48,773
[BOTH GRUNTING]

516
00:31:50,241 --> 00:31:52,016
GUARD 1: I like when they fight.
GUARD 2: Yeah.

517
00:31:52,543 --> 00:31:55,251
MIKE:
Fucking son of a fucking bitch!

518
00:31:57,215 --> 00:31:58,785
Get the fuck off of me!

519
00:31:58,950 --> 00:32:00,429
Fucking piece of shit!

520
00:32:00,585 --> 00:32:02,622
Is this a fucking joke?
What the fuck?

521
00:32:02,787 --> 00:32:04,528
Fuck you!

522
00:32:05,323 --> 00:32:08,793
MIKE:
Please. I didn't do anything.
This is a mistake.

523
00:32:08,960 --> 00:32:09,995
Guys, please!

524
00:32:10,161 --> 00:32:13,005
My name is Mike Malloy
from Arizona. Let me go.

525
00:32:13,164 --> 00:32:15,041
Shut your mouth.
Take it like a man.

526
00:32:15,700 --> 00:32:17,577
Fucking asshole.
Fucking Jes--

527
00:32:17,735 --> 00:32:20,579
Let me the fuck out of here.
Who the fuck are you?

528
00:32:20,738 --> 00:32:23,776
Who the fuck are you?
Get the fuck off of me!

529
00:32:23,942 --> 00:32:25,853
No, no! Aah!

530
00:32:27,111 --> 00:32:28,488
[SOBBING]

531
00:32:28,913 --> 00:32:31,018
This is fucking bad.

532
00:32:34,819 --> 00:32:38,824
Please. Plea-- Fucking please.

533
00:32:42,694 --> 00:32:45,197
What the fuck?
What the fuck are you doing?

534
00:32:45,363 --> 00:32:47,843
Is this a fucking joke?
Oh, yeah.

535
00:32:47,999 --> 00:32:49,808
And the punch line
is a killer.

536
00:32:51,002 --> 00:32:53,778
My friends have money.
We have money. We can pay you.

537
00:32:53,938 --> 00:32:56,544
We can pay you.
You've already been paid for.

538
00:32:56,808 --> 00:32:57,912
[CHUCKLES]

539
00:32:58,209 --> 00:33:00,450
What the fuck is he
talking about? What?

540
00:33:00,611 --> 00:33:04,218
What do you mean "paid for"?
What the fuck is going on?

541
00:33:05,216 --> 00:33:06,251
[WHIRRING]

542
00:33:08,519 --> 00:33:10,521
[♪♪♪]

543
00:33:12,957 --> 00:33:14,561
Who the fuck are these people?

544
00:33:15,326 --> 00:33:17,806
No!

545
00:33:17,962 --> 00:33:19,441
[SCREAMING]

546
00:33:23,868 --> 00:33:27,509
MIKE:
What the fuck is going--?
What the fuck is going--?

547
00:33:34,379 --> 00:33:35,414
[MIKE SCREAMS]

548
00:33:40,151 --> 00:33:42,654
Who the fuck are you people?

549
00:34:02,974 --> 00:34:04,612
[MIKE SCREAMING]

550
00:34:10,081 --> 00:34:11,583
[GRUNTING]

551
00:34:24,529 --> 00:34:25,564
[SCREAMS]

552
00:34:36,974 --> 00:34:38,317
MIKE:
What are you doing?

553
00:34:38,476 --> 00:34:40,649
Oh, my God.
What the fuck are you doing?

554
00:34:41,546 --> 00:34:44,789
No, no. Get the fuck away from me.
Get the fuck--

555
00:34:45,216 --> 00:34:47,719
No, stop.

556
00:34:47,885 --> 00:34:50,263
Stop. What the fuck are you doing?

557
00:34:58,763 --> 00:34:59,798
Stop.

558
00:35:11,509 --> 00:35:12,954
[GRUNTING]

559
00:35:19,951 --> 00:35:21,021
Oh, fuck.

560
00:35:21,419 --> 00:35:24,298
No. What the fuck
are you doing?

561
00:35:24,522 --> 00:35:26,798
Please, don't let me--

562
00:35:30,561 --> 00:35:32,097
Please.

563
00:35:32,463 --> 00:35:33,703
[GASPS]

564
00:35:37,068 --> 00:35:38,604
Please, stop.

565
00:35:38,769 --> 00:35:40,749
Stop! Stop!

566
00:35:41,239 --> 00:35:42,843
Stop.

567
00:35:43,241 --> 00:35:44,515
What is wrong with you?

568
00:35:44,675 --> 00:35:46,245
This is a fucking mistake!

569
00:35:46,410 --> 00:35:50,085
Please, stop.
Please don't. Please.

570
00:35:50,248 --> 00:35:52,990
What are you doing?

571
00:35:55,219 --> 00:35:57,028
[MIKE GRUNTING]

572
00:35:57,989 --> 00:35:59,525
Please. Please.

573
00:35:59,690 --> 00:36:02,728
I have a wife.
I have a daughter, a son.
They're 6 and 4.

574
00:36:02,894 --> 00:36:06,341
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERS]:
Begging for family.
One minute, 58 seconds.

575
00:36:06,497 --> 00:36:07,999
The over-under was two minutes.

576
00:36:08,166 --> 00:36:10,612
Congratulations
to players two, five and seven.

577
00:36:10,768 --> 00:36:14,614
What the fuck is she talking about?
What the fuck is going on?

578
00:36:14,772 --> 00:36:16,945
I don't understand!

579
00:36:17,942 --> 00:36:19,182
What the fuck is this?

580
00:36:19,343 --> 00:36:21,289
This has to be a fucking joke. No!

581
00:36:21,445 --> 00:36:23,152
[MUFFLED GRUNTING]

582
00:36:27,952 --> 00:36:29,954
[♪♪♪]

583
00:36:32,423 --> 00:36:34,767
[MIKE SOBBING]

584
00:36:42,333 --> 00:36:43,641
No, please, don't.

585
00:36:46,571 --> 00:36:48,482
[SOBBING]

586
00:36:58,382 --> 00:37:00,293
[SCREAMING]

587
00:37:06,591 --> 00:37:07,934
Help me, please.

588
00:37:11,095 --> 00:37:12,972
[MIKE SOBBING]

589
00:37:28,946 --> 00:37:31,449
[SCREAMING]

590
00:37:40,958 --> 00:37:42,835
[MIKE SCREAMING]

591
00:37:45,930 --> 00:37:47,807
[SCREAMING]

592
00:38:14,659 --> 00:38:17,936
[SCREAMING]

593
00:38:20,498 --> 00:38:22,671
[CROWD APPLAUDING]

594
00:38:31,575 --> 00:38:33,521
[SCREAMING]

595
00:38:37,948 --> 00:38:38,682
Hey, Mike,
we're still looking for you.

596
00:38:38,683 --> 00:38:39,957
Hey, Mike,
we're still looking for you.

597
00:38:40,117 --> 00:38:42,996
We're starting to freak out
a little bit. Call us back.

598
00:38:44,722 --> 00:38:46,292
Maybe we should
call his wife.

599
00:38:46,457 --> 00:38:48,334
That sounds like
a very good idea.

600
00:38:48,492 --> 00:38:51,473
"Have you seen Mike?
We left him at a party
last night

601
00:38:51,629 --> 00:38:54,838
with a professional escort
and he disappeared."
Good idea.

602
00:38:54,999 --> 00:38:56,342
What do you suggest?

603
00:38:56,500 --> 00:39:00,539
He was probably up
all night dicking that girl.
Give him a couple of hours.

604
00:39:00,705 --> 00:39:03,242
We're just worried about him.
Well, I'm not.

605
00:39:03,407 --> 00:39:05,614
I mean, look around, huh?

606
00:39:05,776 --> 00:39:09,019
Everywhere you look,
there are coeds and milfs

607
00:39:09,180 --> 00:39:12,457
and cougars, you know?
What are we gonna do?

608
00:39:12,616 --> 00:39:15,995
Look for him? Where?
Where did you find those girls?

609
00:39:16,187 --> 00:39:17,791
It's Vegas. It's not hard.

610
00:39:17,955 --> 00:39:20,060
Was it some kind of service
you called?

611
00:39:20,524 --> 00:39:23,562
Yeah, it was 1-800-WHORES,
man.

612
00:39:23,728 --> 00:39:25,071
I know how to find him.

613
00:39:25,696 --> 00:39:26,731
How?

614
00:39:26,897 --> 00:39:30,902
I totally forgot. That girl, Nikki,
she gave me her card.

615
00:39:31,068 --> 00:39:33,878
That's her e-mail address.
We need a street address.

616
00:39:34,038 --> 00:39:37,508
Yeah. No, it's called cyber stalking.

617
00:39:37,775 --> 00:39:39,914
I'm pretty good at it.

618
00:39:41,545 --> 00:39:43,047
JUSTIN:
Hey, Nikki, it's Justin,

619
00:39:43,214 --> 00:39:45,922
the guy with the crutch
from last night.

620
00:39:46,083 --> 00:39:49,758
We're looking for our friend.
We're wondering if you know
where he is.

621
00:39:49,920 --> 00:39:52,457
Please call me back. Thank you.

622
00:39:52,623 --> 00:39:54,603
[♪♪♪]

623
00:40:20,818 --> 00:40:22,764
[DOG GROWLING
AND BARKING]

624
00:40:23,220 --> 00:40:25,291
She definitely lives
in a trailer park.

625
00:40:25,456 --> 00:40:28,926
This is a classic
Vegas fucking fairy tale.

626
00:40:32,096 --> 00:40:35,566
What number is it?
Uh, W17.

627
00:40:36,534 --> 00:40:39,447
And where is that?
You know, I don't know, Carter.

628
00:40:39,603 --> 00:40:42,209
I don't have a white-trash
locator on my phone.

629
00:40:42,840 --> 00:40:45,047
[♪♪♪]

630
00:40:48,679 --> 00:40:50,454
[BABY CRYING NEARBY]

631
00:40:50,614 --> 00:40:52,685
CARTER:
Where is it?
Is it one of these?

632
00:40:53,684 --> 00:40:55,891
JUSTIN:
I think it's further up.

633
00:41:01,826 --> 00:41:03,703
CARTER:
Are we getting warmer?

634
00:41:05,729 --> 00:41:08,505
Is this the one?
Yeah.

635
00:41:10,000 --> 00:41:11,673
Look, I don't think anybody's here.

636
00:41:11,836 --> 00:41:12,974
[KNOCKING]

637
00:41:14,672 --> 00:41:15,707
SCOTT:
Hello?

638
00:41:16,207 --> 00:41:18,915
Nikki? Mike?

639
00:41:22,079 --> 00:41:23,752
No. Mm-mm.

640
00:41:28,252 --> 00:41:29,822
Your show, man.

641
00:41:32,756 --> 00:41:34,394
This is definitely
a bad idea.

642
00:41:35,860 --> 00:41:36,930
[BOTTLES CLATTERING]

643
00:41:37,094 --> 00:41:38,630
Okay.

644
00:41:40,064 --> 00:41:41,338
Are you coming?
Uh, no.

645
00:41:41,499 --> 00:41:45,242
I'll stay out here
and keep watch, I guess.

646
00:41:59,383 --> 00:42:01,385
God, it fucking reeks
in here.

647
00:42:01,552 --> 00:42:03,156
Mike?

648
00:42:03,821 --> 00:42:05,562
Hello?

649
00:42:17,201 --> 00:42:18,839
Jesus.

650
00:42:32,449 --> 00:42:34,486
Does it look like he's been here?

651
00:42:35,753 --> 00:42:37,027
I don't know.

652
00:42:37,187 --> 00:42:39,963
I guess it would explain
all these strap-ons, though.

653
00:42:40,124 --> 00:42:41,933
He's obviously
not here anymore.

654
00:42:42,092 --> 00:42:44,094
Let's get the fuck out of here.

655
00:42:49,433 --> 00:42:50,503
[CLATTERING]

656
00:42:50,701 --> 00:42:52,476
What the hell was that?

657
00:42:55,539 --> 00:42:56,574
SCOTT:
Justin.

658
00:42:57,708 --> 00:42:59,688
Motherfuckers, get down!

659
00:42:59,843 --> 00:43:02,323
All of you,
on your fucking knees now!

660
00:43:02,479 --> 00:43:03,822
It's me, Scott.

661
00:43:03,981 --> 00:43:06,052
I know who you are.
What are you doing here?

662
00:43:06,216 --> 00:43:09,197
We need to talk to Nikki.
So you broke into her house.

663
00:43:09,353 --> 00:43:11,924
I think this is actually a trailer.

664
00:43:12,089 --> 00:43:13,591
Shut up!

665
00:43:13,757 --> 00:43:15,202
Okay, okay! Chill, chill!

666
00:43:15,459 --> 00:43:16,733
[GUN COCKS]

667
00:43:17,294 --> 00:43:20,605
Don't fuck with us.
Why are you looking for Nikki?

668
00:43:20,764 --> 00:43:23,176
Our friend Mike
never came home last night.

669
00:43:23,334 --> 00:43:25,371
She was the last one
we saw him with.

670
00:43:25,536 --> 00:43:28,380
And you think
that he just shacked up with her.

671
00:43:28,539 --> 00:43:31,315
He's such an all-star lay,
she had to take him home.

672
00:43:31,475 --> 00:43:35,389
Kendra, look, he wouldn't
call us back. We don't know
what's going on.

673
00:43:35,546 --> 00:43:38,459
CARTER:
This is obviously a scam
to get more money out of us.

674
00:43:38,616 --> 00:43:41,222
How much do you want?
What about you, meth mouth?

675
00:43:41,385 --> 00:43:42,659
SCOTT:
Carter, shut up!

676
00:43:42,820 --> 00:43:46,597
Look, we're sorry that we broke in.
We just wanna talk to her,

677
00:43:46,757 --> 00:43:50,398
see what she knows about Mike.
You don't get it, do you?

678
00:43:50,561 --> 00:43:52,006
I can't ask her.

679
00:43:54,264 --> 00:43:56,299
Nikki didn't come home
last night.

680
00:43:56,300 --> 00:43:58,302
[♪♪♪]

681
00:43:59,637 --> 00:44:01,583
Tacky hooker.

682
00:44:02,373 --> 00:44:04,751
Too on-the-nose.

683
00:44:10,614 --> 00:44:13,424
[NIKKI GRUNTING]

684
00:44:13,617 --> 00:44:15,790
Shh. Shh, shh, shh.

685
00:44:18,188 --> 00:44:19,826
Much better.

686
00:44:20,491 --> 00:44:22,368
Aah!
Shh.

687
00:44:24,862 --> 00:44:26,466
What do you think?

688
00:44:27,331 --> 00:44:29,140
Rah, rah, rah.

689
00:44:31,802 --> 00:44:32,872
[GRUNTING]

690
00:44:33,203 --> 00:44:35,706
Shut the fuck up.

691
00:44:36,974 --> 00:44:39,580
[SOBBING]

692
00:44:39,743 --> 00:44:41,416
TRAVIS:
Get it done.

693
00:44:46,483 --> 00:44:47,894
[SNIFFING]

694
00:44:51,088 --> 00:44:52,567
[NIKKI SCREAMS]

695
00:44:58,062 --> 00:44:59,666
[DOOR OPENS]

696
00:45:01,031 --> 00:45:02,942
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]

697
00:45:15,746 --> 00:45:17,589
[MAN SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]

698
00:45:20,117 --> 00:45:21,494
[SCREAMS]

699
00:45:33,330 --> 00:45:34,900
[SCREAMS THEN SPITS]

700
00:45:38,268 --> 00:45:40,839
What the fuck are you doing?

701
00:45:41,772 --> 00:45:43,080
What are you doing?

702
00:45:43,440 --> 00:45:45,613
[SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]

703
00:45:49,713 --> 00:45:52,592
Nice and sweet, like you.

704
00:45:53,951 --> 00:45:55,259
Wh--?

705
00:45:55,719 --> 00:45:57,164
Help.

706
00:45:57,855 --> 00:45:59,857
[SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]

707
00:46:03,827 --> 00:46:04,999
[NIKKI SCREAMS]

708
00:46:05,162 --> 00:46:07,164
[♪♪♪]

709
00:46:12,069 --> 00:46:13,844
Help!

710
00:46:17,174 --> 00:46:18,983
Come, mama.

711
00:46:19,176 --> 00:46:21,520
Help me!

712
00:46:26,884 --> 00:46:29,125
What are you doing
with that?

713
00:46:32,689 --> 00:46:34,293
[SCREAMS]

714
00:46:35,259 --> 00:46:37,136
No!

715
00:46:37,294 --> 00:46:39,001
Please. Help!

716
00:46:39,563 --> 00:46:40,769
[SCREAMS]

717
00:46:47,571 --> 00:46:49,380
[SPEAKING IN
FOREIGN LANGUAGE]

718
00:47:00,350 --> 00:47:03,263
NIKKI:
No. No.

719
00:47:06,657 --> 00:47:09,137
What are you gonna do with that?

720
00:47:09,827 --> 00:47:11,204
What are you doing?

721
00:47:16,066 --> 00:47:18,569
What are you gonna do?

722
00:47:29,847 --> 00:47:32,191
[SCREAMING]

723
00:47:37,955 --> 00:47:39,992
Stop it!

724
00:47:40,557 --> 00:47:42,696
[SCREAMING]

725
00:47:44,995 --> 00:47:46,531
[SCREAMING]

726
00:47:47,664 --> 00:47:49,371
[GAGGING]

727
00:48:06,316 --> 00:48:09,820
How do I know
your friend didn't hurt her?

728
00:48:09,987 --> 00:48:13,491
Because I know Mike.
He wouldn't hurt anybody.

729
00:48:14,691 --> 00:48:17,001
You know what this town
taught me?

730
00:48:17,995 --> 00:48:19,736
Nobody knows anybody.

731
00:48:19,897 --> 00:48:21,808
[♪♪♪]

732
00:48:22,266 --> 00:48:26,237
What happens in Vegas
stays in Vegas, right?

733
00:48:26,670 --> 00:48:28,581
There's always
that one son of a bitch

734
00:48:28,739 --> 00:48:32,118
who doesn't realize
that this is all for show.

735
00:48:32,976 --> 00:48:34,421
It's not real.

736
00:48:37,347 --> 00:48:39,850
I've been saying that all along.

737
00:48:40,484 --> 00:48:42,828
Um, how are we gonna
find them?

738
00:48:42,986 --> 00:48:47,128
We're gonna go back to the club.
Start at the beginning,
retrace their steps.

739
00:48:47,291 --> 00:48:49,965
No. I think we should call the cops.
KENDRA: No.

740
00:48:50,127 --> 00:48:52,505
People disappear
off the Strip every night.

741
00:48:52,663 --> 00:48:56,440
Police don't consider it
a missing person till
they've been gone a week.

742
00:48:56,600 --> 00:48:59,274
Look, we're gonna find them.

743
00:48:59,670 --> 00:49:01,149
There's no "we" here.

744
00:49:05,475 --> 00:49:07,580
I just wanna find my friend.

745
00:49:12,849 --> 00:49:14,192
Ooh.

746
00:49:15,152 --> 00:49:17,325
You're still fucking hot.

747
00:49:20,324 --> 00:49:23,237
You are dead fucking sexy.

748
00:49:25,495 --> 00:49:27,338
Oh, shit.

749
00:49:27,497 --> 00:49:29,568
Nasty little bitch.

750
00:49:32,469 --> 00:49:33,539
[SIGHS]

751
00:49:49,820 --> 00:49:52,858
Say "deep throat."

752
00:49:53,490 --> 00:49:54,560
[CAMERA CLICKS]

753
00:49:56,026 --> 00:49:58,006
That's good.
That's really good, babe.

754
00:49:58,161 --> 00:50:00,471
That's nice work.
What do you think?

755
00:50:00,630 --> 00:50:03,406
Hm? Don't you think?
Yeah, me too.

756
00:50:05,402 --> 00:50:06,881
I'll see you.

757
00:50:07,371 --> 00:50:09,874
[♪♪♪]

758
00:50:33,063 --> 00:50:34,201
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]

759
00:50:34,364 --> 00:50:35,672
JUSTIN:
Oh. Whoa, whoa, whoa.

760
00:50:35,832 --> 00:50:37,038
Guys, guys. Hey.

761
00:50:37,200 --> 00:50:40,113
I got a text from Mike.
SCOTT: What is he saying?

762
00:50:40,937 --> 00:50:44,908
Uh, he says,
"Sorry to disappear on you.
Crashed all day."

763
00:50:45,075 --> 00:50:46,611
Where is he?
VVhere's Nikki?

764
00:50:46,777 --> 00:50:48,120
Hold on, I'm asking.

765
00:50:48,278 --> 00:50:50,918
Where are you?

766
00:50:55,719 --> 00:50:56,754
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]

767
00:50:56,920 --> 00:50:59,526
Ah. "I'm with Nikki.

768
00:50:59,689 --> 00:51:02,499
She's sleeping.
Battery dying."

769
00:51:02,659 --> 00:51:04,138
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]

770
00:51:04,561 --> 00:51:06,302
Mm. Check it out.

771
00:51:09,032 --> 00:51:10,773
God, Nikki,
what did you do?

772
00:51:10,934 --> 00:51:12,242
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]

773
00:51:12,803 --> 00:51:13,838
Hey, wait.

774
00:51:14,004 --> 00:51:16,450
"Meet me here.
Room 9, ASAP."

775
00:51:16,606 --> 00:51:20,053
Do you know where that is?
Fremont district.

776
00:51:20,277 --> 00:51:22,518
Okay, well,
let's go kick his ass.

777
00:51:22,679 --> 00:51:24,625
I'm gonna fucking kill him.

778
00:51:24,781 --> 00:51:26,954
[♪♪♪]

779
00:51:35,559 --> 00:51:38,062
[♪♪♪]

780
00:51:58,048 --> 00:51:59,527
Are you coming, gimpy?

781
00:51:59,683 --> 00:52:02,562
I think I'm gonna save myself
for the Special Olympics.

782
00:52:02,719 --> 00:52:03,891
My leg's killing me.

783
00:52:04,054 --> 00:52:06,534
Go get that asshole
and let's get out of here.

784
00:52:08,625 --> 00:52:10,969
[♪♪♪]

785
00:52:43,393 --> 00:52:44,701
Hey, Mikey.

786
00:52:44,861 --> 00:52:46,772
Mike, are you in there or what?

787
00:52:47,764 --> 00:52:49,266
Mikey?

788
00:52:49,466 --> 00:52:50,945
KENDRA:
Nikki?

789
00:52:52,169 --> 00:52:56,311
Well, at least we
know they were here.
This is Nikki's purse.

790
00:52:56,473 --> 00:52:57,713
[SCOTT SIGHS]

791
00:52:57,874 --> 00:52:59,876
What the hell is he up to?

792
00:53:00,877 --> 00:53:02,652
Here's his phone.

793
00:53:03,113 --> 00:53:04,786
And a note.

794
00:53:05,448 --> 00:53:07,928
"Guys, we stepped out.
Have a beer and chill."

795
00:53:08,084 --> 00:53:10,530
At least we know
he hasn't lost his manners.

796
00:53:13,123 --> 00:53:14,864
Hey, Mikey?

797
00:53:23,366 --> 00:53:25,312
SCOTT:
So should we just
wait here for them?

798
00:53:25,468 --> 00:53:27,141
KENDRA:
What if they don't come back?

799
00:53:27,304 --> 00:53:29,284
SCOTT:
I'm sorry this all got so fucked up.

800
00:53:29,439 --> 00:53:32,545
As much as I'd love to have
a moment, I'm just--

801
00:53:33,009 --> 00:53:34,420
CARTER:
Oh, fuck.

802
00:53:36,246 --> 00:53:37,554
What the fuck? Go, go.

803
00:53:37,948 --> 00:53:39,484
KENDRA:
No!

804
00:53:40,884 --> 00:53:42,727
[CELL PHONE BEEPING]

805
00:53:43,486 --> 00:53:44,794
[CELL PHONE CHIMES]

806
00:53:46,756 --> 00:53:48,360
[THUMPING]

807
00:53:51,828 --> 00:53:53,830
[♪♪♪]

808
00:54:15,919 --> 00:54:17,296
Hey.
Whoa. What the fuck?

809
00:54:17,454 --> 00:54:19,161
I'm sorry, man. I, uh--

810
00:54:19,322 --> 00:54:21,598
You Justin?
You scared the shit out of me.

811
00:54:21,758 --> 00:54:25,535
I know. I'm really sorry about that,
but Mike is looking for you.

812
00:54:25,695 --> 00:54:28,938
He's not in there?
He's at a bar right down the street.

813
00:54:29,099 --> 00:54:31,875
Too drunk to walk.
He asked me to come get you.

814
00:54:32,269 --> 00:54:33,304
Okay. He did?

815
00:54:33,737 --> 00:54:34,977
Yeah. Yeah.

816
00:54:35,138 --> 00:54:37,846
Okay, well, let me call him.
Cool.

817
00:54:38,008 --> 00:54:40,511
Oh, one more thing.
What--? Ow! Oh, fuck!

818
00:54:40,677 --> 00:54:43,021
[♪♪♪]

819
00:54:51,721 --> 00:54:54,895
Bet you thought that was
fucking hilarious, didn't you?

820
00:55:27,390 --> 00:55:29,836
Look, you motherfuckers
are making a mistake!

821
00:55:30,760 --> 00:55:34,936
Huh? You're making
a fucking mistake!
You know that, don't you?

822
00:55:35,332 --> 00:55:37,778
You have no fucking idea
what you're doing!

823
00:55:37,934 --> 00:55:40,380
Big fucking mistake!

824
00:55:41,071 --> 00:55:43,847
That's what they all say.
CARTER: Suck my dick, you faggot.

825
00:55:44,007 --> 00:55:45,714
SCOTT:
Where the fuck are we?

826
00:55:46,309 --> 00:55:47,879
Who's doing this to us?

827
00:55:48,278 --> 00:55:50,258
You're gonna meet them
soon enough.

828
00:55:50,413 --> 00:55:52,654
When it's your turn,
they'll come for you.

829
00:55:52,816 --> 00:55:54,818
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]

830
00:55:56,152 --> 00:55:57,859
Come here, you motherfuckers!

831
00:55:58,021 --> 00:55:59,295
CARTER:
Hey! Hey!

832
00:55:59,456 --> 00:56:00,526
Fucking tough guys!

833
00:56:00,690 --> 00:56:02,465
Come over here!

834
00:56:02,759 --> 00:56:03,863
Where is Anka?

835
00:56:05,929 --> 00:56:09,240
JUSTIN:
I don't know what's going on.
I don't-- Hey, no! No!

836
00:56:10,033 --> 00:56:12,172
No.
CARTER: Shit! Justin, Justin! Justin!

837
00:56:12,335 --> 00:56:13,871
JUSTIN:
Why are they doing this to me?

838
00:56:14,037 --> 00:56:15,573
SCOTT:
What is going on here?

839
00:56:15,739 --> 00:56:17,082
Where are you taking him?

840
00:56:17,607 --> 00:56:18,745
That was your friend?

841
00:56:19,142 --> 00:56:20,951
That was my friend. Who are you?

842
00:56:21,111 --> 00:56:23,284
You should've said
goodbye to him, then.

843
00:56:25,548 --> 00:56:26,754
CARTER:
Hey! Hey!

844
00:56:26,916 --> 00:56:28,725
Hey, you motherfucker, stop.

845
00:56:28,885 --> 00:56:29,920
Stop. Come here.

846
00:56:30,086 --> 00:56:33,363
GUARD: Wait your turn, ése.
Yeah, it's my fucking turn right now.

847
00:56:36,626 --> 00:56:37,661
What is that?

848
00:56:37,827 --> 00:56:39,704
GUARD:
Shit, why didn't you say something?

849
00:56:39,863 --> 00:56:41,570
Come on. Hurry up, let's go.

850
00:56:41,731 --> 00:56:42,903
Back up.
No.

851
00:56:43,600 --> 00:56:45,011
[GRUNTS]

852
00:56:46,269 --> 00:56:49,341
Carter, what the fuck
is going on? What is
that all about?

853
00:56:49,506 --> 00:56:51,008
It's Elite Hunting Club.

854
00:56:51,708 --> 00:56:53,244
What the fuck does that mean?

855
00:56:53,643 --> 00:56:55,645
It means members only.

856
00:56:57,147 --> 00:56:59,684
SCOTT:
What are you talking about?
Where are you going?

857
00:56:59,849 --> 00:57:01,886
Where the fuck are you going?

858
00:57:02,051 --> 00:57:03,826
You can't leave me in here!

859
00:57:04,521 --> 00:57:06,000
Carter!

860
00:57:06,756 --> 00:57:08,292
Carter!

861
00:57:12,695 --> 00:57:14,697
[♪♪♪]

862
00:57:40,590 --> 00:57:42,729
Get Mr. McMullin
his Jack and Coke.

863
00:57:46,663 --> 00:57:48,233
You can hold the Coke.

864
00:57:50,700 --> 00:57:53,977
Accept my apologies
for any inconvenience.

865
00:57:54,137 --> 00:57:56,549
Inconvenience?
That's what you call that?

866
00:57:56,706 --> 00:57:59,653
Those guys were gonna
drag me away like a piece of meat.

867
00:58:03,246 --> 00:58:06,489
It must have been
a unique sensation for you.

868
00:58:09,385 --> 00:58:11,592
I'm glad to see you're enjoying this.

869
00:58:11,754 --> 00:58:13,529
FLEMMING:
We are professionals.

870
00:58:13,957 --> 00:58:17,268
There's a reason we kidnap
people who won't be missed.

871
00:58:18,094 --> 00:58:23,066
Your special request has caused
more than a few inconveniences.

872
00:58:23,233 --> 00:58:24,712
CARTER:
That was never my intention.

873
00:58:25,602 --> 00:58:27,548
You know that. I'm a good client.

874
00:58:27,971 --> 00:58:29,575
Top-tier client.

875
00:58:29,739 --> 00:58:33,516
Which is why I entertained the idea
in the first place.

876
00:58:34,644 --> 00:58:38,251
Well, let's just agree that mistakes
were made on both sides.

877
00:58:38,414 --> 00:58:40,155
How do we move on?

878
00:58:44,053 --> 00:58:48,331
The females will make up
for the added expense.

879
00:58:53,496 --> 00:58:54,702
And the others?

880
00:58:55,265 --> 00:58:57,108
Your friends?

881
00:58:59,202 --> 00:59:00,738
Collateral damage.

882
00:59:04,707 --> 00:59:07,210
Do you have a problem with that?

883
00:59:08,311 --> 00:59:10,655
If you do,
I could call the home office.

884
00:59:10,813 --> 00:59:13,089
They don't like to hear
about problems.

885
00:59:18,922 --> 00:59:21,334
They were always more
his friends than mine.

886
00:59:23,993 --> 00:59:25,631
So are we good?

887
00:59:31,868 --> 00:59:33,472
Drink up.

888
01:00:05,268 --> 01:00:07,270
[♪♪♪]

889
01:01:38,961 --> 01:01:40,235
[ARROW FIRES]

890
01:01:40,396 --> 01:01:42,239
[JUSTIN GRUNTING]

891
01:02:16,399 --> 01:02:17,673
[ARROW FIRES]

892
01:02:23,506 --> 01:02:25,508
[GRUNTING]

893
01:02:28,611 --> 01:02:29,919
[ARROW FIRES]

894
01:02:36,052 --> 01:02:37,554
[COUGHING]

895
01:02:52,368 --> 01:02:54,314
[GROANING]

896
01:03:05,014 --> 01:03:07,551
It's okay. It's okay.

897
01:03:09,752 --> 01:03:11,197
It's okay. It's okay.

898
01:03:13,122 --> 01:03:14,692
It's okay.

899
01:03:14,891 --> 01:03:17,633
[PANTING]

900
01:03:29,138 --> 01:03:31,243
[CROWD CHEERING]

901
01:03:31,841 --> 01:03:35,220
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERS]:
That was a total of nine arrows
until termination.

902
01:03:35,378 --> 01:03:38,882
Congratulations
to players five and 11.

903
01:03:46,389 --> 01:03:47,891
TRAVIS:
Showtime.

904
01:03:50,593 --> 01:03:53,495
VIKTOR:
I have big surprise for that
cattle prod motherfucker.

905
01:03:58,167 --> 01:04:00,545
What the fuck they doing
to her?

906
01:04:03,806 --> 01:04:05,752
They took my woman.

907
01:04:06,742 --> 01:04:08,619
[VIKTOR CRYING]

908
01:04:08,811 --> 01:04:10,290
They took my Anka.

909
01:04:11,080 --> 01:04:13,117
These fucking people.

910
01:04:13,282 --> 01:04:15,489
Who knows
what they're doing to her?

911
01:04:15,651 --> 01:04:18,131
[♪♪♪]

912
01:04:18,287 --> 01:04:20,062
She was my life.

913
01:04:22,325 --> 01:04:24,430
She was my everything.

914
01:04:26,262 --> 01:04:28,139
I'm getting married next week.

915
01:04:28,865 --> 01:04:31,368
Well, at least you didn't
get married last week.

916
01:04:33,269 --> 01:04:34,714
And why is that?

917
01:04:35,638 --> 01:04:38,209
Because your woman
would be a widow now.

918
01:04:39,175 --> 01:04:41,917
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]

919
01:04:58,160 --> 01:04:59,639
GUARD:
Let's go, pretty boy.

920
01:05:01,330 --> 01:05:02,502
Fuck you.

921
01:05:02,665 --> 01:05:05,646
GUARD:
Oh, that wasn't a request.

922
01:05:05,801 --> 01:05:07,371
[SCOTT YELLING]

923
01:05:07,536 --> 01:05:08,571
Okay!

924
01:05:08,738 --> 01:05:09,773
Scott!

925
01:05:09,939 --> 01:05:12,351
Okay, okay!

926
01:05:12,742 --> 01:05:15,018
KENDRA:
Where the fuck
are you taking him?

927
01:05:15,177 --> 01:05:16,656
Fuck.

928
01:05:17,613 --> 01:05:19,092
[GUARD GRUNTING]

929
01:05:19,415 --> 01:05:23,124
Come on, pretty boy.
It's just a fucking jacket.

930
01:05:24,453 --> 01:05:27,059
SCOTT:
All right, all right, all right.

931
01:05:28,591 --> 01:05:29,626
That's a nice tux.

932
01:05:30,393 --> 01:05:32,930
Don't bother returning it.
Enjoy your honeymoon.

933
01:05:36,198 --> 01:05:37,643
[WHIRRING]

934
01:05:41,837 --> 01:05:44,647
[DANIEL LENZ'S "ALIENS"
PLAYING]

935
01:05:49,045 --> 01:05:50,922
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERS]:
Welcome, members,

936
01:05:51,080 --> 01:05:55,551
to the Elite Hunting Club's
main event, a very special kill.

937
01:05:55,718 --> 01:05:57,891
Enjoy the show.

938
01:06:23,646 --> 01:06:25,853
Don't get up. It's fine.
SCOTT: What?

939
01:06:27,249 --> 01:06:28,956
What is this?

940
01:06:29,418 --> 01:06:31,295
What is this, Carter?

941
01:06:33,222 --> 01:06:36,203
This? This is actually
a really fucking cheap tuxedo.

942
01:06:36,359 --> 01:06:39,932
I have this very special
custom job I was gonna
wear to the wedding.

943
01:06:40,096 --> 01:06:41,541
Okay.

944
01:06:42,631 --> 01:06:44,838
I guess now
I'll wear it to your funeral.

945
01:06:45,835 --> 01:06:47,178
What are you saying?

946
01:06:48,604 --> 01:06:53,280
CARTER: Ho, ho, ho. I didn't
think they'd be able to find it,
but they did. Recognize these?

947
01:06:53,442 --> 01:06:54,546
This is really great.

948
01:06:54,710 --> 01:06:56,587
Do you know
what these are?

949
01:06:56,746 --> 01:06:59,625
Those are the very expensive
German kitchen knives

950
01:06:59,782 --> 01:07:02,023
that Amy registered for
at Bloomie's.

951
01:07:02,518 --> 01:07:03,895
I'm glad they're here

952
01:07:04,053 --> 01:07:08,661
because I actually used a knife
very much like this one

953
01:07:08,824 --> 01:07:10,895
to kill a girl at the club in Macau.

954
01:07:11,060 --> 01:07:14,633
I skinned her alive.
It took me six hours.

955
01:07:15,364 --> 01:07:16,934
What kind of sick fuck are you?

956
01:07:17,099 --> 01:07:18,737
But the problem

957
01:07:18,901 --> 01:07:21,381
that I keep running into

958
01:07:21,771 --> 01:07:25,082
is that the rush
just isn't there anymore.

959
01:07:25,241 --> 01:07:28,984
I needed to up the ante a bit.
I needed to kill someone
who mattered.

960
01:07:30,112 --> 01:07:33,992
How are you gonna get away with it?
You can't just make me disappear!

961
01:07:34,150 --> 01:07:36,562
That's what I pay these people for.
What?

962
01:07:36,986 --> 01:07:39,125
What, to kill your
fucking friends?

963
01:07:39,288 --> 01:07:40,528
Where are Mike and Justin?

964
01:07:40,689 --> 01:07:43,397
What did you do with them?
That was actually a mistake.

965
01:07:44,493 --> 01:07:46,131
That was
a legitimate mistake.

966
01:07:46,295 --> 01:07:49,469
That Mike was in the wrong place
at exactly the right time.

967
01:07:49,632 --> 01:07:51,077
And Justin...

968
01:07:51,400 --> 01:07:54,347
The poor bastard.
He didn't deserve it.

969
01:07:56,572 --> 01:07:58,609
What, I deserve this?

970
01:07:58,941 --> 01:08:01,114
Why do I deserve this?

971
01:08:01,277 --> 01:08:03,279
[♪♪♪]

972
01:08:04,647 --> 01:08:06,854
Because you got what I want.

973
01:08:10,286 --> 01:08:11,731
Amy.

974
01:08:12,588 --> 01:08:13,999
This is all about Amy?

975
01:08:14,490 --> 01:08:17,403
I thought when she found out
that you cheated on her

976
01:08:17,693 --> 01:08:19,695
she would leave you right away.

977
01:08:20,062 --> 01:08:21,803
You told her.

978
01:08:22,932 --> 01:08:24,775
You told her. You fucking...

979
01:08:25,935 --> 01:08:29,906
Oh, she is going to be devastated
when she finds out.

980
01:08:30,072 --> 01:08:31,107
You sick fuck.

981
01:08:31,273 --> 01:08:36,154
But that's okay, I will be right there
next to her to console her.

982
01:08:36,312 --> 01:08:37,882
You sick fuck.

983
01:08:38,047 --> 01:08:41,153
You sick fuck!
And how long do you think it'll be

984
01:08:41,317 --> 01:08:43,661
before I'm fucking her?
You sick fuck!

985
01:08:43,819 --> 01:08:45,162
In your own goddamn bed.

986
01:08:45,321 --> 01:08:49,531
Don't you touch her! I'll fucking
kill you! I will fucking kill you.

987
01:08:49,692 --> 01:08:53,299
What kind of man are you, huh?
You do this to your fucking friends?

988
01:08:53,462 --> 01:08:55,874
When it comes to pussy,

989
01:08:57,233 --> 01:08:58,644
I have no friends.

990
01:09:00,302 --> 01:09:01,747
[CHAIN SAW BUZZING]

991
01:09:02,071 --> 01:09:03,812
CARTER:
You motherfuckers want a show?

992
01:09:03,973 --> 01:09:06,476
I'll give you a fucking show.
Go ahead.

993
01:09:07,243 --> 01:09:08,688
CARTER:
Yeah!

994
01:09:10,980 --> 01:09:12,313
Let him go.

995
01:09:12,515 --> 01:09:14,495
[CHAIN SAW REVVING]

996
01:09:20,556 --> 01:09:22,433
[CROWD CHEERING]

997
01:09:38,541 --> 01:09:40,111
MAN:
Yeah!

998
01:09:48,651 --> 01:09:50,289
[SCANNER BEEPING]

999
01:09:53,556 --> 01:09:55,900
[CROWD CHEERING]

1000
01:09:56,058 --> 01:09:57,799
[PANTING]

1001
01:10:00,029 --> 01:10:02,532
You motherfuckers
want a show, huh?

1002
01:10:02,698 --> 01:10:05,144
I'll give you a fucking show!

1003
01:10:06,702 --> 01:10:08,113
[GRUNTING]

1004
01:10:19,348 --> 01:10:21,555
The house always wins.

1005
01:10:22,685 --> 01:10:26,633
WOMAN [OVER SPEAKERS]:
The honeymoon isn't quite over yet,
Elite Hunting Club members.

1006
01:10:26,789 --> 01:10:29,429
Now, who wants to bid
on killing the groom?

1007
01:10:29,692 --> 01:10:30,727
[BEEPS]

1008
01:10:33,629 --> 01:10:34,972
[DOOR OPENS]

1009
01:10:39,902 --> 01:10:41,904
[♪♪♪]

1010
01:10:48,744 --> 01:10:52,123
Get me the fuck out of here,
you motherfuckers!

1011
01:10:52,281 --> 01:10:54,227
You sick fucks!

1012
01:10:54,383 --> 01:10:56,863
Come on!
Come to me, you motherfucker.

1013
01:10:57,019 --> 01:10:59,966
Shut your mouth or I'll fuck you up!
Come to me.

1014
01:11:00,823 --> 01:11:02,928
My turn now!
You motherfucker!

1015
01:11:03,092 --> 01:11:04,469
Give me that!

1016
01:11:04,627 --> 01:11:06,231
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]

1017
01:11:07,730 --> 01:11:10,836
Huh? Oh, I'm so fucking happy.

1018
01:11:14,570 --> 01:11:16,641
You die, tough guy. It's your turn.

1019
01:11:16,805 --> 01:11:17,840
[GRUNTING]

1020
01:11:18,540 --> 01:11:21,043
Die, motherfucker!
Die, you piece of shit!

1021
01:11:23,646 --> 01:11:25,319
You motherfucker!

1022
01:11:26,482 --> 01:11:28,484
You fucking die.

1023
01:11:29,818 --> 01:11:31,798
Now I fuck your mother, okay?

1024
01:11:41,497 --> 01:11:43,238
Fuck!

1025
01:11:43,465 --> 01:11:44,569
[GUNSHOTS]

1026
01:11:48,637 --> 01:11:49,672
MAN 1 [ON TV]:
No!

1027
01:11:51,307 --> 01:11:53,184
Die, motherfucker!

1028
01:11:53,342 --> 01:11:55,379
Take that, you fucking bitch!

1029
01:11:55,544 --> 01:11:56,921
Come on, motherfuckers!

1030
01:11:57,079 --> 01:11:59,889
MAN 2 [OVER PHONE]:
I repeat, we have two escaped
prisoners on the loose.

1031
01:12:00,049 --> 01:12:01,460
Okay.

1032
01:12:03,052 --> 01:12:06,659
Sir. Sir, we have two
on the loose.

1033
01:12:07,990 --> 01:12:10,869
Have security round them up.
Yes, sir.

1034
01:12:11,327 --> 01:12:12,931
Sound the alarm.

1035
01:12:13,095 --> 01:12:15,097
[♪♪♪]

1036
01:12:18,901 --> 01:12:20,972
[ALARM BLARING]

1037
01:12:48,497 --> 01:12:50,170
Oh, my God.

1038
01:12:50,332 --> 01:12:52,209
Jesus Christ.

1039
01:12:54,603 --> 01:12:56,014
Oh, God.

1040
01:12:57,873 --> 01:12:59,978
Oh, please.
Please, please, please.

1041
01:13:00,142 --> 01:13:02,713
Come on. Come on.

1042
01:13:03,011 --> 01:13:04,615
Come on, come on, come on.

1043
01:13:12,721 --> 01:13:14,064
Fuck!

1044
01:13:19,328 --> 01:13:22,901
[AX CLANGING]

1045
01:13:23,699 --> 01:13:26,976
That mother--
Fucking shit!

1046
01:13:37,646 --> 01:13:39,182
Shit!

1047
01:13:39,748 --> 01:13:40,852
Come on.

1048
01:13:41,016 --> 01:13:42,586
Come on. Come on.

1049
01:14:02,438 --> 01:14:04,247
Aah!

1050
01:14:06,108 --> 01:14:07,610
[GUNSHOT]

1051
01:14:10,813 --> 01:14:11,848
[GRUNTING]

1052
01:14:21,123 --> 01:14:23,125
[♪♪♪]

1053
01:14:24,860 --> 01:14:27,534
Oh, yes. Yes. Oh, God, please.

1054
01:14:27,963 --> 01:14:30,239
Oh, God. Oh, God.

1055
01:14:30,899 --> 01:14:32,344
Please, please, please.

1056
01:14:32,501 --> 01:14:34,378
Oh, God, please.

1057
01:14:35,137 --> 01:14:37,048
OPERATOR:
911 operator,
what is your emergency?

1058
01:14:37,206 --> 01:14:39,345
Yes, I need help.
They're killing people.

1059
01:14:39,508 --> 01:14:41,044
What is your location, sir?

1060
01:14:41,210 --> 01:14:43,087
Look, I don't know where I am.

1061
01:14:43,245 --> 01:14:45,282
That's okay, sir.
Oh, wait, wait.

1062
01:14:45,447 --> 01:14:48,087
Please wait.
Stay on the line. Stay calm.

1063
01:14:48,250 --> 01:14:51,094
They've killed my friends.
Killed your friends.

1064
01:14:51,253 --> 01:14:52,857
Hurry.
They're gonna kill me.

1065
01:15:05,367 --> 01:15:08,246
Remain calm, sir.
Stay on the line.

1066
01:15:08,403 --> 01:15:10,405
I see dead people.

1067
01:15:10,572 --> 01:15:12,415
We've got a point of location.

1068
01:15:12,574 --> 01:15:15,054
The police are on their way.

1069
01:15:17,312 --> 01:15:18,950
Fuck!

1070
01:15:20,148 --> 01:15:25,097
FLEMMING:
My friends, please, keep your seats.

1071
01:15:25,254 --> 01:15:29,725
We are experiencing
a temporary power interruption.

1072
01:15:29,892 --> 01:15:31,235
As a safety precaution,

1073
01:15:31,393 --> 01:15:33,737
you will be escorted
to your vehicles.

1074
01:15:34,963 --> 01:15:36,442
[BEEPING]

1075
01:15:39,334 --> 01:15:41,678
Yeah. Tennessee tuxedo
called the cops.

1076
01:15:41,837 --> 01:15:43,043
We've been compromised.

1077
01:15:43,539 --> 01:15:45,576
That's it, we're shutting down.

1078
01:15:45,741 --> 01:15:46,913
Kill the prisoners?

1079
01:15:51,880 --> 01:15:53,120
Kill them all.

1080
01:15:53,282 --> 01:15:54,556
No witnesses.

1081
01:15:54,716 --> 01:15:56,718
[♪♪♪]

1082
01:16:12,901 --> 01:16:15,177
KENDRA:
Help me, please. Please, help.

1083
01:16:17,339 --> 01:16:18,647
Please, don't! Please!

1084
01:16:18,807 --> 01:16:19,979
[GUNSHOT]

1085
01:16:22,711 --> 01:16:24,190
KENDRA:
Oh, God.

1086
01:16:24,346 --> 01:16:25,984
[♪♪♪]

1087
01:16:26,148 --> 01:16:28,526
Scott. Scott.
SCOTT: Keys.

1088
01:16:33,755 --> 01:16:35,792
Oh, God. Okay.
Get me out.

1089
01:16:35,958 --> 01:16:37,960
Hurry.
Fuck!

1090
01:16:43,131 --> 01:16:44,610
Come on, come on, come on.

1091
01:16:44,766 --> 01:16:45,972
Come on, come on.

1092
01:16:52,541 --> 01:16:54,020
[GUNSHOT]
[KENDRA SCREAMS]

1093
01:16:57,145 --> 01:16:58,818
Fuck!
Shit!

1094
01:17:00,015 --> 01:17:01,392
Only one way out of here,
motherfucker.

1095
01:17:01,550 --> 01:17:02,824
[GUNSHOTS]

1096
01:17:15,197 --> 01:17:17,507
CARTER:
Why the hurry, huh?

1097
01:17:17,666 --> 01:17:19,839
The place is gonna blow.
Yeah?

1098
01:17:24,206 --> 01:17:26,311
[GRUNTING]

1099
01:17:27,609 --> 01:17:28,849
[CARTER SCREAMING]

1100
01:17:33,649 --> 01:17:35,651
[ALARM WAILING AND HONKING]

1101
01:17:40,856 --> 01:17:42,267
Fuck.

1102
01:17:47,295 --> 01:17:49,036
Fuck.

1103
01:17:52,968 --> 01:17:54,572
Oh, Jesus.

1104
01:17:54,736 --> 01:17:56,545
Fuck.

1105
01:18:01,009 --> 01:18:02,955
Oh, fuck.

1106
01:18:04,680 --> 01:18:05,715
[GUN CLICKING]

1107
01:18:08,684 --> 01:18:09,958
Okay.

1108
01:18:10,686 --> 01:18:12,927
[TRAVIS SCREAMING]

1109
01:18:19,461 --> 01:18:21,270
TRAVIS:
Fuck you!

1110
01:18:21,897 --> 01:18:23,308
Die!

1111
01:18:42,718 --> 01:18:45,255
[TRAVIS SCREAMING]

1112
01:18:52,294 --> 01:18:55,241
[SCREAMING]

1113
01:19:15,817 --> 01:19:17,819
[TRAVIS SCREAMING]

1114
01:19:39,608 --> 01:19:41,053
[TIRES SCREECHING]

1115
01:19:47,149 --> 01:19:49,116
Fuck you.

1116
01:19:49,551 --> 01:19:51,462
[♪♪♪]

1117
01:20:27,455 --> 01:20:29,196
No! Wait!

1118
01:20:31,593 --> 01:20:32,936
You motherfucker!

1119
01:20:33,094 --> 01:20:36,098
You motherfucker, come here!
Come-- Wa--

1120
01:20:39,267 --> 01:20:40,746
No!

1121
01:20:44,940 --> 01:20:46,112
Fuck!

1122
01:20:56,051 --> 01:20:58,053
[♪♪♪]

1123
01:21:00,121 --> 01:21:03,159
[EXPLOSIONS IN DISTANCE]

1124
01:21:13,602 --> 01:21:15,980
AMY:
I can't believe he's gone.

1125
01:21:20,242 --> 01:21:23,348
I just-- I feel like none of this
would have happened

1126
01:21:23,511 --> 01:21:25,923
if I hadn't take him
to Vegas.

1127
01:21:26,081 --> 01:21:28,027
Don't talk like that.

1128
01:21:28,183 --> 01:21:31,426
Hell, at least, you survived.

1129
01:21:34,022 --> 01:21:35,296
[SIGHS]

1130
01:21:37,525 --> 01:21:39,004
It's okay.

1131
01:21:39,728 --> 01:21:41,435
You can cry.

1132
01:21:48,336 --> 01:21:49,872
Carter?

1133
01:21:50,338 --> 01:21:51,817
Yeah?

1134
01:21:55,343 --> 01:21:57,653
I don't wanna be alone tonight.

1135
01:21:59,714 --> 01:22:02,354
You don't have to be, Amy.

1136
01:22:03,151 --> 01:22:04,994
I'm right here.

1137
01:22:06,221 --> 01:22:08,258
I'm not going anywhere.

1138
01:22:13,862 --> 01:22:15,739
I need a drink.

1139
01:22:16,798 --> 01:22:18,607
Would you like a drink?
Yeah.

1140
01:22:18,767 --> 01:22:20,713
I would love a drink. Yeah.

1141
01:22:21,136 --> 01:22:22,410
Okay.

1142
01:22:40,322 --> 01:22:42,893
Oh, can I help you with that?
Oh, no.

1143
01:22:43,058 --> 01:22:44,401
I got it.

1144
01:22:49,831 --> 01:22:50,901
[SIGHS]

1145
01:22:51,066 --> 01:22:52,477
Problem is...

1146
01:22:55,337 --> 01:22:56,509
he's alive.

1147
01:22:56,671 --> 01:22:57,775
[GRUNTING]

1148
01:22:58,139 --> 01:23:01,018
What do you say
we finish that bachelor party?

1149
01:23:07,649 --> 01:23:09,822
[♪♪♪]

1150
01:23:10,418 --> 01:23:11,795
[GRUNTING]

1151
01:23:35,677 --> 01:23:37,714
[CARTER SOBBING]

1152
01:23:37,946 --> 01:23:40,256
Amy, please help me.

1153
01:23:51,059 --> 01:23:52,231
[SHOUTS INDISTINCTLY]

1154
01:23:58,199 --> 01:24:00,338
[SCREAMING]

1155
01:24:02,971 --> 01:24:04,973
[CARTER SCREAMING]

1156
01:24:08,943 --> 01:24:11,719
[♪♪♪]

1157
01:27:39,153 --> 01:27:41,326
SCOTT:
The house always wins.

