SHOESHINE
- Bersagliere is the best!
- Of course, he's a great horse
As soon as I said, "Go, Bersagliere!"
he went like a rocket!
Even in America
you won't find horses like this
Nonsense. In America...
They probably feed horses a lot
over there
Boy! I've told you enough times
not to leave the horse unattended
But that's not a horse -
it's a small table!
He's always joking around.
What about the proposal?
Fifty or nothing
- But it's only 50 of 1,OOO-lira notes
- It's only paper
Yeah, whatever
We're shoeshine boys...
...so everyone thinks
we make a lot of money
Pay him and let's go
- Is it expensive to keep a horse?
- At least 300 lira a day
Bersagliere,
you're an expensive horse!
Fifty is fine, but we're a bit short now.
Can we pay you in a week?
- All right
- Promise?
- Promise
- Goodbye, Mr Anucci
- Goodbye
It's only fair. Until we buy him,
he can rent him out to anybody else
- How much have we got?
- 32 or 35... I'm not sure
I've told you, you must be precise
You're right, but this morning
I made a lot of payments
Five, ten...
I've arranged them in stacks of five
- Good
- 15, 20, 25, 30, 31, 32...
...33,5OO lira
- Plus 7,500 lira from the Genoa man
- And 3,700 from the caretaker
33,500 plus 3,700 and 7,500..
We're short by 5,300 lira
Marcello, did the stuff arrive?
No. He's been saying "Tomorrow,
tomorrow" for a week now...
...and in the meantime
he gets his shoes shined
- When you bring?
- Tomorrow
To you and your grandfather!
These pay!
Do you want these glasses?
No, they break and cannot be hidden
- And they cannot be painted
- Somebody else will buy them
Are you laughing to yourself?
- I was thinking, he eats more than us
- Who?
- The horse
- Yeah
- Shoeshine, Joe?
- Where are we going to put him?
I was thinking of taking him
to that guy at Porta San Sebastiano
He'd starve him to death
We're not stupid. After work,
we go and have him fed in front of us
But in that way
he'd only eat once a day
- Maybe I should sleep in the stable
- I'll come with you
- And your parents?
- They won't care
We'll see
For now,
let's worry about making some money
- Giuseppe!
. What's up?
Hi, Giuseppe
Shoeshine, Joe?
Then Pasquale said, "Go,
Bersagliere!", and he started off...
- Running in circles
- Don't be silly! I meant...
You're such a moron!
When are you going
to bring me chocolate?
Don't sell it, eat it!
I'm not an idiot! Thank you
Our problem is that
we're not organised
That's why the guards
steal our boxes
They've stolen two from me.
What do they do with them?
- They sell them again
- Pasquale!
- Hi, Nannarella
- Where's Giuseppe?
- Giuseppe!
- Hi
- Your Mum needs 300 lira
- I've given her 500 this morning!
- She needs it
- Can I give it to her?
Sure
Money has no value nowadays
Last year I'd give her 200 lira
and it was enough
Lucky you're alone,
you've only yourself to think of
What are you talking about?
If I still had my parents...
...I'd give them one million a day!
What do you mean?
You're not happy at ours?
- No, not at all
- Let's go now
Are you still sleeping in the lift?
No, the damned landlord found out,
so I can't go there anymore
Now I sleep with Giuseppe,
at Dante Alighieri school
It's such a mess in there!
Shoeshine, Joe?
The other day at the hotel
he gave me a chocolate pudding...
...with ice cream inside
If I'd known,
I'd have come with you
I know, but women are not allowed
- Giuseppe!
- Hi
Where's Pasquale?
He's working at Fori Imperiali
- Who's that?
- My big brother, Attilio
- He must be rich
- He can't complain
Can you take me home?
I can't leave Pasquale alone,
otherwise he doesn't do any work
- See you this evening, then. Bye
- Bye
OK, 1:00 at the San Paolo gas tank
Is it something important?
I don't waste time
It's something big
- OK, bye
- Bye
Excuse me
Where have you been?
With Nannarella. Iwalked her
across the street, with all these cars
Damn!
Careful,
or you'll stain his trousers!
What did my brother tell you?
He said that Panza
will meet me today at 1:00
Here's Pasquale
It's 1:30, you know
We were eating
- Who's this?
- My partner
- You even got a partner!
- He's my brother
Let's go
I have business for you -
two American blankets
Go to 48 Via del Babuino.
On the fourth floor there's a lady
Go there at 3:00 and you'll find her
- And?
- She'll buy the blankets
- At what price?
- Why do you want to know?
- I'm the partner
- True!
- Try to get the most
- Prices have gone down
- 2,400 or 2,500 lira at the most
- But 10% is for you
10%...
- 300 lira
- Let's do 20%
Let's say 500 and it's a deal.
Give them the blankets!
Let's go
Come on! Come on!
Go to the lady at 3:00 sharp, OK?
Don't worry, we will
Whoever invented the lift is a genius
Tell me about it.
I've slept in one for three months
Accountant Piatti Giulio
Here we are. "Margherita Donati
Anselmi, qualified fortune-teller"
Goodbye, madam and thank you
Thank you, miss
- Madam?
- What do you want?
- We have two American blankets
- I'm not interested
- How much?
- 3,500
You must be joking!
- 3,000
- Let's have a look
Follow me
- They've never been used
- So I see
- You can make a coat
- To get stopped by some American
Nobody would stop you!
You're such a fine woman,
it would suit you perfectly
- How much?
- 3,000
- And 500
- Shut up, you! 2,500
We haven't stolen them!
I won't give you more than 2,500
Let's do 2,800 and that's it
OK, I'll take them
Why did you accept?
We won't get
more than 500 lira anyway
- 2,000, 2,500..
- What game is this?
Leave those cards!
Where are your manners?
Look what you've done, blast you!
There's the postman,
the train, the funeral...
- What are they for?
- To read the future
Could you tell us
what's going to happen tomorrow?
We'll give you a bottle of milk
- It will be fresh too
- You're only kids
- Why? Kids don't have a future?
- Of course, they have
Then tell us, please
25 cards to ask, 25 devils...
What's your name?
- Giuseppe!
- Pasquale!
Cut
In the home, outside,
what awaits you and what doesn't...
...who loves you and who doesn't.
Pick a card
At home there's an old lady
who thinks about you
My mother is not that old
Stop it, or I won't read you the cards
The old lady is sad about a letter,
but everything will be sorted out
Outside there is a gentleman
protecting you
- Anucci
- But he just guards horses
Somebody's at the door.
It's a customer. Wait a moment
Are you
Mrs Margherita Donati Anselmi?
- Yes, why?
- Police
We have a search warrant
I don't understand. I am licensed
The police chief knows me. His wife
is actually one of my customers
I'm sorry, madam,
but we have to follow our orders
We've been informed
that you buy stolen goods
Me? That's not true, I swear
There they are, those two.
Take them away
We have to come inside, madam.
After you, madam
- What's going on?
- None of your business
Did you sell the blankets?
Keep the money and go
- What do you mean?
- Don't be silly, just go
Here is another 3,000 lira. Now go
You've seen nothing
and you know nothing
- What are we going to do now?
- I don't know
So, 3,000 plus 2,800
from the blankets...
It's 5,800
- Did you hear Attilio?
- We've seen nothing
- And we know nothing
- We were sleepwalking!
Let's go and buy the horse!
Wake up!
- Good morning, Bersagliere!
What a great horse!
There's none like him!
- He's almost eaten everything
- Look at his belly, it's like a drum!
He could have eaten even more.
He stuffed himself!
Hey, boys! What have you decided?
The horse stays here.
We'll pay you stabling fees...
...and we'll come here
to look after him
- Will you groom him and wash him?
- Wash him?
What? Don't you wash your face
every morning?
We'll wash him straight away.
Untie him!
Can you help me?
- There's no stirrup!
- Come on, get on him!
- Come on!
- Let's go!
- Control him well, OK?
- Don't be afraid. Hold on tight
No, no! There they are!
There they are!
- These are the two boys
- Search them
You can go now
- Here I am
- Just one moment
Yes?
We've arrested the two boys
involved in Via del Babuino burglary
- What burglary?
- At the fortune-tellefis home
Ah, yes. Let them in.
Call Losito too
Let it boil a minute over
than a minute less
There have been bad accidents
for not boiling long enough
There they are, Chief. It's them
Make them confess. They know
everything, these criminals!
Calm down, madam.
Don't get so upset
I've been robbed of 700,000 lira!
700,000 lira!
I wish I had that much!
So, why did you go
to the lady's house yesterday?
- To buy some empty bottles
- Liar! You wanted to sell me blankets
And you bought them!
Note it in the records -
she bought two American blankets
It's outrageous!
I'll end up going to prison myself
Mrs Donati Anselmi
bought two American blankets
Where did you steal them?
Look at me, boys!
Excuse me
Where did you steal those blankets?
An American friend of ours
gave them to us
What's his name?
- Joe
Ah, Joe
- What's the name of the fat one?
- Which fat one?
The one who went
to the fortune-teller yesterday
- I don't know him
- Don't play games with me
I'll jail you
and feed you bread and water
- Pasquale!
- He's joking
- You think so?
- With only bread and water, we'd die
- Tell me the truth!
- We have!
Losito, lock them up, then we'll see!
Go! Go!
I'll have to press charges
against you too, madam
I'm a honest woman, ask your wife
who's one of my good customers
Of course! I'm not surprised.
My wife has a pea brain!
- Go away, please, madam
- But, Chief...
I work
and she goes to the fortune-teller
She wants to know
when I'm going to kick the bucket
Chief? Excuse me
What are we going to do
with those two boys?
Take them to the juvenile prison
Tomorrow morning
Is this the house of the refugees?
Excuse me, the Filippucci family?
Second floor, 3 C
Excuse me,
are you the Filippucci family?
Amalia! You're wanted
- I'd like to speak to your husband
- Why?
It's business
- Vittorio! Hey!
- Damn it
- What now?
- This lady wants to speak to you
- Attilio is hereto see you
- Why?
He wants to speak to you
- Dad, they've arrested...
- Who?
Giuseppe. Don't go and get involved
otherwise I'll land in trouble
Don't worry, I won't go
Nannarella!
First, drop the others off
at Regina Coeli, then the kids
Get out
Come on, come with me
- Hi
Thank you
Let's go. No, this way
- Hi
Can I come in?
Your family has been informed.
Here...
Librasi, Angelo. Resident of Bari
But it's been three months since...
What can I do? They'll write. If they
come, I'll let you know. Go, now
Good morning.
I brought you some others
How kind of you
At this rate, they'll have to sleep
in the courtyard
"illegal sale of stolen goods...
..."accessory to burglary..."
..."to be held pending
police investigation"
- Take care
- Goodbye
- Fede?
- Yes, sir?
Book these two
Come here, you two
- What's your name?
- Maggi, Pasquale
- Your father?
- Dead
- I mean, his name
- Luigi
- Your mother?
- Maria Fabris
Living?
- Born?
- In Rome, October 29th 1931
Living at?
30, Via Lombardia
With...?
- With no one
- What? With nobody?
Nobody. I sleep in the lift
Of no fixed abode
Put your hand here and push hard
-3x4?
-12
-4x4?
-1s
-8x8?
-62
Ignorant! 8 x 8?
- 64, ignorant! 3 x 3?
- 9
- It's the director!
- Attention! Turn about!
Good, very good
Morning, Staff era. I've heard.
My condolences
- How old was he?
- 10
Your only child?
No, I have four others. But he was
the youngest and the brightest
Be strong!
Attention!
-6x9?
- s4
-7x7?
-49
-8x5?
-40
-9x3?
-27
It's the director, go inside!
- Good morning, Bartoli
- Good morning, sir
- What are you doing here?
- We're fighting against the bugs
- I'm using a product I invented
- Very good
We should disinfest the place
We'll do it, Barioli
- The boys are complaining
- They always complain
- We have some new arrivals
- As always
Who is he?
- Get up, come on. Stand to attention
- Marcello Scalari from Velletri
Accused of armed robbery.
Confessed
On his own?
No, with four adults
I have a younger sister
and two younger brothers
My father is a prisoner in Germany.
We had nothing to eat
Armed robbery! In a few days,
he'll start complaining too
Who are these?
Come forward, boys.
Come on, come on
- Who are they?
- Maggi and Filippucci
To be held pending investigation
Send them to section one
after the doctor sees them
- Yes
- I wanted to tell you...
...today we had a delegation
of parents
A delegation? Has it come to this?
Did they want to strike?
No, sir, they came to push
for the investigations
These boys have been in jail
for months
And whose fault is that?
If you read the statistics...
...you'll see that, compared to 1936,
crime has increased by 60%
- Judges are overloaded with work
- Yes, but these are only boys
Boys? Armed robbery, burglary,
pick-pocketing, procuring...
Shall we deprive them of fruit
as punishment?
- If only we had fruit!
- You must realise, Bartoli...
...that we're running ajail here
not a day-care centre
And if you forget that,
you'll remain an assistant forever
Attention!
Not bad
Passable
At ease!
As second course,
we have loin steak
Not for me. I'd like something
less heavy. I have heartburn
- Fried sweetbread and courgettes?
- Yes
- Me, too!
- And me!
- Spring lamb for me!
- Hi, Tamburini. Where's Attilio?
He didn't want to come, he's scared
Move over
- So?
- They didn't talk
I always said that those two
were good guys. Boss?
Boss? I've changed my mind. Bring
the steaks, and make them thick
Tomorrow we'll send them a parcel
of goods. They deserve it
- What did you order?
- Sweetbread and courgettes
When the boys are inside,
they have to feel good...
...otherwise they'll keep
bad memories and will be of no use
The trams are still running.
It can't be that late
- Are you hungry?
- No
- Do you think my father knows?
- Sure. Nannarella must've told him
I guess so
These must be lice. They sting
No, they're bugs
If you say so
- What's going to happen to us?
- I'm sure they'll release us soon
They can't keep us here
if we've done nothing
- Yes, but Panza...
- Shut up!
Forget that name!
We know nothing
- What about the blankets?
- It's none of our business
- It's the fortune-tellefis problem
- Hope so
I'm sure about it
These lice really sting!
It's all my stupid brother's fault
I know. But we have to keep
our mouths shut
Then maybe when we get out,
we'll reckon with him
- Will they feed him?
- Of course
Maybe not a lot,
but it's only for a few days anyway
You told Nannarella we bought him?
How? I haven't seen her since
We cannot tell anybody...
...or somebody will take him from us
I can't wait to see him again
Me, too
Mr Annibale!
What is it?
That horse is sick again
He needs to rest.
Give him water and oats
Use water and vinegar,
then we'll have to wait and see
And today of all days,
I've got a funeral
Why don't you hitch the coach
to the boys' horse?
Let's go!
Go!
Breathe. Deeper. Again
Get dressed
Here's your ticket for soup
I want a ticket for bread instead.
The soup is rubbish
Come on! You boys are
always complaining
- As if you ate well at home!
- I did. My father's a fisherman
I had gilthead, sea bass, fish soup
- Delicious!
- Go, I'll take care of the bread
The bread is better,
the soup is rubbish
Rubbish, rubbish
Ouch!
Put the bandage back on
How's the Neapolitan?
Getting worse. You can't expect him
to get better in here
I asked long ago for him
to be transferred to the hospital
At the Forlanini, the patients
are packed in like sardines
- So?
- Send him home. Why's he here?
- Vagrancy
- Better a vagrant than being dead
- Release him
- If it were up to me...
You have to be patient. Like me
Doctor, new arrivals
What, now?
Undress
I'll see the others tomorrow
Maggi, Pasquale?
- Who's Maggi, Pasquale?
- Me
- Have you been sick?
- Measles and whooping cough
And you?
I've never had whooping cough
or measles...
- ...but apparently I've had tapeworm
- You'll get rid of it in here
- Parents' statement?
- They didn't come
As usual
- Have they been to section one?
- Yes, of course
Silence!
Silence, I said!
Silence, silence!
How many of you?
Four. But Gigino counts for two
as he's sick
There has to be five in a cell,
like everybody else
- I want to stay with him!
- Forget it! Leave him!
- Bastards!
- Let's go!
Cowards!
Hello, kid!
- Rat!
- Bastard! Son of a bitch!
Silence! Understand? Shut up!
Silence! Understand?
- Silence!
- What's happening?
Silence, boys! Shut up!
- Shut up!
- What's happening?
A guard knocked around one of
the newcomers, so they're protesting
Exercise in the courtyard
is suspended until further notice!
The director will hold you responsible
for any turmoil that ensues
Exercise in the courtyard
is suspended until further notice
Yes, until further notice!
Open the shutters
When I get out of here...
...I want to smash Staff era's head,
I swear!
What are you talking about?
Pasquale!
- I'm here!
- Calm down!
- What's your name?
- Giuseppe Filippucci
- Why did they arrest you?
- I don't know nothing
You can tell us, we won't say a word
But I don't know nothing
What are you doing?
This is Arcangeli's place
If he finds you there, you're in trouble
- Where can I stay?
- Over there
Did you put your fingerprints
in the book?
- How many fingers?
- Four
What a silly little boy!
- Really stupid!
- Idiot!
- Is it bad?
- Very bad
- Four fingers mean four years in jail
- Four years! You'll rot in here!
Oh, my God!
When you want something,
you have to say the opposite
Like with your friend,
you have to say you hate him
- That's what you do with the masters
- Who?
- The guards, that's what we call them
- Why?
Who knows?
Maybe because they're "literal"
- You mean "literate", you ignoramus!
- Sorry, professor
They're masters
when it comes to stealing cigarettes
- Smoking's allowed?
- No, it's not
And because it's not allowed,
we all smoke
He's the only one who doesn't,
he has a lung disease
I'm going to go to hospital
and be cured when I get out
- Time to eat
- Time to eat, finally!
Time to eat!
Good, I'm starving.
Yesterday we only had bread...
...because we weren't booked yet
Lucky you're hungry...
...otherwise you wouldn't be able
to eat what they give us
- Take it downstairs
- You take it
- No, you take it
Just take it, you idiot!
- My friend Giuseppe isn't here
- Different shift. He'll eat later
Pasquale!
Giuseppe!
I'm here!
Stay in line, or I'll tell the master
Don't react.
He's a bastard. He spies on you
Attention! Face left! Left!
Forward march.
One, two, one, two...
This food isn't edible
It is, it is.
It's always disgusting at first...
...but then you have to eat it,
if you don't want to starve to death
- Disgusting!
- Aren't you hungry, Raffaele?
- I'm not hungry
- Try harder
Even if you don't like it,
you have to eat. Understand?
Of course, I understand
Are you not going to eat it?
You've a strong stomach!
Are you surprised? He had
the stomach to kill his father!
Sit down, don't be stupid
- Vanzetti!
- Vanzetti, ground floor, number 7
Filippucci!
- Filippucci!
- Reach out your hand!
- First floor
- Morriconi
- Morriconi, first floor
- Cardinali
- Cardinali, second floor
- Quintiliani
- Quintiliani, second floor
- Martini
- Martini, second floor
- Geronzi
- Geronzi, first floor
- Valeri
- Valeri, ground floor
- Proietti
- Proietti, ground floor
Filippucci
A huge parcel!
- Where's that moron going?
- How are you? Take some
- That's not allowed!
- Why? He's a friend
Go to your cell,
or I'll confiscate your parcel
- Damn it!
- What a prick!
One day I'll punch that son of a bitch
Calm down,
you have to suffer in silence
- I'm not going to suffer in silence
- You'll get into trouble, then
- I'm starving
- Do this, then!
- You'll soon lose your appetite!
- He's coming!
- Five! Six!
- Seven! Nine!
- Three! Two!
- Five! Four!
- Two! Five!
- Seven! Five!
- Five! Three!
- Five! Four!
- Three! Five!
- Three! Seven!
- Five!
- Three!
Five! Five!
Help yourselves,
there's plenty in here
We'll give you a hand with it
There were 10 pears, but the guard
took four, and an egg
Set that aside. Don't let those
cheapskates stuff themselves
Disgusting!
No! This is for my friend!
- Who's he?
- A newcomer
That's for...
There's a note inside
How can it be? My mother's
very careful when she cooks
"As the heart says: keep quiet...
..."Sincerity is the enemy of love"
- Understand?
- No
You lamebrain!
- They're telling you not to talk
- Now, I understand
Finally!
There was no need for it.
I wouldn't have talked anyway
Very good, I like you!
We'll become good friends
- Amazing! Who gave them to you?
- Santa Claus
We don't have any
Master!
What now?
What a thief!
Only three
Only three? What a wretch!
You keeper of human meat...
...you worthless thief!
- Can I have a smoke?
- I'm first
I'm first!
- Giuseppe
- Pasquale
- I was looking for you
- Me, too
- How is it going?
- Not too bad
Yesterday I ate,
thanks to that parcel
- Yeah, I saw it
- I wanted to give you some but...
Never mind
- I need to talk to you
- What is it?
- That must be the boy's friend
- I don't like the look of him
There was no need for the note,
we're not spies
My brother's so afraid,
he's probably shitting his pants
He's nothing to worry about with me
He's Arcangeli
- Nice to meet you
- You, too
I'll lend you a towel and soap,
if you need them
- Thanks. He found the note
- Him?
He's a great guy.
He's in here for armed robbery
With a machine gun!
His gang steals cars, too.
His father's a doctor, he's a student
- I don't like him
- You don't know him
I like the others, too.
I'd love it if you could be with us
_Ma99i, Pasquale!
FmPPucci, Giuseppe!
- That's us!
- Go see the chief constable
Why did you sack
those two masters?
They were stealing from boys'
parcels and trading cigarettes
Nowadays, poverty
makes people lose their head
- Here are the two boys
- Come in, come in
So, you've stated that
you don't know the three men...
...who entered
Mrs Donati Anselmi's house?
Right
But do you know Mr Anucci?
- Yes
Very good. Now, this man
came to see me yesterday
- He said he sold you a black horse
- No, it was white
Yes, a white one. I misread it, sorry
A white horse,
for 50,000 lira, correct?
- Yes
You made the purchase one hour
after the burglary in Via del Babuino
I understand where you're going,
Chief
But you're wrong.
We already had the money
- And how did you earn it?
- That's our business
Listen, boys. I came here with good
intentions. I want to help you
Yesterday I spoke to your father,
he's distraught
You have to tell the truth,
if you want him to forgive you
We told you the truth.
We know nothing
You're too nice. Give them to me...
...and I'll show you how I can make
them speak by giving them the belt!
Hear that? Why would you
want to get beaten up...
...and end up in a rat-infested cell?
To defend whom? Some criminals
I'd understand if it were family...
...but you are all alone, and you are
from a poor but honest family
Listen, Chief...
...you can kill us, but we can't tell you
what we don't know
- Too bad!
- Bring the youngest!
Don't worry, it's your turn next
Undress him. And remove his shirt
Are you going to talk?
That's enough!
Come on, that's enough
Stop!
Have you made up your mind?
Give me the names
I swear, we don't know anything
Enough,enough
I'll tell you everything
So?
One is called Panza
The other is Attilio,
Giuseppe's brother
I don't know the other one, I swear.
I never saw him before
Giuseppe!
Take him to his cell
Let's go
He's gone up there!
Stop it
- Giuseppe
- Pasquale
- Did they hurt you?
- No. And you?
Me, neither.
Didn't they use the belt on you?
No, they were only kidding.
You haven't said anything, have you?
No, I haven't
What are you doing here?
Damn you!
What did he want?
He wanted to know
if they'd beaten me up
- What happened?
- Nothing, why?
- You've got a look on your face
- It's my face. If you don't like it...
...don't look at it!
I'll go on my own from here,
otherwise Mum will get scared
- Do you have a visitor?
- No
- Then why did you come here?
- Well...
- Mario, take him upstairs
- I'm busy
Keep an eye on him
Come here
- Where's my mother?
- Mrs Di Dio!
I'm here
- Where's my mother?
- She sent me here
She wrote asking me
to come to see you. Look
- But where is she?
- She had to go to Florence
But she'll come here soon
I brought you a parcel
full of nice things
Thank you
Bye, dear. Take care of yourself
- Goodbye
Pasquale, my mother is here.
See you outside!
- Giuseppe!
- What are you doing? Move it
Mum!
Can you forgive me, Mum?
How could you do it?
It's not my fault,
we didn't know anything
We haven't done anything
I know he's a delinquent,
a scoundrel
But he's your brother,
you shouldn't have betrayed him
- What are you talking about?
- No need to pretend
The Chief made it clear
that it was you two who talked
Attilio is nothing to Pasquale, but...
...to you...
Come on, don't be stupid!
"Kiss Raffaele for me. Tell him
that his mother will be back soon...
..."and she'll bring money to pay
the lawyer, so he'll get out quickly
"I like Florence very much,
it's better than Rome
- "Yours, Teresa Di Dio"
- Good
- Is Florence far?
- No
A friend of mine drives there
once a week
Then it's close
- Have one, Pasquale
- No, thanks
Help yourselves
Leave it. It's his stuff.
He needs it because he's sick
- You grassed!
- I thought they'd beaten you up!
- Wait, let me explain!
You're a grass!
Grass! Get away from me!
What's happening?
As soon as you have
a bit of freedom...
...you take advantage of it.
What happened?
- He's a grass
- No
Behave, boys. I don't want to get
into trouble because of you
Behave! I don't want to rot in here
because of you
Behave!
Behave, boys
- I need to talk to you
- What do you want?
- None of your business
- Says who?
Me
Napoli, you have it easy
because you're ill...
...but you'd better watch out
OK. So, can I talk to you?
If you're here on behalf of that grass,
save your breath
Especially with your lungs
Well done, good answer
Arcangeli
Go, Giuseppe. It's the right moment
- You swore you'd go
- Or else you're a coward
What are you talking about?
Of course he'll go
Mr Staff era, in cell 9
they have a file
- What?
- They're hiding a file
Damn it!
- Surely I could've convinced him
- Thanks, but it wasn't a good idea
He's the one who has to apologise
What?
But you were such good friends
- It's a shame
- I still like him, but if he...
Those in cell 9
Whose file is this?
- Whose file is this?
- I don't know
- I swear by...
- Whose file is this?
- Never seen it before
- I don't know
Get out!
Whose file is this?
I swear on my honour that...
- Who sleeps here?
- Me
- The file was in your mattress
- Impossible
Are you saying that I'm a liar?
No, but it's not mine,
I haven't put it there
- You're accusing your mates?
- I'm not accusing anybody!
The file's yours.
What were you going to do?
Nothing. Nobody gave it to me.
It's not mine!
Get out, all of you!
No, no, enough!
Enough! Enough!
- No, enough!
- Stop it! Stop it!
Lock them in!
- Stop crying!
- Whiner!
He sent your brother to jail
Now everybody will know
it was you who told Staff era
Dry your tears, little boy!
Staff era's coming
- What's your name?
- Filippucci, Giuseppe
Well done
If he makes you head of the group,
we're sorted!
I can't believe this guy!
What an idiot!
Stop it!
- Are you ill?
- I'm burning all over
You have to go for a medical visit.
The doctor has an excellent ointment
I wonder who put that file there
When I find out, I swear to God
that I'll give him a thrashing
Even if I end up in Regina Coeli!
But everybody in here
thinks you're a grass
But it's not true!
Napoli, what's the truth?
Did he grass or not?
Damn you! You could have told me
Not even Raffaele believed me
at first
- Me?
- Yes. Imagine the others
But I don't care
if they believe me or not
I just want to know
who put the file there
Forget about it. It's done now
- What?
- I meant... Well...
Tomorrow I'll talk to Giuseppe.
You have to make up
- Whatever
- Don't worry, I'll convince him
It's impossible to sleep in here.
Give over!
- It's freezing!
- Change over!
Next lot!
Damn, it's really cold!
- I've spoken to him. Come
- He has to come to me
You two are really difficult
He says you have to come,
you say he has to come
Just find a compromise
and meet halfway, OK?
- OK, let's meet halfway
- Finally!
Damn! That was some beating
they gave you
- Did you see the doctor?
- No
Careful, don't use the soap
- Does it hurt?
- Yes, but it'll go away
Have you made up your mind?
Damn, you're dragging this out!
Have you told him
who put the file in the mattress?
No, I haven't. And I haven't told him
who asked me to do it either
Go ahead and tell him
- What shall I do?
- Whatever you want
If you want to make peace with a guy
who sent your brother to prison
Didn't you hear what Righetto said?
- He thought they were beating me
- If you listen to this idiot...
Idiot? Watch your mouth!
It's the truth, Giuseppe. Go
Come on, Arcangeli!
- Come on, Arcangeli!
- Come on!
- Come on! Come on, Arcangeli!
- Come on, Pasquale!
- Come on!
Come on, Pasquale! Come on!
Help! Help! They're killing him!
"Violent by nature.
Dangerous to himself and others
"We recommend isolation"
Master!
- What?
- I need to go to the loo
- You have a bowl there
- Yes, but afterwards...
It's not my problem. You're the one
staying in there, not me
- Is that meant to be a horse?
- What do you know?
I hate horses, they're too slow
You haven't seen Bersagliere,
he flies
- Who's Bersagliere?
- Never mind
- Give me a cigarette
- We don't have any
- I've been to the infirmary
- We can see that!
Idiots! I've got everything ready
to make an escape
But I'm an idiot wasting my time
talking to you guys
No, we want to listen
- I can't organise anything with you
- But we're ready
Shut up!
I won't discuss anything with you
- What've I done?
- Made up with Pasquale
- True
- No, it isn't
When I saw you on the floor
looking almost dead...
Anyway,
when entering the infirmary...
- Damn you!
- Shut up, will you?
Carry on
The fence is fastened to the wall
with an iron bar
I've prepared everything.
I've cut through many bolts
You just need to shake it hard
to break it open
From the window to the roof
is less than two metres
Filippucci?
- Yes?
- There's a visitor
- Here he is, sir
- Thank you
Sit down
We have much to discuss.
My name's Bonavino, I'm your lawyer
Your family has hired me
to defend you and your brother...
...Attilio...Attilio Filippucci
- You're Giuseppe, yes?
- Yes
- Your friend is Pasquale Maggi?
- Has his family found a lawyer yet?
- He has no family
Good. We're sorted
Our defence is that
you were forced against your will
You'll say that Maggi incited you
to commit crimes
Incfied?
You'll say you knew nothing
and your friend knew everything
Pasquale knew nothing.
My brother organised everything
Say that in court and your brother
will serve at least five years
- But it's true
- That's for your confessor
In court you say what I tell you
This horse couldn't have been
bought with hard-earned money...
...as the defence wants us to believe
He was bought with money
from stolen goods
- But the goods have been found
- Where's the horse now?
Don't answer!
If I didn't know you well, I'd think
that in your vocabulary...
...the term "horse"
is synonymous with "fee"
- Are you joking?
- Why did you buy the horse?
- To ride him
- To ride him, eh?
- It's the truth
- How much did you plan to earn?
Sergeant, bring in Maggi
May I remind the court that in
the documents Maggi is described...
...as violent by nature
and isolation is recommended
When did you buy the horse?
Excuse me, Your Honour,
why is this horse so important?
I think it's important. Are you
defending Maggi or the Filippuccis?
Filippuccis.
I've been hired by the family
Maggi is with Scardone,
the public defender
How much did each of you
own of the horse?
How much did each of you put in?
- We did fifty-fifty
- Did you put it in writing?
No
If you had a dispute over ownership,
what would you do?
Where have you hidden the horse?
Don't answer!
The accused doesn't have to answer
Who is she?
I don't know.
Maybe it's Queen Margherita
- Excuse us
- Where are you going? Hold on
You can't go in. Stop!
Let us in!
A Roman Emperor, I can't recall
his name at the moment...
...made his horse a Senator
He speaks really well
So, why be surprised
if two poor kids...
...two kids living on the street,
put all their love...
...all their hopes, on a horse?
He saw me
- What's he talking about?
- A horse
- Ever ride one?
- No, but I'd like to try
- Keep quiet!
- Who's talking?
You don't need to be a psychologist
to understand the strong influence...
...that Maggi had on his friend,
the little innocent Giuseppe
Just look at him
Who wouldn't want him as a son?
I'm not accusing Maggi.
That's the district attorney's job
Come on, you have to be strong
- My poor sons
- Don't be like that, Anna
- Wouldn't it be better to go in?
- No
Return these innocents to their
homes, families, schools, jobs
This is no crime
If you think they're guilty...
...then this court must condemn
all of us too -...
...the people who -
in pursuit of our passions -...
...abandon our children
to fend for themselves...
...children who are all alone
Mr Scardone, your turn
I'll be brief, as usual
After all, I haven't had the time
to delve into the details of this case
Therefore, I will entrust my client...
...to the paternal clemency
of this court...
...in requesting a complete acquittal
on his behalf...
...or a very light sentence
Very--- ...
...very light
Marcello, come!
We also sentence
the minors Maggi, Pasquale...
...to two years and six months
in prison and a 2,000-lira fine...
...and Filippucci Giuseppe
to one year in prison...
...and a 1,000-lira fine,
without appeal
Giuseppe, Giuseppe!
You bastards! You villains!
Here they come!
Poor boys, my poor sons!
Giuseppe!
Attilio!
Oh, here he is, at last!
We were starting to think
they'd shot you
How did it go?
I got a year, but I don't care.
Where's Arcangeli?
Gone to see his mother
for the money
- You haven't changed your mind?
- No way!
This morning Sicilia and I
went to the infirmary
He's still there. Everything is ready
I'd love to see the district
attorney's face after my escape!
- How did it go for Pasquale?
- He got two years
- Bloody hell!
- Why?
What happened?
- She didn't come. She sent my dad
- So?
- What?
- Let's escape anyway
Without money,
they'd catch us in no time
What about me? I got one year.
I don't want to stay in here
I want to get out!
Shut up, idiot!
You're going to ruin everything
You're worried about one year?
What can I say, you idiot?
You can't escape with no money.
So I asked my mum for 10,000
But that imbecile spoke to my father...
...and now he wants
to talk to the director
He'll have me put in isolation.
He wants me to pay for it, damn him!
In his eyes, I've disgraced the family
- I have money
- Where?
- I've got it
- How much?
More than 50,000 lira
- Here they come!
- Here come the entertainers!
What are you showing tonight?
- Something good?
- Show us some naked legs!
A comedy would be better!
- It's a movie
- Big deal
Last time they showed us cartoons
as if we were still little children
I like it.
In my village there's no cinema
Did you come to prison for that?
Lucky you
In here they feed us, they shelter us,
they give us clothes...
...and they even entertain us.
What else could we want?
This is paradise!
NEWS FROM THE FREE WORLD
In the Pacific Ocean,
General MacArthur continues...
...the successful campaign
against the Japanese
Bouganville's been targeted by
the US air, sea and ground forces...
...in an attack by destroyers
Look, Pasquale, the sea
The American forces
have disembarked
They're one step closer
to Japan itself
Open it. Open the window!
Lights!
Lights, please
Stop laughing!
BOy5!
What are you doing up there?
Idiots! We've been caught!
- You could have waited a bit!
- Open up!
- What happened?
- They've locked themselves inside
- How many of them?
- I've seen two
Open up, boys! Open up!
Open up, boys!
Stop! Lights!
Lights! Lights!
Calm down, for God's sake!
Calm down!
There's no danger.
Turn on the lights
Lights! Lights!
Master! Master!
Master, it's Raffaele!
Quick, let's take him to the infirmary
Move out of the way!
Open up! Open UP!
Open up, boys! Open up!
Boys! Boys, come back!
Boys, come back or I'll shoot you!
Boys, think about what you're doing!
Boys!
Boys! Boys!
- I want to leave, too!
- Go, go!
Take him back to his cell
- Five or six have escaped
- Sound the alarm
Surround the building
- Where's your cell?
- I want to see him
Tomorrow.
We're waiting for the doctor
- Then he's not dead?
- Let's hope not. Come on
- Let's go
- Take them to their cells
To their cells!
- Arcangeli's escaped
- Who else?
- Arcangeli, Giuseppe and other five
- There were more than 20
- Napoli is dead
- But they caught them
Idiot! They had a car waiting outside
- And a horse, too
- A horse?
- Let's go
- What horse?
A horse?
Where did they keep a horse?
- The guards!
- Stop!
- Stop there, boys!
Come on, come on!
Bartoli, get the forms ready
for tomorrow
And the report. One page is enough
- I might not be here tomorrow
- Where will you be?
This isn't the right place for me
I don't even know where
the right place for me is...
...but in here you need people
stronger than me, much stronger
There was nothing that could be done
This poor kid...
his days were numbered
Don Biagioni, I'm sorry. It's my fault
- It's my fault
- Calm down. It was an accident
We caught them.
We're missing only two...
...Arcangeli and Filippucci,
the one who was sentenced today
We've informed the police.
They won't get far
- Do you think they could leave town?
- Where could they go?
With no money
and dressed as inmates...
...they can't go around naked
Unless the families help them,
but I doubt it
I know Dr Arcangeli, and Filippucci
comes from a poor family
We'll have so many problems
with the department
Mr Staff era!
- What do you want?
- I know where they've gone
- Who?
- Arcangeli and Giuseppe
Where?
I'll take you there
He's not here. They've taken him
Look over there!
What happened?
My head hurts.
He beat me up, the big one...
- Where did they go?
- I don't know. They wanted the horse
They said it was theirs
My head hurts. They beat me up
The bigger one. Vile...
Get down!
Giuseppe!
Giuseppe! Giuseppe!
Giuseppe! No!
What have I done?
Giuseppe!
Oh, my God! What have I done?
What have I done?
Giuseppe!
THE END
Translated by Lorena Uras