LOS OLVIDADOS
This film is based on real events.
No character is fictional.
Almost every capital
like New York, Paris, London
hides, behind its wealth,
poverty-stricken homes
where poorly-fed children,
deprived of health or schooling,
are doomed to criminality.
Society tries to provide a cure.
Success for its efforts
remains very limited.
The future isn't shackled
to the present:
The day will come when the rights
of childre are respected.
Mexico City, a large modern city,
is no exception to the rule.
This film shows life as it is.
It's not optimistic.
The solution to this problem has
been left to the forces of progress.
Leave a bit for the others!
Who wants a smoke?
Do you smoke?
No, it makes me cough.
I don't smoke either.
What a chicken!
You're a wimp!
I have to go to work.
Only morons work.
Too bad. See you later.
You're so polite!
Just a minute!
You know who I've seen?
Jaïbo!
He got away from
the reformatory prison.
Who's this Jaïbo?
Egg tortillas.
Who wants tortillas?
- One tortilla.
- Coming right up.
Do you want it with pickles?
Put in anything you want.
As I was telling you,
in prison, if you're a wimp,
they beat the shit out of you.
Are there tough guys there?
Yes, but if you're
tougher than them,
they respect you.
So they don't bother you.
How's the grub?
Not bad.
And I took the best bed.
But the street is better.
That's why I got away
as soon as I had the chance.
Weren't you scared?
What if they'd caught you...
Jaïbo doesn't fear anyone.
It was Julian's fault
they put you in jail, right?
It was. That bloody weasel...
- Who can give me a cigarette?
- Not me.
- Me neither.
- What about you?
I've got no more.
No cigarette, no dough!
Without me, you're no good.
But I've learned a lot
and if you obey me
we'll all get dough.
You're a real tough-guy.
We'll do everything you want.
I'll sing you a song
from the time of
General Don Porfirio.
You can laugh,
but in these days
people were more respectful
and women stayed at home.
Now they only think
of chasing men.
This song will cost one peso.
I have to sing to live.
The price of bread is going up,
and so is the price of my songs.
This one is from the days of
General Don Porfirio.
A 20 centavo coin and a 10
centavo have just dropped down.
- Here's the blind man.
- Fine.
You, Baldie,
you swipe his bag.
Rush back and give it to him,
and he'll pass it on to me.
You guys, you wait
where I told you.
What if I'm arrested?
Just drop the 'exhibit'.
Don't get nabbed with it!
I know the law!
- Move!
- It's OK.
- What do you want?
- Nothing.
Leave me alone then.
Keep away, son.
Go and tickle the bull's nostril.
Did he hit you hard?
He only scratched me.
What an arsehole!
There was a nail
on the end of the stick.
It's deep!
Ask your mother to nurse you.
My mother? If I go home,
she'll kill me.
Mine's horrible too.
That's why I left.
Gashes from a nail are bad.
Put a cobweb on it. It's good
for stopping bleeding.
Pedro! Bring me one.
- I will.
- Hurry up!
With that, you get over it
or you lose your paw.
Is there a kind soul
who can help me cross?
Who will take pity
of a poor blind man?
Is there anybody?
Why are you crying, my child?
My Dad told me to wait here
and he hasn't come back.
He won't be long. Tell you what:
you can help me, since I'm blind.
You do have small eyes.
The less of us there are,
the better. You guys, wait.
We'll thank him all right.
Have some pity for a poor
defenceless blind man.
Take that, you bloody blind man!
In the head, Baldie,
in the head!
Watch out, or you
gonna break your neck.
What are we getting to eat?
- What is it?
- Nothing.
- Cool, some meat!
- Don't touch it.
You've been given meat?
That's impossible!
Don't touch it!
Where the hell have you been?
Over there... Looking for a job.
All night long?
Why have you come back?
Mum, I'm hungry.
I've told you not to come back
if you hang with these punks.
You don't realise
I work myself to death
washing floors all day long.
I'm hungry!
Ask your friends to feed you.
Punk!
Why are you hitting me?
To teach you a lesson,
you good-for-nothing!
You don't love me any more.
It's your fault.
It was good!
You're not from here, are you?
Yes... from the country.
If you're a peasant,
you're not from here!
Why did you come here?
I didn't come,
I was brought.
Why?
I don't know.
You know nothing!
Hi, Pedro!
Hi, Julian!
Have you seen my father?
I know where he is...
What a prick!
Now I'm hungrier than before.
Have you eaten?
No.
- Are you hungry?
- A lot.
Have you got any money?
Come on, Dad.
You can't stand up any more.
No. Let me go.
You ought to be ashamed.
You shouldn't judge your father.
I'm not judging you, but
you could get beaten up.
- Mum's waiting.
- Let her wait!
Don't you get sick of
being drunk every night?
Me, drunk?
Yes, it's true.
What a shame!
You work yourself to death
to feed us and I...
Forgive me, son.
I swear I'll stop drinking.
You always say that.
This time, it's true.
He's so drunk!
Do you have a problem
with that?
No. Sorry.
Your lack of respect
gets on my nerves
Here we go again!
I'm your father after all!
What a drunkard!
OK... I'm leaving. Bye.
Give me that knife over there.
I'm busy.
Here, I count for less than
an animal. Where's Metche?
Where are you?
I'm going to die alone!
Go find your sister so she can
give her a rub-down.
She'll come back.
It's me, Jaïbo.
My fool of a brother
is forever bringing us tramps.
Hang on. We need to talk.
Aren't you supposed
to be in jail?
I am whereever I want to be.
I've escaped.
Get lost! If they find you here,
it'll be bad for us.
- Want some help?
- No!
You've become so pretty
since the last time I saw you.
You keep quiet or I'll scream!
OK! Don't get mad at me.
I'm going out.
Lie down or you'll cough
and stop us from sleeping.
Pimples!
What?
I've fought with Mum,
I've come to sleep here.
Who's this?
He was lost,
I took pity on him.
Come in but don't make any noise.
Mum's waiting for you.
Hi, Jaïbo!
Pedro! It's getting to be
quite a crowd here!
Who's the guy
with the small eyes?
Well... He's called Small Eyes.
I found him at the market.
- Can you see me?
- Me? No.
Why did you bring him?
Beat it!
Leave him alone!
Don't you have any family?
He could be a bastard.
I have a Dad!
So where is he?
He told me to wait for him,
but he didn't come back.
He's not from here.
We have to go.
Don't touch the animals
and don't make any noise.
Good night, Metche.
When I get rich,
I'm going to marry you.
Don't worry about the chickens!
He said not to touch the animals,
when it's so good to have
some milk before bed!
They haven't left a drop!
Look at him!
Leave us alone.
Pedro and I, we're leaving.
- Gimme your handkerchief.
- Why?
I'll give it back to you.
- My throat's hurting.
- Don't piss me off.
You, follow me.
You guys, see you later.
What about Julian?
- I saw him last night.
- Is he always at the same place?
No. He works on a building site.
Where?
I'll show you if you want.
Let's go and talk to him.
There he is.
Tell him I'm here.
Be careful,
he packs a hard punch.
Since he doesn't smoke,
he never runs out of breath.
Get moving!
Jaïbo wants to see you.
Why?
To talk to you.
If he's looking for a fight,
he'll get what he's after.
- He wants to know if you wimped out.
- He'll find out about that.
- I'll be back right away.
- Don't be too long.
- Just a minute.
- Go on.
What do you want?
I haven't seen you
in a while!
Why did you want to meet me?
I have to talk to you...
but not here.
Wherever you want.
Let's go.
We've walked enough.
Now talk!
I've spent a year in jail
thanks to you, if you recall.
- Thanks to me?
- Sure!
You squealed on me.
If it was me, I'd tell you.
You don't scare me.
I'm not a rat.
The guy who squealed on me
is going to pay for it.
You're bluffing. You know I can't
beat you up because of your arm.
Come back when you're better
and you'll see what you get.
As for you, I'm going to
beat the shit out of you.
Stop hitting him!
Let's get out of here before
he wakes up. That'll show him.
That's for you.
When he comes to,
he won't miss us.
I'll put him back to sleep.
Please, I'd like to cross over.
Can no-one hear
a poor blind man?
I'll help you, sir.
Hang on! It's you from yesterday.
Are you still waiting for your father?
Yes, sir.
For sure he's not coming back.
There's too much poverty these days,
too many mouths to feed.
Listen, son, I need
someone to help me.
Come with me, you'll have a home
and something to eat.
What about my Dad?
We'll come back here every day.
Go on, take that.
If the police question you,
I'm your godfather. Let's go.
Come in, Don Carmelo.
Small Eyes, what are
you doing with him?
Are you called Small Eyes?
What a stupid name!
Wait for me here.
Hi!
How does the patient feel?
Better... but I've been left
on my own.
But your sons are grown-up now.
They're just hooligans,
always lounging around.
I know.
There's nothing to do here.
Turn around, please.
Mother Mary!
Have pity on me and heal me!
It's working!
Look at the pigeon.
You've infected it
with your disease.
When it dies, you'll be cured.
Holy Mary, mother of God!
I can't bear this pain any more.
What's my boss doing inside there?
It's for my sick mother.
Don Carmelo is treating her
with a pigeon.
That's not a good thing to do.
How do you know?
Look.
What is it?
It's the tooth of a dead man.
It keeps the Evil Eye away.
Whoever has it never gets sick.
Where did you find it?
At the graveyard.
I took it by moonlight.
Otherwise, it's worthless.
If you like, I'll give it to you.
To me?
Take it.
Thanks.
So, get well.
Metche, my bottle!
There you go, Don Carmelo.
From now on, Small Eyes
will come and get it.
- Do you hear me?
- Yes, sir.
Let's head off.
For health, nothing beats donkey milk.
Would you have a cigarette?
I don't like to encourage slackers.
Go and keep watch.
What do you want?
A cigarette.
- Go and buy one.
- We don't have any money.
Get a job, and you'll
be able to smoke.
Police!
Let's shut his trap for him.
He's about to find out
who he's dealing with!
Great!
Let him go.
Now, let's all scram!
Take it!
There's one peso for each of you.
And we're not finished.
I'm rusty.
You haven't seen anything yet.
That cripple was
really scared to death.
Hey guys!
I've been looking for you.
Have you heard what happened?
Julian's been found dead.
- You're kidding!
- Julian?
Not far from where he works.
His body's still lying there.
There are lots of people around.
Do they know who did it?
The police say
he was killed from behind.
Are we gonna go and have a look?
Let's do it.
- Come with us, Pedro.
- We're heading there.
- What's the mattern?
- Nothing!
You go now , and we'll follow.
Come soon!
It was you who killed him!
I didn't want to.
You'd better
keep your mouth shut now
if you don't want
us to be arrested.
I didn't do anything.
You were looking for him.
You took half of his dough.
If we get nabbed, I'll end up
in jail, and so will you.
So what do we do now?
We have to split up.
If they catch one of us,
we keep our mouths shut, OK?
OK.
Now we have to rely on each other
more than ever, is that clear?
Pedro darling, what are you doing?
Listen to me, sweetheart,
you're not that bad.
Why did you do it?
I didn't do anything. It was Jaïbo.
I'd like to be
with you all the time.
But I'm very tired.
Look at my hands, they're
worn-out from doing washing.
Why don't you ever kiss me?
Mum, I'm gonna behave.
I'll look for a job,
you'll be able to rest.
Yes, darling.
Mummy...
Why didn't you give me
some meat the other night?
Give it to me!
It's mine.
APPRENTICE WANTED
What are you looking at?
Milk... There's nothing better
for the skin.
What?
If you wash with it,
people say your skin
becomes like satin.
Bloody Small Eyes!
You seem to know everything.
It's 'cause my mother used
to do the hair of girls
who were getting married,
and treat their skin with milk.
OK... see you tomorrow.
Is what you told me true?
Jaïbo!
Haven't you left yet?
I'm not going
while you're still around.
- If Grandpa knows it...
- I don't give a shit.
- Hey, where are you going?
- What do you want?
- To see you.
- Get lost!
Stick around, I'm not going
to eat you.
Don't come near me
or you'll get thumped.
If you give me a kiss,
I'll give you...
What?
Two pesos to buy
whatever you want.
Show me.
Have a look.
Just one, OK?
Leave me alone, don't touch me!
Stop that!
What's going on?
Jaïbo's having fun with my sister.
Let go of me, you animal!
Don't do anything.
Let me go!
You dirty pig, take that!
You'll see,
I'm going to tell Mum.
Are you gonna shut up?
There's no need to make such
a big fuss about nothing.
If you'd have touched me,
I would have smashed your face in.
Let him go,
people can hear you.
You big coward, how dare you
behave like that with him!
Come with me.
Let's go, Grandpa
might be able to hear us.
He's not so deaf as all that.
See you tomorrow, Small Eyes.
Why are you looking at me?
No reason.
What's the matter?
- Is it true that you...
- What?
Killed Julian?
I didn't do anything.
I thought so.
- Just watch what you say...
- Don't worry, I'm your mate.
If you did it,
that's your business.
What are you doing here?
Who's he?
A pal who's helping me.
Do you have a problem with that?
I don't want to see anyone here.
Don't get mad, Grandpa.
If he leaves, I'm leaving too.
Right, clear off!
Let's scram!
What will you do?
I don't know.
I don't got any money.
You'd better go into hiding for.
a few days. We'll come to see you.
I know a great place.
I'll take you there.
- Where is it?
- Come on.
I've got you! What is it
you've come here for?
Some water. I live with
a blind man in this house.
If I wanted to,
I could knock you out.
If you ever tell anyone
you saw me here, I'll kill you.
Yes, sir.
You know I keep my promises.
Hang on a minute.
Don't breathe a word!
Come here, Small Eyes.
Who were you talking to?
Just someone who was passing by.
You're lying. Nobody ever
comes here.
He was there, then he left.
Who was it?
I don't know!
You'll tell me
or I'll tear off your ear.
- Jaïbo.
- What?
He's called Jaïbo.
I forbid you to talk
to other people.
This Jaïbo for sure he's one
of those layabouts...
If I see you with him or another
of them, I'll break your arm.
These days, you all
keep bad company.
Before, it used to be different.
Grown-ups
were respected.
What was that,
Small Eyes?
Just a stone that fell down.
Get lost!
Where's the scum
who killed my son?
Show your face so that
I can kill you!
He was attacked from behind!
Somebody bring me that coward!
Just be patient... Be patient!
I've got a job! On Saturday,
I'll bring you seven pesos.
Get me that bowl.
From now on,
I'm going to behave.
See what happens with your
idiotic carry-on!
You disgusting rooster!
Stop! Stop hitting it!
Mind the shop. If anyone comes,
they can wait.
What do you want?
To talk to you.
Not here!
It's important.
The boss will be back soon.
So what? Just tell him
I'm a customer.
The business with Julian
is starting to cause trouble.
Do they know what happened?
No...
But the police are questioning
everyone in the neighbourhood.
Since you knew him, they'll
be coming to see you.
They're searching for me
as an escapee.
What will I tell them?
It depends...
First, you should tell them...
Scram! My boss is coming!
- What should we do?
- I don't know.
I'll come to your place tonight.
- Did anyone come?
- No, sir.
You can go.
Have you seen
the silver-handled knife?
It was there.
It must have
fallen down somewhere.
Go and get me some water.
Take the jug.
- Come on.
- Hurry up!
Hello.
What do you want?
- Is Pedro home?
- No, not yet.
I'm supposed to meet him here.
If you don't mind, I'll wait.
If you want to.
It must be great
to have a mother!
When I look at you,
I envy Pedro.
I don't even know
what my family name is.
My father... I've never known
who he was.
My mother died
when I was a kid.
Do you remember her?
No... just the once,
from when I was little.
It seems I had these seizures...
like convulsions.
Once, after a seizure,
I saw the face of a woman,
very close to me.
She was looking at me tenderly,
with a sad expression.
She was crying. That's why
I think she was my mother.
And you remember that?
Yes, because nobody ever
looked at me like that again.
Maybe it was a dream.
What did she look like?
She looked like the Virgins
you see in church.
Mummy, a policeman's
asking after you!
- For me?
- Yes, a cop.
- What does he want?
- I don't know.
You'd better come inside.
Do you know about my Julian?
They killed him.
He liked you so much.
My darling... he was so good...
What will become of us?
He was working for us.
Who killed him?
- What?
- You must know.
I swear I don't know anything.
- Yes, you do.
- No!
Try to find out who killed
him and let me know,
so that I can catch him and I...
Pedro!
Are you sure?
Yes, your son was at the shop.
He's the only one who could
have stolen the knife.
My brother hasn't stolen anything.
Shut up.
Cigarette?
I don't know what to do
with that boy.
He stays out all night, I never
know where he spends the day,
and now...
It's serious. If he's convicted
of the theft, he'll go to jail.
Good, it doesn't worry me.
When he gets back, take him away
and give him a good thrashing.
Thrash him
until he's learned his lesson.
You, beat it!
It's ours!
Did you buy it?
Faster!
We're tired.
You'll get a rest
when you're dead.
- When do we get to eat?
- When you get the work done.
Give me the money
you owe me.
Look what I've got!
A bunch of slackers!
If that crook doesn't pay us,
let's wreck the carousel.
Is Pedro here?
He haven't come home
since the other night.
That's strange. Something
must have happened to him.
God only knows!
Tonio has put a marble
in his mouth.
Give me what you've got
in your mouth.
Were you very young
when you got married?
I was 14 when Pedro was born.
Is your husband still alive?
No, he died five years ago.
That's the little dogs.
Let's go and see them!
Are you leaving already?
Please, for the band.
Small Eyes!
Pedro, what are you doing here?
As you can see, I'm working.
How's everything going?
The same as usual.
Have you seen the gang?
I see Pimples
when I go for milk.
- What about Jaïbo?
- I've seen him too.
The cops haven't arrested him?
Get to work!
Where have you seen Jaïbo?
He sleeps next to the place
where I live with the blind man.
- Are they looking for me?
- No.
- Really?
- Nobody knows where you are.
Get lost!
Where are you going?
Where have you been
all this time?
Around here, in the street.
I've been working at a carousel.
Why have you come back?
You should have stayed there.
I ran away...
I can't say why.
But I didn't do anything bad.
Don't treat me like this.
I'd prefer it if you hit me.
Don't touch me.
I'd like to behave better,
but I don't know how to.
You're acting like this with me
because of Jaïbo, it's his fault.
Why did you do that?
Because you're a punk,
and a thief!
You were at the workshop
only so you could steal things.
I didn't steal anything!
I'll gong to take you
where you deserve.
Would you dare do that?
No, Mum...
Take me wherever you want.
We couldn't establish
proof of his guilt.
But since you can't
look after him properly,
we're sending him
to the farm-school.
We need your consent.
- That's fine by me.
- Sign here.
- I can't write.
- Do a cross.
I imagine you'd like
to see him?
No... what for?
It's the parents
we should be punishing
for the way they
raise their children.
They're deprived of affection,
so they look for it anywhere.
I work all day long so that
we can have food to eat.
Don't you love your son?
Why should I love him? I don't
even know who his father is.
That's OK...
but go and see him.
- Mendoza, take her with you.
- Follow me.
What's he done?
I don't know.
The judge told me to see you.
Aren't you talking to me?
They're going to send you
to the farm-school.
I don't want to go.
I haven't done anything.
You're the one who
had me locked up.
Listen, my son...
"My son"!
I came home just to see you,
you brought me here,
and now, you feel sorry for me!
It's your fault.
But you... stole the knife.
I didn't steal it! I told the judge
that, and I'm telling you now.
Why would I lie?
Who did it, then?
It's up to the cops to find him.
That's what they're paid for.
Have they sent you
to make me talk?
Pedro!
Yes, that's why you're here.
Why don't you beat me?
You brought me here, didn't you?
Don't play at being a good mum.
I believe you, my darling.
Now, you've remembered
I'm your darling.
I want to get out of here!
I didn't steal anything! Mum!
I haven't been able to come back
since the other night.
I heard about Pedro,
that's why I've come.
I want to see him.
- I'll help you.
- Let go.
I'm really sorry!
They've arrested the guy and
they could make him talk.
Don't worry.
He didn't rat on you.
Rat on me?
Why should he?
You went to see him
on the day of the theft.
Me?
I can see you're in
a bad mood. I'm going.
Don't ever come back.
When you're clean like you are
now, you become another man.
Your file says you can't read
and you were accused of theft.
I didn't steal anything.
Don't be scared.
You're not in jail here.
We're going to teach you to read
and you'll also learn a trade.
For instance... you could
become a mechanic.
There was a boy like you here.
Now he's driving a locomotive.
- I want to leave.
- Why?
I haven't done anything.
Are you a good boy?
No, but I didn't steal
the knife.
Apparently, you like animals.
You'll be very happy
with the work here.
Assign him to the poultry area.
Afterwards... we'll see.
Hey, don't do that!
What?
- Don't do that.
- We sell the eggs.
I'll do whatever I want.
We'll call the principal.
Go and do it.
You rat!
- Give it to me.
- Watch out or I'll bash you up.
I'd like to see that!
Drop that stick!
Lock him until he cools off.
Go back to work.
What are we going
to do with him?
We'll leave him to stew for a few
hours, and make sure he eats well.
People think better
on a full stomach.
Afterwards... we'll see.
Why are you smiling?
No reason. If we could lock
poverty up instead of children...
Follow me.
You're calmer now, aren't you?
Let's have a talk.
Why did you kill the chickens?
I don't know.
I do. Since you believe
you're in jail,
you think we all hate you
and you wanted to kill us.
But you didn't dare so the
chickens took our place, right?
Yes, sir.
Have a care. The chickens
might want their own revenge.
Look, we're not a prison here.
Look at the gate.
There aren't any policemen.
It's always open.
Seeing that
I want you to trust me...
go on and take it.
You can go out. On the right,
there's a tobacco shop.
Here's 50 pesos.
I don't have anything smaller.
Bring me a pack of cigarettes
like that one.
What are you waiting for?
Go on!
- You've got a lot of money.
- I'd like to have more!
This educational method
is going to cost you a fortune.
If you give money
to all of them...
Not to all of them, each one
has a different problem,
but this boy needs
trust and affection.
What if he doesn't come back?
I'll have lost 50 pesos. You have
to pay for your mistakes.
Pedro!
What are you doing here?
I found out you were here
so I came to see you.
Did they let you out?
I'm running an errand.
They must trust you!
Have you squealed on me?
I'm not a rat.
- You haven't said anything?
- Not a thing.
Good for you!
Move.
You know what happens
if anyone squeals on me?
When I was arrested for the
knife, you didn't say anything.
Why bring that up?
Besides, they've let you out.
A 50-peso note!
Who gave it to you?
The principal.
Well, he won't see it again.
Come on, let's clear off.
- I wanna go back to the school.
- Are you crazy.
I want to go back.
Give me the note.
Give it to me or
I'll break your wrist.
Hey, Pedro!
He's angry with me.
You're not upset any more?
Give me that money.
What money?
The 50 pesos you
stole from me.
Me?
- I want that note.
- Why?
To give it back to the principal.
You're a wimp.
And you're a thief.
Go back to your mother.
Leave my mother out of it.
Didn't she get enough?
Go, Jaïbo!
Bastards!
Let him go.
You won't get me
like you got Julian!
You're lying!
It was him, I saw him!
Liar!
You clubbed him to death.
He's the one who did it,
we have to get the police!
You're going to pay for that!
He's running away! Police!
Let's get away or we'll
all be arrested.
All these criminals should be
strung up by their feet.
In the time of the General,
no one dared speak up.
Bread thieves were executed by
firing squad, to set an example.
But now, we're helpless.
Julian was such a good boy!
It's always the good ones
that are taken from us.
What do you want?
Please, lead me to
the police station.
There are some things I want
to tell them about Jaïbo.
- To the police station?
- Yes, let's go!
- You're alone?
- Yes, come in.
What's up with you?
Nothing.
Does Jaïbo still sleep here?
Yes, but he gets in very late.
Where does he sleep?
In the empty house next door.
Bye!
The blind man's coming.
What should I do?
Hide over there
and don't make a sound.
Are you still sick?
Yes, sir.
If you were able to eat,
you'd get well.
But with me, you have to work
if you want to eat.
You're such a lazybones!
Good evening, Don Carmelo.
I've brought you the milk.
Thank you, my girl.
It had slipped my mind.
What with everything that's been
going on in the neighbourhood...
OK, I'll head off now.
Hang on, this is for the milk.
Thanks.
Ah my wonderful Metche!
Sit down for a minute.
You're a good girl.
Your hair smells nice.
But I never wash it.
You don't need to
at your age.
There's nothing better
than a natural scent.
It's a pity that God
deprived me of my eyesight.
You must be pretty as an angel
but as naughty as a devil.
I'm leaving.
Wait, I want to
give you something.
Two sweets for my little Metche.
And they're nice ones.
But before...
Small Eyes!
Come here!
What was that?
Something... fell down, sir.
Is that why you've been
pretending to be sick?
To let in thieves like you?
Let go of me.
It was no thief.
I'm going to kill you,
you little punk.
It was Jaïbo, he's the criminal!
He wants to kill me!
You old brute!
Don't hit him!
Run!
- You old fool!
- Get out of here!
Your father was right
to leave you. Dead right!
Ingrates!
I'll have done with
all of you soon enough.
Metche, have you seen my son?
Your son? No, I haven't
Why did you lie?
Because she knows he's escaped.
She's looking for him to...
What are you going to do?
Don't know. Maybe go to the market
to look for my Dad.
I've got one peso.
Take it and buy some food.
Thanks. Bye.
Take care.
Small Eyes, take your tooth.
It'll protect you.
He can't possibly escape.
But you'll have to wait,
he turns up late.
Jaïbo!
Now, I'm gonna make you pay.
Stop, don't kill me!
Grandpa!
There's someone in the barn.
The animals are agitated.
It's Pedro!
Someone's killed him.
I know who it was, Grandpa.
Shut your mouth, people might
think we're involved.
I don't want the police
coming here.
What should we do?
We'll load him onto the donkey
and dump him somewhere.
Get dressed quickly!
Stop or I'll shoot!
That's one less...
They'll all end up like that.
It would be better to kill them
before they're born.
You've been taken
care of, Jaïbo.
Right in the head.
Watch out, here's the mangy dog.
Look, he's coming.
That's it, I'm falling
into the black hole.
I'm alone.
Alone!
The same as always, kiddo,
the same as always.
There's nothing more
to think about.
Sleep, boy.
Sleep.
Good evening.