SUNDAYS AND CYBELE
Let go of me, please.
I don’t want to go. Take me
back to Granny. I’ll be good.
That’s enough now. Be quiet.
I don’t want to go there.
Come along. Will you come along?
Excuse me, but could
you please direct me
to St. Marguerite’s?
St. Marguerite’s boarding
school. You know where that is?
No. This is Ville d’Avray.
Yes, I know. It’s in Ville d’Avray.
Oh...
Come on. We’ll ask
someone from around here.
I don’t want to go!
I’ve already told you!
You’ll make friends.
Everyone will be nice to you.
I’ll come see you on
Sundays, and if you’re good,
at Christmas I’ll bring
you a very nice present.
That’s enough now.
- Why is she crying?
- It’s nothing. It will pass.
She mustn’t cry.
Excuse me. I know what I’m doing.
Come along now. That’s enough!
She mustn’t cry.
Take one.
They’re pieces of a star.
It fell from the sky.
No, thank you.
I can’t.
I was just kidding.
It’s water.
It’s just water.
If you’ll excuse us. Come along.
Ah, the new girl. You’ve
brought her very late.
- Forgive me. I couldn’t - -
Are you related to the child?
I’m her father.
Come, my child. I’ll take
you to Mother Superior.
You hear that?
Come, my child. It’s very late.
You’ll be back soon, right?
On Sunday?
Be good. You’re a big girl now.
Good night, Sister.
Slam the gate hard. It’s very heavy.
Well, well! I thought you’d left.
- Did you see a man running?
- The fellow in the raincoat?
Another nutcase buying his ticket
when the train’s already leaving.
“Wait for the next
one,” I say. “Impossible!
My plane leaves in an
hour. I can’t miss it!”
Platform two.
And he thrusts his ticket under my nose.
“All right, just this
once, but next time
“Don’t worry! I’m never coming back!”
Never coming back?
Anyway...
you know him?
He’s never coming back.
“Ruined.” What does
that mean, a ruined life?
When you haven’t been able
to do what you wanted.
A life where you’ve been unlucky.
A life like mine?
Pierre...
why do you say that?
Aren’t you happy with me?
I’m nothing.
I’m nothing anymore.
Pierre, you’re not being reasonable.
Just think.
Only a year ago you
couldn’t even go out alone.
You were still having
those horrible headaches.
Now you’re a man again.
My man...
Now I just walk around and wait!
And my memory’s not coming back.
Luckily, there are the trees.
And in the evening I go to the station
and wait for you.
I’m unhappy, Madeleine.
I still don’t know who I am.
Maybe you know...
but you won’t tell me.
Darling, don’t be cruel.
You know very well
you mustn’t look back.
The doctor told you that.
- The doctor’s not inside my head!
What happened today?
Nothing.
I was at the station, and -
That’s all.
Are you sure?
Ask the attendant.
He’ll tell you.
I believe you.
You should get undressed now, darling.
Do you still love me a little?
Yes.
Will you go see Carlos?
Yes, we’ve started on the birdcage.
Another Sunday without you.
It’s going on six weeks now.
You remember how we
used to go for walks?
But after Christmas
I’ll have Sundays off.
Won’t that be wonderful?
Would you like a little
more? There’s some left.
- No, thanks, Carmela.
- How’s Madeleine?
Tell her she’s becoming
quite a stranger.
Pierre...
look what I found for the aviary.
Don’t turn it down. Let us listen.
It has to be loud.
- You weren’t even listening.
Yes, we were. It just
didn’t look like it.
But you’ll never understand.
Actually, I don’t care.
I know it by heart.
No, be quiet.
This part is the end of the ceremony.
They’ve cast a spell on the universe.
It’s in Tibet.
You feel the forces?
Imagine hearing that at night.
Actually, you must have
heard things like that before.
Does it remind you of anything?
No, nothing.
But I like it.
Help me with this.
You wrap a wire around and tighten it.
And so on, right to the top.
It’ll be good and steady.
Beautiful, isn’t it?
Run along. Go for a walk.
We’ll continue tomorrow.
But no going to the station again, eh?
Because your past isn’t
coming back by train.
No, look at the trees.
People hide behind their masks,
and you think you’re
seeing the real thing.
It throws you.
Good-bye, Pierre. Say hi to Madeleine,
and tell her to come by more often.
Trees are different.
Give it time and you’ll
really understand them.
Yes, trees help.
But if I look up for too
long, I feel ill, I feel -
Vertigo. I’ll tell you something.
The day you stop getting
vertigo, you’ll be cured.
You have to get there gradually.
It’s the same with water.
If I look too long...
I feel like I’m falling, and I feel ill.
Don’t be afraid. Force yourself.
Look.
What are you waiting for? This is heavy!
- Delivering at this hour!
- I deliver when I can, Sister.
My delivery boy’s
sick. I have to fill in.
At my age! And with a
bad heart since Verdun!
- And what do you want?
- I’ve come for that little girl.
What?
I’ve come for the
little girl over there.
You’re the new girl’s father?
You should come earlier next time.
Frangoise, come here.
Someone’s here for you.
You’ve come for me?
Do you recognize me?
But where’s my father?
Are we going to join him?
- Yes, he sent me.
No later than 7:00, or
she can’t go out again.
Those are the rules.
I’m not surprised my father
sent you to take me out.
When I stayed with my grandmother,
he was always putting it off.
And all she thought about
was getting rid of me.
When I think about it,
I’ve really had bad luck.
My mother ran off with a magician,
maybe because my father
would never marry her.
And I’ve seen my father
three times in all.
Pretty sad, don’t you think?
Weren’t you surprised when
the sister called me Frangoise?
No. Why?
You know very well
that’s not my real name.
Did my father tell you my real name?
No.
The nuns made a great fuss about it.
It’s not a Christian name,
so they call me Frangoise.
Not that I really
care about the sisters.
- Tell me your name.
- Guess.
It’s very ancient, because
my grandmother’s Greek.
That’s where it comes from.
You give up?
- What?
You don’t know? It’s a beautiful name.
Tell me. I’d like to know.
That would be too easy.
I’ll tell you if you
get me that steeple cock.
Isn’t it beautiful?
That other Sunday / had the feeling
I’d seen you before,
and I thought maybe you could help me.
He deserted me. I knew it was coming.
That day on the train, he was sad.
He talked about a trip he was going on.
When I asked him when, he didn’t answer.
I thought, “This is it.
I’ll be all alone again.”
I’ve dreaded it for a long time.
When you came to get me for him,
I was glad.
Then, as time went by,
I could tell from your
expression you had bad news.
And that was it. I’m all alone.
Where did he go?
I don’t know.
He explains in a letter
that your grandmother
can’t keep you anymore,
and that he has to go away.
That his life is ruined.
The letter’s in there.
But when you came for me,
what did you tell Sister Opportune?
Nothing.
She thought I was your father.
She took you for my father?
Still, it was wrong to
lie to me like you did.
You’ve been telling me
nothing but fibs for two hours.
No, I really wanted to get to know you
so you’d help me.
But...
it’s no use now.
Well, too bad.
What should I tell the nuns?
Whatever you like.
It doesn’t matter now.
I’ll take you back.
What’s to become of me? My
grandmother doesn’t want me.
My mother already abandoned me.
I wonder what’s to become of me.
Let me stay with you! I don’t
want to go to an orphanage.
I can’t.
Let me stay. I’ll be good.
If they send me to an
orphanage, I won’t have anyone.
Will you let me stay?
Why can’t you?
My grandmother said if
my father gave me up,
I’d be put in an orphanage.
Quiet!
Keep quiet.
May I stay?
I told you. I’m no good
for anything anymore.
You managed to take
me out this afternoon.
Yes, but if Madeleine found out,
I wouldn’t be able to again.
Madeleine? Does she live here?
Why wouldn’t she like
it? Is she jealous?
Perhaps.
Does she love you?
Yes.
And you?
Since you’re not married, she
has no right to be jealous.
What if we don’t say anything?
Then it could work.
Not to let me stay here, but
to take me out on Sundays.
Sundays?
Yes. Is she here other Sundays?
Not right now. She’s on duty.
Then it’s simple.
I’ll go back to the nuns.
I’d rather not, but I’ll have to.
We won’t tell them anything,
or Madeleine either.
Everyone will believe you’re my father.
You’ll see. It’ll be lots of fun.
I’ll be nice, and I’ll love you a lot.
Don’t leave me.
- I’ll come get you.
You won’t abandon me?
Swear on my head.
What?
You put your hand on my
head and say, “I swear.”
If you’re lying, I’ll die.
I swear.
Daddy!
Hello, Daddy.
Monsieur, bring her
back no later than 7:00.
And please leave the gate open.
I called you “Daddy”
because of the nuns.
I figured that out.
Pierre, look.
Look at the circles.
There. Now we’re home.
We’ve entered the circle.
Come on.
Look.
Sir Magician, will
you give me this tree?
Pierre, what’s the matter?
I get vertigo.
Vertigo?
It’s the water.
Sometimes...
it’s as if I were high
up and I were falling.
Good thing you don’t fix houses.
You’d be falling all the time.
You can only fall
once. Then you’re dead.
That depends.
You fell once, and in
an airplane, no less.
My father is dead.
- What?
- My father’s dead.
No!
That’s just how it is. He’s dead.
He’s never coming
back, right? Well, then?
I’ve even decided he’s been buried
and that you’re going
to show me his grave.
Come show me where they buried the body.
Where? There?
Tell me where.
Over there?
Yes.
Thank you, God.
You’ve taken my father
but given me Pierre, who’s much nicer.
Pierre, how old are you?
Probably 30.
Thirty? And I’m 12, or almost.
Let’s see: 12... 30, 13... 31,
14... 32, 15... 33,
16, 17-
You’ll be 36 when I’m 18.
Thirty-six isn’t so old.
We’ll get married when I’m
18. Would you like that?
I know I would.
I can cook, you know, and keep house.
I always shined the crystal
ball at my grandmother’s.
Did I tell you she was clairvoyant?
I used to polish her magic knife.
That’s something you don’t see a lot.
My grandmother has a very beautiful
knife with an ivory handle.
You know what sorcerers in
Africa do with a knife like that?
They stick it in a tree, and
they can hear the spirits talking.
Was your grandmother mean?
Not really.
She always said I was
an extra mouth to feed,
but that I was nicer than my mother.
And your mother?
I suppose you don’t remember her either.
It’s really quite sad.
Deep down, you’re like a lost child.
If you had things to say to your mother,
you can tell me instead, all right?
If you knew how much I love you!
- How handsome he is!
- The horse?
Yes... and the rider too.
I wish he’d carry me off on his horse.
With him I wouldn’t be afraid.
Pierre, wait for me!
Why are you walking away?
- I don’t like the man on the horse.
To each his own.
Don’t you love me anymore?
You said you didn’t want
to stay with me anymore.
Are you crazy?
If you like, I’ll never go back to
school. I’ll stay with you always.
I’m your fiancee, aren’t I?
We’d better turn back.
You can buy me a soda.
I have no money.
We’ll have to find a way.
We can’t live without money, you know,
and I’m too young to earn any.
No, Pierre, wait.
My father didn’t want me
to take one that night.
Take them all.
No, thank you.
This one’s beautiful.
They’re not really
pieces of a star, right?
Where did you find them?
In the hand of a statue
at Carlos’s place.
I said they were pretty,
so he gave them to me.
Carlos is an artist.
I’m sure we wouldn’t
need to hide around him.
Pierre, look.
What’s wrong?
I don’t know. Nothing.
Nothing?
Maybe I’m getting worse.
You have a headache?
No, it’s something else.
I feel strange.
Ever since we came out here, I’ve
forgotten to think about... before.
What do you mean?
Other days I can’t stop
asking myself... Who was I?
Where do I come from?
What did I used to do?
Today I forgot to think
about those things...
and that frightens me.
When I grow up, I’ll study medicine
and make you all better.
Madeleine? Hello.
How is Pierre?
- Fine.
A friend just got married.
We’re celebrating on
Sunday. Will you two join us?
I’m on duty Sunday.
Felicie or Marguerite
could cover for you.
- Good idea. Will you arrange it?
- Consider it done.
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit...
You look like a calendar...
by Hokusai.
It’s really good.
You did a great job.
While I think of it, take this.
- For me?
- Of course.
I’d have had to pay anyone else.
It’s amazing how much
better you seem lately.
Run along now.
It was no coincidence that we’d
arranged to meet that Sunday...
If Mother Superior had been
there, we’d have been done for.
She’s terrible, and nosy too.
She never stops asking questions.
You’re such a bungler, we’d
have been in a real fix.
You have to make sure
you never run into her.
Sister Marie des Anges
is different. She’s nice.
Did you see how flustered she
was because you were there?
I’m sure she thought
you were very handsome.
- Me?
- I’m sure of it.
She saw your eyes.
- Why did she ask for my address?
It’s only natural. She
thinks you’re my father.
There. We’ve entered our home.
I wondered if you’d forget our ceremony.
No. With you I never forget anything.
Hello.
- That’s Pierre, Madeleine’s boyfriend.
- You think that’s his daughter?
How’s the fishing?
Pierre, look!
You see what that
strange fellow is doing?
He has some nerve. That’s my tree.
He has no right.
Don’t you like my painting?
It’s pretty, isn’t it?
It’s a good likeness.
That’s not what I mean. It’s my tree.
Someone I love gave it to me.
I don’t want it taken away.
I’m not taking it away. I’m drawing it.
Same thing. It’s my very own tree.
Children are charming but cruel...
of course.
When I see something
beautiful, I have to paint it.
I can’t help it.
But my only spare time is on Sundays.
On top of that, my wife disapproves.
She doesn’t appreciate my passion.
- What’s your name?
- Come play with us.
And when I say she disapproves,
that’s putting it very kindly.
Pierre, may I go play blindman’s bluff?
Just one game, okay?
You’re it.
Come on, hide!
Who hit you, Charles?
That man over there?
Yes.
You big brute, you should be ashamed!
Are you crazy?
I’m calling my husband. Fernand!
Creep!
What’s wrong?
How dare you ask that!
I could have been attacked
and your son killed,
while you’re off playing battleships!
Pierre, you’re very mean.
You don’t hit someone
smaller than yourself.
Don’t cry.
Don’t cry anymore.
He was annoying you.
That’s not true.
You don’t understand
at all. We were playing.
And you -
Even my mean grandmother
never slapped me.
I’ll never do it again.
I promise.
I should hope not.
Or else I won’t love you
anymore, and I’ll never marry you.
You’ll be left all alone.
Why do you look at him like that?
I’m sure he would
never hit a little boy.
But he doesn’t know you.
Pierre, would you by
any chance be jealous?
Want to be a sweetheart?
Carry me in your arms.
On the palace steps
There is such a pretty girl
Such a pretty girl
She has so many suitors
She doesn’t know which to choose
I was dreaming. It was Christmas.
There was a big fir tree
with stars and garlands.
I gave you a magnificent present,
and you gave me the steeple cock.
And you carried me in your
arms around the tree, like now.
I was looking at the world upside down,
like when you’re dead.
If you knew how nice this feels!
Like I’m flying.
Don’t stop. Keep going.
We drank sparkling champagne,
and I fell asleep in a
big bed next to my Pierre,
with my hand in yours.
On the palace steps
There is such a pretty girl
Such a pretty girl
There is such a pretty
girl Such a pretty girl
On the palace steps
There is such a pretty
girl Such a pretty girl
Keep singing, Pierre.
Oh, Pierre, you were singing.
You’re happy.
You know...
I’ve heard you singing
several times now.
Why do you push me away?
Don’t you want me anymore?
Darling...
understand.
I love you, Pierre.
The rest doesn’t matter.
If you want me again...
your slave will be right here.
But right now she has
to make herself pretty.
I haven’t told you
yet: I have a surprise.
You’re going to put on a white shirt,
a tie, and your suit.
And I’m going to put on
my sexy dress, the one that -
We’re invited to lunch
to celebrate a wedding.
You remember Bernard?
Thanks to him, I got the day off.
We’re having lunch at a restaurant
with his friend who got married.
They’re coming by to pick us up.
Are you pleased?
I’m so happy to have a whole
Sunday with you at last.
And I want to look very beautiful...
for you.
Bernard will be jealous.
I told you he flirted with
me when I started there.
In a friendly way, of course.
But if I’d wanted -
Not many ladies there can boast
that they resisted his advances.
But I have my Pierre,
and the rest -
Stop. That’s Pierre. Where’s he going?
Hey, Pierre!
It’s the guy who lives with Madeleine.
He was shot down in a plane and
found half dead in a remote village.
Come on, we’ll take you back.
That’s how he ended up
at the country hospital
where Madeleine was a nurse.
Madeleine, what’s going on?
Bernard, Pierre’s gone.
Where were you?
You’ll drive me mad.
We saw him on the street,
on his way to see your
friend the sculptor.
I wanted to tell Carlos
we’d been invited out.
But why run off like
that without a word?
I was worried sick.
You can’t imagine what I thought.
Madeleine, you think too much.
Get dressed now.
I’ll get the others to wait.
We thought you’d be ready.
Darling, are you dreaming?
No, I’m just looking.
Don’t you want any more to eat?
Come closer.
- What time is it?
- Why? Are you tired?
Frangoise, give me your
glass. Don’t drink it all.
To your love life, Pierre.
Corot used to come here to paint.
His poetic charm, the
chiaroscuro of his woodlands -
he got it all here.
You should have been an art
critic, not a pharmacist.
He read all that in a guidebook.
It’s a cultural resource like any other.
Please, what time is it?
You don’t drink champagne like water.
Now I’ll tell you the story
of the acupuncturist and the balloon.
Can’t you be quiet for five minutes?
Your loss. You’d burst with laughter.
Frangoise, I’m going to tell you one.
It’s a story without words.
I need a big spoon and a little spoon.
You accompany me by rubbing the
edge of a glass with a wet finger.
Now, try to understand.
There, Pierre. We’re home.
You know the blue stone you gave me?
I still have it.
When they turn the lights
out in the dormitory,
I put it on my pillow and look at it...
as hard as my grandmother
looks in her magic ball,
and I repeat “Pierre... Pierre...”
until you appear.
Then I talk to you.
One night you kissed me.
You know how that happened?
The little blue stone
rolled down the pillow
and touched my shoulder
like two Ups.
If I hadn’t woken up just then...
I’d never have known if
it was for real or not.
You never kiss me.
I love you, Pierre.
I love you.
Take me away, Pierre.
Pierre, what’s wrong? What do you want?
What time is it?
Why? You have an appointment?
You should give him a watch.
He has no notion of time.
Or too keen of one.
It’s not late, darling. Four o’clock.
But if you’re tired, we’ll go home.
You never kiss me.
Miss!
The check, please.
Pierre, are you coming? We’re leaving.
Look, your face is all wet.
You’ll catch cold and
get a headache again.
What’s he doing? Where’s he going?
I want to go home.
- In just a bit.
- No, right now.
They want to visit the fair.
We can’t refuse. It’ll be fun.
There’s too much noise.
Do it to please me, or
at least to be polite.
You looked glum all through lunch.
You might try to be nice.
Are the lovebirds having a little nap?
I’m sure there are
intelligent people among you
who are convinced that
fate influences their lives.
Don’t hesitate. I’ll tell it like it is.
The truth -that’s what you’ll get.
- Today’s the day to try it.
- No, out of the question!
Things like that frighten me.
You, young man.
In your face I see a great future.
No, it’s the past that interests him.
I read the past just as well.
Go on. You caught her eye.
Sure! The clairvoyant
rescues the amnesiac.
Very funny. And intelligent too.
Let’s move on.
- I want to go in.
This is silly. Let’s go home.
Don’t make a scene. We’re
here to have fun, right?
No, madame. Each person
has their own truth,
and each must wait their turn.
Daylight is no friend
to mystery, young man.
Sit down.
It’s 1,500 for a full
reading. All right?
You’re quite the generous one.
Give me your hands.
You had an accident.
A serious one.
Yes, I see it now. Very serious.
Look into my eyes or
I can’t see anything.
That’s better.
Wait.
I see the sun...
trees, the sea.
You’ve traveled.
Clouds. Wait.
You’re fighting.
I see fire... flames.
You know what I’m talking about?
That’s the hair of a Hindu priestess.
Just for decoration.
- And this?
- That?
That’s a sorcerer’s dagger.
It’s from Africa.
You stick it in a tree and
put your ear to the handle,
and you commune with the spirits.
It’s full of fluid,
in case you’re curious.
Should I tell you your love life?
Give me your hand.
No, your left hand.
Oh, my!
You’re loved very much!
Wait. I see...
see...
What did she tell you?
She said I was loved very much.
You have your license?
What?
Serves you right, road hog!
Let me go!
Leave him alone!
Clear the rink or I’ll call the cops!
Well, kids...
My money’s on your pal.
He’s a real champion.
This is all your fault.
You made him drink.
That takes the cake! Now it’s my fault.
It’s the last time I get
involved with loonies.
That’s enough now.
We’ll carry him upstairs.
I’ll stay if you like.
Thanks. I can look after him myself.
Darling, forgive me.
It’s my fault.
I’m such an idiot.
Excuse me, sir, but
it’s about Frangoise.
Come in.
That won’t be necessary.
Besides, I’m not alone.
Another sister is waiting
for me at the pharmacy.
I mustn’t be long.
What is it?
It’s not serious. Don’t worry.
Frangoise is ill. Well, not really ill.
She’s a very sensitive child,
and you didn’t come for her on Sunday.
You’d promised to take
her out, hadn’t you?
That’s the cause of the trouble.
She imagines you don’t love her anymore,
that you’re going to abandon her.
She’s such an excitable
child, so extreme.
And since sick children
can have visitors,
I took the liberty of coming to get you.
Frangoise, your daddy’s here.
I’ll leave you for a while.
I wanted to come last
Sunday. We were invited out.
It’s not my fault that
I couldn’t let you know.
It didn’t end until past 4:00.
Too late.
You remember the other Sunday?
You had a dream about Christmas.
The tree, the stars, the garlands.
I’m going to do all that.
If you won’t look at me, I’m going.
No, stay!
Pierre, you abandoned me.
Who was she?
- Madeleine.
- So she’s your wife?
- No.
Liar. Why did she kiss you like that?
Some manners!
She deserved a good punch,
but you shouldn’t have.
It was awful.
You frightened me.
I suppose you don’t love me anymore.
Of course I love you.
What a mess, I must say.
What did you say you
wanted to do for Christmas?
Like in your dream.
You’re crazy! What will your wife say?
She won’t know about it.
I’ve been thinking,
and I’ve got it all worked out.
Have you seen Pierre?
He must be at the boarding school.
One of the nuns stopped
by your place on a bike.
Two pounds of oranges, please.
Charles, what should I give her?
- Give her the Maltese.
- I’ll pick some out.
And a bit later he practically
ran out of the building.
Perhaps the little girl’s ill.
- Little girl?
- I forgot the biscuits.
Please add them to my bill.
Don’t get so worked up.
It’s probably not serious.
No...
I’m just a bit tired these days.
Yes, he went to see the child.
He should have left me a note.
Thank you.
What did you tell her?
Remember the pretty little girl we
see with him Sundays at the pond?
Yes. But she looked upset.
What’s wrong with her?
It can 7 be.
Oh, Carlos...
he must have met a little
girl from the boarding school.
He’s managed to see her every Sunday.
That’s why he said he was with you...
or that he’d gone to the
station to watch the trains.
He was lying.
The neighbors thought
she was his daughter.
They thought / knew all about it.
But that’s all very sweet.
Something’s not right
if he hid it from me.
He’s scared of me.
My only chance was to gain
his complete confidence...
so we could begin a real life together.
A normal life.
He never spoke to you about all this?
No, but you mustn’t get so worked up.
It’s nothing serious. Pierre loves you.
No, everything’s changed.
And to think I thought
he was doing better.
I even heard him singing once.
Now -
Yesterday we went to the fair.
That morning he’d gone
off without a word.
It was to warn her that
he couldn’t see her.
Yes, of course!
Now I remember clearly.
We were riding the bumper cars.
I saw a little girl from the
boarding school watching us.
I would recognize her now.
It was strange, the
way she looked at us.
It was then that
Pierre seemed to go mad.
He struck me like a brute.
It started a brawl.
When we got him home, he was delirious.
He kept repeating the same words as
when he arrived at the hospital...
half dead.
He kept saying in English, “Is she dead?
Did I kill her?”
You mustn’t mix everything up.
He’s in love.
It’s that simple.
Someone in love naturally has
secrets. Don’t call them lies -
In love with a child?
You think that’s normal?
- I think it’s marvelous.
- Have you gone mad?
What harm do you think he
can do with a little girl?
He’s no Bluebeard.
Pierre’s like a child himself.
With this little girl he’s
found a world where he fits in,
where he’s happy.
Frankly, I’d like to be in his shoes.
You never understand.
Reality isn’t always
like in your dreams!
- Pierre isn’t a child anymore.
- Don’t listen to Carmela.
She’s a good woman, but she
never thinks with her heart.
Listen to me.
I’m telling you this
for your own good...
and for Pierre’s too.
Tell me: Have you looked in his eyes?
Well, I have, and they’re not normal!
And it’s not because he has amnesia.
He probably doesn’t realize
himself that he could be dangerous.
That’s the full moon for you -when
one woman in three goes crazy.
With Carmela it never fails.
Why not just call him a sadist?
Then why does he hide? If
all this is perfectly normal -
When you were a child,
did you tell your parents everything?
Try to understand instead of
brooding over him like a mother hen.
It’s not the same thing.
In any case, she must warn the nuns.
Sure, and kick up a real fuss!
I’m sure his love for
that child is pure.
He’s reliving his childhood.
Just get him to tell you himself.
- But if I ask
him - - Don’t ask.
There’s no point. He’ll just panic.
You have to win back
his confidence first.
He mustn’t feel that he needs you
but that you need him.
I’m sure he wants to tell you about it.
I’d like to believe you, Carlos...
but I have to get to the bottom of this.
Be very careful.
Respect him, Madeleine.
You mustn’t sully something beautiful.
You know, I struck you on Sunday.
I didn’t mean to.
I don’t know what happened.
Perhaps it was all the noise.
There was so much noise and -
It was the noise.
Yes, of course.
We were foolish to take you there.
Christmas is next Monday,
and I have a day off coming.
I can take Sunday or Tuesday.
Which would you prefer?
Tuesday would be best.
I haven’t been to Paris in a long time.
All right. Go on now.
Go on.
Don’t keep Carlos waiting.
There. We’re home now.
Listen.
What can I bring you?
Two warm grenadines.
Two warm grenadines?
Yes.
I mean, no. Two hot toddies.
A hot toddy. Two.
Two hot toddies, please.
Is this like where you went for lunch?
It wasn’t as nice,
but you could see the pond.
You didn’t tell your wife about us?
Good. Are your hands still cold?
Mine are frozen.
Will you tell me your real name someday?
And you? Will you give me
the steeple cock someday?
You think this is a real cafe?
Why?
There’s no one here.
Maybe it’s very expensive.
Do you have enough money?
I think so.
You know, if you ever
stopped coming for me...
I think I’d want to die.
- Die?
- Yes.
To close my eyes.
Turn quite cold.
They’d put me in a coffin...
and nail down the lid.
There’d be no name on my grave...
because no one would know my real name.
Even if they wrote “Frangoise,”
it wouldn’t mean anything.
I wouldn’t exist anymore.
I’ll always come for you.
And if I died, would you die too?
Or go back to your wife
and forget about me?
You’d forget me, huh?
Tell me.
You’d die too?
Yes.
Tomorrow’s Monday.
But I don’t care,
because it’s Christmas...
and you made me a promise.
No, Bertrand! You’ll blind the people!
Higher!
The Lord didn’t favor you, son.
You think people want to
see that scaffolding tonight?
The steeple cock!
Papa!
It’s the man who hit me!
How do you know it was him?
Who else would do such a thing?
And he nearly poked a
neighbor’s eye out with the tree.
I feel bad for my little nephews.
And look at the door. No
need to smash it in like that.
I’m afraid.
You said you saw them
together and understood.
What’s the matter?
Where are you off to?
Where are you going?
I don’t know. To look for them.
I’ll see to my nephews
and call you later.
- May I make a call?
- A Paris number?
You don’t have a booth?
No one here has any secrets.
My dear children, Christmas is
the loveliest day of the year...
What will you have?
...a celebration for the young...
A white wine.
Dry or sweet?
Dry.
Hello, Bernard?
I don’t know what to do.
Pierre hasn’t come home.
He must be with the little girl.
He took a big Christmas
tree from Carlos’s place.
What’s that?
I don’t know.
He must have gone to get her.
Did I call where? The school?
No. Suppose he’s not
with her. Suppose she’s -
Please come. I’ll wait for you.
Hurry.
Rue de Sevres.
Hold on. What’s the address here?
Twenty-two.
How long will you be?
Please hurry. I’ll be waiting.
Bernard, we have to find him,
or I’ll go mad myself!
... electric trains, and
dolls with eyes that dose.
My dear children, Christmas is also...
- What do I owe you?
- With the call, 95 francs.
...to be good little girls and boys...
You haven’t see a man
with a Christmas tree?
Oh, we’ve seen quite a few today.
A big tree... all decorated.
What’s this man look like?
He’s tall and blond,
with very short hair
and light blue eyes.
You don’t mean the Satyr, do you?
- What?
- It’s a joke.
My wife and I call him that
because we see him
every Sunday by the pond,
where we go to fish.
He’s always with a little girl.
You’d think they were lovers.
She must be his daughter,
but since he looks a bit odd,
we nicknamed him the Satyr.
My dear little friends,
even when you’ve grown up,
never miss your rendezvous
with Father Christmas!
Where’d you get all those big candles?
At church.
- They gave them to you?
- Yes.
You’re such a poor liar!
I hope no one saw you take them.
Come look.
Look.
You know, this will be
my first real Christmas.
I’ve always been sent to bed
at 9:00, like any other evening.
Did you cut yourself?
- It broke.
- That’s all right. One will do.
Let me see your finger.
Poor Pierre. Best to let it bleed a bit.
There... all better.
I know all your thoughts now
that I’ve drunk your blood.
Will you open the champagne?
I’ll leave you for a minute.
Don’t turn around.
You know, we should make a wish.
I’d like to stay with
you forever and ever.
We’d go on vacation to the seaside.
I’ve never been to the sea.
We’d see fish that fly.
You laugh, but they really do exist.
There are fish with wings.
I read that in a book.
They must be beautiful.
Let’s drink to make
that happen. Your turn.
I’ve had enough.
Don’t forget I’m a little girl.
Besides, it’s the bubbles I really like.
Well, I’m thirsty.
Pierre, look.
Unfold it.
“Cybele.”
You like it?
It’s your name, your real name.
It’s beautiful.
It sounds like si belle
- so lovely.
It’s my name.
It’s me.
It was the name of a goddess.
The goddess of trees
and earth, so I was told.
It’s an ancient name, you know.
What’s the matter?
Nothing...
but later on...
I’ll have a surprise for you too.
- I thought you’d never get here.
- Have you seen the traffic?
And I stopped by the police
station. I gave them your number.
- What?
- I phoned the school first.
He’d already gotten the
girl, so I told the cops.
I shouldn’t have called
you. You don’t understand.
I saw them last Sunday. They
were like two happy children.
Now the cops think he’s a criminal.
- We can’t take risks.
What risks! You think he’s
going to kill or rape her?
He’s sick. You must expect the worst.
You’re the sick one,
you and Carlos’s wife -
all of you who call yourselves normal.
You reject anyone who finds happiness
outside your conventions. Why?
Does his honesty make you uncomfortable?
Even I began to doubt him.
Let’s not get sentimental.
Pierre’s in a violent phase.
If he subconsciously believes
he killed a little girl once -
You told me so.
If he believes he escaped
punishment, he might kill again
to be punished and be
freed of his obsession.
One must -
“One must!”
You have a lot of common
sense, but no intuition.
We must keep the police out of
this. He’d never get over it.
Call them. Tell them it was a joke -
It’s too late. The nuns
have filed a complaint.
The vertigo...
It’s gone!
- Hello, Pierre?
- No. Who’s this?
Carlos.
Is Madeleine there?
What’s going on?
That was Bernard who answered.
We’re waiting.
Bernard went to the police.
The police! Are you crazy?
You realize what you’ve done?
Listen to me, for your own sake.
This is no time for sentiment.
The line mustn’t be busy when they call.
Madeleine? We were cut off.
I hit the phone with my elbow.
I don’t know what can be
done now, but I’m on my way.
Yes, it’s me.
You found them?
What?
You killed him?
It’s a real miracle.
Two seconds more and
we’d have been too late.
He was approaching the sleeping girl
with a dagger in his hand.
What are you called?
What’s your name?
I have no name now.
I have no name.
I’m nobody now!
I’m nothing!