One October morning
before the first drops
of the long autumn rains
fell on the parched soil,
cutting the town off by
turning the roads to mud,
Futaki was awakened
by the sound of bells.
The solitary chapel was
eight kilometres away,
and had no bell as even its tower
had collapsed during the war.
And the town was too far away
to hear any noise from there.
News of Their Coming
What is it?
Nothing, just go back to sleep.
I'll pick up my share
and leave tonight.
Or tomorrow by the latest.
Tomorrow morning.
- You had a bad dream?
- Yes.
I was sitting in a room.
Suddenly there was a
knock on the window.
I didn't dare to open it.
I peeked through the curtains.
I could only see his back, as he
was trying to get the door open.
And his mouth as he was shouting
something, I couldn't make out what.
His face was unshaven.
His eyes were like glass.
I wanted to cry out,
but I had no voice.
Then, Mrs Halics looked in
through the window, grinning...
You know what she's
like when she grins.
She was looking in, and
then she disappeared.
The man kept kicking the door,
it was about to burst open.
I rushed to the sideboard,
I wanted to open the drawer.
Then I heard the door crashing in.
Whoever he was, he was already
coming down the hallway.
At last I yanked the drawer
open and got the knife out.
And he was coming toward me.
Suddenly he was lying
under the kitchen table,
surrounded by red
and blue saucepans,
clanging and rolling around.
And then the ground
moved under my feet.
The whole kitchen started to move,
as if it were a car.
I was awakened by bells.
Where? Here?
They tolled twice.
- We'll go mad in the end.
- No.
I'm sure something is
going to happen today.
It's my husband, I recognise him.
Hurry.
Listen, do exactly what I tell you.
Is that clear?
Start packing. Move!
We're leaving tonight.
Pack up our clothes, boots,
coats, the radio, everything.
We got to disappear
from here tonight.
You understand?
- You got it?
- You're crazy.
What are you saying?
I've talked to Kráner, we're
off with the money tonight.
If we split it eight ways,
we'll never get away from here.
You think the others will
just go along with it?
Halics, the
schoolmaster and Futaki?
I didn't work for a year
just to give it away now.
They can go to hell.
But it won't come to that.
We can buy the farm
at last, don't you see?
You're out of your
mind. You must be crazy.
Start packing. The jerry-cans,
the lard, flour, bedding...
I left my cane outside.
Get out!
Schmidt, are you in?
You wanted to get away
with the money, isn't it?
I wouldn't have taken you
for someone who'd do that.
I can explain.
Kráner's involved too?
Fifty-fifty.
So, what happens now?
What would happen?
We deal you in too.
We wait till nightfall
and then we set off.
What do you mean?
I mean, we split it three ways.
But don't ruin me.
All I'm asking is
to borrow your share.
Just for a short time... A year.
Until we can find a place
to settle down somewhere.
And where else do you
need me to kiss you?
You said you wouldn't
move anywhere from here.
I don't want to stay here
until the end of my life.
I'm not asking it as
a gift. I want a loan.
I worked as much as the others.
And now you're
talking about "a loan".
So you don't trust me?
Of course not.
You're siding with Kráner.
You want to get away
with all the money.
And I should trust
you after all this?
- What about the others?
- How would I know?
We've got to wait till
dark before we leave.
We said the same to Kráner. We
meet at the cross after dark.
Why did you come back?
We only thought of it
on the way back home.
And leave the woman behind?
That's true. She's really worth it.
- And the Kráners?
- They want to go north.
Kraner's wife heard about
a lumber yard there...
It's raining.
I can hear it.
I'm going south, winters
are shorter there.
I'll rent a farm.
Close to a prosperous town.
Soak my feet all day
in a basin of hot water.
Or...
I'll be a watchman in
a chocolate factory.
Or a porter in a girls' dorm.
And try to forget everything.
A basin of hot water
and nothing to do.
Only watch the fucking life go by.
Where the hell do we wanna go?
We'd be caught by the
police in the first town.
They wouldn't even ask our names.
- Your pocket is full of money.
- That's just the point.
Pack a suitcase and go
like a bunch of beggars.
- None of your business.
- Pardon?
Nothing.
Quiet or he'll wake up.
What are we waiting for?
Why don't we divide the money?
Can't it wait?
Let's divide it now.
Don't worry, you'll get your share.
Let's wait till Kráner
gives us the other half.
It's all very simple.
We'll split what you have.
And the rest, when we get it,
we'll split at the crucifix.
Fetch me the flashlight.
The document...
To see the money better.
So you see I'm not cheating.
Let's count it.
It's exactly that.
Mrs Schmidt! Are you in?
- Mrs Schmidt?
- Hide it quickly.
Get rid of her.
If she sets foot in
here I will strangle her.
- Will your wife be gone for a while?
- I will smash her face.
- What did she want?
- She's gone crazy.
She's saying that Irimiás and
Petrina are coming on the road.
And perhaps they are
already in the pub.
And that they may...
have already arrived.
The conductor's seen them leave.
He also said he'd seen
them arriving in the town.
Then at the Elek crossroad.
They are coming here.
The Bible's driven her mad.
- But what if it's really true?
- Well, if it's so...
They died a year and a half
ago, everybody knows that.
Don't fall for that, it's a trap.
It is possible that Sanyi
Horgos has just simply lied?
- We heard it from him, too.
- Dead for a year and a half!
I suspected it then, but
nobody listened to me.
He told us a lie. Of
course he was lying.
You're out of your minds.
Everything's going
to change, you'll see.
Irimiés is a wizard.
He could build a castle
even out of cow shit...
...if he wants to.
No way.
- You won't screw up my plans.
- I don't intend to.
A dead man comes
back to life? Futaki!
You, at least, should
have more sense.
They suspect something
and want to catch us out.
- I'm going to the pub.
- It might be true.
Damn fools.
If they are here, you
can't run from Irimiás.
You know that. Right?
You're damn fools.
- If you don't believe it...
- Go to hell.
But you'd better leave my
money here on the table.
If you don't believe this
then let your wife go first.
And the money?
Well... let's leave it where it is.
You must trust her, don't you?
Then I'll go.
Have you heard? They're here.
My husband is off already,
he just sent me to tell you.
But you should know.
We saw Mrs Halics here.
I go now, I do not want to bother
you. My husband says, "Fuck the money."
This is not for us. Be on the run
for it? Not having a peaceful night?
No way! Irimiás and
Petrina, you'll see...
I always knew the shifty-eyed
Horgos kid made the whole thing up.
You too can see it, he just made it all
up. And we believed it from the start.
- You're in it too!
- Let them come, I don't care.
So, we're going?
So Schmidt went first.
Futaki staggered behind him.
He was trying to feel his
way with his cane in the dark.
And the relentless rain
blended Schmidt's swearing
with Futaki's cheery,
encouraging words, as he repeated,
"Never mind, old man, you'll
see. We'll have a great life!
'34 great life!"
We shall be resurrected!
The two clocks show
different times.
Both wrong, of course.
This one here is too slow.
The other, as if it shows the
perpetuity of defencelessness.
We only relate to it
as twigs to the rain.
We are unable to defend ourselves.
Twigs and rain?
You're a great poet, I tell you.
- Do you think there's a snack bar here?
- I don't think so.
What are you waiting for?
- We were summoned.
- Let me see.
Can't you read? What floor is this?
- The second.
- Just follow me.
Identification.
Can I have the summons
and your identity cards?
Fill this out and read the
information on the back.
Follow me.
- Irimiés?
- Yes. That's me.
Sit down.
- You're a gypsy?
- No. My name's Petrina.
Petrina? What kind
of a name is that?
Romanian.
- Did you know your mother?
- No.
Irimiés.
So here...
It all depends on what mood I'm in.
Let me ask you.
Since you've been released, why
haven't you looked for a job?
I'm sure you've been busy,
but you could've tried.
You're under
surveillance, after all.
And it is crystal clear that it didn't
occur to you at all to find a job.
You know us, Captain.
Not that well.
You mean your future?
But you're a young man.
I'm not in love with my job either,
but do you really
want to be out of work
the rest of your life?
Yes.
Here's this document,
see, it says that
you do not respect work,
or those who work hard.
Nice words.
But the years will go by one day.
Do you have a wife and kids?
You expect your son to
support you, or what?
When your leg is broken,
or you break your back,
you have a head injury,
serious things, when you can't
look after yourself anymore.
We're on the side of
the law, just like you.
We know the law and we
haven't broken it so far.
According to this document
all you've done is break it.
- No.
- And with considerable effort.
That's just what it looks like.
And so what is the truth if
that's just what it "looks like"?
That we're law-abiding.
- And why start right now?
- We didn't just start now.
You've respected the law
from your early childhood?
- That's right.
- My grandfather respected it.
That was your grandfather, not you.
Talk about yourself, not
about your grandfather.
We're loyal citizens of
this country, Captain.
Let me remind you, our services
have been used for many years.
How did this happen?
Don't call your lives a tragedy.
Be humble, no tragedy.
- You know us, Captain.
- Of course I do.
But this is not a tragedy,
it's plain villainy.
Why don't we leave
everything as before?
Leave it as before? You'll
never want to change?
Not that human life
is so highly valued.
Keeping order may seem to be the
responsibility of the authorities.
But lately it's the business
of the people. The order.
In freedom, there is,
however, something not human,
but rather, divine.
But our lives are too short for
us to find out this properly.
If you searching for a link between
order and freedom, think of Pericles.
He said order and freedom
are linked by passion.
We have to believe in both,
as we suffer from both.
Both from order and freedom.
But human life is meaningful,
rich, beautiful and filthy.
It encompasses everything.
But we abuse freedom, wasting
it as if it were just some junk.
People don't like freedom.
They are afraid of it.
This is strange, because there is
nothing to fear when it comes to freedom.
Order, on the other hand,
can often be frightening.
But I must draw your
attention to certain points.
The fact of the matter is,
you have no choice
but to cooperate.
And my point is, that if
you really respect the law,
then, it is obvious, that I'm
just a little ahead of you in this.
Practically you have... offered it.
We do respect you a lot, Captain...
Not "captain". The law!
But you're the law itself, Captain.
Oh, no. The law, that's
all of us together.
Why not leave things as they are?
Right now you, for
instance, are outlaws.
And you know very well why.
I suppose I do not have
to read out the lot.
I won't say this again.
From now on, you either work for me
or... well, I have to say,
you really have no choice.
Mr Irimiás.
You can go now.
Two rum and liqueurs.
And a pack of cigarettes.
- Large ones I meant.
- Sorry.
Move aside, please.
May I just remind
you of the cigarettes?
Sorry, I forgot.
May we ask what's so funny?
Nothing. Sorry.
Can you hear that?
What is it?
A machine?
The lights?
Someone's singing?
Who would dare to sing in here?
Quiet!
We'll blow everything up.
- Should we call the police?
- There's no need.
We'll blow them all up.
We'll plant explosives in their
jackets... or in their ears.
We'll stick the
dynamite up their noses.
We'll have to stop this
somehow, don't you think?
Sure, why complicate things?
We'll blow them up one by one.
We'll kill them all.
In a very short time.
How do you know
they're still there?
I think they had ran away long
time ago if they have any sense.
Them? They were servants and
will remain so all their lives.
They sit in the kitchen,
shit in the corner,
now and then they look out the
window to see what others do.
I know them inside out.
What makes you so sure?
I think nobody's there. The houses
are empty, the roof tiles are stolen...
At best, one or two rats are
in the mill, all skin and bone.
They just sit on the
same dirty stools.
Stuff themselves with potatoes
and don't know what's happened.
They eye each other suspiciously
as they belch away in the silence,
and wait determinedly, because
they think they had been cheated.
They are slaves who
have lost their master.
They can't live without
pride, dignity and courage,
but they don't feel such
qualities reside within them.
They only know how to live
in the shadow of such things.
Cut it out, will you?
They follow that shadow,
like lemmings, off a cliff.
They can't live
without their fantasies.
But when they get too
close, they can't handle it.
What they really need is a heated
room and a bowl of hot paprika stew.
They're happy if at
night, under a warm quilt
they find the
neighbour's chubby wife.
- Are you listening at all?
- Sure, whatever.
- I've been waiting for you for a while.
- How'd you know we were coming?
- From the conductor.
- What conductor?
- Kelemen.
- Why? Kelemen became a conductor?
Since the spring, on the coach.
But the coach doesn't run now.
You promised that if I spread the
rumour on the farm that you had died,
you'd hook me up with Mrs Schmidt.
I keep my promises.
And you promised me Mrs Kráner.
She has nice tits, that one.
That will happen too, Sanyi.
Since you left here,
not much has changed.
The schoolmaster's
still at home, alone.
Mrs Schmidt's with Futaki.
You know, the cripple.
My younger sister is totally
crazy. Spies on everybody.
My mum tries to beat the crazy out of her,
but everyone knows she's nuts for life.
The Doctor broods at home.
He sits in his armchair, leaves
the lights on all the time.
Sometimes he sleeps in his chair.
His place smells like hell, even
though he smokes good cigarettes.
Drinks a lot of fruit brandy.
Mrs Kráner keeps him supplied.
Schmidt and Kráner are bringing
the money for the cattle today.
Everyone's been doing that
since February, except Mum.
Those bastards didn't include her,
they are happy to have lots of money.
The bar owner's sold
his good Pannonia
and bought a piece of crap you
have to push to get started.
He uses that to go to town
to see his wife once a month,
although now he lives at my
sister's because we still owe him
for what he lent us
to buy seeds last year.
In the east, the sky clears as
fast as a memory is forgotten.
At dawn, it leans all
red on the waving horizon.
In the same way the beggar trudges
up the back steps of a church,
the sun rises to give
life to the shadows,
and to separate earth
and sky, man and animal,
from the disturbing, strange unity
in which they became
inextricably intertwined.
He saw the fleeing
night on the other side,
as its terrifying elements
disappear on the western horizon,
like a desperate,
defeated, confused army.
To know something
Futaki... it seems...
...is afraid... of something.
Early... morning... startled...
...he was looking...
out... of the window.
Futaki...
...is terrified...
he's afraid of death.
They'll die anyway. You
too, Futaki, you'll die too.
Schmidt... leaves
through... the back door...
...and stands... on top of...
...the path to... Sodic Park.
Futaki... quietly... slips
out of... the house...
...crosses... over
to the stables...
...and hides... by the wall.
F. doesn't move.
He waits... for a moment...
...then... he too...
dashes... over to the door...
...knocks, and... enters
quickly... after Schmidt.
What a... hustle and bustle.
It has started... to rain.
It won't... stop... till... spring.
It is fascinating to see,
the erosion caused
by water and wind
at the edge of the Ponticum,
when the sea on the Great
Plain had significantly receded
and it looked like a shallow
lake, like Lake Balaton does now.
Good morning, Doctor.
Quickly, Doctor,
don't let it get cold.
Take it away.
You see, it's raining,
we'll soon have snow, too.
My husband and I feel, it would be
good if you could talk to the pub owner.
He has a car, he could
bring you this stuff.
You mean you won't anymore?
I will, but I can't go on
foot into town in this rain.
Besides, he has a car and could do
your shopping for two or three weeks.
The bus only starts
running again in spring.
It's all right, Mrs
Kráner, you can go.
Then you'll talk to the pub owner?
I'll talk to whoever I want to!
- Where shall I put the keys?
- Wherever you want it.
Good bye.
K. has quit.
She can't...
...do it... any longer.
Last autumn... she didn't...
...mind...
...the rain...
...nor that...
...she had to... walk.
K. has...
...a specific plan.
She's thinking... about
something... in her head.
It seems I got pretty drunk.
Today I ran out... of the
last drop... of fruit brandy.
It looks like I need...
...to leave... the house.
Come on, cut that out.
You hear me? Stop that.
Look after the fire
instead, I'm cold.
I'll look after my arse, man.
I've just looked after
it... You're next.
- You hear me?
- All right, all right.
We're going to freeze again.
- How long are we supposed to wait?
- How do I know?
Leave me alone.
To hell with the whole thing.
Stop whining. Someone's coming.
Good evening.
Haven't seen you for ages, Doc.
Feel like a screw?
I'd like to warm up a
bit if you don't mind.
- Only warm up, Doc?
- Yes.
And what about a good
fuck like in the old days?
Come on, Doctor. It
doesn't cost much.
For such an old friend.
Could I have a cigarette?
- Right there, at your feet.
- Thank you.
- How's business going?
- Bad.
You see, we just sit here
day after day and nothing.
We're all nerves, we
almost go at each other.
What's going to become of us, Doc?
It's the way a person loses
heart in the whole thing.
What do you think we live on?
We have Sanyi living with
us, crazy Estike, Mum too.
They keep asking where's the money?
Give it to them.
The money this, the money that,
but who cares?
We'll leave here anyway.
We'll move to town.
Cut the crap. Either go or stay.
It would make you happy if
I cleared off, wouldn't it?
Today, when they
finally get the money?
They're not coming. They
should've arrived ages ago.
They'll come. I know them.
When they've got money,
they run after their dicks.
You think Kráner admits to
the whole amount at home?
There will be a hell of
a lot of money here today!
- Can I have a cigarette for the road?
- Sure.
- Matches?
- Take them.
So, you won't change
your mind, Doctor?
No. Good luck.
You too.
He hasn't got a lot of time left.
You'd hardly recognise him.
What the hell is he
doing here in the rain?
He hardly leaves the house. Now
he comes out in this weather?
Idiot. Didn't you see the bottle?
Goes to pick up his brandy.
He doesn't even have the
money to pay Mrs Kráner.
- Doctor.
- What do you want?
- What are you doing? Let me go.
- Leave me, go now, you brat.
- Doctor!
Leave me alone, you brat.
Fucking hell.
Where are you going now? Wait.
Where are you going?
Stop!
I won't hurt you.
Where are you running?
Wait.
Hallo, hallo...
Now there...
Time to get off.
"My heart," he
thought, over and over.
He longed to lie in a warm room,
to be taken care of
by sweet little nurses,
sipping his hot soup,
then turning towards the wall.
He felt light and easy,
though the conductor's scolding
words echoed long in his ears.
"You shouldn't have
done it, Doctor.
"You shouldn't have done it."
INTERMISSION
The work of the spider I
You could light a fire.
I could.
I said, you could light a fire.
Stop this.
A litre.
Pick up the hundred for me too.
You only got the
denomination wrong.
Don't worry, pinhead.
I won't do you any
harm. Just quit pointing.
It's raining.
Awful weather.
Yeah.
It destroys everything.
Look at this coat, what
it looks like on me.
This used to be as soft as butter,
and now, it's so dried out,
if I want to sit down,
I have to break it.
Look.
Here, at my groin, with
the edge of my hand.
That's how I do it.
Flexibility, you know,
that's what's missing.
Totally missing.
Then the wind, it can't
keep that out either.
The whole thing's creased. The
leather's crumbling, you see.
You go here and there. Can't
sit inside all the time.
And it gets soaked
inside and outside...
Because the worst is not out there,
but in here.
You haven't heard of the
inside rains, of course not.
You've been saying this for years.
They bathe your
organs night and day.
They come from the heart,
and wash the liver, the stomach,
the spleen and the kidneys.
I am soaking wet.
If it were not for this coat,
I don't know what'd happen.
I don't even dare unbutton it.
A glass of wine
would, of course, help.
Then there's the constant
demand from the liver,
the stomach, the
spleen and the kidneys.
They have to work all the time.
Without a break.
Then this constant
drenching can turn into
a sudden drying out.
Which can soon... turn fatal.
Listen, give me a glass.
Schmidt and Kráner will
be here soon anyway,
they will count what
I'm supposed to get.
Fine.
Nice little wine.
Give me one more.
He's fallen asleep.
How much you think this
one's supposed to eat?
It doesn't eat, it devours.
It can eat half a pig in one
go. Would you believe that?
I would.
That was very close.
Irimiés and Petrina are
coming toward the yard.
- They can't be.
- It's as true as I'm here.
The hauler from the
lumber yard was there,
two loaders...
...the schoolmaster,
the PE teacher...
...and the night barman
from the station café.
And I sat there.
Just sat there!
I couldn't believe my eyes.
And... there they were!
Irimiés and Petrina,
drinking rum and liqueurs!
I waited till they drank up,
and went up to them.
Irimiés gave me a hug and asked,
"Kelemen! How's it going?"
Then he told me everything.
Then off we went.
I had to see Hochan the butcher.
Then... I met young Tóth,
who used to be my
neighbour in Péstanya.
He told me that Irimiás
had been at the Steigerwald's
and talked about gunpowder.
The Steigerwald kids were
talking about it in the street.
And when I was on my way back...
...and turned off...
...at the Elek crossroad...
...I caught sight of them.
And then I understood,
what, how, and why.
Irimiés! Petrina!
I'll get rid of them, drunken pigs!
I'll turn the lights off
and board up the place.
Irimiés and Petrina! They
can't take what is mine.
Mine! Everything
here is mine! Mine!
Irimiés! Petrina!
Everything is mine! Mine!
Petrina!
Then I went up to them.
Irimiés hugged me and said warmly,
"Kelemen! How's it going?"
And right away he bought a round.
The waitresses smiled and
jumped to it like grasshoppers.
And then he told me everything.
So tell me, have you
learned your lesson?
What lesson?
Leave me alone. I've
learned all I need to.
You've never learned anything.
You just keep drinking.
I've learned it all, you old witch.
I want no one meddling
in my business.
In the book of your fate though,
this resurrection is written.
- Don't give me that nonsense.
- But you just go on boozing.
Boozing, sure I'm boozing.
Listen, you witch, why
do you think I'm here?
I came to drink, not to look
pretty for the likes of you.
You know what's waiting
for the likes of you?
No one happens to
be waiting for me.
The blackest fire of hell.
You may have seen a black fucking
arse, but not a black fire,
so fuck the black arse and the fire
and go to fucking hell. That's it.
You think they'll stand
for this forever up there?
No.
Think they sit up
there and just ignore
this Sodom and Gomorrah?
That's exactly it.
There'll be weeping and
mourning, as the prophet says.
No Creation. Spritzer!
Creation is a spritzer.
- None of your business.
- He's always like that, sorry.
A hell of a witch.
Old cobwebbed cunt.
You'd better read this.
Leave the poor thing alone.
Get him a spritzer instead.
Spritzer withdrawal
is a kind of murder.
Don't read Genesis, you poor thing.
That's a mystery.
Read Revelation.
You know what we're
all waiting for?
If you haven't heard it
before, for you to go to hell.
But there's no use waiting, it
doesn't matter if you go away.
It doesn't matter if we
can't see you or hear you.
You'll leave your stench behind.
It lasts forever.
It's no use opening a
window and airing the room.
It remains.
Mrs Schmidt.
Halics can't imagine what
happened to your husband.
You see, this lousy weather.
What can I get you?
- Some cherry pálinka?
- I don't really know.
A small one.
- Have you heard it?
- Are you sure that they must be them?
Must be.
They'll be here in the morning.
They'll be here by midnight.
Takes three hours to get here.
- It's not three hours.
- Why isn't it three hours?
Because it takes much longer.
Won't be any arrivals
before the morning.
Why the morning?
If the three hours
took me three hours,
the three hours will
take them four hours.
They will be here by midnight.
By morning, that road is
full of potholes and ruts.
They'll go round the potholes.
They'll avoid the ruts.
They won't go through the
potholes, or the ruts, you're right,
so they won't be here by
midnight, but by morning.
By morning if they use
the road. I come from here.
They can only come by that
road, they'll only walk on that,
- they care about their shoes.
- Their shoes?
Yes, their shoes. That
road is a long way round.
It's soaked.
It's like having to
go around the sea.
Their shoes! Never mind them.
They'll be here by midnight.
They weren't soaking wet.
The road goes by the fire.
Are you from here?
Have you been there?
I saw them, I kept
going, and I came here.
I saw them, and they'll
be here by midnight.
They're coming by the road and
won't be here before morning.
- Don't give me that.
- They can only come by the road
and that takes a turn
like going round the sea.
Don't give me that, I'm from here.
What's wrong with
this fucking stove?
This is a pub, not a waiting room.
- What time is it?
- 11.
At the latest... 11 or 12.
Who's taken my wine?
You spilled it.
- You're a liar, fool.
- You spilled it.
Then get me another one.
What's that smell?
There wasn't one a minute ago.
Just the spiders
or the coal.
No.
It's the earth.
Unravelling
Come on.
Give me the money.
See, with the knot upwards...
Are you sure the moneystalk
starts sprouting in four days?
Sure. But only if you give
it enough water every day.
- We're going to be rich?
- Sure.
- The others will envy us?
- Of course.
I can stay in the
best room that night?
Yes.
Here, take that home.
Hi. Come on in.
What's up?
Where is your place?
Stay right there.
Behave yourself.
You've made a mess in your pants.
You have a lot of nerve.
I can do whatever I want to you.
I'm stronger than you are.
Come on now.
Come on.
You're dead! I won't
feel sorry for you.
So come on, then. Come on.
See you soon.
Sanyi!
Sanyi, come here! The
moneystalk's been robbed.
- Oh, come on.
- The money's been stolen, too.
It wasn't stolen, I needed
it. It was for me anyway.
- It was my money, too.
- Oh, go away.
- Why? Did you know?
- Get your hands off me!
Go away now. I said go away!
I won't say it again.
Come back here. I said, come back!
I said, come here!
Come on, move it!
Rat poison. You
stole it, didn't you?
You stole it.
And you have the whole
house exterminated, right?
Now, here, but be careful,
I'll have my eye on you.
And now clear off.
I said, clear off.
- Doctor!
- What do you want?
- Let me go. Little brat!
Fucking hell!
What the hell do you want?
Come on, tell me.
What do you want?
Where are you going? Stop
now. I won't hurt you.
Stop!
I won't do you any harm!
"Yes," she said to herself softly.
The angels see this and understand.
She felt peace inside, and
around her the trees, the road,
the rain and the night
all breathed tranquillity.
Everything that happens
is good, she thought.
Everything was, eventually, simple.
She recalled the previous day,
and, smiling, she realised
how things are connected.
She felt that these events
aren't connected by accident,
but there's an indescribably
beautiful meaning bridging them.
And she knew she wasn't alone,
for all things and people,
her father up there, her
mother, her brothers, the doctor,
the cat, these acacias,
this muddy road, this sky,
this night down
here depended on her,
just as she herself
depended on everything.
She had no reason to be worried.
She knew well that her angels
had set out to collect her.
The Work of the Spider ll
(The Devil's Tit, Satantango)
I was plodding and plodding,
just plodding along.
The Steigerwald kids and
Hochan the butcher, the girls,
as they jumped like grasshoppers
when Irimiás hugged me
and asked, "How's
it going, Kelemen?"
and bought a round
and told me everything,
and they were drinking rum liqueur,
even then I was
plodding and plodding
and plodding and plodding along.
They'll be here. They'll
be here in the yard.
They'll be here. The Tóth kid,
Irimiás...
...and they've been
to the Steigerwalds.
And as I was plodding
along, when it became clear
they were leaving for the
yard, then I knew everything.
Irimiés and Petrina were
coming toward the yard.
I met Hochan the butcher and
I bumped into the Tóth kid.
And as I was plodding along,
for I had to plod...
...and saw them by the road,
revelation which
way... why... where to
and the plodding, the why,
the where to and the which way,
the Tóth kid, the Steigerwald kids,
Irimiás and Petrina
and the gunpowder
at the Steigerwald's.
And the Steigerwald kids
talking about gunpowder,
and me plodding and plodding...
And the Steigerwald kids
were talking about gunpowder.
And the Steigerwald kids,
talking about gunpowder...
But the Tóth kid,
he was there... at
the Weighing bridge.
- Put some soda in it.
- I've already put some in.
- And the Steigerwald kids...
- A bottle of wine.
Gunpowder's not gun-powder. They
were talking about gunpowder.
- Careful or it goes to your
head. - Not gun-powder, gunpowder.
I was plodding, plodding along...
Gunpowder's not gun-powder!
Gunpowder! It's not gun-powder!
He hugged me... The waitresses
jumped like grasshoppers...
They were drinking rum and liqueur.
I know I shouldn't drink any more
because it will go to my head.
I was plodding, plodding along...
You're offering it so invitingly.
Just goes straight to your head!
You're pissed to the eyeballs.
As you plod along
you learn everything.
Don't fucking give her another!
Can't you see the state of her?
I shouldn't drink. When I do,
I keep thinking of coffins.
...the Steigerwald's
and Irimiás hugged me,
the girls jumped like grasshoppers,
and bought a round,
drinking rum and liqueur
and he told me everything
and I'm plodding, plodding,
plodding, plodding, and plodding,
plodding and
plodding, and plodding.
But there's a huge
difference between plodding
and plodding along.
I knew exactly when I
saw them at the junction,
why, how, which way, why and how...
I'm plodding, plodding,
plodding, and how am I plodding?
How am I plodding?
The gunpowder, the
Steigerwalds, the Tóth kid...
The whole street was talking,
that they're hiding gunpowder.
Why did they do this? And
why are they coming here?
I know why they're coming
because I had a revelation...
It's too hot in here.
János, please do something.
You don't begrudge the coal?
They are coming at the road
junction. I know exactly why.
Why, why and why they're
coming and why they're coming.
- It's nice and warm in here...
- You let him, dickhead?
What the hell you want? At least
there's something for the others.
For I was plodding and
plodding and plodding along...
They're coming and coming...
- This is not a whorehouse.
- What, then?
...coming and coming. They
stop but they're coming!
Let's go to the mill.
They'll get here.
In a few minutes...
- Where the hell are you going?
- Nowhere, honey-pot, nowhere.
I'll show you who's the honey-pot.
Just you wait and get sober.
Nothing, nothing.
They're coming, because I saw
them by the road. At the junction.
Give me a shot.
The Steigerwald kids
talked about powder.
Irimiés and Petrina are
coming toward the yard.
Gunpowder, Steigerwald... and
they're coming to the yard.
They'll be here in a short while.
We were plodding along...
My husband is a good man,
but the alcohol, you know.
Without that he'd be so gentle.
He can be a blessed good
man when he wants to.
He's a hard worker. You know that.
He can do the work of two.
He only has this small flaw.
Who doesn't have one? Who doesn't?
They're coming, plodding.
Irimiás and Petrina...
Someone's coming!
I was plodding, plodding,
plodding along...
They didn't talk much.
Irimiás and Petrina...
Good evening. A
bottle of beer, please.
The girls jumped around
like grasshoppers.
Irimiés hugged me.
"How's it going, Kelemen?"
And bought us a round.
The girls jumped around
like grasshoppers.
And I was plodding,
plodding and plodding along.
Have you seen my daughter?
- Which one?
- The little one.
Estike.
She hasn't been here.
Since they started toward
the yard at the junction,
I've known everything.
Irimiés and Petrina are
coming toward the yard.
I met Hochan the butcher,
and bumped into the Tóth kid
- at the Weighing Bridge.
- You know what happened?
Yesterday evening there was
a little trouble with Halics.
Now he doesn't even
say hello, the shithead.
I saw them by the road...
Revelation, which
way, why, where to...
...and the plodding, the why and
the where to, the which way...
I slept all day, and when
I woke up no one was there.
The house was empty.
No Mari, no Juli, no Sanyika.
And plodding, plodding
and plodding...
The Steigerwald kids were
talking about gunpowder.
But that's all right, even the little
one has wandered off somewhere too.
When she comes back,
she's gonna get it.
She'll come back.
She's not the wandering type.
She's really not.
...the gunpowder's
no gun-powder...
Wandering in this
rain all night long.
No wonder I stay in bed for days.
The waitresses jumped
like grasshoppers.
They were drinking
rum and liqueur...
That's good for my stomach.
Do you want coffee?
Why? I'd be tossing and
turning all night long.
Then what is it good for?
Nothing.
In a little while, I was
plodding and plodding...
The Tóth kid, the Steigerwald's...
and Irimiás hugged me...
The girls jumped like grasshoppers,
he bought us a round,
they had rum and liqueur.
He told me everything
and I'm plodding...
Well, good night.
If you happen to see any of them,
tell them to hit the road home.
I can't be wandering
around all night long.
Here's the bill.
...why, how, which
way, why and how...
Plodding and plodding and plodding.
And how am I plodding?
The gunpowder, Hochan the
butcher, Steigerwald, Tóth...
Everybody was talking
about the Steigerwald kids
hiding gunpowder. Why?
And why are Irimiás and
Petrina coming toward the yard?
I know why they're coming.
Because I had a
revelation. A revelation.
I know why they're coming.
Because I had a revelation.
They're coming at the
junction. I know exactly why.
They stop but they're coming.
Futaki, that stupid arse,
rolls in the mud like a pig,
then he goes out in the rain
like a sheep that has gone astray.
Have you lost your mind?
You do not know you are not
supposed to get wrecked in here?
And without eating, too.
Wash your face.
Dry yourself.
Do you have anything to eat?
Milk chocolate.
Or cheese rolls.
Give me two cheese rolls.
Bloody hell.
What can't be moved, they soil.
And foul, everything.
I could spend my whole life
following them with a cloth.
The legs of the table, the
window, the stove... the crates.
The worst is that you
can't see them do it.
If I start to watch them,
they can feel it
and get out of sight.
That damn Swabian
did me in...
...he never mentioned spiders.
Nothing will come of nothing.
No.
The real threat comes
from under the ground.
Suddenly...
...one's frightened by
the silence, doesn't move,
crouches down in the
corner where he feels safe.
Chewing becomes pain,
swallowing agony.
Then all slows down and finally
comes the most terrible thing.
Stillness.
There's no help or escape.
Because who can understand?
That I, who could live
till the end of time,
I'd still have to go away from
here all the way down to the worms.
And now there's Irimiás coming.
Irimiés?
He's been drinking
on the house for weeks
and he has the bloody
nerve to come back here.
Because, OK, he said, I
should plant onions everywhere.
And it succeeded.
Because the great
ideas are always simple.
But it's a bit too much
that afterward he comes back
and says that I owe him everything.
And for weeks he's
been boozing for free.
And he has the nerve to come
back to take what's mine.
Everything here is mine.
Because I have done
everything here.
Do they think they
can do anything here?
They come in from
the street and say,
"You can go now!"
There will be law and order
here, my friend, in this country!
There will be order here one
clay! There will be order!
You see, here's Halics!
May I have a tango?
Do you know that
dancing is my soft spot?
You're not like the others.
You need a settled, sober man...
...not a Schmidt...
...whose rough character
does not agree with
your tender personality.
Listen.
If those most excellent people
can again occupy the positions
they deserve in the offices...
...and I am the
schoolmaster again...
...I would take you to the city...
Tango is my life.
Tango, tango, tango!
My mother's the sea.
My father's the earth.
My name is tango... tango... tango.
My father's the sea.
Tango...
...is my life, tango.
My father's the sea.
My mother's the earth.
Never mind.
...is my life...
Tango.
Tango!
Tango...
...is my life...
Tango!
My mother's the sea and
my father's the earth.
No sea, no land either...
Fuck you.
What have you done to
the sea, to the land?
Is my life,
...tango...
...tango, tango?
My mother's the sea...
That was all.
Drawn out by the tender
sound of the accordion
the spiders in the pub
launched their last attack.
They sewed loose webs
on top of the glasses,
the cups, the ashtrays,
around the legs of the
tables and the chairs.
Then they bound them
together with secret threads
so that in their hidden corners
they'd notice every little
move and every little stir
until this almost invisible
web would not be damaged.
They sewed a web on the sleeper's
faces, their feet, their hands.
Then hurried back to
their hiding places,
waiting for an
ethereal thread to move,
to start it all again.
INTERMISSION
Irimiás makes a speech
I am in a state of deep emotion.
As you can imagine,
I am totally confused.
I am bewildered and shocked.
Yet I must pull myself together.
Though right now
all I can say is that
I share in this
broken-hearted mother's misery.
In a mother's never-ending
mourning and sorrow.
In the grief of losing the one
who is dearest to our hearts.
This tragic event weighs
us all down with sadness.
I don't think there's anyone
who would disagree with me.
And now the hardest thing is,
in this sadness with
our teeth clenched,
to get our minds
over the heartbreak,
to defy our tears when
our voices fail us.
For, and I would like to
call your attention to this,
nothing can be more important
than for us to reconstruct
the shocking events which
led to the terrible death
of an innocent child...
...before the police
start investigating.
You'd better expect that
the inspectors from town
will try to make us primarily
responsible for this awful event.
Yes, my friends, they're
going to blame us.
Because, to be quite honest...
...with a little caution,
care and attention,
we could have prevented it.
Just imagine this
vulnerable creature
wandering all night
long in the pouring rain,
at the mercy of the first
passer-by, of the first tramp,
of anybody.
She was whipped by
the wind all night,
she fell easy prey to the elements.
She must have been around here,
wondering here all the time.
She may have looked
in through this window
and saw that you were all
drunk and dancing around.
Don't get me wrong, I don't
mean to accuse anyone personally.
I am not accusing the mother,
who is never going
to forgive herself
for getting up too late in
the morning of that awful day.
I am not accusing
the victim's brother,
nor any other
members of the family.
So I am not accusing anyone.
But let me ask you the question,
aren't we all guilty?
You will, of course,
answer that we are innocent.
But then, what do we
call this poor child?
The victim of the innocent?
The martyr of the faultless?
The slaughtered of the sinless?
I'd rather call her innocent.
I spent the night turning in
my bed till I realised this.
Not only do we not know how
the tragic event happened,
but we don't really even
know what exactly happened.
I am quite convinced that
this event was fated to happen.
Now you also seem to suspect that.
It is not enough, however,
to suspect something.
Things are to be understood
and said without delay.
It had been quite clear for you
before coming here, but you were
too afraid to say that this
yard was ruled by misfortune.
You didn't dare talk about
it. Now you may rightly suppose
an irrevocable
judgment is coming soon.
You are slouching
around in this decay,
far away from everything
that means life.
Your plans come to nothing,
your dreams, still
blind, are shattered.
You expect some miracle
which will never come.
But what kind of misfortune
are you the victims of?
Is it the crumbling plaster,
the roofs without tiles,
the crumbling walls,
the sour taste our friend
Futaki keeps talking about?
Isn't it the shattered prospects,
and broken dreams,
that bend our knees
and wear us numb?
Don't be surprised that I speak
harshly, but let us be honest.
If you felt the yard
was ruled by misfortune,
why didn't you try to
do something about it?
You thought a bird in the
hand is worth two in the bush.
But this is a coward's way.
It is disgraceful and careless
and it has serious consequences.
This is called impotence,
sinful impotence.
This is weakness, sinful weakness.
This is cowardice,
sinful cowardice.
Because, and bear this in mind,
it's not just to others that
we can do unforgivable things,
but also to ourselves.
And this, my friends,
is even more serious.
Yes, when you think about
it, all kinds of vileness
are sins against ourselves.
And you know, my
friends, if I think back
and see you lying half-dead
on the chairs and tables,
on top of each other,
dribbling, exhausted,
my heart sinks and
I cannot judge you,
for I will never be
able to forget this.
From your panting,
snoring and groaning,
I heard your cry for help
which I have to answer.
We know each other well.
I have been keeping my eyes
wide-open for decades everywhere.
I bitterly observe that,
under the thick veil of
trickery and deception,
nothing has changed.
Misery has remained misery.
The two extra spoonfuls
of food we can have
only makes the air thinner
in front of our mouths.
But I realised what I have
done so far is nothing.
A much deeper solution is needed.
So, using the opportunity,
I decided...
...to get some people together
and set up a model farm, which
will ensure a stable living,
and bind this tiny group of
the dispossessed together.
I am creating an island
where no one is powerless,
where everyone will live in peace,
and will feel safe as human beings.
That is why I left
for the manor in Almás.
The main building
is in good condition,
the rental agreement
is a simple matter.
There's just one problem...
...no use in trying to
keep it a secret from you...
...the money.
Without a penny, the
whole thing is dead.
Capital is needed for production,
but this is a bit complicated.
There's no point in
going into details.
And you'll understand that the
circumstances of our meeting
made me feel uncertain, whether
you would be able to do it.
Whether you would be able
to offer the little money,
the result of your extra
hard work and much hardship,
to hand over for a hasty idea.
Think about it.
Calm your thoughts. Do
not decide straight away.
But if fate decides
that from now on we stay together,
inseparable,
do remember the price
that has been paid.
Do not forget the child...
...who may have had to
perish for the very reason
so our star could finally rise.
Who knows, my friends?
All we know for certain is...
...that life is very hard on us.
The Perspective, as
seen from the front
I told you she shouldn't have
been taken from the institute.
I don't know why
you brought her out.
Friends,
words fail me
now that I let you go on your way.
It's hard to describe
the way I feel.
For what could I say...
...of your enthusiasm,
your generosity...
...for the sake of
our common prosperity?
Of that precious thing you gave me,
your confidence.
What else could I say
but that all this gives me courage
and lays a special responsibility on me
which I would like to fulfil
to the best of my ability.
Your enthusiasm and confidence
makes me confident
and enthusiastic.
I'm thinking of the
future we'll share.
Goodbye, my friends.
See you tomorrow at 6am
in the manor at Almás.
Go ahead and think of the future.
From now on you, my
friends, are free.
And you were screwed,
you mean shitbag!
Fuck off! Bastards.
Go fuck yourselves. Fuck off!
Fuck off!
You see, what you have done?
The stuck-up person you were.
- Keep your mouth shut, OK?
- There you are.
Stop crowing and go
to hell. Just go home.
- Oh, yes, once up and once down.
- Go home, will you?
I've been saying, one always
has to have respect for one self.
Now you're finished.
You can close down.
Go home, will you?
Leave me alone.
My husband was the same, he
didn't know what was right.
And where did he end up?
Swinging from a rope in the barn.
Go home, stop bothering
me. Bother about yourself.
Go get your daughters instead
or they might go with them too.
- They'll never. They're locked up.
- Pay for your drinks and go.
They won't leave
me like Estike did.
When they leave the yard,
they'll go and dig the ground.
Go home now.
Go.
Now, just go, go.
- You've finished it?
- I do not want to leave it for the gypsies.
The wind is blowing the clouds
Behind the sky is burning
Give me, my dear, your little hand
God knows if I'll see you again
Whether I'll hold you in my arms
Whether I'll kiss you, dear
God only knows the
day I'll be shipped out
Whether I'll hold you...
You're lovely, you're fair, Hungary
Folks. We forgot the doctor.
Never mind the doctor.
He would have surely come but
I didn't mention it to him.
Come on, he would not be able
to last this long journey.
But he's going to starve now.
He can't even arrange
it with the pub owner.
Then let him starve to death.
I don't care about the doctor, if
you miss him so much, go back for him.
I haven't seen him for months.
There's no need to cry over him.
He's fine. Gets pissed every
day, then goes off to snore.
I wouldn't mind feeling his
mother's share in my pocket.
Are we all here?
No one's lagging behind?
We've done it!
At least we've done it.
You've come well prepared
for this new life.
Come on, Lajos, there
will be lots more of that.
How could those poor
fellows heat all this?
Didn't I tell you? We
should never lose heart.
We have to have trust
until our last breath.
Otherwise what would become of us?
Tell me, what?
I can imagine.
You've seen the outer buildings...
...there's about five of them.
I bet the workshops
are going to be there?
Workshops? What workshops?
Please be quiet. My husband is
already asleep. He wants quiet.
All right, all right.
Can't we just talk?
I think it'll be
the other way round:
we'll live in them
and the workshops will be here.
Won't you keep quiet? No
one can get any rest here.
Who was that?
Leave me alone. It wasn't me.
Nobody wants to own up to it?
Look,
I'll agree to anything
you like, just keep quiet.
Listen,
if everyone works hard,
I say, just one month.
We have great prospects
for the future.
Tomorrow we'll find out what
Irimiás is planning to do.
Tomorrow.
Halics was pursued by a
hunchback with a glass eye.
And after all sods of
trials he fled to a river
but he started to lose heart.
Every time he came up for air,
the little man immediately
hit his head with a long stick.
And each time he shouted,
"Now you're gonna pay for it."
The schoolmaster persuaded
a man wearing an old suit
to go with him to
somewhere he knows.
The man agreed, like
someone who can't say no.
He could hardly control himself
and when they fumed
into a deserted park,
he even pushed him
to reach faster a bench that
was surrounded by bushes.
He made the man lie
down and he jumped on him
and kissed him on the neck.
But seconds later, doctors appeared
on the path dressed in white.
Embarrassed, he waved to
them that he was going,
but he started to reproach
the confused little man,
for by then, he seemed
to hate his guts so much.
The ground trembled
under Schmidt's feet,
as if he was walking on the moors.
He climbed up into a tree,
but he felt it
starting to sink too.
Then he was lying on the bed,
trying to get the
nightgown off his wife.
But she started to yell,
he jumped after her,
the nightgown was torn.
She turned towards him and laughed
and the nipples on
her enormous breasts
were like two beautiful roses.
Mrs Halics was washing
Mrs Schmidt's back,
and the rosary on the rim of the tub
slipped into the water like a snake.
Mrs Schmidt said she had enough,
that her skin was
burning from the scrubbing
but Mrs Hal/cs pushed
her back into the bath
and went on scrubbing her back
because she said she was afraid
that Mrs Schmidt wouldn't
be satisfied with her.
Mrs Kráner heard a
noise from outside
but she didn't know
what it could be.
She put on a fur coat and
left for the engine shed.
She had almost reached the
road when she had a bad feeling.
She turned and saw that the
top of their house was on fire.
"The chopped wood. Christ,
I left the chopped wood out!
"Heavens!" she
screamed, and ran back.
Kráner was sitting at
the table, calmly eating.
"Jéska, are you crazy?
The house is on fire!"
But Kráner didn't move.
Mrs Schmidt was a bird, flying
over the clouds, happily.
She saw that someone down
there was waving at her.
She came down a bit and
heard Schmidt shouting.
"Why didn't you cook anything, you
bitch? Come down here right now."
But she flew over him
and tweeted, "Tomorrow.
"You won't starve till then."
She felt the warmth
of the sun on her back,
then flew closer to the ground.
She wanted to snatch a bug.
Futaki's shoulders were
beaten with an iron bar.
He couldn't move, he
was tied to a tree.
He stretched out and
felt the rope loosen.
He looked at his shoulders
and saw a long wound,
then turned his head, as
he couldn't stand seeing it.
He was sitting on an excavator,
the shovel was scooping
out a huge hole.
A man came up to him and said,
"Hurry up, I won't give you any
more petrol, whatever you say."
But it was no use scooping,
for the earth kept falling back.
He tried again but failed.
Then he cried.
He was sitting at the
window of the engine shed
and didn't know whether
it was daybreak or evening.
The whole thing just
didn't want to end.
He was sitting, not
knowing the time of clay,
and nothing changed outside.
Morning didn't come,
night didn't fall,
day was beginning to break or
night was beginning to fall.
Heavenly Vision? Hallucinations?
Friends.
Words fail me, now that the time
came and I let you go your own way.
It's hard to describe
the way I feel.
For what can I say
about your enthusiasm,
your generosity...
...for the sake of
our common prosperity.
That precious thing you gave me,
your confidence.
What else could I say but
that all this gives me courage,
lays great responsibility on me,
which I would like to
accept and do the best I can.
And that your
enthusiasm and confidence
makes me confident
and enthusiastic.
I'm thinking of the
future we'll share.
Goodbye, dear friends.
See you tomorrow at 6am
in the manor at Almás.
Go now and think of
the future we'll share.
From now on you are free.
And you are screwed,
you mean shitbag!
Fuck off. You bastards! Go
fuck yourselves. Fuck off!
I'm scared shitless, man,
how do we get out of this?
I'd be surprised if you
weren't shitting in your pants.
Do you want some paper?
This is no fucking joke,
it's bloody serious.
I wouldn't say I'm
bursting with laughter.
Stop it, will you?
Would you be surprised if
I said our time has come?
What the hell are you getting at?
Listen to old Petrina this time.
Look, let's take the first train
and get away from here.
We're going to get in big trouble
if they realise what's going on.
Shut up.
Don't you see that we're partisans
in this persistent and hopeless
fight for human dignity?
Petrina, our time has come.
Our time has come.
You keep saying this,
"Our time has come."
Our time will never come.
I had faith and confidence...
And there we are.
The web... don't you understand?
Irimiés' nationwide cobweb.
Is your dull mind getting clear?
Where something stirs...
Go on.
You've never seen
fog before or what?
The horses got away from
the slaughterhouse again.
Who do you support?
Myself.
How are you?
Fine.
You haven't changed at all.
What about you?
Nothing special.
I thought...
Two rum liqueurs
and a glass of wine.
Here you are.
Listen, drink this up.
Then you go see Páyer and tell
him I'm waiting for him here.
Steigerwald.
What is it now?
We're staying here for tonight
but I'll need the car tomorrow.
But then I want the
money before you go.
All right.
- And three bean soups.
- OK.
- With ham.
I'm going to dictate.
Dear Captain...
...eternity...
...lasts forever...
...because it doesn't
compare to the ephemeral...
...the changeable...
...the temporary.
But the intensity of
light penetrating darkness
seems to weaken.
"Seems... to... weaken."
There is discontinuance...
...interruptions...
...holes...
...then finally the black nothing.
Then there are myriads of stars
at an unreachable distance...
...with a tiny spark in the middle,
the Ego.
Tiny... spark..."
Our deeds can be
rewarded or punished,
punished in eternity,
and only there...
...because everything has a place,
a place far away from reality...
...where it has its place,
where it has always been...
"Where... it... has... been..."
...where it will always be...
...where it is now.
The only authentic place.
I hope I didn't wake you.
You didn't disturb my sleep
and I do hope you won't either.
- My collaborators.
- My name's Petrina.
Horgos.
Very nice young man.
He can have a nice career.
Would you get me
something now that...
...you got me out of bed?
What would you like?
Don't ask me what I'd
like, they don't have it.
Get me a glass of plum brandy.
Sanyi.
The gun dealer.
Sports guns.
I don't love this
job, you know that.
You'd better call me Páyer.
Mr Páyer.
I asked you to come here this late
because soon
I will need rather
a lot of explosive.
I'm going to think about it.
And decide as I see best.
And I hope you will do
your best for the success.
Listen, it's not entirely up to me.
But I need to know
whether you can give more
emphasis to this excellent plan
right now, with a
so-called good start?
Certainly.
You are a gentleman...
...Mr Irimiás.
Let me ask you something.
This "something new,"
which is waiting for us after
realizing your excellent plan...
- Well...
- Don't take me for a liberator.
Regard me as a sad researcher,
who investigates why everything
is as terrible as it is.
Would you like to
have dinner with us?
No, thank you.
Well then, we'll discuss
the details another time?
I'll see you on the weekend.
Well, gentlemen...
Sleep well.
Look, it was 25 years ago, when I was
last able to sleep five and a half hours.
Since then, I've been turning
in my bed, half-asleep.
Thank you all the same.
Our Father,
who art in heaven...
...Hallowed be thy name.
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done...
...on earth...
...as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread...
...the power...
Amen.
The Perspective, as
seen from the back
I don't understand Irimiás.
He was one of us. And
now, he's like a lord.
You just can't understand
what he wants.
All the nonsense he said.
Bent knees and cries for help!
Then threatening with the child...
The way he spoke yesterday,
I was beginning to believe it.
Why the hell did he
stir this shit up?
If I'd known he wanted
more of the same,
I'd have saved him the trouble.
It's crazy to say
that it was my fault.
That I had anything to
do with that little idiot.
Even her name drove me up the wall.
"Estike," what's that?
Is that a name?
She ate a lot of rat
poison and that's it.
Perhaps it was better
for the poor thing.
But what's the whole
thing to do with me?
He lured us here,
to this rundown dump.
And we acted like sheep.
Meanwhile he dropped out.
God knows where he's
drinking with our money.
A whole year's pay.
And I'm flat broke again.
And if he appears in a minute,
what are you going to shout at him?
You're the one to say that? You
have the nerve to utter a word?
Stop for a minute!
Whose fault is it
that I was robbed?
Who said that it'd be all
right, to share the money?
Irimiés and Petrina, what?
You fucker...
Give me my money back, you bastard!
Give me my money back.
Give it back, you prick!
Let's give him two minutes,
and see if he calms down.
- Are the two minutes up now?
- Listen, people.
What on earth are you
doing? Not this way!
- Use your heads.
- Shut up!
Here he is. Your saviour's here.
Do you really think it's my fault?
Give me my money back.
You hear me? Give it back!
I don't believe my eyes.
What are you doing there?
You get lost.
Don't worry about it.
It's none of your business.
Get away from here!
I won't say it twice.
What's going on here?
I want to know what's going on!
We thought you wouldn't come.
You said you'd be here
by six in the morning.
I do my best to help you.
I've had no sleep for three days,
I walked hours in the pouring rain,
I run here and there to
overcome difficulties,
and you behave like piglets
when their dinner is late...
What happened to you?
- My nose is bleeding.
- I can see that. But why?
I never expected that from you.
From you neither.
And we've just begun.
What will be later on?
Will you knife each other?
Sad.
This is very sad.
I'm going to forget it this time.
But with a condition that such a
thing can't happen again. Is it clear?
So let's talk sense.
There is something
important I have to tell you.
We must postpone our plans for
the manor for the time being.
Because in certain circles
it wouldn't be desirable
if an establishment for such
vague purposes were created.
Their primary objection is
the fact that the manor,
being almost totally isolated
and a long way from town,
could hardly be brought
under their control.
Therefore,
in the present situation
for us the only way to succeed is
to scatter around the
county for a time being
until these gentlemen
get so confused
that we can safely come back
here and start working as planned.
From now on, you
are special people.
For you are selected
to help in a matter
in which loyalty,
devotion and prudence
are absolutely necessary.
Our goals go way beyond themselves.
Scattering is just
a tactical decoy.
Because you're going to keep
in continuous contact with me,
even if not with each other.
In the meantime, do not believe
that we are going to remain
passively in the background
and wait for things to
get better by themselves.
What you have to do is to
listen to people around you.
Views, stories, events which are
imperative and connected to the matter.
Every one of you will need to
acquire the exceptional ability
by which you can distinguish
between the good and the bad signs.
In other words,
between right and wrong.
And how are we going
to live in the meantime?
Don't worry.
Everything is organized,
everything is prepared.
You will all have work to do.
At the beginning you'll get
enough money for the basics
from our common capital.
But do not waste our time
asking unnecessary questions.
We are late anyway.
We have to start
right now, my friends.
Go pack your things. Hurry up.
Take your things and go.
Take the big things first.
Come on, move.
Kráner, you too, you hear me?
Wait a second. Give
us our money back.
You hear me? Give the money back!
The money?
Is that what you want?
Here, here's your money.
Do what you want to do
with it, alone. Good luck.
This is one year's
of our hard work.
Jéska, give the money back.
No, just share it out.
Perhaps it's better this way.
At least it became clear right from the
start that you have no honour or perseverance.
Good to know from the
start whom I can count on.
I think Mrs Kráner, your
husband may be right.
I cannot realise my plans with you.
I need people who are at least able
to look after their own interests.
I have to go now.
Wait.
And...
...the farm will be working?
I don't know, but this no
longer should concern you.
Give him the money.
I didn't meant it.
Now, take the money.
This rain, you know,
and the long hike.
We were so cold last
night. We are so sorry.
It's not about me.
It's the fact that you deserted,
you betrayed the cause
already on the very first day.
The whole thing is based on
confidence and perseverance.
Take the money now.
We trust you. Take it.
Look, I have no time
or mood for such scenes.
I must admit, you disappointed me.
But I will look past it
this time just for once.
I'm going to try and forget
this whole disgraceful event.
Mind how you sit there,
it takes at least two hours even
with this outstandingly fast vehicle.
Button your coats.
Put on your hoods and hats.
And just turn your backs
to the bright future
or this bloody rain will
get all over your faces.
Schmidts, Halicses,
Kráners, come on!
Futaki, Mr Schoolmaster,
please wait a minute.
What's the matter,
you're not coming?
Is there a pub here?
- We could have a drink.
- No.
Schmidt and family,
you're going to Elek.
I've put everything down,
who to contact and where.
There you'll get work
and a place to live.
And what work is there?
This is a butcher's.
There's plenty to do.
You can serve the customers.
Now the Kráners.
You ask for lstván
Kalmár in Keresztur.
Listen carefully,
it's not written down.
There's a street before
the church on the right.
You go down that street until you
see the "Ladies' Fashion" sign.
That's Kalmér's house.
Tell him Dönci has sent you,
he may have forgotten my real name.
He has a laundry in the
back, you'll stay there.
Is that clear?
Yes, Dönci.
A street after the church
and there's a sign...
Right.
Halics.
You go to the presbytery...
...and ask for Gyivicsán,
the parish priest.
Gyivicsán.
There's plenty of wine there.
You can clean the church
and do the cooking
for the three of you.
Here's a thousand
forints per person...
...if anything comes up.
But don't waste it.
And don't forget what
you're supposed to do.
I think all is clear.
We'd like to thank you for all
the good that you've clone for us.
You don't have to say thank you.
Me too, I'm only a
servant of a great cause.
So remember what you have to do.
Then take good care, as
you know we care about you.
Take care of yourselves.
Listen, you sit up there...
...and we'll take
you to the Streber.
We'll pick you up in an hour
and talk about the rest. OK?
OK.
Futaki.
Don't worry about me.
I know where I'm going.
I could find a job
somewhere as a watchman.
You'd be better off
doing something else.
What? Is there no way to
come to terms with you today?
Come to Steigerwald's by 8 in the
evening and we'll talk it over there.
All right, I'll do it your way.
Here.
A thousand forints.
Buy yourself a dinner
somewhere at least.
This Futaki is the biggest
sucker I've ever met.
What did he think? That
this is paradise here?
What did the poor devil expect?
Nothing but worry and work
- Leave out the part about eternity.
- OK.
"Though I don't believe it's right
to write such information down
"but for you to see my willingness,
"I am following your instructions:
"I've taken into account that
you encouraged me to be open
"in all circumstances.
"I must say that there can be no
doubt about my people's aptitude.
"I hoped I could have
convinced you of this yesterday.
"This is important
to emphasize again
"because from this rough draft might
derive other implications as well.
"I emphasize that in order to keep my
base working, I will be the only one
"to keep in touch with my people.
"Anything else would lead
to complete failure, etc..."
- I think it's all right.
- Then we leave that in.
Mrs Schmidt...
Type it.
Instead of a stupid woman
with big tits, you write,
"mentally immature person,
"who mostly emphasises
her female character."
And what about the "bloody whore"?
Could be a "lady of easy virtue"
or a "woman of low morals"...
How about "a woman prostituting
herself without hesitation"?
OK. Type it.
- Finished?
- Yeah.
"She went to bed with
anyone and everyone.
"And if she missed anyone,
that was only by accident."
"She's a paragon of
conjugal infidelity."
Finished?
Instead of "a stench created
by the mixing of cheap cologne
"with God knows what else..."
"She attempts to relieve
her unpleasant body odour
"in an unusual way."
- Kráner.
- What?
Mrs Kráner. Just type it.
"A termagant with a big
mouth," should be replaced with,
"indiscreet transmitter
of fabricated stories."
- And instead of "a fat sow"?
- Leave that in.
- We shouldn't.
- Then put "big".
- "Overweight".
- OK.
- Can we leave Mrs Halics as it is?
- Sure.
And what about "wrinkled
worm, filled with alcohol"?
"Elderly alcoholic,
short of stature"?
"Eager beaver."
"Inert dullness, blind wandering."
- We can leave that out.
- OK, we left it out.
You finished? Let's go on then.
Schmidt.
What's this? "Crude dullness mixed
"with featurelessness in the
abyss of uncontrollable darkness."
"Extreme stupidity,
inarticulate complaints,
"inert anxiety stiffened...
"...in the solid
darkness of being."
Write this.
"His modest mental ability...
"...his submissive
attitude to authority...
"...make him especially suited...
"...to accomplish the
activity in question...
"...to a high degree."
The schoolmaster.
He must have been
out of his mind here.
Listen to this.
"If someone who's about to commit
suicide by jumping in the water
"were to hesitate at the last moment
on the bridge whether to jump or not,
"he should remember
the schoolmaster
"and he will realise
there's only one chance.
- "To jump."
- Go on.
"He's like a withered
cucumber. In mental ability
"he remains below Schmidt,
a definite achievement."
Let's put, "Appearance:
worn down. No abilities."
- How did the two come together?
- That's what he wrote.
"He compensates for his cowardice
with narcissism and conceit.
"He's rather sentimental,
"as is often the case
with onanistic men."
Then "weak and sentimental.
- "Sexually immature."
- OK, write that.
As for Kráner,
he's a "boorish sloppy buffalo..."
"Though strongly built",
he worked as a smith.
"A strongly-built smith"?
"A stupid arse with
dull eyes." Go on.
"The only dangerous one
is Futaki, but not very.
"A rebel, but a cowardly one.
"He might have had a nice career,
"but he can't get rid
himself of his obsessions.
"I'm sure he's the one
I can surely count on."
- So?
- Leave it.
No.
Write "dangerous, but
can be of use," instead.
"Cleverer than the
others. Crippled."
- Is that all?
- Yeah.
Then sign his name. "Irimiás."
- Is it still raining?
- Yes.
They shook hands outside the gate.
"You go by...?" "Bus."
"OK. II "Bye then," said the clerk.
"Nice day we had,
eh?" the other added.
Yeah, bloody good. 
They shook hands again and parted.
At home, both were asked the
same question at the door,
"Did you have a bad day, dear?"
To which, shuddering and exhausted,
they could only say, "Nothing
much. The usual, my dear."
The circle closes
During the thirteen days...
...I spent in hospital...
Mrs Kráner...
...didn't turn up...
...again...
Everything is...
...like I left it.
Neither of them dares...
...to come out the house.
They must be...
...lying on their beds, snoring
or staring at the ceiling.
They haven't a clue...
...that it is this dull...
...inertia...
...that leaves them...
...at the mercy
of what they most fear.
A cosmic economy.
My hearing...
...is getting worse.
The Turks are coming!
I must be crazy.
I've mistaken the bells of the sky
for the sound of the
bell for the dead.
One morning...
...at the end of October
not long before...
...the first drops...
...of the insufferably long
autumn rains
fell on the parched
some ground
on the western side of the yard...
...when...
...the mud of the stinking bog
makes the roads
impassable,
cutting off the town...
...until the first frosts.
Futaki was awakened...
by the sound of bells.
There was a solitary chapel
eight kilometres to the south-west
at the old Hochmeiss field
but it had no bell
its tower having collapsed
during the war...