Oooroero ♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My Savior God to Thee ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My Savior God to Thee ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ When through the woods ♪
♪ And forest glades I wander ♪
♪ And hear the birds ♪
♪ Sing sweetly in the trees ♪
♪ When I look down ♪
♪ From lofty mountain grandeur ♪
♪ And hear the brook ♪
♪ And feel the gentle breeze ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My Savior God to Thee ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ Then sings my soul ♪
♪ My Savior God to Thee ♪
♪ How great Thou art ♪
♪ When Christ shall come ♪
♪ With shouts of acclamation ♪
♪ And take me home ♪
♪ What joy shall fill my heart ♪
♪ Then I shall bow ♪
♪ With humble adoration ♪
♪ And then proclaim, my God ♪
♪ How great Thou art... ♪
Make the most of this beautiful train.
That's it. Okay.
Yeah.
That's really great. Yeah, yeah.
Okay, now, as I said before,
you're under no obligation to,
but you can if you want to,
give me a tiny, little twinkle.
Yeah, that is... lovely.
All right, a little bit closer.
As you were. Are you all right?
Hair's just a little bit...
That's it. And you've got
an eyelash on your nose.
We don't want that, do we?
It's supposed to be on your eye,
not on your snitch.
That's it! You've got a lovely smile
when you smile, haven't you?
Right, okay.
Now, you keep that lovely, gorgeous smile.
That's lovely.
I think that'll do for the time being.
Well done, Sarah. That's the easy bit.
- They make a noise, don't they?
- At least they can play out around here.
I suppose so.
What is it?
Is that a suit?
It came as a combination.
Do they go together?
Well, if you think they do, they do.
And if you think they don't, they don't.
It's nice.
Twenty-one in August.
She is.
I used to worry meself sick
when she played out.
She survived it, though, didn't she?
All things considering.
She's back on the streets now.
I beg your pardon.
Well, she is, isn't she?
I don't half miss her.
I know.
How long is it since we've seen her?
Two and a half years.
- We could always ask her over.
- I'd like to.
For her birthday.
It's only a couple of months away.
What now?
"Hey, Roxanne,
what are you doing for your 21st?"
"I'm going over to my auntie
and uncle's house for my birthday treat."
It was only a suggestion.
She's probably doing her own thing.
I suppose we'd have to invite
Cynthia as well.
There's no show without Punch.
- I'm sure she'd like to see the place.
- Oh, I'm sure she would.
- She can't help it.
- Can't she?
It's about time we showed it off.
I mean, you've done a lovely job.
I think so.
I really must get down to see her.
- You speak to her on the phone, don't you?
- It's not the same thing, though, is it?
She's your sister.
I'm really proud of that portrait.
I reckon that's the last time
she ever smiled.
I don't know what's got into you lately.
- You complaining?
- No.
Well, shut up, then.
I sit here on me own for years on end,
can't get you to stop in at all.
- Now you never go out.
- Leave it out.
You've been sitting there for a month
with a face like a slapped arse.
Well, what's there to smile about?
Thought he might have
phoned at the weekend.
Who?
Who do you think?
I ain't heard from him for ages.
- He's busy, ain't he.
- We're all busy.
He's got his weddings and that.
It's the summer.
Out of sight, out of mind.
If you're that bothered, why don't you
ring him yourself? He's your brother.
I'm not running up me phone bill!
He knows where I am if he wants me.
He'd have had us up there to see it
by now, I expect, if it weren't for her.
Toffee-nosed cow.
What's he want with six bedrooms anyway?
What's all your mates doing tonight, then?
I don't know. I ain't asked 'em.
You wanna get yourself a bloke.
That's what you wanna do.
I told you, I don't want to get anything.
I'm quite happy here, thank you very much.
When I was your age,
I could have had the pick of the crop.
Well, why didn't ya?
Because I lost my poor mother, that's why.
Oh, here we go.
I was stuck at home from the age of ten,
looking after Maurice and your grandad.
Yeah, we know.
Then I got saddled with you.
That was my downfall, darling.
I didn't ask to be born.
No, and I never asked
to have you, neither.
Well, you should have thought about that
before you dropped your knickers.
With... or without?
- I think without.
- Without?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
What about this one?
Better with or without?
I think this time, it's with.
With?
All right, we'll pop this one in, then.
- I hear you're a really good runner.
- Yeah, cross-country.
Have you won anything?
Not yet. I've only just started.
Okay, then. Look up again.
Now, this is gonna blur a bit,
but just tell me what you can read. Okay?
H-L-A-C-I.
- Right.
- And I can't read any more.
Okay, that's good.
Very good. I'm gonna do
your other eye now.
- You off, then?
- Yeah.
Got any plans for the weekend?
Well, I've got to go to my mum's house
and sort through her things.
- Oh, have you?
- Yeah.
- Hope it goes all right.
- Well, it's gotta be done.
- Yeah.
- Okay, then.
- Right. I'll see you on Monday.
- Yeah.
- Have a nice weekend.
- Cheers.
- Ooh! Enjoy the christening.
- I'll try.
- Okay, bye.
- Bye!
It's ten past.
We've got to pick Shelattica up.
- What are you talking about?
- We've got ten minutes!
Listen, right? We've gotta sort
this out while we're here.
Look, basically, right,
it's you, one, here in this massive house.
Thank you. We have got
two children, you understand?
- And we could have more.
- What?
We want to have more.
Listen, right?
You can't stay here on your own.
It's not fair, is it?
I mean, we can sell the house, can't we?
Sell the house and split the money.
Listen, you know what?
You could split this whole house in two.
You could split this into two flats
and it'd still be bigger than our place.
- Exactly.
- Split it in two? Can't split it.
Let's sort your tie out for you,
if I might.
- Looks just a little bit skew-whiffy.
- Skew-whiff again.
There it is. That's lovely.
Do you want the paper out?
- Yeah, yeah, okay.
- Cheers.
You ladies look gorgeous.
Hands together there. Really nice.
Okay, here we go.
Put your paper down there.
Right, and here we go. Okay, and...
- Do we say "cheese," Maurice?
- You can if you like.
You can. You can say "cheese."
You can say whatever you like.
But just give me a little ̶̶ That's it.
Oh, yeah. Very sweet.
Okay, that's lovely.
- So that took you 15 years, yeah?
- Yes.
- They give you a prize?
- No.
Not even
a stethoscope or something? Lovely.
Ooh, little baby.
- That's really lovely.
- I'm so glad he's got his eyes open.
Yeah, that's it.
And give him a look down. Lovely.
Are you gonna see that flea collar?
Are you gonna see that?
Don't worry about that.
You come out now. Come out.
- You just come of the way.
- That's it.
Pop out now. And out. And here we go.
I think I left the comb
in there that time.
- Lovely! Very good.
- Does he look good?
- He does look good, yeah. So do you.
- Oh, good. Yes, yes.
Thank you very much, Jane. That's lovely.
- It's for my auntie.
- Oh, right. Fond of you, is she?
- No, she's in India.
- Oh, right.
Time I got married, innit?
Oh, I see.
Pick a bride time, is it?
I've told you, I don't want flash ̶̶
And... lovely!
I never thought I'd have any.
Fertility treatment.
It's a miracle.
Don't do that with your nose.
Now, stop it. Put it there.
Hello, Domi ̶̶
Now look at that lovely cat.
- Look over there. Look at that cat!
- It's lovely!
Oh, that's it.
Let him scratch it first.
Go on. That's it. That's it.
Lovely!
This is silly.
Ah, lovely! And that's it!
Ah, thank you very much.
- What do you think you're doing?
- Sorry.
- Didn't you hear me?
- No, I didn't actually.
- Hiya.
- What?
- Mind out of the way!
- Want a drink?
- What?
If I want a drink,
I'll get it myself, thank you.
Since when was hoovering
a spectator sport?
- Can I have a glass too, please?
- I thought you didn't want a drink.
I've changed my mind. I'm having milk.
Not in a wine glass. Give me a highball.
- You don't put milk in a wine glass.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- That'll do you good.
- Meaning?
- Nothing.
Had a good day?
Scintillating.
I suppose you'll be starving as usual.
A little bit peckish, yeah.
- Do you want me to do something?
- Like what?
- Anything you like.
- No, I bloody well wouldn't.
- Fair enough.
- Oh, all right, then.
There's the fridge.
There's the freezer.
There's the hob.
There's the recipe books. Help yourself.
And don't make a mess.
Unless you fancy a takeaway.
- Not gonna smile, are you?
- No.
Okay, it's a free world.
Now, you're under no obligation,
but you can, if you want to,
give me a lovely big smile!
And thank you.
Oh, go on! Come on! Lovely!
You're under no obligation to,
but you can smile if you'd like.
Yes! Thank you.
- Did you smile, Mother?
- No.
That's it. To me. That's it.
Now look at each other.
That's it.
- Don't!
- Go on. Look up.
Keep your face up, 'cause you're allowed ̶̶
That's lovely!
Ah, you were closing your eyes.
Don't forget to burp it properly.
Give it a drop of gripe water.
We used to pour it down
Roxanne by the gallon.
She farted like a trouper.
Runs in the family.
Would madam care to test the temperature?
I'm sure it'll be fine, thanks.
- Been bad, has it?
- It eased off at lunchtime.
Managed a couple of crackers.
It's unpredictable, isn't it?
No, it's not unpredictable.
- You've drawn the short straw, mate.
- You're telling me.
I wish it was unpredictable.
What are you gonna have for your tea?
- Do you know what I really fancy?
- What?
A steak.
You know I haven't
any steak in this house.
Don't worry about me.
You'll be keeling over
with a heart attack.
I'll do myself something later.
There's a chicken Kiev in the freezer.
Be a bit cold, wouldn't it?
Anyway... I'm on a diet.
You're disgusting.
Okay, that's very good.
And we can see the ring perfectly.
All right, now, sir, if you'd just
bring your chin up. Just slightly.
That's perfect. That's brilliant.
All right, great.
Sorry. Sorry.
Can you take your glasses off?
- I don't want to take my glasses off.
- Go on, take them off.
Doesn't matter.
Keep them on, take them off.
- No, he looks better without them.
- It's what I look like, okay?
- All right, okay, and to me.
- One minute, please.
Can you take the cross out, please?
- Hmm?
- Take the cross out.
It was a gift. Take it out.
- I just think it looks awful.
- It doesn't look awful.
It looks awful because it's not gold.
I told you to buy gold.
Okay, right.
Okay, and to me, yeah.
Right. That's lovely.
Now, do you want to look happy or sad?
I don't mind. Whatever.
And look at me, and lovely!
Hello, my name's Hortense Cumberbatch.
I got your letter. Hi.
Oh, right. Tuesday.
Hello?
Hortense! Hello.
Jennie Ford. Nice to meet you.
- Oh, hi.
- Come this way.
- How are you? All right?
- Fine, thank you.
Good. I'm sorry about this prison cell.
We've been banging on about it
for years, but there you go.
Have a seat. Make yourself at home.
Now, before we go any further,
have you got any ID?
- Passport, driving license?
- Yes.
You'll have to get used
to all this red tape.
- Would you like a Rolo?
- No, thank you.
- You sure?
- Yeah.
- There you go.
- Mm. Let's have a shifty.
- That's great, Hortense.
- Thank you.
- You on your lunch break?
- Yeah, an extended one.
- Have you had any lunch?
- No, not yet.
No, me neither. So what do you do?
I'm an optometrist.
Oh, really? Oh, God.
That's one of those things you keep
putting off and putting off, isn't it?
And I've got to the stage now
with The Guardian crossword
where I'm I'm going like this,
so I think the time has come, don't you?
I'll have to pop in. You can give me
a test. Where do you live?
- Kilburn.
- Right, right.
- In a flat?
- Yes.
- You share?
- No, I live on my own.
Oh, right.
I lived on my own for about six years,
before I was married.
- It's all right, isn't it?
- Yeah.
Right, Hortense.
Let's talk a little bit
about you, shall we?
Now, obviously, you've been giving
a great deal of thought to things
and you've come to a decision,
which is good.
But for me the question is, why now?
I just feel that
it's the right time, that's all.
Right, right.
You thinking about getting married?
No.
- Do you have children?
- No.
- You're thinking about having children?
That's fair enough.
Are you sharing this with your parents?
Do they know that you're here today?
I mean, how do they feel about it?
They're both dead, actually.
Oh, right.
Yeah, Mum died two months ago now.
Oh, that is recent.
I'm ̶̶ I'm sorry to hear that.
- Was it sudden?
- Yeah.
Perhaps that's what's
made you start on this.
I don't know.
It's possible.
Well, I'm not trying to replace her.
She's irreplaceable. Well, they both are.
No, of course, of course.
And when you were growing up,
was it a happy environment?
- Yes, very.
- Oh, good, good.
And did you, um ̶̶
Were you able to discuss
the fact that you'd been ̶̶
No, it was never really an issue.
Right, right.
- So you've only just found out?
- Oh, no.
They told me when I was little.
Oh, good, good. And do you remember
how you felt about that?
Well, it's not exactly
something you forget, is it?
No, no.
I'm sure it isn't.
So, how did you feel?
Well, we all just
got on with it as a family.
Do you know what I mean?
Yeah.
Perhaps you should have discussed it.
My parents loved me
and that was all that matters.
Isn't it?
Yeah, yeah.
So, now that we've got you here,
what are your expectations?
Basically, I just want to know.
Yeah, yeah, of course you do.
Let me share something with you, Hortense.
Somewhere out there,
and we don't know where,
is your birth mother.
Now, she's probably married. Perhaps not.
She may have other children.
She might be dead.
She may even be in Australia or somewhere.
We just don't know.
But what we do know is that,
at the time she gave you up for adoption,
she was under the impression
that she would probably
never see you again.
Now, as I know you're very well aware,
the law has changed since then
and you are now legally entitled
to seek your birth mother out.
But the snag is...
she may not want to see you.
So I don't want you to raise
your hopes too high at this stage.
- Sure.
- Okay.
Have a look at this.
What is it?
It's all about you.
I tell you what.
I'll leave it with you
and I'll pop back in in a few minutes.
- Can I get you anything?
- No. No, thank you.
How are you doing? All right?
Thank you.
Cynthia Rose Purley.
That's her.
Cynthia Rose.
It's a nice name, isn't it?
- That's her signature.
- Mm-hmm.
Does that feel strange?
Elizabeth.
That's my middle name.
They must have kept it.
Well, that would be
your birth name, you see?
Elizabeth Purley.
Listen, is there any way
I could get a copy of these?
No, those are the originals
and they're yours to keep.
That's your right under the 1975 Act.
I've made copies upstairs.
I'll pop those in here for you.
So...
what we need to do now is...
you go away and have a think.
And when the time's right,
and not before ̶̶
you know, it's very much
in your own time ̶̶
come back to me, if that's what you want,
and we'll get the ball rolling.
Now, it can be a very long-winded process
and, there's no two ways about it,
it's a very traumatic journey
you're embarking on.
And there may be other people's
feelings to consider too.
So I'll wait to hear from you, okay?
Now, you could decide
to trace your birth mother by yourself,
if you wanted, but I wouldn't advise it.
We're a professional service,
and we know how to handle these things.
So I think you should
take advantage of us.
- Hello.
- Oh, you're back! Hello.
I think I found a mistake.
I'm sorry, I can't stop.
I'm really in a hurry.
- Look, it says she's white.
- Sorry?
"Mother: White."
Well, it's perfectly feasible
that your mother was white, isn't it?
Look, I'm sorry, Hortense.
Really, I've got to go.
- I'm on an emergency case.
- Yes, but could this be a mistake?
I very much doubt it.
Look, give me a ring in the morning and
we'll have a talk then, okay? I'm sorry.
Look at that.
Legs like a teenager.
- Do you have to?
- You'd like a pair like that.
What for?
I'm known for my legs.
If you've got it, flaunt it.
- Are you going out?
- Of course I ain't.
- Who's that?
- Well, I don't know.
If it's what's-her-name,
you could ask her to come in.
I don't even know who it is yet!
What you doing here?
Just come to see you.
Well, you can't come in. My mum's here.
- Who is it?
- I'm going out.
Hello.
You all right, sweetheart?
Would you get inside?
- Nothing's changed much.
- No.
Ain't your mum been
around looking after you?
She came around Sunday after mass.
Didn't take you long to mess it up again.
She's laying off me a bit now, though.
- Well, I should think so too, at your age.
- Yeah.
She should have a word with my mum.
I bet she misses you, though.
Fucking... do without it
altogether, I tell you.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
You and me, mate.
We're better off without 'em.
Look...
I'm sorry about... you know?
So you should be.
- Don't get all serious on me, Paul.
- No, no, I ain't.
Yes, you are, you fool.
I just missed you.
How much?
- A lot.
- Just a lot?
No. Yeah...
Well, I might have missed you a bit.
No, I've been going out of me head.
Same as that.
Just so's you know,
I ain't staying the night,
not every time I come round.
And I weren't in a strop before.
I was just speaking my mind.
All right?
Now, give us a snog.
- Hello, good afternoon.
- Hello.
Thank you very much indeed.
Right, that's fine.
- Is that to post or collect?
- Collect, please.
Collect. Thanks very much.
That's six pounds, please, madam.
Six pounds.
Okay.
- I saw her, you know?
- Did you?
Yeah.
Eight o'clock in the morning, she's down
Harlesden buying her yam and banana.
She's like,
"You got a boyfriend yet, Dionne?"
Nearly everyone who went to the funeral
reckoned they'd seen her
and she'd given them some kind of sign.
"Me see your mother
two years before she dead,
and she hold on to me hand
and look in me eye as if she did know."
I mean, if she knew, I wish she'd told us.
You're getting better, though.
It's a nice day.
Yeah.
I don't know.
My head can't contain it all.
It's too soon.
There's nothing rational about grief.
Maybe you're crying for yourself.
- You been out much?
- No. I can't.
Some days, I'm completely vulnerable.
I can feel everything.
Other days, I'm numb.
- Do you want to come out with me?
- No.
- I've got stuff to sort out.
- What?
Life.
- Look, if there's anything I can do...
- No, thanks.
I'll be all right.
Have you heard from Bernard?
No.
Yes!
- He sent a sympathy card.
- Hmm?
Which I thought was
a very nice thing to do.
I did something really bad.
Oh, no, I don't think
I can deal with no confession.
- Cleanse my soul!
- Mm-mmm.
- I did the do.
- Don't do it.
- Did the deed.
- Did it.
With a complete stranger.
- Nah! Who?
- Don't know who.
- Well, what'd he look like?
- Don't know. He was in advertising.
Oh, Lord!
Did you use a condom?
Yes.
Did you use two?
- Yes.
- One on top of the other?
One after the other.
Oh, God!
Do you despair of me?
No.
Yes, you do.
I don't. Did you have a good time?
- Yeah.
- That's all that matters then, isn't it?
Yeah.
I liked my mum as a person,
but I didn't know her.
- I wish I'd known her.
- She loved you.
Yeah, I know.
But that's not in debate, is it?
My mum, she resents me.
She kept you.
She fed ya, she clothed you.
She didn't give you away.
- She could have.
- I wish she had.
No, you don't.
The thing is, they're so secretive.
It's that "back home" thing, you know?
"Come out. Big people are talking."
That sort of vibe.
So you don't pursue things,
because you're brought up not to.
I just let them get on with it.
All I seem to do is think about things
I wish I could have asked her.
Like what?
I don't know.
There's stuff I wish I knew.
- There's stuff I wish I didn't know.
- No.
If you knew you had a limited amount
of time, you'd sort it out.
You'd ask your mum questions,
regardless of whether she got vexed.
Like, I don't know, what happened
between her and your dad, for example.
No. She didn't make no effort for me,
so why should I be interested in her?
And where's my dad anyway?
I don't want to hear her
and Norbert having it off.
I don't want her to know
who I'm having it off with.
And I don't want her to see me drunk.
I don't want her to know nothing about me.
Maybe that's because you're frightened
that when you look at her,
you can see yourself in 20 years' time.
Please.
We choose our parents.
How do you mean?
We choose the parents in this life
that can teach us something,
so that when we go into the next life,
we'll get it right.
Jhoop!
Of course, sometimes,
it don't work, does it?
I'm gonna pop out for a couple of hours.
- What time will you be back?
- 4:30.
- Okay. Have fun.
- Thanks.
Sorry to interrupt. Could you get me
a few of these things in?
- Right.
- I'm a bit low.
I'll give them a ring.
Seventy...
Hello.
Bloody hell.
What you doing here?
I thought I'd come and see you.
Where's Monica?
She's at home, I think.
- You gonna let me in, then?
- Yeah, of course!
Do you want a cup of tea?
Yes, please.
You all right, then?
Smashing.
You been working down this way?
Yeah, around the back of Tower Bridge.
If I'd known you was coming,
I'd have warmed up the seat.
It's warm enough,
I should think.
Does Monica know you've come round here?
No, I didn't know
I was coming meself.
- She's okay, then?
- Yeah, she's fine.
She's busy with the house.
What doing?
I thought it was supposed to be
a new house, you said.
Stenciling.
- What, drawing?
- No.
Stencils on the wall. Decorating.
You must have seen it in magazines.
It's very effective.
Roxanne not in, then?
She's got some bloke in tow.
- Has she?
- Shifty-looking bleeder.
Walks like a crab.
- Your tea's there.
- Ta.
Do you want a sandwich?
No, thanks. Is that what you're having?
I only see her first thing in the morning.
She comes in, grunts,
then buggers off to work.
You should be glad she's got a fella.
I am glad, Maurice!
I want her to be happy.
But I'd like her to bring him round,
see who she's knocking about with.
Just give her a bit of time.
You used to bring your girlfriends home.
Front of the telly, laugh, drink.
You didn't mind me sitting there, did you?
- What's her name? Never stopped talking.
- Tina.
Tina.
And the other one,
wouldn't open her mouth.
- Maxine.
- That's it.
Dad liked her, didn't he?
Nice thighs.
So how's work, then?
Is it at the same place?
Yeah.
I gotta get her
something for her birthday.
- It's her 21st, Maurice.
- August the 7th.
I don't know what she wants.
- Apart from me under a bus.
- That's silly talk.
Me head in the oven.
When you gonna come and see us, then?
- Eh?
- You know, a bit of a get-together.
You can come on Roxanne's birthday.
We'll have some champagne.
- What about Monica?
- She'll be there.
Won't she mind?
No.
- It's her idea, actually.
- Oh.
- How do you fancy a barbecue?
- If you like.
Anyway, it's about time you saw the house.
- Thought you was never gonna ask.
- I'm asking you now.
- You've been there nearly a 12-month.
- Tell Roxanne.
She might not want to come.
She'll say no just to spite me.
Yeah, well, I demand her presence.
- Tell her.
- What if she wants to bring him?
- Has he got a job, this bloke?
- Scaffolding, she says.
Oh.
That's very well paid.
- Is it?
- Yup.
Twenty-one.
I can't believe it, Maurice.
I was carrying her
when I was 21, wasn't I?
You was good with nappies.
Those safety pins, though. Ooh.
Never stabbed her though,
did you, darling?
Stabbed meself a couple of times.
Seventeen, weren't you?
I was.
The place is still standing, then?
Not for much longer.
You should see Dad's room.
- What's up with it?
- It's like the Niagara Falls up there.
- What's it got, a leak?
- Yeah.
Only when it's raining.
I'll have a look.
Nice to have a man about the place.
Wish I had known you was coming.
It's dry at the moment.
The whole lot's gonna come down.
Yeah, these look a bit dodgy,
I have to admit.
- Are you up to date on the rent?
- Of course I am!
Give him a ring, get him to do something
about it. It's his responsibility.
Don't be daft, Maurice.
He don't give a toss, does he?
I'll get someone to look at it.
And I'll pay.
Look at all this junk.
What you gonna do with it?
Give us a cuddle, Maurice.
Please, sweetheart.
Why have you left it so bloody long?
Well, you know, it's ̶̶ it's work and ̶̶
There's nothing the matter
with your dialing finger.
Well, you can ring me.
You're always too busy, ain't you?
Look, um ̶̶
Look, sit your yourself down.
You're the only one I've got, Maurice.
You love me, don't you?
Hold me tight, Maurice, please.
Sweetheart...
My little brother.
Look at you.
That's the good life for you.
When you gonna shave, eh?
Slap your arse.
Why don't you chuck it all out, eh?
I mean, look at it.
Some of it hasn't been touched
since Mum died.
Can you use anything, Maurice,
in your new house?
To fill a space?
No, thanks.
I thought I might move in here.
Front view.
See the world go by.
Remember this?
Yeah.
That's no use to you, is it?
I don't think so.
You ain't gonna make me
an auntie now, are you?
Sweetheart?
Listen, Cynth...
I'd better be going.
You'll let me know about the barbecue,
then, will you, sweetheart?
Of course I will. Tell her if she
can't make it, I'll give her a clump.
- Not before I do.
- Hang on.
- Shall I say hello to Monica for you?
- If you like, sweetheart.
- There you go.
- Thanks, darling.
See you.
Ta-ra.
What was your mum like when your dad died?
- What do you mean?
- How did she cope?
I don't know.
Too young to remember.
She just got on with it, I suppose,
like everybody else.
Did you have to look after Craig?
What, you mean like
your big sister looked after you?
No, I did not.
My dad never said a word
about my mum after she died.
That's men for you.
I hated him for it.
He must have been in real pain.
Maybe he just couldn't share it.
I didn't know what I felt.
I still don't.
Cynthia's antics
couldn't have helped him much.
Do you miss Craig?
- Why would I miss Craig?
- Well, he's your brother.
- He's in Saudi Arabia, isn't he?
- Yeah.
Well, I don't exactly miss him.
Why? Do you miss Cynthia?
Do you think Roxanne's serious
about this scaffolder bloke?
Well, she's only known him
for five minutes.
Mind you, I was married
at her age, wasn't I?
I wonder if she knows.
What, about us?
- What's there to know about us?
- You know what I mean.
How would she know about that?
- Unless you've told her.
- I haven't told her.
- I hope Cynthia doesn't know either.
- She doesn't.
That's all right, then.
No, I meant if she knows about Cynthia.
- You know, before she was born.
- I don't know.
- I mean, she's got a half-brother
or half-sister knocking about somewhere.
- She's got a right to know.
- That's up to Cynthia.
You'd never say anything, would you?
- Of course not.
- Good.
Anyway, she must have told her.
She never told her who her father was.
None of us knew who he was.
- I wonder if she ever misses him.
- Who?
- Roxanne.
- Can't miss what you've never had.
Can't you?
I was gonna kill him.
Poor Cynthia.
Saint Cynthia.
- She tried her best.
- Did she?
Yeah.
Yeah. She did.
She gave me a lot of love.
What shall I tell him if he phones, then?
- Who?
- Maurice!
- I don't know. Tell him what you want.
- Are you gonna bring your bloke or not?
- No, I ain't!
- Have you asked him?
No!
- Hello?
- That'll be him now.
- Let me talk to him.
Shut it!
Well, there ain't no one there.
- Might be one of them perverts.
- Sweetheart!
Will you stop going on
about this fucking barbecue?
You're going to see him now, ain't you?
You can ask him!
I don't even know if I want him to go,
and it ain't for ages anyway.
See you later!
- I, Zoe...
- take you, Darren...
- to be my husband...
- to have and to hold...
- from this day forward...
- for better or for worse...
- for richer or for poorer...
... in sickness and in health...
Darren and Zoe
have given their consent
and made their marriage vows
to each other.
They have declared their marriage
by joining of hands
and by the giving and receiving of rings.
I therefore proclaim that they are
husband and wife.
Ain't you seeing him tonight, then?
I'm having an early night.
- Keep me company?
- I've got a hangover.
You should stop in more often.
You are looking after yourself with him,
ain't you, sweetheart?
- What do you mean?
- You know, taking care.
I don't want to ask you nothing personal,
darling, but... you taking the pill?
That is personal!
Why don't you bring him round?
- Leave it out.
- I'd like to meet him!
I wouldn't know him
if he stood up in me soup.
Don't hold your breath.
You don't want to leave it up to him,
darling. Men are all the same.
- Mum!
- I hope he uses a what's-name.
- Condoms.
- Mind your own business!
They can leak! You want to be careful!
You're jealous, ain't you?
- Where is he tonight, anyway?
- I don't know.
Most likely out giving somebody else one.
That's how I got caught with you.
Running out of the pill.
- You could have a coil fitted.
- Change the record!
Dr. Mulholland, make an appointment.
- You'd suit the sponge.
- Keep your voice down!
I've got a dutch cap floating
around somewhere upstairs.
You could have that.
Run it under the tap,
bit of talcum powder.
- Where you going?
- I don't have to listen to this!
Sweetheart!
Roxanne!
Sweetheart, darling,
I'm only trying to help you!
- Leave me alone.
- I'm your mother!
Get out of my room!
It don't matter if you have a little baby.
I'll look after it.
- I ain't getting pregnant!
- I'll give up me job.
- It's nothing to do with you!
- Yes, it bloody is!
I'm not having you dropping it at my door!
- Jesus Christ!
- I'm sorry, darling!
Fuck off!
You make me sick, you stupid bitch!
Fuck!
Hello?
I'm sorry to trouble you,
but I'm trying to locate a Cynthia Purley.
Yes?
Is that Cynthia Purley?
Yes.
Cynthia Rose Purley?
Of 76 Quilter Street?
Yes. What is it you want, darling?
Hello?
Did you want Roxanne? She's gone out.
- No.
- She ain't in any trouble, is she?
No, it's about Elizabeth.
Elizabeth? Elizabeth who?
Elizabeth Purley.
Oh! But she's dead.
No, she isn't.
She is, darling. I should know.
I should know.
Look, sweetheart, she's me mother.
She went in 1961.
No, I mean baby Elizabeth Purley.
Baby Eliz...
Who is this?
She was born on the 23rd of July, 1968...
at... sorry about this.
Yeah, at the Haven,
Wells Grange Avenue, Sutton Surrey.
Look, I'm sorry.
I know this must be a shock to you.
Listen, darling. What is it you want?
I'm really sorry.
You mustn't come round here, sweetheart.
I didn't want to upset you.
You mustn't do that.
And you mustn't phone, neither.
I just needed to know.
Yes, but you can't come round,
'cause no one knows about you, see?
- Right.
- Promise me you won't come round.
Promise me!
Look. I've got your address. If I wanted
to come round, I'd have done it already.
I'm ever so sorry, sweetheart.
I'm a little bit upset.
Promise me you won't come round.
All right, I promise.
Thank you.
Um...
C-Can I meet you somewhere?
Oh, I shouldn't think so, darling.
See, I've got lots of, um...
I've got lots of questions
I want to ask you.
Yeah, well, I gotta go now.
Please?
What's your name, anyway? Eh?
- Hortense.
- Hortense?
Yeah.
Hortense what?
Cumberbatch.
Clumberbunch? That's a funny name, innit?
Yeah, I suppose it is.
Are you on the phone?
Yeah. Uh, do you want
to take my number down?
Oh, I don't think I got a pencil.
I'll wait.
I've got one.
Um, it's 0171...
219 ̶̶
Sorry, 619...
4840.
Yeah, ta-ra.
Hello?
- Hello?
- Do you want to meet me or not, then?
Oh, hello.
Yes or no, it's up to you.
Well, yeah, of course I want to meet you.
Well, then...
Are you sure about this?
I mean, if you're not sure...
Where do you want to meet me?
Well, where would you like to meet?
I don't know. Anywhere.
- Not here, though.
- No, of course not.
Uh...
What about outside Holborn tube station?
Holborn.
When?
What are you doing this Saturday coming?
Nothing. I'm never bloody doing anything.
Saturday, then.
What time?
7:30?
Half past seven.
Now, listen,
you mustn't phone me here again.
Do you understand me?
Otherwise, I won't come and meet you.
Now, I'll see you on Saturday.
Hello?
Don't even know what you look like.
- Hello, sweetheart.
- What's for tea?
- Got you a bit of steak.
- What for?
- Little treat for you.
- Ain't you having none?
I'll just fry meself an egg.
Do you want a beer?
- We ain't got none.
- I got you some.
Oh, did you?
- You going out?
- No, I'm staying in.
I'm gonna have a few early nights.
I've decided.
Excuse me.
- What is it, sweetheart?
- Are you Cynthia?
Yeah. How'd you know?
Hello. I'm Hortense.
What you talking about?
Hortense Cumberbatch.
I spoke to you on the telephone.
- What, that was you?
- Yeah.
Oh, no!
No, sweetheart.
No, darling.
You've been ringing the wrong person!
Cynthia Purley.
Where'd you get my name from, anyway?
It's on my birth certificate.
What you talking about,
on your birth certificate?
It can't be!
It's got your name and your address on it.
There.
No, that's all wrong, darling.
They've made a mistake
down in the offices.
You want to get down there,
get that sorted.
- That's someone having a joke.
- I don't think so.
Let me have a look at that.
I'm ever so sorry, sweetheart.
It must be a bit
of a disappointment, poor girl.
Look, I really think you
ought to see these documents.
Why? What is it?
Why don't we, uh, go somewhere
and have ̶̶ and sit down?
No, I think I better be going, darling.
Look, you've come all this way. Please.
Let's go and have
a cup of tea or something.
There's places down there.
Come on.
I hope you find your mum, sweetheart.
You keep looking.
- Go on.
- No, thanks. I don't smoke.
Nor should you.
My daughter smokes like a chimney.
- You've got a daughter?
- Yeah.
Ain't never been in here before.
They shouldn't go
raising your hopes like that.
It ain't fair.
Is this your signature?
This is stupid.
I don't understand it.
I mean, I can't be your mother, can I?
- Why not?
- Well, look at me!
What?
Listen, I don't mean
nothing by it, darling,
but I ain't never been
with a Black man in my life.
No disrespect nor nothing.
I'd have remembered, wouldn't I?
Oh, bloody hell.
Oh, Jesus Christ Almighty!
I'm sorry, sweetheart.
I'm so ashamed.
You shouldn't be ashamed.
I can't look at you.
I didn't know, sweetheart.
Honest, I didn't know.
What didn't you know?
I didn't know you was Black!
See, I ̶̶
I thought they got the dates all wrong.
All this time, I thought you
was born six weeks premature,
but you weren't!
You wasn't.
Who was he?
You don't wanna know that, darling.
I do.
Listen, I want to be honest with you,
but I can't tell you that, sweetheart.
I'm sorry.
Look at you.
I expect I'm a bit of a disappointment
to you, ain't I?
No.
You don't have to say that, darling.
I know.
You've been better off without me,
I can tell you that much.
I done you a good turn.
Your tea's getting cold.
What's your mum like, then?
Does she mind you looking for me?
My mum died recently.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What about your dad?
He's dead and all.
Are you married?
No, no, um, I ain't, uh...
I ain't married, sweetheart.
- Are you?
- No.
I'll bet you've got a boyfriend,
though, ain't ya?
No, not at the moment.
A nice-looking girl like you?
Have you got a boyfriend?
I give them all a wide berth.
They got me into enough trouble
in the past, ain't they?
You got a job, have you?
- Yeah.
- That's good.
What doing?
- I'm an optometrist.
- Eh?
I test eyes.
Optician.
Oh, yeah?
Well...
there's a turn up.
What do you do?
I work in a factory.
Do you like it?
Pays the rent.
How about your daughter?
She works for the Council.
Have you got any sisters?
No, two brothers.
Are they, um...
adopted?
No.
What they do?
One's a computer salesman
and the other one's got his own garage.
I bet your mum
was proud of you, wasn't she?
Yeah, she was.
Yeah, of course she was.
I'd have been proud.
Why didn't you want to see me?
Well, 'cause nobody knows
about you, sweetheart.
I don't want to upset my daughter, do I?
I mean, when I was born.
I couldn't.
I was too upset, see?
They wanted me to look at you.
They wanted me to hold you,
but I couldn't. I just couldn't.
I didn't know if I was coming or going.
I was only a little girl meself, 16.
I didn't have no choice.
If I had seen you,
I'd have wanted to keep you.
You do believe me, don't you, sweetheart?
I don't blame you, darling.
You only just found out?
No.
I've known since I was seven.
- What, your mum and dad told ya, did they?
- Yeah, they did.
They sound like nice people.
Yeah.
My mum told me on the plane
on our way back from Barbados.
Little girl.
Was you upset?
I just looked out at the clouds.
Haven't you ever thought about me?
Yeah, of course I have.
But 'tain't no good
pining over what you ain't got, is it?
But didn't you think I'd look for you?
No, I didn't, as it happens.
Wish you hadn't bothered now, don't you?
No.
I'm glad.
I don't want to disrupt
your family or anything.
I just had to see you.
I had to know who you were.
Listen...
I want to wish you all the best,
sweetheart, whatever you do.
And I'll be thinking of you.
Bit quiet, ain't you?
What's up?
- Are you going out?
- Yeah, in a bit.
You feeling all right?
Oh, there's nothing the matter with me,
sweetheart. Nothing at all.
- Did you find anything today?
- Frozen chicken.
- What, in the road?
- No, in a bin.
Still cold.
Some dirty magazines.
- Do you bring them home?
- No.
Still, I suppose there are worse jobs.
Gotta laugh, ain't you, sweetheart?
Else you'd cry.
- Hello?
- Is that Hortense?
Speaking.
It's Cynthia.
Hello.
I didn't think you'd be in.
I am.
Well, I just, um,
wanted to ring up and say...
how nice it was
to meet you yesterday, that's all.
Thank you.
Been thinking about you all day.
I've been thinking about you.
Yeah, well, um...
I just wanted to say that.
Thank you.
I don't know what to say now.
Daft, ain't it?
Got home all right, did you?
Yeah, thank you.
What have you been doing today?
Oh, just out the back sunning meself.
What you been doing?
Just chilling out, really.
- Yeah, hot, ain't it?
- Yeah.
Well, that's all I wanted to say,
sweetheart.
Ta-ra, then.
I'd really like to see you again.
- Would you?
- Yeah.
Oh, that'd be nice.
Do you like Italian food?
Yeah. Eat anything, me.
Chinese, kebabs, the lot.
- What?
- Nothing.
It's great.
And...
Great. Other side, please.
Lovely. So if you'd bring
your face round this way, please?
Can you shut the door, please?
Yeah, sure.
Sorry.
So who did your original photographs?
My dad, actually, but my solicitor
said that they weren't good enough.
Do you have a police photographer?
No.
I'm just gonna come in a bit closer,
so I hope you don't
suffer from claustrophobia.
No, I don't, actually.
That's good.
Okay, so I'm just gonna move your ̶̶
- Thank you.
- Sorry.
That's great.
Okay, and...
A little bit closer.
Now...
I know this isn't very nice...
but it's gotta be done, hasn't it?
- I want them to look as bad as possible.
- Of course.
I lost my job. I was good at my job.
What did you do?
I'm a beauty consultant.
Okay, and if you'd just
bring your chin up. Put it up here.
Lovely and... that's it.
So what actually happened to you?
My seat belt was broken.
I went through the windscreen.
It wasn't my car. I wasn't driving.
It wasn't my fault.
- Yeah, you said.
- It wasn't!
You okay?
Mm-hmm.
Did the driver sustain any injuries?
No, unfortunately.
He's obviously not in your good books.
I haven't seen him since.
I don't want to see him, either.
Life isn't fair, is it?
Someone always draws the short straw.
Okay, that's very good. Yeah.
One more.
- Here's your receipt.
- Thank you.
Give us a ring in the morning,
we'll see what we can do.
- Fine.
- Bye, then.
Mind how you go.
Oh, Maurice, that's terrible.
How'd she do that, then?
Car crash.
Oh, she's so lovely.
- Not anymore, she isn't.
- It's tragic.
She's getting
some ear hole from that dosser now.
Oh, he's been looking at me.
Gives me the creeps.
I don't believe it.
How much money
do you think she'd get, then?
- What?
- Insurance.
Oh, if she's lucky, 15, 20 grand.
Don't know what I'd do
if it happened to me.
Think I'd kill meself.
- Hello.
- Hiya.
- Didn't expect to see you.
- Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
Hello, Monica!
Hi, Jane.
Just been for a facial.
I'm dying for a cup of tea.
- Over there.
- What?
- That bloke.
- What bloke?
- See who it is?
- What, by the lamppost?
Yeah.
It's Stuart Christian, isn't it?
No.
It is.
But he's in Sydney.
Is he?
He's coming over.
Doesn't look very well, does he?
It's that man!
It's all right, Jane.
We know him.
- Do ya?
- What does he want?
God knows.
- Well, it's over to you then, buster.
- Thanks very much.
Hello, Stuart.
Maurice.
Long time, no see.
Yeah.
How's things?
Fine, thanks. Fine.
Good.
You're looking well.
- You're still here, then?
- Yup.
Good.
I thought we'd lost you to Australia.
Well...
How's the wife and kids?
- Maureen.
- Monica. Haven't got any kids.
- Haven't you?
- No. She's great, thanks.
Good on you, mate.
- You still in the game?
- Look at all this.
What are you doing?
It's lost its style, Maurice.
Has it?
Looks like a dentist's waiting room.
I'd kill for a cup of tea.
If you're 21 or a millionaire, it's great.
Or you've got nine kids, you're fine.
Brilliant.
Open arms.
But for guys like you and me,
it doesn't matter
how good you are, forget it.
But it was an experience,
and now I'm back.
That's too bad.
You were full of such big plans as well.
Well, it's a big place.
- That's true.
- Too fucking big.
You're looking as gorgeous
as ever, Monica.
So, Stuart, you thinking
about setting up again?
No, forget it.
Too much of a pain.
You know what it's like, Maurice.
You sweat your balls off for years,
you try and make people happy,
and what do you get back?
Nothing.
Thanks.
And by the way, Stuart,
this is Jane, my assistant.
This is Mr. Christian,
the gentleman I bought the business from.
Hello.
Hiya, Jane.
I hope he's treating you well.
- He's all right.
- You can work for me anytime.
I'm all right where I am, thank you.
Your wife must have been
sorry to come back.
Which wife?
Oh, that bitch.
She never came out there
in the first place.
No?
So where are you living
at the moment, Stuart?
- Down at Grays.
- Essex?
Yeah, my mum's place.
- Must be nice for her.
- Having her boy to fuss over.
She's dead.
She died when I was still in Bangkok.
Oh...
- Sorry to hear that.
- That's a shame.
Didn't see much of her, anyway.
It's my dad I miss.
You win some, you lose some.
You must have had
some lovely weather in Australia.
Too hot.
It's too hot over there,
it's too cold over here.
Hasn't changed much in here.
Just a lick of paint.
Still got the Bronica, then?
Yup.
I should have thought you'd be able
to afford a Hasselblad by now, Maurice.
I can.
Well off, are you?
Surviving, mate.
Yeah.
You've done very well
out of my business, haven't you?
My business.
- No, it's my business, Maurice.
- No, Stuart, no.
Used to be your business.
I bought it from you. It's my business.
Listen. This was an antiques shop.
- That's right.
- There was nothing here.
That's right. I know.
I gave you my goodwill,
I gave you my clientele,
I gave you my fucking reputation.
You gave me nothing, Stuart.
With all due respect,
your client list was shit.
It wasn't.
I followed it up.
I wrote to them, I rang them,
I didn't get one bite.
Now, if there's any success in this shop,
it's down to me.
That's bollocks!
No, it's not bollocks, Stuart.
It's the truth.
- How many weddings do you do?
- Oh, enough.
- How many?
- Oh, about 40 a year.
- I used to do 140.
- What, personally?
No, not personally, no.
Nobody does them personally.
- I do.
- Well, then, you're a bloody fool.
You get people in, get them out there.
If the work's there, take it.
You gotta grab it while you can.
It's not in my interest
to get some tosser in.
I mean, I'll have no control.
He could fuck up my reputation.
I'm not a tosser!
- I didn't say you were.
- I'm not a fucking tosser!
I'm not talking about you.
- Don't call me a tosser!
- I wasn't talking about you, Stuart!
I can still do it!
I've still got an eye.
They can't teach you that.
I'm still a photographer!
Of course you are.
So if you want someone to help you out,
no worries, mate.
I'll be all right.
Right. Right, right.
I see what you're saying, Stuart, yeah.
I'll bear it in mind.
You can lend me a camera.
Yeah, sure.
I had mine nicked.
Yeah, great.
Thanks.
Sure.
I thought we were
never gonna get rid of him.
There but for the grace of God.
Tea's on the table!
All right.
- Ain't you having none?
- No.
Why not?
I'm going out.
Where are you going?
I'm off now then, sweetheart.
Ain't you gonna tell me where?
You never tell me where you're going.
You don't never go nowhere.
Well, I'm going somewhere tonight.
- Ta-ra.
- Have fun.
Don't wait up.
She's been acting right funny.
- Where's she gone?
- Who the fuck knows? She won't tell us.
He's all right, though, Maurice.
He's always got plenty
of wine in and that.
- We'll get well pissed.
- Yeah, nice one.
I'm a little bit shy of you,
to tell you the truth, sweetheart.
Of me? Oh, you shouldn't be.
And look at you, sitting there.
- You look like a model.
- Oh, do I?
I bet you was a pretty little girl.
Weren't you?
Yeah, lovely.
Don't do that. You'll stay like it.
Stop it! Don't spoil it.
I used to drive my mum mad pulling faces.
Did you? Bet she was a laugh, wasn't she?
No, not really.
Thought you said she was a midwife.
Yeah, she was.
Oh, I'd like to have been one of them.
I love babies.
- I'm sorry, darling.
- It's all right.
- Cheers.
- Is that all right for you?
- Yeah, it's lovely.
Wet, innit?
Where's this food, then? I'm ravishing.
What?
I've got so many things I want to ask you,
but I can't remember what they are.
Nice to have somebody to talk to, innit?
Give us your hand here.
God, you've got beautiful skin.
Right, let's have a look at you.
- What, can you read palms?
- I used to.
I ain't done it for years.
Nobody's interested no more.
Now, if I didn't know you,
I could see just by looking here
what a nice girl you are.
Big heart.
Oh, you're gonna live
to a ripe old age and all.
Let's have a look.
- Couple of kids.
- Wow.
- Do you want babies?
- I'm not sure, really.
Oh, don't you?
Maybe. I don't know yet.
Yeah, of course you do.
- What star sign are you?
- Leo. I'm on the cusp of Cancer.
When's your birthday?
Oh, it's the 23rd of July, ain't it?
You'd think I'd know that, wouldn't ya?
- That was the other day, wasn't it?
- Yeah, Sunday.
Well, why didn't you say nothing
when I phoned ya?
- It's not a big deal.
- Did you have a party?
- No.
- What'd you do, then?
Stayed in, read me book,
had a little drink.
- What, on your own?
- Yeah.
Oh...
Well, happy birthday
for Sunday, sweetheart.
Aw, thank you.
You're out now, ain't you?
- Yeah, in good company.
- With your mum.
You thought about
having some driving lessons?
- What for?
- I could get you some for your birthday.
Don't be stupid.
Get yourself a little motor. Eh?
Ain't you going out tonight?
- No.
- Why? What's happened?
- You going out?
- Yeah, later.
- Where are you going?
- Down to the pub.
- I hope you're taking care of yourself.
- What do you mean?
You don't want to go
getting knocked up, do ya?
Don't be so bloody cheeky.
Not at your age.
- All right?
- Missed a bit, darling.
Who's this?
Oh, don't start with that again.
Come on. Who is it?
- 'Tain't me, is it?
- No.
- Well, who?
- Sylvester Stallone.
I can't understand a word he says.
You like looking at him, though.
No, he ain't my sort.
- What is your type?
- What, film star?
- Yeah.
- Marlon.
I like a bloke with a bit of meat on him.
What sort of bloke do you go in for, then?
Hmm.
Intelligent, sensitive.
Well, don't you care what they look like?
Yeah, but they gotta have
something going on upstairs.
You only have Black boyfriends, do you?
Yeah.
How do you look after yourself, then?
You know, if you don't wanna have babies.
Condoms.
Oh, well, you just stop at that,
then, do you?
- Yeah, it's the best way, really.
- Well, you can't be too careful.
- Can you, these days?
- You gotta protect yourself.
It's my daughter's birthday next week.
- How old is she?
- Twenty-one.
- Nice age.
- Well, she's your sister now, really.
- Ain't she?
- Yeah, I suppose she is.
Does she look like you?
Yeah, a bit.
You look more like me than she does.
We're the same build.
What are her eyes like?
Blue.
My brother's doing a party for her.
That's nice.
At least it takes the strain off of you.
Yeah, well, there is that.
Shame you ain't coming, really.
- Ah.
- Meet your new family.
Oh, sweetheart...
I nearly forgot!
- Happy birthday for Sunday.
- Oh!
- Oh, you shouldn't have bothered.
- Oh, 'tain't nothing much.
Oh.
Oh, thank you.
Don't start crying.
Perhaps I should ask him.
- What?
- If I can take someone.
Oh, I don't know.
It's a family thing, isn't it?
Well, you are family, ain't you?
I'm proud of you.
Listen, Maurice, sweetheart,
I wanted to ask you a favor.
Go ahead. What's that, then?
You know the party Sunday?
- Barbecue, yeah.
- Yeah.
Can I bring a mate, sweetheart?
- Hello?
- Is it a bloke?
Of course it ain't a bloke,
you silly bugger.
Chance'd be a fine thing.
Who is it, then?
Oh, just someone at work.
We've been out a couple of times,
and I was meant
to have seen her Sunday, only I forgot.
Is that all right, then?
- I suppose so.
- What do you mean, you suppose so?
That'd be fine.
Smashing.
- I have to check it out, though.
- Check it out? Who with?
Listen, uh, if I don't phone you back,
bring her, all right?
I don't want to upset nobody.
No, don't worry.
Are you sure, then?
Yeah, yeah, no problem, yeah.
Okay, then, sweetheart.
Looking forward to it.
All right, yeah, well,
say hello to Roxanne for me.
Yeah. Ta-ra, then.
All right, ta. Bye, Cynth.
Listen, I spoke to my little brother today
and he says it's all right.
So do you wanna come, then?
Oh, I don't know.
I told him you was me mate.
I'd still feel a bit awkward.
Oh, don't be daft, sweetheart.
You'll be with me, won't ya?
It won't feel right.
I thought you wanted to come.
Yeah.
Well, of course,
if you changed your mind...
I was looking forward to it.
Oh, I know.
What do you think, then?
- All right, I'll come.
- You're coming?
- Yes.
- All right then, sweetheart.
Listen, I'll give you a ring
later in the week
and give you the address and everything.
Okay, then.
Okay. Ta-ra, then!
Bye-bye.
Jesus.
You should have just said yes.
Making me look like a...
I can hardly say no now.
It's up to you.
I don't know anything about this person,
whoever she is.
Some new mate.
They've been out a few times.
Two hysterical nutters.
I'm just glad she's got a friend.
I'm gonna have a great time.
I thought I'd ask Jane as well.
Anybody else you want to invite?
I've only got four garden chairs.
Oh, give us two of them painkillers.
There you go.
Do you fancy some fish and chips?
Don't be sarcastic.
I wasn't. Sorry.
Cheers, mate.
- There's a bell here.
- Don't do that!
- I've just done the knocker!
- All right!
Hello there.
Hello, sweetheart.
You got here in one piece, then?
Long time, no see.
Yes, that's right. Thank you.
- Hello, birthday girl!
- All right, Monica.
- Oh, look at you!
- This is Paul.
- Hello, Paul.
- How do you do?
Nice to meet you.
Oh, there's Maurice.
Now, come away in.
- Hi, Jane.
- Hello, Monica.
Oh, this is Jane. Maurice has just been
picking her up from the station.
Here he is! Hello, sweetheart!
- Hiya.
- You all right, Maurice?
I got you that.
- You didn't have to do that.
- It's all right.
- You all right?
- Yeah.
This is Paul. That's Maurice.
- Hello, mate.
- Ain't you got one for me, then?
- Yeah, of course I have.
- Hello, darling.
- Don't kill him.
- You've landed on your feet here.
Ain't you, Maurice?
This is Jane, my lovely assistant.
I talked to you on the phone,
ain't I, Jane?
- Yeah, that's right.
- Can I take your coats?
- Yes.
- What do you want to drink?
- Red, white, rosé, beer?
- Oh, I'll have white, Maurice.
Oh, thanks a lot. Cheers.
- Cynth?
- I'll have white please, Maurice.
- Jane?
- Rosé.
Okeydoke.
- Where's the friend, then?
- I have no idea.
Have you got an ashtray, darling?
There's one on the coffee table, Cynthia.
I didn't think you would have given up.
One of the few pleasures in life, Monica.
- These are very bright.
- Don't you like them?
Yeah, I'll just put them in a vase.
What you got that out there for?
We like it.
Well, don't laugh! It's stupid.
It's one of my early works.
Miserable little git.
He was fucking around
behind the camera.
Oi, mind your language, you little sod.
- So how's work, then?
- It's all right, yeah.
- Still enjoying it?
- Yeah, it's all right.
- When are you going to college again?
- Shut up about college.
- You're going to college, ain't you?
- No, I ain't.
- You should do. You got a good brain.
- I don't want to use it, though.
- Suit yourself.
- Yeah, I will.
- Paul's a scaffolder.
- Yeah, your mum said.
- I bet that's hard work, innit?
- Can be, mate.
- Yeah, especially in the winter.
- That's right.
I wanted to give it a Mediterranean feel.
- Well, it's a lovely kitchen.
- And this is the ̶̶ Oops.
- Oh, it's a big lavatory.
- This is the downstairs toilet.
Oh, that's handy, isn't it?
'Cause if you're in the garden ̶̶
Exactly. It's really convenient.
And I think the peach tones
make it quite tranquil.
Yeah.
So you know where it is if you need it.
Now, excuse me, Jane.
- This is the garage.
- I thought it was the cupboard.
- Is that a new car?
- Yes, that's my car.
What was the matter with your other one?
Nothing. I'll show you upstairs.
We'll start with this.
- Oh.
- There's the tank.
That's where I keep
my towels and bed linen.
- Just your airing cupboard.
- Hmm. It's not very capacious.
And this is Maurice's bathroom.
It's green! Matches your tank!
Are these all new carpets,
are they, sweetheart?
Oh, yes.
And this is the master bedroom.
Gosh, it's
more like the bridal suite.
It's beautiful!
I have always wanted a four-poster.
I can see Maurice
thrashing about in there.
It is a king-size.
Oh, it's like something
out of a fairy tale.
I bet this cost a bob or two.
Well, it certainly wasn't cheap.
And here's another lavatory!
Oh, that bathroom's mine. The en suite.
You've got
the one each, have you?
- That's nice, ain't it, Jane?
- It's like a hotel.
We don't want to be
tripping over each other.
Aw, you've got everything, Monica.
- So where's this friend, then?
- He's here, isn't he?
No. Your mum's.
What you talking about?
She rang me at the shop and asked me
if she could bring a friend from work.
- That's the first I've heard of it.
- Is it?
- Yeah.
- What, she's never mentioned it?
- No.
- Peculiar.
That must be who
she's been going out with.
She's a dark horse, isn't she?
- Hello.
- No, I'm sorry.
I'm a friend of Cynthia's.
Yes. Oh, yes, of course.
Hello, sweetheart!
- Hello.
- I thought you were ̶̶
Come on in!
That's me mate, Hortense.
- Hi.
- That's my brother's wife.
- Oh, pleased to meet you.
- Monica.
- Hello, Monica.
- But come on out the back.
- Meet me brother.
- Okay.
- Can I take your coat for you, um ̶̶
- Hortense.
- Thank you.
This is me little brother, Maurice.
- Hello. Pleased to meet you, Maurice.
- How do you do?
Ain't that little, is he? That's Hortense.
- Hortense?
- Yeah, that's right.
And this is me daughter, Roxanne.
Oh, happy birthday. There you go.
Oh, you didn't have
to do that, sweetheart.
- It's okay.
- That's Paul, her intended.
- He ain't me intended.
- Pleased to meet you, Paul.
- And this is, um ̶̶
- Jane.
- Maurice's assistant.
- Hi.
- Very nice to meet you, Hortense.
- You too.
- That's nice, isn't it, sweetheart?
- What would you like to drink?
- Red, white, rosé?
- White wine, please.
- Thanks. That's really nice.
- You're welcome.
- We'll have it later.
- No, don't waste it!
I've got some for later
to have with the cake.
We thought you got lost.
Well, I took a couple of wrong turns.
- Did you come by minicab?
- No, she's got a car.
- That's really nice, that.
- Thanks.
- There you go.
- Thank you.
- Who wants a top up?
- I'll have one with you, Maurice.
- Not for me, thanks.
- You all right?
- Yeah, so far.
- Would you like a crisp, Hortense?
No, I'm fine, thanks.
I only met Paul
for the first time today, Hortense.
- Really?
- He's a scaffolder.
- Are you?
- Yeah.
Another one bites the dust.
That must be quite dangerous, Paul.
- Yeah, well, it can be.
- Here, come and lollop over here.
Do you have to go up really high?
Sometimes.
- Just you and the elements, really.
- Ever fallen off?
- Would you like a crudité?
- Thank you, no.
- I think I'll wait till later.
- Oh!
- So you work with me mum, yeah?
- Yeah.
- Not on the machines?
- No.
- You coming round tomorrow night, Paul?
- Mum.
- Well, it's ̶̶
- We're going out.
You'll come round before then, won't you?
- Have a drink? It's her 21st!
- It's no big deal!
Well, I ain't give you your present yet.
Chicken drumsticks.
- Do you want some salad, sweetheart?
- Yes, please.
I'll get you some.
You doing something
special tomorrow night, you two?
- No, down to the pub as usual.
- Oh?
Can we use fingers?
Use what you like.
Use your feet if you want.
You've a knife and fork there, Jane.
- It's a bit late now.
- What do you do at the factory, then?
This looks really lovely, Maurice.
Thank you.
- I hope it don't kill you.
- There's salad servers there, Cynthia.
- You ain't her boss, are you?
- No.
- Here you are, sweetheart.
- Thank you.
- Do you want some salad, Paul?
- No, I'm all right, thanks.
- It's good for you. Make you grow.
- He don't want none.
What about Jane? Does she want salad?
Yes, thanks very much.
What do you do then, Roxanne?
- I work for the Council.
- What, doing the dole?
- No, I'm a road sweeper.
- Wow.
- Are you?
- Yeah.
- Who's for a potato?
- She's got my plate.
- Here you are, sweetheart.
- One for you, Hortense?
- Yes, please.
- Yeah, I'll have some of that and all.
- Please.
- You do get girl road sweepers, don't ya?
- Right, burgers and bangers.
- Nice one.
Yeah, that's your one, Roxanne.
That's the one with your name on it.
The burnt one.
- Yeah.
- Potato for you, Paul?
- Please.
- There's a nice, big one.
- Here you are, darling.
- One for you, pet?
- No, ta.
- Shall I do you, Monica?
I can see to myself, thanks, Cynthia.
- Why don't you sit down?
- What about Maurice?
- Who's looking after the worker?
- Don't worry about me.
- I've been picking all evening.
- Whoops, sorry.
Your potato's on your plate there,
Cynthia.
- I'll have some salad.
- Can I have my tongs back, please?
- Oh, sorry.
- Got butter?
Yes, just a minute.
- May I have some mustard, Monica?
- Uh-huh.
Oh, you like the American,
don't you, Roxanne?
Yeah, ta.
All right, I'll just get some salad.
- Do you want some butter, Paul?
- All right, darling?
- Yeah, just waiting for the butter.
- There you go, Cynth.
- Oh, Maurice!
- That'll shut you up.
Oh? You having a steak, are you, Cynthia?
Yes, thank you, Monica.
Well, that'll put hairs on your chest.
Like some mustard?
Or would you prefer the French?
This looks lovely, Maurice.
Right. There you go, mate.
- Oh, thanks, darling.
- Half a cow for you.
Fucking hell, look at the size of that!
Oh, that's ridiculous.
There's enough there for all of us.
That'll put some color
in your cheeks, Paul.
Right. You sure no one else wants a steak?
- Well, ain't you having one?
- No, he's not, Cynthia.
- Not allowed.
- Would you like some mustard, Paul?
- Oh, it's lovely.
- Can't get rid of it, can you?
Oh, it's a real communal thing, eating.
Yes.
This is a lovely house.
Well, we like it.
- I'll show you around later if you want.
- Yeah, thanks. That would be nice.
Yeah, it's brilliant.
Do you live in a flat then, Hortense?
- Yeah.
- Yeah, it's her own.
She's got a mortgage and everything.
Whereabouts are you?
Kilburn.
That's a bit of a schlep, innit?
The Old Kent Road and back every day?
- I just get on the tube.
- She drives!
I drive to the station.
You've got a bedsit, ain't you, Paul?
- Yeah, that's right.
- Oh, that's a shame.
Wish I had a place of me own.
Do you still live at home, then?
No chance.
So, do you two work on the same machine?
No. I'm the only one on slits.
Hmm.
Do you choose
your own working hours then, Roxanne?
Not bloody likely.
Just biding her time
till you go to college, aren't you?
- I ain't going to college!
- Hortense went to college.
Mmm? What did you study?
Optometry.
What's that, then?
- It's to do with the eye, isn't it?
- That's right.
- Testing.
- Mmm.
- And you've given it all up now, have you?
- Not exactly.
What you doing working
in a cardboard box factory, then?
- I'm doing research.
- Oh.
That's interesting.
- What sort of research?
- Medical.
What, you looking at her head?
Take no notice.
There's nothing wrong with her head.
- Did you go to university?
- Yeah.
- Did you do a degree?
- Yes, I did.
She just looks at our eyes, don't you?
- Yes, I do.
- What for?
Well, you can tell a lot about people
from looking at their eyes.
- That's true.
- Can you?
Windows to your soul.
That's a nice way of putting it, Jane.
- It's true, though, ain't it?
- Right, who wants a top up?
- Hortense?
- No, thanks. I'm driving.
- Yes, please, sweetheart.
- Yeah, Maurice.
Oi, greedy guts.
You want to take
a leaf out of her book, Paul.
- Lost his license.
- All right, Mum.
Why? Did you have an accident, Paul?
- I just had one too many, that's all.
- There you go.
The demon drink, eh?
Is that who you've been
going out with, then?
Yes. She thought I'd been seeing a bloke.
Could have been, I suppose.
- I can still turn a few heads.
- Turn stomachs.
Gee!
Got my fingers cut off now.
I was just playing.
Do you want one, Hortense?
Oh, well,
we might as well pop the lot, then.
- No!
- It's like a bonfire.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, dear stinker ♪
Oh, yeah, Maurice, very funny.
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
- Nice one, champagne!
- Oh, I need my camera!
- Did anybody bring it in?
- I did. It's there, Monica.
- Do you have to, Monica?
- Of course I have to!
Watch where
you're pointing that, Maurice.
Right, all under cover? Okay. And...
Yeah!
Come on, blow your candles out, Roxanne.
Everybody else, gather around. Come on.
- Come on, darling.
- All right, Cynth, you tuck in there.
Okay, Hortense, in there.
- Right, come around here.
- Hurry up! It's burning me eyebrows off!
Right, make a wish. One big blow.
- And...
- Cheese!
Hey!
I hope your wish comes true, pet.
- Here, Roxy.
- Ta.
- Here you are, Cynth.
- Here you are, sweetheart.
- That's nice.
- And Paul.
All right. Cynth again.
Thank you, Maurice.
Oh, this is living, ain't it?
Yeah. Thank you.
One for me.
All right.
On you go, then.
Oh, yeah. Okay.
Uh...
I would like to propose a toast
to Roxanne on her 21st birthday.
Now it's all legal
and twice as boring for it.
Mind you, it's been legal
since you were 18 anyway.
- So I don't know what I'm talking about.
- Happy birthday, sweetheart.
- Ta.
- To Roxanne.
Happy birthday.
- There you go.
- What's that?
- Book token.
- Don't be stupid.
Fucking hell, Maurice.
Thanks!
Yeah, well,
it's your 21st, isn't it?
Thanks, Monica!
Happy birthday, pet.
Don't spend it all in the one shop.
Here, happy birthday.
Wish I'd brought my present with me now.
You can give it to her tomorrow,
can't you? That's her birthday.
Don't expect I shall see her tomorrow.
Are you gonna sit down, darling?
Yes, come and sit down.
Everybody have some cake. Hortense?
- Jane?
- Where am I going?
Anywhere you like.
Uh, here. Have a chair.
- Come on the end, Paul.
- Hortense.
Thank you.
Where's the bathroom?
It's just through this way, darling.
Yeah, it's the door straight
ahead, and the light's on the left.
She's a nice girl.
Yeah, she is, Maurice.
- Seems very pleasant.
- Yeah, she's all right.
- How are you doing, Paul?
- All right.
- Is your shirt dried off now?
- Yeah.
She takes after her mother.
Does she?
Do you know her as well?
Work at the factory, does she?
You're looking at her.
Eh?
She's my daughter.
What's the matter with ya?
Maurice...
it's me daughter.
Don't be stupid.
She's had too much to drink.
She can't be the one that...
What?
Hortense, sweetheart...
she's your sister.
What?
That's her half-sister, Paul.
- You eat the cake, sweetheart.
- Thanks.
- What's the matter?
- I'm all right, darling.
I told 'em.
Tell them who you are, sweetheart.
It wasn't supposed to happen like this.
Yeah, well, it has, ain't it?
So you tell 'em. Go on.
Is it true?
Yes, it is.
- You never told her, then.
- I'm sorry, darling.
Will someone tell me
what the fuck's going on?
She's your sister!
Maurice?
Monica?
I always said she had a right to know.
No, Roxanne, sweetheart, darling!
Darling, please.
Don't touch me or I will smack you,
you slag!
You fucking slag!
Ain't it enough you had one bastard!
You had to have two and all!
Stop it! Roxanne?
Roxanne?
Sit down, darling. Sit down, Paul.
- Cynthia, I think I should go.
- No, I don't want you to go, darling.
You sit down.
Eat your cake, Jane.
You don't half choose
your moments, Cynthia.
Well, when's the right moment, Maurice?
You tell me that.
- Paul, get my coat. We're going.
- Don't go, Roxy.
- Why didn't you tell me, Maurice?
- I thought you knew.
- You used to tell me everything!
- I'm sorry.
- Well, you fucking well let me down!
- Oh, don't say that.
As for you, well, thanks for the present.
You've ruined my party
and I hope you're happy!
Roxy. Roxanne!
She don't mean it, darling.
She's just a little bit upset.
- Where are you going?
- I don't know.
This has all been a bit of a shock,
innit? Hey?
Look, I don't get it.
Did you know about her?
I always thought she'd had a boy.
- She's a slag.
- No, she's not.
- Yes, she fucking is.
- She loves you. We all love you.
- Are you coming back?
- No.
- You've got to.
- Why should I?
- You've got to face up to it.
- Face up to what?
She's left her card.
Oh, well.
I'll post it on to her.
I'll take it.
The state she's in,
you'll be lucky if you ever see her again.
Oh, you'd like that,
wouldn't you, sweetheart?
- Would I?
- You've been working at it for 18 years.
Ain't ya, Monica?
You turned my father against me.
You turned my Maurice against me.
And you turned my daughter against me.
You'll be having a go
at her next, I expect.
Sorry about this, Hortense.
You finished there, Jane?
Why don't you sit down?
- You've got a short memory, ain't ya?
- What are you talking about now?
You wouldn't have none of this if I hadn't
given Maurice the money to start with.
That money wasn't yours to give.
That was your father's insurance money!
- That money was for me and Roxanne.
- And Maurice!
And he didn't want none of it
till he come over and talked to you!
He was entitled to it!
I was going out cleaning
at 5:00 in the morning,
coming home, taking her to school,
and then going out again
to do a full day's work!
And didn't we know it?
You've done nothing but spend his money
since the day you clapped eyes on him.
Well, what are you supposed
to do with money but spend it?
At least we've made
something of ourselves!
Oh, haven't you?
Just you ought to try
bringing up a kid on your own!
She can't help it.
She's never had enough love.
- And you've never got on.
- That ain't my fault.
I know, I know.
But she needs you.
- Come on.
- I don't want to.
What do you think, Paul?
I think he's right, darling.
- Do ya?
- Yeah.
- Well, I ain't saying nothing.
- You won't have to.
You just have to listen. Come on.
I'm sorry, Roxanne.
It just came out, darling.
I didn't mean to spoil your party.
- Tell her, Maurice!
- Now, leave her alone, Cynth.
Just tell her the truth.
Darling...
I got pregnant when I was 15.
And your grandad sent me away
to this place.
Didn't he, Maurice?
I didn't know she was
gonna come looking for me, did I?
But I gotta tell you the truth, darling.
I'm glad she did.
It ain't her fault, sweetheart.
She didn't even want to come!
She didn't want to hurt you
no more than I did.
Oh, you tell her, sweetheart.
It's true.
She didn't want to upset you.
I'm sorry.
All right?
She said you weren't
never gonna come back.
Who did?
I never said any such thing.
She's twisted everything as usual.
Yes, you did, Monica.
Well, you was wrong, weren't you?
'Cause she has come back.
- Ain't you, sweetheart?
- Mum.
I always thought
you should have known, Roxanne.
You should have told her, Cynthia.
Of course
I should have told her, Maurice.
But I didn't think there
was ever gonna be no need to.
You seem to have told all and sundry.
Meaning me, I suppose?
And why shouldn't he?
I am his wife, after all!
Then why don't you
behave like his wife?
What?
Why didn't you give him no kids?
- Be quiet, Cynthia.
- That's between Maurice and me.
You're so selfish, Monica.
You might not have wanted them,
but he did!
Shut up, Mum!
- You don't know what you're talking about.
- Don't I?
- There are things you know nothing about.
- Maurice.
Like what?
Tell her.
Tell me what?
Why can't you tell her?
She can't have kids.
Simple as that.
She's physically
incapable of having children.
We've had every test
known to medical science.
She's been pushed around, prodded,
poked, had operations.
We've had 15 years of it,
and she can't have a baby.
I love you to bits.
But it's almost
destroyed our relationship.
You know it has.
There.
I've said it.
So where's the bolt of lightning?
Secrets and lies.
We're all in pain.
Why can't we share our pain?
I've spent my entire life
trying to make people happy,
and the three people I love the most
in the world hate each other's guts!
I'm in the middle.
I can't take it anymore!
I'm sorry, Hortense.
But you are a very brave person.
- A very stupid person.
- No, you're not.
You wanted to find the truth and you were
prepared to suffer the consequences.
And I admire you for that.
I mean it.
You're so lucky, Cynthia.
Have you really been
working in the factory?
No.
What do you do, then?
I'm an optometrist.
Hmm.
Well, welcome to the family.
Maurice...
I wish I'd had a dad like you.
You're lovely.
His name's Bingham, your father.
He's from America.
And I met him on holiday. Benidorm.
He was a medical student.
And one morning, I come down
and he wasn't there no more.
But he was a nice man.
He was.
Was my father a nice man?
Oh, don't break my heart, darling.
I'm all right.
Oh, please, Roxanne, sweetheart!
Please!
Please.
I'm frightened.
Why?
You don't love me anymore.
Not like you used to.
Maurice...
you don't know how much I love you.
Do you?
We've got each other, haven't we?
Bet you never seen
so much shit, have you?
You ought to see my mum's house.
Do you miss her?
Yeah.
- Did you get on with her?
- She used to drive me mad.
That's what they're
there for, though, ain't it?
Yeah.
That's me old chair there.
Ah.
I always wanted a little sister.
No, it's just that my brothers
were much older than me,
so I ended up playing
on my own most of the time.
Oh, I know what you mean.
What you laughing at?
Do you feel like we're sisters?
I don't know.
Do you?
- It's a bit weird.
- Yeah.
- I don't mind it, though.
- No. Nor do I.
I don't even know you yet, do I?
- Do you want to go out one night?
- Yeah.
Yeah.
- You can take me to one of your pubs.
- Yeah, all right.
How would you introduce me?
As your half-sister?
Yeah.
- No, man. Too much explaining to do.
- It's what I'd say, though.
- Would you?
- Yeah.
- Yeah. Better to tell the truth, innit?
- Yeah, it is.
That way nobody gets hurt.
Here you are, sweetheart. Tea's up.
Go on, darling. Want a biscuit?
- No, I'm all right, thank you.
- Sit yourself down.
- Are you all right with that?
- Yeah.
That's it.
Who would have thought it, eh?
Look at you two, sitting there
like a couple of garden gnomes.
Oh, this is the life, ain't it?
Yeah.