BABETTE'S FEAST
Copyright A.S. Maniacs Film
International 1987. All rights reserved.
- In this remote spot
there once lived two sisters... -
- who were both past
the first flush of youth. -
- They had been christened
Martina and Philippa... -
- after Martin Luther
and his friend Philipp Melanchton. -
- They spent all their time... -
- and almost all their small income
on good works. -
Thank you.
- Their father had been
a priest and a prophet... -
- the founder of a religious sect... -
- who was well-respected,
and perhaps also a little feared. -
- The minister had married late
and by now had long been dead. -
- Every year his disciples
became fewer in number. -
- But they continued meeting
to read and interpret the Word... -
- and to honor
the spirit of their master... -
- whose presence they felt
was among them. -
Jerusalem
my heart's true home
Your name
is forever dear to me
Your kindness
is second to none
You keep us clothed and fed
Never would you give a stone
To the child
who begs for bread
- The two sisters
had a French servant. -
- Her name was Babette. -
- This may seem strange
for two puritan ladies... -
- living in such a remote,
desolate place... -
- and it deserves an explanation. -
- Babettes presence in the house
of the two sisters... -
- can only be explained through
the hidden regions of the heart. -
- As young girls, the beauty
of Martina and Philippa... -
- had been extraordinary,
akin to flowering fruit trees. -
- They were never to be seen
at balls or parties. -
- The young men went to church
in the hope of seeing them. -
Oh, Lord, allow thy kingdom
To descend upon us here
So that the spirit of mercy
May wipe out all trace of sin
Then we shall know
in our hearts
That God lives here with us
And that Thou art dwelling
With those that trust in Thee
- In the minister's flock,
earthly love and marriage... -
- were considered to be of scant worth
and merely empty illusion. -
In this calling of mine...
my two daughters
are my right hand and my left.
Would you rob me of them?
- Never the less,
these two beauties... -
- had upset the peace of heart
and the destinies... -
- of two young gentlemen
from the great world outside. -
- One was a young officer
by the name of Lorens Lowenhielm. -
- He had led a merry life
in his garrison town... -
- and had fallen into debt. -
Attention!
Captain, sir!
Twenty men accounted for!
Lorens!
Get a grip on yourself.
You will spend three months
at your aunt's house.
- The old lady?
- Yes.
At Norre Vossborg?
Injutland?
At Norre Vossborg Manor
you'll have time to think...
about your conduct...
and to set about
improving it.
Welcome to Norre Vossborg.
Come along.
I will show you your room.
- At this very moment
he had a mighty vision... -
- of a higher and purer life... -
- without creditor's letters
or parental lectures... -
- and with a gentle angel
at his side. -
- With the help of his pious aunt... -
- he gained admission
to the minister's house. -
Don't just stand there, Martha!
Fetch a cloth!
Mercy and truth are met together...
my dear brothers and sisters.
Righteousness and peace
shall kiss one another.
- He repeated his visits,
but it seemed to him... -
- that each time he grew
more insignificant. -
Excuse me.
God's paths
run beyond the seas...
and the snowy mountain peaks...
where the human eye
sees no tracks.
Amen.
I am going away forever...
and I shall never,
never see you again.
For I have learned here
that life is hard and cruel...
and that in this world
there are things that are...
impossible.
- Where the other young officers
spoke of their loves... -
- he was silent about his. -
- For, reliving it now,
in the officers' mess... -
- and seeing it
through others' eyes... -
- it appeared to him
a pitiful affair. -
Lorens.
How can a lieutenant
of the Hussars...
allow himself to be
defeated and frustrated--
By some pious "melancholics"...
who can't even afford
the salt for their soup?
I cannot forget the picture
of that lovely maiden.
You are a dreamer, Lorens.
I would prefer to be like you.
I will forget what happened
on the jutland coast.
From now I shall look forward,
not backward.
I will think of nothing
but my career, and some day...
I will cut a brilliant figure
in the world of prestige.
- He married a lady-in-waiting
to Queen Sophia. -
- At that time piety
was fashionable at the court. -
- He knew how to apply words
and phrases from the parsonage... -
- that were engraved in his memory. -
We implore God's mercy.
We must carry out
the Lord's tasks with love.
Do you remember
that silent young man...
who appeared so suddenly,
and vanished just as suddenly?
Yes.
- A year later, an even more
distinguished person arrived. -
- The famous singer from Paris,
Achille Papin... -
- who had been performing
at the Royal Opera in Stockholm. -
Thank you, dear lady.
You are so kind, dear lady.
Stockholm is
a very beautiful town.
Scandinavia has
a wealth of beautiful cities.
I travel much...
but what I yearn for most
is to be alone.
I love silence.
Silence,
and the sound of waves.
Then you should visit
the coast of jutland.
It is magnificent...
and totally unspoiled.
There you could get
your fill of fresh air...
and you could rest.
I know a place.
You could stay
with the grocer.
- But Achille Papin
fell into a kind of melancholy. -
- He suddenly saw himself
as an old man... -
- at the end of his career. -
Lord, our God
Thy name and glory
Should be sung
throughout the world
And every soul
Thy humble subjects
And every wayfarer
shall sing aloud
Thy praises
God is God
even if all lands be deserts
even if all life were ended
If the people should vanish
and you, divine heavens
Will reign over the countless
and play the harp so beautifully
Highest mountain
and deepest vale shall vanish
Heaven and earth as well
will perish
Each height and peak
shall be no longer
But the Lord's glory
shall rise again
In a thousand hearts
Almighty God...
Thy mercy
ascends to the heavens...
and Thy righteousness
reaches to the ocean's depths.
Here is a diva.
She will have Paris
at her feet.
Good day, sir.
Good day.
I've come to your country
for reasons of health.
I'm staying at the grocer's.
I'd be happy
to give singing lessons...
to the young lady who lives here.
She has a lovely voice,
and with some training...
she will sing like an angel.
That's important
when one sings God's praises.
Are you a Papist?
Yes, Roman Catholic.
Papist.
Come in, Monsieur...
Monsieur Achille Papin.
I spoke with my daughter,
and I give my consent.
I am delighted. Thank you.
Good-bye, sir.
Good-bye, Monsieur Papin.
Good-bye, ladies.
Good-bye, Monsieur.
- See you soon?
- Yes.
Ah, thank you.
Very good.
You will be like a star
in the heavens.
No one ever sang as well
as you will sing.
You will be the only star.
The others will fade out
by themselves.
The Emperor
will come to hear you...
and so will
the modest seamstress.
You have enough talent...
to distract the rich...
and to comfort the poor.
Well, Philippa, are you making
progress with Mr. Papin?
Yes, Father.
A voice with in me calls you
It calls you from my heart
Come now
don't fight against it
It is the voice of joy
I tremble, yet I listen
I'm fearful of my joy
Desire, love and doubting
Are battling in my heart
Come, then, with me
my beauty
Masetto still loves me
I'll make you a great lady
My soul weakens already
Come on, come on
Come with thy hand
in mine, dear
I would, and yet I would not
Don't fight
It will be fine, dear
I'm afraid of my own joy
Let us leave, my beauty
Come, then, with me
my beauty
Masetto still loves me
You will be a great lady
My soul weakens already
Oh, come
Let us go
Yes, hand and heart uniting
Each other's love requiting
Love will unite us
Love will unite us...
Love will unite us.
Good day, Madame!
Good day, Madame! La-la-la!
I do not wish to continue
my singing lessons.
Please, Father,
let Monsieur Papin know my decision.
The Lord's paths also run
across the rivers, my child.
Kindly give this to your guest.
Yes, sir.
Good-bye, my life
Good-bye, my heart
Good-bye, my hopes.
- Achille Papin took the first boat
from Frederikshavn... -
- back to Paris. -
That's the house over there.
- Many years later... -
- one September night in 1871. -
Come inside.
" Dear ladies...
- Do you remember me? -
- When I think of you... -
- I recall the perfume
of wild lilies of the valley. -
- Could the memory of a Frenchman
who is forever devoted to you... -
- move your hearts to save
the life of a French woman? -
- The unfortunate bearer of this letter,
Madame Babette Hersant -
- like my beautiful Empress herself -
- had to flee from Paris. -
- Civil war has been raging
in our streets. -
- Madame Hersant's husband and son
were killed like rats. -
- She, herself, narrowly escaped... -
- the blood-stained hands
of General Galliffet. -
- She has lost everything
and dares not to remain in France. -
- A nephew of hers works aboard
a ship bound for Frederikshavn. -
- He has arranged
a passage for her. -
- She asked whether I knew
any generous people in Denmark. -
- This evoked my memories of you
that I have cherished. -
- For 35 years, Miss Philippa... -
- I have deplored the fate
that kept your voice... -
- from filling
the Grand Opera House in Paris. -
- When I think of you honored,
respected and surrounded... -
- by a warm and happy swarm
of children... -
- and when I think of myself
a lonely, graying old man... -
- forgotten by those
who once applauded and adored me -
- I feel that it is you who
chose the better path in life. -
- What is fame?
The grave that awaits us all. -
- And yet, my beautiful soprano
of the snows... -
- as I write this
I feel the grave is not the end. -
- In Paradise I shall
hear your voice again. -
- There you will forever be
the great artist... -
- God intended you to be. -
- Oh, how you will enchant
the angels. -
- Babette knows how to cook. -
- Ladies, please accept
the humble homage of a friend... -
- who was once Achille Papin. -
Madame...
I am afraid
that we cannot employ you.
We do not have
sufficient income...
to allow us to engage...
such an experienced housekeeper.
But I only want to work
for Monsieur Papin's friends.
I will work without wages.
If you won't let me serve you...
I will simply die.
No. Stay with us.
Stay.
- Let it soak.
- Yes.
You must soak it.
Yes.
Let it soak.
Cut slices.
Bread.
Let it soak.
A little ale.
- A little ale.
- Ale.
Through a sieve...
like this.
- Ale-bread.
That's right.
Then it cooks for one hour.
- It must be cooked for one hour.
- Cooked.
- Good morning, Mr. Larsen.
- Good morning, Madame Babette.
- Onion.
- Two onions.
Two onions.
- Sugar.
- 20 skillings.
- 20 skillings?
Twenty.
20 skillings.
Thank you.
Good day, Mr. Larsen.
Good-bye, Madame Babette.
Good-bye.
Here you are.
Thank you, Babette.
Amazing. Since Babette came,
we have more money than before.
- Babette had now worked
for the minister's daughters... -
- for fourteen years. -
- Not fresh.
- Not fresh?
My fish are not fresh?
They were swimming
two minutes ago!
- How much?
- 30 skillings.
- Twenty.
- Thirty.
- Forty.
Thirty.
All right. Give us your basket
and take them away.
Many thanks!
Those two for 30?
No! That's enough!
These cost 50, and that's that.
- Good morning.
- Good morning, Madame Babette.
I'd like a small piece
of bacon.
The last one I had was rancid.
I can't understand that.
In the land where I was born
Don't you miss France?
My only link with France
is a lottery ticket...
that a faithful friend in Paris
renews for me every year.
Not much of a link.
Thank you very much.
Good-bye.
Good-bye, Madame Babette.
She's a clever one.
Yes.
These sins of your youth
will be forgiven, Christopher.
Christ loved us and cleansed us
of our sins with His blood.
Hallelujah.
You who seek Christ...
turn your eyes
on the vault of heaven.
There you will see the signs
of His infinite kingdom...
the eternal light.
" For Thine is the kingdom,
the power and the glory...
forever and ever. Amen."
And thank You, Lord,
for sending Babette to us.
She helps our little sisters
so they can devote themselves...
to those most wretched
in Thy little flock.
- As the years went by
the minister's disciples... -
- became somewhat testy
and querulous. -
- Sometimes small schisms
would erupt among the congregation. -
Even though it was
a long time ago, Solveig...
I remember very well
how badly you once treated me.
You remember that
I treated you badly.
Well, I remember
how jealous you were.
You were anything but nice
to my poor mother.
Now let us all sing
"Thy kingdom come, O Lord."
My good Paul, you cheated me that time;
I've always known it.
"Always known it." Ha!
You can't even remember
what you had for supper yesterday.
I remember perfectly well.
I always knew you robbed me.
Well, now! May we have
some peace and quiet?
Do you think my dear husband
will forgive me for deceiving him?
Yes.
We were so young.
That's no excuse.
I was married to him.
You made me do it.
Yes.
- But you wanted to yourself.
- You tempted me.
Will God forgive me?
Or will my soul be tormented
for what we did?
Of course not.
God forgives everything.
Doesn't He, Martina?
My dear brothers and sisters.
You know that December 15th
is the hundredth anniversary...
of the birth of our dear father.
Philippa and I have long
looked forward to this day.
We wish to celebrate it...
as if our father
we're still with us.
My sister and I
are much grieved...
over the intolerance
and disagreements among us.
Please remember...
that peace and brotherhood
should reign here.
I've seen through you, Christopher.
You are a sly one.
Hallelujah!
That is all for today.
It's from France.
Come in.
It's for Madame Babette Hersant.
- Thank you.
- It's from France.
Yes. Thank you.
It's for Babette.
There's a letter for you,
Babette.
Thank you.
Dear God!
I've won in the lottery!
10,000 francs!
Congratulations.
Congratulations, Babette.
Thank you.
Well, it had to happen.
The Lord gave and...
the Lord took away.
- Thank you for helping me.
- You're welcome.
May I ask a favor, ladies?
Of course, Babette.
Sit down, Babette.
I would like to prepare
the celebration dinner...
for the minister's birthday
by myself.
But dear Babette, we didn't
intend to give a dinner party.
My sister and I were thinking
of a modest supper...
followed by a cup of coffee.
You know we never offered our guests
anything more than that.
I'd like to prepare
a French dinner.
A French dinner?
Just this once, I beg you.
A real French dinner.
All right, Babette.
We agree, Babette.
I would like to pay for the dinner
with my own money.
No, Babette. No.
That's out of the question.
- We could not accept that.
- No, Babette. We couldn't allow that.
Ladies...
have I ever asked you
for anything?
Hear my prayer today.
It comes from my heart.
Babette is right.
It's the first time
she asks us for anything...
and it's probably the last.
So be it, Babette.
- We agree, Babette.
- Thank you.
I'll have to ask for
a few days off...
to give my nephew
some instructions...
concerning the dinner.
Ah, yes, your nephew.
It was his boat that brought you
from France to Frederikshavn.
- Take some time off.
- Of course, Babette.
I thank you, ladies.
She'll be leaving us soon.
Her heart is already in France.
We mustn't neglect
our old people...
when we'll have to manage
by ourselves.
- She'll be back in a week.
- Yes, but for how long?
Thank you, johannes.
Welcome back, Babette.
Did you have a good journey?
Very good, thank you.
Did you make your arrangements
and meet your nephew?
Yes. Everything went well.
I gave my nephew
a list of the goods...
he is to bring me from France.
Careful!
All right.
Martina, I am rather worried
about this.
I am not too happy about
this French dinner either.
My little quails!
There she is.
Praise the Lord!
All the goods arrived safely.
What goods, Babette?
The ingredients for the dinner.
For the French dinner.
Surely that's not wine?
It's Clos de Vougeot 1 845...
from Chez Philippe,
Rue Montorgeuil.
We had no bad intentions.
Philippa and I merely wanted
to grant Babette's wish.
We had no idea
where it might lead.
And now...
we have exposed ourselves...
to dangerous,
or maybe even evil, powers.
I cannot even tell you what you
may be served to eat and drink.
What will happen to us?
Lord, grant us Thy mercy.
Oh. Forgive me.
Don't cry, Martina.
If you only knew how often...
I think of my father now.
I feel he's looking down at me
and is seeing his daughters...
use his home
for a witches' sabbath!
We shall not say a word
about either food or drink.
Hallelujah.
For the love
of our little sisters...
we promise,
no matter what happens...
not to say a single word
about the food or the drinks.
Not one comment
will pass our lips.
The tongue.
The tongue,
this strange little muscle...
has accomplished great
and glorious deeds for man.
But it is also the source
of unleashed evil and deadly poison.
On the day when we solemnly
pay homage to our great master...
we shall use our tongues
for prayer...
in gratitude
for all he meant to us.
The Lord be praised.
Grant us Thy salvation.
It will be as if we never
had the sense of taste.
Jerusalem
my heart's true home
Your name
is forever dear to me
Your kindness
is second to none
You keep us clothed and fed
Never would you give a stone
To the child
who begs for bread
Here is a letter
from Mrs. Lowenhielm.
Thank you. Get yourself
some refreshments in the kitchen.
This is from Mrs. Lowenhielm.
She writes that she has
an unexpected visit...
from her nephew,
General Lorens Lowenhielm.
He has spoken of our father
with admiration.
She asks if she may bring him
with her this evening.
We have had a message
from Mrs. Lowenhielm.
Her nephew, General Lorens Lowenhielm,
will accompany her.
So we shall be twelve for dinner,
not eleven.
The general is with
the Royal Swedish Court.
During his youth
he lived in Paris.
A general.
Do not worry.
There will be plenty for everyone.
This is for the turtle soup.
It is?
Hold that end.
Is there anything you need,
Babette?
No. Everything is ready.
The candles.
Vanity.
All...
is vanity.
I have found everything
you dreamed of...
and satisfied your ambition.
But to what purpose?
Tonight we two
shall settle our score.
You must prove to me that
the choice I made was the right one.
God's will be done.
Good evening.
Thank you, Philippa.
Come inside where it's warm.
They're here.
Jerusalem
my heart's true home
Your name
is forever dear to me
Your kindness
is second to none
You keep us clothed and fed
Never would you give a stone
To the child
who begs for bread
Could many years of victories...
result in defeat?
Well!
Here comes the general.
And our dear old
Mrs. Lowenhielm.
She is one of the faithful.
Welcome to you all.
It was so good of you
to invite us.
Thank you for inviting me.
Thank you for coming
such a long way.
Good evening, Mrs. Lowenhielm.
Good evening, dear sisters.
Good evening, dear brothers.
Please sit down.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
Come inside where it's warm.
Thanks.
Now we're ready to serve.
Babette says dinner is served.
Let us take our places
at the table.
Remember, we have lost
our sense of taste.
Let us pray,
using the minister's own words.
May the bread
nourish my body.
May my body
do my soul's bidding.
May my soul rise up
to serve God eternally.
Amen.
- Not a word about the food.
- Not a word.
Like the wedding at Cana...
the food is of no importance.
We won't even think about it.
Amazing!
An amontillado!
And the finest amontillado
I have ever tasted!
This is quite definitely
real turtle soup.
And what a turtle soup!
Now, Erik, the champagne.
One glass per person.
And fill the general's glass
whenever it is empty.
It must be some kind
of lemonade.
This is good.
- Here you are, sir.
- Thank you.
But that's Blinis Demidoff!.
And this most certainly is
Veuve Clicquot 1 860!
Uh, yes, uh-- I am quite sure
it will snow all day tomorrow.
I shall never forget
my first meeting with the minister...
and the sermon he preached.
I was a depraved
and quarrelsome person.
I have tried to become
a good Christian.
Do you remember
what he taught us?
" Little children,
love one another."
Little children,
love one another.
Friends, I can assure you
the minister's collected sermons...
are among the favorite reading
of Her Majesty, the Queen.
In the large glasses.
Carefully!
This is good.
Remember the time--
indeed, it was almost
a miracle--
when our minister had promised
to conduct a Christmas sermon...
at the church across the fjord?
For two weeks the weather
had been so bad...
that no captain or fisherman
would risk the crossing.
The villagers
had given up all hope.
The minister told them
if no boat would take him...
he would walk across to them
on the waves.
And behold, three days before Christmas
the storm abated.
A cold spell set in and the fjord
froze from shore to shore.
And this had never happened before
in any man's memory.
One day in Paris, after I had
won a riding competition...
my French fellow officers
invited me out to dine...
at one of the finest restaurants,
the Cafe Anglais.
The chef, surprisingly enough,
was a woman.
We were served
Cailles en Sarcophage...
a dish of her own creation.
General Galliffet,
who was our host for the evening...
explained that this woman,
this head chef...
had the ability...
to transform a dinner
into a kind of love affair.
A love affair
that made no distinction...
between bodily appetite
and spiritual appetite.
General Galliffet said
that in the past...
he had fought a duel
for the love of a beautiful woman.
But now there was
no woman in Paris...
for whom he would shed his blood--
except for this chef.
She was considered
the greatest culinary genius.
What we are now eating...
is nothing less than
Cailles en Sarcophage.
Hallelujah.
But this really is
a Caille en Sarcophage!
Yes. That it is.
Man shall not merely
refrain from...
but also reject any thought
of food and drink.
Only then can he eat and drink
in the proper spirit.
As our minister always said:
" Dear brothers and sisters...
the only things we can take away
from this Earthly life...
are those we have given away."
Our dear sisters
will be rich in the next life.
Erik!
No, no, no.
A good meal, eh, Aunt?
Yes.
The gale has died down.
Water in the small glasses.
Here you are, sir.
Did you see
these beautiful grapes?
"And they came unto
the valley of Eshcol...
and cut down a branch
with a cluster of raisins.
And two of them
bore it upon a staff."
Mercy and truth
have met together.
Righteousness and bliss
shall kiss one another.
Man, in his weakness
and shortsightedness...
believes he must make
choices in this life.
He trembles
at the risks he takes.
We do know fear.
But no.
Our choice
is of no importance.
There comes a time
when your eyes are opened.
And we come to realize...
that mercy is infinite.
We need only await it
with confidence...
and receive it with gratitude.
Mercy imposes no conditions.
And, lo!
Everything we have chosen...
has been granted to us.
And everything...
we rejected...
has also been granted.
Yes, we even get back
what we rejected.
For mercy and truth
are met together.
And righteousness and bliss...
shall kiss one another.
Here you are, sir.
You rascal! You did cheat me
with that timber you sold me!
Yes, dear brother. I cheated you
more than you realized.
I knew.
But I played a trick on you,
and you never knew.
Then I deserved it.
Is there more of the
Clos de Vougeot, my lad?
Can the general have
more Clojouvo?
Erik, leave the bottle in there.
After the coffee,
in the small glasses.
And light the candles
in the sitting room.
"Vie... ux... marc...
fine... champagne."
May this meal have pleased you.
Thank you. Thank you.
God bless you, dear Solveig.
God bless you too, dear Anna.
God bless you, Christopher.
My brother!
Oh, watch the day
once again hurry off
And the sunbathe itself
in water
The time for us to rest
approaches
O God, Who dwelleth
in heavenly light
Who reigns above
in heaven' shall
Be for us our infinite Light
in the valley of night
The sand in our hour glass
will soon run out
The day is conquered
by the night
The glories of the world
are ending
So brief their day
So swift their flight
God, let Thy brightness
ever shine
Admit us Thy mercy divine
Lorens.
It is time for us to go home.
The general and his aunt
are about to leave.
- Thank you for the nice evening.
- Thanks for your help.
I thank you.
I have been with you...
every day of my life.
Tell me you know that.
Yes, I know it.
You must also know
that I shall be with you...
every day that is granted to me
from now on.
Every evening I shall sit down
to dine with you.
Not with my body,
which is of no importance...
but with my soul.
Because this evening
I have learned, my dear...
that in this beautiful
world of ours...
all things are possible.
The clock strikes
and time goes by
Eternity is nigh
Let us use this time to try
To serve the Lord
with heart and mind
So that our true home
we shall find
The stars have moved closer.
Perhaps they move closer
every night.
Perhaps there will be
no snow this year.
Hallelujah.
Oh, that was indeed
a very good dinner.
They all thought
it was a very good dinner.
At one time I was the head chef
at the Cafe Anglais.
We shall all remember
this evening...
when you are back in Paris.
I'm not going back to Paris.
You're not going back to Paris?
There's no one
waiting for me there.
They're all dead.
And I have no money.
No money?
But the 10,000 francs?
All spent.
10,000 francs?
Dinner for twelve at the Cafe Anglais
costs 10,000 francs.
But dear Babette...
you should not have given
all you owned for us.
It was not just for you.
Now you'll be poor
the rest of your life.
An artist is never poor.
Did you prepare that sort of dinner
at the Cafe Anglais?
I was able to make them happy.
When I gave of my very best.
Papin knew that.
Achille Papin?
Yes.
He said:
"Throughout the world sounds one
long cry from the heart of the artist:
Give me the chance
to do my very best."
But this is not the end,
Babette.
I'm certain it is not.
In Paradise...
you will be the great artist...
that God meant you to be.
Ah, how you will delight
the angels!
Video Subtitles By
Captions, Inc. Los Angeles