Rock-paper-scissors.
Got you, fucking queer!
Nico.
Luis.
Cristian.
Diego, over here.
Nahu.
Mati, with us.
I don't know... Joaquin.
Manu, come on. Let's go.
Let's go! I want you in there, man.
Come on, come on!
The ball is ours!
Look who's on our team.
Kick-off's on us.
What about this red one?
- I like it.
- Here.
- Girls!
- What?
I wanted to die when Gutiérrez
caught Rocío with the letter!
Oh my God! He's the worst!
- It sucked!
- Terrible!
I could never go back
to school after that.
I forgot to tell you!
I'm going to go to law school
in Buenos Aires after graduation.
Weren't you going to study to be a teacher
at the Manuel Belgrano?
Yeah, but I thought about it,
and I like law better.
- No, girls. Please, no.
- Yeah, come on!
- Please, stay here.
- No.
Please, don't leave me alone.
- We're going to the the bakery.
- We'll be right back.
- We've got cookies.
- I know, but Mora wants a pastry.
You guys keep doing.
They're morons.
They're really stupid.
Gra...
you have a boyfriend.
Yeah, I know.
And we're friends.
I don't understand what you mean.
Nothing.
Forget it.
Yes.
Alright, let's talk soon.
How's that sound?
Don't worry about it.
Yeah, let's talk. Bye.
- Was that Carlos?
- Yes.
Carlos who?
Carlos,
my friend from Buenos Aires.
The fat guy! He used to do magic tricks
with coins for you.
- Do you remember that?
- No.
- He was really little.
- Yeah, he was.
The one that did some time in jail?
- Luky...
- What?
Don't say that. And?
How is it my fault
that he's been in prison?
Loren, do you remember
that he had a son about your age?
Remember?
There's a chance...
that his son
come here to stay with us for a while.
- For a visit?
- Yes...
For a visit...
No. Not a visit...
Until things settle down a bit.
Do you have any idea
how long that could take?
- What happened?
- I'm not so sure.
He called a couple of times today.
They had a problem.
Did he mention anything about
when the accident took place?
Yesterday or this morning.
Accident?
Can you tell us something please?
We don't know much.
Just that a friend asked for a favor,
and we're trying to help out.
I'd love to help him, really.
But this doesn't feel right.
I already told you what I think.
I'll call him and tell him no then.
Hey...
Hi.
Excuse me. I'm Caíto.
Caíto?
Carlos's son, your dad's friend.
- What's up? How are you?
- What's up?
Do you want to come in?
Sure. Why not?
Thanks.
- How's your dad doing?
- Not so good.
His wife's son had a...
an accident and he's in the hospital.
What happened to him? Is it bad?
I think he's going to die.
I'm sorry.
What happened?
We crashed the motorcycle.
Hello! Caíto, look how big you are!
How are you? So cute!
You're huge. Welcome.
- He looks just like his dad, right?
- Just like him.
- Identical.
- Amazing. When did you get here?
A couple hours ago.
- Good.
- We didn't think you'd...
We weren't expecting you.
It's a real surprise.
This is Lucas's room.
You'll be just fine here.
I guess you'll want
to put your things away.
Maybe in here...
No, this is all full.
Luky, would you empty out a drawer for him?
It'd be best if he weren't left alone.
And...
that the's not alone in the house.
That you...
That you stay alert.
But be subtle, you know?
We don't want him to feel watched, but...
He shouldn't feel watched...
but I should watch him. Is that it?
No. I didn't say you should watch him.
Well, yeah. A little.
The usual.
How do you see yourself working here?
Fine.
Hang on a second.
- How are you doing?
- Good, you?
Good, you know.
Caíto is in the car.
The boy I talked to you about.
Foul, ref!
Come on, kick it.
Come on, you play like a little girl.
Pinching is off-limits.
Loren, is that your new cell phone?
- Take it.
- Let me see.
What did we say about phones at the table?
I was checking out
Loren's new phone.
Did you finally buy it?
- Yeah.
- How nice.
It has to be great,
being that expensive.
He used his savings to pay for it.
Give me that.
How did it go today?
Very good.
We had a meeting with the principal.
We left a note for her.
- Use a napkin, honey.
- No. I'm embarrassed, we have guests.
So what? Use a napkin,
or take your shirt off.
What did the note say?
You can't begin to imagine how hard
it was for all of us moms to agree.
Some said we should call the mother
and make her take responsibility and pay.
Another mom said that we should request
a thorough report
by the school psychologists.
Some others wanted
the Department of Education to intercede.
Just imagine the madness...
- "The mommies."
- Exactly.
I'm on the PTA at Loren's school.
And we're dealing with a serious issue.
One of the kids...
One of the kids messed up really bad.
So? What's the final decision?
We all voted in favor
of expelling him.
- That bad?
- It's terrible, poor thing.
He's in your class, isn't he?
What's his name?
- Ramiro.
- What's he like?
He gets in trouble a lot,
but he's a nice kid.
He's a nice kid. That's true.
If you ask me, there are less drastic ways
to make him understand.
He needs to be punished in some way.
He messed up really bad,
he damaged school property.
"The school property"...
He just broke a window.
That's school property.
Not only that,
he broke into the school at night.
Did you know he was carrying
a bottle of alcohol and a box of matches?
Did you know that?
The curse of the tomato sauce.
- Told you!
- A ravioli landed on my pants.
You're such a snitch!
The curse of the tomato sauce...
Are you going out?
I'm going to take a walk.
Do you want to come?
It's a bit late to go out.
It's just a little walk.
I'll be right back.
Hang on.
I'll change and go with you, okay?
Sure.
We should leave soon, okay?
You can go ahead.
I'll wait for you.
Do it behind your back.
Like this.
- I'll help you.
- Let's see...
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Let it go, come on.
What's up?
Caíto.
We should go.
We're leaving.
- What are you doing?
- Drop the stick, we have to go.
What are you doing?
- We have to go, Caíto.
- What are you doing?
We're leaving.
Get up.
It's alright.
BAD: 1/2 PILL
VERY BAD: 1 PILL
DO NOT TAKE
MORE THAN 2 PILLS A DAY!
What we're being told is:
"This is how you have to behave.
This is how...
life should be." Alright?
The classic viewpoint states
that truth is exterior to art,
but that this truth is also innocent.
Lorenzo!
Would you like a bed?
- No, sorry.
- Okay.
Then a subject is created...
Lu, go get Caíto.
Lunch is ready.
- I already did.
- Well, go again. Come on.
Go.
You two got into
some trouble last night.
What were you up to?
We went for a walk.
Right...
- What time did you come back?
- Really late.
- Good morning.
Where did you go?
We just went to a place nearby.
Who gave you permission?
We'll talk about it later, Lolo.
Caíto, let me tell you something:
you're new here,
maybe you don't know the house rules.
Maybe it's different in your house,
but I'd like you to know that
you have to ask for permission
to go out at night here.
Right, mom. It was my bad, sorry.
And it's not really allowed
to go out on a school night
because we have to study
or work the next day. And alcohol, never.
Am I clear?
- Yeah, mom. He got it.
- I'm talking to Caíto.
Is that clear, Caíto?
Yes.
Good.
- What's up?
- Hey... Come in.
Thanks.
What´s with all these books?
What about them?
- Are they yours?
- Yeah. You want one?
Look what my mom found.
- Look.
- No way!
Check out those curls.
And your bangs.
We looked terrible.
You went all crazy last night.
I'm not telling you off.
It's done, it's over.
I have to admit
you scared the shit out of me.
Since we'll be living together
for a couple of months, I thought...
If you ever feel like talking
about your problems...
- About your brother.
- He's not my brother.
Okay, the son of...
Or maybe about other stuff...
You can also talk to my parents.
You may think
they're a bit uptight,
but they're actually pretty cool.
Or we could find a therapist.
I'm not crazy.
You don't need to be crazy
to go to therapy.
I think some day I'll go too.
What I'm trying to say is that...
it´s not good
to keep things inside,
it's better to talk about them.
- Alright.
- Okay.
Cool.
Need some help?
No, it's fine. I've got it.
Watching your dad play
was quite something.
You know, we were pretty...
close.
Buddies, pals.
Our life stories...
were pretty similar.
He was amazing, Carlitos!
He made it to Division One.
We had kids at the same time, you know?
You were born...
You're one year older than Lorenzo.
We were so young.
We had no idea
what we were doing.
We went from
thinking about girls, partying...
to changing diapers.
To earning a buck to buy milk.
And then... you know what happened.
Come with me.
You want one?
Thanks.
Something to drink?
No, thanks.
Are you sure?
I'm fine.
So...
Were you busy or anything?
No, I was going to call the girls,
see what they were up to.
Should I call them?
Sure, no problem.
What time will your parents be back?
They won't be back till tonight.
You want to sit here?
Let's talk later.
Sounds good.
- Well, bye.
- Bye.
What's up?
Hey, just wanted to see how you were.
We just saw each other.
Yeah, I know.
I kind of miss you.
You're nuts.
Also, I have something to tell you.
I think I'm going to dump Matías.
Did you text him again?
Did you call?
Yeah, I called him a bunch of times.
He's out of range.
Maybe his bike broke down.
Or he had an accident.
I don't know.
- With a truck.
- Lucas!
That crashed right into him.
Ran its four wheels over his head.
- Stop!
- The ground is all flooded with blood.
- Red.
- Lucas!
- What?
- Stop it!
Did you guys give him any money?
No.
Not even to buy a soda
if he's thirsty?
If he wants something,
he asks for it and we buy it.
I don't get it.
I thought that was better.
He got really wasted the first night.
- You never got drunk?
- What? I'm not Caíto!
I don't know him that well.
Was it a one-time thing?
Maybe it was, maybe it wasn't.
Trust us.
Nothing.
I called the cops. They say
we have to wait 24 hours to file a report.
What about the hospital?
I called. Nothing.
Does he have cell phone credit?
I don't know.
Let's go to the road post.
Maybe the cops saw him pass by.
- Let's go.
- Okay, I'll come with.
No. It's super late, honey.
Go to bed.
You have school tomorrow, alright?
Lolo, would you stay?
Let me know if he turns up.
Call us.
Yes.
Hey.
- What's up?
- Where were you?
Around, biking.
It's two in the morning.
I went along the road,
all the way up...
Down, up, I don't know...
The area is nice
but I have no idea where I ended up.
They're looking for you.
Did they go to the cops?
The cops, the hospital...
They worry too much.
I mean, they spend the whole day
worrying about what I do or don't do.
I'm not used to that.
I bet your dad would worry too.
Wouldn't he?
Caíto!
Caíto, you're okay.
Oh my God, we were so worried!
What happened to you?
Where were you?
Biking around.
Biking around?
- At this time of the night?
- I didn't realize.
You didn't realize?
It was dark and you didn't realize?
He made it to the fire hydrant.
He must have taken a wrong turn.
He ended up in Perales.
He got lost.
Is that true?
Yes.
I'm glad you found the way
back home then.
Are you asleep?
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I couldn't sleep.
Do you believe in God?
Yes.
I do,
but I'm not sure
in same way that other people do.
Well,
Me neither.
Why?
I feel there is a god,
but I don't trust religion.
Right.
Do you know anything about
the son of my dad's wife?
Just what you told me.
He had an accident.
Right...
Well, it was actually a fight.
With who?
Me.
Why?
He wanted me out of the house.
Why would they want that?
Because I skipped rent.
Did you steal the rent money?
No.
You know Graciela?
My dad's wife.
She hates my guts.
She always has.
She kept complaining
that I didn't study or work.
One day, she said
that if I wanted to live in the house,
I had to start bringing money in.
That I had to start paying rent
for the room I shared
with her son.
He's a year younger than me,
but he's 6.2 feet tall
and does kickboxing.
He beat the shit out of me.
So I grabbed an iron rod
from the backyard...
and smashed his head with it.
Are you kidding me?
He should be happy
I didn't shoot his brains out with my gun.
I controlled myself.
You told me it's not good
to keep things inside.
I'm telling this for the first time.
It's okay,
you just caught me off guard.
My dad's wife reported me.
That's one of the reasons I'm here.
Don't worry,
I won't tell a soul.
I know.
Thanks.
Is everything alright?
No. Not really.
Last night was a big deal.
A really big deal.
He got lost.
Okay, let's say he got lost.
Let's say he got lost,
- but we had a terrible time.
- Yes.
It's terrible. He's out on his bike now
and I'm so worried.
What Mom is trying to say...
is that Caíto is not a bad kid
or a bad person.
- Right?
- Right.
But we can't take responsibility for him,
we can't be responsible.
I...
I'm having a hard time
sleeping with Caíto.
He's awake all the time.
Well, but...
We can't send him back home.
Lolo...
Really? What are we going to do?
Tell me.
Are you going to take care of him?
Can you be responsible?
You can sleep here, and...
I'll make it fit.
During the day, we can put it in here,
so it doesn't block the way, okay?
Alright.
Do you want to
leave your bag in the closet?
Wake up, asshole.
You have to wake up.
- Come on, man! Take it!
- I don't know, man!
Come on, get up!
You have to go to work, come on.
Come on, get up.
I'm going to beat the shit out of you, man.
Cut it out, come on.
No, it's late. We have to go.
Here, open your mouth.
Come on.
It's freezing.
Is that your mom?
Yeah.
You never mentioned her.
Is she alive?
Sort of.
What do you mean?
She sleeps all the time.
She's on pills for depression.
She lives with my grandparents.
She can't live alone.
Come on, let's get in.
It's dangerous.
What could happen?
It gets very deep,
and there are strong currents down there.
Three tourists have died
from hypothermia right here.
What is hypothermia?
When your body temperature
suddenly drops.
You pass out and drown
in less than a minute.
I'm still going in.
You can stay here if you want.
Caíto, can I ask you a favor?
No!
Caíto!
Can I ask you for one little favor?
No, that's not a favor.
You're right.
It's none of my business.
Bye.
Wait up!
- What's up?
- Hey, Andrés. What's up?
Mario, how's it going?
- Come on in, let's talk.
- Sure.
- How is everything going?
- Good.
Perfect.
Do you want to count it?
No, it's fine.
Here's a whole month.
And here's the fee.
This is for you, to keep track
of what you spend.
So, this is October...
Here...
Are you happy?
Caíto, that money is yours.
It's for you.
You earn it with work.
You should be proud of yourself.
When your dad finds out about
how much you've saved,
he'll be proud too.
He's going to want to borrow some...
- to buy dope.
- What are you saying?
That was before. It's different now.
No.
Don't buy that whole rehab image
he keeps trying to sell people.
He's no saint.
What songs do you know?
None. But I can try and play one.
What do you mean, none?
I play classical guitar,
I only read sheet music.
You're such a character.
What's the point of learning to play guitar
if you don't know any songs?
Classic guitar is the best way
to study music,
and after that you can play
any song you want.
But you don't know any.
Have you read all of these?
You're obsessed with them.
You're such a nerd.
Can I tell you a secret?
Sure.
Promise you'll keep it between us.
What happened?
It's my birthday today.
You scared me! Happy birthday!
Keep it down.
Why didn't you tell me?
Let's celebrate!
- No, wait.
- Yeah, let's celebrate.
Don't tell anybody.
Why not?
Because it will make me feel...
uncomfortable.
Besides, it's not that big a deal.
Just know it's party time.
I don't have any nice clothes...
Don't worry about it.
Pick out a shirt.
Come on, pick one!
Happy birthday, dude.
Hey...
Thanks.
You're welcome.
I mean it.
Wait.
Let's make a deal.
A deal? You already said yes.
I know, but listen...
If you guys come back tonight,
I'll let you go
to grandma and grandpa's this summer
for a whole month.
No. Let it go, mom.
Let it go.
Don't worry, it'll be fine.
It's just one night.
It'll be fine. And if it's not,
they'll call us and we'll go get them.
- Don't worry.
- No. I do worry.
That's the point, I worry.
Hey...
Let's stay one more day?
I have to go to school
and you have to work.
Besides, we don't have that much food.
Who cares about food?
Besides, look...
Look what I've got.
You know what it is, right?
Of course I do. I'm not an idiot.
But...
Have you ever smoked?
No.
But I'm not into it.
Cool. More for me then.
Remember what you told me,
about going to therapy some day?
Yeah.
What about it?
What for? I mean...
What's your problem?
I don't think
I have one particular problem.
But I guess there are some things
that could improve.
Like what?
I'm not sure...
if it's something that specific.
But...
Some things are just not that clear to me.
Name one.
Let's see...
Sometimes...
even though I have people around me...
I feel kind of lonely.
Pussy.
You're such an asshole.
I'm sorry.
I thought you were going to say
something more serious.
You're unbelievable!
What?
It's alright.
I'm just freezing my balls off,
that's all.
Do you know how to swim?
- What?
- Do you know how to swim?
No.
Come on, get out.
What's wrong?
I got a cramp, it's gone now.
Get out!
What's wrong?
Motherfucking asshole!
Caíto!
Caíto.
You scared me, asshole!
Stop! What the hell?
- What's wrong with you, moron?
- It was a prank.
It was a prank!
You're an asshole!
Are you mad?
Come on, it was a prank.
Who gets into the water
with all their clothes on?
I was holding my breath.
Let's start a fire...
to warm ourselves.
It's not allowed to start a fire here.
It's good
to break the rules once in a while.
We're going home.
Calm down.
Get your things. We're leaving.
Why?
Can't you see I'm freezing?
I want to take a shower.
Fine.
You can go ahead. I'm staying.
The tent is mine and I'm taking it.
"The tent is mine." You pussy!
What are you doing?
Give it back!
Come on, give it back!
If we stay, I'll give it back.
Let's stay.
No!
What the hell
is wrong with you, asshole?
It's not mine, it's from the library!
You're an asshole!
How much did your cell phone cost?
I'll buy you a new one.
You don't have to.
I have a lot of money saved.
You're strong, motherfucker.
I'm sorry.
It's alright.
You had a fit.
It happens.
But acting on impulses is wrong.
Smashing someone's head
with an iron rod is wrong.
I'm sorry.
It's fine.
I wasn't trying to make excuses.
I wasn't accusing you either.
Not yet...
Let me see. Give it to me.
Hi, dad.
Yeah, we're having a great time.
Actually, we were thinking...
about staying here one more night.
Come on, man!
One more time.
You could remove the tip.
It's all wet with drool.
- Wait.
- It will drag better now.
Hey...
It hasn't kicked in.
Listen to this!
What's wrong with you, pothead?
Come here.
It's chilly.
Hey...
Close your eyes.
Come on, close them.
I love you, man.
Me too.
Where'd you get that t-shirt?
It's Caíto's.
He has only three, poor Caíto,
and you use them.
What's the problem? He uses mine too.
- Who's he talking to?
- His dad.
Bye.
- Is everything okay, Caíto?
- Yes.
Good.
It's stuffed squash.
Home made, I made them.
I remember how hard it was
to make Lucas eat veggies.
Remember, Luky?
It was huge battle, poor thing.
That reminds me
of this one time when I was six,
and you left me all alone until midnight,
sitting and eating a slice of chard pie.
And it was cold too.
So?
So, I ate a few bites
and we negociated.
But you like vegetables now.
Are you okay?
Yes.
I'm okay.
Wait, let me help you.
Do you want us to call a doctor?
No!
I'll be fine.
Those pills...
you have in your bag.
Do you want to take one?
- I'll go get water.
- No, no.
No water.
It's fine.
From putting it under the sun. It's not...
- If it's not breathing, I'm dead.
- Yeah.
- That's it.
- Good morning.
- How are you doing, sweetie?
What a face... Where's Caíto?
He's not feeling very well.
I think he should skip work today.
We should let him rest a bit, I guess.
Because he's...
What do you mean skip work?
He's not feeling good.
I'll go see.
- No, but he's really not feeling good.
- Don't worry, I'll go check on him.
Caíto.
Caíto, wake up.
You have to go to work, come on.
Let's go.
Caíto!
Is he drunk?
He took some kind of pill.
Some kind of pill? What kind of pill?
What is this?
Lorenzo, why didn't you say anything?
He was going really crazy.
Why didn't you wake me, us?
What's wrong with you, son?
Should we go to the hospital?
No. He's going to be fine.
He's fine.
How would you know he's going to be fine?
Do you know what this is?
Did you know that if you take two of these
you can die?
He only took one.
- I swear.
- What's going on?
- It's nothing, honey.
- Nothing.
It's time to go to school.
Are you all set?
Let's go.
- Is your bag all set?
- Yeah.
Jacket?
Scarf? It's chilly out.
I think I'm going to stay home.
What?
I'd rather skip school today.
You'd rather skip school?
Honey, let's go, please.
I'm having a bad day already.
Yeah, come on. Let's go.
- Lorenzo, get in the car, please! Now!
- I'm getting my bag!
One minute.
- Ready?
- Ready.
Here.
It's cold out. Put it on.
No, I'd better stay.
Alright, I really have to go.
Hello.
This is Lorenzo,
Andrés's son.
I was calling to let you know that...
Caíto is not feeling very well.
He won't be coming in today.
Yes, I'm sorry. Bye.
Where did these come from?
He's had them in his bag
since he got here.
But I'd never seen him take one
until last night.
What's this?
- This was not prescribed by a doctor.
- No.
I bet his dad gave it to him.
How could you hide this from me?
I didn't want you
to get mad at him.
Am I a witch? Is that how you see me?
No, mom.
I didn't say you were a witch.
You just assume.
I know he means well.
I really care about him, Lolo.
You don't care about him.
I do care about him.
Why would you talk to me like that?
You try really hard to like him.
You're nice to him.
But he's Carlos's son.
So?
And you'll never accept that.
Lolo...
Do you know why
we came here in the first place?
Yes.
To get dad away from his friends,
and drugs.
I'm glad that you know.
You know it perfectly well.
Did you also know
that I left my life there?
I left my parents, my friends...
I left everything
to came here and start from scratch.
To this fucking cold, this wind...
that won't stop blowing,
with two kids, a husband...
I'm asking you one thing:
next time you feel like judging me,
please try and be understanding.
At least try with love, please.
- I'm not judging you.
- Yes, you are.
No.
I'm just trying to make you understand...
that Caíto is not Carlos.
Are you...
Are you feeling...
something special for him?
Something special?
- It's okay, Lolo.
- Mom...
Please,
I don't want to talk about this now.
You can tell me.
Dad and I talked about it.
It's fine. It's...
It's okay.
- Mom...
- There's nothing wrong.
Can I please ask you not to?
You've never had a girlfriend, Lolo.
- I don't want to talk about this.
- Trust me.
- You don't trust me anymore?
- Listen to me when I talk.
I'm listening.
I don't want to talk about his now.
Are you in love with Caíto?
Mom!
Can I please ask you?
I don't want to talk about this!
There's nothing wrong with it.
What are we talking about?
You can trust me.
I'm not in love.
I just feel bad for him.
That's it.
Alright.
If you're not going to school,
at least make lunch.
If he wakes up, let me know.
Wait.
What?
I love you.
Me too.
I'm sorry.
You scared me.
What are you looking for?
I was just looking for some aspirin.
There's no aspirin in there.
But once I saw your mom...
No.
That's not the medicine cabinet.
Maybe it was just that one time.
No, Caíto.
I saw her, dude.
I'm not lying.
What are you doing?
Wait.
Can we talk?
What do you want to talk about?
We can settle this ourselves.
No.
Give it to me!
I will. Just wait.
It's my phone!
You want to take it too?
Who the fuck do you think you are?
Stop!
- I'll give it back.
- Give me my phone!
Give me my phone!
Wait, dude! I'll give it back.
You're making a big deal
out of nothing.
You want money?
Here.
Look.
This is your dad's handwriting.
It's all written down here.
The month,
and the amount...
that goes to me.
All here.
Do the math.
I wasn't trying to take
what's not mine!
Couldn't you ask for it?
They were going to ask me what is was for.
So?
They wouldn't haven given it to me.
It's done now.
You have money now.
You don't need to explain yourself.
It's not that simple.
Some things have happened.
I have to go.
I can't stay.
What happened?
He died, right?
He died.
You're not making things right by leaving.
My dad knows lawyers.
They could help you.
You were both in the fight, right?
He kicked your ass too.
You could explain yourself.
Hang on a sec.
Hi, mom.
Yes.
I was looking for something,
but I found it.
See you.
My mom is on her way.
What do you want to do?
I don't want to be an asshole to you guys.
You've all been so nice to me.
My parents will understand.
I already have.
What do you want to do?
Come on, dude.
Stay.
Please.
We'll figure it out.
We could clean the place up fast
before my mom gets home.