RIFIFI
Full house.
Paulo...
Stake me.
Impossible, Tony.
Not during a game.
OK, I'll call for cash.
Who's trying to hang
me in the closet?
Hey, mister, watch the cuff!
Tonio, will you leave
your father in peace!
You're spoiling him rotten, Jo.
Yes, he's here.
It's Tony.
Cut it out, Tonio!
No, not you. It's your
godson crushing my toes.
Sure thing.
Be right over.
- How about me?
- We don't bet promises here.
No cash, no cards.
Hi, Jo.
So you're the back-up.
Someone's gotta be.
You waiting for me?
Yeah. Their faith is touching.
But you all know him,
he's Tony the Stephanois!
Tony or no Tony,
only one thing counts...
Hard cash.
Forget these lugs.
Hey, you!
- You're not polite.
- That bug you?
Relax. He's still green.
Let's go.
Hello, Suzanne.
Poor Tony's not a pretty sight.
Five years in the pen
marks a man.
Poker all night in a smoke-filled
room! Just what you need!
Get out to the country.
Get some air in your lungs.
You see me milking cows?
It's a bit late for that now.
We'll talk about it tonight
at the house over some grub.
Louise keeps busting my chops
about your damned health.
OK, doc. Drop me off
at my place. I'm beat.
I wanna show you something first.
- What'll you have?
- Coffee.
- Three coffees.
- Three?
Mario's coming.
- Thanks.
- Shut up! Thanks for what?
If you'd squawked 5 years ago,
you'd be slipping me a roll now.
And I'd be thanking you.
You took the rap
because I was just a kid then.
Tony... I hear Mado's back.
You sure?
I've been waiting 5 years for this.
Where is she?
Dunno yet, but we'll find her.
Thanks, waiter.
You make me feel young again.
- Good, we need a young man.
- Let's hear it.
So?
Aren't you fed up
with cheap poker games?
Let's hear it, I said.
"Webb"? You're nuts!
Why not the Bank of France?
- Time was you'd jump at it.
- Time was, Mario.
The place has more alarms
than a firehouse.
We don't have to go in.
The 3 rocks in the window alone
are worth a fortune.
Remember the Bond Street job.
I remember. They cut out
the glass in broad daylight.
- And cleaned up in 17 seconds.
- A piece of cake.
We've timed it at least 20 times.
We attack at 1:06.
The street's not too busy then.
You're parked over there.
The light at the intersection
goes red. Traffic stops.
You pull up, we start, we cut.
When the light's green,
we drive off with the rocks.
- Yeah, you gotta be young.
- You in?
Sorry, guys.
I don't run so fast anymore.
- Wind it up.
- Again?
Come here.
It's you I'm gonna wind up.
The penguin's cry...
Time for bed.
Your penguin has to go beddy-bye.
Good night, junior.
How's it going, Mario?
Thanks for the penguin,
Uncle Tony.
I'll see.
I hit the bull's-eye
with that penguin.
Ever heard of the "L'Age d'Or"
in Montmartre?
Why?
Mado works there.
She looks after the girls.
She's shacked up with the boss,
Pierre Grutter. Know him?
Vaguely. His kid brother's
a junkie, I think.
Yeah, he's hooked bad.
And they say Grutter is
too friendly with the cops.
Kiss Louise for me.
I'm turning in.
Don't go there alone.
They're tough customers.
Hear what I said?
I'm not deaf.
The show's about to begin!
Check your hat, sir?
This one's not empty yet!
So what?
You got moths in your wallet?
Oh, all right.
That's a good one,
"Moths in your wallet"!
Beat it, chump!
Scram!
Do as he says.
- Check!
- I'll get it.
Coming, Mado?
Tony, I thought you were still...
As you can see, they let me out.
For good behavior.
Go on in.
Have a seat.
Not very fancy, eh?
When a man's alone...
Nothing like our old place.
You fixed it up nice.
How much did you unload it
for while I was inside?
You never had a head
for figures.
I got busted in May.
In June you were on the Riviera
with a gigolo.
You didn't lose any time.
I thought I loved him.
Stop it, you're making me cry.
It's true, Tony.
And now it's the likes
of Pierre Grutter.
I had Jo on my tail.
He could've gotten nasty.
I knew it, so I left.
I met Grutter in Morocco.
It was him or someone else.
Nice sparkler.
- Did he...?
- No. I earned it.
You always did manage.
Do what you want.
I'd like to help you.
No kidding.
Put the ring on the table.
The bracelet.
Fine.
Now the coat.
Come here.
The rest of it.
All of it.
Believe me, Tony,
I never forgot you!
Please, Tony!
Get dressed.
Beat it!
- Let me dress!
- Out!
Hello, Jo... it's Tony.
Meet me at Mario's right away.
The job interests me after all.
A man's gotta live.
Not so hard.
Go easy.
Hi, Ida, taking a bath?
Not me. Mario.
Knock first! A little decency!
Tony's thought it over.
He's in.
No kidding.
Is it true?
This is a cause for celebration!
- It's gonna be sheer genius!
- Mario, my carpet!
Go to bed, pet.
We have to talk.
Warm up my side.
Good night.
Don't get excited.
I've got conditions.
None of these.
It's too risky.
Get caught with a rod,
and it's the slammer for life.
Maybe I should go back
to my soap bubbles.
Maybe you should.
He in or what?
For me, the rocks in the
window are chicken feed.
We gotta go for the real thing.
The jackpot. The safe!
Sure, it's gonna mean
careful preparation:
Knocking out their alarms,
and, most of all,
getting a safecracker.
Ever heard of Cesar the Milanese?
What's the wait for Milan,
please?
For a job with you, he'll come.
They say there's not a safe
that can resist Cesar,
and not a woman that
Cesar can resist.
How long?
Right away.
Get me 868-861.
But first we make sure
we can fence the goods.
I know just the guy:
Teddy the Levantine in London.
I'm sure he'll go for it.
You have a spare passport,
so you go see him.
Book a flight the day before.
I've got a great job.
Right up your alley.
With a friend. He's the best.
Can you come?
Great! I'll be at the airport.
- Who lives upstairs?
- Webb himself. He's always home.
Except weekends.
He goes hunting every Saturday.
Jo, let's test your memory.
You name each store as we pass.
Without looking up, OK?
I can do it with my eyes shut.
And Cesar?
"Ferrugia," pricey custom-made
boots for the missus.
- It opens when?
- Late.
"Tecla," cultured pearls,
costume junk. Opens at 10.
Florist. Salesgirl has
the biggest boobs in town.
Careful, it opens at 6 a.m.
Even earlier.
So we gotta be out
no later than 5.
That's for sure.
"Henri Maupiou,"
silks for evening gowns.
Branch stores in London and NY
for emergency repairs.
Swell.
- The other sidewalk now?
- No, I trust you.
We have to case it by night.
Things change then.
Sure. Tonight?
Tonight...
I was at the "L'Age d'Or"
last night.
You saw her?
- I took her to my place.
- And Grutter?
He wasn't in. He won't have
to look for me. I go back tonight.
- You're nuts!
- Expect me to hide?
Then I'm coming with you.
No way. I don't need
my friends to settle this.
Keep away.
It's my business.
I'll handle this Grutter alone.
Pierre, please!
I'm fed up with your big shot act.
You'll get yours some day.
Take a look at yourself,
you little punk.
You're a pretty picture. Dope's
gonna land you in the nuthouse.
Please!
- Give me a little.
- Put that down.
Just a bit.
When I feel like it.
Got that?
We all just happened to be here.
Hello, you.
Hello, kid.
Sit your moneymaker down.
Champagne.
What's your tag?
Maximilian.
Viviane!
I got a guy who knows what's what
He ain't the kind to bust a gut
He's got lotsa philosophy
Only he's too sweet on "rififi"
If another guy just gives me a nod
Right away he goes for his rod
He tips his hat and yessiree!
It's time for some "rififi"
I step in, but he don't give a damn
He points me out and says: Scram!
And when he's back after a while
He's got this nasty little smile
And sure as sure can be
I'm next in line for "rififi"
You look like
you don't have a clue
Like no one ever spoke to you
'Bout "rififi"
It's not a word that people use
Among the swells,
the Who's Who's
"Rififi"
It's the lingo of the streetwise
The battle cry of real tough guys
"Rififi"
So don't fry your brain and grumble
All it means is "rough n' tumble"
"Rififi"
When I'm done workin' the beat
He takes me to the movies as a treat
He don't care what flick we see
So long as it's got "rififi"
In love, he can be kinda rough
He don't go for sentimental stuff
A chick, he keeps telling me,
Gets her kicks on "rififi"
And when he really lets himself go
I get a cuff just for the show
And when I'm lying by his side
I'm nothing, I got no pride
In paradise I wanna be
I'll pay the price in "rififi"
You look like you don't have a clue
Like no one ever spoke to you
'Bout "rififi"
It's not a word that people use
Among the swells,
the Who's Who's
"Rififi"
It's the lingo of the streetwise
The battle cry of real tough guys
"Rififi"
So don't fry your brain and grumble
All it means is "rough n' tumble"
"Rififi"
Champagne, sir?
- What are you doing here?
- What a surprise!
That's perfect. This is Cesar...
The Stephanois.
That's your Cesar?
You cut him out of a catalogue?
He says you look like a tramp.
Glad to meet you.
Why'd you bring him here?
He insisted. He says we should
stick together on everything.
A Saint Bernard.
So you quit the "Rêve Bleu"?
Three weeks ago.
Mr Cesar... He's sorry
but he don't yack in French.
But I understand everything.
Don't recognize me?
Should I?
Tony the Stephanois.
Nothing to say to me?
I thought you were still doing
time. You're out, congrats.
I know Mado was with you.
But now she's with me. That's life.
So don't try anything. You lay off
me and I'll lay off you.
Okay?
I don't believe it!
Mado didn't tell him.
She didn't have to.
It's stamped across her back.
Hey, Maximilian,
I'm running on empty.
Then back to the garage.
By the way...
- You know Mado?
- Sure, I do.
- Where is she?
- She's taking a trip.
When was this?
Last night. She took off,
then phoned Viviane later.
- Is that all?
- That's all.
Go play with boys your own age.
- Well?
- Tell you later. What about Cesar?
Thanks a lot!
Don't cry. He just learned
some women have guts.
Proposition interesting. Certain can
handle in London. Teddy Levantine.
"Florist delivery.
5:50 a.m."
- Ready?
- Just about.
"Sure-Alarm."
What's it say?
It's no pushover.
It's the latest model.
It's getting harder to make
a living.
After you!
Turn it on.
"Severing any wire
causes a power cut
"and activates the alarm system."
Now we know.
Hook it up.
Ready?
The bastards thought of everything.
They're clever, but
maybe not clever enough.
Contact!
You ain't seen nothin' yet.
This little box...
this is our deadly enemy.
In every door, every window.
"Any vibration in a wall
or a floor
"momentarily causes a power cut
"which activates the alarm
by way of a relay system."
- Vibrations... And the floor?
- Depends on the touch.
A little harder.
We have some leeway.
Once more.
- It's chancy.
- You'll have to go easy.
The ceiling will take 2 hours,
at least.
And we can figure on
3 hours in the store, easy.
But down there we can't even breathe
if we don't muzzle this thing.
That's why we're here.
Now let's see...
That, too.
The alarm system is
battery- and circuit-powered.
If the battery runs down...
Morning bells are ringing
Ding ding dong!
But when the box is shut...
Through here?
Why don't we just pour
in hot wax with a funnel?
Why not spaghetti?
With parmesan.
Out of the way!
We're all set, guys!
Excuse me, I heard singing.
Hello there!
Who wants coffee?
Nobody. Go back to bed, pet.
You all right?
In the pink.
Run along now.
So, Tony...
Never in my whole crummy life...
200 million, at least.
Even with the Levantine's take,
it was worth the risk.
Now Ida and me can try out beds
in all the chic hotels.
How about you?
Four sisters.
Nice girls.
But no beauties.
Gonna buy them husbands?
Exactly.
My kid.
What about you?
What do I want?
Dunno.
Let's not start spending it yet.
There's still the fence to deal
with. Could be a hitch.
And the cops will be hot
on our tails.
We're not out of the woods yet.
Still have your stash?
Keep the goods here.
Jo, your flight's in an hour.
And you look grounded.
I'll have Louise take care of you
while I'm away.
You sleep here at Mario's.
No hotel registers.
And no runnin' around Montmartre.
Heard what I told your paisano?
No problem.
Read all about it! 240 million!
Biggest take since the Sabine women!
London on the line. Booth 3.
How's it going?
He drives a hard bargain.
But we've clinched it.
I'll be home tomorrow.
Great. Listen, remember that
rubber clown Jimmy got in London?
Yeah, the one that bounces back.
Get me one for your kid.
He'll go for that.
Sure thing.
It's beautiful.
You're sweet.
I can tell you since you don't
understand: I know it's a fake.
Mado! Where you been?
Pierre sent Rémi out to find you.
I'll explain later.
Please don't tell him I'm here.
As you like.
I understand.
Goodnight, Inspector.
What'd he want?
They're offering 10 million
for a lead on the jewelry job.
- Meaning they're in the dark.
- It's our play.
You've got a visitor.
Hello there.
So, your trip...
Let's hear it.
Hello, Pierre.
Did you trip?
And how'd you get this?
Answer me. Who did it?
I can't stay with you.
You can't hold me.
You can't.
I suppose you don't know
the Stephanois is back.
One...
Two...
I want you to take out
the Stephanois. He's in my way.
- He don't weigh much.
- Go on, Rémi.
Hold on a sec!
Close the door.
Look at this!
Nice ring.
Where'd you get it?
Some crazy little Italian
gave it to Viviane.
All this fuss over some cheap stone!
- How'd you meet him?
- Through his pal Mario.
Which Mario?
Some hood. You must know him.
Remember, Ida's man...
Ex-"Rêve bleu" dancer!
Mario Ferrati.
He works with the Stephanois.
I'm on in 5 minutes and
my Italian's waiting backstage.
He can wait. You stay put.
- Let's go.
- My ring!
Relax. It's a fake.
- A fake worth a million.
- No kidding!
This changes everything.
We need Tony alive now.
It adds up. The Italian's got the
hots for Viviane. He's Mario's pal.
Mario's in with Tony, who's just
done a stretch... for a jewel heist!
This morning, the Webb
job... and now this!
It adds up, I tell you.
It's like being brought
10 million on a platter.
What did the papers say?
240 million, no?
Let's go get it.
What are you gonna do?
Practice my Italian.
No, this way, Spaghetti!
This comes from Webb's?
Not a sound. Or else...
The ice, and fast!
What ice...
No games! I know
you've got it stashed here.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
You don't?
Your pal Cesar thinks you do.
What's he got to do with this?
So, don't know where they are?
In that case...
The Stephanois...
Maybe he knows.
The Stephanois?
Who's he?
Call him.
Get him here.
I forgot his number.
Hurry up, creep!
Is it coming back to you now?
- No.
- My turn!
I'll call him.
Ida, don't!
They'll kill him!
You know Tony, he'll never talk!
They'll kill him! Don't do it!
Please, Ida, don't!
It's me, Ida.
You gotta get over here now...
Don't come, Tony! The Grutters
are here for the rocks!
You idiot!
Let's get the hell out!
- How'd you find me?
- Skip it.
- I don't want to see you.
- I figured.
Just tell me where
I can find Grutter.
Look, Mado, I know
you left Grutter.
I also know you didn't tell him
about that night.
Maybe we can wipe the slate clean.
Never!
I want Grutter.
He murdered my friends.
So what!
You'll all die, one by one!
The whole rotten bunch of you!
I get it.
Goodbye, Mado.
Grutter!
You alone?
How's Mario?
Not now.
Please, tell me.
How's Mario?
He's dead.
Forgive me.
It was you.
You ratted on him.
Forgive me.
I was afraid.
I liked you.
I really liked you, Macaroni.
But you know the rules.
The rules.
Police?
You'll find two bodies
at 40, rue Fontaine du But.
At Mario Ferrati's.
Hello, Inspector.
Can I ask why you're attending
Mario Ferrati's funeral?
Just an idea.
With all these police, is there
a hood crazy enough to show up?
I doubt it.
There's the procession.
Flowers. Without cards or names.
Not a soul behind the hearse.
I came as a matter of form.
Freeze, for the kid's sake!
Hold your balloon tight.
See what can happen to it?
Is that clear?
Tell Jo, the kid or the gems,
and to wait for our call.
And not a word to the cops.
Mommy's not coming?
Later.
So, tough guys,
is this war games?
Where's my baby, you thug?
Where's my baby?
Let me call the police.
They'll do something. Please, Jo!
- You gotta keep calm!
- Let me call, Jo.
You know if you call the cops
I can't make a move.
Have patience, honey.
They'll call soon.
This way.
- How's it going, Tony?
- In here.
It's all there.
120 million, as agreed.
Amusing.
Your work's done.
Ours is just starting.
The rocks have to be recut.
I'll take a loss.
But that's how the trade goes.
Cute.
I'll be running along.
I'll turn this town inside out,
but I'll find them.
Stay here.
I'll call in every 20 minutes.
If they call,
I'll have to give it to them.
Out of the question!
I meant my share.
Not your share, not anyone's!
It's mine!
Don't be a fool! They won't
give you the kid in exchange.
The longer they wait, the better
the kid's chances. They'll kill him!
- A kid's a witness. He remembers.
- He's only 5!
At five, you've got eyes and ears.
And a tongue.
No, take my word for it.
The only chance of getting
the boy back... is this.
The only chance.
You may be right.
Look after Louise. It's rough on
her. I'll send Fredo's wife over.
See you tomorrow.
The bastards!
This kind of thing
doesn't happen here.
Just say the word and
all the guys are behind you.
We can't risk letting the cops
get wind of this.
So what'll you do?
I'll do the rounds of friends
I can count on.
If they hear anything, they'll
call here. I'll keep in touch.
Okay.
Why look at me like that?
He's my kid, too! Why blame me?
I'm not blaming you.
There's something
I always wanted to tell you.
There are kids...
Millions of kids who've
grown up poor. Like you.
How did it happen...
What difference was there
between them and you,
that you became a hood,
a tough guy,
and not them?
Know what I think, Jo?
They're the tough guys, not you.
No, Tony. Still nothing.
Nothing?
How's Jo?
He's thrilled.
Fredo told me about the kid. It's
disgusting. If I can be of help...
Thanks. Tell me where
Grutter and his boys hide out.
I think I know. He's building a villa
near Saint-Rémy-lès-Chevreuse.
A guy goes out there all the time:
Charlie, the dope dealer.
Know where to find him?
Let's go.
The kid's OK.
Got the ice?
The fence has them.
He's bringing the dough.
- When?
- Any minute now.
I'll call one more time.
It'll be the last.
- In the cleaner's...
- I'll go.
No, let me. The guy knows me.
Have any money?
I'm close.
Pierre just called.
I told him the money's
coming, to wait,
but the bastard means business.
I can't take any more!
This is no time to lose your
head. We'll get 'em.
But the kid, Tony!
Just hold on, Jo! I'll call you
back in a few minutes.
I'll be waiting.
I want to see Charlie.
But I don't know if he...
If it isn't Mado! Come on in.
How's Pierre?
Fine, fine.
- Coffee?
- No, I haven't got time.
It's for Rémi.
He's crying for more dope.
You have to take him
some at the villa.
Oh, him!
Just when my car breaks down.
I'd have to take the Metro.
It's pretty far.
You go.
I can't. Pierre's waiting.
- Why is it always me?
- Be nice.
What about my car?
He's a good customer.
I'll go.
- And quick.
- Where's the fire?
Can I use your phone?
Sorry, pal. It's an inside line.
- What're you doing here?
- I have Rémi's stuff.
Pierre sent you?
No, Mado.
- What's so odd about that?
- Nothing.
Mado paid already.
Okay then. So long.
Uncle Tony!
Isn't it a funny-Iooking house?
- Mommy's not here?
- We're going to meet her.
Go and get into the nice car.
Aren't you coming, Uncle?
Sure, I am. If you're a good boy
I'll let you drive.
On your feet, punk.
Wake up, you bastard.
I don't want you to miss anything.
Come on, Uncle Tony! All aboard!
Let me drive, Uncle Tony!
Later.
No, don't hang up!
The money just arrived.
You know
Saint-Rémy-lès-Chevreuse?
It's about 200 yards from
the station.
Take a left until you reach
a house under construction.
You can't miss it.
I'll give you 40 minutes.
Make sure you're alone,
and unarmed.
What is it, Jo?
- I need to call.
- The phone's there.
I'm hungry, Uncle Tony.
Wait until we get home.
I'm calling Mommy.
Say hello to Daddy.
I'm okay. Did Daddy go out?
Where's Jo? Sure, I have Tonio.
Where's Jo, goddamit?
I don't know. Someone called.
He ran out with a suitcase.
- Can you make the boy a sandwich?
- Of course, sir.
- Where are you going?
- I'll be right back.
I leave him in your care.
Go right ahead.
So what'll you'll have, little man?
A big, big, big sandwich.
Louis...
What happened?
The Stephanois...
What's your worry?
You have the kid.
- Got it all?
- Come here.
Let's have it.
The kid first.
Okay. Come in.
Come on up.
Where's the kid?
The Stephanois pulled a fast one.
He took him.
Your change!
I'm cold, Uncle Tony!
Put this coat on.
Look at those trees!