[ Birds Squawking ]
[ Man ]
The feeling begins.
Very tender, very loving.
Then the pain starts.
CIaws slip underneath the skin
and tear their way u¤.
Just before they reach my eyes,
they dig in.
Then I remember.
[ Pounding ]
First, l fasted
for three months.
I even whipped myself
before l went to sleep.
At first it worked.
Then the pain came back.
And the voices.
They calI me by name -
Jesus.
[ Sighs ]
[ Jesus ] Who is it? Who are you?
Why are you foIlowing me?
Are you ready?
No, no. No more crosses.
We're ready.
Do you hear? Where's your mind?
Do you hear what I'm saying?
The Messiah won't come that way.
What do you mean by that?
Who toId you?
[ Spits ]
You're a disgrace!
The Romans can't find anybody
to make crosses except for you!
You do it!
You're worse than them!
You're a Jew killing Jews!
You're a coward!
How will you ever pay
for your sins?
With my life, Judas.
l don't have anything eIse.
Don't turn away.
Look at me. Look at me.
With your life?
What do you mean?
PIease, Judas.
l don't know. l don't know.
- Are you still taking the cross?
- Yes, l am.
No, you're not.
[ Mutters ]
[ Groaning ]
l won't let you!
No! l won't let you!
Please, I beg you, Judas.
Don't get in the way.
What way? What's happened to you?
Who's doing this to you?
l'm struggling.
- With who?
- I don't know. l'm struggling.
No.
l struggle.
You collaborate.
[ Shouting, Grunting ]
[ Scream, Groaning ]
[ Groans ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Neck Snaps ]
[ Panting ]
[ Quiet Chattering ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ lndistinct Shouting ]
[ Man ]
Leave him alone. Are you ready?
Stop him! Stop him!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Man ]
Traitor!
You are the peopIe of lsrael.
Your children are watching.
You are the peopIe of God.
He is judging us.
He's watching you. PIease.
- There he is.
- KiIl him!
Don't touch him!
Get away from him!
- Don't defend him.
- He's my son!
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Man ]
God is with us. He's judging us.
Fight! Fight!
[ Man #2 ]
God help us! God give us strength!
Give us strength now!
[ Quiet Chattering ]
[ Children Giggling ]
[ Prisoner Muttering ]
You are His chiIdren.
[ Dog Howling ]
Come. Come with me.
[ Centurion ] This man naked before you
now is condemned for sedition...
for lifting his hand against Rome.
He ralIied the people to revolution.
He promised that a Messiah would come
from among the people...
to rise up and destroy Rome.
- [ Man ] Rome is nothing.
- [ Centurion ] Murder.
- [ Man ] lt's smaIl.
- [ Centurion ] Betrayal, looting, and so on.
And so, therefore,
he is condemned to die.
Rome condemns him.
And aIl the gods
of Rome condemn him.
[ Woman Wailing ]
The shield is -
He is - He is our heart.
He is our heart.
He is our -
He is our shield.
- [ Jesus ] Lazarus.
- He is our shield.
He is our shield.
He will not abandon you.
He will not -
- [ Hammering ]
- [ Lazarus Screaming ]
- [ Gasps ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
[ Gasps ]
[ Man Chanting ]
Mercy on him. Mercy on him.
[ Woman Wailing ]
[ Lazarus Screaming, Groaning ]
[ Groaning ]
Aaah! No!
- [ Screaming ]
- No.
[ Jesus ]
God loves me. I know He loves me.
l want him to stop.
I can't take the pain.
The voices and the pain.
- [ Groaning Continues ]
- I want Him to hate me.
I fight Him and make crosses
so He'll hate me.
I want Him to find somebody else.
I want to crucify
every one of his Messiahs.
You're sure it's God?
You're sure it's not the devil?
l'm not sure.
l'm not sure of anything.
lf it's the devil,
the devil can be cast out.
But what if it's God?
You can't cast out God, can you?
[ Loud Footsteps ]
[ Footsteps Stop ]
[ Footsteps Continue ]
[ Thinking ] Who's that?
Who's foIlowing me? ls that you?
[ Footsteps Continue ]
- [ Bird Screeches ]
- [ Yelps, Groaning ]
[ Bird Squawking ]
[ Thinking ]
Magdalene. Magdalene.
♪♪ [ Instrumental Folk ]
♪♪ [ Men Singing In Arabic ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Donkey Braying ]
♪♪ [ Singing Continues ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
[ Jesus ] Thank you, Lord, for bringing me
where I did not want to go.
He must be one of God's angels...
who came down
to show me the way.
[ Woman Panting, Moaning ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
♪♪ [ Singing Continues ]
[ Foreign Language, lndistinct ]
[ Moaning Continues ]
[ Panting, Moaning Continue ]
[ lndistinct ]
Who's out there?
Who is it?
What are you doing here?
l want you to forgive me.
l've done too many bad things.
l'm going to the desert,
and l need you to forgive me...
before l go.
Please.
Oh, l see.
You sit out there alI day
with the others.
And then you come in here
with your head down, saying...
"Forgive me"?
"Forgive me."
lt's not that easy.
Just because you need forgiveness,
don't ask me to do it.
- I'm sorry, Mary.
- Now get out! Go away!
[ Sobs ]
Look, Mary. Look at this.
God can change this.
God can save your soul.
He already broke my heart.
He took you away from me.
And l hate both of you!
Hate me. Blame me.
It's all my fault.
But not God's.
Don't say that about God.
Who made me feel
this way about God?
l know.
That's why l'm here.
That's why l want you to forgive me.
l'll pay my debt.
l know...
the worst things l've done
have been to you.
Pay or go away.
[ Sobbing ]
Mary...
don't you remember?
No, l don't remember.
Why should l?
Nothing's changed.
Save the truth.
You want to save my soul?
This is where you'lI find it.
You know that.
You're the same as aIl the others,
only you can't admit it.
You're pitiful.
l hate you.
Here's my body.
Save it.
Oh! Is that the way
you show you're a man?
Turn away.
Don't look at me.
You never had the courage
to be a man. Don't look at me.
lf you weren't hanging on to your mother,
you were hanging on to me.
Now you're hanging on to God.
Going to the desert to hide
because you're scared.
Well, go. Whenever I see you,
my heart breaks.
l do remember
when we were chiIdren.
Never have l feIt so much
tenderness toward anyone...
as l felt toward you then.
All l ever wanted was you.
Nothing else.
What do you think l wanted?
Please... stay.
ls it so bad
sharing a prostitute's room?
l won't touch you. l promise.
You'lI still be a virgin for the desert.
Mary, l'm sorry. l can't stay.
Welcome. This way.
Do you always pray
this late at night?
lt's a funeral.
The master of the monastery died.
Shall l pray with you?
No. Sleep.
You must be tired.
l know who you are.
♪♪ [ Chanting ln Distance ]
That was the man
who brought me here last night.
Last night?
He was dead last night.
♪♪ [ Chanting Continues ]
The master's souI is gone to heaven.
His body's work is completed.
lt walked under the sun
and the moon...
over sand and stone...
sinned, felt pain...
yearned for heaven.
We commend his remains to our god.
Flesh, the master
no longer needs you.
Melt away.
First came the wings,
then the angel.
His spirit actuaIly appeared to you.
He treated you like a royaI visitor.
He recognized you for something.
No, he couldn't have
recognized me for anything.
l only came here to serve God.
That's all.
That's alI God wants from me.
l'm sure of it.
But think of how you're blessed.
God actually makes himself
known to you.
l don't know what God wants from me.
All my life l've wanted
to hear God's voice.
l've dedicated my life to Him.
Sometimes...
l think l feeI Him...
but l'm never really sure.
But you always know.
God took you by the hand
and brought you here.
[ Laughs ]
You think it's a blessing
to know what God wants?
I'Il telI you what He wants.
He wants to push me over!
Can't He see
what's inside of me?
All my sins?
- We all sin.
- Not my sins.
l'm a liar, a hypocrite.
I'm afraid of everything.
l don't ever telI the truth.
l don't have the courage.
When l see a woman,
l bIush and look away.
l want her, but I don't
take her... for God.
And that makes me proud.
And then my pride ruins Magdalene.
l don't steaI, l don't fight
and I don't kiIl.
Not because l don't want to,
but because l'm afraid.
l want to rebel against you,
against everything, again -
against God, but... l'm afraid.
You want to know
who my mother and father are?
You want to know who my god is?
Fear.
You look inside me,
and that's all you'Il find.
But the more devils
that we have inside of us...
the more of a chance
we have to repent.
Lucifer is inside me.
He says to me,
'¤ou're not the son of King David.
You're not a man.
You're the son of man.
And more. The Son of God.
And more than that. God."
[ ChuckIes ]
Do you want to ask me anything eIse?
[ Rattling ]
[ Magdalene Laughing ]
[ Jesus ]
Everything is from God.
Everything has two meanings.
[ Magdalene's Voice ]
Jesus, oh, my sweet Jesus.
I forgive you.
Leave me! Leave me.
They're gone.
You have to Ieave too.
No.
- l have to stay.
- No, you've been purified.
God has just blessed you.
The snakes came from inside you.
Now you have to leave too.
You have to go back...
and speak to peopIe
and share your heart.
Speak to who?
- To anyone who will listen.
- And say what?
Just open your mouth.
Do you love mankind?
l see men, and l feeI sorry for them.
That's alI.
[ Sighs ]
That's enough.
[ lnsects Buzzing ]
[ RustIing ]
[ Grunts ]
- l've got orders to kill you.
- Go ahead. Tonight I was purified.
l can't fight with God anymore.
Here. Here's my neck. Cut it.
l'm ready.
[ Gasps ]
[ lmitates Knife Slicing ]
What are you?
What kind of a man are you?
[ Jesus ]
What you want, l want.
That's why He brought us together.
lt's God's plan.
l come to kill you and you help me,
that's God's plan?
These voices you hear, it's God's voice?
Only you understand it?
Well, you better make me
understand it too.
l'll tell you as much as l know.
The fainting speIls,
the voices, the visions.
Power, magic.
ls there some secret?
- Tell me your secret.
- Pity.
- Pity for who? Yourself?
- Pity for men.
- Our enemies are men.
- I feel pity for everything.
Donkeys, grass, sparrows.
What about ants?
Feel pity for them too?
Yes. Everything's a part of God.
When l see an ant,
when l Iook at his shiny black eye...
you know what l see?
l see the face of God.
You're not afraid of dying?
Why should l be?
Death isn't a door that closes.
lt opens.
lt opens, and you go through it.
lf l don't kilI you,
what happens?
l'll speak to people.
What are you going to say?
l'lI just open my mouth,
and God wiIl do the talking.
[ Jesus ]
Mmm.
Maybe God didn't send you here
to kiIl me.
Maybe He sent you here
to foIlow me.
Just so there's no mistake...
l'll go with you until I understand.
But if you stray this much...
from the path, l'll kill you.
[ Shouting, Screaming ]
Stop!
[ Magdalene Screaming ]
lt's Magdalene.
She deserves it.
[ Sobbing, Whimpering ]
- [ Men Shouting ] Stone her!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Man ] Get out of there!
Get out of there! Get out of the way!
This is not your business!
Do you want to get hurt?
Didn't you hear
what he said, idiot? Move!
No. l don't want this.
Listen to him.
He doesn't want this. WelI, we want it.
- Why?
- We don't have to teIl you why!
Bad enough we live
in a whorehouse.
But she's a Jew.
She works on the Sabbath.
She goes with Romans on the Sabbath.
She broke Moses' law. She dies.
Who has never sinned? Who?
Which one of you people
has never sinned?
Whoever that is...
come up here!
And throw these!
l have nothing to hide.
Good. Take this. lt's bigger.
[ Whimpers ]
Be careful, Zebedee.
There is a god.
He's seen you cheat your workers.
He's seen you with that widow.
What's her name?
- [ Woman ] Judith.
- Judith.
Aren't you afraid God will paralyze you
if you lift that stone?
That your arm will wither?
That you'Il lose all strength?
[ Gasps ]
[ Whimpering ]
[ Jesus ]
God has so many miracles.
What if l say the wrong thing?
What if I say the right thing?
Come closer.
We're all a famiIy.
Come closer so you can hear.
l have something to telI you.
Who is he?
lt's Jesus from Nazareth.
Nothing good can come out of Nazareth.
Even the scriptures say so.
Uh...
l'm - I'm sorry, but...
the easiest way
to make myseIf cIear...
is to tell you a story.
A farmer was pIanting in his field.
Some seed fell on the ground,
and the birds ate it.
Some seed fell on rocks
and dried up.
But some seed -
Some seed fell on rich soil...
and grew into enough wheat
to feed a whole nation.
- Can you hear me?
- Oh, we can hear you fine.
I'm the farmer!
The farmer is me.
And two and two makes four.
Another lunatic!
Rabbi, teIl me.
lf you're the farmer...
and we're the stones...
what's the seed?
What's the seed?
Love.
Love one another.
That's easy to say. Maybe that's
good advice, but for some other world.
These peopIe are starving.
First you feed them, then you taIk.
Listen. l used to think God was angry too,
but not anymore!
He used to jump on me
Iike a wild bird...
and dig His claws into my head.
But then one morning,
He came to me.
He blew over me
Iike a cool breeze...
and said, "Stand up."
And here l am.
- And you will go to heIl.
- These are children's stories.
- How can they help us?
- What are you hungry for?
What are you thirsty for?
For justice.
- Justice!
- And bread.
Bread? Bread too.
You're thirsty for justice...
for peopIe to treat you fairIy...
for people to treat you with respect.
What l'm teIling you is,
whoever's hungry for justice...
they're the ones
who'll be blessed.
They'll be fiIled with bread.
They'll never be hungry again.
They'lI have the real value, the value
of love - to love, share and comfort.
They'll have the courage
to do the good.
And you - you're mourning.
Mourners wilI be blessed.
You'lI have God to comfort you.
You won't need men to do it.
And the meek - they're the ones
who will be blessed.
And the suffering -
they'll be bIessed too.
And the peacemakers
and the merciful...
and the sick and the poor
and the outcast.
You'll aIl be blessed,
because heaven is yours!
[ Man Laughing ]
And believe me -
[ Laughing Continues ]
BeIieve me,
those who are laughing now...
will be crying later.
Those whose stomachs are filled now
wilI be hungry later.
And the rich will be poor forever!
- Kill the rich!
- Kill them! KiIl them!
- [ Woman ] Kill the rich!
- [ AIl Shouting ]
No! l-l-I didn't -
l didn't say death!
[ Shouting Continues ]
l said Iove!
- Enough. Come.
- No, Father, l'm staying.
We have to work.
l need you.
John!
- Come.
- I'm sorry, Father. l'm staying too.
Oh, no, no, no.
Not the two of you! Come on!
Let me come with you.
l can help.
[ Sighs ]
No. Stay here.
You'lI know when.
TelI people about me.
[ Quiet Chattering ]
James.
Andrew.
Move over, John.
- Move over, James.
- What? l was just comfortable.
- Peter wants to lie down.
- Peter, there's no more room.
l'm cold. l want to be by the fire.
[ James ]
Well, go over by Phillip. We're all cold.
[ Peter ]
Shut up.
Rabbi, can l talk to you?
[ Sighs ]
l'm not like these other men.
l mean, they're good enough.
They're good men.
But they're weak.
One's worse than the other.
Where'd you find them?
Look at me.
lf l Iove somebody,
l would die for them.
lf l hate somebody, l kiIl them.
l could even kilI somebody l Ioved
if they did the wrong thing.
Did you hear me?
Do you understand what l said?
Yes, l understand.
The other day you said if a man hits you,
you turn the other cheek.
l didn't like that.
Only an angel could do that.
Or a dog.
l'm sorry, but l'm neither.
l'm a free man.
l don't turn my cheek to anyone.
We both want the same thing.
We do?
[ Chuckles ]
You want freedom for lsrael?
No. l want freedom for the soul.
No. That's what I can't accept.
That's not the same thing.
It's not the same thing!
First you free the body, then you free
the spirit. The Romans come first.
You don't build a house from the roof down.
You build it from the foundation up.
The foundation is the soul.
The foundation is the body!
That's where you must begin.
No. lf you don't change the spirit first,
change what's inside...
then you're onIy gonna replace
the Romans with somebody eIse...
and nothing ever changes.
Even if you're victorious,
you'Il still be filled with the poison.
You've got to break
the chain of eviI.
How do you change, then?
- With love.
- [ Footsteps Approaching ]
- Who's there?
- It's me, Andrew.
ls everything -
lt's aIl right. Go back to sleep.
Judas and l are talking.
There's an example.
You know, the ZeaIots
ordered me to kill you.
Why did you change your mind?
l decided to wait.
For what?
l thought maybe you were the one...
to unite us.
l didn't want to destroy that.
How do we know?
How could l be the Messiah?
When those people were torturing
Magdalene, l wanted to kiIl them.
And then l opened my mouth...
and out comes the word "love."
Why? l don't understand.
You can't look to the others for answers.
All they can do is follow you.
We'll go to Judaea
and see John the Baptist.
Every day he teIls hundreds of people
the Messiah is coming. He'll know.
He'll know.
Judas... l'm afraid.
Stay with me.
♪♪ [ Chanting ln Arabic ]
[ Man ] Behold! I wiIl raise up
eviI against you out of your own house.
And l will take your wives before your eyes
and give them to your neighbor.
And he shall lie with your wives
in the sight of this sun.
You may listen and Iisten again,
but you wiIl never understand.
You may look and look,
but you will never know.
[ Voice Echoing ]
These people's wits are dulled!
Their ears are deafened
and their eyes bIinded...
so they cannot see with their eyes
nor hear with their ears...
so that they may turn
and be healed!
The Lord of Hosts says,
"On this day" -
- He sounds like the Messiah.
- No.
"I wiIl crush the horns
of the new moon...
and l wilI spill darkness
over the world.
l will reverse your Iaughter,
turn it into tears" -
Go in front.
Let him see you.
Hands, feet, noses, ears
will falI to the ground.
Listen. lt is the thunder
of many people.
[ Jesus ] Even from behind,
I knew I had seen him before.
Where? Was it a dream?
Yes, it was.
But in the dream,
he was dressed in white.
You wilI have the smell
of decay and branding...
instead of beauty.
Your men shall faIl by the sword...
and your women shalI sit
on the ground, stripped bare!
Who are you?
Do you recognize me?
Do you know the prophets?
What does lsaiah say?
He says,
"Prepare the way of the Lord."
Are you telling me that's you?
l don't know. TeIl me.
- [ Sounds Fade ]
- [ Water Trickling ]
[ No Sounds ]
Why are you here?
To be baptized.
No, no. l don't dare.
If you're the master,
then you have to baptize me.
Baptize me.
♪♪ [ Resumes ]
♪♪ [ Chanting ]
[ Quiet Talking ]
Love. What does it mean?
Love is sweet as honey,
but it's also blood.
Love is action. You want a new crop,
you burn the earth.
But isn't love enough?
No, no!
Look at the world. Look around you.
Plague, war, corruption,
false prophets...
faIse idols, worship of gold.
Nothing is of value.
The tree is rotten.
You have to take the ax
and cut it down.
lf l was a woodcutter, l'd cut.
If I was a fire, l'd burn.
But l'm a heart and l Iove.
That's all l can do.
I'm a heart aIso,
but l can't Iove what's unjust.
What l can't love, I attack.
God demands it.
- Anger?
- Yes, God demands anger.
Anger?
But we're all brothers.
You think love is God's only way?
Go to the Dead Sea.
Look in the bottom.
You'Il see two whores,
Sodom and Gomorrah.
That's God's way.
On the day of the Lord,
bIood will flow from wood.
The stones of the houses wiIl come alive
and kill their owners.
That day is here.
He gave me the ax.
Now l give it to you.
That's not the answer.
Then what is the answer?
l don't know.
Well, if you won't listen to me,
who will you listen to?
God.
The God of lsrael
is a god of the desert.
lf you want to speak to Him,
then you'll have to go to the desert.
l'll go to ldumaea.
Thank you, Baptist.
Be carefuI.
God isn't aIone out there.
l'm not going to leave this circle.
l'm not going to leave here
until You speak to me.
No signs. No pain.
Just speak to me in human words.
Whatever path You want, l'lI take.
Love... or the ax...
or anything eIse.
Or if You want me to stay here and die,
l'll do that too.
But You have to tell me.
[ Rattling ]
[ Hisses ]
[ Magdalene's Voice ]
I feeI sorry for you. You were lonely.
You cried. So I came.
l didn't calI for you.
Who are you?
Your spirit.
My spirit?
You're afraid of being alone.
[ Chuckles ]
You're just like Adam.
He called me,
and I took one of his ribs...
and made it into a woman.
You're here to trick me.
[ Chuckles ]
Trick you?
To love and care for a woman...
to have a family -
this is a trick?
Why are you trying
to save the worId?
Aren't your own sins
enough for you?
What arrogance to think
you can save the worId.
The worId doesn't have to be saved.
Save yourself.
Find love.
l have Iove.
Look... in my eyes.
Look at my breasts.
Do you recognize them?
Just nod your head...
and we'll be in my bed together.
Oh... Jesus!
[ Shuddering ]
[ Sobbing ]
[ Jesus ]
After ten days...
the hunger went away.
[ Animal Growling ]
[ Growling ]
[ Judas's Voice ]
WeIcome, Jesus. Congratulations.
You're past the smalI temptations
of a woman, a family.
- We're both bigger than that.
- Who are you?
You don't recognize me?
[ Judas's Voice ]
I'm you. l'm your heart.
Your heart is so greedy.
It pretends to be humble...
but it realIy wants
to conquer the world.
l never wanted
a kingdom on earth.
- The kingdom of heaven is enough.
- You're a Iiar!
When you were making crosses
for the Romans in Nazareth...
your head was exploding
with dreams of power!
Power over everyone.
You said it was God,
but you really wanted power.
Now you can have what you want.
Any country you want.
AIl of them.
- You could even have Rome.
- Liar.
Step into my circle
so l can pulI your tongue out.
[ Moaning ]
ArchangeI, move back.
Move back. You're blinding me.
[ MaIe Voice ]
Jesus.
l'm the one
you've been waiting for.
Remember...
when you were a Iittle boy?
You cried, "Make me a god!
God, God, make me a god!"
But l was just a child then.
You are God.
The Baptist knew it.
Now it's time you admit it.
You are His Son.
The only Son of God.
[ Echoes ]
Join me. Join me.
Together, we'll rule
the Iiving and the dead.
You'll give Iife,
and you'lI take Iife.
You'll sit in judgment,
and I'Il sit next to you.
lmagine how strong
we could be together.
Satan?
We'lI see each other again.
Don't be afraid.
You are the one.
My work is done.
Now l can die.
The Lord wants me
to teIl you to stand up.
His day is here.
Take this ax.
Take this message to everyone.
[ Sheep BIeating ]
Please.
[ Gasps ]
What do you want?
l'm a foreigner... from GaIilee.
l'm tired.
You don't know
how good this tastes.
Some more wine, pIease?
Mary.
Martha.
l want to say
that you're both blessed.
l came here,
you didn't know me.
You took me in,
fed me, restored me...
and God came down
and went into my heart.
- Go on.
- No.
l've talked too much already.
Silence is better.
No, it's not.
Do you have a wife?
- No.
- How can you live like that in the desert?
Tell me the truth.
Don't you miss all this -
having a home, a reaI life?
l admit it.
- I'd Iike it, but I'Il never have it.
- Listen.
If you really want God,
don't spend your time in the desert.
He's not there.
He's right here.
Read your scriptures.
God doesn't want you to fast and pray.
He wants you to make chiIdren.
Mary, you're making him uncomfortable.
He's a guest.
- He knows what l'm talking about.
- [ ChuckIes ]
[ Martha ]
Come and help me.
- It's not right to tease these men.
- l wasn't teasing.
Remember the Baptist?
lt's nothing to tease about.
- The Baptist? What?
- He's dead.
He was killed by Herod.
You didn't know?
[ Martha ]
They say the king was drunk.
They say he cut off his head -
the Baptist's head - to satisfy a girl.
- It happened in his paIace in Jerusalem.
- No, at his palace in Tiberius.
♪♪ [ Flute, Drum: FoIk ]
Now they say they're gonna kill
everyone who was baptized.
- No one forced you to be baptized.
- You were baptized too.
You begged for it, so be quiet.
[ James ]
l can just imagine in GaIilee right now.
The sea.
They say the fishing's so good, you just
touch the nets and the fish jump in.
Don't talk about fish. Reminds me of my sheep.
I don't know what's happened to them.
Maybe we should wait
for him in Galilee.
[ James ]
No, we promised the master we'd wait here.
That was over a month ago. Τhere are
thousands of people waiting to see him.
They're waiting to hear him, and he's gone.
The whole movement. We look like fools.
- Nathaniel's right. He makes sense.
- [ AlI Arguing ]
- Go back to Galilee like Peter says -
- Brothers!
l don't understand you.
Think of the last words
the Baptist said.
He said, "Jesus of Nazareth,
Ieave the desert.
l am finished.
And return to mankind."
- How do we know the Baptist realIy said that?
- Everybody says he did.
- But how do we know?
- WeIl¤ even if he didn't, the words are still important.
Why?
Because people believe them.
[ Sighs ]
And what if our master's -
Well, what if he's the one?
- What one?
- The one.
What do you mean?
The Messiah?
We don't know the Baptist said that.
- Nobody knows what they talked about.
- [ AlI Arguing ]
He's saying that the world
of God is here now.
What if he just meant...
continue my work?
Continue to do the same work
that l've been doing.
lt was right here at the Jordan River
Elijah ascended to heaven.
Doesn't that mean something to you?
- We're waiting here!
- [ Arguing Stops ]
We're waiting here.
l don't think we should go back to GaIilee.
l think we should wait here.
[ ChuckIes ]
That's what l Iove about you, Peter.
You're as steady
and as solid as a rock.
Nobody can change your mind.
What good are you?
Master.
Rabbi...
John heard your footsteps
in his heart... in a way.
And we were preparing
to welcome you.
Were you baptized?
Yes.
John baptized with water
and they killed him.
Now l baptize with fire.
ls that what the Baptist toId you?
l have an invitation for you.
- Is there a celebration?
- No.
l'm not inviting you
to a celebration.
l'm inviting you to a war.
This is my heart. Take it.
God is inside of us.
The deviI is outside us
in the world alI around us.
We'll pick up an ax
and cut the deviI's throat.
We'll fight him wherever he is.
ln the sick, in the rich...
even in the temple.
l'll Iead you.
lf you have sheep,
give them away.
lf you have a family, leave them.
l believed in Iove.
Now l believe in this.
Who's with me?
Adonai.
[ Jesus ] Today and tomorrow
I cast out deviIs and work cures.
On the third day...
I shalI be... perfected.
[ Moaning ]
Out!
Satan! Leave!
- Satan, out!
- [ Moaning ]
Leave him!
Moses, EIijah, lsaiah...
touch my mouth...
touch my lips.
Go the temple.
Let the high priests see you.
Look!
[ People, Disciples Chattering ]
He was blind, and Jesus healed him.
Look. Look.
Look at his eyes. He was blind,
and Jesus heaIed him. Look. Look. Look.
♪♪ [ lnstrumental FoIk ]
♪♪ [ People Chanting, Singing ]
♪♪ [ Continues ]
You! You don't belong at a wedding.
We're here to celebrate purity.
- I'm sorry, but these people are my guests.
- Please.
Let me explain something to you.
What do you think heaven's like?
lt's Iike a wedding.
God's the bridegroom,
and man's spirit's the bride.
The wedding takes place in heaven...
and everyone's invited.
God's world is big enough
for everybody.
Nazarene, that's against the law.
Then the law is against my heart.
Don't touch me.
You are now sacred to me
through this ring.
[ Bridegroom ]
You are now sacred to me through this ring.
According to the law
of Moses and IsraeI.
According to the Iaws
♪♪ [ Women Chanting ]
My cousins are very upset.
They only bought enough wine for three days.
Now another day's gone past, and it's gone.
What's in those?
- Water.
- No. It's wine.
- No, no, it's water. l put it there myself.
- lt's wine.
- lt's water.
- Go over there and make sure.
Do it.
♪♪ [ Continues ]
You're right. lt is wine.
♪♪ [ Drums Pounding ]
[ Chattering ]
[ Jesus ]
Brothers!
My oId friends!
Listen to me!
lt's me the prophets
preached about.
God talked to me in the desert.
He gave me a secret
and toId me to bring it to you.
[ Chuckles ]
Didn't you hear me coming?
l ran here to Nazareth,
where I grew up, to bring you the news.
- The world of God is here now.
- [ Man ] You work miracIes.
Make a miracle for us.
Make us believe in you.
Otherwise, go away.
The Messiah doesn't need miracIes.
He is the miracle.
Now he's here.
Are you ready for me?
l'm here to tear down
everything around you.
And you know what l'm going
to replace it with? Something new.
God. The worId of God.
So take your bread
and give it to the poor.
What difference does it matter
what you own?
You have goId and silver?
lt's going to rot.
And that rot is going to
eat away your heart.
All of you. There will be a flood,
and there wiIl be a fire.
Everything will be destroyed. But there
wilI be a new ark riding on that fire!
And l hold the keys
and l open the door...
and l decide who goes in
and who doesn't!
You're my brothers from Nazareth,
and you're the first l invite on the ark.
Don't wait.
Don't waste your life.
- Come with me.
- [ Man ] You're the son of Mary, right?
Who are you to tell us about God?
- You made better crosses than speeches.
- [ Laughter ]
Go get somebody from his famiIy
to take him away. He's insane.
- [ People Laughing ]
- What are you laughing at?
Everything you have is going to burn... soon.
Get out now. Come with me to Jerusalem.
See? This is what happens
when a man doesn't get married.
The semen backs up into his brain.
- [ Laughter ]
- Go home!
You're a demon! You're possessed!
You're a lunatic!
- This is my home!
- You should be ashamed.
KilI him! He's a magician!
He's going to burn us!
Don't touch him!
The love of God is for the poor!
[ All Shouting ]
lf l could touch every stone...
if l could breathe on every branch,
they'd get up and follow me.
- So what's wrong with you?
- [ Shouting Continues ]
Come with me to Jerusalem!
Jerusalem is faIling!
l feel it. l know it.
[ Jesus ]
You see these people?
They're poor, they're blind,
they're crippled.
They're going to be our army.
We're going to need
better men than this.
God wiIl give them to me.
We're going to buiId a new Jerusalem.
Son.
Come back with me, please.
Who are you?
- Your mother.
- I don't have a mother.
l don't have any famiIy.
l have a father... in heaven.
Don't say that to me.
Who are you?
l mean, realIy.
[ Sobbing ]
Mary, why are you crying?
Didn't you see them?
[ Sobbing Continues ]
What?
When he spoke to you, there were
thousands of blue wings behind him.
l swear to you, Mary,
there were armies of angeIs.
[ Shudders ]
- There were?
- Thousands.
l'd be happier if there weren't.
[ Chanting, Wailing ]
When was he buried?
Three days ago.
RoIl away the stone.
[ Chanting, WaiIing Continue ]
[ People Coughing ]
[ Whispering ]
Lazarus.
ln the name of the prophet...
in the name of Jeremiah
and my father...
in the name
of the Most Holy God...
l call you here.
l call you here!
[ Whispering ]
Lazarus.
[ Gasping, Panting ]
[ People Gasping ]
[ Grunting ]
[ Breathing HeaviIy ]
Adonai.
[ Jesus ]
God, heIp me.
♪♪ [ lnstrumental FoIk ]
[ Goat Bleating ]
[ Whining ]
We came here to pray.
Look at this.
The moneychangers?
lt's for the temple tax, for the feast.
l know.
- How's the exchange today?
- Fair. At this stall, it's always fair.
- Making a good profit?
- Fair.
[ People Shouting ]
[ Shouting ]
This is my father's house!
lt's a place of worship!
Not a market!
Nazarene, what are you doing?
- [ Shouting Stops ]
- What are you doing?
God doesn't need a paIace!
He doesn't need cypress trees
or dead animals!
He doesn't need shekeIs!
You expect peopIe to pay the tax
with Roman coins?
They have images
of faIse gods on them.
You want pagan gods in the temple?
All foreign coins have to be
exchanged for shekeIs.
- That is the law.
- I'm throwing away the law.
- I have a new law and a new hope.
- What?
Has God changed his mind
about the old law?
No. No, He just thinks our hearts
are ready to hoId more, that's all.
This chaos is your new law.
How can you presume -
How can l presume?
Because I'm the end of the old law...
and the beginning of the new one!
- Watch what you're saying.
- Maybe we should go.
When I say "I", Rabbi,
l'm saying God.
That's blasphemy.
Didn't they telI you?
l'm the saint of bIasphemy.
Don't make any mistakes.
l didn't come here to bring peace.
l came to bring a sword.
- Talking like that wilI get you killed.
- Me killed?
Listen to me. This temple will be
destroyed in three days.
Torn down to the ground!
There won't be one stone
left to build with!
You think God belongs
onIy to you? He doesn't.
God's an immortaI spirit
who belongs to everybody!
To the whole world!
You think you're special?
God is not an IsraeIite!
[ Crowd Chattering ]
[ Shouting, Arguing ]
- Magician, heal me.
- Cure us. Make us rich.
HeaI me. Do a miracle. You want me to
enter the world of God crippled like this?
Don't touch me! You're fiIled with hate!
Get away! God won't help you.
- You cure us, or you won't leave this city alive.
- [ Grunting ]
You don't make demands on God!
[ Shouting Continues ]
Judas, what are you doing
with this magician?
You had orders to kilI him,
and you haven't done it.
Now he acts like a prophet,
and you follow him.
[ Panting ]
Did you hear what he said back there, Saul?
Yes, l heard him.
We took an oath against Rome.
l don't see anything against Rome around here?
AlI l see are Jews against Jews.
Then you're not listening.
[ Saul ]
Lazarus.
Lazarus!
How do you feel?
l Iike the light.
Well, what was it like?
Which is better, death or life?
l was a little surprised.
There wasn't that much difference.
Give me your hand.
[ Judas ] l'm not surprised.
How could they let Lazarus live?
He was proof of your greatest miracle.
Now he's gone. There's no more proof.
That's what the Zealots want.
Their revolution, not yours.
- Do you want to go back to them?
- No.
You're the one l follow.
You are the strongest, aren't you?
Of all my friends,
you're the strongest.
Judas, my brother...
l have something to telI you.
l have a terrible secret from God.
- You know why l came to Jerusalem?
- Yes.
This is where the revolution's
going to begin.
Last night, lsaiah came to me.
He had a prophecy.
l saw it written.
It said...
"He has borne our fauIts;
he was wounded
for our transgressions...
yet he opened not his mouth.
Despised and rejected by aIl...
he went forward without resisting,
Iike a lamb led to the slaughter."
Mmm.
l don't understand.
[ Chuckles ]
Judas, I am the lamb.
- I'm the one who's going to die.
- Die?
- You mean you're not the Messiah?
- I am.
That can't be. lf you're the Messiah,
why do you have to die?
Listen. At first,
l didn't understand myself.
No, you listen! Every day,
you have a different plan.
First it's love, then it's the ax,
and now you have to die.
- What good could that do?
- I can't help it.
God only taIks to me a little at a time.
He only tells me as much
as l need to know.
- We need you alive!
- Now l finally understand.
All my life - All my life
l've been followed...
by voices...
by footsteps, by shadows.
And do you know
what the shadow is?
The cross.
l have to die on the cross,
and I have to die willingly.
We have to go back to the temple.
And after you die on the cross,
what happens then?
l come back to judge
the Iiving and the dead.
l don't believe you.
You have to.
l'm worried he's gonna
change his mind again.
No, he won't. This time we're not
going to the tempIe to pray.
He said he'll destroy the temple
in three days, and he'll do it.
And what if he doesn't?
- Then?
- What if he doesn't?
You won't have anything to worry about,
'cause we'Il alI be dead.
We're setting up a new government.
We're building a new JerusaIem.
We can ask for anything we want.
First, l'd like more sheep.
You know, my other sheep,
l don't even know where they are now.
This time, l want a large herd, and l'll get
other shepherds to take care of 'em.
l wouId just like to be able
to worship in the temple.
I mean really worship...
without Roman banners and soIdiers.
- That's what l'd like.
- Of course. But what eIse?
l'll do anything the master asks.
Anything but get crucified.
- You're a coward, Τhomas.
- Yes, I am. You know why?
You ever seen anybody hanging
on a cross after two days?
You know what they look like?
They don't even have eyes.
The crows come
and suck out your eyes.
And after that, you know what?
Dogs come and rip your feet off.
Don't talk that way.
l've made my decision.
You make yours.
And if you can't, then get out now,
before we get to Jerusalem.
l'm ready.
l have my knife.
Master, l've been taIking with
the others and, uh, listening and -
Some of them wanted me
to ask you...
will there be angels there
to meet us?
Or anyone besides who's here?
Master?
♪♪ [ People Chanting, Cheering ]
King of the Jews!
[ People Shouting, Cheering ]
[ Cheering Continues ]
King of the Jews!
Jesus!
- Jesus!
- [ Screaming ]
[ Shouting ]
Lord, l hope this is what You want.
Let me die here. PIease Iet it
happen fast whiIe l have the strength.
Go! I'm here to set fire
to the world!
ln the desert, the Baptist
warned us God is coming!
Well, l'm telIing you it's too late.
He's already here!
l'm here!
And l'm going to baptize
everybody... with fire!
[ Crowd Shouting ]
He's leading us.
Follow him!
They're alI with you.
They're waiting for your signal. Give it.
Now. Do it now.
Please. l'm waiting too.
Give me an ax, not the cross.
Let me die like this.
lf you don't give the sign now,
we're finished. They'll kiIl us for this.
- We came to fight, not to die!
- Master, we knew it would be like this.
This is the way. Do it.
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Weakly ]
Judas, help me.
Stay with me.
Don't leave me.
[ Angry Shouting ]
- [ People Shouting ]
- [ Woman Screaming ]
[ Jesus Panting ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
l wish there was another way.
l'm sorry, but there isn't.
l have to die on the cross.
- l won't let you die.
- You have no choice. Neither do l.
Remember, we're bringing
God and man together.
They'll never be together unless I die.
l'm the sacrifice.
Without you, there can be no redemption.
Forget everything else.
- Understand that.
- No, I can't.
Get somebody stronger.
You promised me.
Remember, you once told me...
that if l moved one step
from revolution, you'd kiIl me.
Remember?
- Yes.
- I've strayed, haven't l?
Yes.
Then you must keep your promise.
You have to kill me.
If that's what God wants,
then Iet God do it. I won't.
He will do it... through you.
The tempIe guards wiIl be looking for me
where there aren't any crowds.
We'll go to Gethsemane.
You'lI make sure that they find me there.
No.
- I am going to die.
- [ Sighs ]
But after three days...
l'll come back... in victory.
You can't leave me.
You have to give me strength.
lf you were me,
could you betray your master?
No.
That's why God gave me
the easier job...
to be crucified.
[ Sobbing ]
What about the others?
l'll tell them tonight.
[ Horn Blaring ]
♪♪ [ lnstrumental FoIk ]
♪♪ [ People Singing ]
[ Bleating ]
[ Sheep BIeating, Gurgling ]
♪♪ [ Singing Continues ]
Listen to me.
Take this bread.
Share it together.
This bread is my body.
Now drink this wine.
Pass the cup.
This wine is my blood.
Do this to remember me.
- We're not finished.
- Let him go.
All of you...
l want to tell you something.
[ Jesus ]
Wait for me here.
Father in heaven.
Father on Earth.
The world...
that You've created
that we can see is beautiful.
But the worId that You've created
that we can't see is beautiful too.
l don't know. l'm sorry, Father.
l don't know which is more beautiful.
This is my body too.
Together...
we're going to die.
[ Crying ]
Oh, please, Father.
l've been with You for so long.
l never asked You to choose me.
l aIways did as You said.
You made many miracIes for others.
You opened the Red Sea for Moses.
You saved Noah.
You took Elijah to heaven
in a fiery chariot...
and now You're asking me
to be crucified.
[ Sobbing ]
Can l ask You...
one last time?
Do l have to die?
ls there any other way?
You're offering me a cup,
but l don't want to drink what's in it.
Please, take it away.
Please, stop.
[ Sobs ]
Please, Father, Father.
Please.
[ Breathing HeaviIy ]
[ Wind Blowing ]
ls this your answer?
All right.
Just please give me the strength.
CouIdn't you stay awake with me
for just an hour?
- l'm sorry.
- [ Guards Shouting ]
lt doesn't matter.
- It's too late.
- [ Nightingale Chirping ]
Welcome, Rabbi.
[ Screams ]
No. You live by this,
you die by it.
[ Guard Groaning ]
Take me with you.
l'm ready.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
So, you are the King of the Jews.
[ Jesus ]
"King" is your word.
- WeIl, you are Jesus of Nazareth, aren't you?
- Yes, l am.
Well, that's what they're saying you are -
the King, the Messiah.
[ Horse Whinnies ]
lt's aIso said that you do miracIes.
ls this good magic or bad magic?
CouId we have some kind
of a... demonstration?
l mean, can you do a trick
for me now, say?
No.
l'm not a trained animal.
l'm not a magician.
Well...
that's disappointing.
This means that you're
just another Jewish politician.
Do you want to know something?
You're more dangerous than the ZeaIots.
Do you know that?
[ Horse Whinnies ]
Say something.
You had better say something.
All right.
Tell me what you tell people
on the streets.
Yes?
Yes.
The prophet Daniel had a vision.
A tall statue had a gold head
and silver shoulders.
The stomach was bronze,
the Iegs were iron, the feet were cIay.
A stone was thrown.
The clay feet broke,
and the statue colIapsed.
Yes?
You see, God threw the stone.
The stone's me, and Rome -
Rome is the statue, yes.
So your kingdom, or your world...
will replace Rome.
- Where is it?
- My kingdom?
lt's not here.
Not on Earth.
lt wouldn't be, would it?
You know, it's one thing to want
to change the way that people live...
but you want to change
how they think and how they feel.
AlI l'm saying is that change
will happen with love, not with kiIling.
Either way, it's dangerous.
lt's against Rome.
lt's against the way the world is.
And kilIing or loving,
it's alI the same.
It simply doesn't matter how you want to
change things. We don't want them changed.
You do understand
what has to happen.
We have a space for you
up on Golgotha.
Three thousand skulls there by now -
probably more.
[ Horse Trotting, Whinnying ]
Guard.
l do wish you peopIe would go out
and count them sometime.
Maybe you'd learn a lesson.
No. ProbabIy not.
[ Groaning ]
[ Groaning Continues ]
[ All Shouting ]
[ Man ]
l know you!
l saw you with him!
You must be mistaken. It wasn't me.
It must've been someone eIse.
No, l'm right.
He is one of his foIlowers.
- He is one of his followers!
- He doesn't know what he's talking about!
- I don't know what you're talking about!
- lt's him! Get him!
- [ PeopIe Shouting ]
Hold it there.
[ Jesus ]
Mother, Magdalene...
where are you?
Mother, I'm sorry
for being a bad son.
Father, stay with me.
Don't leave me.
[ Screaming ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Pounding Continues ]
[ All Shouting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Shouting Continues ]
[ Panting ]
[ Groaning ]
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Laughing, Chattering ]
[ Speaking Hebrew ]
[ Chattering Continues ]
Father, forgive them.
[ Rumbling ]
[ All Shouting ]
[ Thunder Rumbling ]
[ Wind Howling ]
Father!
Why have You forsaken me?
[ ThundercIaps Crashing ]
[ Wind, Thunder Fade ]
[ No Audible Sounds ]
Who are you?
l'm the angel who guards you.
Your father is the God of mercy,
not punishment.
He saw you and said...
"Aren't you his guardian angel?
Well, go down and save him.
He's suffered enough."
Remember when He told Abraham
to sacrifice his son?
Abraham was just about to kill the boy
with his knife when God stopped him.
So if He saved Abraham's son...
don't you think He'd want
to save his own?
He's tested you,
and He's happy with you.
He doesn't want your blood.
He said,
"Let him die in a dream...
but Iet him live his life."
All the pain.
- That was real.
- Yes.
But there won't be any more.
You've done enough.
[ No Sounds ]
l don't have to be sacrificed?
No. No, you don't.
l'm not the Messiah?
No. No, you're not.
What about the others?
Don't look back there.
God gave you life.
Look ahead.
Where are the discipIes?
They became frightened
and ran away.
[ Jesus ] ls this the world of God,
the one l spoke about?
[ Chuckles ]
No, this is Earth.
- Why has it changed so much?
- It hasn't changed. You have.
Now you can see its reaI beauty.
Harmony between Earth and the heart -
that's the worId of God.
Maybe you'Il find this
hard to beIieve...
but sometimes we angeIs
Iook down on men and envy you.
Really envy you.
What's that?
A wedding ceremony.
Who's getting married?
You are.
[ Weeping QuietIy ]
What's wrong?
Why are you crying?
l'm thanking God...
for bringing you here.
[ Sobs ]
- We could have a child.
- Yes.
[ Whispers ]
Oh, we could have a child.
Yes.
[ Wind Whistling ]
[ Wind Howling ]
[ Door Opens ]
[ Bird Screeches ]
[ Sobbing ]
Magdalene.
Where are you going?
Who are you going to kill, Jesus?
God? Are you going to kilI God?
Didn't you hear me, Jesus?
There is nothing you can do.
God kilIed her!
God's kilIed her.
[ Shouting ]
Oh, God!
[ Panting ]
[ Groans ]
[ Grunts ]
God took her away
when she was happy.
Now she's immortal.
She won't see her love die
or body decay.
l was there the whole time
He was kiIling her...
and l saw what happened.
But it wasn't right.
It wasn't right
for God to take her.
You didn't compIain
when God let you live.
You can't complain now
because He Iet her die.
Trust God's way.
Listen.
There's only one woman in the world.
One woman with many faces.
This one falIs, the next one rises.
Mary Magdalene died.
But Mary, Lazarus's sister -
she lives.
She's Magdalene with a different face.
She's carrying your greatest joy inside her.
Your son.
Come with me.
[ AngeI ]
This is the way the Savior comes.
Gradually...
from embrace to embrace...
from son to son.
This is the road.
[ Jesus ]
I understand.
Mary.
Look.
Rabbi, l just want to see
if it's really you.
He's real, Iike us.
Don't you see?
Come in.
Come here.
Master, l want to teIl you one thing.
l'm sorry about Magdalene.
l won't ever leave you alone again.
l'll aIways protect you.
l don't want you to take
the wrong road and get lost again.
Come inside.
l'll cook for you and your friend.
[ Chopping ]
Are you satisfied with me?
Do you have any complaints?
None.
l'm ashamed when I think of it.
Of what?
Of all the mistakes l've made.
Of all the wrong ways
I'd looked for God.
Where's Mary?
She won't be back till this evening.
Come inside.
lt's too hot out here.
There's only one woman in the world.
Go inside.
[ Woman Giggling ]
Well, we bought them -
- Hey! What -
- You don't have to get invoIved.
- Come on. Stay out of it.
- [ Children Giggling ]
[ Man ]
And l thought of stealing wheat.
We are dying.
So l intensified my efforts -
- Here, watch your brother.
- [ Murmurs ]
Remember to thank God for the food,
and leave some for me.
- l'lI be back soon.
- Aren't you going to eat?
- I want to hear what he's saying.
- You don't have to go there.
[ Man ]
l was one of the worst sinners.
l Iied, l stole, l cheated...
l gambled, l whored, I drank...
and persecuted, tortured and murdered.
Yes, murdered!
l kilIed anyone
who broke the law of Moses...
and l loved it.
l enjoyed it. l relished it.
l reveled in it.
Because l thought
l was doing God's will!
l thought l was doing God's will.
And the high priest of Jerusalem
sent me to the city of Damascus...
to scourge that city.
And on the road to Damascus,
just outside the city, in the middIe of the day...
l was struck by a white light...
that bIinded me!
Yes.
And l heard a voice say...
"SauI, why are you persecuting me?
Why are you against me?"
'¤ho are you?" l said.
And the voice said, "Jesus."
And he made me see.
l was led helpIess, like a child,
into a city that l was sent to scourge...
and God sent me Ananias instead.
And he put his hands on me,
and l opened my eyes...
and l was baptized and became Paul.
And now l bring the good news to you.
And it's about Jesus of Nazareth.
He was not the son of Mary.
He was the Son of God!
His mother was a virgin.
And the Angel Gabriel came down
and put God's seed in her womb.
That's how he was born.
And he was punished for our sins.
Our sins!
Then he was tortured and crucified!
But three days later...
he rose up from the dead
and went up to heaven.
Death was conquered.
Amen.
Do you understand what that means?
He conquered death!
All of our sins were forgiven...
and now the worId of God
is open to every one of us...
to everybody!
Did you ever see this Jesus of Nazareth
after he came back from the dead?
l mean, with your own eyes?
No, but l saw a Iight that blinded me,
and l heard his voice.
- You're a liar.
- His disciples saw him.
They were hiding in an attic
with the doors Iocked...
and he appeared to them.
Liar. He's a liar.
Wait a minute.
l wanna talk to you.
l was never crucified.
l never came back from the dead.
- I'm a man, like everybody eIse.
- Quiet!
- Why are you teIling these lies?
- What are you talking about?
¤¤ the son of Mary and Joseph.
l'm the one who preached in GaIilee.
l had followers.
We marched on Jerusalem.
- Pilate condemned me, and God saved me.
- No, He didn't.
Who are you talking about?
Don't try and tell me
what happened to me, because l know.
I live Iike a man now.
l work, eat, have chiIdren.
l enjoy my life.
For the first time, I'm enjoying it.
Do you understand what l'm saying?
So don't go around telling lies about me,
or I'Il telI everybody the truth!
Just a minute.
What's the matter with you?
Look around you.
Look at aIl these people.
Look at their faces.
Do you see how unhappy they are?
Do you see how much they're suffering?
Their only hope is the resurrected Jesus.
l don't care whether you're Jesus or not.
The resurrected Jesus wilI save the world,
and that's what matters.
Those are lies.
You can't save the world by lying.
l created the truth out of what people
needed and what they believed.
lf l have to crucify you to save
the world, then l'll crucify you.
And if l have to resurrect you,
then l'll do that too, whether you like it or not.
- I won't let you. l'lI tell everyone the truth.
- [ ChuckIes ]
Go ahead. Go on.
Tell them now.
Who's going to beIieve you?
You started alI this.
Now you can't stop it.
All those people who believe me
wilI grab you and kiIl you.
- No, that wouIdn't happen.
- How do you know?
You see, you don't know
how much people need God.
You don't know how happy
He can make them.
He can make them happy
to do anything.
He can make them happy to die,
and they'Il die.
All for the sake of Christ.
Jesus Christ.
Jesus of Nazareth.
The Son of God.
The Messiah.
Not you.
Not for your sake.
You know, l'm glad l met you...
because now l can forget
all about you.
My Jesus is much more important
and much more powerfuI.
Thank you.
lt's a good thing l met you.
Don't ever leave me.
l'm happy here.
l remember when Mary and l
planted these vines.
You know, this will aIl pass.
Why?
Are you Ieaving me?
We have to move on.
You've grown old.
You've done well.
We've both done well.
[ Women Screaming ]
Get inside! Get inside!
They're kilIing everyone!
Jerusalem is on fire!
lt's burning!
The Romans are kilIing everyone!
They're kiIling everyone!
- [ Flames Roaring ]
- [ People Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Door Opens ]
Get out of the way.
We were sent here.
God told us you would
show yourself to us.
Said you were dying.
Peter, is that you?
[ Sighs ]
l can't tell.
What happened to you?
l got old.
You got old.
[ Sighs ]
[ Jesus ]
Oh, this one l know.
No matter how oId you get,
I know you, Nathaniel.
You were the best shepherd,
because you had no sheep.
Oh, Rabbi.
l missed you.
[ Sighs ]
And you?
They cut you.
Your face.
- Who are you?
- Rabbi.
John.
The Romans tortured me.
They cut my face.
l tried to tell them all about you.
Then l saw Jerusalem burn.
l even saw the Ark of the Covenant
stolen from the tempIe.
They destroyed the temple,
just like you said.
The Ark?
[ Peter ]
There's someone else outside.
[ NathanieI ]
Be careful. He's stiIl angry.
[ Jesus ]
Judas.
Judas, come in.
[ Sighs ]
Didn't you hear me?
Oh, I missed you so much.
He hears you.
He just won't say anything.
[ John ]
He's been fighting in Jerusalem.
Look at his hands.
There's still blood on them.
Judas, the master is speaking to you.
Answer him.
Traitor!
[ Sighs ]
Your place was on the cross.
That's where God put you.
When death got too cIose,
you got scared and you ran away...
and hid yourself
in the life of some man.
We did what we were
supposed to do. You didn't.
You're a coward!
- Don't you have any respect?
- For him?
You don't understand.
[ Judas ]
Understand?
Rabbi.
[ ThundercIap ]
You broke my heart.
Sometimes l curse the day
l ever met you.
We held the world in our hands.
Remember what you told me?
You took me in your arms -
[ Whispers ]
Do you remember?
And you begged me,
"Betray me. Betray me.
l have to be crucified.
l have to be resurrected
so I can save the world.
l am the lamb," you said.
"Death is the door.
Judas, my brother, don't be afraid.
HeIp me go through the door."
And l loved you so much...
l went and betrayed you.
[ Sighs ]
And you -
You -
What are you doing here?
What business do you have here
with women, with children?
What's good for a man
isn't good for God.
Why weren't you crucified?
Look at his wounds, Judas.
They're bleeding.
You're hurting him.
That's enough.
[ Judas ]
He was going to be the New Covenant.
- Now there's no more lsrael.
- No.
No. You don't understand.
[ Sighs ]
The guardian angel.
God sent the guardian angel to save me.
Angel? What angel?
Look at her.
Satan.
[ Satan ]
l toId you we wouId meet again.
[ Judas ]
lf you die this way, you die like a man.
You turn against God, your father.
- [ Screaming, Faint ]
- There's no sacrifice. There's no salvation.
- [ FIames Roaring ]
- [ Screaming Continues ]
[ Satan ]
There's nothing you can do.
You Iived this Iife.
You accepted it.
It's over.
Just finish it. Die.
Die Iike a man.
[ Grunting ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
[ Panting ]
Father.
Will You Iisten to me?
Are You stilI there?
WilI You listen to a selfish
and unfaithfuI son?
l fought You when You called.
l resisted.
l thought I knew more.
l didn't want to be Your son.
Can You forgive me?
l didn't fight hard enough.
Father...
give me Your hand.
l want to bring salvation!
Father, take me back!
Make a feast!
Welcome me home!
l want to be Your son!
l want to pay the price!
l want to be crucified
and rise again!
I want to be the Messiah!
[ Crowd Shouting ]
- [ Groaning ]
- [ Shouting Continues ]
[ Man Screaming ]
[ Screaming Continues ]
lt is accomplished!
lt is accomplished.