Use the free code JOINNOW at
www.playships.eu
DIGITALLY RESTORED IN 2015
SHAME
You know...
I had the strangest dream
last night.
Know what I dreamed?
We were back with the philharmonic,
sitting side by side,
rehearsing the fourth
Brandenburg Concerto, the Largo.
And everything happening now
was behind us, like a bad dream.
I woke up crying.
I'd started crying
while we were playing.
It was the slow movement.
You know the one...
Aren't you going
to shave today either?
If you insist.
- Why are you in a bad mood?
- I'm not.
You're always
in a foul mood these days.
Go get dressed
or we'll miss the ferry.
We have to be
at the mayor's by 9:00.
That's hardly my fault.
I didn't start this damned war.
Listen...
maybe we could afford
a bottle of wine?
What do you say, Eva?
You're so silly.
Go get dressed.
I think I'm getting a wisdom tooth.
Is that dentist still around?
- We'll find out.
Wisdom teeth can be nasty.
I had one up here on the right.
The dentist had to extract it
piece by piece.
Took a whole day.
No anesthetic either.
I had a fever
for weeks afterwards.
I hope this one isn't as bad.
That would be nice.
Can you see anything?
No, not a thing.
Feel here. It feels swollen.
And there's a lump.
I guess we'd better hurry.
Did you pay the phone bill?
Shit! I forgot.
But why pay for something
that never works anyway?
They'd better fix the darn thing...
or I shouldn't have to pay.
- We have to have a phone.
- Of course.
But we don't get a lot of orders.
With no phone
we might as well pack it all in.
People could call the Olssons,
and we could pay them.
You hear the church bells?
Is it a holiday?
No, just an ordinary Friday.
What could it mean?
- Nothing. Hurry up, now.
It's ominous hearing church bells
on an ordinary day.
What time is it?
- Five past 6:00.
I think it's going to rain.
Go get your leather jacket.
Oh, for God's sake!
Jan?
What is it now?
You mustn't be so sensitive.
I can't take it.
Try to control yourself. I do.
Can't you ever shut up?
I'm sorry.
I forgot my jacket after all.
There sure have been
a lot of transports lately.
I didn't mean to be nasty.
It just happened.
Don't worry.
I give as good as I get.
You know what?
Tomorrow it will be four years
since we moved to this island.
And Grandpa died
a year ago yesterday.
We mustn't forget
to go put flowers on his grave.
Hi there, Filip!
What were you talking about?
He said the radio warned
of an impending invasion.
They've been saying that
for years.
- Our radio's always acting up!
- Not to mention the car.
If you didn't insist
on fixing things yourself...
It's better not to know anything.
God, your escapism drives me mad!
But I wasn't going to nag.
I got us some fish for dinner.
- That's good.
As you stood talking to Filip,
I felt really in love with you.
You looked so beautiful.
From a distance, right?
Good morning.
We were just coming to see you!
Really? Nice to see you.
We have some berries for you.
Morning.
We have lingonberries for you.
- Hello, Mrs. Rosenberg.
We just went out to check
on the summer cottage.
I was just telling the mayor we have
delicious lingonberries for you.
I'm afraid we're not
headed home just now...
- We'll drop them at your place.
- Sure it's no bother?
No bother at all.
- Is anyone at home?
- Miss Almberg should be there.
Why don't we get together for dinner
and make some music together
like in the old days?
I've missed our soirees.
We both have.
Ever since our conductor,
Mr. Kreisler, was drafted.
Mayor, may I ask you something?
Are these troop movements
significant?
The situation has become
more critical lately.
You hear so much on the radio...
Our radio's always broken!
I think you have
to hope for the best.
You never know what's in store.
My sister was evacuated
to a transit camp,
and they're bombed almost daily.
I think we're almost there.
We better say good-bye.
It would be great to see you.
- Give us a call.
Good-bye.
Give our best to your son.
- Thank you. We will.
- Can we go in the main entrance?
- Of course.
They gave us an extra ten kronor!
Let's get some wine at Fredrik's.
I guess he's out.
He never goes out.
Hi!
Have you been drafted too?
Yeah, just look at this getup.
And I haven't handled
a weapon in over 20 years.
Have a seat.
And I have no one
to look after the shop either.
Not that it makes
much difference.
How can I help you?
- We'd like a bottle of wine.
I have a few bottles left.
Listen, I want
to show you something.
You have to see this.
- Look at that!
- The finest piece I own.
- An antique, right?
- Meissen, 18th century.
- Where did you get it?
- My mother left it to me.
I'll never sell it.
Listen to that.
I'll be right back.
- Do you listen to the radio?
- No, ours never works.
I can't seem to fix it.
Yesterday our side
threatened to take
the most atrocious measures.
And today
the other side congratulated us
on our imminent destruction.
We've heard it all before.
I suspect we needn't
take it too seriously.
Wait a minute!
Taste this. It's quite good.
But we came to buy a bottle.
It's not bad at all.
Cheers.
- That's delicious.
- It really is.
May I have a look?
- I have just five bottles left.
- Look at that.
From 1959.
- Could we really afford a bottle?
- Sure.
Cheers.
You know, sometimes
when I sit here all alone
among my things...
I start feeling so miserable.
I'm not sure why.
Maybe because no one
would miss me if I were gone.
Not even Mrs. Prins.
- Mrs. Prins?
The lady who cleans for me.
Once a week she cleans the place
and makes coffee...
and we sleep together.
No, Mrs. Prins
won't particularly miss me.
You'll be back before you know it.
How much for a bottle?
For you, ten kronor.
I'd give it to you...
but I need the money.
To pay Mrs. Prins, in fact.
She's going to look
after my things while I'm gone.
Well, we have to catch the ferry.
You know, I have a bad foot.
You think they'll take that
into account
and give me
an administrative job?
Of course they will.
They didn't want me at all!
- Enough about you.
You have to show good faith
and not hide behind
a doctor's certificate.
But you have to tell them.
Maybe they'll send you home.
Thanks so much.
- See you soon.
- I hope so.
Well, good-bye.
Thank you. Good-bye.
I think we should drink
to Filip and his fish.
- And my cooking.
- And your cooking.
By the way,
the radio's working again.
- You fixed it?
- Yes, finally.
- Aren't you clever!
- I am, huh?
- When you want to be.
- I'm always clever.
Know what I'm going to do?
I'm pretty clever too.
I know you are.
- Take up Italian again.
- Finally!
- Starting tonight.
- You've talked about it for ages.
But I need your help.
You have to tell me
every night to study.
I'll time you and quiz you,
and I'll be very strict.
You know what else
we should do every morning?
Right after feeding the chickens,
we should practice our instruments.
You, that early?
This I'll have to see!
I swear I will!
A half hour every day.
We have our instruments
and tons of sheet music.
We have to keep up our skills.
Jan, I want children.
I really want to have children.
- Right now?
- No, not quite yet.
- Why?
It's not something
one can explain.
Try.
It's this feeling that...
Let's wait until things calm down.
No, I think this is important.
A lot of the problems
between us
might be because
we don't have kids.
Me being a woman
and not having kids.
I'd like to have kids before I'm 30.
You can wait till 40.
No, the younger, the better.
By 40 I want three kids.
We'll be a family.
Listen, this is serious,
what I have to say.
You mustn't get upset.
- I won't.
The next time we go into town,
I want us to go to a doctor...
Why?
...and get a checkup,
since I never seem to get pregnant.
I'm perfectly healthy.
So am I. We both are.
It's probably just your nerves.
- I mean it.
I want us to go
so you can get a checkup.
Don't take it personally.
That time we separated
for a while...
You were up to all sorts of stuff.
I didn't do anything.
That could be
why we don't get pregnant.
Because you had
lots of other women.
I did not.
Why bring that up?
It meant nothing.
You're the one I've always loved.
- What about that opera singer?
- She meant nothing.
It was just that one time.
I've always loved you.
I love you right now.
I'm not sure
you know what love is.
I certainly do.
Self-love.
You know a lot about that.
I'm not as selfish as you think.
I think you're very selfish.
I'll be a better man next year.
Next week!
- Is that right?
- I promise.
I believe one can change
completely if one wants to.
- You?
- Yes.
I'm not a determinist, you know.
- A what?
- A determinist.
What's a determinist?
A determinist is a person who...
Never mind.
Just so you fix the sink tomorrow.
Let's not do the dishes now.
No? What should we do instead?
- Where are you going?
- He'll die hanging up there!
- It could be the enemy.
- You coward!
- Stay here. You're not going.
- He's caught in the trees!
You're not going...
Then go!
I'll go call an ambulance!
- Did one or two men bail out?
- We only saw one. Right?
- Did you shoot the pilot?
- Was I supposed to?
No, I guess it wasn't you.
I suggest you clear out.
They dropped paratroopers
just half a mile from here.
I know what we'll do.
I'll put it in gear, and you push.
It's downhill anyway.
What are you doing?
Hurry up! Come on!
- You shot the pilot, didn't you?
- No, I didn't!
Lying will only make it worse.
He was dying when we got there.
Isn't that right?
- Yes!
Have other soldiers been here?
Yes, about 30 minutes ago.
They warned us
that you'd landed nearby.
They were in two jeeps,
about 14 of them.
They told us to clear out
and headed for the shore.
Just calm down.
Breathe! Don't be afraid.
Is that mic and camera ready?
Come on.
We'll just chat a bit
for the folks at home.
Why are you resisting?
We want to show the folks
what sort of people we've liberated.
Camera.
"Voices of the Liberation 78."
Hand me the mic.
Your name?
Speak up. Don't be afraid.
Eva Rosenberg.
Tell us about yourself.
I'm 28.
I'm first violinist
in the philharmonic.
Jan and I have been married
for seven years.
We've lived here
since the orchestra was disbanded.
Tell us more.
There isn't any more.
What's your political affiliation?
- I don't have one.
- No political affiliation?
I don't really have the time,
and our radio's broken.
Don't you care
what political regime governs you?
It's not that.
It's just that the war has gone on
so long that it's hard to...
- So you're not indifferent?
- No!
- You've taken a stand?
- Yes.
Good. Excellent.
And your name?
I'm not feeling well.
I have a weak heart.
He isn't well.
Jan, wait a minute.
Keep rolling!
Get him passing out.
Come on.
Quick, Jan.
Let's get inside.
Help me out here.
Please help me, Jan.
You know what I was thinking
the whole time?
No.
It's good we don't have kids.
We'll have kids when peace comes.
We'll never have kids.
Jan, grab your boots and let's go!
We have to hurry.
Come on!
- We'll head for the shore.
- Fine. As long as you drive.
Hurry!
- What about food?
- I didn't have time to cook!
Let's take the chickens.
- Who's going to wring their necks?
- Not me!
We'll shoot them.
You ever hear
of shooting chickens?
- I refuse to wring their necks.
- Fine, shoot them!
Do whatever you want.
Not me!
It's still standing there.
Shoot the damned thing!
- I can't do it.
I'm so sick of you!
Eva, come!
We have to head back!
Jan, drive us home!
Pull yourself together!
It sounds like...
It's sounds like
they're at the crossroads.
This god-awful noise!
I can't stand it!
I can't take it anymore!
Maybe we'd be safer
in the basement.
I won't be trapped like a rat!
Did I ever tell you about Pampini?
No.
He was a contemporary
of Beethoven's.
He made instruments in Vienna.
Trained in the Italian school.
He served in the Russian army
and fought Napoleon for many years.
Then he lost a leg
and went back to making violins.
This one was made in 1814,
same year
as the Congress of Vienna.
He died of cholera.
I forget what year.
My hand is ruined.
You want to try?
Do you care for me a little?
Yes, I care for you a little.
Do you love me?
Do you?
Sure, I love you.
What is it?
What's wrong?
- I got a cramp.
There.
It's letting up.
Hang on.
Jan.
Get over here.
Stop right there.
- I have to close up the store.
- Hurry up!
I'm Filip Olsson.
Take them inside.
Move it!
Everyone inside!
Sit them down over there.
Would you like to sit together?
- My name's Oswald.
- Rosenberg.
We've met, actually.
The charity concert a few years back.
Of course.
I'm a teacher... or I was.
It doesn't look good.
You know...
sometimes this is all like a dream.
Not my own.
Someone else's dream
that I'm forced to be in.
What happens when they wake up
and feel ashamed about all this?
Jan and Eva Rosenberg.
I see.
We have reason to believe
you've collaborated
with the other side.
The most serious evidence
is Mrs. Rosenberg's TV interview
in which she endorses
the political views of the enemy.
- That's not true.
- Not true?
We happen to have
a copy of the interview.
Would you care to see it?
Lights out.
We've been oppressed
for far too long.
We've longed for liberation
like those thirsting in the desert.
I wish your troops victory.
That wasn't my voice!
I never said that.
Tell the truth now,
or you and your husband will pay!
We never collaborated.
How do you explain the fact
that paratroopers liquidated
every civilian
within almost two square miles
yet spared the two of you?
I don't know.
I don't understand any of this.
Take her out.
I want to speak to him alone.
No! Let me go!
Hello again, Mrs. Rosenberg.
Sit down.
What did they do to you?
Let me see.
Doctor, please.
Can you stand up?
Nothing wrong with you.
Your limbs are intact.
You look dreadful. Stand up.
He'll have to go to the hospital.
What about you?
How are you doing?
Your shoulder's been dislocated.
Give me a hand.
We'll pop it back in place.
No, don't!
No tennis for a few weeks.
What do we have here?
Is he asleep?
Take him away.
He can't lie here rotting.
Have they fed you at all?
- No.
Sorry about that.
We're not yet properly organized.
I'll have them send in some food.
And the lady?
Is anything ailing her?
Nothing? Good.
Cigarette?
Good evening.
Was the man they carried out dead?
Who was that?
- The editor of the local paper.
- Really?
A false rumor went around saying
the invasion had been a success.
So they made up a front page
welcoming the liberation forces.
- What about you, Vicar?
- They treated me humanely.
They let me go
once I started screaming.
Almost as if
they were embarrassed.
Well, they certainly beat me!
They hit me on the head.
- Where? I don't see anything.
The gray-haired guy said...
"This is for that TV segment."
How many are in here?
Oh, there are three of you.
I'll be back with one more.
- Need some help?
- No, I'm fine.
I'll hold it.
- I'm just a bit stiff.
- I can imagine.
That's fine, thanks.
It looked painful.
I'm fine.
Does it hurt?
It's more of a throbbing now.
Report to the courtyard!
Fall in!
Order arms!
Hurry up!
This man collaborated
with the enemy
and caused us heavy losses.
But the government
has pardoned him
and commuted his death sentence
to life at hard labor.
The rest of you will also receive
more leniency than you deserve.
Some of you
will be freed immediately
and transported home.
Take these two to my office.
May we please sit down?
Hell no.
If Jacobi saw you,
he'd have my hide.
What will happen now?
Come inside.
Have a seat.
I heard about
the infamous interview.
We knew it was a complete fake...
but they needed someone
to make an example of.
Are you all right?
No serious injuries?
I gave orders not to touch you.
- They behaved... almost correctly.
- That's something at least.
I hope we'll meet again soon
and have a chance to talk.
Where the hell are those drivers?
I assume
you're anxious to get home.
Things better shape up
around here come Monday!
I'm trying to get a car
to spare you the jeep.
Jacobi here.
Please send a car here at once.
Peters, make sure they get home
as quickly as possible.
Good-bye.
I'm sick of this.
You keep on if you want.
Playing the martyr, huh?
All sanctimonious
and full of hate.
It's funny.
As long as there was a war,
we were relatively decent
to each other.
I'm going in to hear the news.
You do that.
It'll be a relief not to see you.
Jacobi gave us that radio
and said it was important...
Then go listen to the damn thing
if it's so important!
Just the other day...
you said it was good
we had Jacobi as a friend.
- I said no such thing.
- You did too.
You were just too drunk
to remember it.
I'm going to ask Jacobi
to stop coming here.
Filip says it could
make things worse for us.
It's none of Filip's damn business
who comes here!
- Well, you're such a suck-up!
- You should talk.
I don't suck up.
You do too.
You're a suck-up.
Don't you dare call me that!
Suck-up, suck-up, suck-up!
When peace comes,
we're going our separate ways.
It will be heaven to get away
from you and your childishness.
You're not the only one
whose life has been ruined.
There are other people
in this world!
Stop grinning like that!
You're not as remarkable
as you think!
I'm sorry.
You say that,
but you don't mean it.
The words just fall
out of your mouth.
Can't we be friends?
- What day of the week is it?
- I don't know.
It's Saturday.
No, that was yesterday.
Today must be Sunday.
What time is it?
Must be that damned Jacobi.
Am I disturbing you?
Not at all.
I was on my way home
after a walk.
I thought I'd stop in,
if I'm not disturbing you.
No, we're just listening
to the radio.
My shoes are muddy.
Might Jan have some slippers
I could borrow?
These are soaking wet.
They should go by the fire.
Jan!
Jan Rosenberg,
where the hell are you?
I brought you a present, Jan,
a damn fine one:
Dvorak's Trio in E-flat Major.
An uncle left it to me.
- Thank you!
Perhaps we'll play it
together one day.
I have something
for you too, Eva.
I hope it's the right size.
It's an old family heirloom.
You really mustn't give us so much!
Hello, Jan.
Eva...
talk to me.
Say something.
My dear Eva, don't be sad.
Who was that?
A neighbor who gives us fish
now and then.
But I got the feeling...
- He's just a good friend.
He needed some kerosene.
Thanks for that whole drum,
by the way.
Those men are driven
by a terrible idealism.
And you're not?
Eva doesn't like me this evening.
If I asked her for a kiss,
she'd claim it would bother you.
But it wouldn't, would it?
You'll have to ask her.
How about a kiss?
You're so nice.
But you know you put us
in a difficult situation
by coming here so often?
I see.
You're telling me
you don't want me here.
Don't get Eva wrong.
All she meant was...
Too bad I happen
to like you two,
that we became friends
in spite of everything.
Otherwise I could have
sent you to a labor camp.
Jan Rosenberg, are you afraid?
- No.
- Are you an artist or a mouse?
- Oh, I'm a mouse...
The sacred freedom of art.
The sacred gutlessness of art.
I'm going out to take a piss.
God, I wish I could sober up!
That was too much.
We have to get rid of him.
That was
a nasty moment with Filip.
Did you know
that the woods are full of people?
I've often wondered
what they'll do to me.
The thought frightens me, I admit.
They have no reason to torture me.
I have no secret information.
But perhaps they just feel
like making me suffer.
Don't worry. I'm just kidding.
This part of the island
has been pacified.
Eva...
touch me.
No.
Touch my head.
There.
Can you feel that I'm here?
Touch my eyes.
Here.
Put your hand here.
Can you feel who I am?
- No.
Jan, take my hands.
You feel who I am?
- Of course, but...
It's odd, you see.
I've only felt close
to others a few times.
Always in connection with pain.
Is it the same for you two?
- No, it's not.
It's not something
you can talk about.
There's nothing to say,
nowhere to hide.
No excuses, no evasions.
Just great guilt, great pain...
and great fear.
Damn, it's cold.
- I think it's time you go home.
I feel the change in weather
in my bad leg.
Eva, come here.
I have something for you.
Here's 23,000 kronor.
I want you to have my life savings.
- I don't want your money.
- Don't be silly.
We'll consider it an inheritance.
My dear Eva...
can I talk to you?
I was at my son's place
a few days ago.
He's on leave...
and he has
a little boy of 19 months.
It was the boy's bedtime,
and his daddy was feeding him
pap from a big cup.
There he sat,
like a baby monkey,
cuddled up
in his father's great big body.
By the time he was full,
he was practically asleep.
Eva?
May I tell you something else?
My mother died a few years back.
She was old and had a bad heart.
I got a call one Sunday
saying she was very ill...
so I went to see her.
When I entered the living room,
the doctor approached me.
I asked him,
"May I go in to see my mother?"
He replied...
"Your mother just passed away."
I sat at her side for an hour,
looking at her.
She had a bandage
on her index finger.
At times I thought
I could hear her breathing.
There isn't much
that gets through.
You know why I took this job?
No.
I was given a choice...
and I was afraid
of going to the front.
Do you regret your decision?
No.
I've never been unfaithful
to Jan before.
Sometimes it frightens me
to think about it...
so I don't.
No, not here.
Come with me.
He's asleep.
I'll get your cane.
Cry if you think it will help.
Where did that money come from?
The yard's full of people.
We're going to have a talk.
All right!
Come in here a minute.
We've talked things over.
Filip says I can buy my freedom
because their organization
needs cash.
So I'm asking you, dear Eva:
Lend me the money I gave you.
Jan has it.
I don't know anything
about any money.
- You didn't take it?
- I don't know what you mean.
Tell your husband to hand it over.
Go get the money if you hid it.
It's not yours anyway.
I don't know what you're talking about.
We'll have to search the place.
Where's the money?
I don't know
what you're talking about!
Let's blow the joint sky-high!
Well?
- Where did you hide the money?
- I didn't.
Where is it?
Why didn't you hand over
the money?
- They'd have shot him anyway.
- That's not true.
Stop it.
Stop it!
Don't shoot. We're not armed.
Are you hungry?
We'll feed you.
Wait.
Did you desert?
Did you hurt your hand?
A dog bit me.
Shall I have a look?
Come sit down. I'll bandage it up.
Hang on.
I'll get you something to eat.
Want some?
Aren't you hungry?
- What's your name?
- Johan.
- Have you been hiding out long?
- A few weeks.
- You have a bandage on you?
- In my pocket.
I'll get it.
Is Hammars far from here?
- What will you do there?
- None of your business.
Are you tired?
Want to get some sleep?
Why did you run away?
A bunch of us ran off together.
I don't know
where the others went.
Have something to drink.
I haven't slept in days.
Tell us why
you're going to Hammars.
Leave him alone.
Let him sleep.
No, leave me alone!
Get up!
Leave me alone.
Leave me alone!
Just let me go!
Don't shoot!
You can have my shoes!
What did you do with him?
There's a fishing boat leaving
from Hammars tomorrow.
A friend who'd paid to be on it
told him about it.
That friend was shot
that same day.
What did you do to him?
These shoes will come in handy.
Mine are worn out.
What did you do to him?
I'm not going with you.
Easier that way.
Maybe we should bring some food.
Jan?
What will happen if we can never
talk to one another again?
The boat's here.
Is there room for me and Eva?
It'll cost you.
Will this do?
I had a dream.
I was walking
down a very beautiful street.
On one side were white houses
with towering arches and pillars.
On the other side was a leafy park.
Dark green water flowed
beneath the trees lining the street.
I came to a high wall...
overgrown with roses.
Then an airplane came
and set the roses on fire.
But it wasn't all that terrible,
because it was so beautiful.
I looked down into the water
and watched the roses burn.
I held a baby in my arms.
It was our daughter.
She snuggled up to me...
and I could feel her mouth...
against my cheek.
And the whole time I knew
there was something
I should remember...
something someone had said.
But I'd forgotten what it was...
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm