THE VIRGIN SPRING
Adapted from a 13th-century Ballad by
ULLA ISAKSSON
Cinematography by
SVEN NYKVIST
Directed by
INGMAR BERGMAN
Odin, come!
Come to my aid.
Heavenly Father, Son, and Holy Ghost,
with all your hosts of angels,
guard us this day and always
from the devil's snares.
Lord, let not temptation, shame...
nor danger befall
thy servants this day.
It's Friday,
the day of our Lord's agony.
So help me God,
I nearly stepped on them
out there in the dark.
You poor thing...
live out your wretched little life,
the way God allows all of us to live.
Where were you all night?
If you don't care where you sleep,
you could at least
come back for the milking.
I had to run around
on these poor legs.
Jesus and Mary, you're a sight!
What's wrong?
Nothing more than the usual...
that bastards beget bastards.
Serves you right,
the way you behave,
spitting and snarling
like a wildcat.
You should thank God
on your bare knees for his mercy.
To come to a farm like this
and stay in this house
like a child of the family.
But you are, and always will be,
a savage child.
The milk is still on the porch!
You'll have to ride to church
with the candles for the Virgin.
- Me?
- Yes.
- Isn't Karin to take them?
- Karin's not well today.
She'll sleep through morning mass
and then feel just fine.
I think she has a fever.
Her skin was so warm.
She certainly burned with fever
at the dance last night.
Watch your tongue!
I'm not afraid my daughter
will walk in your filthy footsteps.
You two have always been
as different as rose and thorn.
You've always pricked others
and made them suffer!
You can't help yourself.
We should throw you out, after
the mess you've gotten yourself into.
Lord, bless this,
our daily bread. Amen.
Where's Karin?
Shouldn't she be leaving
for church with the candles?
Karin's not feeling well today.
She didn't seem sick last night.
She's fond of sleeping away the morning.
Nevertheless, she's sick now.
She can't suddenly be so sick
that she can't ride to church.
Frida will have to take the candles.
You know tradition says
a virgin must take the candles.
You're always so concerned
with discipline and duty
when it comes to Karin.
And you're always so soft and weak
when it comes to her.
She's the only child I have left.
All the more reason
to raise her properly.
I had bad dreams last night.
You shouldn't practice
such harsh penance at night.
Now send Ingeri to wake Karin.
I'll go myself.
Yes, go and put some life
into that loafer.
Ingeri will have to prepare
a lunch for her.
Put some cheese
in the wheat cakes.
And some mutton too.
Are you sick, Karin?
No, not sick.
Just sleepy.
Can't I have
breakfast in bed today?
Father says you're to get up at once
and take the candles to church.
No.
If you're not well enough,
Frida has to go.
- I'm not sick.
- Then you have to go.
Then I want to wear
the yellow shift.
My child,
it's the middle of the week.
Then I won't go.
You're behaving like a little child.
If I'd used that tone of voice
with my parents at your age,
I'd have gotten a good thrashing
and nothing to eat.
Then give me a thrashing
Give me berries with my bread
instead of butter.
You know very well I can't be
hard on you, though I ought to be.
You laugh...
but Father's angry...
and one day
you'll bring shame down upon me.
Get out my yellow silk shift,
and my Sunday skirt
and blue cape.
Then I'll be happy,
and you'll be happy,
and Father as well.
Mother, I'll ride to church
with such dignity,
and Blackie will raise
his hooves gently,
like in a pilgrim's procession.
I'll look neither right nor left
but straight ahead,
thinking of the candles
and of God's holy mother.
The white stockings too,
and the blue shoes
with the pearls.
This is certainly no everyday shift!
Fifteen maidens sewed this.
Calm down!
Was it really 15,
all at one time?
Yes.
Come sit down
and I'll comb your hair.
No, I'll wear my hair down,
since I have these fine clothes on.
If you always get your way,
you'll give the devil such joy
that the saints will punish you
with boils and toothaches.
Why are you always talking
about the devil?
Father never does.
Because the devil
seduces the innocent
and seeks to destroy goodness
before it can blossom.
I always say my prayers, Mother.
Who did you dance with
last night?
I danced
with him...
him...
and him.
Why do you want to know?
I had such wicked dreams last night.
What did you dream, Mother?
I wish I had dreams too.
Big, wonderful dreams.
But I never do.
Now the skirts, Mother.
The blue one, and the bright one
with gold thread.
Pull harder,
or it won't puff out
the way it should.
You forgot the necklace.
Leave the necklace for Sunday.
This is quite enough already.
You're in my light.
That's your father.
Now he's angry.
Sick, are you?
Mother said some such thing.
Do I look sick to you?
Pale and frail and ill?
Is this proper,
sleeping past sunrise?
Father, when I get to church,
I'll kiss Father Erik's hand
and beg forgiveness
for not arriving in time for matins.
"Mother was sick," I'll say.
"And Father was sick,
and Frida was sick,
so they didn't wake me.
And the candles weren't yet dipped,
and Blackie wasn't yet shod."
I'll ride into the mountains
with this naughty girl,
and I'll say...
"I won't have such a daughter.
Imprison her in the mountains
for seven years
until she's been tamed.
Then I'll come
take her home again...
maybe."
Let Ingeri come too, Father.
She never gets away from the farm.
It's a shame
it's such a long way to church.
A woman like you no doubt needs
a confessional closer at hand.
Says the man who had to flee
the country to save his hide.
I know all about you, Professor.
Now, now.
A bird on the wing finds something,
while those who sit still find only death.
I've seen
both women and churches.
- What were the churches like?
- Tall as the sky.
And big.
Not of wood,
but of mortar and stone.
With windows
in every color of the rainbow.
You get to come too, Ingeri.
Father promised.
Now be on your way,
or you won't get there until nightfall.
Hurry up, Ingeri.
Drink some warm ale.
It's a long journey,
and you've eaten nothing.
I don't want it. Give it to Ingeri.
She's coming along.
- When was that decided?
- Father said so just now.
You could at least give me
a farewell kiss.
Christ our Lord,
bless this young life.
These cheese cakes and candles
are for Father Erik from me.
Give him my best wishes
and tell him they're for
"you know what."
And he should say
five Our Fathers and 15 Hail Marys.
So lovely an apple orchard I know
A maiden with virtues so dear
Her hair like spun gold does flow
Her eyes like the heavens so clear
The streams flow so merrily
All under the verdant trees
In springtime's breeze
The little bird, he soars so high
And rides the wind on his wing
It is such work, such work to fly
And over high mountains to spring
The streams flow so merrily
All under the verdant trees
In springtime's breeze
Does the baby hurt you, Ingeri?
What's the matter?
You'll learn for yourself one day.
Then I'll be married,
and mistress of my house with honor.
We'll see about your honor
when a man takes your waist
or strokes your neck.
No man will get me to bed
without marriage.
And if he meets you in the pasture
and pulls you down behind a bush?
I'll fight my way free.
But he's stronger than you.
You're too late for matins,
you know.
But better to bloom on the road
than wither in church.
I'm taking candles to church.
I see.
In the Holy Virgin's honor,
you've bedecked
and bejeweled yourself
like a bride for her groom.
No, because it's such nice weather,
and because Mother was against it.
Not because I expected
to meet you.
Thank you for last night.
- There's nothing to thank me for.
- Really?
No, and you know that
just as well as I.
What is it, Ingeri?
I saw you two
in the barn last night.
I wanted to speak to him about you,
about help for you and the child.
He probably said there'd be help
if you offered him your mouth,
and even more if you rolled
with him in the hay!
You smiled at him...
and took his hand in the dance.
I danced with anyone
who offered me his hand.
Forgive me for slapping you.
Don't ask me for forgiveness!
- Let's turn back.
- Why? We must get to church.
I'll take the candles
and explain to Father.
Why? Mother and Father
wouldn't like that.
The forest is so dark!
I can't go on!
Don't cry so hard.
You could hurt the child.
Are the young maidens
frightened of the forest?
I'm not frightened.
I'm going to church.
May she rest in your cottage
until I come back?
Look here.
This is enough for both of you.
Did you think
I was going to slap you again?
Are you in labor?
Worse than that.
Come, I can help.
Sit down.
It's been so long since anyone sat
with me in the seat of honor.
What's your name?
Nowadays I have no name.
This is a quiet, lonely place.
You're a long way from neighbors.
I hear what I want to hear
and see what I want to see.
I hear what men whisper in secret
and see what they think
no one sees.
You can hear it yourself,
if you wish.
Just listen.
What's that pounding outside?
Three dead men riding north.
It's been a long time since a woman
made my chair narrower for me.
Here is a cure for your anguish.
Here is a cure for your woe.
Blood, course no more.
Fish, stop still in the brook...
and you, eagle, in the sky.
Here is the power.
You've taken human blood.
You've made an offering to Odin.
I recognized you
at once on the path
by your eyes,
your mouth, your hands.
But you're afraid.
You mustn't be.
I will give you strength.
What a funny little mouth harp!
I inherited it from my father,
who inherited it from his,
who inherited it from his.
May I please see?
Who are you?
Three brothers who lost
both father and mother too early.
Who takes care of you?
We drink from the creek
and eat roots from the earth.
Mother gave me a lunch sack.
- My brother says...
- Is your brother mute?
Evil men cut his tongue
out of his throat.
No!
But I understand him.
He says only if the proud maiden
will keep us company
can we accept such a gift.
I must ride to church
with the Holy Mother's candles.
- For matins?
- I'm too late for that.
I overslept.
But if matins are over,
there's no great hurry.
And if your dear mother made
a lunch for her proud maiden,
she meant for her to eat.
My brother says there's
a nice glade warmed by the sun,
if only the proud maiden
would join us there.
O blessed Jesus,
God the Father's son,
you are the living bread
that from heaven comes.
You bless me
with this bodily bread
and save my soul
from eternal death.
My brother's very curious:
Where is the proud maiden's farm?
It's east of the mountain
and west of the forest,
and so large that you must press
your neck hard against your back
to see the battlements.
The proud maiden
must be a king's daughter.
Father wears silk garments every day,
and a golden helmet,
and his lance flashes
like gold in the sun.
And Mother's key ring is so heavy,
she can't wear it on her belt.
A little maid follows behind her all day,
carrying it on a pillow.
And you three could be
enchanted princes
under a wood nymph's spell.
And the goats could be bears
and wolves that she has transformed.
My brother says the proud maiden
has such white hands.
Because princesses needn't do
the washing or make fires.
My brother says the proud maiden
has such a pretty neck.
To make a princess's gold necklace
shine all the brighter.
My brother says the proud maiden
has such a narrow waist.
Cut this up
and we can all have some.
But perhaps you have no knife?
These look like
Simon of Snollsta's marks.
I'm on my way to church
with the Virgin's candles.
Watch the goats
till we come back.
Do as I say,
or you know what will happen.
If you have something to say,
speak up.
We have nothing
to say except that...
the night is cold and the road long.
Where are you from?
The north. The northwest.
How's the winter been there?
It's been hard,
and there's been much sickness.
The people are faint with hunger
and can hardly leave their cottages,
while the cows sink down
in their stalls.
So I've heard.
You've had a crippling winter.
Where are you headed?
- We seek work further south.
You may sleep in the manor hall.
There will be frost tonight.
Good evening.
We met the master in the yard,
and he invited us in.
Sit there until he comes.
Those shoes
have been through a lot.
A day can start out beautifully
yet end in misery.
Rarely have I seen a morning
so full of promise as this morning.
The sun shone in all its fairness
and made you forget winter's rages.
My legs wanted to dance for joy...
but before nightfall she lay dead.
I saw the May Queen herself
ride into the sun...
but she never returned.
O blessed Jesus,
God the Father's son...
you are the living bread
that from heaven comes.
You bless me
with this bodily bread
and save my soul
from eternal death.
- Did you finish?
- Yes.
The northern pasture
has been fertilized and plowed.
My father used to say,
"Feed the clay heavy, the sand light."
Please forgive
my poor little brother.
Is he like this often?
Only when we've starved
for a long time.
Rub his temples and hands
with salt and vinegar,
and place a warm wooden lid
on his belly.
Thank you kindly,
but there's no need.
The less fuss made,
the quicker it passes.
There'll be work here on the farm.
But we can discuss that tomorrow.
You can keep the fire burning.
It'll be bitterly cold.
Good night.
Come.
Come on.
Good night.
You say your prayers, don't you,
even if no one keeps after you?
You poor thing.
But God is merciful,
more merciful than you think.
Say your prayers properly tonight,
and don't forget them from now on.
See how the smoke trembles
in the roof hole?
As if whimpering and afraid.
Yet it's only going out
into the open air,
where it has the whole sky
to tumble about in.
But it doesn't know that.
So it cowers and trembles
under the sooty ridge of the roof.
People are the same way.
They worry and tremble
like leaves in a storm...
because of what they know...
and what they don't know.
You...
shall cross a narrow plank...
so narrow you can't find your footing.
Below you roars a great river.
It's black...
and wants to swallow you up.
But you pass over it unharmed.
Before you lies a chasm...
so deep you can't see the bottom.
Hands grope for you...
but they can't reach you.
At last you stand
before a mountain of terror.
It spews fire like a furnace,
and a vast abyss opens at its feet.
A thousand colors blaze there:
copper and iron,
blue vitriol and yellow sulfur.
Flames dazzle and flash
and lash at the rocks.
And all about, men leap and writhe...
small as ants...
for this is the furnace
that swallows up
murderers and evildoers.
But the very moment
you think you're doomed,
a hand shall grasp you
and an arm circle around you,
and you'll be taken far away...
where evil no longer
has power over you.
If Karin doesn't come home tonight...
she'll surely return tomorrow.
Calm down, Märeta.
How can you tell me to calm down?
That's all you ever say.
What would have become of us
if I'd always done like you?
Never troubled or worried,
never praying to God.
Open your fists, Märeta.
Open your fists!
I know you're worried about Karin.
She's all I have!
But she's stayed in the village
overnight without permission before.
She's all I have.
She's the only one I have left.
They struck the boy.
I thought I heard the boy scream.
It was just an owl in the forest.
We've heard it all night.
This silk shift...
and what's in this bag
is all we have left of our sister.
She died at Candlemas.
It's a precious keepsake...
but need knows no law,
and we thought
we would offer it to you.
We see you are a lady
who understands
the value of beautiful things...
and this is what
our sister treasured most.
It's a bit torn and spotted...
but look at the embroidery.
It's surely the work
of nine young maidens.
Skillful hands like yours will know
how to make it like new again.
I must ask my husband...
what a fitting reward would be
for such a valuable garment.
Now see that you get some rest too.
What's the matter, Märeta?
The herdsmen offered it to me for sale.
It's Karin's.
There's blood on it.
What are you going to do?
First I'll put the crossbar
on the outer door.
It's already done.
Will you take the farmhands with you?
Be careful!
Tell me what you know.
Kill me first.
My guilt is greater than theirs.
I willed it to happen.
Ever since I became with child,
I've hated her.
The very day I prayed for it,
he did it.
It was him and me,
not the herdsmen.
He possessed them,
and they threw themselves
on her like devils, all at once.
They fell upon her and held her down...
and they took her.
You saw it?
I was in the forest.
I saw it...
and willed it to happen.
I picked up a rock to throw at them,
but I let it fall.
And when it was over,
they beat her to death with a club.
I saw that too!
Heat up the bath.
I'll get some birch branches.
Bring me the butcher's knife.
No!
God forgive me
for what I've done.
We must find Karin.
I loved her too much, Töre,
more than God himself.
When I saw how she favored you,
I began to hate you.
It's me God meant to punish.
I bear the guilt.
You're not alone, Märeta,
and God alone knows where guilt lies.
You saw it.
God, you saw it!
An innocent child's death,
and my vengeance.
You allowed it to happen!
I don't understand you!
Yet still I ask your forgiveness.
I know no other way
to make peace with myself
than with my own hands.
I know no other way to live.
I promise you, God...
here, by the dead body
of my only child,
I promise
that as penance for my sin,
I shall build you a church.
On this spot I shall build it.
Out of mortar and stone...
and with these very hands!
O Lord, receive my soul
And grant me everlasting peace
Grant me everlasting peace
At your side, O Lord