Master Li is here!
- Master Li is here!
Xiulian!
Xiulian! Li Mubai is here!
- Master Li.
- Hello.
- How's everything?
- Fine. Please come in.
- Mubai. It's been a long time.
- It has.
- How's business?
- Not bad. And how are you?
Fine.
Monk Zheng came by
from the Wudang Mountain.
He said you were practicing
deep meditation.
The mountain must be so peaceful.
I envy you.
My work keeps me so busy
I hardly get a minute's rest.
I broke it off.
I couldn't complete the training.
Why? You're a Wudang disciple.
Training is everything.
During my meditation training,
I came to a place of deep silence.
I was surrounded by light.
Time and space disappeared.
I felt I had come to a place
my master had never told me about.
- You were enlightened.
- Far from it.
I didn't feel the bliss
of enlightenment.
Instead, I was surrounded
by an endless sorrow.
It was more than I could take.
I couldn't go on. I failed.
There was something pulling me
back into the world.
What was it?
Something I can't seem to let go of.
I see you're preparing to leave.
We're making a delivery to Beijing.
Perhaps I could ask you
to deliver something to Bei-leye for me.
The Green Destiny Sword?
You're giving it to Bei-leye?
I am. He has always been
our greatest protector.
I don't understand.
How can you part with it?
It's been with you a long time.
Too many men have died at its edge.
It only looks pure
because blood
washes so easily from its blade.
You use it for just causes,
making you worthy of it.
It's time for me to leave it behind.
So what will you do then?
Come with me to Beijing.
You can give the sword to Bei-leye in person.
It'll be just like old times.
I need to visit my master's grave.
It's been many years since
he was murdered by Jade Fox.
I have yet to avenge his death,
and yet I'm thinking of quitting.
I must pray for his forgiveness.
Catch up with me when you have finished.
I can wait for you in Beijing.
Perhaps.
- Okay, you may pass.
- Thanks.
Let's go into the city. We can rest
after we unload the shipment.
Thank God everything is safe.
Much obliged, Miss Yu.
Just doing my job.
Sun Security has been the best
since your father started it.
You're a credit to his memory.
- Thank you.
- It's the truth.
This is Li's personal sword.
A great hero is worthy of a great weapon.
He is the only one in the world
worthy of it.
It's too fine a gift. I cannot accept it.
The sword has brought Li Mubai
as much woe as glory.
Li wants to leave these troubles behind.
Taking the sword will help him
leave his old way of life.
I see. All right.
I'll act as the sword's custodian.
Ninth Level Counsel, Governor Yu has arrived.
I'll be right there.
Thank you. You've always been
a great friend to Li and I.
No hurry to leave. Please feel at home.
You'll stay the night as my guest.
Now, Xiulian,
tell me something,
and forgive me for prying.
But your father was like a brother to me
and I think of you as my own daughter.
Please, Bei-leye, what is it?
Li Mubai giving up his sword
and his warrior days,
maybe he's hinting something to you.
- I don't know.
- Don't be coy.
I've known all along about
your feelings for each other.
Neither of you have been brave enough
to reveal your feelings to each other.
So many years went wasted.
Li Mubai and I aren't cowards.
Maybe it isn't what you've thought.
When it comes to emotions,
even great heroes can be idiots.
If Li Mubai doesn't talk straight
next time you see him,
let me know, and I'll give him an earful
You will stay in this room.
Miss?
I am your guest here today.
I'm Governor Yu's daughter.
This is Bei-leye's study. You are here to...
It's so crowded out there.
I was looking for a quiet place.
I'm Bei-leye's head servant, De Lu.
This is another of our guests.
It's heavy for such a thin piece of metal.
It's all in the hilt.
And that blade is no ordinary metal.
Still, the sword is the lightest
of all weapons.
You're just not used to handling them.
But I have had much practice.
As a child in the west, a garrison lived with us.
They'd let me play with their weapons.
This scabbard is so beautiful.
Beautiful and yet dangerous.
Once you've seen it tainted with blood,
its beauty is hard to admire.
It's 400 years old.
It's exquisite.
You said this sword belongs to...
My friend Li Mubai.
He's given it to Bei-leye as a gift.
Li Mubai! The famous warrior?
I've heard so much about him.
Why would he give his sword to Bei-leye?
You're too young to understand.
- You must be a sword fighter, too.
- Yes, but I prefer the broadsword.
Certain moves, however, call for a straight blade.
Really.
It must be exciting to be a fighter,
to be totally free!
Even Jianghu society has rules.
Friendship, trust, integrity.
Always keep your promise.
Without rules, we wouldn't survive long.
I've read all about people like you.
Roaming wild,
beating up anyone who gets in your way!
Writers have to write like that
to sell books.
You're just like the characters
in the stories.
Sure, no place to bathe for days,
sleeping on flea-infested beds.
Do they tell you all about that in those books?
You know what I mean.
I'm getting married soon,
but I haven't lived the life I want.
I've heard of your engagement.
Congratulations.
It's the most important step
in a woman's life, isn't it?
- You are not married, are you?
- What do you think?
No. You couldn't roam around
freely if you were.
I admit you're probably right.
Go ahead, Governor.
2 feet 9 inches long, 1.1 inch wide.
The hilt is 8 inches long, 2.6 inches wide,
0.7 inch thick, each side is 1.5 inches.
With seven rubies missing from the hilt.
You can tell from the design that
it was made during the Qin Wu era.
Engraved with a technique lost by
the time of the Han Dynasty.
Your knowledge is remarkable.
A sword by itself rules nothing.
It comes alive only through
skilful manipulation.
I see your point. Please continue, Bei-leye.
The Imperial Court isn't the problem.
With royalty and officials everywhere
the Royal Guard keep security tight.
But Beijing is not like the Western provinces.
It's full of complex characters.
Proceed with caution
in your quest for law and order.
Don't depend only on the court.
Keep some contacts
in the Jianghu underworld.
It can ensure your position.
Be strong yet supple.
This is the way to rule.
Governess.
You may leave.
- Please sit.
- I've made a pair of silk pajamas.
- Want to change into them?
- Leave them there.
I heard you met Yu Xiulian today.
You know her?
Your mother would not want you
consorting with her kind.
I'll socialize with whomever I please.
Don't invite danger
into your father's house.
- I'm tired now!
- Go to bed then.
Miss has grown up
and is getting married soon.
God knows what the future will bring.
It'll be just the same.
Enough, I'm tired.
It's autumn now.
I'll shut the windows for you.
Chilly, eh?
Thief!
Someone help! Catch the thief!
He's on the rooftop!
The sword's been stolen! Someone help!
He's on the roof! Stop, thief!
Catch him!
Avenge my mother!
What are you standing here for?
Go get him!
Return the sword, and I'll let you go.
You've been trained at Wudang?
We are street performers. You're wrong.
- We're just practicing the stunts.
- Father-.
Practicing? Who are you trying to fool?
Where did they go?
Governor Yu's house.
Get down here!
Give me the sword.
Bei-leye awaits you in the great hall.
I didn't get the sword back.
But I'm sure the thief is in the Yu household.
- How dare you!
- But I saw...
Enough! Get out!
Has Governor Yu ever seen the sword?
Yes, though I doubt he's involved in this.
But the sword is somewhere
in his compound.
Then someone's out to frame him.
We should get word
to Li Mubai about this.
Watch your step, Madame Yu.
- What is it?
- Someone's put Wanted posters up.
Let me see.
Someone's after Jade Fox.
Preposterous, looking for her here!
- Best spear fighting in the world!
- The Yang School of Spear Fighting!
- Where did they go?
- I really don't know.
I saw them couple of days ago.
Probably gone by now.
Miss, there's a Miss Yu Xiulian
asking to see you.
- Our Lady is busy right now.
- I will tell her then.
Show her in.
Yes.
This spells trouble.
I have a guest now.
This way please, Miss Yu.
- I've missed you!
- How so?
I have nothing to do.
You're practicing calligraphy.
I'll write your name. Just for fun.
I never noticed that my name
looks like the word for sword.
You write gracefully.
Calligraphy is so similar to fencing.
Maybe it is. I wouldn't know.
Please.
Thank you for seeing me.
I hear your wedding day is near.
You must be overwhelmed
with the preparations.
I'm hardly doing a thing.
The less I think of it, the better.
My parents are arranging everything,
including the groom.
Mother says the Gous
are a very powerful family.
My marrying into this family
will give my dad's career a big boost.
It's a great fortune to marry
into such a noble family.
Is it? Actually, I wish I were
like the great heroes in the books
just like you and Li Mubai.
Marriage is a good thing.
But to be free to live my own life,
to choose who I love
and love him in my own way.
That's real happiness.
- Think so? Let me tell you a story.
- About you and Li Mubai?
Yes. I was once engaged
to be married when I was young.
- Really?
- His name was Meng Si Zhao.
He was a brother-by-oath to Li Mubai.
One day,
while defending Li Mubai in battle
he was killed by another man's sword.
After Meng's sacrifice,
Li and I went through a lot together.
Our feelings for each other grew stronger.
But how could we dishonour Meng's memory?
The freedom you talk about,
I too desire it,
but I've never tasted it.
It's not your fault, or Li Mubai's.
Too bad for Meng,
but that's just the way things turn out.
As a woman,
I still must abide by tradition
even if I'm not an aristocrat like you.
Don't distance us.
From now on, let's be sisters.
All right. As a sister,
I hope you find real happiness.
Miles and miles of nothing.
Can't your father get an appointment
closer to civilization?
This place!
Jiaolong, are you listening to me?
Let's go!
- Who are you?
- Dad!
Hold it! I'm a friend!
I don't care about your sword.
- Why are you spying on the Yus?
- I'm looking for someone. Jade Fox.
I'm a prefect from Shaanxi,
Gansu district.
This Jade Fox is a master criminal.
I hear she infiltrated the Yus.
She must have come with them
when he transferred here.
But I cannot just go in and catch her there.
I have to lure her out.
- This Jade Fox is a woman?
- You bet.
Then leave her to me. Don't worry.
Thank you, but I doubt you can handle her.
My wife was quite skilled at martial arts.
Jade Fox killed her in four moves.
It's both an official and a personal matter
to me.
- Meatballs are ready!
- I'm more than ready for them.
Wait, dad gets first dip!
Hey!
They are gone.
What does it say?
We'll settle this at midnight tonight
on Yellow Hill.
Good! The Fox is out of her hole.
Please.
Xiulian, look who's here.
Bei-leye thinks it's not appropriate
to cast doubt on Governor Yu.
But there is something amiss
in the Yu household. I'm investigating.
What have you found?
Jade Fox? Impossible!
You'd always suspected
she'd fled to the west.
I didn't think she'd dare
come back to Beijing.
Is there any place safer than
under the nose of Governor Yu?
I shall avenge my master's death after all.
But be careful, Mubai.
Bei-leye requires discretion.
Official business is already
difficult to resolve,
it'd be a bigger mess
with your personal matters involved.
And I don't know,
this flyer may not be reliable.
It could be some sort of trap.
- Did you see who posted it?
- No, it was done at night.
It says Fox is hiding at Yu's.
Bei-leye says the night of the theft
there was a fight in front of Yu's.
Were you involved?
No, that was Yoshi,
Bei-leye's house guard.
He followed the thief to the Yus.
- Have you cross-examined him yet?
- Yoshi? No, not yet...
But you have your men
watching over Yu's compound?
No, I'd already sent them back.
You can blame me for losing the sword
but trust me, I'll get it back soon
using my own methods.
That's not what I meant.
I don't care about the sword.
What do you mean?
Didn't you come back here for it?
I didn't know it was stolen until I got here.
Then, why did you come?
Well, we had talked...
Pardon my intrusion.
Master Li, your room is ready.
Thank you.
Please, lead the way.
This Fox doesn't care much for punctuality.
There's no sign of her.
Halt! Show your face!
Cai Qiu! You scum!
Leave me alone or you'll
pay with your life!
That's what you think, old witch!
If you surrender now, you'll suffer less.
If you resist, I won't stop
until you're dead.
Father! Let me avenge my mother's death!
You'll soon end up like her,
you little whore!
You'll pay for that, you old fox!
Dad!
- I'll Kill you! You ruined my life!
- Out of my way or I'll kill you too!
Watch her hands! She'll paralyse you!
Xiaomei!
Die, you filthy dog!
An ambush! You cowards!
- Dad, are you okay?
- I'm fine.
The Wudang masters should have
killed you long ago.
You've had ten years too many, Jade Fox!
You probably don't remember me.
But you remember my master.
You infiltrated my clan while I was away.
You poisoned my master
and stole the secret manual.
Now it's time for you to pay!
Your master had no respect for women.
I was good enough to sleep with
but not to teach.
He deserved to die by a woman's hand!
You stole the top secrets
of Wudang's martial arts.
But after ten years of training,
your moves are still undisciplined.
For you to die under a Wudang
sword today
is no disgrace!
My disciple! Fight with me!
We'll kill them all!
- Fox has a disciple!
- Just let me get rid of that meddler!
Who are you?
Why is the Green Destiny
in your possession?
- What's it to you?
- My name is Li Mubai.
The Green Destiny Sword is mine.
Jade Fox can't be your master.
Where did you learn this "Xuan Piu" move?
Just playing around.
Who is your real master?
- Let's go.
- I'll kill them once and for all.
Let's go!
Dad!
This is Cai Qiu?
My father.
Prefect from Gansu, Cai Qiu.
Homicide must be reported to Governor Yu.
Particularly when the victim is an officer.
Yet you say the killer is hiding
out in Yu's compound?
I'd stake my life on it, sir.
Come with me.
This needs to be resolved quickly,
before there is a scandal.
I'll get into the Yu household and get her.
I'll ferret out this Fox
and her gang in no time.
Too dangerous. Yu is a court official
and in charge of security.
This could ruin his reputation and career.
It might also get Bei-leye in trouble.
This calls for the utmost delicacy.
Bei-leye, can you find some excuse
to invite Madame Yu and her daughter?
What do you have in mind?
The best way to trap a fox
is through her cubs.
Oh, my! Bei-leye's wife is spoiling
us with all these wedding gifts.
She is being so considerate
to our daughter.
I'm sorry she's not feeling well enough
to entertain you today.
I heard Bei-leye has lost something.
And now his wife is not feeling well.
We know who stole the missing item.
If the thief returns it
I'm sure Bei-leye will pursue
the matter no further.
That's good.
It's an emparassment when the help
can't keep their hands to themselves.
Bei-leye knows that even well-meaning
people sometimes make mistakes.
Some mistakes can ruin
not only themselves
but their entire family as well.
But don't be too lenient.
Yes, and I'm sure we will see
no mercy granted to the murderer
who just turned up in Beijing.
- A murderer?
- Yes,
the very killer of Li Mubai's own master.
Last night she killed an official
who had tracked her for many years.
A female criminal! Now that's news!
You say she killed an officer?
Yes, from the west.
He went undercover as a street performer,
and followed her here.
I'm no detective, but maybe
the murderer and thief are the same.
I doubt that.
This particular thief is very unusual.
And much smarter than a mere killer.
- Jiaolong humbly greets you, Bei-leye.
- Hello, Mrs Yu.
Let me introduce Li Mubai,
the renowned swordsman.
It's a pleasure to meet you,
Mrs Yu, Ms Yu.
Ms Yu is getting married soon.
May your future be fortunate.
Why don't you come in?
- I'm standing guard.
- Come in. It's cold.
Come in. We don't have to fear
Jade Fox if we're together.
Isn't it a little late to be out?
You can give the sword to me.
I'll do as I please.
- Where's your master?
- None of your business!
Had enough flying?
You've got potential.
You've studied the Wudang manual
but you do not understand it.
You need a real master.
A master like you? It's a meaningless title.
You're right, it's all meaningless.
School is meaningless,
the secret manual is meaningless
even this sword.
It is just a state of mind.
Don't talk like a monk
just because you're in a temple. Just fight!
- Then tell me where Jade Fox is!
- Defend yourself!
True sharpness is effortless.
No growth without assistance.
No action without reaction.
No passion without control.
Know your limits.
Give yourself up and find yourself again.
There is your first lesson.
Go ahead.
Why should I? You need practice.
I can teach you to fight with the
Green Destiny,
but first you must learn
to hold it in stillness.
Why do you want to teach me?
I've always wanted a disciple
truly worthy of the Wudang secrets.
Aren't you afraid that I'd kill you
once I mastered it?
That's a risk I'm willing to take
as your teacher.
Deep down you're good. Even Jade Fox
hasn't been able to corrupt you.
Wudang is a whorehouse!
Keep your lessons to yourself!
You're home late, or should I say early?
Why are you still here?
You've killed an official!
You'll bring ruin on my whole family.
They wouldn't have tracked me here
if you hadn't stolen the sword.
You're not a little girl any more.
Did you think stealing would be fun?
That death is on your head
as well as mine.
Come with me, Jiaolong.
You don't want to waste your life
as the wife of some pompous bureaucrat.
- As master and disciple, we will rule.
- I'll never live as a criminal.
Stealing that sword already
made you a criminal!
That was just for fun.
Why would I leave? Where would I go?
Wherever we want.
We'll get rid of anyone in our way.
- Even your father.
- Shut up!
That's Jianghu way of life.
Kill or be killed.
Exciting, isn't it?
- I owe you nothing.
- Yes, you do!
To have you as my disciple
is the thing in my life I'm most proud of.
You think you've been teaching me
all these years from the manual?
You can't even read.
I studied the diagrams,
and you studied the words.
You hid the details from me?
You wouldn't have understood it
even if you knew how to read it.
You know you've gone
as far as you can go.
I hid my skills from you because
I was afraid it would hurt you.
If I hadn't seen you fight
with Li Mubai,
I'd still be ignorant
of all you've hidden from me.
Master.
I started learning from you
in secret when I was 1O.
You enchanted me with the dream
of the Jianghu underworld.
But once I realised I could surpass you,
you can't imagine how frightened I was!
I had no one to guide me,
no one to follow,
no one to learn from.
Believe me, my lessons aren't over yet.
Are you happy now that the sword is back?
I admit, getting it back made me realise
how much I missed it.
But it's no longer yours any more, is it?
You gave it to Bei-leye.
True. But I must borrow it
for one final task.
Jade Fox will die on its edge.
Did you know what you were hiding
when you covered for that girl?
My job was to recover the sword
without embarrassing anyone.
I wasn't about to ruin her life,
or her father.
You did your job well.
The sword is back. But... this girl.
I saw her last night.
I knew she would intrigue you.
She needs controlling.
She needs real direction and training.
She's an aristocrat's daughter,
she's not one of us.
It will all be over soon.
You'll kill Fox and Jiaolong will marry.
That's not for her. She should come to
Wudang and become a disciple.
But Wudang doesn't accept women.
For her, perhaps they could make
an exception.
If not, left to her own, I'm afraid
she'll become a poisonous dragon.
It's not our affair.
Even if Wudang accepts her,
her husband might object.
I thought by giving away the sword,
I could escape the Jianghu world.
But the cycle of bloodshed continues.
I had hoped so, too.
I wish there were something
I could do to help you.
Just be patient with me, Xiulian.
Don't move!
- Xiaohu!
- Jiaolong!
You shouldn't have come.
With all the traffic
on your rooftop these days
it took me a while to get in here.
I can't wait any longer, Jiaolong.
I was wrong to let you go.
Come with me, back to the desert.
You'll be free there.
You can do whatever you want.
You have been looking for me all this time?
Jiaolong, stop playing with it.
I won't break it, mother.
Charge!
Stop!
It's Dark Cloud!
Dark Cloud is coming!
Lower the shade, don't be seen!
Don't be afraid, Miss.
Don't touch the women!
Catch up! Come get it!
Hey!
Your mother will miss you.
Hurry back to her.
Hey!
She's mine! Leave her to me!
- Let's take a break.
- Give me back my comb!
Take a break.
You're tired. You need rest.
Your horse needs water.
There's a stream up here.
Well, there was when I last visited.
Your name?
My name is Luo Xiaohu.
The Hans call me Dark Cloud.
I'm not that tall or that big,
but I'm quick as lightning.
Here.
Give me my comb.
If you like that, I can make you a bow.
Great for hunting wild chicken.
They're delicious.
You need to eat something. Understand?
That way, you'll have the strength to fight.
Understand?
You'll slowly regain your strength.
Don't rush.
You have a bad temper.
It's much better this way.
You coward!
You're still mad?
At least you're speaking.
What's your name?
Pei? I didn't know the Hans
had such beautiful names.
Relax. If I wanted to do what you're
thinking, I'd have done it already.
You must be dying for a bath.
The water source is far,
and difficult to get to.
I managed to bring back some fresh water.
You can wear my clothes
when you are done.
They're clean.
Don't worry.
I'll sing a song, so you'll know where I am.
After the bath, you will calm down a little.
But promise me,
no more rocks on the head.
- All this trouble, just for a comb?
- It's mine.
And it's worth a lot to me.
But to a barbarian like you, it's nothing.
Not true. I can use it
to pick fleas from my horse.
By the way, I'm a real Manchurian.
I'm sorry, I guessed wrong.
I thought you were a Han.
Give me back my comb.
I don't take orders from anyone.
Give it to me.
One night, when I was a boy
I saw a thousand stars fall out of the sky.
I remember thinking,
where did they all go?
I'm an orphan.
I used to look for stars alone.
Maybe if I rode to the other end
of the desert, I'd find them.
I've been riding in the desert ever since.
And so that little boy became
a fearsome bandit.
Couldn't find the stars, so now
he robs young girls of their combs.
Out there,
you're always fighting for survival.
You have to gang up
just to stand a chance.
Slowly, your gang becomes your family.
All that Dark Cloud stuff
is just to scare people
but it does make my life easier.
So you are still the little boy at heart
looking for fallen stars.
A grown man, gazing at the sky, thinking that
the brightest star has fallen at his side.
Your father's men are looking for you.
They're still out there, circling closer.
They'll stop some day.
They won't, and we'll be running forever.
Don't send me back.
You must decide.
You might get tired of this
and start missing your family.
If we had a daughter,
we'd look for her, too.
She'd miss us, too.
Jiaolong, I want you to be mine forever.
What if I make my mark on the world,
earn your parents' respect?
We nomads have a legend. Anyone
who dares to jump from the mountain,
Will have their greatest wish fulfilled.
A long time ago, a man's parents were ill,
so he jumped.
He didn't die, wasn't even wounded.
He just floated away, far away,
never to return.
He knew his wish had come true.
If you believe in it, it will happen.
I've asked Han people, they say,
"A sincere heart will make
your dreams come true."
Keep it safe.
And return it to me
when we are together again.
I will.
If you don't return it to me,
I will have to chase you down.
And next time, I won't go easy on you.
Wherever I went,
they always recognised me.
I really tried.
I heard you came to Beijing.
I was afraid I'd never see you again.
So I came.
I can't let you get married like that.
Go back.
Jiaolong.
- Don't ever come back.
- So it's over?
Yes.
We heard noises. Is everything all right?
Fine. It was just a cat.
You think Jade Fox will show up?
She must be nearby.
But I doubt she'll let herself be seen.
We'll keep our eyes open.
She'll come for the girl sooner or later.
Jiaolong!
Go back to Xinjiang with me!
Let go of me!
You're mine!
Go back to the desert with me!
Jiaolong, come back to Xinjiang with me!
- Tell me. Where is Jade Fox?
- Come with me. Hurry.
You really thought she'd give it all up
and go back west with you?
- She's mine.
- Whether she's yours or not
you will be no good to her dead.
With Gou and Yu hunting you,
it won't be long until
you're in their hands.
I don't care any more.
If you truly loved her,
you wouldn't say that.
Don't you want to see her again?
I'll write an introduction for you.
Take it to Wudang Mountain.
Wait there for news from me.
Okay.
When will this end?
They take it, put it back, and take it again.
My home is turning into a warehouse.
Come in.
- Speak.
- Yu Jiaolong has run away.
The groom found her missing.
Governor Yu requests your assistance
since you know
the Jianghu underworld so well.
He wants to find her
and keep her from harm.
Bei-leye, leave this to us. Don't worry.
What can I bring you?
A clean cup.
Hi there. May I ask your name?
Long.
It's young master Long. My apologies!
I'm Iron Eagle Sung Ming.
This is my fellow brother,
Flying Cougar Li Yun.
What brings you to Huai'an
and where are you headed, Master Long?
Anywhere there's action.
In that case,
perhaps we could be of assistance.
Don't bother.
You don't seem to have understood.
And if I haven't?
We have ways of helping you understand.
Are you related to Li Mubai?
He's my defeated foe.
Some tea.
Xiulian.
Things we can touch have no permanence.
My master used to say,
"There's nothing we can hold onto
in this world.
"Only by letting go can we
truly possess what is real."
Even to an old Taoist like you,
not everything is an illusion.
When you were holding my hand just now,
wasn't that real?
Your hand is rough and calloused.
The hand of a broadsword master.
All these years, I've longed to
touch it, and never had the courage.
Xiulian, Jianghu is a world of
crouching tigers and hidden dragons.
but so are human feelings.
Swords and knives harbour unknown
perils, but so do human relationships.
I gave away the Green Destiny
with sincerity.
But it brought us more troubles.
Repressing your feelings
will only make them stronger.
I can't repress my desire.
I want to be with you.
Just sitting like this
gives me a sense of peace.
Please follow me.
- I want a clean room.
- There are plenty of rooms.
- What would you like to eat?
- Some steamed cod, fried ribs,
meatballs, not too big, a little
starchy, but keep the sauce light!
And cabbage shark fin soup, mixed
vegetables, and a bottle of warm rose wine.
I have to order them from
a bigger restaurant.
- Hurry then.
- Yes.
It's him.
I am Iron Arm Mi Dabiao.
I heard a true master has arrived.
I seek a lesson.
Then it is a lesson you shall have!
What kind of Iron Arm are you?
That's amazing technique!
I am Flying sabre.
Are you related to Southern Crane?
Southern Duck?
I don't eat anything with two feet.
Who could remember such lengthy names?
You!
If Li Mubai is your defeated foe,
why don't you know his master?
Who are you?
I'm called Shining Phoenix Mountain
Gou Jun Sihung.
Gou? I hate that name.
It makes me want to vomit.
For having that name, You'll be
the first to taste my sword today!
Hold it! Don't you know Monk Jing?
A monk eating meat and not reading
scriptures? You need a lesson, too.
- Who the hell are you?
- Who am I?
I am...
Be careful of her sword!
...the invincible Sword Goddess
with the Green Destiny
that knows no equal!
Be it Li or Southern Crane,
lower your head and ask for mercy!
I'm the dragon from the desert
who appears from nowhere,
and leaes no trace!
Today I fly over Mount Emei,
tomorrow, I'll topple Wudang Mountain!
We politely asked for a friendly match,
but she showed no respect
and started to reproach and attack us.
My friends offered to come by
and teach her a lesson.
Her sword is just too powerful.
I've traveled far and wide,
but I've never met anyone that uncivilized.
She kept accusing me of being
the brother of Gou Junpei.
Who is this Gou Junpei, anyway?
Her husband.
Sun Security is nearby. Why don't you
go home and see how things are going?
- What about you?
- l'll look around and catch up later.
Not a bad idea.
Let's stay at Sun Security tonight.
- Get a good night's sleep.
- Yes.
- You are back.
You're back, Master!
- Hello guys. How's home?
- Things are fine.
- You've been gone a while.
- Something came up. I leave tomorrow.
- Ah Wei, your wife was due?
- Yes, a baby girl.
- A girl? Good.
- I'd be happy if she grows up like you.
- Mrs Wu.
- You're back!
- How's the arm? Still sore?
- Much better.
I've been worried about you.
Mrs Wu,
Li Mubai is coming to stay the night.
Really? I'll go and tidy up the room then.
Sister Yu!
Here, let's get you some proper clothes.
I'm just borrowing them.
I'm not staying.
You get around pretty well.
I don't think you need my clothes.
I just happened to be around.
I wanted to see how you're doing.
Sister...
Now, now.
With all the trouble you've caused,
now you know what Jianghu life
is really like.
You came here,
that means you think of me as your sister.
If so, let me give you some sisterly advice.
You don't have to marry,
you can't just leave your parents.
They forced me to marry.
Go back to your parents first.
Then you can decide about Xiaohu.
You know about Xiaohu?
He really loves you.
Come back to Beijing with me.
We'll figure a way out for you.
- Where is he now?
- Li Mubai has made arrangements.
- Li Mubai?
- He sent him to Wudang Mountain.
So, you're all working together
to set me up.
Jiaolong, shut up! How dare you accuse us!
From the beginning,
I knew you stole the Green Destiny!
I've done nothing but protect you
and your family.
And you've repaid me
with nothing but contempt.
Li Mubai spared you,
and all you do is insult him.
All we hoped for was a little peace,
and you've ruined it for us!
You're no sister of mine!
What do I care?
You were never a real friend anyway.
But I wonder,
how long could you last as my enemy?
Put the sword down.
Jiaolong!
Everyone out. Shut the doors.
Fine. Not friends. Not sisters.
Don't touch it! That's Li Mubai's sword.
Come and get it if you can.
Without the Green Destiny,
you are nothing.
Don't blame the weapon
if you can't defeat me.
Go ahead. Take your pick.
I'll wait.
Anything you want.
Give me the sword.
Take it!
Stop!
You are not worthy of this sword.
Not another lecture! On guard!
- Stop yourself before I do.
- Only the sword will settle this.
I held back at the monastery
because I wanted to see the real you.
What do you know about seeing
a true heart?
- What is it you want?
- What I have always wanted.
To teach you.
All right. If you can take back the
sword in three moves
I'll go with you.
- Give it back!
- Bow to your master.
- Never!
- Then you have no use for this sword.
Sooner or later, they'd drag you
back to Beijing.
Your parents value their reputation.
They'll never accept you again.
What good's a home? You've gone so far.
Now we can go all the way together.
You'll always be my Lady.
After all, happiness is the most
important thing in life, isn't it?
We'll be our own masters at last.
All we have left is each other, right?
Now lie down and rest.
Crazy girl like that,
you should have killed her.
I didn't have the heart to do it.
Maybe Li Mubai can do it.
Is it the girl or the sword you want?
You've been drugged.
Where's Jade Fox?
What happened?
Jade Fox drugged her.
How did you get here?
We followed Jade Fox.
Watch out!
Governess!
And so you die.
And so shall you.
A poisoned needle!
You deserve to die
but the life I was trying to take
was Jiaolong's.
Ten years I devoted to you.
But you deceived me!
You hid the book's true meaning.
I never improved
but your progress was limitless.
You know what poison is?
An eight-year-old girl who's full of deceit!
That's poison!
Jiaolong!
My only love,
my only enemy!
You can't die! Tell us,
what poison did you use?
What poison?
You can't die, tell us the antidote!
You can't let him die! Mubai can't die!
- It's the Purple Yin Poison.
- What?
Purple Yin Poison.
It goes straight to the heart.
My blood will stop flowing
within two hours.
It's the same poison that killed my master.
- There's no antidote.
- There must be an antidote!
Every living thing has its antithesis.
Why not this?
There is. Fox taught it to me.
The recipe isn't complicated, but the
ingredients are hard to find. It takes time.
Please, trust me.
As you have helped me, let me help him.
All right. Hurry up.
Maybe I can hold on for two hours.
Ride my horse to headquarters.
They have the ingredients.
Give this to Mrs Wu.
She'll help you. Hurry!
Save your breath.
Guard your energy. I'll be back.
Who is this?
Mrs Wu! Where's Mrs Wu?
Stop it!
Yu gave me this
and told me to come to you.
Let her come in!
Mubai, hold on.
Give me some hope.
Xiulian.
Don't waste your breath.
My life is departing.
I've only one breath left.
Use it to meditate.
Free yourself from this world
as you've been taught.
Let your soul rise to eternity
with your last breath.
Don't waste it on me.
I've already wasted my whole life.
I want to tell you
with my remaining strength
that I love you. I always have.
I would rather be a ghost,
drifting at your side
as a condemned soul,
than enter heaven without you.
Even if I was banished
to the darkest place,
my love
will keep me from being a lonely spirit.
He's gone?
Yoshi,
please take this sword back to Bei-leye.
You may go to Wudang Mountain.
Xiaohu awaits you there.
Promise me whatever path
you decide to take in this life,
be true to yourself.
Jiaolong!
Jiaolong.
Remember the story
you told me in the desert?
Have faith, then the dreams will come true.
Make a wish, Xiaohu.
To be back be in the desert,
together again.