Jesus, oh!
Oh God
No metal in the microwave
No metal!
Martha, it's Robert
Just to let you know to keep an eye peeled
for the first reviews of
your breathlessly awaited first novel
Word is, the Times is going to rave, rave, rave
Talk to you soon
Thanks
You look like shit
Where's Grandpa?
He's so cute with the headphones on
Hi Grandpa!
Do you think he remembers me?
Come on, it's a steal. You've got to see it.
You'll have your own room to write in
Grandpa can be out in the back chopping
bricks or whatever he does out there
You'd never even know he existed
I wish he didn't
God, he's really getting you down
From the way Alex has acted
for the last seven years
you'd have thought he didn't have a father
And then boom, a month ago
this shows up on the doorstep
I haven't written a word since
Well, Alex has got to get him out of here
It's not that simple with Alex
and frankly we can't afford
to get him his own place
let alone buy a mansion
Of course you can
especially if your mother's offer
is still good
Alex will never accept money from her
you know that
Work on him!
For God sakes, Martha
you have a lot to learn about men
And you have a lot to learn about husbands
Sorry
It's okay. I'm getting a dog.
Hi Alex!
Smells good. Good Jimmy boy.
Grandpa, I'm home
How's my boy!
What's that?
It's a book that I made for you
Animals that change
One day
I saw the most weird thing
It was a turtle and a fish and a rat
They were in a puddle of potion
They grew
They destroyed the universe. The end.
Where does he get these ideas?
Come on. Let's go get you
cleaned up for dinner
Dad, you shouldn't eat so much fat
at your age
How are you today?
Did you watch those tapes I rented for you?
Terrible!
I'll get you some Taiwanese tapes
They'll be just as bad
Well, what about some Hong Kong kung-fu movies?
The worst!
Their kung-fu's a joke
Dad! They're only acting
You're a Tai Chi professor
They can't compare
Damn, I can't learn English
It's a disgrace to go back
My life is going nowhere
Dad
It hasn't even been a month
since you retired and came to America
Give yourself some time
Jeremy come here
Come here you little rascal
Come here
Come here, Jeremy. Get off the couch
I don't have time for this, come here
Whoa!
My precious young man running bare naked!
Let me see!
The future of the Chu family
is depending on your little treasure
What does he think he's doing?
That's all right
Chinese elders must always
reassure themselves
that their family name will go on
Come on Jeremy, upstairs with you!
She's afraid he'll catch cold
Kids aren't made out of paper
Thanks
No, thanks
Why does this American woman
only eat vegetables?
She's afraid of getting fat
Why am I not fat?
On this Earth, there are two kinds of food
Cereal and vegetables are 'yin'
and meat is 'yang'
You must eat both to be balanced
and to be healthy
Alex, Linda came over today
Great
What's that supposed to mean?
Just great
What exactly do you have against her anyway?
So what if she was a Maoist in college?
From Maoist revolutionary
to real estate baron
If there's one thing worse
than a communist
it's an ex-communist
who's become a capitalist
Well, she's ready to do us quite a big favor
Oh no. She's trying to sell us
a house again
What's she mumbling about? Nothing
Something about cigarette butts?
What?
Mommy said she wants to move out
Quiet!
Alex, I'm talking to you
Mommy, can I watch cartoons?
Here
put some meat on your bones!
I don't want it, thank you
Jeremy, finish your milk
and you can watch TV
What did she say?
If he finishes his milk, he can watch TV
American people teach children
everything's a deal, like doing business
You should at least
take a look at the photos
It's apparently a real steal
If children can't concentrate on eating
what else can they concentrate on?
No, I don't want to look at any photos
Yes, father
And, these American cartoons
are only adding weirdness and violence
to this messed up world
Can I talk to you for five minutes?
For children? It's just a mess
Our sages said... Dad, eat!
Don't get upset. I'm just afraid
your dinner's getting cold
What has he been babbling about?
The violence in cartoons
How can he complain
he's martial arts expert himself
isn't that violence enough?
Would you cut it out? Both of you!
Just eat
You finish up. I'm going out for a smoke
In America, you're so polite to kids
You think so?
You don't treat kids as kids
It's not so simple
It's called democracy
No big and no little
I see, you understand America
better than me
Chinese time
Jeremy, stop playing
Come on, time for homework
Alex
The teachers' Putonghua is poor
Is his Chinese school any good?
Don't be too picky!
We only have one Chinese school
around here
Every weekend Jeremy learns some Chinese
I can play basketball
and you get to teach Tai Chi
Thank God for it!
Let's follow what they teach
Eh! Not like that
Dad, I've got some things
to take care of
Jeremy, come on
Grandpa will teach you an old Chinese rhyme
On East West Street, North South Go
Outside the gate, a man bites a dog!
Grab the dog to hit a brick
Watch out that brick might bite the hand
Follow Grandpa
On East West Street
North South Go
Outside the gate a man bites a dog
Outside the gate a dog bites a man
a man bites a dog!
Shit
Just one more sentence
Okay
How's your computer virus?
Almost killed
And when can I start reading your new book?
There is no new book, can't you tell?
Shit Alex, are you as out of it
as your father?
You don't know my father
I have spent every single day
in the same room with that man
since he showed up here a month ago
Alex, it's impossible
He's taken over my work room
I just don't have the space to think
Not enough space?
In China, this house is big enough
for four families
Sure, but they'd speak the same language
so they could talk to each other
Alex, he hasn't learned one word of English
And what about you?
What have you done but make fun of him
treating him with disrespect?
Alex, I tried
I'm his only son.
What do you want me to do?
You could at least consider moving
into a bigger place. We can afford it
No
I don't see why we have to pay
for his insurance
let him eat us out of house and home
when we can't accept a little loan
from my mother
It's not a little loan, it's a bribe
a big bribe and you know it
You look a little freaked out here
Come on, let's go to bed
Good night, Alex
Honestly Linda, I don't know why we're here
Come on, let's explore
Father and son
Father
Sweep
Step back
Collect
Hook
Step out
Single whip
Play guitar
Lean
White crane spreads its wing
Left hand ward off
Right hand attack
Excuse me, are you the instructor here?
I teach the cooking class
My name is Chen and you?
What's your name?
Chu
Master Chu
Please, we're all friends here
Don't call me master
Mr. Chu, I don't know
what our headmaster's thinking
my class is making dumplings, half-done
Some workmen just came in
to do some repairs
we have to leave
I see you have plenty of space here
could we move in
just this once?
Dumplings can be moved in
but they can't be moved out
We've also got scallion pancakes
and spring rolls!
Come on, let's help!
Thank you
Sink your chest
Stretch your back
lmagine a string pulling up your head
Sink lower your body
Master Chu
don't torture the child!
Look at all his weight
How can he 'sink his chest'?
Let him help me knead the dough
Oh, it's so difficult
Mrs. Chen, next week
I'll help you make dumplings
Can I enroll?
Next week, no dumplings
but General Tso's Special Chicken
Master Chu, would you please demonstrate
how to emit force with Pushing Hands?
Okay, let's try
My God, would that hurt?
Hey, Mr. Chu, try me
You're too heavy
So your kung-fu can only go so far!
Okay
Mr. Chu, can you take the fighting away?
Don't you see these burners
and the boiling water!
It's alright if Heavyweight gets burned
but the dumplings!
If you smash them
what're we going to eat?
We'll eat roast piglet!
Oh, okay!
Far enough? I'm ready Master!
What! Haven't you any eyes to see!
Sorry...!
I don't mean you!
It's your Master who wasn't looking
of all the directions!
Why did you throw Heavyweight
right smack on the dumplings!
Excellent aim!
Okay! No dumplings today!
Instead, we'll have sandy crab
scalded noodle lump soup!
I'm sorry
It wasn't on purpose!
It was on purpose
Are you okay? It was on purpose!
You got mad
In front of all these people sooner or later
I knew you'd show off!
Sorry...!
Okay! Don't stand there with a red face!
Let's clean up!
Everyone help!
No more Tai Chi Chuan!
We'll make dumplings!
Come... Did you hear that?
Master says no more Tai Chi!
Let's move
Oh my, what's this shape?
Hold on. Let me see your hands. Filthy!
Men, all of you wash your hands
Use soap! No dirty hands on my dumplings
Is that clear? Quick...
Mr. Chu, sit!
Let the young people stand
Come and sit
Not bad
Thin skin, plump stuffing, nice twist
It's nothing
Northerners like making things from dough
Are you from Beijing? Yes.
How long have you been here?
Just over a month
Are you used to it here?
If I was would I be here messing around?
Watch what you're saying, I'm here too
I don't mean that
America is a world for young people
Are you also from Beijing?
Do I seem like I am?
By your accent, yes;
the way you look, no
That's right
In 1949, I went with my husband to Taiwan
to escape the communists
And Mr. Chen is... He's dead
His name wasn't Chen
Not long after we arrived in Taiwan
he got liver cancer and passed away
I'm called Mrs. Chen
because of my second husband
Oh
and Mr. Chen?
He's dead too, just last year
Life and death, it's fate
Riches and rags are given by the gods
You just accept it. Everything is destiny
Sure...
Earlier this year, I left Taiwan
and came to live with my daughter
Every Saturday, I bring my granddaughter
here to study Chinese
Are you used to it here?
How did you put it just now?
If I wasn't so bored at home
how could your Heavyweight
have smashed my dumplings?
A computer couldn't have aimed
more accurately
Destiny, it's all destiny
That's right!
What kung-fu!
What's the matter?
Since last year sometimes
my right arm just gives out
when I pick up something a little heavy
it's helpless
Have you seen a doctor? Yes
Chinese doctors, western doctors
accupressure, acupuncture
herbal remedies, shots, medicine
I've tried everything
but getting a spell cast on me
I'm just old
Mrs. Chen, I don't want to sound
like a self-promoter
but practising Tai Chi will heal your arm
Okay, spare me!
Haven't I suffered enough in this life?
Practise? I won't be that stupid
No, when you practise Tai Chi
your circulation and energy will flow
I've let go, I'm not holding on
Energy must be released to me
When its released there's no tension
and one feels at ease
What's up?
The review, I can't find it
When you arrive at old age
everything is quiet
There the gentle wind passes through
the pine forest
15 minutes to practice, okay?
When the moon is rising
and shining on the mountain
I only want to go to the familiar forest
I reply with a simple fisherman's song
Alex
Yes?
Does New York have a place
to mat Chinese calligraphy?
Who's the present for?
You know, last week
I smashed Mrs. Chen's dumplings
I was so embarrassed
I want to give her this
I'm just afraid she'll laugh
at my calligraphy
Come on, Dad
we know you're good
What's the matter?
They've ignored the book
Just pretended it doesn't exist
It'll be in next week
What's a matter with her?
There's no review of her book
Years from now
we'll all be lying peacefully underground
What's the big deal?
Dad, when're we going? Coming
What is it?
A stomach cramp or something
Nothing important
Do you want to lie down on the couch?
What's wrong with her?
A stomach cramp
Let me take a look. Make her lie down
Dad says he wants to look at it
He knows this kind of thing
He does?
He's an expert
She's too tense
something's wrong with her stomach
You're too tight
Thanks for letting me know
Tell her to relax
Just relax
What happened? Mom!
Oh my god! What have you done to me?!
Get away from me! Relax!
What did you do to her?
Her stomach's bleeding!
Quick get her to the hospital!
I want to go too.
Jeremy, be good
You broke Mama
Jeremy wants a goldfish, right?
Here's a big tail
Big eyes and thick lips
And wings
What's Martha's condition?
Her stomach was bleeding
She has to stay in the hospital
How's Mommy?
Oh
Mommy's all right
She just needs a little rest, okay?
I didn't do anything to her
Her tension caused her stomach to bleed
I know that
Can I go to the hospital with you?
Dad
Is this the calligraphy you want matted?
Go take care of Martha
Don't bother about me
Can I have some macaroni and cheese, please?
Wait until Sunday
when your mother comes home, all right?
Master Chu
Hello everybody!
Master Chu, they tell me
your kung-fu is great
Last week, you barely touched Mr. Sung
and you sent him flying
And you threw Heavyweight
right on the dumplings
Nah, where's Mrs. Chen then?
I don't know. She's not coming anymore
I'm the new teacher
Mrs. Chen not teaching?
Yes
Why?
I don't know
You can ask them
Her family's going to that other school
north of here
If you want to contact her, you can ask
the principal about her telephone number
Okay, I'll go for my class
Is this General Tso's Special Chicken?
No, we aren't making chicken
This is to make 'eoly ice'
'Eoly ice'? Yes
Oily rice. Oh yes, OlLY RlCE!
Hey, do you want us to bring the oily
rice over so you can throw Heavyweight in?
Alex, will you make a call for me?
Mrs. Chen's family doesn't come here anymore
I still have to
give her the calligraphy
No one's home. It's their machine
Yici Chen. This is Alex Chu
My Dad has a present to give your mother
Give us a call
at 287-0425. Thanks
How can you talk like that?
Like what?
I'm not going to the hospital
with you to see Martha
Take me home to wait for the call
Relax Dad, they're not going anywhere
I can't communicate with Martha
You'll be there for hours
and all I can do is stare into space
Okay
Hey mister, don't kid me
I never kid anybody
Hello... It's me
Mrs. Chen?
Why weren't you at school?
Yes...
Don't listen to my kid. What nonsense!
It's not a present
I'm still embarrassed
about what I did to your class last week
Okay. How about this?
Tomorrow at 11:00 AM, my son's going to get
his wife at the hospital
We'll come by at 10:30 AM
Okay...
It's nothing
She has a small stomach problem
Right, then
see you tomorrow
Hello, Uncle Chu!
Not at all. Welcome!
Mother, they've come!
How are you, Yici?
Hi! Hi, Jeremy Hi, auntie
Why are you all guarding the door?
Come in, sit down!
Sorry, we've got to get to the hospital
to pick up my wife
Oh, you can't be late then
Is your wife, all right?
What am I talking about!
She's getting out of the hospital
Mr. Chu, how are you?
Good, Mrs. Chen, at your new school
is there a cooking class?
Not until I showed up
There's a kung-fu class too
But it's only Karate
They don't have grace
Better than Tai Chi Chuan
they sound much tougher
but they can't throw anywhere near
as far as you!
Dad, we'd better get going
I planned for you to stay for lunch
but you've got to get to the hospital
I won't keep you
for dinner
Next time.
Thanks and bye
Uh, you stopped by today to?
Ah! I forgot
You shouldn't have. Thank you
I'm going to hang it up right away
It's nothing
Drive carefully!
Bye
Good bye!
Bye!
What's the rush!
We didn't even get the scroll open!
Thanks!
Toothache?
There isn't much you can do,
but you sure have a lot of problems
Mr. Philips called
Jeremy received the lowest
reading score in the gifted class again
That school is too distracting for him
No Alex, we're too distracting for him
He's only responding
to the situation at home
Then change it!
What's your problem?
I ain't got any problem
Get back in the car, Alex!
Shut up!
Great
Martha
What do you want?
I'm going for a walk
A walk? I don't know
I don't want to see you getting lost
Smoking
You know, in a way
I'm kind of baby sitting you
I'll just hang around here, I won't go far.
Do you understand what I'm saying to you?
All right. Go ahead
What do I care?
Oh Jeremy, where'd you get those?
Teddy gave them to me
Well go put them away
Go on. Go get yourself cleaned up
Dad?
What're you looking for?
Dad
Where is he?
Oh
Is he back? No
Did you check with the police?
Alex, I'm sorry
I should've been more careful
But I'm... uh... with the book
In some ways, your father is more and
more like a child cooped up here with me
And I can't talk to him
I was trying to write
I had a feeling that
he was gonna get himself lost
just like a kid
trying to get some attention
I grew up believing
you should care for your parents
the way they care for you
My father is a part of me
Why can't you accept that?
I know. I tried
Just leave me alone
Oh my god. You've found him
Thanks God he's safe
We're looking for a Mr. Alex Chu
Alex is still out
looking for his father. I'm his wife
Okay. Mr. Chu, you take care of yourself, now.
All right?
Thank you very much officers
Alex is still out looking for you
Are you hungry?
Thirsty?
You really should eat something
I'm sorry too. Alex is furious
Jesus! How did you get so drunk?
Where did you go?
I was just walking around
and I lost sight of the church steeple
my landmark
The police brought him back a couple of hours ago
You're back, that's good
What are you doing?...
What're you doing, Alex?
Nothing
I know this wall, it isn't thick
What are you doing?
Mommy
Calm down...
Jeremy, Daddy's not feeling well
He'll be all right
Let me talk to him
Jeremy. Dad banged his head by accident
Do you need a band aid?
Okay
Jeremy... is the good one
who knows better than Mommy and Grandpa
how to care for Daddy
I haven't seen you that drunk
since the night we got married
That drunk?
Yeah
Well, my head's clear now
What're you mumbling about?
I've made up my mind already
About what?
The old man has to go
I'll send him to an old people's apartment
Are you sure?
I really don't have too much choice, do I?
I'll go tell him right now
Come in
Dad, why didn't you get up
and exercise today?
Aren't you feeling well?
What's wrong?
I probably caught cold
from being outside too long last night
I'm going to call a doctor
You've got important business at work
Don't waste your time on me
Come on Dad, cut it out!
You're never sick
if you don't feel well
it must be serious
I'll find a doctor for you
Why get sick now?
The vital organs aren't in harmony
The circulation's blocked
That's why I'm sick
Dad, Ma's been gone for so many years
and you've never wanted to look at her picture
I couldn't face her
Do you remember this scar!?
The day when the red guards came to our house
they knew they couldn't hurt me
so they took it out on you and your mother
I only had this one body!
In protecting you
I couldn't protect your mother
When they finally stopped their beating,
she was too gravely injured to survive
In this one life
I can never face your mother again
but I can face you!
It's been so many years
why talk about it now?
I feel stifled
Let me tell you something
compared to loneliness, persecution is easy
Look at how much hardship
and injustice I've endured
in the last 40 years
Their tortures only inspired me
to perfect my kung-fu
To study the Soft internal style of strength
we pursue more refined states of being
with the loss of tension
we attain concentration
And from that one
we achieve carefree nothingness
but this is nearly impossible to attain
Yes, it's easy to have physical strength
but inner strength is harder to practise
Go on, don't bullshit me!
Okay, I'll go call a doctor
Do me a favor
and call the Chinese school principal
tell him I can't teach
the class on Saturday
Okay. You'll go when you're better
I'm not going anymore
Why?
The students always want me to show off
I hate that
Then what will you do on the weekends?
Why don't we change
to that school north of here
You mean with Mrs. Chen?
No! They say it'll be good
for Jeremy's studies
I heard they're much stricter
How about it?
So did you tell him?
He's sick. Caught a cold from last night
I couldn't tell him
I hope it's not serious
No, I don't think so
But I'd better take him to the doctor's
I've got a great idea
about what to do with him
without hurting anyone's feelings
What's that?
Just be patient
Promise me, you'll be nice to him
for the time being
Okay?
Go on!
What?
Nothing
Then why do you keep looking
at your watch?
Nothing
Hello... yes, I am. Yici
How's the picnic?
Sorry for bothering you again
Yes, it's great weather
and great for a picnic
Unfortunately he doesn't have much energy now
If he got sick again, it'll be trouble
Take a break
Say thank you to Chen Mama for me
Okay
Don't hang up. Hold on
Who said I'm sick?
I didn't say sick, I said energy
No energy - means you need to get out!
My father says he's fine
he'd like to get some exercise
Let's use our plan then.
Okay
Okay, that's settled then
Bye
Right
How can it be healthy
to stay home all the time!
Ma, I've already had two
Have more
Here, Yi-yi. Thank you.
Kids should eat more
Jeremy
No, thanks
Have more!
Help yourself, don't worry about him
Have another piece No...
There's lots of meat
no point in saving it
I have to leave some room for tonight
It's the middle of the day
You're a big man!
Come on!
I haven't eaten since yesterday morning
I've been preparing for the dinner
you're cooking tonight
You're a stupid one
Nonsense! Here
He's reaching middle age
he's afraid of fat
cholesterol, and high blood pressure
Give it to me
Ma, again?
Yes, damn it
Can you give me a little massage?
Let me take a look
How can I let you do that?
It's okay
Did you find the spot?
This is the trouble
If it's trouble, leave it alone.
No
There's too little qi flow and too much blood
This kind of problem
is called Mid-Spring Paralysis
Now try to move the pinky toe on your left foot
Did you feel that subtle pain?
So, I was right
When this illness gets serious
you'll get a spasm under your knee,
a sore waist,
you back will give out,
your neck will tense up,
you won't be able to lift your arm,
and your muscles will be stretched
between your armpits in one tight knot
Enough! In a minute
you'll be looking right through
at all my internal organs!
Let me see
It's her right shoulder that's stiff
He knows!
He was rubbing your left hand
Shush!
It's burning.
Burning?
Your meat, on the barbeque
Why don't you pay attention
to your own business?
Mr. Chu, thank you
I've just begun
You've got a complicated problem
It would take over a year of treatment
to get results
What a bother!
Okay, don't break me apart
Jeremy, let's go play frisbee
Oh goody, goody
I want to look now
Don't go too far, you hear me?
Okay
Mr. Chu, your kung-fu is so powerful
how do you manage
to have such elegant calligraphy?
I'm ashamed to talk about it
My grandfather
was a Ching Dynasty Scholar
my father was one of the founders
of the Nationalist government
My son is a Ph. D. in computer science
In the middle of this line
there's worthless me
Fate and circumstances
pushed me to spend my life
practising martial arts
You shouldn't say that
I had bad health when I was a kid
I'm an only son
My family was worried
They took one of the doctor's advice
and made me practise kung-fu
I couldn't take the hard styles
I could only take the gentle styles
like Tai Chi Chuan
Who would have thought that
a couple of years later
I was completely vigorous and healthy
At 30
I won a national
Tai Chi Pushing Hands Championship
Exercising the body and teaching students
That's a relatively simple,
trouble-free life
What's good?
Since the communist liberation
I've been persecuted in every movement
Let's not talk about it
Teaching students has hurt me so much
Yes
Have you gone back to see your old home
and relatives since Taiwan loosened up?
Last year
I went back but I don't have any
close relatives, just a few nieces
and nephews
Still, a reunion with your family
it must have been a happy time
Not really
When I left, they weren't born
I felt like Santa Claus
giving so many gifts
None of them were born when I left!
Beijing seemed to have
lost its flavor
the old warmth was gone
But I was very young when I left 40 years ago
maybe my memories are mistaken
Anyway
I don't know what it was
everything seemed unreal. I couldn't
put my old and new impression together
Your impressions are not mistaken
Beijing has changed a lot
Is that so?
When I talk with you, I feel closer
to you than with my neighbors in Beijing
Really?
Relax, don't move
Ma, you're still in one piece
You child!
We're going to take the kids up the hill
Don't go too far.
Okay
Don't leave us here!
I'm going with you
Ma, it's a steep climb
You won't make it
I'll take it slow
Come on! Let's get everything cleaned up
and put in the car
Let the young folks go ahead
You take it slow
No, I'm fine
How come your son-in-law
didn't come today?
Gone... gone... a... way on a bus...
business trip
If he weren't away we wouldn't have you
over for dinner
Don't mention him
He makes me angry
What about your daughter-in-law?
Ah... let's go
Chen Mama, it's too much for you
Let's go down
Nonsense! Let's go!
Don't run so fast, wait for me
Hey!
The young are so energetic
They can't slow down. Let them go ahead
I'll climb slowly with you. Why not
sit down and rest a bit
I'm old, useless
No one wants me
We're out for fun
Why get mad at the kids?
How can you be so developed in kung-fu
and not have any insight?
They set us up
Set us up?
Your precious son came to our house last week
and arranged for my daughter
to call and invite you
They thought I was taking a nap
but I heard everything
Can it be?
How come
at our age
we don't have any self-respect?
Letting two children manipulate us!
What is this?
I'm old and useless
Son, thank you for your good will
trying to fix me up with Mrs. Chen
But we still have our pride
No need to drive me out
I have the sense to leave on my own
You know the saying
'It's easier to struggle together
than to pass happy days together'
I never imagined
this would apply to us
In China
we managed to stay happily together
through so many bitter times
but here in America, with so
many fine material things
it seems there's no place in your home for me
Comparing the two
I can't help but recall the days
when you were a small, lovely boy
Don't look for me
Enjoy your life with your family
I wish you all the best
If you have time
send my regards to Mrs. Chen
and her daughter
The world is so big
I'll find a little room
where I can spend my worthless old age
Life passes before one's eyes like smoke.
Nothing but emptiness
One shouldn't set one's heart on anything
Father
Thank you, come again
Bye-bye
Please, faster
if I can't put out the soup
my other dishes can't go out
I'll wash you a bowl
Sorry
Thanks
Old Chu, I beg you please, faster
Coming...
Why do you keep sending out
the take-out orders?
There's guests at the tables
with nothing to eat!
And a line around the block!
We can't put out the food
without dishes!
Yesterday at the employment agency
you said you had experience!
More or less
I'm running a business to make money
not to invite you for dinner
What do you mean more or less
This is less!
Yeah... don't get mad, I'm hurrying
You have to soak the honey banana
ball plates in hot water
Don't just scrape them!
You break the plate, you pay for it!
Yes...
Hey, Boss
Do us a favor, let's quit selling
those dick-haired honey banana balls?
It's hard for us to make and
hard for him to wash. It's not worth it
I'll decide if it's worth it
If you don't like making them
go work somewhere else
Just a good-hearted suggestion
Thanks!
What are you three guys stuck here for?
Waiting for bowls
Can't you do something else while you wait?
Are your brain dead?
There's nothing else to do!
Are the Mu Shu Pork pancakes steamed?
In the steamer
The pickled cabbage is out
The wontons are boiling
the forks are cleaned
the tables are cleared
the checks are paid
Chu
here's today's pay
Thank you
This isn't working out
Don't come tomorrow
I'll find someone else
Boss he's going okay now
Enough
No Problem
there were enough dishes
What do you mean enough dishes?
No problem?
It was only after the dinner rush hour
that thing returned to normal
Don't plead for him because he's old
Lots of young guys would fight for the chance
to make 700 dollars a month washing dishes
Why should I have an old man?
I'm not running an old folks home
Boss, please give me another chance
We all have to start somewhere. Right?
Okay... One more chance
Thank you
Is Sergeant Warren there?
It's Alex Chu... yes
No?
Thanks Sargeant. Bye bye
Linda. It's Alex
Let's have a talk... about the house
Hey, congratulations on your review:
You're a bold new voice in women's fiction
Better late then never
I'm really proud of you, although
the whole thing makes me feel like I should quit
my job and become a painter
In the meantime, all I do is eat
Maybe you're pregnant
Sure, if you believe in immaculate conception
I'm even thinking of going to my high
school reunion to see
if there's any aging jocks still available
Linda!
Well at least I have my work
How's yours coming?
Two chapters this week
Oh, more travails of sturdy pioneer women
Actually, I've written in a Chinese family
The father brought over to work
on the railroads
Don't tell me you miss the old geezer?
Of course not
Runaway Grandpa
I am gonna have nightmares
for the rest of my life
imagining his face
on the side of my milk carton
It's sad
And Alex...
He blames you, does he?
No, he's just anxious. I blame myself
How can I let you do this?
You'd better do your own work
Don't worry about me
Once I get busy
I won't be able to help you anyway
Wu, thanks a lot
but everyone's got work to do
Don't treat me special. I'll manage
Chu, this is for you, I got someone
Boss, I've been doing all right
Eight bowls, five plates
it's only 6:30p.m.
You need those two to help you
What happens at 7:30
when the guests are lined up outside the door?
He didn't ask for help, we volunteered
You volunteered, fine!
He asked for help, fine!
I don't care. I can't take any risks tonight
Liu go downstairs and get yourself an apron
Here's ten dollars. Take it or leave it
Boss, why do you have to treat
an old man this way?
I'll wash faster
Not just faster but clean too!
Come on, cut the crap, go!
This is money
Have you heard that before?
Probably not, being from the mainland
I know everything's shared there.
Working more gets you nothing
Four decades of such thinking produced
all you lazy bums
Who are you calling a lazy bum?
Eh? What's wrong? You don't accept that?
Then go back to China and live off
your relatives. Go on!
No one's stopping you
I'm telling you, this is America
There's no communal property
You have to earn everything
yourself!
If you want to be American
then why don't you go all the way
and buy a dishwasher
It'll wash faster and cleaner
Yeah! I'm offering you ten dollars
because I respect your age
I'm saving face for you
if you don't want that
I'll throw you out!
See if you can
Don't think I won't touch you
because you're old
Come try me!
If you can move me half a step
I won't say another word
I'll turn and leave
Don't
So the old geezer knows kung-fu
No wonder you dared be so arrogant with me!
Oww! Li, Wu, help me!
I'm not getting involved in this
Cooks, Chang, Chien, get over here!
Boss, this is none of our business
Do you want to keep working here?
Quick
Old Chu, don't get angry
but we've all got families to take care of
We'll just move you half a step, okay?
Then the business will keep going
Everyone, thank you
Come on, careful now
Get him!
Liu, help out!
Wu, help!
Go and help
Chu, you're a hero. We can't move you
We brothers apologize
Boss Huang, we quit
Go find yourself some of those thick-
skinned types with big muscles
I can't take this
Hey, you can't all leave!
Okay! I'm calling every employment agency!
Don't think you'll work in New York again!
Fuck you!
All right tough guy!
The business is closed tonight
But I'm calling the cops on you!
I don't have a green card
You hired me illegally
They'll fine you three thousand dollars
I'm telling you
I'll move you without the cops!
Thank you, come again
Grab him! He's like an eel
He's like a slimy fish
Yeah, I've seen this kind before
Ten police officers from the Fifth Precinct
were injured earlier this evening
in a brawl inside a Chinatown restaurant
Helen Wong reports
Shirley, I'm standing
in front of the Lai Fu restaurant
The owner Frankie Huang
tried to fire his 70-year old dishwasher
here earlier this evening
But Huang got more than he bargained for
Because the man he tried to fire, Mr. Chu
refused to leave the restaurant
Alex
Police said that Mr. Chu is a Tai Chi master
and he let lose a 130 pounds
of martial arts fury
on more than a dozen of New York's finest
Now it appears that Mr. Chu's being led
out of the restaurant by police
and is being put into a squad car
and taken down to the precinct and arrested
Reporting live, this is Helen Wong
now back to you in the studio
He's been like this
ever since he came in
The entire time he's been here
he hasn't said anything
nor has he had anything to eat or drink
I tell you I don't know
if he's meditating or sleeping
If you don't mind me saying so Mr. Chu
it's, it's kind of depressing
I'll let you go in and talk to him
Thank you, Officer
Any time
Dad
Ah, attaining nothingness isn't easy
Dad, we've bought a new house
it's much bigger than the old one
What for?
I'm here to take you home
Home? Whose home?
My home is your home!
Forget it. I see clearly now
the only thing that matters
is that you have a happy life
If you want to show me some filial respect
get me
an apartment in Chinatown
Let me peacefully pass my days there
disciplining my spirit
In your free time bring the boy to see me
This way when we get together
there'll still be some good feelings
Dad
all these years I've studied and worked hard
and built my family
in order that one day
I could bring you to America
so you could have some good days in your life
Dad!
Alex, can you give a hand up here?
Okay, coming up
Is this straight?
Lower in the left
Yeah, it's fine
Do you think he'll ever spend a night here?
Oh, yes. As long as Jeremy is here
Grandpa will visit
Jeremy wants to be a Tai Chi master
Why didn't you ever learn
any Tai Chi from your father?
You know, for Dad
Tai Chi was a way to escape from reality
Even when he did pushing hands, for him
it was a way to avoid other people
Pushing hands?
Yeah, it's like Tai Chi for two
A way of keeping your balance
while unbalancing your opponent
Like marriage... only kidding
Okay, you stand like this...
Balanced?
Yep
If you try to unbalance me
I simply avoid your energy
and turn it back on you
Relax
Don't resist and don't break contact
Feel it?
Step out and collect
Moving up on left
Collect and moving up
Turn to right
Hugging your back
Hand down
Turn back and attack
Get back
Spread your legs
Get in
Squat down
Collect
Swing hands and step forward
Moving forward
Get in and spread your fingers
Step back and collect
Hook
Get in
Sweep
Turn hands
Single whip
Very good...
Relax, relax your whole body
Relax your hips and get lower down
Relax...
Good, raise your arms up
Relax a little with your
eyes looking into the distance
Mrs. Chen, long time no see
You've come a long way to buy groceries
No, not far. I live in the area
Your daughter moved?
No, I moved
That's great! Living on your own, you're free
You can do whatever you want
I just finished shopping
saw it was early and decided
to stop by your class
How did you know I was teaching here?
Wow! Who doesn't know about
the hero old Mr. Chu
famous all over Chinatown
The TV news showed that you knocked flat
a gang of American police and Chinese hoodlums
From what I can see if
Tai Chi Chuan could be practised upside down
the ceiling of this old age centre
would be packed with your students
You're making fun of me!
I'm speaking the truth
did you make a fortune?
No way
Every morning I come here
and pass the time with the students
Anyway we old folks
have nothing but time to kill
I earn my own money
and don't take anybody's flack
That's why I always say
you can't hold everything inside
Sometimes you've got to lose your temper
to straighten things out
The kids are grown up
If we old folks don't
take care of ourselves
who will?
You're right
Is your shoulder better?
Better?
At my age, I just thank the heavens
that it doesn't get worse
I don't know kung-fu like you
But is it convenient living alone?
It's all right
My daughter comes to see me every two
or three weeks
when she goes shopping around here
she cooks and eats with me
Uhhhh. That's good. Alex
and his family do the same
You'd better take care of your students
I'm leaving now
When you're free, stop by
We're neighbours now
Well, take care
You too
Mrs. Chen!
Why did you come out?
To see if you had left
The sun is so pleasant today
I was thinking, I'm just one person
I could go home or stay out
both would be good
Anyway, standing here I got lost in thought
Where do you live?
I live in that building, number 1068
I live in that building, number 20101
Stop by for a visit sometime
Do you have anything to do this afternoon?
Uh... Nothing