Shanghai, 1910
(DRUMS BEATING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
My lords, ladies and gentlemen,
today's competition will be
between the four representatives
of the Foreign Chamber of Commerce
and Huo Yuanjia of the
Jingwu Sports Federation.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Whichever side falls first
or signals to admit defeat
shall lose the match.
(RINGING)
Start!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(IN ENGLISH)
What's going on?
(BELL CLANGS)
(YELLING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Good.
Good fighting, Master!
(GRUNTING)
(YELLING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
JUDGE: The fourth and final
contest will now begin.
The competitors are Tanaka
from Japan
against Huo Yuanjia from the
Jingwu Sports Federation.
Tianjin, Huo's home,
30 years ago.
(EXCLAIMING)
(GASPS)
Young Master, we must leave.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Stop!
How dare you!
Who gave you permission
to come in?
I am bringing you tea.
How many times have I said
you are not allowed in here?
Go practice
your calligraphy.
Go on.
(EXCLAIMING)
I do your homework everyday.
You'd be in trouble
if your father knew.
Don't say anything,
and no one will know.
Come. I want to
show you something.
Nong Jinsun, come on!
I'm coming!
WOMAN: Look,
they're fighting again.
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(DRUM BEATING)
Today's match is between
Huo Engdi of the Huo Clan
and Zhao Zhongqiang
of the Zhao Clan.
Why are you two here?
Looking for trouble?
Your father will lose today.
Our Huo wushu will beat your Zhao wushu.
You wait and see.
The death waiver
has been signed.
Win or lose, it's up to you.
Live or die, it's up to God.
Gentlemen,
let the contest begin!
Zhao, now your father
has tasted Huo wushu!
(GASPING)
The winner is
Zhao Zhongqiang!
Thank you!
Yuanjia, let's go home.
Yuanjia, come on.
Let's go home.
Look who's here.
Has the cat got your tongue?
Don't be a wuss.
Act like a man. Get up!
Zhao, you've gone too far!
You shut up!
You're worthless.
Your Huo wushu is
even more worthless.
Fight me if you dare.
Then you'll know
Zhao wushu.
Get up there!
(SCREAMING)
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
Yuanjia, stop!
Stop!
Now that you've had a taste of my
wushu, you can shut up about yours.
Yuanjia. Get up, Yuanjia.
Yuanjia,
let's get out of here.
I, Huo Yuanjia,
swear never to
be defeated again!
On your knees.
You're fighting again?
You don't study.
All you do is cause trouble.
Lai.
Yes.
Bring the whip.
He's already hurt.
There is no need
to beat him again.
Master.
Lai, take him to his room.
Go write Confucius' doctrine
10 times.
I want it before dinner.
Understood?
Yes.
Young Master, let me
put some medicine on it.
Lai, you may leave.
Yes.
Why are you upset?
Mother, why doesn't
Father teach me wushu?
Because Father
cares about you.
You have asthma.
The training is too much
for you.
But it can make me strong.
You want to learn it
just to be strong?
When I'm good enough,
I'll take revenge.
I want Zhao to feel
our Huo wushu.
My child,
wushu is not about winning.
It's about discipline
and self-restraint.
One practices wushu for inner
strength and to help the weak.
Wushu is not for revenge.
In order for others
to respect you,
you must first learn
how to respect others.
If I'm really good,
everyone will fear me.
Fear and respect
are two different things.
Now, do your penance.
Don't make your father angry.
(EXCLAIMING)
lwon!
Fly! Fly!
You're falling down, falling.
I'm not falling.
Then Father knocks you down.
I'm not falling down.
Faster.
Be careful with her.
(JADE GIGGLING)
Good morning, Mother.
Yuanjia, you didn't
take your medicine again.
Mother, since I began
training, my asthma has gone.
Look at your daughter.
You've spoiled her
since her mother died.
Your daughter
needs a mother.
You should marry again.
Mother, I am too busy building
up the family reputation.
Soon, everyone in Tianjin
will respect the Huo name.
There's no time for marriage.
Father, I want to
go to see your fight.
All these years,
you haven't lost once.
You are your most
formidable enemy.
Your biggest challenge
is to win over yourself.
I understand.
Challenge Letter
Young Master.
Oh, yes.
Mother,
why not go take a rest?
Father,
your fist wasn't fast enough,
and your heart
wasn't hard enough.
Rest assured,
as long as I live,
the Huo clan
will never lose again.
Huo Yuanjia's Death Waiver
I'll be
the Champion of Tianjin.
Father!
Jade.
For me?
No.
Please?
When do I get it?
When you win.
Really?
Yes.
Promise?
MAN: Master Huo, we expect
a good fight from you.
Huo Yuanjia,
when will you be
the champion of Tianjin?
I don't know.
What do you think?
Today! It'll be today!
Death Waiver
Come up!
I have fought in 38 cities
in 17 provinces
and remain undefeated.
Get up here!
Let's wait and see.
The death waiver
has been signed.
Let the contest begin!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Come! Come on up!
What's the matter? Scared?
Afraid you'll fall
and hurt yourself?
You wish!
(CROWD CHEERING)
Great!
Master! Great!
I am unyielding
like a mountain,
and my legs
are like strong bedrock.
Today,
Huo wushu becomes history.
Fine, you'll have
your chance to lose!
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
Cat's paw?
Tiger's claw!
Give up!
Great!
Did you think you'd win so easily?
Cat's paw.
Tiger's claw!
(BONES CRACKING)
You've lost!
Be careful!
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
Master!
Are you okay?
Fine.
So you're still alive.
The winner is
Huo Yuanjia!
(DRUMS BEATING)
Thank you.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(ALL CHATTERING)
This way, please,
Master Huo.
Yuanjia!
Jinsun!
You've just arrived?
Your usual table is ready.
MAN 1: Congratulations! MAN 2:
Master Huo, congratulations!
Thanks, thanks.
JINSUN: Come on, drink up.
Jinsun, your restaurant
is more popular than ever.
Thanks to all my friends,
it's getting by.
When we were young,
you were such a nerd.
Who could imagine you'd become
such a great businessman?
No one will pay me
to read books all day,
but being a businessman?
It's a living.
Yuanjia,
you must try these.
I've recruited the best chefs
from across the country.
Have a taste.
Tell me what you think.
Come, come, eat!
MAN: Master, after you.
I'm Xia Xiang.
I'm Xu Dashan.
Please take us
as your disciples.
We want to learn wushu, and
we'll devote ourselves to you.
Good.
You look tough enough.
Give them drinks.
Bottoms up
and we'll all be brothers.
Cheers!
Master Huo, congratulations!
(ALL CHEERING)
Tonight is a joyous occasion.
Everything's on me.
Enjoy! Have a seat!
It's time for bed.
Go tuck her in.
Miss, it's time for bed.
Be a good girl. Come on.
It's bedtime. Come on.
What is this? It tastes horrible!
It's called coffee.
A Western thing.
Not used to it, are you?
These are turbulent times.
Our country has grown weak.
The West is dominating us.
People like me must not be
concerned only with money.
People like you should not be
concerned only with fighting.
Our country deserves better.
Politics is for intellectuals.
Being the champion of Tianjin
is all I care about.
It's that important to you?
Come.
Let me show you something.
HUO: You've only watched
from below.
Now you're standing up here.
Do you feel the difference?
What difference?
When you are down there,
life and death up here
have nothing to do with you.
It's all entertainment.
But when you are up here,
you have to win.
Losing is not an option.
But you can choose
not to be here.
Jinsun, listen.
To what?
I don't hear anything.
I can hear.
MAN: Master Huo,
you're our hero!
Huo Yuanjia is
champion of the world!
Here comes my Head of Iron!
(BONES CRACKING)
Thanks a lot.
That's great!
This is taking too long.
Get everyone who has signed a
waiver to come up at once.
All you challengers,
get up there!
Huo Yuanjia, when will
you be champion of Tianjin?
What do you think?
Today! It'll be today!
What's the matter?
We seek to be your disciples
and devote ourselves to you.
Fine, you may join.
A round for everyone.
Come on, give them drinks!
MAN: Master Huo,
you're great!
Bottoms up
and we'll all be brothers!
Come on, come on.
Master Huo, congratulations!
See you. Have a good day.
H U O: Let's toast.
Master Huo's bills
are long overdue.
It's okay.
A toast!
Bring a bigger jug!
You're not drinking?
Now you must drink two more!
You have not fought
my godfather, Master Chin.
JINSUN: Yuanjia,
you've won
38 fights in a row
and defeated
every fighter in Tianjin.
There's no one left.
No, you're wrong. There's
still one left to beat.
So you're not
going to stop?
I have to fight in order to be
the true champion of Tianjin.
What about elsewhere?
Beijing, Guangdong, Hunan?
When will you stop?
I know what you're saying.
I cannot stop now.
I can only keep on fighting.
I need to prove that I am
the best, the strongest.
For what?
Yuanjia,
I think you need to
take a break and reconsider.
What's this?
These are bills
from this month's drinking
and eating
with your disciples.
I'll take care of it.
Of all your freeloading friends
and so-called disciples,
only a couple
are true brothers to you.
In Jianhu,
this is called brotherhood.
Brother...
Fine.
I will settle
the bills tomorrow.
Yuanjia, I am not here
for your money.
Friends should be sincere.
Disciples should be loyal.
Judge them by their integrity,
not by their drinking.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Good morning, Master Huo!
Good morning, Master Chin!
Aren't you the self-proclaimed
champion of Tianjin?
What a coincidence.
Master Chin,
it's been a long time.
At your age,
I thought you'd retired.
So many new disciples
want to join my school,
I couldn't retire
even if I wanted to.
Is that so?
Congratulations on the purchase
of a coffin for your retirement.
You're too kind.
Actually,
this is my gift to you.
Your master needs help.
MAN: Master Chin,
this way, please.
Young Master,
the income of the wushu school barely
oovers the household overhead.
The expenses incurred by your disciples
are getting bigger and bigger.
What about
the household reserve?
It's been depleted
for three months.
Depleted?
Master! Master!
How many times have I told
you to hone your skills?
No one listens.
Who did this?
Master Chin.
Master.
Tonight, we celebrate
Master Chin's birthday,
wishing Master Chin
a long and prosperous life.
Terrific!
Godfather,
we wish you good fortune
and great health.
Great!
Master Huo, today's
my godfather's birthday.
These tables are reserved.
As a favor to me,
please drink somewhere else.
Please do me a favor.
You don't qualify
to speak to me.
I'm not in the mood
to fight on my birthday.
Maybe some other time.
As a master, you should
be ashamed of yourself.
You injured my disciple.
I'm here to settle the score.
What do you want?
Here is my signature.
Sign yours if you dare.
Otherwise,
kneel down and apologize.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
Let me through. Yuanjia!
You've crossed the line.
Let's not do this
in front of all the guests.
My disciple is hurt.
I must do something.
I don't care what happened, you
mustn't spoil their celebration.
I'm not here
to spoil anything.
Yuanjia. You're afraid I
might trash your place?
I'll pay for all damages.
I can't believe
you just said that.
You should go.
Forget that
we've ever been friends.
You're asking me to leave?
You're willing to
throw away our friendship?
My sword seeks vengeance.
Everybody out!
Stay at your own peril.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(THUNDER CRASHING)
(BONES SNAPPING)
Master!
ALL: The Master has won!
Let's drink!
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
JINSUN: Master Huo.
Congratulations.
Like you wished, you're finally
the champion of Tianjin.
You might like to know
Master Chin
died two hours ago.
Huo Yuanjia!
When will you be
the champion of Tianjin?
It'll be today!
Huo Yuanjia!
Champion of Tianjin!
Today is the day!
Mother!
(sesame)
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
(WOMAN WAILING)
Yes, I killed your family.
I am responsible.
Godmother, take good care.
(SCREAMING)
(sesame)
Tell Master the truth!
Master, I'm very sorry.
It's all my fault.
I got drunk. I insulted
Master Chin's concubine.
He was defending his honor,
and that's how I got injured.
Master.
All the disciples knew,
but nobody told you.
Master.
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(GIGGLING ECHOING)
He has a fever.
I'll make him some herbs
and he'll be fine.
That's great.
Leave him alone.
Let's go. Let him sleep.
(MAN SCREAMING)
(MAN SOBBING)
(ROOSTER CROWING)
Let's eat.
My eyesight began to fail
when I was 13.
Everything turned blurry.
I cried a lot.
My grandma told me,
"Cry if you are sad.
"When there are no more tears,
life will go on."
I can see
everything in my heart.
Do you believe me?
I'll wash your hair.
Your hair will get knotted
if you don't wash it often.
Grandma always says,
"Cleanliness brings
purity to life."
Every knot can be untangled.
Ox!
Ox, you sleep a lot.
You sleep as much as our ox.
That's why we call you Ox.
Come this way.
Let's catch some dragonflies.
(BUZZING)
Cheer up.
You will get over it.
Eat something.
Tomorrow, you should take
him to work in the fields.
He'll feel better.
Yes.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
Ox.
Ox, Ox, Ox,
come, quick. Come on.
Come over.
Look. Moon told me
not to say anything.
You did a bad job.
She is re-planting for you.
Crops have lives of their own.
If you plant them too olose
together, they will not grow.
Just like people, they
need to respect each other
in order to
live together peacefully.
I'll always remember.
Grandma, let's eat.
Sure.
Grandma!
Moon.
Yes, Grandma?
It'll be the Day of the Dead
in a few days.
We should visit
your parents' graves.
Yes.
Have a drink of water.
Can we talk?
You are leaving?
I was thinking that maybe I
should visit my parents' graves.
Family is important.
You should go.
I'll come back soon.
You have been here
for so many years.
Yet, I've always known
that one day you would leave.
The truth is, I...
Take these clean clothes
for your trip.
You don't even know
my real name.
You don't have to tell me.
I don't need to know
where you're from
or where you're going.
You will always be Ox to me.
My name is Huo Yuanjia.
I'll always remember.
Tianjin, 1907
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(CAMELS GRUNTING)
(CLAMORING)
God's words
are in this book!
It's the truth!
He is speaking to us!
SOLDIER: (IN ENGLISH)
One, two. One, two. One, two.
(m ENGLISH) You stink!
MAN: (IN ENGLISH) Come
on, get off me! Letgo!
Huo Yuanjia!
Champion of Tianjin!
Huo Yuanjia has returned
to the ring!
Young Master.
Lai.
You've finally returned.
Let me take your bag.
Please forgive me. I haven't
kept the house in order.
Young Master,
please forgive me.
I did my best
to keep everything the way
it was for you to return home.
It must have been
very hard for you.
I'm sorry
for not doing better.
After you left,
the creditors came every day,
tearing this place apart.
The house
was almost foreclosed.
We would have
lost everything,
but someone sent money.
I later realized
it was your good friend,
Mr. Nong Jinsun.
I don't need these anymore.
Neither do my parents.
Father, please forgive me.
I've finally realized
why you held back
the last blow.
You are the true champion
of Tianjin.
Mother,
you taught me
how to be a good person.
I was too arrogant
to understand.
Rest assured, I will not
disappoint you again.
My dear Jade,
I didn't take
good care of you.
You suffered because of me.
I was not a good father.
Get out of here,
you filthy scum!
You come here with no money?
LWlbeatyou
if I ever see you again.
Get off the premises at once!
Master!
Master. Master, forgive us.
Forgive us.
I studied wushu
with you all my life.
I know no other way
of making a living.
The foreigners are in control
of Tianjin now.
We have no jobs.
It's so great
to have you back.
Master, please forgive us.
You can get up.
WOMAN: Extra! Extra!
The Westerner,
Hercules O'Brien,
has defeated
every challenger in China
with his brutal fists!
He is the champion
of the world!
He calls all Chinese
"weak men of the East."
No one dares to challenge him.
HUO: Jinsun.
I know you can't forgive me,
but I wanted
to come and see you.
I don't want to talk
about the past.
What do you want?
Jinsun.
It's hard for me to ask,
but you're the only one
I can turn to.
I need to borrow some money.
What for? Another fight?
Yes.
I need some money
to go to Shanghai.
The prize money
is important to me.
If it's for another fight,
then you can
forget about the loan.
Hercules O'Brien Vows to Defeat
"Weak Men of the East."
Mrs. Chin, I am very sorry
for what I have done.
Please allow me
to pay my respects.
Mother! Mother!
Young Master.
Master Huo, my master
wants you to have this.
To Huo Yuanjia
Who's your master?
His name is Nong,
Nong Jinsun.
Shanghai Horse Racing Club,
(MARCHING BAND PLAYING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(IN ENGLISH)
Ladies and gentlemen,
(IN CHINESE) today,
you are about to meet a man
who can move a train
with one hand
and punch through the Great
Wall with his bare fist.
He can kill a Chinese fighter
with his little finger.
Now, let's welcome the
strongest man in history,
O'Brien!
Today's challenger is
Huo Yuanjia of Tianjin!
Sign the death waiver.
Please inform him
that taking a life
in a competition
is a cruel and backward
Chinese tradition.
May I suggest that we compete
with honor and civility.
(IN ENGLISH)
He wants to kick your butt.
(IN ENGLISH) Come on! Come on! (IN
CHINESE) Let the match begin!
(IN ENGLISH) Come on! Yeah!
Come on!
Come on.
(BONES CRACKING)
(YELLING)
(IN CHINESE) Great fight!
(CROWD BOOING)
It's an honor.
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(GROANING)
Thank you.
That was great!
(IN ENGLISH) Come On!
Chinese Martial Artist Defeats
US Champion O'Brien
Huo Yuanjia Calls for All
Martial Artists to Be United
Huo Yuanjia ls Starting
the Jingwu Sports Federation
(IN ENGLISH) Thank you once again.
Thank you.
(IN CHINESE) Master, you've
received a dinner invitation.
I didn't know
the invitation was from you.
When did you
come to Shanghai?
Your friendship
is important to me.
Very important.
Come, have a seat, Yuanjia.
Here, your favorite wine.
What's the matter?
I've stopped drinking.
A long time ago.
But you used to love to drink.
I've learnt from my mistakes.
That's wonderful.
Let's have tea instead.
Yuanjia.
Your victory gained respect
for all Chinese people.
The foreigners have
bullied us for too long.
Someone should
stand up to them.
Why do foreigners
look down on us?
Because we're not united.
It's a fact. For years, we
fought, Chinese against Chinese.
That's why
the West belittles us.
"Weak men of the East,"
what an insult!
But that isn't
the worst of it.
Some of us don't even realize
how sick the country is.
You really understand
what's going on.
Jinsun,
when do you return to Tianjin?
I'm going to
stay here in Shanghai.
What about your restaurant?
I sold it.
What?
But it was so profitable.
The Jingwu Sports Federation
needs start-up funds.
But the restaurant
has been your life.
My restaurant means little
compared to your vision.
Yuanjia, I don't know wushu,
but I do know how to help.
I hope it will be enough.
Jingwu Sports Federation
As we've discussed, the
Jingwu Federation handbook.
Take a look.
"The Jingwu motto
has three parts:
"body, mind and soul.
"Wushu is a way to cultivate
one's body, mind and soul.
"All wushu disciplines
are respected equally.
"By working together,
"we can better ourselves
"and stand strong
as one nation."
We influence others
through cooperation,
not intimidation.
Through this ideal,
we will always stand strong!
Ready?
(IN ENGLISH) Well, gentlemen,
it's too rich for me.
I only bet on sure things.
Then perhaps you'd be interested
in joining our little wager
against this Yuanjia fellow.
I've suggested a competition
of four matches
between our countries' best
against him.
We beat him and leave the Chinese
with nothing to brag about.
Mita, you are certain
Yuanjia will lose?
With what I have in mind,
our victory is guaranteed.
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
Yuanjia.
One of the Japanese
contestants,
Tanaka, wishes to meet you.
Ihear
he remains undefeated.
Good, one can always
learn from the best.
Yuanjia, I suspect that the
Foreign Chamber of Commerce
might have a hidden agenda.
How can they set up
a four-against-one contest?
I suspect it is
an attempt to humiliate us
and undermine the Jingwu
Sports Federation in Shanghai.
You're right.
Four against one is unfair,
and I have to win every match.
Yet who is to guarantee that
everything in life is fair?
For the sake
of the Federation,
I have no other choice.
What if...
Jinsun, there's something
I want to ask you.
What is it?
After the contest, I need
you to run the Federation.
Why?
I want to visit
Moon and Grandma.
I promised Moon
I would return.
Do you know anything
about teas, Mr. Huo?
I don't really want to know
because I don't like categories.
Tea is tea.
Each has its own characteristics,
hence different grades.
What's the purpose
of grading?
All teas are grown in nature with
little discernable differences.
Once you learn,
you can tell the difference.
Maybe you're right.
The way I see it,
the tea is not in a position
to judge itself.
We should let people
be the judge of the tea.
As for me,
I don't want to do that.
Why not?
When you are in a good mood,
the grade of the tea
does not matter.
I've never seen it that way.
Even with the various wushu
styles, you still claim
that no one style
is superior to the others?
That's what I believe.
Then I have another question.
If no particular style
is superior,
why have
so many competitions?
I believe it is impossible to claim the
superiority of one style over another.
It's just that the people who practice
them have different skill levels.
Competitions can help us
uncover our weaknesses
and discover that
we are our own true enemy.
Mr. Huo,
your words are poignant.
Please enjoy.
Thank you.
The fourth and final contest
will now begin.
In this round,
Tanaka of Japan will fight
Huo Yuanjia of China's
Jingwu Sports Federation.
(IN JAPANESE) This is unfair.
Four against one?
You never told me.
Both the Chamber of Commerce
and the Federation agreed.
Don't be concerned.
This is not a competition.
This is murder.
Tanaka, you're overreacting.
Huo Yuanjia has fought the best
fighters from around the world
and has won every time.
He agreed to the rules.
Mr. Mita,
what's your deal?
Is this really for Japan's national pride?
Or did you place a large bet?
To compete is to win.
(m CHINESE) Begin!
Master Huo,
this is an unfair contest.
If you wish to fight
at some other time,
it would be fine with me.
I appreciate
your thoughtfulness.
We started the fight.
Let's finish it.
Please.
Begin!
Great! That's great!
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(BELL DINGING)
This round is even.
The next round
will be a fistfight.
Please prepare.
(COUGHING)
Yuanjia!
Time out!
(IN JAPANESE)
What are you doing, Tanaka?
What's going on?
What is he doing?
(BELL DINGING)
Yuanfla!
Tanaka!
(m ENGLISH) Go now! Go!
(IN CHINESE) Yuanjia,
what happened?
Poison.
Poison?
What poison?
How did this happen?
What do you need?
Tea...
Tea!
What's wrong with the tea?
The tea is poisoned,
but the evidence is gone.
Yuanjia, we're going to the hospital.
Too late.
I've exerted
too much strength.
The toxin is in my blood.
Master,
let me take revenge!
Zhensheng,
we must not take revenge.
Revenge only brings
more bloodshed.
That's not what I want.
We must strive
to better ourselves.
Yuanjia,
forget the competition.
We're going to the hospital.
Let's go.
Jinsun,
I'm just a fighter.
It took me years to understand
the true meaning of wushu
and its purpose.
The competition is not over.
One cannot choose
how one's life begins,
but one can choose
to face the end with courage.
Master.
(IN JAPANESE) What are you doing?
Finish him off!
Why do you say that?
It's not for you to decide.
Whatever it takes, just win.
(IN CHINESE) Stand strong!
Stand strong! Stand strong!
(ALL CHANTING)
(IN JAPANESE)
You really want to win?
(IN CHINESE) Let's stop.
Treasure your life.
Listen to them.
It's not just about me.
If you want to continue,
I won't hold back.
It would be my honor.
Young Master.
(IN ENGLISH) Mister! Mister!
Yuanjia is down. Go! Go!
Go! Go!
Make the announcement!
(IN JAPANESE) Wait!
(COUGHING)
Huo Yuanjia!
Yuanjia! Yuanjia!
CROWD: Huo Yuanjia!
Huo Yuanjia! Huo Yuanjia!
(IN JAPANESE) Tanaka, you son of a bitch!
What is this?
I lost.
Who said you lost?
I know it in my heart.
I lost. Fair and square.
Who do you think you are?
You have no right to decide!
You are not Japanese!
You are a disgrace to Japan.
CROWD: Huo Yuanjia!
Huo Yuanjia! Huo Yuanjia!