Once you start asking
questions, you can't stop.
You see, good health makes a lot of sense,
but it doesn't make a lot of dollars.
And not considering nutrition seriously,
we've done a terrible
disservice to all these people.
Every single person in the world,
every culture, every
language, every country,
every person in the world knows it,
you are what you eat.
Food does matter.
The Supermarket:
symbol of the high standard of living
in this country today.
These products come from farms and ranches
despite distance and season.
They are the result of a
miraculous agriculture,
maintaining farm fresh quality
all the way to your dinner table.
How old is your Food?
If you think about it, your
food really, in the best of times
is traveling between fifteen hundred
and two thousand miles before you get it
and is at least a week old.
Which becomes the next question:
How much nutrition value
are you getting from food
that's at least five days old?
And if you're lucky, you're getting maybe
fourty percent of what you need.
Nearly every food that you'll
find in the shops in a big city
has been processed,
it has been delayed to the shops
quite often nutrients have deteriorated
or disappeared from the food
by the time gets onto the plate.
We, for whatever reason, decided
we were going to spray everything
with every kind of pesticide,
herbicide, larvicide, fungicide,
we decided we were going to genetically
modify things we don't know anything about.
And one of the major
problems is of course the soil
and what we do to the soil
and the air and the water and
everything we take in our food.
Soils are used and used and used
and nutrients are drawn out of the soils
and the soils become new deserts
and that's happening worldwide.
We do really need to look
at our systems of agriculture
and what we are really eating
and how we are producing food.
The so-called fertilizer is made up
of mainly three minerals:
N, P, K, nitrogen,
phosphorous and potassium.
Well, that's nice,
but,
the problem is that the soil requires
approximately fifty-two different minerals.
So where is the calcium and the magnesium
and the manganese and the zinc
and the iron and all of the
other things I can't mention?
They're missing.
But when the soil is deficient the
plants also are deficient and weakened,
and they lose their defenses,
and the bugs come and attack them
and the diseases and
fungus come and attack them.
So now they come crying to the
chemical companies and they say
well, our plants are
dying and they won't grow
and we have pests,
and of course the chemical
companies are terribly happy
to sell them pesticides and fungicides
and growth stimulants
and all kinds of other things.
Through his intellect,
man has developed a superiority
over every other form of animal life.
From his modern chemistry, biology
and dedicated research
have come thousands of effective
chemical compounds,
all to help revolutionise the productivity
of our own agriculture.
So what were getting
even if we eat just
commercial vegetarian food
we get deficient toxic food
because with all these pesticides and
chemicals and sprays and all of that,
the food is not healthy.
And its deficient.
So we can't help but
be deficient and toxic.
And then...
Then we cook it!
And studies show that even
if you lightly steam your food
you are going to lose
the enzymes that are in it.
The simplest thing is
there are live enzymes
or live workers inside of foods
that help with your
body's digestion of foods
and the use of the
nutrients that are there,
so raw foods should be
apart of everybody's diet.
When you cook food the immune system
reacts to it as a toxin.
Most people don't know that.
When you cook your food
the body goes through a process
called digestive leukocytosis
where it starts generating white cell
activity against the cooked food you've eaten.
Presumably because the cooking process has
bastardised the food structure.
In a way that the body cannot recognise, and so
the body is now treating that food as a toxin.
That's not a good thing for your body to do to the
food that you're hoping is going to nourish you.
There was a Swiss doctor by
the name of Paul Kouchakoff
who was the first to show in the 1930's
that if you ate a diet that was more than
fifty-one percent cooked food
that your body would react to the food as if
it was being invaded by a foreign organism.
Dr. Kouchakoff was
the first to demonstrate
that if fifty-one percent
of your meals were raw
that you would have no leukocytosis.
Or you would actually have
no white blood cell reaction
so your immune system would not be
activated with a false alarm.
Because we are dealing with so many
immune system issues today
we have to make sure that at least fifty-one
percent of every meal that we have is raw,
So that we don't overburden that already
burdened immune system.
How can you build a building that
you expect to last a hundred years
if you put poor building materials in?
Same thing with your body,
how can you expect your body to last for
a long and enjoyable lifetime
if you don't put the proper
building blocks in there.
Everybody knows we are what we eat.
If you eat garbage you
are going to get garbage.
Think of it as chronic malnutrition
because that's what's going on.
That's why people look tired.
You are not supposed to
be tired in the afternoon.
You are supposed to be alive and vibrant.
This has lead people
naturally to discover super foods
and to discover certain foods have an
extraordinary quality of vitamins and minerals
and all kinds of co factors and
enzymes and special chemicals
that for example, that
will cause us to live longer,
will cause our skin to be softer etc etc.
Spirulina was consumed in Mexico City as the
primary protein source for five thousand years.
Spirulina is the highest
protein content food in the world.
The Max Planck Institute discovered
that fifty percent of protein
is destroyed in any food
once you cook the food.
Therefore, super food
plant-based protein sources
are going to be a key food of the future.
Because we can get all the protein
that we need from those sources,
they've been undamaged by heat
and they are completely absorb able.
They can be liquified easily -
that's what I am saying by absorb able.
How much energy do you think it takes to turn
Spirulina into a liquid and get it into your body?
Well you put Spirulina in
water and it's already liquified,
you drink it and it goes
right into your cells like that.
But a steak requires a massive
amount of energy to liquify it
and make it absorb able
by your digestive system.
These super foods can confer exceptional
properties to your health and well being.
Cacao beans stack up on the mineral
content against anything in the world.
It's the highest natural
source of magnesium.
source of chromium.
It's very likely the highest
natural source of iron.
natural source of manganese.
It's one of the highest contents of zinc.
It's one of the highest
contents of copper.
All the co factors needed for healthy
metabolism - it's in the cacao bean.
It's one of the highest Vitamin
C content foods in the world
but all processed chocolate has no Vitamin
C in it because heat destroys Vitamin C.
It has the highest anti-oxidant content
that means that if we are really going to take
advantage of what we have learned in nutrition
that anti-oxidants protect us from
DNA damage, viral damage, cancer,
protect us from skin damage etc etc.
It's either going to be this and then we eat
or it's going to be this and then we eat.
And this right here could be the most
horrid chemical soup of all time
or it could be the most
extraordinary super food of all time
and it's the same amount of
work to get it into our mouths.
We probably as a culture
have got our values inverted.
We would rather spend our money on rent
than we would on the best food ever.
We would rather spend
money on a car or a house
than on feeding our children the greatest super
foods that have ever been discovered in the world
because we don't know!
It's just a values inversion
because we just got confused.
We saw some program that sold us on buying
this car and suddenly we are buying that car,
when really we should take that money
and invest it into our families health
by the best food ever which is the basis.
If I eat a lousy bread roll everyday,
have a cup of tea for
breakfast, and a piece of toast,
a sugary drink for
mid-morning, a donut for lunch
and take away fried chicken at night,
I am going to be massively deficient
in a whole range of nutrients,
and that's only one day.
So I'm going to need something
in the way of supplements.
So the next day I eat salad until it's coming
out of my ears to try and make up for it
but I never ever correct the deficiency
that occurred from the day before.
There is always going to be a
residual problem somewhere
so you cannot punish yourselves without
having to pay for it sooner or later.
We are lucky,
in the last hundred years we went from
not having any vitamin supplements
to having them over the
counter and readily available.
And yet most people don't know
how important vitamins really are.
And if they take large enough doses
they can use them to prevent illness
and if they take large enough doses
they can use them to treat illness.
Once again how can that be?
I didn't hear it on the news...
in fact on the news it said,
"You shouldn't take too many of those
vitamins, it might not be a good idea."
And yet they don't provide
any evidence of that, they just say it.
Doctors say...
"I don't believe in vitamins."
Well...
We're not going to a shaman! We're
supposed to be going with scientists here.
It's not about belief; it's about facts.
Over the last twenty-three years according to the
American Association of Poison Control Centers
there have been ten-
a total of ten deaths alleged
to be caused by vitamins.
That's one zero, ten
in twenty-three years.
That's less than half a death per year,
and these are unproven, unverified but
they are attributed to vitamin consumption.
We have a nation where the
very thing that will help people
is being presented as actually dangerous.
There have been studies that purport to show
that if you take an extra multi vitamin everyday
that it's going to hurt you.
And that's just nonsense.
There are studies that purport to say that
Vitamin C will cause a kidney stone.
Well, I have searched the medical literature and I've
asked all my students to search the medical literature
and my colleagues to search it and as soon as they find
scientific evidence of a Vitamin C caused kidney stone,
send me the paper. Send me the reference.
It's been thirty years
and I’ve never gotten one.
Now either everybody is dumb...
...or it's a myth.
There is an assumption that vitamins are basically
like drugs and should be regulated like drugs.
There is an assumption that if it's therapeutically
valuable it must be dangerous because drugs are.
So we have been taught our
whole lives to be consumers,
mostly consumers to modern medicine,
which is pharmaceutical medicine.
What about drugs that
you get by prescription?
Well nowadays there are many powerful drugs that
are not safe to take without a doctor's supervision
but you can rely upon your
doctor and your pharmacist.
They're both professionally trained men.
A druggist must have received training
at an accredited college.
A doctor goes to a medical school,
gets a medical education,
practices medicine, prescribes medicines
and is called an MD.
Well let's put nutrition into
that and see how it sounds.
My doctor is a nutritionist
who went to nutritional school,
studied nutrition and has a nutritional
degree and prescribes nutrients.
It sounds very strange.
When we say I went to the doctor it is
implicit that the doctor was a medical doctor.
It surprised me in my clinical years
that nobody was interested
in the patients' diets
when I spoke to my profs,
they weren't interested in diets,
the patients weren't interested in diets
and neither were the hospitals
so diet didn't come into it.
Whenever I mentioned it - nutrition -
it was basically put to the side.
I spent time as a student at the
Brigham Hospital in Boston,
which is right next to Harvard Med.
And this, even then back in
1974 it was a crisis hospital.
There were more doctors than patients.
It was really a grim place.
And I got a chance to see and
observe the failure of medicine.
You would see people like the
one woman I remember with Leukemia
and they would give her
Jell-O and white bread to eat.
Now I am not saying that Jell-O
and white bread caused cancer
but they sure aren't the cure.
Twenty six percent of patients
who are discharged from hospitals
are more malnourished
then when they went in.
And the reason they go in,
in eighty to ninety percent of cases
is related to their
poor state of nutrition.
I started reading papers by William J.
McCormack and Frederick Robert Klenner;
the pioneers of using
high doses of Vitamin C
and these gentlemen were curing
viral disease with high doses of Vitamin C
in the 1940's!
And then I had a poser.
Now just a minute here, hold on a second.
These are medical doctors
and they're using vitamins
and they're using high doses of vitamins
and they're getting success.
But I didn't get any of this in college.
The medical profession,
medical education,
for that matter undergraduate education,
common education through
magazines and television,
all manage to walk around
the rhinoceros on the living room.
And I saw the rhinoceros
in the living room and I said:
"Hey there is a rhinoceros
in the living room!"
and there it was right in the center
this body of knowledge,
this whole body of knowledge
and the more I looked into it
the more I found.
Linus Pauling first suggested that Vitamin
C could be useful against the common cold
but this was based on quite a lot of science
at the time and not just a guess or a whim.
Pauling was of course a
colleague of Albert Einstein
and quite a large number of other
high level intellects of the time.
And he won two Nobel prizes:
one in chemistry and one in peace.
So he is a brilliant man and should
not be taken lightly.
The problem was that he was
getting in the area of clinical medicine
and he didn't have qualifications in this area
and so he was at the time very open to criticism
and his suggestion that Vitamin C would
have an effect on the common cold
was boo hoo'd by the medical profession.
And I must say that the medical profession is
not always that scientific and clear thinking.
And the other thing that
we have a problem here,
a public relations problem with nutrients,
is that one nutrient is
good for too many things.
Vitamin E is good to fight heart disease,
it's also good to put on burns,
it's also good to help reduce seizures
in teenagers that are Epileptic.
Now that's pretty diverse.
Vitamin C, let's see,
anti-toxin, anti-histamine, anti-viral,
helps regulate blood sugar, helps to
elevate mood in people that are depressed,
it's just too good for too many things
and I have an answer.
The reason one vitamin
can cure so many illnesses
is because a deficiency of one vitamin
can cause many illnesses.
There's only about two dozen nutrients
and yet in your body there are
countless thousands of chemical reactions.
So obviously anything that is
vitamin mediated we can expect
that one vitamin is going to be
involved in multiple reactions.
This is true with the minerals as well.
We have an idea that one drug one disease;
it's an old medical idea.
One drug, one disease;
the doctoring of specifics.
And that is not true with nutrition.
You cannot heal selectively.
If you truly heal, everything heals.
If a patient comes for instance not only with
cancer but with high blood pressure, and or diabetes
and maybe fibromyalgia
and other pains and so on...
...all the problems disappear.
You can't heal one disease
and keep two others; it's impossible.
When the body heals, it heals everything.
You nourish the body
and then the body fixes it.
When people take vitamins,
the vitamins don't specifically do it
they enable the body to do it,
they enable the body to heal itself.
This is a totally different
way of looking at it.
The body has what my father called
it's own healing mechanism
and he went further and said,
"It’s the doctors duty to activate and
reactivate the body's own healing mechanism."
And the patients heal
and it doesn't matter what
you called the disease.
Not one cell in the human
body is made out of a drug.
Surgery doesn't put anything into you.
They might put in
something made of plastic;
they might take out
something that is harmful.
But in the end, cutting into the body
doesn't really make it better.
Giving the body drugs
doesn't really promote health.
So what we need is a new paradigm,
we need a whole new way of looking at it.
Boosting health has not been tried yet, it's
really kind of the one thing we haven't done.
When nutrients are tested as therapy
they use very low doses
and that's why the public and physicians see all
these research papers that show ambiguous results.
One study is published and
says vitamins help a little bit
and another study is published that says
vitamins don't help very much
and you have this back and forth.
But the problem is because
all of those studies are low dose studies.
The recommended daily allowance
is the amount of a nutrient
that's required by the majority of the population
to prevent an overt deficiency disease.
That is if we give everybody in Australia
the recommended intake
of Vitamin C at 60 mg per day
then we should not see
scurvy in this country.
However we still see
If you are indulging in a high stress job
or if you have a stressful lifestyle, got
some kids, running a home, doing a job,
then the body is going to be breaking
Vitamin C as you are generating adrenaline.
This is the link between
stress and heart attacks,
that when you are stressed out
the body is making adrenaline
and is drawing down the
levels of Vitamin C in the body.
So that's going to cause a vulnerability
to your cardiovascular system
because of the lack of Vitamin C.
The medical profession just treat disease,
they don't go back to the primary causes
of a lot of things because they can't;
they don't understand what
chemicals come from exercise,
chemicals come out of meditation,
they don't understand what
chemicals come out of your food.
Where conventional medicine
misses the boat in a big way
is for long term, hard to deal with,
the chronic problems.
And the reason why they miss the boat
with the chronic problems
is because they do nothing to change the reasons
why the patient got the disease in the first place.
Basically they treat symptoms.
And if all you do is treat symptoms
you are not going to cure the disease.
What you need to do is
change the root cause.
It took me about two years of seeing
patients that should already have died
with conventional medicine
with their prognosis,
their ability to survive more than just a few months
under traditional clinical conditions was fairly limited
and most of the patients who would have
followed conventional medicine would have died.
After I had been with the
program for a couple of years
and I'd see patient after patient
so alive and getting better
and tumors going away and
multiple sclerosis disappearing
and arthritis going away and lupus going
away and all these really dramatic problems
and that's what really made me
one hundred percent fully convinced
that I was in the right line of work and
that this work really had something valuable.
Cardiovascular disease
is a disease of civilization
it is a lifestyle disease
because we are eating
too much of the wrong thing
and not enough of the right thing.
And your grandmother said it
and her grandmother said it
and everybody knows
it's true but instead...
...it's fast food and meat, and fat,
and sugar, and starch,
and processed food that has few vitamins
and don't take vitamin supplements
because they might hurt you!
Of course cardiovascular disease -
that's not the risk!
I’ve been saying for at
least twenty-five years
that cardiovascular disease is reversible.
Conventional medicine has claimed for a
longtime that it was not reversible.
To look at the cure I think
tells us something of cause.
Dr. Dean Ornish has done a really good job with
people who have severe cardiovascular disease
and he puts them on a strict diet
which is basically a vegetarian diet.
That means a plant based diet, a high fiber
diet loaded with vitamins and nutrients
and good things that grow on the ground or
at least ground that is organically tended.
Ornish also has them do stress reduction
and these people are able to arrest or reverse
cardiovascular disease in a year or two.
The cause of cardiovascular
disease therefore
is a failure to take the vitamins
and a failure to eat right.
The good news is that even people with
advanced cardiovascular disease
when they start taking the nutrients
and they change their diet
they can arrest it or
reverse it without surgery.
What amazed me is that
we have some very smart people,
we have the brightest and the best wandering the
corridors of our leading medical institutions
with unlimited budgets and they
don't seem to want to finger food
and also the western
lifestyle as being causative.
In fact about half of all deaths
are from cardiovascular disease
and in half of those deaths,
the first symptom is death.
So people can go through their life
for decades with no symptoms at all
and then drop dead and
then of course it's too late.
It’s too late for a drug, it's too late for
a bypass, it's too late for the ambulance,
it's too late for resuscitation.
If one in every two and a half people,
if you can picture such a creature,
are perishing from cardiovascular problems
that follows that society is
doing something fundamentally wrong.
The only way to win is not to play and
that requires that they change their life.
Yet what are we doing?
Every year we are doing billions
of dollars worth of bypass surgery
that can be totally controlled just by
changing the way you eat, drink, live.
Did I mention it was safer?
Did I mention it was cheaper?
And it works very well.
Therefore why don't all cardiologists
recommend this approach?
Well, in fairness not all
of them have studied it.
And in fairness...
...the drug companies have
something to say about it!
Did you notice there is
no drugs in there at all?
There is just like no drug therapy at all,
its just meditation and vegetarian diet.
There is no profit in this!
...Prozac, ADD tablets, coke, smack,
now you know I am turning tricks 'cause.
I used to get high for a livin'
believing everything that I saw on the TV
I used to get high for a livin' eatin'all
the bullshit food that you sold me...
One of the big problems with the drug
approach is the issue of side effects;
adverse drug reactions
just for a start, in the UK
the generally accepted figure
of the number of people who die each year
as a result of adverse drug reactions
is about ten thousand.
To put that into some sort of perspective
the number of people who die from motorcar
accidents is about three and a half thousand.
We are all very worried
about motorcar accidents;
we don't seem to be so worried
about adverse drug reactions.
The number of people who
die as a result of prostate cancer
which is of enormous concern
and we have campaigns and so on
is round about nine
thousand in this country.
The Journal of the American Medical
Association published papers,
which indicated that approximately
one hundred and six thousand Americans die
from pharmaceutical drugs each year.
Now these are drugs that
are properly prescribed,
not physician errors and these are
side effects that are normally expected.
And these are people who
took the medication as directed.
This doesn't count overdoses or misuses.
So if a hundred and six thousand people die
from normal expected side effects of drugs
just in America just in one year
in twenty-three years
that's an enormous number of people,
were talking millions of people
dead from pharmaceutical drugs.
And in twenty-three years -
ten allegedly dead from vitamins.
Clearly we have to be a lot
more serious about prescribing nutrition.
And as Roger Williams said,
the discoverer of panathenic acid,
when in doubt use nutrition first.
The pharmaceutical industry is
in business not to make drugs.
It’s in business to make money.
Which I think is perfectly reasonable
they are large international corporations
and they have a duty to their shareholders
and that's what corporations do,
is they make money.
We live in a capitalist society, and I
don't happen to think that is a bad thing.
And I think capitalism
has it's great advantages
and I think it can be abused roundly
and we have seen both sides of it.
The problem lies in the
way that they are regulated.
I believe we have some
very good regulators
but we've got some
very incompetent regulators as well.
The bodies which are required to both license drugs
and then to see what happens to them afterwards
are all paid for by the drug companies.
If you discovered that all the people who
were your hygiene inspectors for restaurants
were all paid for by the restaurant owners, you
might be rather suspicious about their findings.
That's the kind of situation we have with
the drugs and that's what needs to change.
They pay the regulators who are
supposed to be overseeing the drugs,
they pay the academics who are
meant to be researching the drugs
and very often the trials that they run will be
run by people who are part of the drug company.
They also put in adverts
into the medical journals
most of the medical journals are
supported by drug company advertising.
If we check the medical literature for the
last sixty-five, seventy-five years
there are thousands of papers showing
that high doses of nutrients cure disease.
Now some of these
papers you don't get to read
because they were
published in journals that, say,
the United States National Library
of Medicine refuses to index.
Isn't that interesting?
So there are medical journals out there
that are basically blacklisted.
Whatever is published
in certain medical journals
such as the Journal of Ortho-Molecular
Medicine of which I am assistant editor
whatever is being published in our journal
for the last forty-one years
and that's hundreds of papers,
none of that is indexed by the
US National Library of Medicine
self proclaimed as the
largest medical library on earth.
So that what looks like pure
scientific academics researching
journals publishing and the
whole edifice of science is actually,
has been turned by the drug companies
into an arm of their marketing department.
But I'd like to know about health information
that comes to us from advertising?
That's what we call
commercial health information.
It’sa mighty big business.
Millions of dollars are spent to
advertise health products
and all kinds of pills and other medicines
for all kinds of aches and pains.
You see sometimes the
advertising can be deceptive.
There are twenty-five percent of the TV
ads in this country are drug commercials.
First question, why?
It’s not because they like
spending a lot of money.
It's because while they're spending
hundreds of millions of dollars on TV time.
They are getting back billions on people
buying those things because people are sick.
They are not feeling well.
We need drugs.
There's no question about that at all.
Pain management, brilliant.
And drugs are necessary but there
comes this whole point where
we live in a society where if a little
is good more must be much better.
So we end up with now a drug industry that
is trying to find a drug for everything.
You know got a bad attitude - have a drug.
Feeling a little depressed you know - have a drug
and the public has come to rely on it,
the public has come to accept this
whole idea of taking a pill to fix an ill.
What would happen if everybody ate
lots and lots of fresh organic food
that was minimally processed?
I think we would have
an epidemic of health.
I think the stock market would tremble.
The drug industry is a half trillion
dollar a year world wide conglomerate.
Almost three hundred billion dollars
just in North America.
This is really, really big business.
What would happen if everybody were well?
There is no money in health.
You see good health makes a lot of sense,
but it doesn't make a lot of dollars.
I think we can have
an ethical drug industry.
I really, really do.
But I think we've really got to
start sharpening up the divides
between the regulators and
the people making the drugs
and this is an absolute
shambles right now.
The idea that all drugs are
firmly based in the evidence
and all of the non-drug treatments
are just a mixture of hope and delusion
and placebo effect and charlatans just
doesn't really stand up to examination.
For example,
in order for a drug to be licensed
it has to show that it is more effective
than a placebo in two trials.
This doesn't mean to say that the
drug company can't do lots of other trials
in which it doesn't prove to be more effective,
it just doesn't need to publish those.
What it needs to do is go along to the
regulator and say we have these two trials,
which show the drug is
more effective than a placebo.
Can we have a license to market it please?
Now these are samples taken from
manufacturers batches of insulin
and antibiotic drugs.
We test them for purity and potency
before they are sold.
Of course new drugs
are always coming along
and we make sure that they have
been tested and found to be safe
before they are put on the market.
The doctors will tell you that
the drugs have been trial led
and tested but what you have to realize
when you take a new drug
is that you are essentially embarking
on an uncontrolled experiment.
The drugs will only have been tested,
for the purposes of getting their license,
on maybe a few hundred,
at the most a few thousand people
and they are then going to be
given to literally millions.
And within those millions of people there
is going to be an enormous range
of the way that their systems work,
the way that they react to the drugs.
And so people are
going to have side-effects.
There is also the fact that the problems
most people in the west face
are not really acute disorders, which
medicine is very good at dealing with,
but they are chronic disorders.
They are disorders like depression,
diabetes, heart, arthritis and so on.
They are things that don't kill you
they just make you rather miserable
and feel rather terrible and they go
on for a long period of time.
And these are the kind of conditions
that all of the drugs are targeted at
but they're the conditions that
the drugs don't treat very well.
Short term some of them are very
life saving-you need to have them.
Some of the corticoid steroids some of the
other things that everybody says no, no, no.
Short term, life saving - fine.
Antibiotics short term,
life saving - no problem.
I abhor having patients on
any long term medication
and there is almost no medication in the
world that you can't get patients off of.
The perfect drug from the point of view
of a drug company is one first of all,
that doesn't cure people because
people need to take the drug
for a long period of time in
order for it to be profitable.
Secondly, are they the best way to
treat everything from the start
and the answer would
seem very clearly to be not.
And so for a lot of the chronic conditions,
it seems to make a lot of sense to start off
by doing what you can
with non-drug approaches.
Firstly because they are very unlikely
to have the same range of side effects
and secondly because in a number of cases
it looks as though they have better chance
of tackling the underlying problem
rather than simply
dealing with the symptom.
Doctor Abram Hoffer worked with Bill W
the founder of Alcoholics Anonymous
and Bill W and Abram became good friends.
Bill W suffered from severe depression.
Abram said, "You should take some Niacin".
He suggested 3,000 mg of Niacin a day.
That was the end of Bill W's depression.
Bill W then suggested to people that were
alcoholic why don't you try taking Niacin
and see if it helps your depression,
see if it helps your alcoholism.
And the majority of the people that tried
the Niacin had great improvement.
So Bill W, founder of Alcoholics Anonymous (AA),
wanted AA to use Niacin and vitamin therapy.
But AA, which had already been
infiltrated, I would say, is a good word
by the medical profession, rejected that.
So to this day Alcoholics Anonymous
focuses on many laudable steps
alcoholics can and
should do to stop drinking.
But it does not recommend vitamin therapy.
At the time when there was concern,
a growing concern about the issue of
whether the anti-depressant SSRI drugs
were causing suicide and there had
been a few campaigners in roundabout 2000
who had been saying there were
problems with these drugs
and the regulatory authorities and the
drug companies had been denying it.
We did a whole study on those
school shootings over in America.
And we studied a number of these
incidents and in most cases,
in most cases...
the shooter is either on or withdrawing
from these types of psychiatric medications
at the time that they
commit these of fences.
And yet none of this stuff really
comes out in the trials at all.
And an American researcher came up
with the fact that Prozac,
which was of course the
brand leader at the time,
was about to come off patent and so they
wondered whether there was a new drug coming up.
And they did some research
and they found indeed there was,
there was a thing called Prozac R
and there had been some tinkering
with the molecular structure of it.
In order to produce a new drug you
have to say what the improvements
are going to be and in the patent application
for Prozac R it said will not cause
the suicidal thoughts and feelings, which
are associated with the existing drug.
Precisely the thing the drug company had been
denying was going on for the past 10 years.
I worked with a lady once who
was suicidally depressed.
She lived at home with her family.
She was in her 50's and she spent all day
sitting in a corner, face to the corner.
She wouldn't talk to anyone.
She wouldn't eat with anyone.
She was totally uncommunicative.
She was under the care of a psychiatrist,
of course, as she should be
and the psychiatrist had her on a variety
of medications, which you would expect.
The family was wondering about nutrition
and I mentioned to them about
Dr Hoffers work with Niacin
and they wondered how much she needed to
take, this person was very seriously ill.
And I mentioned that Dr Hoffer normally
gave about 3,000 mg a day of Niacin
but some people need a lot more
especially very sick people
and they should give her as much
as it takes to make her better.
Well they figured they could do that.
So at 11,500 mg of Niacin a day she was
sitting at the table and talking to them
like nothing had happened.
So they went to the psychiatrist,
showed the psychiatrist this recovered
person and the psychiatrist said,
"Well I don't think you should take
all that Niacin it might be harmful."
So they stopped giving her the Niacin
and she was back in the corner.
Safety with Niacin? There's not one death
from Niacin per year on average,
There have been one or two attributed
over the last 15 or 20 years.
But there is not even one death
per year from Niacin.
And how many people
that are suicidally depressed
actually go and end their lives.
Two handfuls of cashews give you the therapeutic
equivalent of a prescription dose of Prozac.
Now everyone then says,
"Oh but two handfuls of cashews,
isn't that fattening?"
And my point is - do you care?
Do you want to get over the depression?
Were having a difficult time
accepting a simple therapy.
Here is what you can do.
If someone is depressed the first thing they
can do is know that it's okay to be depressed.
If you are malnourished
you should be depressed!
So don't do that anymore
go and eat good food.
What's going on in the mind, in the brain.
-Whatever the mind is - can be influenced
by the nutrients, the chemicals going
into it and what is happening as well.
This is not to say that psychological
treatments aren't important, they are
but you can't get anywhere with a patient who's
got psychological and psychiatric symptomatology
if their brain is hungry, if it's starved,
or if it's poisoned.
There is a fact of life in medicine
that if I take your bone and measure it
you've got 5,000 times more lead in it than you
would've been if you'd been an Egyptian pharaoh.
If I take some fat samples you've still
got DDT, DDE and DDD in your fat samples
even though DDT has been
banned a long time ago.
As well as a whole
range of other chemicals.
But does anybody want
to hear about that? No.
And that has not yet registered or if
it has doctors simply refuse to do it
because everything they do is toxic,
every drug they use,
Prescription drugs, over the counter drugs
all drugs are liver toxic bar none.
Something like 79 million Americans
are getting mercury fillings
put in their mouths everyday right now.
Legally we are not supposed to say they are
toxic so I never mention that to patients.
But for a documentary, are they?
You betcha.
If I look at your brain
and do a brain biopsy
I'll find a large amount
of Mercury in your system
if you've had amalgam
fillings put in your mouth.
What makes amalgam and mercury
so much safer when you put it into a tooth
compared to when it's sitting
on a dentist's tray?
It’s highly toxic and the dentist has to handle it
as one of the most toxic substances known to man
but it's made safe when put into
your tooth. Which is nonsense.
Suffice it to say if you have it in your
mouth you are being poisoned by it.
End of story.
These toxins when you stop pushing them
into the system start to come out.
And actually if you now only change your
diet to the point of eating all organic
you are releasing all these poisons,
they go into the bloodstream
and into the liver and unless you help the
liver get rid of it you can cause new damage.
It’sa mistake, it's half a therapy,
the other half of the therapy is detoxify.
Colonics, enemas, things that
help to move stuff out.
Herbs that help to move things out.
Water that helps to move things out.
These are critical factors
in the cleansing equation
because our body's primary method of cleansing
and detoxification is through the bowels.
We have to get the toxins out to even allow
the nutrients to get into the tissues.
You can't get them in there
if they are full of poisons.
You can't get two things into one space.
The basic idea is, is you've got to start
by doing the simplest thing ever which is
upon rising drink lots of water.
As simple as that is it's amazing
how few people actually do that.
Drink a litre, two litres of water
before you have any food,
before you have any coffee, whatever tea,
whatever you start your morning with.
Drink, just straight water
and then begin your day.
What we notice first is initially -
boom, things flow out.
My cousin lost 150 pounds in about
an 18-month period on our program...
Raw organic natural foods across the
selection we have been talking about.
And he actually moved all that toxicity
out of his body through his bowels.
Twelve bowel movements a day.
One day he lost 15 pounds in one day.
That is really interesting but really
difficult to talk about to the general public
because when we think of weight loss
we think were going to go work out
and convert it into muscle and sweat
it off but actually in this day and age
with the toxicity that's in the average
fat cell of the average person
you don't want to move that
stuff out through your skin.
You want to get it out through
your bowels as quickly as possible.
The big problem with cancer research
is that the public is lead to believe
that the cancer breakthrough
is around the next corner.
Look at any newspaper most weeks and there
will be a story in there - new cancer cure.
And yet when you stand back and
look at what's actually happening
your relatives continue to die,
my relatives continue to die,
the cancer breakthrough turns out to be
just another drug that causes cancer
because most of these chemos are themselves
carcinogens that's the whole point
these are cell toxins they're designed to
poison tumor cells so they don't replicate.
So the big mistake that is happening here
is that the cancer industry is continuing
to view the tumor as the cancer
and we know the tumor is not the cancer
because if the tumor were the cancer
that would mean that we could cut
the tumors out of the human body
and they would never grow back
and we know that's not true
we know these tumors can and
do grow back and the reason they grow back
is you have not corrected
the underlying metabolic process.
Cancer is one of the most deadly
and elusive enemies ever faced by man.
Once cancerous cells appear they soon
develop into a clump of tissue
that lives at the expense
of the entire body.
This tissue crowds and robs nourishment
from other cells, tissues or organs.
There's a lot of people that are beginning to realize
that conventional medicine just does not work.
The AMA (American Medical
Association) themselves said
that for cancer specifically independent of the
stage that the patient comes to the doctors office
whether it's stage 1 or 4,
most cancers are divided into 4 stages-
Independent of the stage that the patient
first arrives less than 30% survive 5 years
using chemo, surgery or radiation.
That means that more than 70% of them die.
That is just not acceptable.
What chance do I really have doctor?
Marshall...
I have no desire to mislead you.
I am sure you realize that recovery
is not a sure thing, but...
...if we can go through surgery
as quickly as possible
I believe you have a
good chance at recovery.
We have the precedent set by Dr Max
Gerson back in the 1930's and 1940's
who showed that vitamins and especially
large quantities of fresh vegetable juices
and organic foods would
help to reverse cancer
and Gerson had about a 50% cure rate
with terminally ill patients -
that's extremely high.
With malignant melanoma,
the Gerson Therapy is spectacular.
That in itself is enough reason for every physician
to learn about the Gerson Therapy - but they don't.
Medical school does not talk
about these alternatives.
Normal human body has
powerful defenses
to the point where cancer is impossible.
The human body has such powerful defenses
that a normal healthy body cannot,
will not, develop cancer
or any other chronic
disease for that matter.
Not only that but with good
healthy normal rich organic food
you can reverse these diseases,
and that's what we do.
So if you want to reverse cancer
what you really got to do
is get in there and wreck the internal
environment that cancer depends on to thrive
and that's how these clinics are doing it.
What they are not doing is loading loads
of chemotherapy, and radiation and toxicity
into the body to create more problems
for the immune system,
which is already weakened, and vulnerable.
-That's why the person has got cancer.
And as G. Edward Griffin says if you
want to give somebody cancer...
...give them chemotherapy.
Because those chemotherapies are
themselves carcinogens most of the time.
I receive thousands of phone calls a year
and not a few of those
are coming from people who went through all the
best medicine that hospitals could give them
and the tumors kept growing back...
and when they said; "Why do I
keep getting this cancer back?"
doctors said; "We don't know - in fact
we don't really know what causes cancer."
I mean we've known for 60 years!
In fact we have known
since professor John Beard
of Edinburgh University
wrote his thesis in 1904,
that cancer is a healing
process that hasn't switched off.
But you see again it comes back to, it's not that
the drug industry is selectively lying to people
they're just not covering the issues
the way they should be covering it.
A classic example is the way they've
manipulated the survival rates.
The word "survive" you know
you'll hear an advert which says;
"Well now, give to this charity, we are
now seeing that eighty percent of women
are surviving breast cancer."
And yet what they have done is
they've redefined the word "survive" to mean
only five years after initial treatment.
So take my aunt - my aunt got cancer, she
is forever immortalized as a cancer survivor
'cause she survived the five years
but she died six months later.
So she is cured and dead.
In 1972 our then President Nixon stated
that if we throw enough money at this
cancer problem we will solve it.
We were able to put a man on the moon
and we ought to be
able to solve the problem.
Together we can hardly fail
for there is no force on Earth to
match the will and spirit
of the people of America.
And in 1972 he agreed to make
a great deal of money available.
That year, 220,000
Americans died of cancer.
Exactly twenty-five years later,
USA Today, the big newspaper,
I think it was also in Newsweek,
published the figures of
what actually did happen.
What happened was the US government;
us taxpayers put out over 39 billion
US dollars for research on cancer.
The result was twenty-five
years later in 1996
560,000 people died of
cancer, more than double!
The five year or better survival rate
for almost all forms of cancer
is unchanged for the last four decades.
That's pretty sad.
Cancer remains man's number two killer,
second only to heart disease.
Little wonder that a victim of cancer
like Mr. Marshall feels depressed.
You see the thing about a war,
and this is a cancer war -
wars are only profitable when
you are fighting them.
Let's face it, if cancer disappeared tomorrow,
millions of people would have to retrain.
I mean this is a 200 billion dollar a year
industry that you are going to have to dismantle
if the truth ever came out
about what we would need to do.
A lot of people ask, you know,
why I am in Mexico?
That's precisely why.
I am an American citizen, I live in
San Diego, my kids went to school here,
I would love to be able to do what I believe
is correct in the country of my birth.
My patients, a lot of
them come from the US.
They would like to be able to do what is
in their opinion a good program
to cure their disease problem in their
countries of birth whether that be Australia,
whether that be New Zealand,
whether that be Canada,
England, the US it doesn't matter.
Unfortunately, we can't until we
get the health care laws changed.
The war against cancer has been fought
with one arm behind the back
and I would never go into the ring with
the heavyweight champion of the world
and fight with one arm.
And yet by restricting cancer research and
cancer treatment to basically
drug,
surgery,
radiation approaches
and not considering nutrition seriously
we have done a terrible disservice
to all these people.
So it's not that people are lying,
it's not that everybody who works in the cancer
industry is somehow an evil and wicked person.
What we look at here
is we are seeing that a lot of people
are doing what they believe is best.
You can be sincere and
you can be sincerely wrong.
The good news is we change that today.
One of the few free choices a person has
is what they will or will not eat.
So we have to make sure that we are
looking at doing everything possible
to build the body up and not break it down. That
makes all the sense in the world, doesn't it?
You should do everything you possibly can
and stack the deck in your favour
and that means building the
immune system nutritionally
and using vitamins to help
the body fight the disease
because being malnourished
can't possibly help you beat cancer.
In males the digestive tract is
most frequently afflicted with cancer.
Colon cancer is a good place to start
because it's not very easy to treat.
Colon cancer is a very serious disease and
I would say its 100% preventable
by having a high fiber diet and avoiding
things that we know that aggravate cancer
such as certain additives, food
preservatives, environmental chemicals
they could be a cause
of any number of cancers.
The Japanese who live in Japan and
eat the standard Japanese diet,
live the standard Japanese lifestyle, have
the lowest incidence of cancer in the world.
And it's believed that the low incidence
is due to the high intake of seafood
including fish and sea vegetables.
With that diet there is a high intake of trace
elements like selenium, zinc and germanium
and a whole range of other
anti cancer trace elements.
There is also a high intake of the Omega 3
fish oils which are protective as well
not only for cancers but
heart disease and Alzheimer's.
And they also drink green tea
and green tea has got a range of chemicals
to protect us against cancer as well
protect our cells and our genes and so on.
In the female cancers of the breast
and the uterus are the most prevalent.
You take a Japanese woman from Japan
where the incidence of
breast cancer is very low
and transplant her into America
and she changes her lifestyle
the incidence of cancer then starts
creeping up to that of the American woman,
which is round about 13% now.
So 13% of females in America are at risk,
will get cancer of the breast.
Japanese are less than 1%.
We doctors are improving our techniques.
No individual is alone in
the fight against cancer.
Research workers are finding and
reporting more and more facts.
We will conquer cancer.
When we look at high doses of
Vitamin C given intravenously
as an actual chemotherapeutic agent,
we have wonderful uplifting news
for every cancer patient in the world.
And it's easy and safe - and did I say inexpensive?
-To have a physician give an IV.
You just have to insist on it.
I believe in the next ten years
this will become more accepted
but people with cancer
can't afford to wait
and the ones that are already dead have been
grossly mistreated by the medical profession
and by the government that is supposedly
supposed to encourage
free research and
development of all possibilities.
So when you come along and say instead
of treating cancer with chemotherapy
you can give intravenous Vitamin C
30... 60... 100,000 mg a day
directly into the blood stream,
and that will kill cancer cells.
Vitamin C at that high dose is
selectively toxic to cancer cells
and that's exactly what chemotherapy
is but with Vitamin C
there's no damage to healthy cells
and people don't get nauseous,
they don't lose their hair
all they do is get better.
We pushed the dose up
to 40,000 mg, 50,000 mg,
60,000 mg,
we pushed the dose up to 100,000 mg,
we even went to 200,000 mg,
we nearly got to a quarter
of a kilo, IVin 24 hours.
No adverse events, no adverse side-effects
apart from thirst
and feeling a little
bit woozy in the head.
Now that's with huge amounts of Vitamin C
the substances that were meant to cause
kidney stones if you took 100 mg.
Now we wonder; why isn't this being done?
Because the next assumption is,
if this were so good
my doctor would already know about it,
it would be on television,
if this were so good
it would be taught in medical school and
that's another one of those assumptions.
Why would you want to teach
about vitamins in medical school?
Why would medical doctors who
studied medicine and practice medicine
and are heavily funded by
pharmaceutical companies
why would they go and look into vitamins?
The pharmaceutical companies are
not going to advocate vitamins,
that's not going to work.
The government doesn't know
anything that it isn't told
by the pharmaceutical companies and
other lobbies and by medical lobbies.
The people don't know
because they had an education
that never had the
word orthomolecular in it.
Dr Hugh Reardon said that orthomolecular,
which is therapeutic nutrition,
orthomolecular medicine
is not the answer to any question
posed in medical school.
So what you're set here with is
two divergent views on health care
and whenever you have that you have
what we are experiencing today,
an impossible dichotomy.
When you talk to people about using
high dose Vitamin C for cancer
and then you tell them
that it's been heavily tested,
even the National Institutes of Health
are showing that this is working.
Dr Reardon's team has been doing this
for twenty-five years or more now.
I’ve seen for thirty years
that high doses of vitamins
greatly improve a cancer
patient's quality of life
and greatly improve a
cancer patient's length of life.
And there's many, many places in
the literature where you can look
and find support for high dose nutrient
therapy to arrest or even reverse cancer.
It’s an impossible question.
Why isn't it being done?
And the answer of course is
until enough people complain
laughs
it won't be done.
But if everyone demands
nutritional therapy it will change.
Right now if you want nutritional therapy
and you go to your doctor and ask for it
its sort of like ordering chow me in
in a French restaurant.
It’s not on the menu,
and they don't know how to make it,
and you're not going to get it.
You have a right to
self-care and self help.
We need to again teach the regulators,
the politicians, the doctors and get to the
universities and the people training in medicine
to understand that there are plants
with anti-cancer properties,
there are plants with anti-nausea
and anti-vomiting properties,
there are plants that
will help with rashes,
there are plants that will help with
headaches and tiredness
that occur as a result of chemotherapy.
Mom listen...
Now I am sure that those government people
are experts at their work.
But ever since I have been taking
Mr Kahumana's tea.
I’ve felt simply wonderful!
Why, I never knew that a remedy
could be so effective.
Why I haven't been having
my usual attacks at all.
Now why is that if it isn't because
of Mr Kahumana's tea?
What if they gave everyone in America free
health insurance and no one needed it?
There's a lot of debate over how we
should finance and change
provide health care to
everyone in the United States.
Most civilized countries do have a
national program of health care
guaranteeing health care
for pretty much everybody.
The United States is conspicuously absent.
We have 30 maybe 40 million people
that are uninsured in the United States.
That's getting some
attention as it rightly should.
But is the solution to simply give them access
to a system that doesn't work very well?
Or would it be a good idea to
teach them how to be healthy?
I think they need education
and not medication.
People need to be made aware of the
great benefit of improving their health
if they've got a cancer or
whatever disease they've got.
We are at a stage now where there is a major
change in what's happening with medicine,
which is that medicine no longer
has a lock on all the information,
the internet has changed that.
And as more and more and more of our population
start taking their health into their own hands.
There's going to be even
more and more of a change,
it can't go on the way it is.
I mean the system
right now is falling apart.
We must make nutrition the primary
prevention strategy for the population
and we have to be as zealous on nutrition
as we are apparently on global warming.
What we need to be able to
do is to persuade the public
that you are what you eat,
food can change your mood,
that you are everything you
have ever done to yourself
and the choices you make directly
affect the outcome of your life.
And it might be easy enough to forget that
right now when your 21 years old
and very, very fit and
healthy eating badly
but it all looks a lot different when get
into your 40's, 50's and 60's
and start to go down with a
serious degenerative illness.
We've still got a health system which
really is a disease care system
and dominated by doctors and hospitals,
pathologists, and pharmacologists.
And that sort of a system
is going to look after itself,
it wants more work and is truly not interested
in reducing the amount of illness and disease.
The more work they get the more profit there
is and so that's part of the medical industry
and it does need to be there,
it's very, very important.
The medical industry
does get a lot of things right.
Infant survivability at birth - brilliant.
A&E (Accident & Emergency)
trauma medicine - brilliant.
God forbid you get smashed up on a motorway
and they have to put you back together again
they're very good at doing that.
Disease - pathetic.
The medical profession has it wrong.
Even the medical schools that offer
nutrition do not offer mega dose nutrition.
Even the medical schools that have courses in
alternative medicine are not really focusing on it.
I believe they are just giving it a nod.
The answer is for every person to realize
that if you want something done right
you have to do it yourself.
You have to read. You have to dig.
You have to want to have this information
and of course I might add
you have to be willing to actually take the
vitamins and actually juice the vegetables.
You have to walk the walk.
And anybody who is watching this right now
has at some level made a choice
that they want to do something that is going
to improve their lives, their families lives,
their kids lives and the
life of the planet itself.
And the life of all the
plants and everything.
If that is our choice then our
food choices must correlate with that
because if you've ever flown in a plane
and you look out the window of the plane
and you see what's down
there you'll see its all farms.
The primary way that we are interacting
with our planet is through agriculture
and if we change our food choices,
we change agriculture and all of a sudden
we shift away from for
example corn, wheat, soy diets
over to super food diets and
organic diets and raw food diets
and we shift the whole way that
we literally interact with the planet.
The number one thing we are doing
on this planet is growing things.
In spite of all the chemical controlled
giant agricultural businesses
were still growing stuff.
We could grow genetically modified corn
or we could grow the most
extraordinary goji berries in the world.
There's a lot more turning to alternatives
because what's being done beforehand
doesn't work, it just doesn't work.
When I look cancer rates going up,
heart disease going up, stroke going up,
Alzheimer's and senile dementia and
cognitive impairment going up...
A change is due. Clearly
the old ways aren't working
and what we need to do, we need a fresh
paradigm and we need to go back to basics.
And basics is all about going back to look at
these cultures who don't get these problems.
In the same way if you want to be
a millionaire, go talk to a millionaire
don't talk to the guy down at the pub still
recovering from the last golden opportunity.
Go find these people who are living
a hundred years routinely
without cancer, heart disease and see if
you can figure out how they are doing it
and we've done that work, we have done that
science its been done over the last hundred years
and its been completely ignored.
The very first course I
ever taught was in 1976
and it was called forgotten
research in medicine
and I am doing the same thing to this day.
I feel very strongly that
the best doctor in the world,
the best nutritionist in the world
is you.
You actually have everything inside
of you, all of the equipment necessary
to feel if something
is right for you or not.
The good news is that people
are not a bunch of dummies.
Abraham Lincoln
expressed that when he said,
"You can fool some of
the people all the time,
and all of the people some of the time,
but you can't fool all of
the people all of the time."
And that's why over half of the population
now takes vitamins even though
most doctors would say
that its really not necessary.
We have a public that's catching on
quicker than the medical professions.
In a way it's sad but in a way it's great.
People should stop being patients
and start being people.
Why not be healthy and happy? Why not?
You change your life, you do
some exercise, you eat right,
you feel better, alright that's good,
you look better, alright that's good,
you live longer, that's good,
you save money, that's good
and you have the enormous satisfaction
of having done it yourself.
People think; "I don't have a
medical education, I can't know this."
Oh please! How complicated is it to eat right
and drink vegetable juice sand exercise?
You don't need any degree to know that.
It’s too simple to work.
It’s cheap, it's simple,
it's safe, it's effective.
The biggest single reason why
people aren't doing this
is that it requires taking responsibility
and that is the only way out.
When we choose raw, organic plant
based foods we take our power back
and we decide that we
are going to have quality
and that we are not going to suffer
from some 50 ingredients
that are in there of chemicals
we've never even heard of before.
I am not a big advocate of preaching vegetarianism
to everybody or veganism or even rawfoodism.
But we do know for a fact that an 80% raw,
organic plant based diet
that covers all the different facets of
fruits, vegetables, nuts, seeds, seaweeds,
sprouts, grasses, super foods and
herbs is a massively valuable part
of a healthy and
wonderfully abundant lifestyle.
There is no magic bullet; there is no mono therapy
that cures cancer, that cures heart disease.
But there is a lifestyle change
that prevents, arrests, and
reverses serious chronic disease.
The solutions are here;
they've always been here.
The only thing that's
left is just the education,
because I am convinced that once people
know what the solution is they'll act on it.
They will decide - yep, were doing it.
Subs by Zgrybla (03.2010)