Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
1945, ODO ISLAND AIRFIELD,
FINAL DAYS OF WORLD WAR II
ODO ISLAND NAVY DETACHMENT
- The engine is fine. - Roger.
- Fully refueled.
- Roger.
Lieutenant Shikishima?
Tsukuba Naval Air Corps, Tachibana.
Remember me?
Of course.
I am greatly in your debt.
I'm amazed you were able
to land that bucket of bolts...
on this Swiss cheese of a runway.
You haven't lost your touch.
In simulated dogfights, yes,
but suddenly I'm a real kamikaze pilot.
Then be grateful for the down time.
But it's strange.
We have examined the aircraft
but we could not find any defects.
What are you implying?
Don't worry, I'm totally on your side.
We need more people like you.
Why obey an order to "die honorably"
when the outcome is already clear?
- Get the guns!
- Yes, sir!
- Enemy raid?
- I don't know!
- What is it?
- Something big!
A new Yankee weapon?
Taki, Taki!
- Light the beach!
- Roger!
Taki!
What in the hell?
It's Godzilla.
- What?
- A local told me.
That comes from the deep,
Godzilla they call it.
G... G-Godzilla?
We're screwed. Take cover!
Take cover!
What the hell is that?
Nobody knows.
- Lieutenant Shikishima. - Sir?
Can you reach your 20mm machine gun?
You're our only gunner.
We're just mechanics.
But what if it only makes it angry?
A 20-mm machine gun can kill anything.
Hurry, before it gets too close.
Go now!
Go!
Hurry up!
What's he doing in there?
Quick, shoot!
It's coming this way.
- What do we do, sir?
- Ammo!
Fetch the ammo!
You idiot! Don't shoot!
Cease fire!
You must not shoot!
Fall back! Fall back!
Retreat!
Sir Tachibana!
I lure it over. And then you shoot it down!
You guys didn't deserve this.
Hello?
Everyone is dead!
They're all dead!
Because you didn't shoot.
Damn it!
You...
Listen now!
December 1945 Tokyo
Look out!
Is that you, Koichi?
Sumiko!
How is this possible?
Weren't you a kamikaze pilot?
You have the nerve to show your face?
You are a disgrace!
Look what happened
because of cowards like you!
If you'd only done your job...
My children wouldn't have died.
Do you know if my parents are still alive?
Everyone is dead.
The whole place was in flames.
Your parents too.
My children met the same fate.
'Koichi, my dear son…
"Come back alive," right?
That's what you said.
Stop the thief!
Move. Move!
- To the side!
- Grab the woman!
- Here!
- What?
Get back here!
What...
Hello.
Finally.
Where did you go?
It's your fault
for sitting out in the open.
You've been here the whole time?
Yeah, waiting for you to get up and move.
You must be hungry.
Why didn't you just leave her behind?
What?
Leave her in a place like that?
Stop joking.
Wait a minute!
Please don't follow me.
Are you going to leave us to die on the streets?
I don't care.
You must leave when you finish eating.
Do you hear that? He's so mean and scary.
Where is your husband?
Is he a soldier?
- Do I look like I have a husband?
- What?
Whose kid is she?
- Does it matter?
- Of course it does!
During the air raids...
her dying mother begged me to adopt her.
So you are…
so not related to this child at all?
Nope, so what?
What are you, stupid?
You're in no state to care for a baby.
You couldn't leave her behind either.
Name?
"Akiko"
No, I meant you.
Noriko.
Why do you dress like a vagrant?
By choice?
Well, I'm no harlot.
Don't look so offended.
To find a way to survive.
No one can blame you for that.
And what about family?
HARU SHIKISHIMA - EIICHIRO SHIKISHIMA
Your parents?
Yes.
They were killed in the air raids.
Then you and I are the same.
What?
No, you can't...
stay...
Hey!
What's the story?
- What do you mean?
- Don't play dumb.
The mother and child you picked up.
- Think you're some kind of saint?
- No.
They just showed up.
If they're staying, you picked them up.
It's a bit late to play the hero.
Count me out.
No more caring for others.
Wait.
Is that girl able to breast feed?
No, she is not the child's mother.
Say what?
At this rate, she'll die of malnutrition.
Right?
So you've found a child,
but have no idea how to provide for it.
What were you thinking?
Sorry I didn't know.
It's not for you.
Adults can survive on all kinds of food.
Make porridge out of it.
Well...
there goes my prized white rice.
What a nuisance, I swear.
March, 1946
Damn, I'm drenched.
Have you found a job yet?
Well I did find something.
What's that?
Money's not bad, either.
Look. They even paid an advance
of 3,000 yen.
That's wonderful!
It must be a scam.
Like the rice you carried that got stolen.
It's nothing like that.
What makes you so sure?
It's government approved.
There's a reason why it pays well.
And what is the reason then?
During the war, both sides laid
thousands of mines in the sea.
It's a cleanup job.
The pay is good because, uh...
the work is quite risky.
What are you, crazy?
You just survived a war.
What else can I do?
At this rate, we'll starve.
Akiko's life depends on it.
I understand that, but...
This brings in money.
With money, we can even buy American powdered milk!
For that, I'd do...
I forbid you to die!
Don't worry. Just because it's
dangerous doesn't mean I'll die.
It's not like being a kamikaze pilot.
And besides... I'll be on a special boat
made to evade mines.
This is specially made?
- Hey, are you our new sharpshooter?
- I'm Shikishima.
- Sailor?
- Fighter pilot.
- What? The guy is useless.
- Are you an ex-pilot?
Just a military castoff.
Worthless.
Disappointed? Seeing this boat?
The US and imperial navies laid
60,000 mines off Japan's coasts.
All kinds. But the worst are
the American magnetic mine.
Any approaching boat made
of metal sets them off.
Ah, hence the wood.
The boy catches on fast.
We mostly handle moored mines.
But wood boats are the best
countermeasure.
I'm Noda.
I developed naval weapons
during the war.
Boat captain Akitsu, and Mizushima.
"The kid" and "Doc."
- Not fond of that nickname.
- And I'm no Kid.
You're still green, so "Kid" it is.
I know, I know.
I wasn't in the war.
This is the minesweeper Shinseimaru.
Paired with Kaishinmaru.
The mines rise up from the seabed
like balloons on strings.
A cutting claw is placed
between the two boats.
All we do is clip the mine wire...
and it floats to the surface.
Then we fire on it with this baby, Okay?
Take a look.
Well... This one is a bit tricky.
May I give it a try?
Are you sure?
You have to estimate it's position
accounting for the movement.
Whoo-hoo!
- Nice shot!
- It's the same as in a fighter plane.
- Although I haven't been in action.
- What?
You didn't? That makes me
and Shikishima equals.
Hardly. You can't fly a plane.
If I'd gone to war, I would've learned.
Only the war had lasted a little longer.
You can't think that.
No sorry.
You are a fool.
Shoot, shoot. Seek cover!
Everything is alright?
Did you dream again?
A dream?
And.
I lay dreaming.
Or maybe...
are you just a dream
What is wrong with you? You can tell me.
It's Japan, right here?
I survived, didn't I?
- I survived. - Stop!
Yes, now I know.
I know.
Now I know.
July 1946 Bikini Atoll,
Operation Crossroads
Nice place you built here, Shikishima.
Worth every saved penny..
- Do you want something to drink?
- Oh thank you.
Can I take a picture?
- Don't waste your movie on me.
- Maybe a little smile?
Yes, like that! Just like that!
Perfect.
- Thanks.
- Listen, Doc. Stay in your skin, right?
Of course. Noriko is a married woman.
Please stop.
I'm not married.
What should it say?
She just moved in here.
She had nowhere else to go,
so I let her stay.
And the child?
She brought her, too.
But they aren't related.
Akiko was orphaned during the air raids.
- Wow, that's a beautiful story!
- No.
It just sort of happened.
Father.
- Akiko.
- Yes?
I told you. I'm not your father.
Shikishima.
- Don't say that.
- He's right.
Fate has brought you together as a family.
- Accept it. Embrace it.
- Make them happy.
Then that's enough!
What are you wearing?
Why not?
March, 1947
Welcome home. I just got home too.
What kind of clothes are you wearing?
How does it look?
I got a desk job in Ginza.
But don't I give you enough money?
It's time I stood on my own two feet.
At this rate,
you'll never find a wife.
Have you seen how fast Ginza
is rebuilding?
It's just so sudden.
Not for me, it isn't.
What about Akiko?
What will you do with Akiko
while you are away at work?
Sumiko has promised to look after her.
She was very excited,
boasting she'd raised three kids already.
In that case,
I suppose it's all right.
Thanks. I'll go get Akiko now.
The cruiser USS Lancaster was attacked
and eliminated by an unknown enemy.
Further details are missing at this time.
The navy picked up distress signals...
from the Pacific Ocean.
After successfully photographing
the object…
the ship made physical contact
and was eliminated.
Radioactive signals were picked up
when the ship hit the creature.
The colossal sea creature
is projected on a course...
to reach the Japanese
archipelago within a few weeks.
General Douglas MacArthur
stated with regret...
that recent Soviet movements
prevent US military assistance...
but called upon Japan...
to begin strengthening its security forces.
May 1947
Near the Ogasawara Islands
What has caused this?
A giant shark?
Or a whale?
No shark or whale could do that.
A new Soviet weapon?
That's not weapon damage.
So what could it be?
- An enormous creature.
- Of what kind?
Just admit you don't know.
I was skeptical until I saw it myself.
Godzilla.
Look there!
Floating deep sea fish.
Just like at Odo Island.
What did you see there?
It was like a prehistoric dinosaur
turned monster.
The local inhabitants called it "Godzilla."
Godzilla?
Nonsense. You were half asleep
and saw an enemy tank.
Believe me or not,
something wiped out...
the entire garrison on Odo.
Hold on.
I thought it was the Americans.
Odo was never targeted by
US island-hopping forces.
It was a repair base for kamikaze planes.
Does this mean that...
have you been a kamikaze pilot?
If it's the same Godzilla I saw back then…
it must have grown much larger
and more powerful.
Hold on a second.
Why were we called out here to begin with?
They don't expect us to
fight that in this boat!
Yes, they do.
We don't stand a chance!
That's a US warship!
What can we do in this little rig?
Stall for time.
- Stall?
- The Takao is coming from Singapore.
The heavy cruiser?
Rather than scuttle it,
it's being returned.
That's good news!
The Takao's a beast!
So we've been ordered to stall for time.
Why can't the US handle it?
It's their ship.
They're worried about the Soviets.
Any military maneuvers would raise alarms.
They prefer we handle the small stuff.
This isn't small stuff,
and all we've got is a 13 mm gun.
I was told to make use of recovered mines.
Ah, now I see!
This is why they called us out here.
Plus our main weapon has to be
locally scavenged?
We are not to say anything to anyone either.
There it is.
Their favorite gag order.
This country never changes.
Perhaps it can't.
Take a breather.
Thank you.
Don't push yourself too hard.
I can't help it. This is Godzilla.
I hear you.
When I start remembering the war...
I get sleepless nights.
I will avenge them.
But at the same time, I am…
terrified of the monster.
We'll need more than a pair of those.
What is it?
There are way more of these fish
then I saw off Odo.
Sound the alarm. Sound the alarm!
Godzilla is coming!
Sound the alarm!
So it's coming, huh?
Hey kid!
Prepare to drop the mines!
- Roger!
- Man the gun!
We can't fight it on this!
- We can still flee!
- Agreed.
- Doc, stand by aft and report!
- Captain!
Kashinmaru, do you copy?
Get ready to land a big one!
We take credit for the victory.
- You idiot.
- Captain!
If we run, Takao will never catch up.
And the monster heads for Tokyo.
I don't want to see it in flames again.
We don't stand a chance in this boat!
I thought you hated government orders.
With a passion.
But you know what?
Someone has to do it.
Okay, never mind!
Doc, the engine!
I'm on it!
Shikishima!
Hurry up. Here!
- Captain!
- I know!
- Full speed ahead!
- Okay!
Drop the mine!
We'll never make it!
So try anything!
Now, Kid!
This is it!
Did it work?
No, it didn't.
Bad, bad, bad, bad, bad...
Shikishima, the gun!
Roger!
Shikishima!
It's no use at all!
The mouth! What about the mouth?
Reel! Reel! Reel!
Drop it!
Mizushima, now!
Right!
What? No!
No!
Get down!
Did we get it?
No.
Takao!
They made it!
Oh no!
Is it down?
What's that?
You're finally awake.
Where am I?
A Yokosuka hospital.
We were airlifted here.
And Kaishinmaru and Takao?
Godzilla.
What happened to the monster?
We don't know where it is.
It's on its way to Tokyo.
The city must be evacuated.
The government is not telling the public.
Why? We must hurry!
To prevent mayhem and confusion.
Are you kidding me?
We need to begin evacuating now!
No one will take responsibility...
for all that chaos.
Information control is Japan's specialty.
Tell me what happened.
It has nothing to do with you.
What's bothering you so much?
You took me in, saved me,
and we've been together since.
But there is a part of your life
that you hide from me.
If you are carrying some burden...
I wish you'd share it with me.
I am...
someone...
who fled my duty...
as a Kamikaze pilot.
What?
The day I had to do my assignment...
I pretended my plane was broken.
I took a detour...
and landed on Odo Island.
These pictures...
belonged to the mechanics on the island.
They all died.
That night...
a dinosaur-like monster came ashore.
I was asked...
to shoot it with the gun on my fighter.
But I froze up...
and fled once more.
When I came the next day...
I found them all dead.
People longing to see their families!
They called the monster...
Godzilla.
The other day, it reappeared.
And once again...
I couldn't do anything.
I'm someone...
who wasn't supposed to live.
Listen to me.
Everyone who survived the war
is meant to live.
- How do you know?
- I just do!
As flames took past, my parents,
they ordered me to live.
So whatever happens next,
I know I must survive!
That's kept me going.
I can't.
They beckon to me in my dreams every night.
“Hurry and come,” they say.
"Why are you still cheating death?"
It's just a dream, ghosts you created.
Maybe it's an illusion.
What if I'm really dead already?
I died long ago on that island...
and lie rotting.
You and Akiko are just the last
dream of a dead man.
That must be it! It has to be!
You are still alive!
You're alive, Koichi.
Can't you feel it?
Okay, hold the spoon.
Careful, careful.
- Hold it tight.
- Okay.
Good, now stir the broth.
You're doing great!
- There, it's done!
- Yeah!
I added your favorite, radish.
- Radish!
- Taste it for me.
- Okay.
- Let's do it.
First the soup, then the radish.
Can I...
put this all to rest?
I'd like to try to live again.
Is it what I think it is?
Hurry and report it.
Hurry up!
Yes, sir!
Patrols report the Creature is
heading east towards Tokyo Bay.
Is it close then?
- What is it?
- I don't believe it.
Is it here?
- Is that really a living thing?
- Oh, yeah.
This is Tokyo Bay Defense,
requesting permission to detonate Zone 4!
It's getting closer.
Entering Zone 4!
- Now!
- Detonate!
Status?
Nothing.
It had no effect at all.
Blockade breached!
It's heading to Shinagawa!
And it's gigantic!
Ups.
So.
It's an emergency message!
A giant sea monster has landed at Ginza!
Those near Ginza,
follow police instructions and evacuate.
- It's serious.
- Ginza.
Are you hurt? Are you okay?
- What's wrong?
- What happened?
Is that... Godzilla?
It's a scene that defies belief,
a giant creature on the loose...
trampling Ginza underfoot!
Tearing whole buildings apart!
The Nippon Theater,
a beloved icon of the people...
is crumbling before our very eyes!
The Ginza survived the air raids
but not this! This monster...
has turned it to rubble!
And now the monster is coming this way!
I can see its enormous head
passing in front of us!
It's dangerously close!
Move!
Get up!
- Koichi!
- Do you want to live? Come on!
Did they get it?
It is...
exactly like then.
Noriko.
Noriko!
N-Nori...
Damage wreaked by the giant creature...
includes some 30,000 killed and injured...
20,000 homes and buildings were destroyed.
Recovery operations are underway,
but the path the creature took...
carries the risk of radiation that
is impeding progress.
Police have cordoned off central Ginza
to collect shards of the creature...
which are of unknown composition
and potentially hazardous.
I'm so sorry.
What are you doing now with Akiko?
We have to support each other, we have to.
Hey, Akiko.
You like playing with me when
Father's away at work, right?
Where's Mommy?
Mom had to go away for her work.
But I'm here with you, right?
You can't forgive me, can you?
It's my fault...
for thinking I could dream again.
Mr. Shikishima.
There's actually a strategy being hatched
to defeat Godzilla...
led by private citizens.
It lacks any real basis
for viability, but...
will you take part?
"Special Disaster Countermeasure Hearing"
- Wait, everyone here is...
- Yes.
- Ex-navy personnel.
- You're informed.
Really?
I'm ex-"Yukikaze" Destroyer Captain Hotta.
As you all know, Tokyo again faces...
an unprecedented crisis,
this time, a monster attack.
But we have no defense apparatus
of our own to protect our people.
What's more, any GHQ-led military
action runs the risk of escalating
US-Soviet tensions.
In short, we must confront the monsters
with our strengths as private citizens.
This is why we've gathered you here.
But we've negotiated the
use of four destroyers...
originally slated for handover to the UN.
Are you saying...
you want us back on navy ships?
I saw what it did in Ginza.
There's no way to defeat it.
Especially from boats
that have been disarmed.
You're dreaming!
That is what I would like to explain,
if you will allow me.
Mr. Noda?
The plan...
Pardon me.
The plan was drafted by me,
Kenji Noda, ex-Navy technical officer.
The first thing to know...
is that this creature the people
of Odo Island called “Godzilla”...
cannot be hurt by conventional firearms.
I saw it take heavy artillery fire
from the guns of Takao...
but quickly heal itself.
Quiet, please.
So we need a totally different approach.
Let me give you a demonstration.
This is concentrated salt water.
This wood model is weighted down
just enough to barely float.
What happens if we pipe in freon gas,
enveloping it in bubbles?
That's easy. Bubbles or not,
it would stay afloat.
That's what you'd think.
It sinks!
The freon bubbles prevent the model
from seawater contact.
My idea is to entrap Godzilla like this
and sink it to the ocean floor.
Did you have any idea Doc was
such a bigwig?
No.
At over 1500 meters in depth...
the Sagami Trench is the deepest
place in nearby waters.
The plan is to strap freon cylinders
to Godzilla and let them foam.
We create a bubble membrane.
It'll sink so rapidly that
the pressure will crush it.
We kill it with the power of the sea.
That's the outline for
Operation Wada Tsumi.
It's of the sea.
Won't it withstand the pressure?
After 25 seconds, every square
meter applies 1,500 tons of pressure.
Even ocean-born creatures cannot
bear such rapid pressure change.
Can you promise...
that would kill Godzilla?
Godzilla is an unknown organism.
We can only guess what will happen.
But it is our best alternative.
Will it kill it?
Or will it not?
I can't absolutely guarantee it.
- Shikishima!
- It is possible that it can succeed!
Mr. Shikishima.
Hear me out, please.
Now let's get to the details.
Two ships will corral Godzilla
and wrap it in cable.
The cable will have multiple
freon gas cylinders attached to it.
The gas will be released as it's being tied.
And Godzilla will take a rapid
plunge of 1,500 meters.
- What if the plan fails?
- There is a plan B.
Look into the courtyard.
We raise it from the bottom of the sea!
I'm Itagaki of Toyo Balloon Company.
What you just saw...
is an inflatable levitation device
like the kind used in navy aircraft.
CO2 is shot into air sacs for buoyancy.
It's a life preserver.
When Godzilla lands on the ocean floor…
We raise it quickly back up to the surface.
If it bears the pressure,
it'll then contend massive decompression.
I can't say for sure if it will survive the pressure...
but we must try every possibility.
You've all survived a tragic war.
So it pains me to ask you again
to put your lives on the line.
But I hope you understand...
We can't rely on the US
or the Japanese government.
So the future of this country is in our hands.
I can't do it.
I have a family.
And that goes for most people here.
Why are we always the ones
drawing the short straw?
We got enough of that in the war.
Please.
I beg you to listen very carefully.
This is not an order.
You're all free to leave if you wish.
We have no right to stop you.
This plan...
does it mean certain death?
Of course not.
Then it's not as bad as a war.
It can't be helped.
Someone has to do it.
Who can sail the ships if not us?
That's right.
- So what? Shall we do it, boys?
- Yes!
My friends...
thank you.
Hear, hear!
What a surprise, to find you're
the mastermind of such a grand plan.
Well, I've had a direct encounter.
So the task fell to me.
And we were called for the same reasons.
Do you think Godzilla will return?
I think we can assume that Godzilla…
has incorporated Tokyo into its territory.
I expect it to return in 10 days at the latest.
That soon?
Did you set up radiation detection boys?
Visual detection isn't enough.
How can you expect it to
walk right into your trap?
- I can't.
- What, no plan?
Who do you think I am?
Of course, I have a plan.
We have acoustic minesweepers.
We use speakers to play
a recording of Godzilla's voice.
- Its voice?
- Yeah.
It sees it as another territorial competitor.
- Hopefully.
- Hopefully?
You don't sound very convincing.
And that levitation device?
I can't envision that working well.
Any other ideas, then?
I know!
We pull it up with the destroyers.
Godzilla weighs some 20,000 tons.
Too heavy for two destroyers.
Oh.
In short, your plan is full of holes.
If you have a better one, let's hear it.
Mr. Noda.
Can we get hold of a fighter plane?
A fighter plane?
I could anger it with gunfire
and draw it to Sagami Bay.
All planes were decommissioned.
Even if you could, it shoots a heat ray.
You risk your life flying so close.
I'll take that risk.
A fighter jet is more nimble than a boat.
You don't want to crash, do you?
Do you have a death wish?
- You're drunk.
- You just want to avenge Noriko.
- Is it a problem?
- It is too late.
You should have married her.
- You knew how she felt about you.
- Don't you think I would like to?
Then why didn't you do it?
Because...
my war isn't over yet.
- Have you found a plane?
- Yes.
But it's a unique one.
It was developed at the end of the war,
Local Fighter Shinden.
Designed to shoot down bombers.
It could fly at a speed of over 400 knots.
It's got a tail wing,
four 30 mm guns, and it's nimble as hell.
It's a plane full of innovations.
Only a few prototypes were field deployed.
They were kept here for
a mainland battle that never came.
They were left to rust,
and are in bad shape.
It's not air-worthy as is.
What we need is a top mechanic.
Someone who knows their
way around a jet fighter.
I know the right person.
Ex-Odo Island detachment mechanic.
- Sosaku Tachibana.
- Exactly.
Tachibana, Tachibana, Tachibana.
No known current address.
- I'm sorry.
- We're swamped with search requests.
It will take a long time.
I have to find him.
So does everybody.
- I'm begging you!
- What?
The country's future depends on it!
I'm sure,
but I can't do the impossible.
Well then...
Where was he posted before Odo Island?
I've asked everywhere.
But this Tachibana probably
doesn't want to be found.
We can find another mechanic.
- Do you have other options?
- Wait just a moment.
Why does it have to be him?
- Godzilla could be here any minute.
- It must be Tachibana!
He's going to get my message.
Please!
Tachibana.
Mr. Tachibana! It's really you!
What is it about?
Wait.
The Odo Island massacre was all my fault?!
Are you serious?
I'm sorry.
I knew if I angered you,
you'd come to find me.
How dare you?
The attack on Ginza...
similar to that of Odo Island.
It was Godzilla.
I need you to repair
a fighter for me.
so I can kill that monster!
I needed to find you,
to ask for your help.
That's why I wrote those letters.
Please forgive me!
You're on your own.
I'm not helping you.
No, wait, Mr. Tachibana!
Please listen to me!
I need your help killing Godzilla.
It's something only you can do.
I burst a mine in its mouth,
and hurt it more than ship guns.
It's vulnerable from the inside.
Do you get me?
You don't mean...
I can kill it if I fly a plane full of
explosives into its mouth.
Kamikaze...
The war isn't over...
for you, either.
- You got that injury falling down?
- Ow.
It's swelling up like a grapefruit.
It's embarrassing, but I was drunk.
I don't quite remember what happened.
I guess you deserved to celebrate
after finding Mr. Tachibana.
Tail wing, huh?
I'd heard rumors,
but they actually did it.
Mr. Tachibana.
Thank you all for coming!
You're Mr. Tachibana?
So this is the phantom
Local Fighter Shinden, huh?
Can you make this fly?
We'll do all we can.
Thank you.
Good luck. Good luck.
What's wrong?
Brighten up, Mastermind.
It's bad for morale.
I know that's my plan.
But I'm feeling we'll need
a miracle to make it work.
Doing nothing won't cause
a miracle, either.
You're right.
Take a look at these guys' faces.
They are not stupid.
They know they're risking their lives.
And yet...
Their faces are beaming.
They are happy.
This time they will make a difference.
Make a difference.
We have all experienced the war.
This time we make sure to win.
"2 Floor Conference Room 3,
Special Disaster Countermeasure HQ"
Hurry up!
Make room!
One hour ago, east of Hachijo Island...
33.10 north, 140.01 east...
We got Geiger readings from multiple buoys.
Followed by...
here and here.
Godzilla is coming.
At last.
At this rate, it's due to
arrive over the Sagami Trench...
at 1100 hours tomorrow, which means...
We have to mobilize
and be in positions by 0800.
But tell me...
will your device be ready by then?
Take us with you.
The final 3 hours will be critical.
We want it perfect.
But you could get caught in the fight.
We've all seen war, too.
Then everybody, go home tonight.
Spend the time with your families.
You mean... be prepared?
Come to think of it...
this country has treated life
far too cheaply.
Poorly armored tanks.
Bad supply lines that resulted in…
that half of all deaths were due to hunger and disease.
Fighter planes built without
ejection seats.
And finally, kamikaze
and suicide attacks.
That's why this time.....
I'd take pride in a citizen-led effort...
that sacrifices no lives at all!
This next battle...
is not one waged to the death.
But a battle to live for the future.
- Let's do it!
Finally, tomorrow's the day.
- I can't wait.
- You're not going.
What do you mean?
You are of no use with that hand.
Even Shikishima's going!
Is it because I haven't been a soldier?
I can be of use.
It is precisely something to be proud of...
that you have never been to war.
I also want to defend my country.
Take me with you!
We've been a team for a long time!
You don't want enough!
Take me with you!
I want to join!
We make sure you have a future.
Captured!
Mr. Noda!
A little lower.
Careful.
Here you go, Akiko.
I want to...
thank you for everything.
Akiko.
Was it fun at Auntie's?
It was fun.
Good. I'm glad.
Is it for me?
Thank you.
- Akiko.
- Yes.
Is this you, me and mom?
That's mom there.
I see.
It's really good.
Why do you look so sad?
What's wrong?
Akiko.
There there.
It'll be all right.
I'm not leaving you.
Mr. Tachibana.
It is ready?
Give me a minute.
The bomb you ordered.
Two machine guns,
140 kg... 120 rounds, 80 kg...
And one main fuel tank,
400 kg removed.
Instead, a No. 25 bomb in the nose,
and No. 50 in the fuselage.
Now, I can finally pay them back.
That's funny.
Part of me wants to live.
Like all those men back then.
They wanted to go home to their families.
But instead,
they got squashed like bugs.
I understand you.
This was drawn by a girl named Akiko.
I want to protect her future.
I will stop Godzilla no matter what.
You're finally ready.
Then, this is important.
Look here.
The bomb's safety pin.
Pull it out before flying in.
Got it?
One last thing.
Akiko.
Are you all by yourself?
Look here.
“To Sumiko...”
"Look after Akiko.
Use this money for her."
From Daddy?
Huh? Yeah, from Daddy.
It's all right.
Don't worry.
This is Kuroshio 12, 35.03 N, 139.41 E.
Many deep sea fish were found!
Godzilla is sighted in Sagami Bay!
Underwater guidance decoy activated.
Take only the essentials with you!
Get on board quickly.
Let's speed up!
- Mizushima took our advice?
- It's the best thing for him.
I didn't want Shikishima to fly either.
A failed kamikaze pilot?
It worries me.
He's got Akiko.
He'll make it back alive.
The underwater decoy team was destroyed!
Godzilla has entered Sagami Bay!
Wada Tsumi ships, leave port now!
Look.
There!
It's already here.
Godzilla's through the final defense line!
Heading for shore!
I'm off!
Time to end it once and for all, Shikishima.
Leave port now! Repeat.
Wada Tsumi ships leave port now!
What now?
The plan's ruined!
We board anyway.
We need to sink it over the Sagami Trench
or it won't work.
Shikishima will have to lure it!
- Come on!
- We are going!
Radio from Mr. Shikishima!
I'm in the air preparing to lure
Godzilla to target area.
- We are ready.
- Get there quickly.
Don't do anything rash!
I won't forgive you if you orphan Akiko.
You hear me, Shikishima!
He's ignoring me.
Mail!
Coming.
- Hello? - Ms. Shikishima?
You have a telegram.
- Thanks.
Wow. What a way to lure it away!
Godzilla looks really ticked off.
- It follows him.
- Now it's our turn.
- All ships in battle position!
Freon cylinders are ready!
46 cm cannonballs ready!
Levitation switch ready!
Cables ready!
All circuits are on!
Turn on the power and
release the safety device!
Fine. Come on.
- Team one attacks as planned.
- As planned!
Atta boy.
That's Godzilla's heat ray.
The ships won't survive this.
All ships must evacuate!
No, this is okay. We stick to the plan.
But the heat ray!
Once fired, it takes time to regenerate.
We go now!
Give the order!
Commence Operation Wada Tsumi!
Fire 46 cm cannonballs,
cylinders and levitation switch!
Shikishima!
- Crane ready!
- Roger!
Hold courses, Hibiki!
Hibiki, maintain course!
Maintain speed, some damage is inevitable.
Hibiki approaching, 4 meters!
2 meter.
- Be prepared for collision!
- Crossing complete, Full speed ahead!
- Full speed ahead!
Very good!
- Captain, the switch.
- Roger!
Oh no. Not yet?
Almost.
Ready...
- Hit it, Captain!
- Now!
- Freon!
- Got it!
Depth 1,200 meters!
1,300 meters!
- 1,400 meters!
- Keep going!
- Dive!
- 1,450 meters!
1,500 target passed!
We sunk Godzilla!
Did it succeed?
Persistent bugger.
- We'll go to plan B.
- Do it.
Now rise
Depth 1,200 meters!
1,100 meters 1,000 meters!
Cables stopped!
They have stopped at 803 metres!
Why? What's wrong?
They are bitten over.
Hibiki, pull Godzilla up!
90 degrees max speed!
The two ships lack the thrust.
We've no choice.
Give it all you can!
Yes, sir!
At this rate...
the crane won't hold.
Get away quickly!
This is Yokohama tugboat Fujimaru!
- Doing our best to help!
- That voice there.
Mizushima here! Are you there, captain?
Is that you, Kid?
You bet!
This is Toyo Kisen's Koeimaru,
here to help.
And Yokohama Eisen's Nikkomaru!
At your service!
- Shiokazemaru, assisting!
- Tetsuyumaru.
- Nanamimaru.
- Minamimaru.
- Kisshomaru.
- Junseimaru.
- Wakamaru.
- Heimitsumaru.
Tenyumaru.
- Kaiomaru.
- Hyūga.
- Choukamaru.
- Shuseimaru.
- Taramaru.
- Yasakamaru.
The useless to the rescue!
I'll be damned.
I gotta admit I'm glad to see him.
All you tugboats out there!
Let's catch a Godzilla!
- Everybody pull!
Godzilla's rising again!
Come on, show your face!
Depth 700 meters!
Keep coming, keep coming!
It's not damaged enough!
All ships, get away!
What's he doing?
No.
- Don't.
- Stop!
Shikishima!
Shikishima...
No, look!
I see him.
I see him!
Pilot ejected!
He's alive!
This seat h
Just pull that lever.
Live.
Mr. Tachibana.
Shikishima!
You did it!
Kid!
- Sumiko!
- Koichi!
- Koichi.
- Akiko.
What?
Is your war…
now finally over?
Ryunosuke KAMIKI
Minami HAMABE
Yuki YAMADA
Miou TANAKA, Yuya ENDO Kisuke IIDA, Sae NAGATANI
Hidetaka YOSHIOKA
Munetaka AOKI
Sakura ANDO
Kuranosuke SASAKI
Script, direction and VFX: Takashi YAMAZAKI