Announcer:
It‘s our pleasure
to welcome you
to your friendly
drive-in theater.
Our ultra-modern snack bar
is now open
and ready to serve you.
How about a thick
crunchy hamburger;
a big cup of hot chips
or fish and chips;
icy orange or lemon drink;
smooth creamy ice cream;
and giant-sized hot dogs
with sauce or mustard?
Thanks, everyone.
We trust you have a
very pleasant evening.
THERE WAS JUST THIS CERTAIN
FLAVOR ABOUT...
THE AUSSIE EXPLOITAT--
I CALL IT "AUSSIE ‘XPLOITATION."
- AHHH!
- WEIRD, WONDERFUL...
- ...REALLY STRANGE MOVIES.
- ( screams )
- DOWN AND DIRTY.
- AHHH!
- VERY FAST...
AND CHEAP.
URBAN VULGARITY...
- BAD LANGUAGE...
- COP THAT, YOU ROTTEN
POMMY BASTARD.
SOMETHING‘S GOING
TO BLOW UP.
...SEXUAL OVERTONES...
- AHH!
- AUSSIE BULLIES...
TERRORIZING PEOPLE.
MURDER, RAPE AND MAYHEM.
( screaming )
THRILLER, CHILLER...
- AHH.
- SLASH AND CUT AND KILL.
BAD ADVERTISEMENTS
FOR AUSTRALIA.
MOST OF THE AUSTRALIAN GENRE
FILMS WERE ACTUALLY RELEASED
IN AMERICAN, ALL RIGHT,
THROUGH EXPLOITATION HOUSES
AND STUFF.
AND IT WAS ACTUALLY
COINCIDING WITH THE WHOLE
BIG AUSTRALIAN BOOM--
THE BIG AUSTRALIAN NEW WAVE--
THAT WAS COMING OUT
WITH "MY BRILLIANT CAREER"
AND "THE GETTING OF WISDOM"
AND "BREAKER MORANT"
AND ALL THOSE MOVIES.
NOW WHEN THOSE MOVIES
WERE COMING OUT,
THEY‘RE LIKE, YOU KNOW,
"THE NEW AUSTRALIAN FILM--
AUSTRALIAN CINEMA, AUSTRALIAN
CINEMA, AUSTRALIAN CINEMA."
THAT WAS LIKE THE KEY WORD
FOR INDEPENDENT CINEMA.
BUT THE AUSTRALIAN
GENRE FILMS WEREN‘T
BEING TOUTED AS AUSSIE FILMS.
I DIDN‘T KNOW THEY WERE
AUSSIE GENRE FILMS UNTIL
I BOUGHT MY TICKET
AND THEY OPENED
THEIR MOUTHS.
COME ON, MAN,
SHOOT ME!
YOU FINISHED
THE KANGAROO OFF!
SHOOT ME!
( rock song playing )
♪ OH YEAH ♪
♪ HEY ♪
♪ YEAH ♪
♪ IF YOU WANT TO BE
IN MY GANG ♪
♪ STAND UP WITH ME ♪
♪ WE‘LL START
A REVOLUTION ♪
♪ AND MAKE
THE STREETS FREE ♪
♪ WE‘LL NEVER
WEAKEN ♪
♪ WE‘LL GIVE IT
OUR BEST ♪
♪ CAN‘T BE DEFEATED,
WE‘RE FITTER THAN THE REST ♪
♪ SHOULDER TO SHOULDER
WE‘RE GONNA STAND ♪
♪ WE‘RE GONNA FIGHT TILL
THE VERY LAST MAN ♪
♪ CAN‘T BE DEFEATED ♪
♪ DON‘T KNOW THE WORD ♪
♪ SHOULDER TO SHOULDER ♪
♪ WE‘LL FIGHT THE WORLD ♪
♪ ‘CAUSE WE CAN‘T
BE BEATEN ♪
♪ HEY HEY ♪
♪ WE CAN‘T BE BEATEN ♪
♪ YOU GOTTA
BELIEVE IT ♪
♪ WE CAN‘T BE BEATEN ♪
♪ THEY‘LL SOON
FIND OUT ♪
♪ WE CAN‘T BE BEATEN ♪
♪ OOOOWWWW ♪
♪ AHH ♪
♪ WE CAN‘T BE BEATEN. ♪
PEOPLE KNOW NOTHING
ABOUT AUSTRALIA
EXCEPT WHAT IS HANDED OUT
IN THE TRAVEL BROCHURES,
WHICH DOESN‘T REALLY INDUCE
PEOPLE TO COME TO AUSTRALIA
BECAUSE THERE ARE NOT SO MANY
PEOPLE IN THE WORLD
WHO ARE THAT INTERESTED IN
KANGAROOS AND KOALA BEARS.
THE LATE ‘60s AND THEN
THE EARLY ‘70s
WAS A SEISMIC MOMENT
IN AUSTRALIA CULTURALLY
AND POLITICALLY.
PEOPLE DIDN‘T WANT TO BE
CONTROLLED BY GOVERNMENTS
AND BY THE STATUS QUO.
THE WHOLE WORLD IS IN
A DESPERATE SITUATION.
AND THEY CAN‘T AFFORD
TO SIT WITH THEIR HANDS
FOLDED ANYMORE.
FEMINISM WAS JUST BEGINNING
TO FRACTURE THE RELATIONSHIPS
BETWEEN MEN AND WOMEN.
Announcer:
Germaine Greer writes, "Women
should seek a revolution."
- THERE WAS A LOT OF
OPPOSITION TO THE WAR.
- ( machine gunfire )
IT WAS UNBELIEVABLE
TO LIVE IN A SOCIETY
WHERE THEY WERE CONSCRIPTING
WITH A LOTTERY.
WE WERE INVOLVED IN
THE MORATORIUM.
- APARTHEID.
- STANDING UP AND SAYING
THINGS ABOUT ABORTION.
- ( chanting )
- Rod Mullinar: D IN
NUCLEAR DISARMAMENT.
WE FELT WE WERE PART OF
THE REBELLION THAT WAS
STARTING WORLDWIDE.
WE CERTAINLY
HAD THE IDEAS
THAT WE COULD
CHANGE EVERYTHING.
AND YOU COULD DO THAT
AS WELL AS GETTING STONED
OUT OF YOUR MIND.
THERE WAS A YOUNG ARISTOCRACY
WHICH WERE RULING THINGS
AND PREFERRING FORNICATION
AND HALLUCINATION
TO WHAT HAD PRECEDED.
IF YOU WEREN‘T WILD,
YOU WEREN‘T HIP.
IT WAS A TREMENDOUS ENERGY
AND THAT CARRIED OVER INTO
THE ARTS GENERALLY.
I NEVER THOUGHT THAT AUSTRALIA
WAS A PLACE THAT NEEDED CULTURE
OF ANY DESCRIPTION, BUT WE DID
FEEL WE HAD TO HAVE IT--
WE HAD TO HAVE AN OPERA HOUSE--
SOMETHING TO PUT ON THE STAMPS.
AND SLOWLY OF COURSE,
IT BEGAN TO GROW.
AND IT ONLY REALLY GROWS
ON DECAYING THINGS,
BECAUSE CULTURE IS,
AFTER ALL, CHEESE, ISN‘T IT?
OR YOGURT?
TODAY THERE‘S NO INDUSTRY
IN THIS COUNTRY
MAKING FEATURE FILMS.
WE RANK WITH ECUADOR
AND ICELAND
WHICH, LIKE US, ARE AMONG
THE GREAT NON-FILMMAKERS.
BUT THERE ARE SIGNS THAT
WE MIGHT HAVE FOUND OUR
DORMANT FILM INDUSTRY.
THE GREAT CINEMATIC SILENCE
IN AUSTRALIA
WAS OCCASIONALLY BROKEN
BY AN INTERNATIONAL CREW
WHO WOULD WANDER IN AND TRY
AND MAKE AN AUSTRALIAN FILM.
TED KOTCHEFF CAME IN AND MADE
A FILM CALLED "WAKE IN FRIGHT."
Announcer:
This is John Grant,
a handsome, intelligent
young schoolteacher.
This is John Grant,
an ugly, sweaty,
desperate animal.
What happened to
John Grant?
The Outback happened
to John Grant.
IT WAS A SLOWLY DEVELOPING
NIGHTMARE OF DRINKING...
FIGHTING, SHOOTING,
HUNTING KANGAROOS.
AUSTRALIANS AT THE TIME DIDN‘T
WANT TO SEE IT AS AUSTRALIAN.
PEOPLE WALKED AWAY
SAYING, "THAT‘S NOT US.
WE DON‘T BEHAVE LIKE THAT."
AS A FOREIGNER,
YOU SEE THINGS
WHICH AUSTRALIANS TAKE
FOR GRANTED
OR ACCEPT AS PART OF
THE DAILYNESS OF THEIR LIFE.
THEY DON‘T SEE WHAT‘S
ECCENTRIC OR IDIOSYNCRATIC
ABOUT THEIR LIFE.
( all chanting )
Man:
Thank you, ladies
and gentlemen.
AND THE EARLY EFFECT
THAT THE FRONTIER HAS
ON THOSE WHO SEE THEMSELVES
AS CIVILIZED EUROPEANS...
Phillip Adams:
IF IT HADN‘T BEEN FOR
THESE INVADERS
TELLING US SOMETHING ABOUT
WHAT WE LOOKED LIKE
AND WHAT OUR LANDSCAPES
LOOKED LIKE,
OUR CULTURAL ANONYMITY
WOULD HAVE BEEN UTTER.
WHAT THEY PROVIDED WAS
A KNOWLEDGE FOR WOULD-BE
AUSTRALIAN FILMMAKERS
THAT WE HAD THE ABILITY
TO TELL TALES
ABOUT OURSELVES IN
A WAY THAT WAS DYNAMIC
AND INTERESTING.
WE WERE REALLY VERY LUCKY
THAT WE HAD AT
THE RIGHT TIME,
AT THE RIGHT PLACE, TWO PEOPLE
WHO WERE DEEPLY COMMITTED
TO THE IDEA OF AN AUSTRALIAN
FILM CULTURE.
IF YOU COULD SHOW A HINT OF
CREATIVE ABILITY IN AUSTRALIA,
SUDDENLY YOU WERE BEING
LAVISHLY FUNDED.
THE GOVERNMENT‘S SHELLING OUT
PILES OF BLOODY MOOLAH
FOR ANY BASTARD WHO RECKONS
HE CAN PAINT PICTURES,
WRITE POEMS OR MAKE FILMS.
AND THE WHOLE
THING TOOK OFF.
( game theme playing )
( crowds cheering )
Phillip Adams:
I GOT A FUNNY IDEA
ABOUT MAKING A FILM
ON AUSTRALIAN SEXUALITY.
WHAT DO YOU THINK OF
"LES-BI-ANISM"?
LES--
I‘M AFRAID I DON‘T
UNDERSTAND MEDICAL TERMS.
THE IDEA WAS TO HAVE
A DR. KINSEY CHARACTER
WANDERING AROUND
TAKING NOTES.
Announcer:
He saw sex as
Australia sees it.
He talks with the madam
of a brothel...
I USED TO BE A PROS--
PROSTITUTE MYSELF.
BUT OLD AGE AND...
EVERYTHING CAUGHT UP
WITH ME.
...with fashion models,
photographers, the guy
on the street...
THE FILM WAS CONSTANTLY POUNCED
ON BY CENSORSHIP AUTHORITIES
AT EVERY LEVEL.
EVENTUALLY WHEN IT WAS SHOWN,
MANY SEQUENCES WERE CUT.
I‘D BE TERRIFIED
TO SLEEP WITH A MAN.
I WOULDN‘T KNOW
WHAT TO DO.
AND THE DIRECTOR,
JOHN B. MURRAY,
INCLUDED DRAWINGS OF
A NAKED BUNYIP
TO SIGNAL THE SHOTS THAT
HAD BEEN TAKEN OUT.
THE BUNYIP WOULD LEAP
AND CAVORT AND DANCE
ON THE SCREEN.
AND THE AUDIENCE WENT WILD.
THEY MUCH PREFERRED THOSE
PARTS OF THE FILM
THAT ONLY HAD
THE BUNYIP IN THEM.
AUSTRALIAN CENSORSHIP
WAS THE MOST REPRESSIVE
ANYWHERE IN
THE WESTERN WORLD.
Man:
IF YOU HAPPENED TO SEE
BREASTS BARE,
AND CERTAINLY IF YOU SAW
PUBIC HAIR,
YOU‘D JUST
ABOUT FALL OUT OF YOUR SEAT.
WE HAD IN AUSTRALIA
IN THOSE DAYS A CENSOR--
A MAN CALLED PROUSE.
I DIDN‘T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT HIM MUCH,
EXCEPT THAT HE HAD ONE ARM.
PROWSE COULDN‘T MASTURBATE AS
EASILY AS PERHAPS OTHERS COULD.
AND WHEN I WAS INVOLVED
IN CENSORSHIP ROWS,
BARRY HUMPHRIES WOULD THROW
PRESS CONFERENCES AND SAY--
"I WAS SORRY MR. PROUSE
COULDN‘T ATTEND,
BUT I HAD HEARD THAT
HE WOULD HAVE GIVEN HIS
RIGHT ARM TO BE THERE."
I THINK IT WAS THE ADVENT
OF DON CHIPP AS MINISTER
OF THE CUSTOMS
THAT LEAD TO SOME SLACKENING
OF THE CENSORSHIP LAWS.
I HOPE YOU HAVE A VERY
HAPPY STAY IN AUSTRALIA, SIR.
I THINK COMMUNITY
STANDARDS CHANGE.
AND THE CENSORSHIP
PHILOSOPHIES FOLLOW IT.
HE PIONEERED
THE "R" CERTIFICATE.
THE "R" RATING ALLOWED
MUCH MORE EXPLICIT VIOLENCE
AND MUCH MORE
EXPLICIT SEX.
AND SUDDENLY, IT WAS
ON FOR YOUNG AND OLD.
Announcer:
It‘s the bawdiest, craziest,
most hilarious comedy
you‘ve ever seen!
AS I COME TOWARDS YOU,
I STUFF THE SMOKED OYSTER
UP MY NOSTRIL LIKE THIS.
EXCUSE ME, MADAM,
BUT HAVE YOU GOT A HANDKERCHIEF?
"STORK" WAS THE VERY FIRST
OF THE SO-CALLED OCKER COMEDIES.
AND HOW‘S THE MOLE
SITUATION AROUND HERE?
THERE WAS A LOT OF FRANKNESS
ABOUT THE MORALS OF THE TIME,
I THINK.
WHOO-HAA!
THE OLD MÉNAGE À TROIS, EH?
BUT SOMEHOW IT DOESN‘T
COME ACROSS AS DIRTY.
ARE YOU A VIRGIN, STORK?
Tim Burstall:
TO EVERYONE‘S AMAZEMENT,
"STORK" TURNED OUT TO BE
THE FIRST AUSTRALIAN
COMMERCIAL SUCCESS
IN SOMETHING LIKE
15 YEARS.
David Williamson:
IT WAS A TURNING POINT
IN AUSTRALIAN FILMS
BEING ACCEPTED AS POSSIBLY
BEING SOMETHING
THAT AUSTRALIAN PEOPLE
WANTED TO SEE.
NOT SO MANY YEARS AGO, IF YOU‘D
ASKED AN OVERSEAS RESIDENT
WHAT THEY THOUGHT
TYPIFIED AUSTRALIA,
THE CHANCES ARE
THEY‘D PROBABLY SAY, UM...
A KANGAROO OR A KOALA.
NOW THE ANSWER IS PROBABLY
MORE LIKELY TO BE
OUR SELF-PROCLAIMED
NATIONAL HERO BAZZA McKENZIE.
Barry Humphries:
BARRY McKENZIE WAS
AN AUSTRALIAN
LOOKING FOR
SEXUAL ADVENTURES
AND AT THE SAME TIME,
FEARFUL OF THEM.
Barry Jones:
A SIMPLE CHARACTER WHO
FINDS HIMSELF
IN THE FAR MORE SOPHISTICATED
MILIEU OF LONDON.
WE TRIED TO MAKE ENGLAND LOOK
AS BAD AS POSSIBLE.
THAT‘S NOT DIFFICULT.
LIKE IT?
ONE COAT OF DULUX DONE THIS.
IT WAS VERY IMPORTANT
THAT THERE BE A LOT OF
DOGSHIT EVERYWHERE.
I‘D EVEN WRITTEN A SONG:
"LOOK OUT FOR POOP ON
THE PAVEMENT.
DON‘T BE CAUGHT
TAKING A NAP.
THE BUILDINGS MAY BE
OLD AND HISTORIC,
BUT THE STREETS
ARE PAVED WITH CRAP."
BLOODY DOG CRAP!
NEARLY BREAK MY LEG ON
THAT ALSATIAN‘S VISITING CARD.
THERE ARE A FEW FIRSTS
IN THE "McKENZIE" FILM,
AND I THINK THE VOMITING SCENE
IS THE MOST SEMINAL.
I EVEN MIXED
THE CHUNDER...
WHICH MOSTLY CAME OUT OF
A TIN OF CORN SOUP.
- PEA SOUP...
- FRUIT SALADS...
...AUGMENTED BY A CERTAIN
AMOUNT OF POTATO SALAD.
IT NEEDS LEMONADE
TO GIVE IT A FIZZ.
I REMEMBER BARRY SAYING,
"MAKE SURE YOU GET
A COUPLE SHREDS OF
TOMATO IN THERE.
THAT‘S ALWAYS PRESENT."
WE HAD ONE CHUNDER SCENE
IN THE FIRST MOVIE.
WE WERE COPIED
IN "THE EXORCIST."
I‘M NOT SUING.
I THOUGHT, "WELL, WE‘LL HAVE TO
HAVE TWO IN OUR NEXT MOVIE."
- WE HAVE. R SCENE
- AHHHH!
ONE OF THE SCENES
THAT I TREASURE
WAS TO HAVE
BARRY McKENZIE VOMIT
FROM THE TOP OF
THE EIFFEL TOWER.
GOT A FUNNY FEELING
IN ME NED KELLY
I‘M GONNA CRY RUTH.
THE PEOPLE ARE PUZZLED BY THIS:
"CRY RUTH"?
HE LEANS OVER,
YOU HEAR HIM CALLING,
"RU-- RUTH!"
RUUUUTH!
NAUSEATING EVEN
TO THINK ABOUT.
IT IS ONE OF
THE GREAT MOMENTS
IN THE AUSTRALIAN CINEMA.
AND IF THERE‘D BEEN MORE OF IT
IN "PICNIC AT HANGING ROCK,"
IT WOULD HAVE BEEN
AN EVEN GREATER FILM.
HOW COME A GOOD-LOOKING
CLEAN-CUT AUSTRALIAN LIKE ME
GETS SO MANY KNOCKBACKS
WHEN SOME DIRTY, GREASY,
IKEY-MO-STYLE BASTARD
LIKE YOU
SCORES IT FOR
A KNEE-TREMBLER WITH
AN ABO IN AN AIRBORNE DUNNY?
HOMOPHOBIA AND RACISM
CAN BE CHARMING...
JEEZ, IF IT WAS RAINING VIRGINS,
I‘D BE WASHED DOWN THE GUTTER
WITH THE POOFTERS.
- ...DELIGHTFUL...
- WHAT A SWEET LITTLE
TINTED PERSON.
- ...ESSENTIAL.
- I WILL NOT HEAR ANYONE
ATTACKING THEM.
THIS-- THIS MAKES US
WHO WE ARE.
WE DID HAVE
A CLASSIFICATION--
"N.P.A.
NO POOFTERS ALLOWED."
HOW MANY TIMES
I TOLD YOU, RHONDA,
NOT TO BRING ANY OF THEM
MALE-MODEL POOFTERS OF YOURS
THROUGH OUR PRIVATE QUARTERS?
ESPECIALLY THE AUSTRALIANS!
THEY ARE THE BIGGEST
POOFTERS OF THEM ALL.
YESSAH!
Phillip Adams:
BARRY HAD ALWAYS
LOATHED AND DETESTED
THE AUSTRALIAN OCKER.
Men singing:
♪ ...THROUGH AND THROUGH... ♪
TO HIS HORROR,
THE PEOPLE HE MOST LOATHED
MOST LOVED THE FILM.
Man: Are you happy to have
a girl with you when
you see this movie?
Aw, yeah.
Like the song says, you know,
put your sheila in a frenzy.
Oh, I‘m prepared, you know,
to be Australian.
It makes me feel
like I‘m Australian.
Man:
Yeah, I reckon
he‘s a true-blue Aussie.
LOOK, THERE ARE ALWAYS
MORONS WHO SEE
SATIRE AS DOCUMENTARY.
THEY THOUGHT IT WAS
AN ENDORSEMENT OF THEIR
WAY OF LIFE.
IN FACT, IN A FUNNY KIND
OF WAY, I SUPPOSE IT WAS.
IT WAS CERTAINLY
QUITE AFFECTIONATE.
I‘VE BEEN SPEAKING TO SOME
OF MY MATES--
SOPHISTICATED MATES IN
THE FILM PRODUCTION BUSINESS.
AND THEY RECKON THIS IS
THE TYPE OF SHOW
THAT‘S GIVEN AUSTRALIA
WORLD LEADERSHIP IN
FILM PRODUCTION TODAY.
SO I BELIEVE, BARRY.
DID YOU KNOW THE CRITICS
HAVE GONE ABSOLUTELY BERSERK?
A THIRD- OR FOURTH-RATE
NASTY LITTLE MOVIE.
IT WAS LOATHSOME, REALLY.
TAKE A LOOK AT IT.
IT‘S JUST HORRIBLE.
IT‘S UGLY AND CLUTTERED
AND UNPLEASANT.
- SMUTTY...
- I MAY BE OLD-FASHIONED,
YOUNG WOMAN,
BUT LESBIANISM HAS
ALWAYS LEFT A NASTY TASTE
IN MY MOUTH.
- ...UN-AUSTRALIAN...
- IS IT TRUE THAT
ALL AUSTRALIANS
ARE HOMOSEXUALS?
NO, MATE,
THAT‘S JUST A RUMOR
SPREAD BY THE AUSTRALIAN
GOVERNMENT TO ATTRACT
POMMY MIGRANTS.
I THOUGHT IT WAS PERHAPS
TOO AUSTRALIAN.
WE WEREN‘T MAKING
A FILM FOR THE AUSTRALIAN
TOURIST COMMISSION.
IF YOU CAN‘T SATIRIZE YOURSELF,
YOU HAVE NO IDENTITY.
I THINK THAT‘S
A VERY IMPORTANT FILM.
SOCIETY WAS CHANGING--
THE PERCEPTION
OF SOCIAL VALUES...
AND POLITICAL VALUES
WAS CHANGING.
"LET THE LEGAL BARRIERS
AGAINST PORNOGRAPHY
BE SWEPT AWAY.
LET‘S ABOLISH THE CENSORS,"
THEY SAY, "AND HAVE OUR FUN."
PERHAPS IN THE
TELEVISION FIELD, AUSTRALIA
LED THE WORLD WITH
"NUMBER 96."
Deborah Gray:
"NUMBER 96" WAS A MAJOR,
VERY SUCCESSFUL TOP-10 SHOW.
Sandy Harbutt:
IT TURNED TELEVISION
ON ITS HEAD
BECAUSE IT WAS
ALL SHOCKING.
AHHH!
THAT KIND OF LIBERATION
WENT THROUGH TO FILMS
AS WELL.
IT‘S JUST DE RIGUEUR TO HAVE
AT LEAST ONE NUDE SCENE.
"THE NUDE NEXT DOOR,"
I GOT DUBBED A LOT.
IT WAS A STANCE
OF LIBERATION.
Wendy Hughes:
IT WAS ACTUALLY
A WAY OF SAYING,
"I AM WHO I AM,
AND LOOK OUT."
THE AUSTRALIAN GIRL IS
JUSTIFIABLY PROUD OF HER FIGURE.
SHE HAS EVERY RIGHT TO BE--
IT‘S LOVELY.
NUDITY WAS NO ISSUE
IN THIS PERIOD
BECAUSE EVERYBODY WANTED
TO BE NUDE.
IT‘S THE IN THING
TO TODDLE AROUND
WITH JUST THE BOTTOM HALVES
OF YOUR BATHERS.
AND IF YOU‘RE WEARING YOUR TOP,
YOU‘RE DEFINITELY OUT.
EVERYONE WAS FLASHING THEIR...
EVERYTHING AND WHATNOT.
Graeme Blundell:
PEOPLE WERE NUDE IN THE STREET;
THEY WERE NUDE AT HOME;
THEY WERE NUDE
AT PARTIES.
ANYONE FOR STRIP POKER?
WOMEN ARE PROUD
OF THEIR BIG BODIES;
MEN ARE PROUD OF
THEIR BEER BELLIES.
IT WAS JUST A CELEBRATION
OF FLESHINESS.
THERE WERE CERTAIN ELEMENTS--
VERY CONSERVATIVE ELEMENTS
IN AUSTRALIAN SOCIETY
THAT WERE ALARMED BY
THE NEW FREEDOMS.
Man:
YOU‘VE WARNED THAT CIVILIZATION
COULD FACE DISASTER
IF MORALITY CONTINUES
TO BE DEGRADED.
HOW LONG HAVE WE GOT,
IN FACT?
WELL, I‘VE HAD DISCUSSIONS
WITH LORD LONGFORD
AND MALCOLM MUGGERIDGE,
AND THEY GIVE A PERIOD
OF 10 YEARS.
I WAS WAITING KEENLY
FOR THE MORAL DECAY
AND IT DIDN‘T HAPPEN AS BADLY
AS THEY SAID IT WOULD,
BUT THERE WAS ENOUGH AROUND
TO MAKE IT INTERESTING.
♪ ALVIN... ♪
Announcer:
"Alvin Purple" was shot
earlier this year
by Australia‘s leading
filmmaker Tim Burstall.
"ALFIE" WITH MICHAEL CAINE
WAS OUT AT THE TIME.
- AND I DID A REVERSE
SITUATION-- T WOULD,
- ALVIN?
ALVIN WAS A VICTIM.
- ALVIN.
- THE WOMEN BECAME
THE PREDATORS.
TIM SAID THEY WANT TO HAVE
SOMEONE PLAYING THIS ROLE
WHO‘S NOT AN OBVIOUS STUD.
IF YOU CAST A REAL STUD
AS YOUR LEAD,
ALL THE MALES WOULD HATE HIM
FOR BEING SO MASTERFUL
AND GETTING OFF
WITH EVERYBODY;
ALL THE FEMALES WOULD
FEEL RESENTFUL, YOU KNOW,
"I‘D NEVER COME ACROSS
TO A FIGURE LIKE THAT."
GRAEME BLUNDELL
WAS PERFECT FOR IT BECAUSE
HE LOOKED LIKE EVERYMAN.
HE BECAME ONE OF OUR
FIRST MEGASTARS.
Graeme Blundell:
IT WAS QUITE EXCITING TO BE
AT THE CENTER OF THAT,
BUT ALSO DAUNTING TO HAVE TO
COPE WITH IT IN MY REAL LIFE.
PEOPLE WOULD COME UP TO ME
WHEREVER I WAS--
"THAT‘S MY WIFE OVER THERE,
MATE. SHE WANTS TO-- HEH HEH--
TALK TO YOU!"
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
I DIDN‘T REALLY
THINK ABOUT IT AT ALL
IN SOME JEALOUS,
POSSESSIVE WAY.
MY MARRIAGE BROKE UP.
MY WIFE WAS A PIONEERING
FEMINIST,
SO OBVIOUSLY SHE WASN‘T
GOING TO LIVE WITH ALL OF
THE SHENANIGANS
THAT FOLLOWED THE CHARACTER
OF ALVIN PURPLE IN REAL LIFE.
THERE ARE VERY FEW ACTRESSES
OF MY GENERATION
WHO WEREN‘T TITS AND ASS
ON AN "ALVIN" FILM.
DID YOU LEAVE IN A HURRY
FOR WORK THIS MORNING?
GIRLS WHO HAVE BECOME
QUITE PRIM
ARE BOLLOCKY
AND ENJOYING IT.
APPARENTLY ON VERY LOW WAGES,
I WOULD SUGGEST,
SINCE BURSTALL WAS INVOLVED.
TIM LOVED GETTING TIT IN
THE SHOT IF HE POSSIBLY COULD.
- I MEAN, THAT WAS
THE NAME OF THE GAME.
- IT WAS ALL FOR THE ART.
I BELIEVE THAT TIM ACTUALLY
MAY HAVE ENCOURAGED
SOME OF THE ACTRESSES
TO BE A LITTLE MORE DARING
IN TERMS OF THE CLOTHING
THAT THEY SHED BY GIVING THEM
ADDITIONAL REMUNERATION
IN ORDER TO MAKE
THEIR WELL-BEING HEALTHIER
AND MORE STABLE.
TIM BURSTALL DID NOT BRIBE ME
TO SHOW MORE TIT.
YOU COULDN‘T HAVE SEEN MORE
THAN WHAT YOU GOT.
Rob Copping:
I CAN REMEMBER TIM OFFERING
JACKI WEAVER
$500 I THINK IT WAS,
CASH, JUST TO GO OUT
AND TAKE HER CLOTHES OFF.
AND JACKI SAID,
"HOW MUCH? OKAY."
BIG BUDGET.
I REMEMBER ON ONE OCCASION
SAYING TO JOHN SEALE,
"HOW WAS IT?" AND HE SAID,
"VERY HARD TO JUDGE.
THE EYEPIECE WAS
COMPLETELY...
MISTED OVER."
THE EYEPIECE FOGGED UP
QUITE REGULARLY.
Tim Burstall:
"BY GOD," HE SAID,
"THAT‘S STEAMY STUFF."
YOU WANT TO GET A GOOD LAUGH;
YOU WANT TO SEE A LITTLE
BIT OF BOOBS,
AND THAT GAVE IT ALL.
IT WAS A HIT OF QUITE
ASTRONOMIC PROPORTIONS.
THE BUDGET WAS $200,000
AND IT TOOK $5 MILLION.
TO SEE THOSE HUGE
QUEUES AROUND THE BLOCK
KNOWING THAT IT WAS
A HIGHLY-PROFITABLE FILM
WAS A HUGE BOOST
TO THE INDUSTRY.
I WORKED WITH
ROBERT ALDRICH,
ROBERT ALTMAN
AND TIM BURSTALL.
AND ALL OF THEM HAVE THAT
WONDERFUL QUALITY OF VULGARITY.
Announcer:
Out of our rollicking,
passionate past
comes a story so bawdy,
so brilliantly beautiful,
so breathtakingly
exciting...
thank goodness it happened
140 years ago.
TIM WANTED TO MAKE A FILM
ABOUT ELIZA FRASER
BUT HE DIDN‘T WANT A DEADLY
SERIOUS ANGST-RIDDEN PIECE.
IT WAS TO BE A ROMP WITH
BAWDINESS BEING THE KEYWORD.
NO DOUBT ABOUT IT
THAT "ELIZA FRASER"
WAS A HUGE GRAND MIXTURE, G
A GREAT POTPOURRI.
I SUPPOSE THAT MIGHT
HAVE BEEN BECAUSE THE
AUSTRALIAN FILM INDUSTRY
WAS SEARCHING
FOR A WAY FORWARD.
AND IN TIM THEY FOUND
THE PERFECT PERSON
WHO WOULD ACTUALLY BE ABLE TO
PROVIDE A BIT OF EVERYTHING.
Bob Ellis:
HE WAS SCUM, REALLY.
HE WAS THE CRAB LOUSE ON
THE AUSTRALIAN FILM INDUSTRY.
ON THE OTHER HAND,
ALL OF US WILL ALWAYS
OWE HIM EVERYTHING.
Rob Copping:
HE WAS THE PERSON WHO WAS
MOST RESPONSIBLE
FOR GETTING THE RENAISSANCE
UNDERWAY AT THAT TIME.
IF TIM BURSTALL
HAD ENERGY,
JOHN LAMOND
HAD UBER ENERGY.
JOHN HAD A GREAT KNACK
OF UNDERSTANDING WHAT THE PUBLIC
WAS INTO AT THE TIME.
A BIT OF CRUDITY
AND A BIT OF NUDITY.
Announcer:
We will explore the weird,
the erotic, the ugly,
the obscene
and the beautiful;
A strange and sometimes
disturbing trip
around darkest Australia.
I SPENT ABOUT A YEAR
GATHERING MATERIAL
ON PEOPLE WHO SWAM AROUND
NAKED UNDERWATER AND
FILMED TROPICAL FISH.
THERE WAS A MAD BASTARD
WHO USED TO CONDUCT
ORCHESTRAL MUSIC
AND PAINT HIS WOMEN DIFFERENT
COLORS AND MAKE A NAKED MURAL.
THERE WAS A LADY IN
KINGS CROSS NAMED MADAM LASH.
- LASH IS READY!
- Man: OH, LOOK AT THAT RACK.
YOU DON‘T SEE CRAFTSMANSHIP
LIKE THAT THESE DAYS.
IT WAS HAPPENING
FOR REAL AROUND US.
WE WERE SEEING THINGS
I‘VE NEVER SEEN AGAIN--
I WOULDN‘T MIND SEEING AGAIN,
BUT I‘VE NEVER SEEN AGAIN.
Announcer:
Black witchcraft ceremonies
are weird and frightening.
We witnessed such a ceremony
in the middle of a forest
not far from Melbourne.
PEOPLE WERE QUITE SHOCKED.
THEY SAID, "DEVIL WORSHIPPERS
IN MELBOURNE!
I CAN‘T-- OH, THIS IS--"
AND JOHN SAID,
"I CAN‘T TELL YOU
ANYTHING ABOUT IT.
THEY‘LL PUT A HEX ON ME.
I‘LL BE CURSED."
I SAID, "TELL!
YOU HAVE TO TELL ME."
HE SAID, "IT WAS IN
MY MOTHER-IN-LAW‘S BACKYARD.
AND IT WAS ALL MY MATES
AND A MIST MACHINE,
AND WE HIRED SOME BIRD
TO WRITHE ON THE ALTAR."
AFTER KINGS CROSS,
YOU RAN OUT OF VICE.
SO WE HAD TO SORT OF CREATE
PHONY VICE.
John Lamond:
"JAWS" WAS ON AT ONE THEATER
AND 14 DRIVE-INS
AND WE WENT IN THE NEXT WEEK
AND WE TOOK AS MUCH.
Drive-in announcer:
Information for those
who are attending the drive-in
for the first time:
The following hints
will make you feel at home
and add to your enjoyment.
IF YOU GO FROM ONE END OF
AUSTRALIA TO THE OTHER,
THERE USED TO BE SOMETHING
LIKE 400 DRIVE-IN SCREENS.
BOTH AMERICA AND AUSTRALIA,
BECAUSE WE BOTH FETISHIZED
AND BUILT AROUND CARS,
ACTUALLY HAVE
A DRIVE-IN CULTURE.
Lamond: I CAN SEE THAT THERE‘S
A GREAT POSSIBILITY
FOR AUSTRALIAN FILMS
TO GET ON THERE.
I MEAN, IF THEY COULDN‘T WIN
SORT OF THE JOCKSTRAP AWARD
AT THE KRAKOW FILM FESTIVAL,
THEY CAN MOST CERTAINLY
FILL THE GAP WITH SOME OF
THE DRIVE-IN AUDIENCES.
Woman:
Sink your teeth
into one now.
( all vomiting )
Announcer:
Now for the first time ever
on the motion-picture screen,
we bring you a revealing
and light-hearted look
between the sheets at
modern-day sex and love.
WE SAT AROUND ONE SATURDAY
AFTERNOON AND KNOCKED OUT
AN IDEA FOR
"A.B.C. OF LOVE AND SEX."
WHAT WE DELIBERATELY SET OUT
TO AVOID
WAS TEXTBOOK DOCUMENTARY.
John-Michael Howson:
JOHN LAMOND CONVINCED ME
I SHOULD BE IN THIS FILM
PLAYING SOMEBODY WHO
WAS DRESSED IN LEATHER.
OOH!
OUTRAGEOUS.
EVERYBODY WAS STANDING AROUND
IN THEIR DRESSING GOWNS
AND THEY TOOK
DEEP BREATHS.
AND EVERYBODY LIFTED UP,
THEIR STOMACHS WENT IN,
AND WE GOT INTO
THE ORGY.
BUT YOU WOULDN‘T WANT
TO HAVE AN ORGY WITH ANY
OF THESE PEOPLE.
- YOU WOULD HAVE RUN! on:
- WE DID RATHER GO OUT OF
OUR WAY TO BE CONTROVERSIAL.
Announcer:
The vagina is a remarkable
erogenous zone,
and because of
its elasticity,
can accommodate various
sizes of penis.
JOHN COULD COOK THIS STUFF UP,
AND HE REALIZED
IF YOU HAD NUBILE YOUNG LADIES
SOAPING EACH OTHER
UNDER A SHOWER, YOU‘RE
PROBABLY GOING TO ATTRACT
SOME SORT OF AN AUDIENCE.
Announcer:
Meet Felicity.
She‘s the world‘s cheekiest,
spunkiest, sexiest new girl.
I LOOKED AT THE SCRIPT
AND I THOUGHT,
"OOH, THIS IS
A BIT HOT."
John Lamond:
"FELICITY" STARTS OFF
IN A CONVENT SCHOOL,
BECAUSE I‘VE ALWAYS HEARD
THAT PEOPLE WHO COME FROM
DEVOUT CATHOLIC BACKGROUNDS
ARE THE HORNIEST ONES
WHEN THEY GET A GO AT IT.
I WAS VERY WOMEN‘S LIB
WHEN I WAS YOUNGER.
I MEAN IT‘S AMAZING,
IN A WAY, THAT I
DID THIS MOVIE,
EXCEPT THAT THE MOVIE IS
ACTUALLY PRO-WOMEN.
MILES, I FEEL
SO HORNY.
JUST WATCH THIS BIT.
THERE IS SOME
MALE FANTASY IN IT.
John Lamond:
THE NUMBER ONE FANTASY OF
ALL THE PEOPLE
WHO GO TO SEE THESE FILMS,
AND NOT JUST THE BLOKES,
IS THE LESBIAN SCENE.
I THINK TWO GIRLS LYING DOWN
TOGETHER THAT AREN‘T LESBIANS--
THAT‘S SORT OF
MORE MALE FANTASY.
GLORIA DOESN‘T LIKE
LESBIAN SEX IN FILMS,
AND I CAN‘T SPEAK
FOR THE PRIVATE PART.
I CAN SAY IN MY DEFENSE THAT
LESBIAN THINGS REALLY HAPPEN.
John-Michael Howson:
AND OF COURSE IT WAS
EVEN MORE INTERESTING
IF THE LESBIANS
WERE GORGEOUS,
NOT LADIES THAT LOOKED LIKE
THEY MAY DRIVE A MACK TRUCK.
IT‘S CONTRIVED BUT
THAT DOESN‘T MEAN IT‘S BAD.
JOHN KNEW THAT OUT THERE
THERE WERE ENOUGH PEOPLE
THAT WANTED TO
SEE PEEPING TOMS
AND PANTY-SNIFFERS
AND LEATHER ORGIES.
HE COULD BE SCURRILOUS,
BUT HE WAS
TOTALLY LOVEABLE.
Alan Finney:
AND JOHN NEVER TOOK
HIMSELF SERIOUSLY
AS EITHER AN EVANGELIST
IN TERMS OF SEXUAL MORES
AND FREEDOMS,
OR AS A RESPECTABLE,
RESPONSIBLE DRAMATIST.
I‘M TOLD I TREAT WOMEN
LIKE A SEX OBJECT,
AND I SUPPOSE IT‘S TRUE ‘CAUSE
I ASK FOR SEX AND THEY OBJECT.
BY THE MIDDLE ‘70s, BONKING
HAD TURNED INTO BANKING.
THERE‘S NO DOUBT ABOUT THAT.
Richard Brennan:
THERE BECAME AN INCREASING
NUMBER OF FILMS
WHERE PEOPLE HAD MADE
INCREASED SALES
BECAUSE THE FILM FEATURED
A NUDE APPEARANCE FROM
SOMEBODY ATTRACTIVE.
Alan Hopgood:
ABIGAIL MADE HER NOTORIETY
IN "NUMBER 96."
Phillip Adams:
AND SHE HAD A SORT OF
A RISQUE REPUTATION ABOUT HER.
Alan Hopgood:
SHE WAS DEFINITELY
A SEX SYMBOL.
WE ADVERTISED THE FACT
THAT WE DID THE FIRST
FULL-FRONTAL WITH ABBY.
OOOH!
SHE FELT SHE WAS
TAKEN ADVANTAGE OF.
Richard Franklin:
SHE HAD THE PRESS SAY,
"HE USED MY BODY."
AND I WAS RATHER SHOCKED
AND RANG HER UP
AND SAID, "I DIDN‘T KNOW
YOU FELT THAT WAY."
SHE SAID, "I DIDN‘T.
I WAS JUST GETTING YOU
SOME PUBLICITY."
Candy Raymond:
THE MEDIA TOOK THIS ON
AS TITILLATION.
IT RAN WITH
"WOMEN AS SEX SYMBOLS."
( rock song playing )
IT WAS, YOU KNOW, KIND OF
THE THING TO BE AT THAT TIME.
IT HAD A LOT TO DO
WITH BIKINIS,
WET CLOTHING, RUNNING AROUND
HALF-DRESSED AND IN SHOWERS
AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
I WAS EMPLOYED PARTLY
BECAUSE I WAS PRETTY
AND I WAS WILLING
TO TAKE MY CLOTHES OFF.
I THINK IT‘S GREAT
TO ACTUALLY DOCUMENT THAT
YOU LOOKED PRETTY DAMN GOOD.
I THOUGHT THAT WE WERE
DEMYSTIFYING THE FEMALE BODY.
I WAS REALLY
SORELY MISTAKEN.
IT WAS SOMETHING
OF AN EXPLOITATION.
ONE OF THE REVIEWS
I READ SAID MY TITS WEREN‘T
IN VERY GREAT SHAPE.
SO YES, MY BREASTS WERE REVIEWED
AS OPPOSED TO MY PERFORMANCE.
CONSEQUENTLY SOME OF
THE BETTER ACTORS TENDED
NOT TO BE IN FILMS,
AND YOU HAD MORE AND MORE
MODELS TAKING LEADS IN FILMS.
MY NAME IS TONY GINNANE.
LAST YEAR I BROUGHT A MOVIE
COMPANY TO HOLLYWOOD,
THE FILM CAPITAL OF
THE WORLD,
AND BROUGHT YOU
"FANTASM."
IT WAS IMPOSSIBLE TO
GET A CAST THAT WOULD
PARTICIPATE IN IT.
AND THE IDEA CAME UP TO
SHOOT IT IN THE UNITED STATES.
I WAS IN CHARGE OF
THE BIGGEST NUDE THEATRICAL
MODELING AGENCY IN THE WORLD.
AND INTO MY OFFICE
ONE DAY COME THESE GENTLEMEN
FROM AUSTRALIA.
AND OF COURSE THE VERY FIRST
NAME I MENTIONED
WAS JOHN HOLMES,
THE KING.
JOHN WAS LIVING PROOF THAT ALL
MEN WERE NOT CREATED EQUAL.
THAT‘S A SHOT THAT TENDS
TO MAKE YOU GASP.
Tony Ginnane:
YOU KNOW, EVERYBODY HAS
THEIR 10 MINUTES OF FAME.
MAYBE JOHN HOLMES HELPED ME
GET 12 INCHES OF FAME.
I‘VE NEVER SEEN
ANYTHING LIKE IT.
I‘D CERTAINLY GO AGAIN.
I THOUGHT IT WAS
REALLY AMUSING.
GREAT FUN.
GREAT FUN INDEED.
THERE WAS A BRIEF MOMENT
IN AUSTRALIAN HISTORY
WHERE MIDDLECLASS
MIXED COUPLES
WANTED TO SEE NUDITY AND SEX
ON THE SCREEN.
NOW WE‘RE BACK
IN HOLLYWOOD
TO BRING YOU THE MOST
OUTRAGEOUS EROTIC COMEDY EVENT
YOU‘LL EVER SEE.
AND UNFORTUNATELY, BY THE TIME
WE GOT "FANTASM COMES AGAIN"
INTO RELEASE, I THINK THAT
THAT MOMENT HAD PASSED.
THE SO-CALLED CRITICS
IN THAT PERIOD JUST HATED
THIS KIND OF FILMMAKING.
I‘D FEEL MORE SECURE IF
I ASKED THE PILOT
HOW MANY HOURS
HE‘S PUT IN.
YOU MUST COME UP
AND LOOK AT MY LOG.
IT WAS REALLY A SENSE
OF SHOCK AND HORROR
THAT WE WERE GOING TO ADMIT
TO THE WIDER WORLD
THAT WE WERE... YAHOOS.
♪ I‘M A BAD BOY ♪
♪ A BAD BOY
FOR LOVE ♪
♪ YEAH, I‘M A BAD BOY ♪
♪ A BAD BOY
FOR LOVE ♪
♪ SO BAD. ♪
Graeme Blundell:
YOU HAD THE FEELING THAT
GOVERNMENT AGENCIES
WOULD ACTUALLY STAND
AT THE BORDER WITH POLICE
AND SECURITY
TO STOP THESE CANS OF FILM
BEING SEEN OVERSEAS.
Jack Thompson:
SO INSTEAD OF MAKING FILMS
THAT JUST CAME LIBIDINOUSLY
OUT OF WHO WE WERE,
WE STARTED TO MAKE FILMS
ABOUT WHO WE THOUGHT
WE WANTED THEM
TO THINK WE ARE.
Barry Humphries:
SUDDENLY AUSTRALIA HAD
TO HAVE AN IMAGE.
AND THERE WERE THOSE
ENEMIES OF OUR IMAGE...
SHE‘S SCREAMING
FOR IT, CURL.
HER OLDIES WANT TO
GET ME TO THE CHURCH
BEFORE I SPEAR
THE BEARDED CLAM.
PARTICULARLY THOSE WHO
DID NOT DEPICT AUSTRALIA
AS NICE GIRLS IN WHITE
DRESSES VANISHING INTO ROCKS.
Phillip Adams:
BUT PETER WEIR AND THESE OTHER
MORE CULTURED DIRECTORS
HAVE TO ACKNOWLEDGE
THAT WITHOUT BAZZA AND
WITHOUT ALVIN,
WITHOUT THESE VULGAR FILMS,
WE WOULDN‘T REALLY HAVE
AN INDUSTRY.
IT IS VERY CLEAR NOW WHAT
AUSTRALIAN CINEMA WAS DOING.
IT WAS BASICALLY CREATING
A HYBRID BETWEEN EUROPE
AND HOLLYWOOD.
AND VIRTUALLY ALL
THE AUSTRALIAN FILMS
THAT WERE BEING FUNDED WERE
CATCHING UP WITH OUR HISTORY.
SO THAT WAS ONE MOVEMENT
THAT WAS TENDING TO HAPPEN.
THERE WAS ANOTHER MOVEMENT
WHICH WAS GENRE FILMMAKING.
( circus music playing )
( girls screaming )
♪ DON‘T GO WALKING OUT
LATE AT NIGHT ♪
♪ BOLT YOUR DOOR,
LOCK YOUR WINDOWS TIGHT ♪
♪ BE MUCH SAFER
STAYING OUT OF SIGHT ♪
( all screaming )
♪ SHADOW BOXER, AHH ♪
♪ SHADOW BOXER,
AHH AHH ♪
♪ SHADOW BOXER, AHH AHH... ♪
( screaming )
TERRY BOURKE-- PRODUCER,
DIRECTOR, WRITER,
EGOTISTICAL BASTARD.
HIS ATTITUDE WAS VERY MUCH TO
APPEAL TO EVERY KIND OF AUDIENCE
YOU COULD POSSIBLY REEL IN.
SO IF YOU HAVE A MURDER,
IT‘S 10 BUCKETS OF BLOOD.
( screams )
"NIGHT OF FEAR" CERTAINLY
WAS A TRAILBLAZER.
AN EXERCISE IN SLOW DESCENT
INTO MADNESS.
IF WE LOOK AT CONTENTIOUS
SCENES IN THAT FILM,
THE ONE THAT CAUSED ENORMOUS
CONFLICT WAS THE SCENE
IN WHICH WE HAD
THE SEVERED HEAD.
Man:
I‘VE GOT THIS DECAPITATED HEAD
IN FRONT OF MY NAKED BODY.
JUST STANDING,
LOOKING DOWN AT HER.
I DIDN‘T WANT TO SEE IT
IN THERE
BUT WE WERE MAKING HORROR,
WE WERE TOUCHING NEW GROUND.
Norman Yemm:
HE GETS THIS LEVER, PULLS IT
AND 400 RATS COME INSIDE
AND EAT HER.
AND I‘M SITTING OUTSIDE
GOING, "OH OH."
TERRY KEPT SAYING,
"OH, DON‘T WORRY, YOU KNOW,
THE RATS ARE BEHIND THE GLASS."
JUST AS I WAS ABOUT TO START,
HE SAID, "OH, BY THE WAY,
WE‘RE HAVING A BIT OF A PROBLEM
WITH THE GLASS CASE, YOU KNOW.
AND IT REALLY WOULD BE
SO MUCH MORE EFFECTIVE
IF WE COULD
DO IT REALISTICALLY.
AND WOULD YOU MIND IF THE RATS
JUST REACH YOUR HAIR?"
- CARIN SCREAMED.
- ( screams )
IT WAS A SCREAM THAT WAS
A GENUINE SCREAM.
Norman Yemm:
LIVE RATS ARE CRAWLING
RIGHT OVER THE BODY
GOING...
( makes chewing sounds )
WHERE HE COULD PUT SOMETHING
ELSE INTO A FILM
THAT MIGHT BE CONTENTIOUS,
HE WOULD MAKE SURE IT
WOULD GO IN THERE.
Man: "THE LADY STAYED DEAD"
WAS JUST A HORROR FILM THAT
HE WANTED TO MAKE.
THE VILLAIN OF THE PIECE
PICKED THE LEAD LADY UP,
STUCK HER HEAD IN
THE FISH POND.
TERRY TOLD HER, IF SHE RAN
OUT OF AIR TO KICK HER LEGS.
WELL, THAT GIRL WAS KICKING
THE LEGS LIKE FURY
AND CHAD HAYWOOD
KEPT HER UPSIDE DOWN.
AND HAVING THE LEAD IN
THE FILM, CHAD WAS LIKE,
"OH MAN, I‘VE GOT TO KEEP
THIS GOING,"
SO HE DIDN‘T TAKE ANY NOTICE
OF THE GIRL‘S LEGS KICKING.
AND TERRY DIDN‘T CALL CUT AND
THE GIRL HAD NEARLY DROWNED.
THEY GOT HER
OUT OF THERE EVENTUALLY.
BUT THAT‘S THE SORT OF GUY
HE WAS--
DETERMINED TO GET WHAT HE WANTED
IN REAL LIFE AND ONSCREEN.
( all screaming )
Roger Ward:
IN "BROTHERS," TERRY HAD NUNS
COMING OUT OF THE BUS
SET ALIGHT.
ONE WAS GRANT PAGE--
UGLIEST NUN I‘VE EVER SEEN.
HE WAS THAT SORT OF GUY
THAT WANTED TO BE THE BEST
AND DIDN‘T QUITE MAKE IT,
UNFORTUNATELY,
BUT HE CERTAINLY TRIED HARD.
IN THAT THRILLER GENRE,
THE FILMS WERE MORE
INTERNATIONAL
AND MADE FOR A MORE
INTERNATIONAL AUDIENCE.
Narrator:
Ladies and gentlemen, may we
introduce you to Patrick?
- Man:
PATRICK WINDS UP IN A COMA. CE
- HE CAN‘T HEAR YOU. HE‘S DEAD.
THE YOUNG NURSE BEGINS TO
SUSPECT THAT HE‘S CONSCIOUS.
YOU CAN FEEL THAT,
CAN‘T YOU?
THAT HE‘S NOT ONLY CONSCIOUS
BUT THROUGH PSYCHOKINESIS
HE‘S ACTUALLY KE IT,
CONTROLLING PEOPLE...
WHY ARE YOU DOING THIS?
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
...AND STARTS TO GET
QUITE NASTY.
Richard Franklin:
A SCRIPT WAS PRESENTED TO ME
IN ITS FINISHED FORM AND
I WAS REALLY KNOCKED OUT BY IT
AND THEN I FIXED IT.
THE FIRST THING I KNEW
ABOUT RICHARD
WAS WHAT
A HITCHCOCK FAN HE WAS.
Rod Mullinar:
HE WOULD STUDY HITCHCOCK‘S
PICTURES
FRAME BY FRAME
BY FRAME.
AND HE VERY MUCH DESIGNED
PATRICK ALONG THOSE SAME LINES.
WE RIPPED OFF "PSYCHO"
AND HAD HIM MURDER HIS MOTHER
AND HER BOYFRIEND.
PATRICK?
( both screaming )
JESUS, PATRICK,
YOUR MOTHER!
I HAD TO ACT
WITH A CHARACTER
WHO DIDN‘T HAVE
ANY REACTION WHATSOEVER
EXCEPT SPIT.
PATRICK DOES LIKE TURN UP
IN "KILL BILL"
WHEN THE BRIDE IS IN A COMA--
AND HER SPIT THING.
I‘LL ALWAYS REMEMBER
THAT ACTOR.
I THOUGHT HE WAS AMAZING
LOOKING IN THE MOVIE
WITH HIS EYES JUST WIDE OPEN
AND EVERYTHING.
IN THE ORIGINAL SCRIPT
I HAD IT WRITTEN LIKE THAT.
AND THEN I SHOWED IT TO UMA,
AND SHE SAID, "I‘M NOT
GOING TO DO THAT."
AND I GO, "WHY?"
AND SHE GOES,
"YOU WOULDN‘T HAVE
YOUR EYES OPENED LIKE THAT
IF YOU WERE IN COMA.
THAT‘S NOT REALISTIC."
I GO, "ACTUALLY,
I NEVER THOUGHT WAS IT
REALISTIC OR NOT.
IT‘S JUST, PATRICK
DID IT, ALL RIGHT?  AND IT
LOOKED REALLY COOL."
I‘M GOING TO TRY
SOME E.C.T. ON PATRICK
TO SEE IF I CAN SHOCK
SOME RESPONSE OUT OF HIM.
Richard Franklin:
WHEN WE SHOT THE
SHOCK-THERAPY SCENE,
THE GUY WHO WAS THERE AS OUR
TECHNICAL EXPERT
SAID, "WELL,
WHY DON‘T WE JUST GIVE HIM
SOME SHOCK TREATMENT?"
AND ROBERT SAID,
"YEAH YEAH, GREAT IDEA."
HE WAS SO KEEN TO GET
TO DO SOMETHING.
I WOULDN‘T LET THEM DO IT,
OF COURSE.
BUT IT MIGHT HAVE
BEEN EFFECTIVE.
Susan Penhaligon:
I THINK THERE WERE
SOME MOMENTS
WHICH PERHAPS WENT
A BIT TOO FAR.
I THINK WHEN ROBERT HELPMANN
ATE THE FROGS,
- WE WERE INTO
ANOTHER GENRE THERE. IM
- HE MADE ME.
EVERY MOVIE, TO BE
A BIG SUCCESS,
NEEDS TO HAVE
AT LEAST ONE MOMENT...
COME ON, LOVELY.
I‘LL TAKE YOU HOME.
...THAT EVERYBODY
TALKS ABOUT.
- AHHH!
PATRICK LEAPING FROM THE BED
WAS CERTAINLY
THE MAJOR REASON
FOR ITS SUCCESS.
Tony Ginnane:
IT WAS SO SUCCESSFUL
THAT A ROGUE ITALIAN PRODUCER
RIPPED US OFF
AND MADE AN UNAUTHORIZED SEQUEL
CALLED "PATRICK VIVE ANCORA."
Quentin Tarantino:
I DIG ON THE FACT THAT AT
ONE MOMENT IN TIME,
AUSTRALIAN FILMS WERE
SO BANG-ON
THAT THE ITALIANS, YOU KNOW,
DID RIP-OFFS OF THEM.
UNAUTHORIZED OR NOT,
"PATRICK VIVE ANCORA"‘S EARNINGS
ARE AN EXAMPLE OF A SEQUEL
SPIRALING OUT OF CONTROL.
AHHH!
Everett De Roche:
IT‘S GOT NOTHING TO DO
WITH "PATRICK"
EXCEPT EVERY NOW
AND THEN THEY SUPERIMPOSE
THE ACTOR‘S HEAD ON THE SCREEN.
I SUPPOSE IT‘D HAVE TO BE
FLATTERING, YES.
BUT I WISH THEY‘D COME UP
WITH A BETTER SEQUEL.
ALMOST EVERYTHING THAT
EVERETT DE ROCHE WROTE IS ONE
OF MY FAVORITE FILMS.
THE FILM THAT HE DID
THAT WOULD BE
IN MY TOP-FIVE FAVORITE
AUSTRALIAN MOVIES IS
"LONG WEEKEND."
THE STORYLINE IS ABOUT
THIS COUPLE THAT FIGHT AND
BITCH ALL THE TIME.
AND THEY‘RE GOING OUT FOR
A WEEKEND IN THE WOODS
TO TRY AND LIKE ALMOST
SAVE THEIR MARRIAGE.
ALL RIGHT, YOU‘RE NOT WILD
ABOUT CAMPING.
WE‘RE NOT EXACTLY
ROUGHING IT EITHER.
$2,000 WORTH OF CAMPING GEAR,
I SHOULD HOPE NOT.
FOR THAT WE COULD HAVE A V.I.P.
SUITE AT THE SOUTHERN CROSS.
YEAH, YOU‘D BE
AN AUTHORITY ON HOTEL ROOMS.
GET FUCKED.
NOT ONLY ARE THEY AT
EACH OTHERS‘ THROATS,
BUT THEY PROCEED TO
TRASH THE ENVIRONMENT.
AND THINGS GO VERY
VERY WRONG.
( woman screaming )
Quentin Tarantino:
THE GENRE IN HORROR FILMS
- THAT IT WOULD SEEM
TO TAKE PLACE IN... I.P.
- PETER!
...IS A MOTHER-NATURE-GOES-
APESHIT KIND OF MOVIE.
Narrator:
Every living creature,
every blade of grass
- will turn against you. -
- ( squawking )
Everett De Roche:
I JUST LIKE THE IDEA OF
NATURE FIGHTING BACK;
THAT IF PEOPLE
BECOME TOO INTRUSIVE,
LIKE A CANCER
ON THE ENVIRONMENT,
NATURE HAS ITS
OWN IMMUNE SYSTEM.
Quentin Tarantino:
YOU START BEING ON
THE ANIMALS‘ SIDE,
BECAUSE THE MOST DESTRUCTIVE
AND SCARY AND DEADLY THING
IN THIS FOREST
ARE THESE TWO.
YOU WANT THIS COUPLE
TO GET KILLED.
BUT THEN AGAIN THERE‘S ANOTHER
WEIRD ASPECT ABOUT THE FILM.
AS YOU WATCH THE MOVIE,
THINGS ARE NOT EXACTLY
WHAT THEY SEEM TO BE.
THEY NEVER EVER MAKE IT CLEAR,
OR SAY OUT LOUD,
IF ANYTHING WAS WRONG
IN THE FOREST.
THAT‘S REALLY TERRIFIC
AND THAT‘S REALLY HARD
TO PULL OFF.
- WHAT‘S THAT?
- WHERE?
- THERE, IN YOUR HAIR.
- ( both scream )
WHEN IT HIT THE SCREENS,
IT JUST DIDN‘T RESONATE
WITH AN AUDIENCE HERE.
MAYBE AUSTRALIANS DIDN‘T
WANT TO SEE THEMSELVES
PORTRAYED LIKE THAT--
AS AN UGLY COUPLE
THAT‘S GREEDY AND DESTRUCTIVE.
LOTS OF ELEMENTS OF NATURE
FIGHTING BACK
SEEMED A LITTLE
BIT PREPOSTEROUS TO
AN AUSTRALIAN AUDIENCE.
THE LANDSCAPE‘S VERY FAMILIAR.
IT DOESN‘T LOOK MENACING.
TO AN OVERSEAS AUDIENCE,
IT WAS REALLY EXOTIC.
♪ IF YOU GO DOWN IN
THE WOODS TODAY YOU MIGHT
GET A BIG SURPRISE. ♪
IT‘S A TRUE LITTLE
UNDISCOVERED GEM
THAT IS JUST BEGGING
TO BE REDISCOVERED
AND ACTUALLY HAVE IT TAKE
ITS PLACE IN ‘70s GENRE CINEMA.
Narrator:
"Long Weekend."
An experience in terror.
YOU KNOW, THE NAME
THAT JUST SHOWS UP MORE
THAN ANYBODY ELSE
IS ANTHONY I. GINNANE.
HE WAS THE PRODUCER OF
ALMOST EVERY SINGLE GENRE FILM
THAT CAME OUT OF AUSTRALIA
AND THAT I SAW.
HE WAS SERIOUSLY
MISJUDGED AT THE TIME.
TONY GINNANE AND HIS WORK
SHOULD BE BURNED TO THE GROUND
AND THE ASHES SEWN
WITH SALT.
I WANTED TO BLOW THINGS UP...
HAVE PEOPLE BEING CHASED
AROUND WITH KNIVES AND GUNS.
I DON‘T KNOW THAT
HE‘S RESPONSIBLE
FOR AN AWFUL LOT OF
REALLY GOOD CINEMA.
Tony Ginnane:
I DIDN‘T WANT TO PUT
AUDIENCES TO SLEEP.
- I WANTED TO WAKE THEM UP.
- ( screaming )
HE WAS ACTUALLY
GENUINELY INTERESTED IN
THE CREATIVE SIDE OF IT,
BUT A LOT OF PEOPLE
JUDGED HIM NOT TO BE.
TONY WAS A BIT OILY,
FULL OF CRAP.
Richard Brennan:
HE WAS ONE OF THOSE PEOPLE
WHO USES EXPRESSIONS LIKE,
"I‘M GETTING REALLY HORNY
WHEN YOU TALK ABOUT LARGE
SUMS OF MONEY."
AUSTRALIA‘S ROGER CORMAN.
PROBABLY AN ACCURATE WAY TO
DESCRIBE ME, TRUTHFULLY.
IF I SEE HIS NAME AS
A PRODUCER
OF A FILM I HAVEN‘T SEEN BEFORE,
I‘LL GIVE IT A SHOT.
Narrator
From the decadent nightlife
and the jetset discos,
Angela is playing a deadly
game of hide and seek.
( screaming )
I THINK EVERETT MUST HAVE BEEN
DRINKING SOME VERY STRANGE WINE
OR TAKING SOME VERY STRANGE
DRUGS WHEN HE WROTE THAT SCRIPT.
CAN YOU THINK OF A MORE ABSURD
PREMISE THAN THE MR. WHIPPY VAN
BEING THE INSTRUMENT OF EVIL?
"SNAPSHOT" IS PRETTY LIGHT
ON SUBTEXT.
Sigrid Thornton:
I THINK PEOPLE FEEL AS THOUGH
BECAUSE I HAD TO TAKE
MY TOP OFF,
THAT IT MUST HAVE
BEEN SOMETHING THAT I MUST
HAVE FELT A BIT NERVOUS ABOUT.
BUT FOR ME IT WAS JUST
A TERRIFIC ADVENTURE.
THE STORY REQUIRED IT BECAUSE
OF THIS MAN‘S OBSESSION.
AND SHE WALKS INTO THIS ROOM
AND SEES THIS CENTERFOLD
PLASTERED ALL OVER THE ROOM.
IT WAS KIND OF CREEPY WALKING IN
AND FINDING THIS IMAGE
OF HERSELF AND THEN THE WHOLE
THING CATCHING ON FIRE.
THE STUNT GUYS WERE
EXPERIMENTING WITH THE WATER GEL
WHICH MEANS YOU COULD
SET FIRE TO YOURSELF AND
JUST RUN AROUND ON FIRE
WITH THE LEADING ACTRESS.
( both screaming )
Simon Wincer:
WHEN IT‘S ACTUALLY HAPPENING,
IT‘S MUCH MORE REAL
THAN YOU THINK.
AND SO HER REACTIONS
ARE VERY REAL.
GO ON!
THEY RETITLED
THE FILM IN AMERICA,
"THE DAY AFTER HALLOWEEN."
AND THAT WAS GINNANE
AND HIS OVERSEAS LOT
TRYING TO CAPITALIZE ON
JOHN CARPENTER‘S FILM.
ANYTHING WITH THE NAME
"HALLOWEEN" IN IT
AND LIKE, COULD BE
A SEQUEL TO "HALLOWEEN,"
YOU WENT AND SAW IT.
LIKE, "WHAT‘S THIS SHIT?"
IT HAD NOTHING TO DO
WITH THAT AT ALL.
HALLOWEEN‘S
NOT EVEN MENTIONED.
Quentin Tarantino:
IT WAS EXPLOITATION
AT ITS BEST,
BECAUSE PART OF THE THING
ABOUT GOING TO SEE EVERY
EXPLOITATION MOVIE
THAT CAME OUT IS YOU HAD TO BE
JUST COMPLETELY RIPPED OFF,
YOU KNOW, AT LEAST FIVE
TIMES DURING THE YEAR.
"DAY AFTER HALLOWEEN" WAS
ONE OF THOSE RIP-OFFS.
TONY STUMBLED ONTO
A FORMULA WHICH WAS OBVIOUSLY
VERY SUCCESSFUL FOR HIM.
THRILLER, HORROR,
WITH A PSYCHOLOGICAL
OR SUPERNATURAL TWIST.
Narrator:
Vampires--
driven by insatiable thirst.
GINNANE‘S FIRST COMMENT WAS,
"I WANT YOU TO KNOW
RIGHT UP FRONT, THIS IS BEING
MADE FOR THE DRIVE-IN SET."
SO WE TRIED TO FIND
A SEQUENCE THAT WOULD REALLY
KEEP THE AUDIENCE ON EDGE.
THE THIRST IS IN ALL OF US.
NOT IN ME!
Tony Ginnane:
IN "THIRST," WE BROUGHT
IN DAVID HEMMINGS;
WE BROUGHT
IN HENRY SILVER,
WHO COULD
NOT READ HIS LINES
WITHOUT WEARING GLASSES,
WHICH MADE HIM THE ONLY
GLASSES-WEARING VAMPIRE
IN THE HISTORY OF CINEMA.
THERE IS A SHOT IN "THIRST"
WHERE DAVID HEMMINGS
IS IN A HELICOPTER AND
HENRY SILVER GOES UP AND
LETS GO OF THE SKIDS.
AND HE DIDN‘T WANT TO GO
NEAR A HELICOPTER--
"I‘M NOT GOING
NEAR THAT DAMN THING."
SO WHAT WE DID WAS WE GOT
THE SKIDS OF A HELICOPTER
AND BOLTED THEM TO
A CHERRY PICKER,
AND SAID, "LOOK, HENRY,
WE‘RE JUST GOING TO LIFT YOU
A FEW FEET OFF THE GROUND."
IT DID GO A LITTLE HIGHER
THAN HE EXPECTED.
Vincent Monton: FT YOU
WE TOOK HIM UP 70‘,
AND HE WAS SCREAMING
AND YELLING AND CARRYING ON.
I‘M SURE HIS PANTS WERE WET
AT ABOUT 50‘.
AHHHH!
TONY MADE FILMS
WITH A VERY CLEAR EFFORT
THAT HE WANTED THOSE FILMS
TO BE SOLD OVERSEAS.
THAT DIDN‘T WIN ME
A WHOLE LOT OF FRIENDS
EXCEPT THE PEOPLE
WHO BANKED MY CHECKS.
MOST OF THESE FILMS
WERE RUBBISH.
I OPPOSED THEM
VERY STRENUOUSLY.
Narrator:
Is he the new messiah
or a demon from
another world?
"HARLEQUIN" HAD ITS
SMATTERING OF SEX
AND IT HAD BRODERICK CRAWFORD
AND DAVID HEMMINGS AND
ROBERT POWELL.
IT IS A SORT OF MODERN
POLITICAL STORY, I SUPPOSE,
BASED ON THE UPDATING
OF THE RASPUTIN THEME.
AND THAT IS REALLY ALL.
IT EXCITED ME
ENOUGH TO SAY YES...
AND COME 12,000 MILES
TO SHOOT IT.
FLIMFLAM...
AND HOCUS-POCUS.
( all screaming )
WE WERE TRYING
TO PRESENT THE FILM
AS NOT BEING SET
IN AUSTRALIA.
IT WAS SET
IN NOWHERE LAND.
I THINK ATTEMPTS TO CURRY
TO THE AMERICAN MARKET
WERE OFTEN SILLY.
( American accent )
HELL, I DON‘T KNOW.
THEY JUST SAID PROCESS HIM
AND STICK HIM IN THE SLAMMER.
SO WHAT AM I SUPPOSED TO DO?
- DAMN FEDS.
- WE DIDN‘T SEE IT THAT WAY
AND IT CERTAINLY
WASN‘T SEEN THAT WAY BY
INTERNATIONAL AUDIENCES.
THOSE FILMS, IF YOU
ADDED THEM ALL UP,
PROBABLY MADE QUITE A BIT OF
MONEY FOR TONY GINNANE.
THEY DIDN‘T
FOR THE REST OF US.
TONY DID DELIVER.
HE DID RAISE FUNDS
FOR PICTURES
AND HE ENABLED A LOT OF
PEOPLE TO MAKE PICTURES.
Narrator:
James Herbert‘s
frightening novel
of supernatural power
is now a movie.
"THE SURVIVOR" WAS
THE FIRST MOVIE IN AUSTRALIA
THAT WENT OVER
A $1 MILLION BUDGET.
THE FILM OPENS
WITH A PLANE CRASH.
IT WAS THE LARGEST AMOUNT
OF GASOLINE
AND OTHER FLAMMABLE SUBSTANCES
THAT HAD EVER BEEN USED
IN AN AUSTRALIAN MOVIE.
IT WAS PRETTY AMBITIOUS
TO BUILD AND BLOW UP A 747,
AND THEN TO GO INTO THIS LONG,
DEEP THING
ABOUT THE PILOT
BEING RESURRECTED.
Narrator:
300 murdered souls
combine their psychic energy
to hunt down their killer.
ONE OF THE MISTAKES
I THINK I MADE
WAS TO THROTTLE BACK ON
THE GORE COMPONENT;
MOOD, MYSTERY, AMBIGUITY
RATHER THAN SLASH
AND CUT AND KILL.
Narrator:
Brace yourselves
for a journey
to the outer limits
of nightmare.
TONY HAD THIS THEORY
THAT YOU NEEDED TO SELL
INTO THE AMERICAN
AND EUROPEAN MARKETS BY
EMPLOYING AMERICAN ACTORS.
ACTORS THAT WOULD OTHERWISE
BE SITTING AROUND IN
THE OLD ACTORS‘ HOME.
"HAVE I GOT
A FILM STAR FOR YOU!
REMEMBER HIM?
HE WAS SO GOOD IN THAT
MICKEY ROONEY FILM OF 1935.
YOU REMEMBER HIM?
HERE HE IS. HERE HE IS. IA
HE‘S GOING CHEAP."
IT WAS NOT A CASE OF BRINGING
IN SOME, YOU KNOW, DESPERADO.
BRODERICK CRAWFORD--
ACADEMY-AWARD WINNER...
HE LOOKS AT ME
VERY BLEARY-EYED AND SAYS,
"WHY DON‘T YOU GET FUCKED?"
...JOSEPH COTTON--
ACADEMY-AWARD WINNER.
AN EXTREMELY
ADEQUATE ACTOR IN 1940.
A LOT OF THOSE ACTORS
ACTUALLY I LIKED QUITE A BIT.
IT WAS GOOD TO SEE THEM
GETTING THE OPPORTUNITIES THEY
WOULDN‘T GET IN AMERICA.
THAT WAS VERY VERY
UNPOPULAR WITH ACTORS‘ EQUITY.
THEY MADE NO SENSE CULTURALLY
OR PHILOSOPHICALLY,
AND FRANKLY DID NOT MAKE
SENSE ECONOMICALLY TO US.
FAIRLY OBVIOUSLY EQUITY
BASED THEIR DECISIONS ON
FANTAIL WRAPPERS.
Narrator:
The hitchhiker plays games...
AREN‘T YOU KIND OF YOUNG
TO BE HITCHHIKING OUT HERE
ALL BY YOURSELF?
AREN‘T YOU KIND OF OLD
TO BE PICKING ME UP?
...the truck driver
plays games...
ONE TORSO IS PRETTY MUCH
LIKE ANOTHER.
OH, FOUL.
YOU LOSE A TURN.
...and a killer is playing
the deadliest game of all.
EVERETT WENT AWAY WITH
THE SCRIPT OF "REAR WINDOW"
AND CAME BACK WITH
"REAR WINDOW" SET IN A TRUCK.
I‘D ALWAYS BEEN INTRIGUED
BY THE IDEA
THAT WHEN YOU GO ON
A LONG ROAD TRIP,
YOU‘LL PASS SOMEBODY AND THEN
LATER ON THEY‘LL PASS YOU.
AND IT‘S LIKE THIS
TRAVELING COMMUNITY.
THEY MAKE STUPID JOKES...
NOW THERE‘S A MAN
WITH BALLS.
...AND PLAY STUPID GAMES.
AND TO HAVE THIS
LIGHT-HEARTED FEEL
AGAINST A BACKDROP
OF EXTREME VIOLENCE.
SO WHAT IF HE IS A
MURDERER AND HE‘S GOING AROUND
SYSTEMATICALLY BUTCHERING
EVERY FEMALE IN SIGHT,
- MAKING THEM INTO TACOS? EY
- ( gasps )
I GOT THIS CALL THAT THEY
WERE GOING TO MAKE THIS FILM
IN AUSTRALIA
WITH A DIRECTOR WHO WAS
THE ALFRED HITCHCOCK
OF AUSTRALIA.
JAMIE LEE AT THE TIME WAS
THE GODDESS OF THAT GENRE--
THE QUEEN OF SCREAM.
SOMEBODY ASKED HER
THE QUESTION,
"WHAT IS IT LIKE PUTTING
AUSTRALIANS OUT OF WORK?"
I FELT THEN AS NOW
THAT AMERICANS ARE SCUM
AND SHOULD NOT BE LET
ANYWHERE NEAR OUR MONEY.
IT‘S A VERY SCARY
THING TO DO,
TO BE THE SORT OF TOKEN
AMERICAN ON SOMETHING
THAT THERE IS
SOME HOSTILITY ABOUT.
I KNEW THERE WAS HOSTILITY
ABOUT BEING A TOKEN AMERICAN,
LET ALONE THAT I HAD
TAKEN ANOTHER PERSON‘S JOB.
THE CONCEPT OF TWO AMERICANS
MEETING IN THE MIDDLE OF
THE AUSTRALIAN DESERT
IS A BIT OF A COINCIDENCE--
THERE‘S NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
BUT IT WORKED.  I THINK THAT‘S
WHERE THE ATTRACTION COMES.
THAT KIND OF SYNCHRONICITY
AND SERENDIPITY HAPPENS OUT
IN THE MIDDLE OF NOWHERE.
Narrator:
Across 1,600 miles
of desert highway,
they‘re playing games of
violence and sudden death.
WE STARTED SHOOTING THE FILM
IN MELBOURNE
AND SHOT ALL
THE WAY TO PERTH.
Jamie Lee Curtis:
THE ENTIRE MOVIE MOVED
THROUGH THE NULLARBOR PLAIN.
IT WAS LIKE A JOHN FORD MOVIE,
YOU KNOW?
BECAUSE WE WERE
THIS GUERRILLA DESERT CREW.
AFTER FIVE DAYS FILMING,
THEY WERE FOUR DAYS BEHIND.
Richard Franklin:
SUDDENLY THEY WERE
GOING THROUGH THE STORYBOARD
SAYING, "WE WON‘T SHOOT THIS
AND WE‘LL GIVE YOU FOUR TAKES
OF THIS AND NO MORE."
GIVEN THE BUDGET
AND THE CONSTRAINTS
THAT HE WAS UNDER,
I THOUGHT IT
TURNED OUT VERY WELL.
Quentin Tarantino:
THE FIRST MURDER IS ABSOLUTELY
FANTASTIC WITH THE GUITAR WIRE.
THE WAY THAT WHOLE PIECE
WORKS IS JUST MASTERFUL.
IN FACT THAT‘S THE SCENE
THAT WHEN YOU‘RE WATCHING
THE MOVIE YOU GO,
"OH, WOW, THIS ISN‘T JUST
GOING TO BE A SLASHER MOVIE
OF THE WEEK.
THIS IS REALLY GOOD."
- ( screeching )
- ( honking )
THE BOAT STUNT IS PROBABLY
ONE OF THE MOST EXTRAORDINARY
IN THE FILM.
I LOOKED AT THE CHARIOT RACE
IN "BEN HUR"
AND I GOT THE WHEELS OF
THE TRUCK RUBBING ON THE BOAT
AND VARIOUS OTHER THINGS.
Stacey Keach:
AND WHEN YOU‘RE GOING
TO DESTROY A BOAT,
YOU ONLY HAVE ONE CHANCE.
AND IT WENT OFF, THANK GOODNESS,
WITHOUT A HITCH...
COCK.
THERE ARE ELEMENTS OF THAT
THAT I‘M SURE WOUND THEMSELVES
INTO "WOLF CREEK"--
THAT NOTION OF THE ADVENTURE
ON THE HIGHWAY AND THE MEETING
OF THIS EVIL CHARACTER.
I MEAN, IT‘S STILL THERE IN
THE FINALE OF "WOLF CREEK,"
THAT INFLUENCE OF "ROAD GAMES."
YOU COULD REMAKE "ROAD GAMES"
TOMORROW AND NOT CHANGE
A DAMN WORD OF IT
AND IT WOULD SCARE
THE HELL OUT OF EVERYBODY.
IT‘S AN AMAZING MOVIE.
IT‘S REALLY TERRIFIC.
Narrator:
"Road Games"--
if someone doesn‘t stop soon,
they‘re won‘t be anyone left
alive to play.
AT THE TIME, THERE WAS
A HUGE SENSITIVITY ABOUT
CULTURAL IDENTITY.
ONE OF THE PROBLEMS
WITH THE FUNDING BODIES
WAS THAT THEY HAD THIS BRIEF
THAT THE FILM
MUST SING AN AUSTRALIAN SONG.
IT MUST SMELL EUCALYPTIC.
THEY‘RE TALKING ABOUT EMUS
AND CLOSEUPS OF GUM TREES
AND A COUPLE OF PRETTY SUNSETS
IN THE OUTBACK AND THERE YOU GO.
THAT‘S AUSTRALIAN CULTURE.
YOU CAN MAKE ANY FILM
YOU LIKE.
IT DOESN‘T HAVE TO BE RELEGATED
TO WHAT HAPPENS IN THE OUTBACK
TO BE AUSTRALIAN.
CRITICS COULDN‘T GET USED
TO THE FACT
THAT SOME FILMMAKERS
WERE MAKING FILMS
THAT THEY SAW AS
EXCLUSIVELY AMERICAN GENRE.
Narrator:
Watch closely now,
but don‘t dare look behind you.
Just feel the skin crawl
on the back of your neck.
John Lamond:
I THOUGHT IF I‘M GOING TO
MAKE A GUTSY HORROR FILM,
THERE‘S NO POINT IN
BEING SUBTLE.
AND I THOUGHT I‘D LIKE TO SLASH
THE BARE BEHIND OF SOME BIRD
WHO‘S BEEN SCREWED
IN THE MAKEUP ROOM.
WHEN JOHN‘S ON THEME,
HE LIKES TO KEEP IT GOING.
THEY SAID, "WHICH PART
WOULD YOU LIKE TO PLAY?"
( screaming )
AND I SAID, "JUDY, PERHAPS.
SHE‘S THE ONLY ONE
WHO DOESN‘T GET KILLED
WHILE SHE‘S SCREWING."
IT‘S NOT SOME OF MY FINEST
MOMENTS ON SCREEN
AND IT‘S A FAR CRY
FROM CONTENT
WHICH PHILOSOPHICALLY ADDRESSES
THE HUMAN CONDITION
AND CONTRIBUTES IN THAT WAY.
Narrator:
Many motion pictures
promise you terror,
but "Nightmares"
is truly frightening.
THE BIG DANGER OF BEING
AN AUSTRALIAN GENRE FILMMAKER,
I THINK, IS THAT YOU CAN
EASILY FALL INTO
AN AMERICAN
DERIVATIVE PATTERN.
Philippe Mora:
I FELT "THE MARSUPIALS"
WAS USING A HOLLYWOOD GENRE,
AN ESTABLISHED ONE, AND TURNING
IT INTO AN AUSTRALIAN COMEDY.
ARRGH!
G‘DAY.  WANT TO PUT A SHRIMP
ON THE BARBIE?
Narrator:
The howling terror continues
with a whole new breed of
werewolves in "Howling III."
Philippe Mora:
IMOGEN AINSLEY PLAYED
THE WEREWOLF GIRL.
THE RUNNER-UP FOR THE ROLE
WAS NICOLE KIDMAN,
BUT SHE JUST WASN‘T
WEREWOLF ENOUGH FOR ME.
THERE WASN‘T THAT WEREWOLF
TANG WE NEEDED.
THERE‘S A LOT OF RIDICULOUS
THINGS IN THAT MOVIE.
MY FAVORITE IS THE BALLERINA
TURNING INTO A WEREWOLF.
( all screaming )
THERE WAS A SCENE
WHERE SHE‘S LYING IN BED
HAVING THIS DREAM AND SOMETHING
COMES THROUGH HER POUCH.
THE WEREWOLF HEAD BURSTING OUT
WAS A REFERENCE TO "ALIEN."
MORE AMUSING TO ME
IS THE MARSUPIAL BIRTH.
I STUDIED SOME REALLY BORING
FILM AUSTRALIA DOCUMENTARIES
ON KANGAROOS BEING BORN.
AND I WAS TRYING TO FIGURE
OUT HOW TO DO THAT WITH
BOB McCARRON,
AND BOB McCARRON SAID,
"WHY DON‘T WE PUT A MOUSE
IN A WEREWOLF FETUS SUIT?"
I SAID, "GOOD IDEA."
SO WE GOT THIS MOUSE AND WE PUT
A WEREWOLF FETUS SUIT ON IT.
IMOGEN STARTED SCREAMING AND
IT WAS RUNNING ALL AROUND
AND BOB SAID, "WE‘LL HAVE
TO SEDATE THE MOUSE."
SO WE GOT THE NURSE.
SHE INJECTED THE POOR MOUSE
AND IT DROPPED DEAD.
SO WE SAID LOOK,
"USE LESS SEDATIVES."
SHE SAID, "I‘M REALLY SORRY."
SO WE HAD TO GET ANOTHER MOUSE,
USED A LITTLE BIT OF
THE SEDATIVE.
IT WAS IMPOSSIBLE GETTING
THE MOUSE INTO THE POUCH.
SO I PUT THE MOUSE IN THE POUCH,
FILMED IT IN REVERSE,
AND OF COURSE IT CAME OUT.
SO ALL WAS WELL.
WE ALL KNEW IT WAS RUBBISH.
WE KNEW EVERYTHING
WAS A JOKE.
( screaming )
Philippe Mora:
IT GOT A THEATRICAL RELEASE,
TO THE PUZZLEMENT OF MANY.
THAT‘S THE UNDERSTATEMENT
OF THE NIGHT.
"THE NEW YORK TIMES" SAID,
"IF YOU SEE ONE WEREWOLF MOVIE,
SEE THIS ONE."
I USED TO GET REALLY SICK
AND TIRED OF GETTING THIS
SORT OF BACKLASH ABOUT,
YOU KNOW, "WHY ARE WE MAKING
THIS SORT OF FILM IN AUSTRALIA?
WE HAVEN‘T GOT ENOUGH MONEY
ANYWAY AND WE‘RE ONLY DOING
LITTLE "b" B-GRADE FILMS.
LEAVE ‘EM TO THE AMERICANS,
THEY MAKE THEM BETTER THAN US."
YOU KNOW,
AND I THINK THAT‘S CRAP.
I DON‘T REMEMBER TRYING TO
COMPETE WITH THE AMERICANS.
IT WAS JUST REALLY JUST
TO FILM WHAT WAS TRUE.
I WAS REALLY ACTUALLY INTO
RUSSELL MULCAHY ALL RIGHT.
I THOUGHT HE WAS
THE POOR MAN‘S RIDLEY SCOTT.
Narrator:
From Australia‘s hottest
new director Russell Mulcahy,
"Razorback."
ONLY GOT TWO STATES OF BEING:
DANGEROUS OR DEAD.
Man:
BOB McCARRON HAD A VERY
LARGE RAZORBACK.
AND RUSSELL SAID, "SHOULDN‘T IT
BE MUCH BIGGER THAN THIS?"
LIKE, AT LEAST
2‘ or 3‘ BIGGER?"
WE WENT,
"YEAH, THAT‘D BE SO COOL."
SO WE DID IT.
AND THINKING ABOUT IT,
WE PROBABLY SHOULDN‘T HAVE.
A $100 MILLION FILM
WITH A $10 PIG.
( man screaming )
IT LITERALLY ROLLED IN
LIKE A WHEELBARROW.
GREGORY HAD THE TEETH
GNASHING AWAY AT HIS FACE
TRYING TO ACTUALLY BITE
HIS FACE OFF.
Gregory Harrison:
AND THAT SALIVA WAS SOME
GROTESQUE COMBINATION
OF-- WELL, WE USED TO
MAKE SPERM JOKES ABOUT IT.
IT WAS JUST REALLY GROSS.
THERE WERE MANY POINTS
WHERE I HAD SECOND THOUGHTS
ABOUT, "WHAT HAVE I DONE?"
I HAD A HUGE SCENE WITH
A MECHANICAL PIG
WHERE IT JUST TOOK ME APART.
( screaming )
AFTERWARDS YOU THINK,
"OH, THAT WAS REALLY STUPID.
I COULD HAVE REALLY
HURT MYSELF IN THAT CAR."
YOU JUST DON‘T THINK
THAT A MOVIE ABOUT
A GIANT MONSTER PIG
WOULD HAVE SUCH A GREAT
AESTHETIC VISUAL TO IT,
BUT RUSSELL REALLY
WENT ALL OUT.
I WAS LEAPING OVER CHASMS
OF MISSING DIALOGUE
OR MISSING SUBTEXT
AND HE WOULD BE SAYING,
"YEAH, BUT THERE‘S SMOKE
COMING FROM THE FAN.
AND I NEED YOU
TO ZIP THROUGH THAT
BECAUSE THAT SMOKE STARTS TO
WAFT AWAY IF WE DON‘T HURRY."
HOW DO YOU ACT WITH THAT?
YOU CAN‘T ACT
WITH THE SMOKE.
RUSSELL ENCOURAGED ME
TO BELIEVE
THAT THEY‘RE NOT GOING TO BE
LISTENING TO THE DIALOGUE
AS MUCH AS YOU THINK
BECAUSE THE VISUALS ARE
GOING TO BE SO SPECTACULAR.
THAT‘S A HORRIBLE THING
TO SAY--
"DON‘T HIT THE DIALOGUE.
THE VISUALS WILL BLOW AWAY YOU.
NOBODY WILL BE
LOOKING AT YOU."
IT WAS CLEARLY
CAPITAL-C COMMERCIAL
AND MANY WOULD ARGUE
HAD LITTLE IF NO ARTISTIC
OR INTELLECTUAL MERIT.
I THINK WHEN THE DOG
GOT RUN OVER...
♪ EASE ON DOWN,
EASE ON DOWN THE ROAD. ♪
...I NOTICED A NUMBER OF
EXECUTIVES WHO LEFT THE CINEMA.
- WHAT DID YOU DO THAT FOR?
- I DON‘T KNOW.
SO KILLING DOGS
IS NOT A GOOD THING
TO DO IN MOVIES,
I LEARNED.
Hal McElroy:
WE HAD TO WORK ON A CAPITAL-C
COMMERCIAL CRITERIA,
AND IN THAT REGARD, THERE WERE
BIGGER AND BETTER AMERICAN
FILMS THAN THIS ONE.
Gregory Harrison:
I THINK "RAZORBACK"‘S PROBLEM
WAS STYLE OVER SUBSTANCE.
- BUT THERE IS
A LOT OF STYLE.
- ( cawing )
IT‘S NOT THAT I TRIED TO MAKE IT
LOOK LIKE A LONG VIDEO,
IT‘S JUST THAT WAS MY STYLE.
AND THAT WAS SEEN
AS A MINUS AT THAT POINT,
WHEREAS NOW IT‘S SEEN
AS AN ABSOLUTE PLUS.
( screaming )
MAYBE THAT‘S WHY IT HAS STOOD
THE TEST OF TIME
BECAUSE IT‘S GRADUALLY GROWN
IN TO THE STYLE OF FILMMAKING
THAT IS MUCH MORE MODERN NOW.
THERE‘S AN ANIMAL OUT THERE
AND IT‘S HUNTING US.
Man:
HALFWAY THROUGH WRITING
THE SCRIPT FOR "ROGUE,"
I FOUND OUT THERE WAS ALREADY
AN AUSTRALIAN CROC MOVIE
CALLED "DARK AGE."
( screaming )
Quentin Tarantino:
I ACTUALLY THINK YOU COULD
RELEASE "DARK AGE"
IN THE THEATER TOMORROW
IN 2,000 SCREENS
AND PEOPLE WOULD GO
SEE IT.
THE ONLY NEGATIVE IN IT IS THAT
THE CROC ISN‘T THAT GOOD.
I HAD TO ROPE THE HEAD AND
IT CAME UP AND WENT...
"BRRRR... ARRR."
SO I‘M TRYING TO MAKE IT LOOK
FRANTIC, YOU KNOW?
Tony Ginnane:
THE CROCODILE WAS SUPPOSED TO
MOVE AT A REASONABLE CLIP.
WELL, I SUPPOSE THAT MIGHT
HAVE DEPENDED A LITTLE BIT
UPON WHAT YOUR DEFINITION
OF WHAT A REASONABLE CLIP WAS.
John Jarratt:
I MANAGED TO GET
THE LEGS TO WORK,
AND WE WERE RUNNING ALONG
LIKE IT WAS A LABRADOR
DOG BESIDE IT.
AND HIS LITTLE OLD LEGS
WERE DOING THIS.
AND WE WERE GOING,
"COME ON, NUMMINWARRY."
COME ON.
"HERE, BOY,
INTO THE BILLABONG."
I PUT IT IN THE WATER
AND IT FUSED.
( electricity buzzes )
THERE WAS A SPATE OF
CROCODILES EATING PEOPLE
AND I THOUGHT THAT IT WOULD BE
A WONDERFUL OPPORTUNITY
TO SEE IF I COULD BUY
"DARK AGE" BACK...
( crying )
...BUT I COULDN‘T CONVINCE
HOYTS OR VILLAGE.
AND SO IT‘S ONE OF THOSE
FORGOTTEN MASTERPIECES.
THESE FILMS ARE NOW
SORT OF RELEGATED
TO THE DUSTY BACK SHELVES
OF VIDEO STORES, IF THAT.
Tarantino:
THERE‘S A WONDERFUL
AUSTRALIAN HORROR FILM
- CALLED "NEXT OF KIN."
- I WAS INTERESTED IN
LESS OF THE GORE,
BLOOD AND ALL OF WHAT
YOU DIDN‘T KNOW WAS GOING ON
AND MORE INTO FEAR,
I GUESS.
( screaming )
THE FILM THAT IT REMINDS YOU
OF THE MOST IS "THE SHINING."
"NEXT OF KIN" HAS
A SIMILAR TONE AND FEEL,
WHICH IS ONE HELL OF A FUCKING
COMPLIMENT TO GIVE TO A MOVIE.
AND I‘M NOT
OVER-PRAISING IT.
THE THING I REMEMBER
ABOUT "NEXT OF KIN"
MORE THAN ANYTHING IS
THE FINAL SHOT.
THE IDEA WAS THE CAMERA WOULD
CRANE FROM A HIGH ANGLE
AS THE GIRL CAME OUT
OF THE DINER.
THE CAMERA TRACKS INTO
THE BACK OF THE TRUCK
UNTIL WE‘RE LOOKING AT HER
THROUGH THE BACK WINDOW.
AND AS WE PAN BACK TO
SEE WHERE WE‘VE JUST BEEN,
THE WHOLE BUILDING BLOWS UP.
THE SPECIAL EFFECTS GUY
PUSHED THE BUTTON,
AND WE HADN‘T PANNED AROUND.
AND SO THE INITIAL EXPLOSION
IS SEEN AS A REFLECTION
ON THE SIGN AND BY THE
TIME WE‘D PANNED AROUND,
MOST OF IT WAS OVER.
BUT THEN THE PUBLIC SAW IT AND
SAID, "WE LOVED THAT END SHOT.
NOT SEEING THE EXPLOSION TILL
THE END WAS JUST SUCH RESTRAINT.
IT WAS BRILLIANT."
MANY OF US WERE VERY SNOBBY
ABOUT GENRE FILMS--
THERE‘S NO QUESTION ABOUT IT.
WE DIDN‘T APPROVE OF THEM.
"COMMERCIAL" HAS ALWAYS BEEN
A DIRTY WORD FOR SOME REASON
IN THIS COUNTRY.
YOU GO TO PLACES LIKE
THE CANNES FESTIVAL...
90% OF THE PICTURES ARE
JUST EXPLOITATION PICTURES.
YOU HAVE ARTY PICTURES AND SEX
PICTURES AND MONSTER PICTURES
AND ALL THAT SORT OF STUFF.
THEY CAN‘T GET A RELEASE.
OVERLY COMMERCIAL
AIN‘T THAT EASY.
( fanfare )
IF YOU GREW UP WATCHING
AUSTRALIAN GENRE FILMS,
YOU ARE GOING TO BE
OF THE MIND
THAT, ONE: THERE‘S
A DESERT EVERYWHERE...
AND TWO: MARAUDING PACKS
OF BULLIES IN CARS
THAT THEY COULD
NEVER AFFORD--
SHEENING MECHANICAL MONSTERS
JUST ROAM THE HIGHWAY
LOOKING FOR PEOPLE
TO PICK ON, ALL RIGHT?
WOMEN TO RAPE
AND GUYS TO BEAT UP.
IN LOVE STORIES,
THOSE GUYS SHOW UP.
YOU HURT MY CAR.
Quentin Tarantino:
IN A MOVIE ABOUT A GIANT PIG,
THOSE GUYS SHOW UP.
THEY JUST ROAM THE COUNTRYSIDE
LOOKING FOR PEOPLE TO FUCK WITH.
Narrator:
The Gravediggers are
on the move--
a new breed of
motorbike gang.
Somebody wants them dead.
So the cops sent Stone.
I‘VE SEEN THIS BLOKE.
HE‘S A PIG.
CERTAINLY "STONE" WAS NOTHING
LIKE ANYTHING THAT HAD COME
OUT OF AUSTRALIAN CINEMA.
IT‘S A TRIP INTO
ALTERNATIVE CULTURE,
ROCK ‘N‘ ROLL CULTURE.
AND THAT WAS THE SORT
OF ATTITUDE...
ONE OF MY FAVORITE SHOTS
IN THE HISTORY OF BIKER FILMS
IS THAT FUNERAL PROCESSION.
YOU JUST SEE THAT SHOT,
YOU GO, "OH MY GOD.
WHAT A MOVIE."
Narrator:
The copper and the bike gang.
- Two lifestyles clash... G,
- SLUT!
...in a suspense thriller
you cannot predict.
Sandy Harbutt:
PETER ARMSTRONG‘S STUNT
IS THE MOST AMAZING THING
I‘VE EVER SEEN ANY HUMAN
BEING EVER DO.
AHHH!
IT KNOCKED HIM OUT.
IT WAS THE HARDEST IMPACT
I HAVE EVER HAD IN MY LIFE.
AND I WAS BLACK AND BLUE,
FULL OF BRUISES FOR
TWO WEEKS.
AND VERY STIFF.
BUT THE SHOT WAS WORTH IT.
WHILE WE WERE MAKING
THE PICTURE I THOUGHT,
"WE‘RE GOING TO FUCK UP."
IT WAS A ROLLER-COASTER RIDE.
WHAT I DECIDED TO DO WAS
ACTUALLY FORM A MOTORCYCLE CLUB
AND SHOOT THE PICTURE
AS A CLUB.
IT WAS AS SEXIST IN
PRODUCTION AS THE WORLD
THAT IT WAS PORTRAYING.
SHUT YOUR FACE, TART.
THE ACTORS VERY MUCH
EMBRACED THE REALITY OF
BECOMING A BIKIE GANG.
Rebecca Gilling:
THE WOMEN DID AS THEY WERE TOLD
AND THE BLOKES SEEMED TO
HAVE ALL THE FUN.
I CAN‘T SAY I ENJOYED
WORKING ON IT ALL.
WE HAD ONE EXTRAORDINARY
SCENE IN THAT
WHICH TOOK 25 HOURS TO FILM,
SMOKING REAL DOPE.
BUT IT WAS
A RADICAL PICTURE!
Ian Barry:
SEVERAL OF THE SEQUENCES
INVOLVED THE HELLS ANGELS.
I GOT ON THE BALCONY OF
THE HOTEL AND TOP OF
MY VOICE YELLED OUT,
"ALL THE HELLS ANGELS
ARE POOFTERS."
THAT WAS THE MOMENT
THAT I THOUGHT WE WERE
GOING TO BE DEAD.
OH, YOU‘VE GOT TO BE DUMB
NOT TO BE SCARED BY...
A GROUP OF TOUGH BIKERS...
BECAUSE NOTHING
WILL STOP THEM.
THERE WAS A FIGHT SCENE
OUTSIDE THE PUB.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE A BRAWL
THAT ENDED UP BEING A BRAWL.
Ian Barry:
THE REMUNERATION FOR
THE HELLS ANGELS
UNFORTUNATELY WAS IN BEER.
THEY WENT BERSERK
THAT NIGHT AND JUST BASHED UP
EVERYBODY IN SIGHT.
THERE WAS A GUY THERE
WITH TWO GIRLS AND HE GOT INTO
A DISCUSSION
- WITH ONE OF THE CLUB MEMBERS.
- WHAT‘S YOUR PROBLEM?
AND HE SAID STUPID THINGS
LIKE, "FUCK OFF!"
David Hannay:
SO THEY TOOK HIS SCALP OFF.
NEVER SEEN SO
MUCH BLOOD IN MY LIFE.
IT WAS ALL OVER THE CEILING
AND ALL OVER THE WALLS.
YOUSE BLOKES--
YOUSE ARE NOT REAL GOOD AT
PUBLIC RELATIONS, ARE YOU?
SANDY WAS HOPING IN A WAY
THAT SOMETHING DANGEROUS
WOULD HAPPEN BECAUSE THEN
HE COULD GET IT ON FILM.
HE‘D MADE A TOTAL COMMITMENT
TO EMBRACE THE REBELLIOUS.
CUT IT.
Narrator:
The director of "Stone"
is Sandy Harbutt.
He plays a leading
role in the film.
He co-authored
the screenplay,
and consequently "Stone"
is very much an auteur picture.
HE‘S LIKE A TRUE,
REAL VISIONARY, ALL RIGHT,
WHO ACTUALLY HAS THE GOODS
AND ACTUALLY DELIVERS
A TREMENDOUS AMOUNT OF IMPACT.
AFTER ALL THE COOL STUFF
THAT HAPPENS IN "STONE,"
THEN IT JUST HAS MAYBE
THE MOST AUTHENTIC,
REALISTIC ENDING OF A BIKER
MOVIE IN THE HISTORY OF FILM.
THEY JUST SHORT OF
STOMP HIM TO DEATH.
BUT HE UNDERSTANDS
THE BIKE CODE.
NO COPS.
AFTER HE GETS HIS KICKING,
HE WORKS IT OUT.
Tarantino:
HE KNOWS HE HAD IT COMING.
I THINK HE WANTED THEIR RESPECT.
HOPEFULLY HE GOT IT.
I SUPPOSE HE BECOMES ONE OF THEM
BY TAKING THE PUNISHMENT.
Narrator:
Critics and bikies alike
have acclaimed it
as the first honest appraisal
of their lifestyle.
Take the trip.
ROLLING, SPEED, BUZZER,
CLAPBOARD, TAKE SIX,
BANG CLANK, POWDERPUFF,
ACTION.
Narrator:
They called him Mad Dog Morgan.
- He was the outlaw‘s outlaw.
- YOU.
WE WANTED TO FIND A PERSONALITY
WHO WOULD HAVE SOME SORT OF ECHO
OF AMERICAN CINEMA,
OF WESTERN CINEMA.
Narrator:
Dennis Hopper
is Mad Dog Morgan.
WE WERE JUST THRILLED TO HAVE
"EASY RIDER" AS MAD DOG.
- HOWDY.
- Jeremy Thomas:
WE‘VE GOT A GENUINE OUTLAW.
LITTLE DID WE KNOW THAT
HAVING THE REAL THING
WAS GOING TO MAKE THE FILM
SOMEWHAT DIFFICULT TO MAKE.
HEY.
COME BACK HERE, HORSE.
I SAID COME BACK HERE OR I‘LL
BASH YOU ON THE HEAD WITH THIS.
MAD DOG MORGAN WAS
A PSYCHOPATH.
AND DENNIS BROUGHT
THAT INTENSITY TO IT.
IT WAS EASY.
EASY, I DON‘T KNOW,
BUT IT WAS OBVIOUS.
ARROGANT SON OF A BITCH,
SPEAKING IN AN IRISH ACCENT
ALL OF THE TIME.
EASY RIDER HERE.
Philippe Mora:
DENNIS WAS A FULL-ON
METHOD ACTOR.
I‘VE COME FOR OPIUM.
THAT WAS CONVENIENT FOR HIM
BECAUSE MAD DOG DRANK
A LOT OF RUM,
WHICH DENNIS HAD RESEARCHED
BEFORE HE ARRIVED.
I GOT THAT PART OF IT RIGHT,
FOR SURE.
Jeremy Thomas:
HE WAS ARRESTED AND PUT IN
JAIL WITHIN A NIGHT
OF HIM ARRIVING IN SYDNEY.
HE WAS ALREADY IN FIGHTING
DOWN AT THE PUBS.
HE SNORTED A LOT OF COCAINE.
HE STARTED DRINKING WHEN
HE WOKE UP IN THE MORNING,
WHICH IS VERY EARLY.
DENNIS COLLAPSED IN
THE MIDDLE OF SCENES.
HE WAS 39 WHEN
WE WERE MAKING THE FILM.
I REALLY BELIEVED HE WOULD
NEVER HIT 40.
Philippe Mora:
DAVID JUST COMPLETELY
DISAPPEARED.
FOUR DAYS LATER,
THEY BRING DAVID BACK.
I SAID TO DAVID,
"YOU CAN‘T JUST GO WALKABOUT
IN THE MIDDLE OF A SHOOT.
IT‘S BEEN A HUGE PROBLEM."
AND HE SAID, "OH, I HAD TO
ASK THE KOOKABURRAS AND
THE TREES ABOUT DENNIS."
AND I SAID, "REALLY?
WHAT DID THEY SAY?"
DAVID SAID, "WELL,
THE KOOKABURRAS AND THE TREES
ALL SAY DENNIS IS CRAZY."
AND I SAID, "LOOK, DAVID,
I COULD HAVE TOLD YOU THAT."
ARGGH ARGHHH ARGHH.
WHEN I GOT TO THAT 151 RUM,
YOU KNOW,
IT WAS DEFINITELY ON
THE ROAD TO HELL.
I‘LL TAKE YOU TO THE WILDS,
TO AUSTRALIA,
WHERE THERE‘S
17 WOMEN TO EVERY MAN.
John Seale:
REHEARSALS, FORGET IT-- ,
BE READY FOR ANYTHING.
HE WALKED BEHIND THE CAMERA. Y
IT WAS LIKE,
"YOU KEEP UP WITH ME.
OTHERWISE YOU‘RE A GONER."
Philippe Mora: WE WERE
READY TO SHOOT AND I SAID,
"DENNIS, WHERE ARE YOUR BOOTS?
AND HE SAYS, "FUCK BOOTS, MAN,
I‘M MAD DOG MORGAN."
I SAID, "I KNOW YOU‘RE
MAD DOG MORGAN, BUT YESTERDAY
MAD DOG HAD HIS BOOTS ON.
IT‘S THE SAME SCENE.
IT‘S NOT ABOUT MAGIC BOOTS."
HE‘S FIRED, MAN.
HEY, OFF THE SET.
Man:
HERE WE GO.  QUIET PLEASE.
Philippe Mora:
THERE WAS ONE SCENE WHERE
MAD DOG MORGAN DIES.
AND THERE WAS AN OLD ACTOR
WHO HAD TO PUT HIS HEAD
ON DENNIS‘S CHEST,
- LOOK UP AND SAY, "HE‘S DEAD."
- HE‘S DEAD.
DENNIS WAS OBVIOUSLY
STILL ALIVE-- HE WAS GURGLING.
AND SO I SAID, YOU KNOW,
"WHAT‘S WRONG?  OBVIOUSLY
HE‘S NOT DEAD."
HE SAID, "LOOK,
I NEEDED THE MONEY.
I DIDN‘T TELL ANYONE.
I‘M COMPLETELY DEAF AND I CAN‘T
SEE ANYTHING REALLY."
HE SAID, "I‘VE GOT AN IDEA:
GET A 20‘ LONG STICK,
AND WHEN YOU WANT ME TO SAY
"HE‘S DEAD," POKE ME.
I SAID,
"THAT‘S A BLOODY GOOD IDEA."
SO DENNIS DIES,
I POKE THE GUY-- "HE‘S DEAD."
PERFECT.  AND THEN DENNIS
GETS UP AND HE SAYS,
"LISTEN, MAN,
I‘VE WORKED WITH SOME
MOTHERFUCKERS IN MY TIME.
I‘VE WORKED WITH SOME REAL,
ASSHOLE DIRECTORS.
BUT I‘VE NEVER WORKED
WITH AN ASSHOLE
WHO POKES ACTORS
WITH A STICK.
WHAT IS THAT, MAN?
WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
WE‘RE NOT PUPPETS.
WE‘RE NOT ANIMALS."
Dennis Hopper:
I PROCEEDED TO DOWN A BOTTLE
OF 151-PROOF RUM
AND THEN I DECIDED THAT
I WOULD DESTROY THE CEMETERY.
AND THEN DENNIS LEAPED
BEHIND THE WHEEL,
ANNOUNCED THAT HE USED TO BE
A RACING-CAR DRIVER.
Philippe Mora:
THE POLICE STOPPED HIM,
AND HE‘S DRESSED AS MAD DOG.
THEY PRONOUNCED ME DEAD.
THEY SAID, "YOU‘RE DEAD."
YOU KNOW?  "YOU HAVE SUCH A--
THE ALCOHOL CONTENT YOU HAVE
IN YOUR BODY-- YOU‘RE DEAD."
SO THAT WAS GOOD NEWS.
"NOT ONLY WILL YOU NOT
BE ALLOWED TO DRIVE
IN THE STATE OF VICTORIA..."
I WAS NEVER ALLOWED TO BE
A PASSENGER IN A CAR.
"...AND YOU ARE BEING TAKEN
STRAIGHT TO THE AIRPORT."
HOW WE FINISHED THE FILM,
I‘VE GOT NO IDEA, REALLY,
THINKING BACK TO IT.
WE WEREN‘T OVER BUDGET;
WE WEREN‘T OVER SCHEDULE.
AND LIKE, YOU KNOW,
THEY GOT SOME MAGIC.
IT‘S YOUR MONEY OR YOUR LIFE,
AND IT‘S IN THAT ORDER.
WHEN THE GOVERNMENT OFFICIALS
SAW MAX FAIRCHILD RAPING
DENNIS HOPPER
AND THE CHINESE
BEING MASSACRED...
SOME OF THEM NEARLY HAD
A HEART ATTACK.
THEY SAID IT WAS,
YOU KNOW, DISASTER.
AND THEY WERE THE ONES WHO SAID
IT WOULDN‘T MAKE A DIME.
AND THEN "MAD DOG"
AT CANNES THAT YEAR WAS
THE ONLY FILM THAT SOLD.
AND IT OPENED IN THE U.S.
IN 40 THEATRES.
IT WAS THE FIRST
AUSTRALIAN MOVIE TO GET
AN OPENING LIKE THAT.
Narrator:
Outwitting, outriding,
outgunning an army of police,
here at last is the truth
about Mad Dog Morgan.
IT BECAME CLEAR
TO ME THAT ACTION
WAS THE UNIVERSAL CURRENCY
OF THE MOVIE MARKET.
AND ACTION, YOU KNOW,
TRANSCENDED ALL
LANGUAGE BARRIERS.
A GOOD PUNCH-UP PLAYS
JUST AS WELL IN HONG KONG,
AUSTRALIA, ICELAND,
ARGENTINA-- EVERYWHERE.
Hal McElroy:
THE BRUCE LEE KUNG-FU
CHOP-SOCKY MOVIES
WERE QUITE POPULAR.  AND BRIAN
THOUGHT, "WHY NOT HERE?
WHY NOT ON TOP OF
AYERS ROCK?"
♪ YOU ♪
♪ YOU‘VE BLOWN IT ALL
SKY HIGH ♪
♪ A LOVE THAT WINS
TONIGHT ♪
♪ YOU COULD HAVE
TOUCHED THE SKY ♪
♪ YOU‘VE BLOWN IT ALL
SKY HIGH. ♪
THE MOVIE FUCKING
KICKS ASS, MAN.
IT‘S A REALLY GOOD FILM
AND HOLDS UP TO THIS DAY.
THIS IS INSPECTOR FANG SEN LAN
FROM HONG KONG.
A CHINESE "DIRTY HARRY"
COMES TO AUSTRALIA
AND WRECKS THE PLACE
IN THE NAME OF JUSTICE.
"DON‘T WORRY ABOUT WHAT
HE MIGHT HAVE SAID.
DON‘T WORRY ABOUT
GATHERING EVIDENCE.
OH NO, MAN, JUST..."
Narrator:
Asia‘s international superstar
Jimmy Wang Yu
arrives in Sydney to star in
"The Man From Hong Kong."
Jimmy Wang Yu is regarded
as Asia‘s Steve McQueen.
- JIMMY WAS JUST HORRIBLE.
- A NASTY PIECE OF WORK.
ONE OF THE TWO WORST PEOPLE
I HAVE EVER WORKED WITH
IN MY LIFE.
DON‘T GIVE ME ANY SHIT.
HE BASICALLY HAD
NO RESPECT FOR ANYBODY.
WHITE WOMEN WERE... SCUM.
AND WHITE ACTRESSES
WERE WORSE THAN SCUM.
AND REBECCA, CHARMING
AND WONDERFUL AS SHE IS,
WAS OF COURSE THEREFORE JUST
A PIECE OF DIRT ON THE GROUND.
AND HE HAD TO DO
A LOVE SCENE WITH HER.
DO YOU THINK YOU‘RE
RECOVERED ENOUGH FOR ME
TO MAKE LOVE TO YOU?
I THINK I COULD
STAND THE PAIN.
HE INSISTED ON CATCHING
FLIES FROM THE AIR
AND EATING THEM
BEFORE HE KISSED HER.
- WHAT?  HE WHAT?
- LOOK, I DIDN‘T WARM TO HIM.
John Seale:
BRIAN USED TO STAND IN
FOR JIMMY IN THE LOVE SCENES
SO THAT HE COULD LIE ON TOP
OF REBECCA GILLING.
AND HE‘D SAY,
"THIS IS THE SORT OF ANGLE.
JOHN HAVE A LOOK AT THIS.
THIS IS WHAT YOU NEED."
AND HE‘S LYING RIGHT
ON TOP OF HER.
AND SHE‘S LYING THERE GOING...
WHAT DID YOU EXPECT,
ACUPUNCTURE?
WANG YU WAS
A TOP STAR IN ASIA.
AND HE‘D ALSO DIRECTED
EIGHT MOVIES.  AND HERE WAS I,
THIS KID, DIRECTING
HIS FIRST MOVIE
WITH A BUDGET FOUR TIMES
THE SIZE OF ANYTHING
WANG YU HAD HAD.
JIMMY WANG YU WANTED TO BE
THE BOSS OF THE SHOW.
HE WANTED TO BE
THE DIRECTOR.
AND BRIAN WAS
HANDLING IT SO WELL.
HE ACTUALLY DID A PRETTY
GOOD JOB BECAUSE IT WAS
PRETTY DEMANDING ON HIM,
NOT ONLY DIRECTING IT,
BUT PERFORMING IN IT AND
COPPING THE PUNCHES AS WELL.
EVERY TIME I LOOK
AT THE FILM
AND SEE HIM KICKING
THE SHIT OUT OF BRIAN...
THAT‘S NOT ACTING.
HE TREATED ME BADLY.
A MASTER OF KUNG FU--
HE USED HIS ART
FOR AN EVIL PURPOSE.
Roger Ward:
I SAID TO BRIAN, "LOOK, DO YOU
WANT ME TO TAKE CARE OF JIMMY?
YOU WANT ME TO GIVE
HIM A HIDING?"
BECAUSE I WAS QUITE PREPARED
TO DO THAT FOR BRIAN.
AND BRIAN SAID "NO NO NO.
I‘LL WIN MY BATTLE
AT THE BOX OFFICE."
AND HE DID.
Narrator:
George Lazenby is Jack Wilton,
ruthless czar
of international evil.
I NEEDED SOME MONEY
AND I HAD A HARD TIME
GETTING A JOB IN
THE FILM BUSINESS.
BECAUSE OF MY RECORD
AS JAMES BOND, I WOULDN‘T
SIGN THEIR CONTRACT.
SO I WAS BASICALLY
BLACKLISTED.
Grant Page:
HE‘D HAD A MOMENT OF GLORY.
AND I THINK HE‘D ACCEPTED
THE FACT THAT THINGS WEREN‘T
THAT BIG ANYMORE.
"THE MAN FROM HONG KONG"
WAS PROBABLY THE LIMO BILL
OF THE BOND FILM.
I WANT THAT LUNATIC STOPPED.
WE DIDN‘T REALLY KNOW
WHAT WE WERE DOING.
WE JUST KIND OF LEAPT INTO IT
AND JUST TRIED TO SHOOT
THE LIVING CRAP OUT OF IT.
SOME OF IT WAS PRETTY GOOD
AND SOME WASN‘T SO GOOD,
BUT ALL OF IT WAS DANGEROUS.
THERE WERE MANY TIMES I
THOUGHT I WOULD GET KILLED,
THAT PEOPLE WOULD GET
KILLED OR HURT.
THE SCENE AT AYERS ROCK
WHERE THE CAR ROLLS
AND BLOWS UP,
THE DOOR FLIES OFF--
YOU THINK, "WHOA, THAT THING‘S
GETTING AWFUL CLOSE."
Roger Ward:
DANGEROUS STUFF.
EVERYBODY DID IT AND
JUST HOPED FOR THE BEST.
John Seale:
THESE STUNTIES ARE
JUST SMASHING CARS TOGETHER
AND YOU‘RE IN IT.
Hal McElroy:
HIGH-SPEED CAR CHASE
SEQUENCES ON OPEN HIGHWAYS...
WITHOUT ANY TRAFFIC CONTROL,
WITHOUT POLICE PERMISSION,
WITHOUT ANYTHING.
WE JUST SHOT ‘EM.
IT WOULD GET OUT OF CONTROL
AND SPIN IN FRONT OF YOU
AND YOU‘D T-BONE IT.
AND YOU WERE SITTING IN
THE PASSENGER SEAT.
MAYBE YOU HAD A SEAT BELT;
MAYBE YOU DIDN‘T.
NOBODY REALLY WORRIED
ABOUT IT.
WE SAW PEOPLE HIT BY CARS
AND THEY‘D JUST PICK THEM UP:
"YOU ALL RIGHT?  HAVE A V.B.,
MATE, YOU‘LL BE ALL RIGHT.
JUST STAND THERE BUT MAKE
SURE YOU GET OUT OF THE WAY
A LITTLE EARLIER."
IT WAS CRAZY WHEN
YOU THINK ABOUT IT.
IN THE OLD DAYS IT WAS JUST
A CASE OF RIDE THE BIKE DOWN
THERE AND GET KICKED OFF.
HE JUST SAID, "YOU JUST
RIDE AT ME AND I‘LL KICK IT."
AND HE DID.
I‘D BEEN SET ON FIRE,
YOU KNOW, SEVEN TIMES
AND ONE OF THOSE OCCASIONS
WAS TO SHOW GEORGE
HOW YOU COULD BE VERY
SAFELY SET ON FIRE.
ALL THE GUYS
ARE AROUND SAYING,
"HEY, THIS IS
GOING TO LOOK FANTASTIC.
YOU‘VE GOT TO DO IT."
Brian Trenchard-Smith:
I DULY GOT LIT UP.
CHINESE CREW WERE GOING,
YOU KNOW, "THIS CRAZY GWAI LO.
WHAT‘S HE DOING NEXT?"
AND AFTER THE DIRECTOR
SET HIMSELF ON FIRE,
I THOUGHT, "JEEZ, IF HE‘S GOING
TO DO IT, I‘LL HAVE TO DO IT."
AHHH!
KNOWING THAT IT‘S REALLY
HAPPENING, ALL RIGHT,
YOU JUST CAN‘T BUY
THAT THRILL.
YOU CAN‘T CREATE IT.
THERE‘S NO SPECIAL EFFECT...
BUT WHEN THEY
ACTUALLY DO IT.
Brian Trenchard-Smith:
GEORGE GOES THROUGH ALL
THE MOVEMENTS
AND THEN HE HAD DIFFICULTY
GETTING THE JACKET OFF.
AND GEORGE STARTS TO
FEEL THAT HE‘S BURNING.
MY ARM WIPED OUT THE GREASE
AND THE FIRE JUST BURNT
MY ARM RIGHT UP HERE.
I‘VE NEVER SEEN ANYBODY TRY
TO RUN AWAY FROM HIS OWN ARM
SO FAST IN MY LIFE.
GRANT TACKLED HIM TO THE GROUND
AND WE PUT THE BLANKET ON HIM.
GEORGE WAS
UNDERSTANDABLY FURIOUS.
HE THREW A PUNCH AT
BRIAN TRENCHARD-SMITH.
NO, I DIDN‘T.
HE JUMPED UP AND WENT WHACK!
AND DICK TRENCHARD
WHACKED HIM AND, YOU KNOW,
NEARLY BROKE HIS JAW.
I DON‘T REMEMBER
PUNCHING HIM.
IF I DID, I‘M SORRY.
GOSH, YOU‘RE NOT EVEN ALLOWED
TO LIGHT A MATCH ON A SET NOW
WITHOUT FULL SAFETY OFFICERS
AND THINGS LIKE THAT.
SO IT WAS PRETTY
GUNG-HO BACK THEN.
Narrator:
This is Grant Page,
professional stunt man.
GRANT IS THE GUY THAT YOU GET
TO DODGE THE CARS,
SLIDE DOWN THE CLIFF ON FIRE,
JUMP INTO THE WATER
AND FIGHT THE SHARK.
GRANT PAGE WAS ONE OF
THOSE GUYS THAT YOU RESPECTED.
THE MOST FEARLESS MAN
I HAVE EVER MET.
HE WAS GONZO, JUST WHACKED.
( animal growling )
IN AMERICA WE JUST
CALL THAT INSANE.
HE‘S THE KIND OF GUY
THAT JUST BLOCKS OUT PAIN
FOR AS LONG AS IS NECESSARY.
"IT WILL HURT LATER."
THE WHOLE SCALP WAS OPENED UP
AND SORT OF LAYING DOWN HERE.
AND I THINK THEY PUT
120-ODD STITCHES IN MY HEAD.
HE‘S STILL ALIVE.
THAT‘S A MIRACLE RIGHT THERE.
I HAD THIS IDEA OF MAD DOG
COMING OUT OF THE WATER ON FIRE.
THE ONLY WAY TO DO IT WAS
TO SET GRANT ON FIRE
AND HAVE HIM DIVE INTO WATER.
UNFORTUNATELY THEY
COULDN‘T GET THE POOL OF WATER
WITH PETROL ON IT TO LIGHT.
SO I‘M STANDING THERE ON
THIS LITTLE TINY LEDGE,
THE GEL IS DRYING OUT...
AND WHEN HE WAS SET ON FIRE,
HE QUICKLY BURNED.
Grant Page:
I HAD A NARROW LEDGE TO
GET PAST DENNIS HOPPER
WITHOUT SETTING HIM ALIGHT.
Richard Brennan:
GRANT MOVED SWIFTLY AWAY IN
THE WRONG DIRECTION.
IT WAS HARD TO GET
HOLD OF HIM.
Philippe Mora:
HE STARTED SCREAMING AND
THEN HE WAS PUT OUT.
HE WENT TO HOSPITAL AND HE
WAS BURNT QUITE BADLY.
IT WAS NOT PAINFUL ENOUGH
TO KEEP ME IN HOSPITAL.
SORRY ABOUT THAT
GOING WRONG THERE,
BUT IT‘S SUCH A DRYING DAY.
A VERY DANGEROUS STUNT.
WE PREPARED THE STUNT
THE NEXT DAY.
THE MAJOR PART WAS
THE BACK FALL INTO THE WATER.
John Seale:
THAT WAS 80‘.
Grant Page:
A LOT OF ROCK ON THE BOTTOM--
QUITE JAGGED.
John Seale:
HE CAME UP WITH BLOOD COMING
OUT OF HIS EARS AND HIS NOSE.
OH, HE TOOK A HECK OF
A BANG ON THAT.
21 YEARS IN THE BUSINESS,
I‘VE NEVER SEEN ANYTHING
LIKE THAT.
I‘VE WORKED FOR ALL THE MANIACS:
HATHAWAY, GEORGE STEVENS.
ALL THE MANIACS,
YOU KNOW WHAT I MEAN?
I‘VE ALWAYS HAD THE FEELING
THAT GRANT WAS INDESTRUCTIBLE.
BRIAN WAS MY REASON FOR
STARTING IN THE FILM INDUSTRY.
HE HAD HEARD OF SOME OF
THE OLD STORIES OF WHAT
HAD HAPPENED BEFORE
AND THOUGHT THEY
WERE WORTH FILMING.
Brian Trenchard-Smith:
I THOUGHT, "WELL,
THIS IS SOMEONE
WHO SHOULD BE IN FRONT
OF THE CAMERA."
I OFFER YOU REAL EXCITEMENT,
A GENUINE TEST OF
YOUR SKILLS, INGENUITY
AND BLOOD-COOLING COURAGE.
I OFFER YOU
UNMISTAKABLE DANGER,
PLUS A LOT OF FUN.
IT‘S NOT MUCH, I KNOW,
BUT THAT‘S ALL I‘VE GOT.
Brian Trenchard-Smith:
A DUTCH DISTRIBUTOR HAD BOUGHT
"DEATHCHEATERS"
AND SAID, "IF YOU EVER HAVE
A BRIGHT IDEA FOR ANOTHER FILM,
COME AND SEE US."
SO I SAID I‘VE GOT THIS IDEA
CALLED "STUNT ROCK."
♪ STUNT ROCKER... ♪
FAMOUS AUSTRALIAN
STUNTMAN MEETS FAMOUS
AMERICAN ROCK GROUP.
MUCH STUNT AND
MUCH ROCK TAKES PLACE.
THE KIDS WILL
TEAR UP THE SEATS. US
WHAT‘S NOT TO LIKE?
THE DUTCH COMPANY SAID,
"FIND A BAND BY MONDAY
OR WE SHUT DOWN THE PICTURE."
♪ OOH YEAH... ♪
SO I WENT AND FOUND A BAND
THAT YOU FIND BY MONDAY.
Narrator:
The new discovery
rock group Sorcery.
BRIAN FOUND THIS GROUP
OF MAGICIANS WHO ALSO
PLAYED INSTRUMENTS.
UNFORTUNATELY, THEY DID BETTER
MAGIC THAN THEY DID MUSIC.
Narrator:
This dynamic combo
gets involved
with stuntman Grant Page,
and a blaze of fire,
smoke and sound erupts
all over the screen.
SO IT DOESN‘T HAVE,
YOU KNOW,
A THREE-ACT STRUCTURE OR
A DEEP AND MEANINGFUL STORY...
IN WHICH A CHARACTER‘S ARC
CAUSES HIM TO CHANGE
HIS WORLD VIEW.
BUT IS THAT REALLY WHAT
THE KIDS ARE INTERESTED IN?
I THINK THEY‘RE INTERESTED
IN GUYS BLOWING SHIT UP.
♪ OOH YEAH... ♪
IT‘S LAUGHS AND GASPS.
THAT‘S WHAT A LOT OF MY FILMS
HAVE BEEN ABOUT.
PRINT THAT.  LET‘S SET UP FOR
THE HIT-AND-RUN NOW, PLEASE.
AND OUT OF GRANT PAGE
AND BRIAN TRENCHARD-SMITH
COMES "MAD MAX."
GRANT PAGE BROKE HIS LEG
AND THE LEAD LADY‘S LEG
ON THE WAY OUT TO LOCATION
ON A MOTORBIKE ON DAY ONE.
WHEN GIBSON MET HIM,
THE FIRST DAY I THINK HE WAS ON
CRUTCHES AND ARMS IN PLASTER.
"THIS IS YOUR STUNTMAN."
"OH MY GOD."
WHEN YOU SEE THAT VEHICLE
GO THROUGH THE CARAVAN...
- HE‘S DRIVING WITH
HIS LEG IN PLASTER.
- OH, MAN.
David Eggby:
HE FLEW THROUGH THE CARAVAN
AND COLLECTED THE BONGO.
AND I REMEMBER IT SPINNING.
AND WE WERE ALL AMAZED
AT HOW MANY TIMES IT SPUN.
Man:
"MAD MAX" WAS
B-MOVIE FILMMAKING
WITH A-MOVIE ASPIRATIONS.
WE REALIZED THAT WE HAD TO
FULFILL FANTASIES
OF A LARGE CROSS-SECTION OF
THE AUDIENCE
TO A DEGREE THAT WOULD SATISFY
US IF WE WERE SITTING THERE
WATCHING OUR OWN PROGRAM,
AND PAYING $5 TO DO SO.
George Miller:
IN AUSTRALIA, WE HAD AUTOCIDE
RATHER THAN HOMICIDE.
BECAUSE I WAS WORKING IN
A BIG CITY HOSPITAL,
I WAS AT THE SORT
OF COALFACE OF THAT.
IT WAS VERY
VERY CONFRONTING FOR ME.
I WAS INTERESTED IN
A CHARACTER LIKE MAX
WHO WAS IN VERY BRUTAL WORLD...
AND BASICALLY TRYING TO
AVOID HIS BRUTAL NATURE.
Narrator:
Into a world without law,
a world without order,
comes a man without fear.
JUST THE IDEA THAT THIS DOCTOR
WITH HIS OWN MONEY
WENT OUT THERE
AND SET UP ROADBLOCKS
AND SHOT THESE SCENES.
FOR US FILM KIDS, IT WAS
SO INSPIRATIONAL TO KNOW
THAT THAT‘S WHAT THEY DID.
THOSE CRAZY STUNTS
SHOT ON WEEKENDS,
WITH DAVID EGGBY HANGING OFF
THE BACK OF A MOTORBIKE.
THERE WAS A SEQUENCE
IN IT WHERE THE GOOSE LEAVES
THE NIGHTCLUB...
AND THERE‘S THIS ONE BIKE...
DAVID‘S SITTING UP IN
HIS SHORTS AND T-SHIRT
WITH HIS CAMERA OVER
THE LENS FILMING THE SPEEDO.
David Eggby:
THE SPEEDO WAS HITTING
AT 180kmh.
IT BECAME GONZO FILMMAKING
BECAUSE THERE WAS NOTHING
IN THE LAW THAT ALLOWED YOU
TO BLOCK OFF THIS ROAD
AND THEN DRIVE A CAR OVER
THE SPEED LIMIT
AND ROLL IT AND CRASH IT
INTO ANOTHER CAR.
I‘M A FUEL-INJECTED
SUICIDE MACHINE.
THE NIGHT RIDER‘S CAR
IMPACTS WITH A PETROL BOWSER.
IT WAS A GENUINE,
GOVERNMENT-ORDINANCE ROCKET
IN THE BOOT OF THE CAR.
I KNEW THAT WE WERE
RISKING OUR LIVES, AND OFTEN.
AND I KNEW THAT THE GUYS ON
THE BIKES WERE IN A VERY
DANGEROUS SITUATION.
THE BIKE BESIDE IT
FLIPPED SIDEWAYS AND...
SLAPS HIM IN THE HEAD
AS IT CONNECTS.
HE FELT A BIT OF A BELT,
ENOUGH TO GIVE HIM A HEADACHE.
WE DIDN‘T KILL ANYBODY,
BUT WE DAMAGED SOME GOODS.
THERE WAS A LOT OF CHAOS.
NUMEROUS BROKEN BONES--
LEGS AND COLLARBONES.
IT APPEARED TO DAVID
THAT IT WAS OUT OF CONTROL.
WE DIDN‘T KNOW WHETHER
WE HAD A FILM OR NOT.
HE AND GEORGE CAME
TO LOGGERHEADS ABOUT, YOU KNOW,
WHERE THINGS SHOULD
BE SHOT FROM, AND I KNOW THAT
THEY HAD THEIR BATTLES.
THERE WAS TWO
DIFFERENT SENSIBILITIES.
I KNEW THERE WAS
A DIFFERENT WAY TO SHOOT,
BUT NO ONE HAD SHOT LIKE
THAT IN AUSTRALIA.
AND THAT WAS WHERE
THE CONFLICT WAS.
David Eggby:
GEORGE WAS THE VISIONARY.
THE TECHNIQUE OF FILMMAKING
HE WAS INEXPERIENCED AT.
I COULD HEAR THE MURMURINGS.
THEY WERE SAYING, "GOD, WE ONLY
GOT NINE SETUPS TODAY.
IF WE‘D SHOT WITH SUCH-AND-SUCH
DIRECTOR, WE‘D GET 43."
THE ACTUAL PRODUCTION
SIDE OF IT, HE HATED.
IT WAS LIKE WARFARE.
I DIDN‘T KNOW WHERE
THE BULLETS WERE COMING FROM.
THE MINES WERE.
I DON‘T KNOW HOW A FILM
WHICH ULTIMATELY WAS SUCCESSFUL
CAME OUT OF THAT EXPERIENCE.
THE FILM WAS
PRETTY WELL ACCEPTED
AND PEOPLE SAW IT AS
A NEW WAVE.
THE IMPACT ON AUDIENCES
WAS MIND-BOGGLING.
IT REALLY GOT TO THEM.
WE RAMMED IT DOWN
THEIR THROATS.
YOU CAN ONLY DO THAT
DOING 100kmh
WITH THE LENS
6" OFF THE GROUND,
WITH A WIDE ANGLE AND
THE FUN OF A CAR DODGING FROM
ONE SIDE TO THE NEXT.
George Miller:
THAT WAS THE THING
THAT ULTIMATELY DIFFERENTIATED
"MAD MAX," I THINK,
FROM OTHER FILMS.
THE VIOLENCE THAT WAS SHOWN
AND THE VIOLENCE THAT WAS
POWERFULLY IMPLIED...
REALLY KNOCKED
THE STUFFING OUT OF ME.
I‘VE SAT THROUGH HOURS
OF LOOKING AT FILMS
OUT OF THE DEATH CAMPS.
I REMEMBER THERE WAS
A REVIEW OUT OF INDIA
WHICH SAID THE PEOPLE WHO MADE
THIS FILM SHOULD BE DRAGGED INTO
THE STREET AND HUNG.
I ACTUALLY WENT AND SAW IT AFTER
READING THIS HORRIBLE REVIEW.
ALL RIGHT? I‘M LIKE,
"THIS MOVIE FUCKING ROCKS."
"MAD MAX" IS A TERRIFIC PICTURE,
BUT YOU KNOW,
IT‘S NOT ALL THAT ORIGINAL,
FOR CHRIST‘S SAKE.
Leigh Whannell: SOME GUY
JUST GETS PUSHED TOO FAR.
HIS FAMILY GOES DOWN.
THAT‘S WHAT THE FIRST
"MAD MAX" IS--
JUST A STRAIGHT UP
‘70s REVENGE MOVIE.
SO AT THE END,
HE‘S AN ANTI-HERO.
AND HE‘S DRIVING ALONG
AND HE HAPPENS UPON JOHNNY,
THE BOY WHO‘S RECENTLY
KILLED SOMEONE.
HE MAKES HIM HANDCUFF
HIS ANKLE
TO THE BOTTOM OF THE CAR AND
THEN THROWS HIM THE HACKSAW.
THE CHAIN IN THOSE HANDCUFFS
IS HIGH-TENSILE STEEL.
IT WILL TAKE YOU 10 MINUTES TO
HACK THROUGH IT WITH THIS.
NOW IF YOU‘RE LUCKY,
YOU CAN HACK THROUGH YOUR
ANKLE IN FIVE MINUTES.
THAT‘S THE CENTRAL CONCEIT
OF THE FIRST "SAW,"
IS THESE GUYS WITH A HACKSAW
HAVING TO CUT THROUGH A CHAIN.
HE DOESN‘T WANT US TO CUT
THROUGH OUR CHAINS.
HE WANTS US TO
CUT THROUGH OUR FEET.
SO IT WAS DEFINITELY A BIG
DIRECT INFLUENCE.
Man:
"MAD MAX" LITERALLY STARTED
THAT WHOLE SUBGENRE
OF ITALIAN POST-APOCALYPTIC,
YOU KNOW, ACTION PICTURES.
IT GETS COPIED A LOT
INTERNATIONALLY BUT HERE, NO,
YOU DON‘T GET A FOLLOW ON.
THE EXPECTATION WAS AT
THE TIME THAT WITH "MAD MAX"
BEING SO SUCCESSFUL,
THAT THERE WOULD BE A 150
CAR-CHASE FILMS MADE HERE.
IT DIDN‘T HAPPEN.
George Miller:
IT WAS DIFFICULT TO EMULATE,
BUT I THINK AUSTRALIAN
FILMMAKING WAS UNCONSCIOUSLY
ON A DIFFERENT COURSE,
CATCHING UP
WITH PERIOD PIECES.
IN A WAY,
"CHAIN REACTION" DID FOLLOW.
Narrator:
Somehow the one thing
that should never
have happened has begun.
Soon the dead
could be the lucky ones.
GEORGE MILLER IN FACT CAME OUT
AND DIRECTED SECOND UNIT.
TIME FOR A BIT
OF DUCO DAMAGE.
I DON‘T THINK GEORGE
HAD CHOREOGRAPHED
A LOT ON DIRT.
IT‘S VERY DIFFERENT TO TAR.
YOU CAN‘T SQUEAL THE
WHEELS ON DIRT.
Arna-Maria Winchester:
"CHAIN REACTION" WAS
A CAR-CHASE ROMP.
THAT WAS THE ENGINE
THAT DROVE THE STORY
BUT THE BASIC STORY
ALSO HAD SOME DEPTH
AND INTEREST.
A CHAIN REACTION
OF CONTAMINATION.
A NUCLEAR SPILL...
DONE ON THE CHEAP WITH THIS
LARRY STILLSON CHARACTER
TRYING TO GET A BIT
OF QUALITY TIME
WITH HIS LEOPARD-PRINT-
DRESSED WIFE.
NOTHING WRONG
WITH THAT AS AN IDEA.
THE WHOLE NUCLEAR MESSAGE
WAS SOMETHING THAT WAS VERY
TOPICAL AT THAT TIME.
I THINK ENTERTAINMENT
WON OUT
AND THE MESSAGE PROBABLY
TOOK THE BACK SEAT.
ROMANCE, SEX, CAR CHASES.
YOU KNOW, THERE‘S SOMETHING
FOR EVERYBODY, REALLY.
NOBODY SHOOTS A CAR
THE WAY AUSSIES DO.
THEY MANAGE TO SHOOT CARS
WITH THIS FETISHISTIC LENS
THAT JUST MAKES YOU
WANT TO JERK OFF.
- ( punk rock playing )
- ♪ TAKE A LONG RIDE ♪
♪ TAKE A LONG RIDE ♪
♪ TAKE A LONG RIDE
WITH ME ♪
YOU JUST LOOK AT THE TRAILER
FOR "MIDNITE SPARES."
THE CARS ARE BETTER LOOKING
THAN "THE FAST AND THE FURIOUS."
THERE‘S LIKE A HELL
OF A LOT MORE
ACTION AND CRASHES
JUST IN THAT TRAILER...
THAN THERE IS IN BOTH OF THOSE
"FAST AND THE FURIOUS"
MOVIES PUT TOGETHER.
Burstall:
"MIDNITE SPARES" HAD
A WHOLE RACE TRACK SEQUENCE.
AND THERE WAS
A TERRIBLE ACCIDENT
WHERE A SPRINT CAR DRIVER
HITS AN ASSISTANT CAMERAMAN
WHO WAS RUNNING AWAY
FROM HIS PROTECTED CAMERA
POSITION AND HE WAS KILLED.
WE JUST WEREN‘T AS CAREFUL
ABOUT THE SAFETY THINGS
AS WE ARE NOW.
AND IT WASN‘T QUITE
AS TIGHTLY CONTROLLED
AND, YOU KNOW, THINGS
OCCASIONALLY WENT WRONG.
WE DID HAVE A VERY
DISTRESSING INCIDENT
ON "YANKEE ZEPHYR."
Vince Monton:
WE HAD A JETBOAT
THAT WAS GOING TO BE DRIVEN
BY KEN WAHL
AND DONALD PLEASANCE.
THEY WERE GOING TO DRIVE THROUGH
THESE RAPIDS
WHICH WE WERE ASSURED
WERE VERY GENTLE AND
NO PROBLEMS.
THE JETBOAT DRIVER
JUMPED INTO THE JETBOAT
AND TOOK IT FOR A RUN
AND THE BOAT WAS COMPLETELY
DEMOLISHED IN THE RAPIDS.
THE JETBOAT DRIVER
AND ANOTHER PERSON
AND ULTIMATELY
A THIRD PERSON WERE KILLED.
WE WERE PERHAPS LUCKY
THAT THERE WEREN‘T
MORE MISHAPS.
DIRECTING HIGH-END
ACTION PICTURES IS A VERY
SPECIALIST SKILL.
YOU THINK I‘M SUPPOSED
TO BE IMPRESSED
BY THAT KIND OF FLYING?
I AM NOT!
Tony Ginnane:
PROBABLY DAVID HEMMINGS
WAS NOT THAT DIRECTOR.
HIS DRINKING
WAS A PROBLEM ON THAT
BECAUSE IT TOOK AWAY
HIS STAMINA;
IT TOOK AWAY
HIS CONCENTRATION.
AND ONE WILL ALWAYS
LOOK BACK ON "YANKEE ZEPHYR"
AND HAVE TO ADMIT THAT PROBABLY
IF BRIAN TRENCHARD-SMITH
HAD DIRECTED IT,
IT MIGHT HAVE BEEN
A DIFFERENT FILM.
BECAUSE ALL THE ELEMENTS
ARE THERE FOR A RIPSNORTING
ACTION MOVIE.
YANKEE ZEPHYR!
( howls )
AND SOMEHOW
IT DIDN‘T GEL.
COULD IT HAVE BEEN
A BETTER PICTURE? YES.
DID WE MAKE MONEY OUT
OF IT? YES.
30 DAYS, NEXT CASE.
THE INDUSTRY WAS GREEDY
TO TAKE THE NEXT STEP
AND THIS WAS A TAX
CONCESSION CALLED 10 B.A.
YOU WOULD BE OFFERED
A 150% WRITE-OFF ON
A FILM INVESTMENT.
THAT LED TO A WEALTH
OF GENRE MATERIAL BEING MADE
BECAUSE A LOT
OF THE FINANCIERS DIDN‘T
REALLY CARE WHAT GOT MADE.
THEY CARED ABOUT THE DEAL
AND THEY CARED ABOUT
PUTTING THEIR TEAMS TOGETHER
AND MAKING A LOT OF MONEY
AS THE MONEY WASHED THROUGH.
AND WE MADE FILMS LIKE
YOU WOULDN‘T BELIEVE.
Narrator:
It is 1995.
Hunting is
the national sport.
People are the prey.
"TURKEY SHOOT"‘S ANOTHER ONE
OF THESE FUN GINNANE MOVIES
THAT ALWAYS SEEMS
TO BE YANKED OUT
WHEN THERE‘S A BIT OF
CONTROVERSY TO BE DISCUSSED.
SOMETHING FELL
INTO A BIG ABYSS.
WE HAD SOME FINANCIAL
PROBLEMS EARLY ON.
HALF THE BUDGET
DID NOT TURN UP.
WE DIDN‘T LOSE
HALF THE MONEY.
I THINK BRIAN LIKES
TO EXAGGERATE.
Trenchard-Smith:
THE STUNTMEN WOULD BE
PAID TO TURN UP
AND WHATEVER THEY DID
WAS UP TO THEM.
THAT WAS HOW POVERTY-STRICKEN
THE BUDGET SUDDENLY BECAME.
THE PRODUCERS WERE OUT
AT THE RACECOURSES EVERY DAY
GAMBLING
TO GET MORE MONEY.
THEY SPENT A LOT OF TIME
AT THE TRACK.
NOW...
I DON‘T THINK WE SHOT
THAT $2.5 MILLION.
THEY THREW 25 OR 30 OR, 17--
YOU HEAR DIFFERENT STORIES.
HOW MANY PAGES OF SCRIPT
THEY THREW OUT I DON‘T KNOW.
WHEN YOU HAVE NO BEGINNING,
YOU HAVE NOTHING.
YOU‘RE SCREWED.
WITH ALL DUE RESPECT TO STEVE,
I‘M NOT SURE THAT THE
STATE OF HIS MIND
DURING THAT FILM
WAS SUCH THAT HE COULD
REMEMBER ANY OF THE PAGES.
STAY AWAY
FROM THE TRACK.
DON‘T BLAME IT ON THE $700,000
THAT WAS CUT,
BECAUSE THAT HAD
NOTHING TO DO WITH IT.
STAY AWAY FROM THE TRACK--
THAT DID HAVE SOMETHING
TO DO WITH IT.
IF WE QUIT NOW,
EVERYTHING WE BELIEVE IN DIES.
WE‘VE GOT TO KEEP GOING.
RIGHTLY OR WRONGLY,
I DECIDED TO MAKE IT
INTO A HIGH-CAMP
SPLATTER MOVIE.
STUNTS MAY BE EXPENSIVE,
BUT BLOOD IS CHEAP.
Tarantino:
THE PRISONERS HAD TO
RECITE THIS MANTRA
WHICH BASICALLY SAYS
THEY ARE THE LOWEST FORM
OF LIFE ON EARTH...
I AM A DEVIANT, THE LOWEST
FORM OF LIFE ON EARTH.
...WHILE ROGER WARD,
THE GUARD FROM HELL,
IS THROWING
SHADOW PUNCHES AT HER.
I SAID TO HER,
"LOOK, I MAY SEEM LIKE
I‘M A RUTHLESS BASTARD.
BUT DON‘T BE CONCERNED,
I‘M ONLY ACTING."
AND I BASHED HER
AND BEAT HER.
I‘VE SEEN LIKE PEOPLE
GET KICKED IN MOVIES,
BUT IT LOOKS LIKE
HE‘S KICKING HER TO DEATH.
I LIKE THE WHOLE MOVIE,
BUT LIKE AFTER I SAW
THAT SCENE,
I‘M GOING TO LOVE
THAT MOVIE, ALL RIGHT.
DO YOU WANT ME
TO BURY HER, MR. RITTER?
- SHE AIN‘T DEAD YET, DUTCH.
- I COULD DO IT ANYWAY.
ANYTHING THAT PRODUCED
A GORY LOOK, GOOD.
TRENCHARD-SMITH‘S
GOOD AT THAT SORT OF THING.
HE‘S GOOD AT MAKING SPLATTER
AND HE‘S GOOD
AT DEVISING MEANS
WHERE PEOPLE‘S TOES
ARE RIPPED OFF...
- THE LITTLE ONE.
- (screams )
...AND OTHER PEOPLE COME
ALONG AND EAT THEM.
THIS THING WAS
TURNED INTO A PIECE OF CRAP.
AND I HATED TO SEE IT.
AND WHEN SHE TURNED
THAT ARROW AROUND
AND PUT IT IN HER THROAT
AND THEN HER HEAD BLEW
OFF AT THAT POINT--
ALL IT DID
WAS MAKE SPARKS BEFORE.
BUT I TELL YOU WHAT DID WORK
IS WHEN I BLEW THAT HEAD OFF.
( yells )
I THOUGHT THAT ONE WORKED.
IN A WAY.
Bob McCarron:
DAVID HEMMINGS WAS
THE SECOND-UNIT DIRECTOR.
AND I REMEMBER THE SCENE
WHERE ONE OF OUR ACTORS GETS
HIS HANDS CHOPPED OFF.
OLIVIA HAD THAT BLOODY
MACHETE IN HER HANDS
AND DAVID SAYS,
"AND CUT."
MEANING
"CUT. STOP THE FILM."
SHE THINKS HE MEANS CUT.
SO SHE GOES FOR IT...
NO NO, DON‘T CUT!
...MISSING HIS REAL
HANDS BY INCHES.
I WANT TO TELL YOU
SOMETHING.
NOBODY
SHOULD EVER
EVER
EVER BE HURT
ON A FILM SET.
McCarron: E SCENE
WE ACTUALLY HAD
LIVE AMMUNITION
FIRED AT ACTORS
TO HIT ROCKS NEARBY.
WE HAD A STUNTMAN--
GLEN BOSWELL, HE WAS
CROSSING THE RIVER.
WHEN THE SCENE WAS FINISHED,
HE GOT UP AND FOUND HE
WAS STILL BLEEDING.
ON EXAMINATION,
WE FOUND THERE WAS
A BULLET IMBEDDED IN HIM.
I THINK PEOPLE WERE
SHOOTING BALL BEARINGS
AT THE WATER.
I WOULD NEVER ALLOW
REAL BULLETS TO BE SHOT.
THE GOOD THING
ABOUT "TURKEY SHOOT"
IS THAT IT ALLOWED US ALL
TO HAVE A LOT OF LAUGHS
AT THE EXPENSE
OF THE FILM ESTABLISHMENT.
DEAR OLD PHILLIP ADAMS,
NOT CONTENT
WITH TRASHING "MAD MAX,"
DECIDED THAT HE‘D BETTER
HAVE A GO AT ME.
"TURKEY SHOOT"
IS ONE OF MY LEAST
FAVORITE FILMS OF ALL TIME.
I BELIEVE I SAID
THAT THE SIGHT OF LYNDA STONER
BEING STABBED
THROUGH THE LEFT NORK
BY A CARNIVOROUS LESBIAN
WAS TOO MUCH
FOR ME TO TAKE.
AND INDEED IT WAS.
HE WAS ONE OF THE ONES
WHO BOLTED OUT THE DOOR.
PERHAPS HE THOUGHT
ONE OF HIS SARCOPHAGUSSES
WAS BEING STOLEN.
IT WAS A FAR WORSE FILM
THAN ANYONE COULD
HAVE IMAGINED.
IT HAS PROFESSIONAL
SHORTCOMINGS AS WELL AS
MORAL SHORTCOMINGS.
TOUCHDOWN.
"TURKEY SHOOT"
WAS REALLY OUT THERE.
BUT THAT TO ME
WAS BRIAN MAKING MOVIES.
HE JUST THREW HIMSELF
INTO EVERY MOVIE.
SOME OF THEM,
LIKE "BMX BANDITS" ARE--
NOT MUCH DEEP AND MEANINGFUL
STUFF IN THERE,
BUT IT‘S GREAT
ENTERTAINMENT.
Narrator:
BMX Bandits,
they‘re wild in the streets,
a high-flying ride
to adventure.
THE BMX BIKE APPEALED
TO HIM GREATLY
BECAUSE IT WENT DOWN STEPS.
THEY COULD RIDE UP
THE SIDES OF WALLS.
HE COULD HAVE CAR CHASES,
EVERYTHING THAT HE LOVED DOING
WAS IN THAT MOVIE.
AND SOMEHOW IT ALL WORKED.
EVEN THE MOST CYNICAL CRITIC
IN AUSTRALIA GOT SUCKED IN.
I THINK THE MOMENT
THEY SAW NICOLE KIDMAN,
THEY WERE DEFINITELY SUCKED IN.
YOU KNOW WHAT THEY SAY:
TWO‘S COMPANY, THREE GETS
US TALKED ABOUT.
IT RESTORED PEOPLE‘S
FAITH IN ME, I SUPPOSE.
THIS REMINDS ME
OF A REALLY GOOD MOVIE
I SAY AT THE DRIVE-IN ONCE...
"KISS THE BLOOD
OFF MY CARBURETOR."
- IT WAS A HORROR ROAD MOVIE.
- AREN‘T THEY ALL?
"FAIR GAME" HAS BAD-ASS,
SCARY, BITCHING-LOOKING
MECHANICAL MONSTERS
AND THE BAD GUYS
ARE DRIVING.
GET OUT OF THE WAY,
YOU CRAZY MOLL.
THEY‘RE KANGAROO KILLERS
WHICH AUTOMATICALLY MAKES
THEM THE BAD GUYS.
AND THEY‘RE FUCKING
WITH THE CHICK.
YOU BASTARDS!
THEY WERE DESTROYING
THE HOUSE AROUND ME.
A TRUCK WOULD DO ONE TAKE
AND COME AND SMASH IN ONE WALL
AND I‘D RUN FROM THAT WALL
TO THE NEXT WALL.
IT WAS PRETTY SCARY
BUT I MADE IT OUT OF THERE
LIKE A LITTLE RABBIT.
IT‘S A CAR-- AS OPPOSED
TO AN AMERICAN SLASHER FILM,
IT‘S THE KNIFE-- AND IT‘S
THE ACCOUTREMENT OF THAT.
NO, IT‘S HOW SCARY
DOES THE CAR LOOK?
THE MALE CHARACTERS
WERE A LITTLE ...
A LITTLE NASTY.
SNAP.
GOTCHA.
AND THEY GOT EVEN NASTIER.
NO.
SO I JUST HAD TO
KILL THEM.
IT‘S A FEMALE
"STRAW DOGS."
AFTER YOU‘VE SEEN
A BUNCH OF AUSTRALIAN FILMS
AND YOU WATCH
"STRAW DOGS," YOU GO,
"WHY THE HELL DID PECKINPAH
SET THIS IN ENGLAND?"
THIS IS SUCH
AN AUSTRALIAN STORY.
( screams )
IF YOU LIKE
OUTRAGEOUS CINEMA,
YOU LIVE--
YOU LIVE AND BREATHE
TO WAIT FOR THOSE
WEIRD MOMENTS
THAT HAPPEN EVERY ONCE
IN A WHILE IN GENRE CINEMA
WHERE IT‘S LIKE
YOU CAN‘T BELIEVE
YOU‘RE SEEING
WHAT YOU‘RE SEEING.
WELL, "FAIR GAME" HAS
ONE OF THOSE MOMENTS, MAN.
AND THAT‘S WHERE AFTER FUCKING
THE GIRL OVER LIKE CRAZY
THEY STRIP HER NUDE.
THEY TIE HER TO THE FRONT
OF THEIR MONSTER TRUCK.
AND THEN THEY JUST PROCEED
TO DRIVE DOWN THE ROAD
AT 100mph
WITH HER TIED NAKED
TO THE FRONT OF THE TRUCK.
ALL RIGHT, SO SHE‘S
A HUMAN HOOD ORNAMENT.
WHO IN THE FUCK
THOUGHT OF THAT?
WHAT BRAIN THOUGHT OF IT?
WHO LET THEM DO IT?
AND THEN WHEN THEY DID IT,
WHAT THE FUCK WAS
GOING THROUGH THEIR MINDS
AS THEY‘RE SHOOTING
THIS SEQUENCE?!
TO ME, THAT‘S THE REASON
YOU WATCH EXPLOITATION CINEMA--
IS TO HAVE
THOSE MOMENTS LIKE,
"IS THIS ACTUALLY HAPPENING?
AM I ACTUALLY SEEING THIS?
AM I HAVING AN ACID FLASHBACK
OR IS THIS GOING ON?"
IT‘S A CLASSIC MOMENT
IN GENRE CINEMA, HANDS DOWN.
THERE‘S AN AWFUL STATISTIC
THAT SOMETHING LIKE
HALF THE FILMS
MADE UNDER 10 B.A.
WERE NEVER RELEASED
THEY WERE SO BAD.
Narrator:
The ark has been raided,
the stone
has been romanced
and now the great
adventure is back.
"Sky Pirates."
It will be the ride
of your life.
"INDIANA JONES
AND THE TEMPLE OF CRAP."
THEY CERTAINLY HAVE
PUT THE CURSE
ON THE TERM "GENRE FILM"
IN AUSTRALIA.
- ♪ WHAT THE WORLD NEEDS NOW ♪
- ♪ Whoa yeah! ♪
- ♪ IS A GENRE HERO ♪ "
- ♪ Oh yes we do ♪
- ♪ WHAT THE WORLD NEEDS NOW ♪
- ♪ World needs now ♪
- ♪ IS A GLORY MAN ♪
- ♪ A glory man ♪
♪ WHO WILL FLY DOWN
AND DOWN AND DOWN ♪
♪ AND SAVE THE DAY ♪
♪ WHAT THE WORLD
NEEDS NOW ♪
♪ YEAH, IS A HERO
TO HELP US THROUGH. ♪
DID IT ALL
MESH TOGETHER?
I DON‘T KNOW
HOW IT COULD HAVE,
IN RETROSPECT.
BUT IN AMONGST
THAT DROSS, YOU KNOW,
THEY WERE STILL MAKING
BLOODY FANTASTIC FILMS,
AND SOME INCREDIBLY QUITE
ORIGINAL FILMS.
Narrator:
Now comes a startling
new vision
that takes you into the
apocalypse and beyond.
"DEAD END DRIVE-IN" IS MY
FAVORITE BRIAN TRENCHARD-SMITH
MOVIE, ALL RIGHT?
THAT‘S THE ONE YOU CAN JUST
SHOW TO ANYBODY AND ANYONE
WILL JUST RECOGNIZE IT
AND ACCEPT IT FOR LIKE,
YOU KNOW QUITE AN EXCEPTIONAL
PIECE OF WORK.
- I COULD BE ODDBALL...
- SHIT, WE‘RE ON FIRE.
- ...BUT I COULD
ALSO BE GLOSSY.
- ( screams )
SOMETIMES IN THE LAND
OF LOW BUDGET
IT IS HARD TO BE BOTH.
Narrator:
When the show is over,
there is no way out.
"Dead End Drive-in."
THE STORY AND THE IDEA
IS SO INTRIGUING.
THE GOVERNMENT
DEAL WITH A CRIME WAVE
BY TAKING THE PURPORTED
CRIMINALS, YOUTH, AND
INCARCERATING THEM...
Tarantino:
IN A DRIVE-IN
AS A CONCENTRATION CAMP.
AS LONG AS THEY JUST GET
TO LIVE IN THEIR CARS
AND THEY KEEP CONSTANT
EXPLOITATION MOVIES
PLAYING ON THE SCREEN
ALL THE TIME...
- OH MY GOD.
- ...IT‘S ALL GOOD,
ALL RIGHT.
- FORGET THE BLOODY FILM.
- I HAVE TO SEE THE END.
Trenchard-Smith:
"DEAD END DRIVE-IN" SHOWCASES
ANOTHER GREAT AUSTRALIAN
STUNTMAN-- GUY NORRIS.
HE WANTED TO ACHIEVE
A WORLD-RECORD TRUCK JUMP.
( man yelling )
160‘ HE FINALLY MADE
THAT TRUCK GO.
THE WRITING WAS
ALREADY ON THE WALL
BY THE TIME "DEAD END
DRIVE-IN" CAME OUT
THAT THE EXPLOITATION CINEMA
WAS JUST ON ITS WAY OUT,
THAT FROM HERE ON IN
IT WOULD BE HOME VIDEO.
Trenchard-Smith:
I WANTED IT TO BE
THE ULTIMATE MOVIE
YOU COULD EVER SEE
IN A DRIVE-IN
AND DRIVE-INS
WERE RAPIDLY DYING OUT.
PEOPLE WERE SEEING THOSE KINDS
OF MOVIES IN THEIR HOME.
WHAT WAS SAD
WAS TO SEE THE GRADUAL
DECLINE OF THESE MOVIES
AND TO SEE THEM GET
CRAPPIER AND CRAPPIER.
I REMEMBER SEEING THIS THING
CALLED "BLOOD MOON"
WHICH HAD A FRIGHT BREAK
IN THE MIDDLE OF IT.
IT WAS SUPPOSED TO BE
FOR THOSE WHO WERE
TOO SCARED TO MAKE IT
THROUGH TO THE FINALE.
Narrator:
Take the "Blood Moon"
challenge.
Can you take the heat?
IT WAS A CHANCE FOR THEM
TO ESCAPE AND GET
THEIR MONEY BACK.
I GOT MY MONEY BACK.
IT WAS LIKE, STRAIGHTAWAY,
"GIVE ME THAT MONEY BACK."
AS THE FUNDING BODIES
CAME BACK INTO IT,
IT‘S MUCH HARDER
FOR A FUNDING BODY
TO SAY, "HERE WE‘RE GIVING
TAXPAYER‘S MONEY
TO GENRE MOVIES BECAUSE
THEY‘RE SEEN AS IMPORTED FILMS,
NOT OUR CULTURE."
THE ATTITUDE WAS
"CLEARLY THOSE GENRE
EXPLOITATION FILMS FAIL.
WE SHOULD NOT WASTE
OUR TIME ON ANY OF THEM.
WE SHOULD JUST BE MAKING
THE ARTISTICALLY
MERITORIOUS THINGS
THAT WE ALWAYS
SHOULD HAVE BEEN MAKING."
MORE SORT OF CULTURALLY
REFLECTIVE,
SOCIALLY
MEANINGFUL FILMS.
AND GENRE DIED
FOR A SHORT TIME.
MAYBE IT‘S ONLY
BECOMING NOW
THAT WE‘RE SEEING, YOU KNOW,
THAT AUSSIE EXPLOITATION
IS ACTUALLY STARTING
TO GET SOME SORT OF RECOGNITION
AND SOME SORT
OF REDISCOVERY.
THERE IS A NEW GENERATION
IN AUSTRALIA
THAT WANTS TO GO BACK
TO GENRE AND REINVENT IT.
Director:
AND ACTION!
THERE‘S ALL THIS ACTIVITY
ALL OF A SUDDEN
AND THAT‘S COMPLETELY
DUE TO "WOLF CREEK."
WHAT DO YOU
ACTUALLY DO NOW?
I COULD TELL YA,
BUT THEN I‘D HAVE TO KILL YA.
PLEASE!
Greg McLean:
THE FILM WAS TURNED DOWN
BY LOTS OF PEOPLE
FOR STUPID REASONS.
IT‘S TO DO WITH NOT
WANTING TO BE RISKY.
FOR HORROR,
IT‘S GOT TO BE EXTREME,
OTHERWISE IT‘S JUST GOING TO
FALL INTO THE WASH
OF THE MILLIONS OF HORROR
FILMS THAT COME ALONG.
THAT‘S NOT A KNIFE.
- THIS IS A KNIFE.
- NO!
Matthews:
WATCHING THAT FILM
GETTING MADE,
IT REMINDED ME VERY MUCH
OF THE FILMMAKING ENERGY
OF THE ‘70s.
IT FELT LIKE
A LITTLE BIT OF A
NEW WAVE HAPPENING.
WITH FILMS LIKE
"WOLF CREEK" AND "UNDEAD"
AND FILMS LIKE THIS
BEING MADE,
I‘M HOPING
THAT IT LEADS TO
A SORT OF A LITTLE RENAISSANCE
OF GENRE FILMS.
THESE FILMS
ARE COMING BACK.
( shrieks )
IN "STORM WARNING"
WE REALLY TRIED
TO PUSH THE ENVELOPE
IN TERMS OF CONTENT
AND BRING IT BACK
TO KIND OF WHAT IT USED
TO BE A LITTLE BIT.
Sigrid Thornton:
IT‘S A SIGN OF
TREMENDOUS MATURITY.
IT‘S A VERY VERY GOOD SIGN,
I THINK, FOR THE INDUSTRY
THAT WE‘VE SORT OF COME
FULL CIRCLE, IF YOU LIKE.
THE ENERGY LEVEL,
THE AUDACITY OF THESE FILMS,
I THINK SETS--
IN AN INTERESTING WAY,
SETS A VERY GOOD BENCHMARK
FOR FILMMAKERS NOW.
PEOPLE LIKE ME AND A LOT
OF OTHER DIRECTORS
ARE KIND OF SEEING THEM GOING,
"THAT‘S A HERITAGE WE HAVE."
I THINK I CAN SAY
WITHOUT FEAR
OF SUCCESSFUL CONTRADICTION
THAT AMONG THE MANY FIELDS
OF ARTISTIC ENDEAVOR
IN WHICH WE AUSTRALIANS
HAVE SHOWN
SUCH WONDERFUL
LEADERSHIP
IS THE ART OF THE
MOTION PICTURE.
( screams )
♪ THIS TIME,
GONNA TAKE YOUR HAND ♪
♪ GONNA TAKE YOU
TO THE PROMISE LAND ♪
♪ AND THIS TIME ♪
♪ THIS TIME ♪
♪ THIS TIME, GONNA HEAD
IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION ♪
♪ IN THE RIGHT DIRECTION ♪
♪ IN THE RIGHT
DIRECTION. ♪
WHEN I HAD THE SYDNEY
PREMIERE OF "KILL BILL,"
A GOOD SECTION
OF THE AUSTRALIAN
FILM INDUSTRY
WAS OUT IN THE AUDIENCE
THAT NIGHT.
I KNEW THAT THEY‘RE SNOBS
AND I LIVE TO STICK A WEED
UP THE ASS OF SNOBS.
SO I DEDICATED IT
TO BRIAN TRENCHARD-SMITH.
IF YOU DON‘T LIKE BRIAN
TRENCHARD-SMITH,
YOU AIN‘T GOING
TO LIKE THIS MOVIE,
SO GET THE FUCK OUT
RIGHT NOW.
I‘VE JUST WARNED YOU.
IF YOU READ
AUSTRALIAN FILM,
YOU KNOW, LITERATURE
AND ANALYSIS,
I AM A SORT OF
A GUILTY PLEASURE FOOTNOTE.
THE POWERS THAT BE
WOULD BEGRUDGINGLY AGREE
THAT I‘M A HALF-DECENT
CRAFTSMAN
AND I DOUBT THAT
IT‘S MORE THAN THAT NOW.
THERE‘S NO QUESTION THAT
THE LIKE OF RICHARD FRANKLIN
AND JOHN LAMOND
WERE VERY VERY UNDERVALUED.
INTERESTINGLY ENOUGH,
THE ONLY TIME
I MET THEIR LIKE
WAS WHEN I FIRST MET
SCORSESE AND SPIELBERG.
I STILL HAVE
A NEWSPAPER CLIPPING
OF JOHN IN HIS RAINCOAT
OUTSIDE A SEX SHOP
IN MELBOURNE.
I PRIZE THAT.
IT‘S VERY MUCH JOHN.
IT WAS GREAT FUN,
AND I‘D DO IT AGAIN.
I WILL DO IT AGAIN
IF SOMEONE PUTS UP THE MONEY.
I WILL MAKE EPICS
ON A SHOESTRING
AND BE GLAD
FOR THE OPPORTUNITY.
I LOVED WORKING
WITH BRIAN.
EVERYTHING HE DID WAS BIG
AND MORE EXCITING.
MOVIE MAKING
WAS HIS FORTE.
AND WHETHER THE REST
OF THE INDUSTRY THOUGHT
THOSE FILMS
WERE OF A CALIBER
THAT WAS WORTHY
OF THE NEW AUSTRALIAN
FILM INDUSTRY
REALLY ISN‘T IMPORTANT.
IN HINDSIGHT, THEY ALL WERE.
- IT WAS AN ADVENTURE.
- IT WAS LIKE THE WILD WEST.
IT WAS JUST
COMPLETELY THRILLING
TO BE PART OF IT.
IT DID NURTURE YOU
FOR A FUTURE
IN A BIGGER, BETTER,
BRIGHTER WORLD.
I‘D ULTIMATELY LIKE
TO BE SORT OF VIEWED
AS THE SORT OF
A LONE GUN
RIDING OUT THERE
AT THE EDGE OF THE PRAIRIE,
MAYBE A LITTLE BIT
LIKE SORT OF JOHN WAYNE
WALKING OUT THE DOOR
AT THE END OF "THE SEARCHERS,"
KNOWING THAT YOU‘RE
PROBABLY ARE NEVER
GOING TO BE INVITED
TO STAY IN BY THE FIRE,
- BUT THAT‘S OKAY.
- GIVE ME A BREAK.
GO HOME,
TAKE YOUR MONEY,
RETIRE, GET OUT OF MY LIFE.
I HATE YOU.
THE TOORAK DRIVE-IN
ON FRIDAY NIGHT WAS
YOUR LITMUS TEST.
DOESN‘T MATTER A RAT‘S ASS
WHETHER THE CRITIC LIKED
IT ON THURSDAY,
IF YOU DRIVE
OVER THAT TOP OF THE HILL
AND YOU SEE THE CARS
AROUND THE CORNER
YOU THINK,
"SHIT, WE‘VE GOT A FILM."
YOU‘LL GET ANOTHER FILM.
AND I DIDN‘T DO IT
TO GET A BIGGER HOUSE.
I DID IT
TO MAKE ANOTHER FILM.
IT‘S A STRANGE INDUSTRY,
THE FILM INDUSTRY.
MASTERPIECES
ROTTING IN DRAWERS,
MEDIOCRITIES
WINNING OSCARS.
C‘EST LA VIE.
THAT‘S AN AUSTRALIAN TERM.
Narrator: Before leaving,
replace the speaker
on its stand,
then drive forward
and move to your left.
Thanks, everyone.
We trust you have
a very pleasant evening.