For best IPTV provider, please visit: www.IPTV.CAT
Look, Kuba.
They're flying away.
Hanka! Come over here.
Has God blessed you
with a good potato harvest?
Yes, indeed.
She said the baby has
the same eyes, dark and rheumy.
The spitting image of Boryna.
No!
Many a young girl
will chase after him.
They had no room for her
in the hallway, or the barn.
- They did the same to me.
- Right.
The plague-ridden scum.
Her own children.
It's getting cold. Come get
your mother's wool, Magda.
There's no point.
Father won't hand over anything,
not even her clothes.
Jagna, come.
You're so dressed up.
What a fancy necklace.
Made from an alder branch
I found. I cut it and...
Beautiful and talented.
She could marry a rich widower.
I won't look after
someone else's children.
There's nothing to worry about.
His are already weaned.
I'm fine where I am.
Sooner or later
you'll have to flee the nest.
Get a good husband
and you'll have a good farm.
And you'll be a good woman.
I don't care about that.
Don't talk rubbish, Jagna.
She's still young
and speaks without thinking.
Don't you dare
slink off to the inn.
- You'll feel my whip if you do.
- Come on, Mother.
No.
And you?
As if I needed more trouble.
What did I do?
You talked back
to the mayor's wife.
Do you want them
to speak ill of you?
I didn't mean to offend her.
I'm just happy here with you.
My dear child.
What's going on at Boryna's?
Poor thing.
I won't be ringing the bell
at her funeral.
Clink your pots instead.
Daddy!
Rosey is dying.
Jambrozy has bled her,
but nothing happened.
Then we put melted wax
down her throat. Still nothing.
Our best cow.
May the Devil twist your guts
if that's how you tend her.
Always eager to eat my food,
but you won't lend a hand.
I've been out digging potatoes
all afternoon.
As if you ever notice anything.
Scum! To waste such a beast.
What? Sniveling again?
It's all you're good for.
Leave her alone.
Don't insult my wife.
You're no better.
- Do you care for this farm?
- What am I? Your farmhand?
I work like a horse for nothing.
Not a nice word from you.
Shut up before I lose my temper.
You live on my land,
eat my food.
- My bread's making you bold.
- This bread is my birthright!
You've inherited it as I should
now inherit it from you.
I doubled this land
with my own hands.
And while these hands can work,
it stays mine.
If you don't like it,
try your luck elsewhere.
You can get fresh bread daily
from Hanka's three acres.
I'd eat moldy potatoes, if they
weren't thrown in my face.
Father wants you
to butcher the cow.
I'm no butcher.
Must you always fight with him?
He's your father.
Make peace with him.
Do it for us, for our children.
Come on, Antek.
You make peace if you want.
But don't tell me what to do.
Without a housewife at home,
there's no one
to keep tabs on things.
It's time for you to marry.
Period.
You're joking.
My wife's body is still warm
in her grave.
The whole village
would start talking.
Eat up.
Listen, Boryna.
There are so many
unwed girls here,
that when a man
goes about the houses,
he smolders hot as a stove.
Take Zoska.
Slender, hardworking,
and her dowry is not bad.
She's a grumpy shrew,
and has one thick hip.
What does he need her dowry for?
Isn't he the richest farmer
in the village?
How about Staszek's Weronka?
Taken.
Roch's son
sent her vodka yesterday.
Jagna Dominikowa?
A fine girl!
- Jagna?
- Yes.
They say
she's always chasing after boys.
Oh, well. It's just a rumor.
People gossip
just for the sake of it.
Take care.
I'll be back. Don't worry.
Let's go.
God bless.
Jasio left for his studies?
He'll be back soon enough.
I shouldn't worry.
He's off to the seminary
to become a priest.
You've brought me some herbs.
Thank you.
Give your mother our blessings.
The priest talks so well of her.
Such a wise woman.
Wait, I'll give you something
for these.
Mother said there's no need.
Don't be silly. I insist.
Poor thing. His wing is broken.
Will you take him, Jagna?
I can't. Father would
get rid of him for sure.
Take Storky.
I'll cure him before spring.
I'll feed him and everything.
Take him.
Do take him, Jagna.
Maybe I could find room
somewhere in the barn.
Hatching some plan, are you?
Antek, don't tell Father.
Why would I, Jozka?
Go home.
Father's looking for you.
You really want to keep
this scrawny thing?
I really do.
Have you heard?
The squire's driving everyone's
livestock out of Wolf's Hollow.
All that land! He begrudges us
our grazing rights.
They say your son-in-law
means to take you to court.
That damned blacksmith.
Running amok, the lot of them.
Coveting what's mine.
They might back off
if you were to marry again.
I won't take just any girl.
Throw in some land
and even the very best
won't hold back.
For land, they run
like sows to a trough.
Are men any different?
Always sniffing around
for a dowry, like dogs.
Only...
Look, it's Boryna.
They say the squire
wants to sell Wolf's Hollow.
He can want all he likes,
but we have wood gathering
and grazing rights there.
Sue him then.
Who has time for the courts
when there's so much work
to do before winter?
True. The burdens we bear.
Potatoes! Cheap potatoes!
Three notes.
If anyone has a pot with a hole,
come to me.
Boots with laces. Red and black.
And greased with fat.
It looks good on you.
How much?
Three notes.
I'll take it.
You'd make a fine farm boy.
Or not.
Oh, well.
I'd hire you in an instant.
I'd be too expensive.
For some,
but not for me.
And I wouldn't work
in the fields.
I'd do all the work for you.
Jagna.
Take this.
I bought it for you.
Pure silk.
I can't.
Take it, Jagna.
And if some boy
brings you vodka,
don't drink it...
Why the rush?
I said seven.
Six and a half.
It's all blighted.
Your face will be blighted after
I punch it. The wheat's pure.
People say
I should take you to court.
Go ahead!
Give Magda the land
that is rightfully hers.
I won't take it to the grave
with me.
But as long as I breathe,
I won't give up a single acre.
Then pay us the value
of those two acres.
Enough.
A man has a need for money
when he's on the lookout
for a new wife.
Yeah, sure.
If I choose to, I'll marry.
Any objections?
Objections? No, but...
I might even
send vodka tomorrow.
Do it. Why would I mind?
But give us the calf at least,
Rosey's calf,
and I'll help you.
You'll help. Sure you will.
Jambrozy!
Come, drink with us.
What are you
thinking about, Jagna?
Nothing much.
How's the stork? Better?
He's better, thank you.
I'd like to hang
onto those clouds
and float far away with them.
I'd go with you.
Would you like that?
An owl sits in the grove
And listens to people talk
Day by day, night by night
There was hunger
There was passion
And listens to people talk
There were two people
And both were young
Day by day, night by night
There was hunger
There was passion
And both were young
And from their whispers
Came a...
Shut it!
Sounds like you're being
skinned alive.
Came a child!
Day by day, night by night
There was hunger
There was passion
And there came a child!
There were two people
And both were young
Day by day, night by night
There was hunger
There was passion
And both were young
And from their whispers...
Did you hear that Walek
is sending vodka
to Ala Paciotkowa tomorrow?
Is she already old enough?
She's got so much land
that boys are in a hurry.
They'll line up for you too
for sure.
Only if your daddy doesn't spend
your dowry on a new wife first.
Stop spouting nonsense.
He buried Mother in the spring.
What does that matter to a man?
Every man is a pig,
always ready to thrust his snout
into a fresh trough.
Come on, Jagna!
I'm soaked to the bone.
If you run into Antek,
tell him to hurry.
- Hail Mary, full of grace...
- Hurry! Let's hurry!
Move, come on.
Come on, girl! Come on!
Go! Move your ass!
Jagna!
You shouldn't have loaded
so much for one horse.
I'm not doing two trips
in this weather.
We'll push on three.
One, two, three!
Come on! Move!
Go on! A little more!
You're clear now, Szymek!
Thank you, Antek.
God be with you!
- Jagna!
- You go on!
Hanka is waiting for you.
I'll walk you
to the mill, Jagna.
The water
has caused a breach there.
It got so dark, hasn't it?
Are you afraid?
Why would I be?
Will you come
to the cabbage party tomorrow?
Go now.
They are waiting for you.
Will you come?
I will.
Hey! Off with you!
- Ala and Walek got engaged.
- Really?
She'll be a beautiful bride.
She bought such pretty ribbons
at the market.
Beautiful for a day.
Until they chop off her braids
at the unveiling.
Then the guy
will get a surprise!
Jagustynka, never a nice word
for anyone.
I'm just telling it how it is.
We all have to go through that.
Let's have them.
Colorful as a flowery meadow.
The girls are all dressed up,
like for a wedding.
Planning on marrying cabbages,
are you, girls?
Did you know Mateusz is back?
He alone built the counselor's
house in six months.
He built us a new henhouse
in one day.
He's a skilled craftsman.
Skilled indeed.
I bet he'll be able to make
something new pop out
in the village in nine months.
Lukasz! Play some music!
Well, ladies, all this work
must be making you thirsty.
Jagusia, some bread and lard.
- Give me some.
- For you, and for you.
I don't like the taste of vodka.
One for you, Jagustynka.
Cheers!
Bravo!
- Bravo, musicians!
- Bravo!
Thank you for the hospitality,
but I have to run now.
You didn't even eat anything.
Mother's expecting me.
- God be with you.
That one's like me.
Flying away before the others.
No.
This one's like you.
So bulky
he might fall out of the sky.
And then he'd crash
on some pretty girl below.
This is you.
I'm like dirt to you?
No...
You are like the holy soil
that brings life.
You bring life to me.
Yes! Come in!
Praised be.
Mind you, an important man
has come to see you.
I'm listening.
You're a wise woman, so you know
that sooner or later, Jagna...
has to leave her home.
I am bringing this
from the village's top farmer.
Shall we drink to that, Mother?
Drink away, but you haven't
told us who the man is.
Who?
Why, Boryna himself.
An old widower!
Old? He recently went to court
for a paternity case!
True...
- Except it wasn't his.
- Of course it wasn't.
A farmer like him
with a wench like that?
Let's drink, Mother.
I could, but likely he'll soon
be drinking with the angels.
Then what? His children
will kick the stepmother out.
No, that's not for us.
Maciej promised
a land settlement for Jagna.
I... the mayor, swear it.
Well...
We'll think about it.
Drink, Jagna.
Drink.
We've got you a man...
as solid as an oak.
You'll be the first lady
of the village.
Drink up.
I said, drink.
Drink, Jagna.
- Jagna!
- Leave her, Mother.
I've told you, Mateusz.
You did, you did...
What did you tell me?
To leave me alone.
I just want to talk to you.
Be quick. I have work to do.
Your mother wants to sell you.
Like selling a heifer
on market day.
You'll go with the old man?
If she tells me to, I will.
Do I have a choice?
You do!
Just tell her... what you want.
Sure. That's easy
for you to say.
Jagna.
- Back from your travels already?
- I'm back, Mother.
Your mother was a bitch.
There's nothing for you here.
I've come to see Jagna, not you.
Stay away from Jagna,
do you hear?
She's been maligned
in the village because of you.
I'll leave her those three acres
next to Michal's land.
Her late father left her five,
and one in the forest.
Match that and give her six.
What?
The land by the road is better,
where you grow potatoes.
Those are my best fields!
And isn't Jagna
the best girl in the village?
I suppose.
But six acres? To most people
that's a lot of land.
No one will take it
as long as you live,
and remember, the fields
from her father will be yours.
You can sow them immediately.
To you, farmer!
Thank you, my friends!
Cheers!
Play some music!
Jagusia is moving in!
My dear. Sit down.
Don't worry, Jagna!
You'll like it here with me.
Better than staying
with your mother.
You're on Father's side.
I'm on the side of order.
Paid you off well, has he?
Not from your pocket.
From my pocket, damn it, mine!
You've taken enough,
so you're not bothered.
And the calf he just gave you?
Is that nothing?
- You could have taken it too.
- I'm not a thief.
Calling me a thief?
Hey, hey!
I'm a public official.
Easy, Antek, or you'll be sorry.
You're nothing but a drunk.
A Judas and an embezzler.
I bet he paid you both well
to be on his side!
It seems to me, Antek...
that it's not the land
that's bugging you.
What then?
You've been chasing
after Jagna...
so now you're moody.
Let go of him.
Antek.
And on the second day,
when all the people had left,
and the Blessed Virgin,
and the Holy Apostles were gone,
only the little dog remained.
And he sat, and howled...
Do you ever shut up?
Why are you
jumping down her throat?
Cheers!
Cheers.
You've signed over
a whole six acres to Jagna.
Because I chose to.
And if I choose, I can sign over
everything to her.
You could,
if it belonged only to you.
Who else does it belong to?
Who else? Tell me.
It's ours.
You fool. The land is mine.
And I'll do
whatever I want with it.
You can't take what's ours.
Listen to her!
Brought us three acres of sand,
and now she talks back to me.
If your lot is so bad here,
go find something better.
We're not going anywhere.
Our land is here.
Give it to her if you want to,
but divide the rest
among your children.
Antek, Magda and Jozka.
Look at her.
Now she's dividing up my land.
We only want what's just!
You'll find justice
at the end of my stick.
Lift a finger against her
and you won't live
to see your wedding day.
Six of our best acres
signed over to her.
Mother's clothing,
her beads, everything!
And for whom?
For whom? For that dirty sow!
- What did you say?
- She's a dirty whore...
and the entire village knows it.
The whole world even!
Don't you dare,
or I'll beat your foul mouth
to a pulp!
I'll say it too.
Your Jagna is a common whore.
You hear me?
Whoever wanted her, had her.
Stop this!
Antek!
For God's sake, men! Stop!
Enough!
A worthless bitch.
You're just too old to realize
that you've paid more
than others would.
Leave.
Come sunrise,
I don't want to see you here.
Why so gloomy?
Don't be like this with Boryna.
Be soft, be gentle...
He might gift you more land
or toss a pretty coin your way.
I don't care about money.
There must be something
more important.
Have you no fear of God?
Foolish girl.
Look. Look!
Your settlement from Boryna,
six acres of pure soil.
Do you think that you'd be happy
without that holy soil?
God did not create you
to be poor. No!
Love comes and goes...
but land remains.
She let her golden hair down
Welcome! Drink people, drink!
Drink, my dears!
Her golden hair
She let her golden hair down
Don't let me go
Please, Mum
Let me stay
How can I, my dear child
Not let you go?
A good man
Came to claim you
To be his wife
A good man
Came to claim you
To be his wife
In the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Eat something.
Look at her. A grand lady.
She's the first lady
of Lipce now,
and she sits there
as if she's at a funeral.
She's overwhelmed.
She's a beauty though.
I'll give her that.
Why wouldn't she be?
All she does is sleep and eat.
And lie behind every bush
with anyone in trousers.
Zoska, in the name
of the Holy Virgin.
This is no place
for such gossip.
They'll last till spring.
Then she'll get bored
and start chasing farmhands.
Her mother was the same.
Jagustynka.
Aren't I right?
She prays away now
because she's wrinkled
as a potato after winter.
But in her youth, she'd fall
on her knees for other reasons.
Now she'll feel at home.
And help herself
to Mother's things.
- Cheers!
- We'll fight for what's ours.
- One, two...
Go on, dance.
Beautiful!
Look, Mother.
Our Jagna looks beautiful.
- Pour!
- More!
So beautiful!
There's never been
a wedding like this in Lipce,
nor will there ever be again.
Jagna, my beauty!
- I have to rejoin the guests!
- What a hostess.
Drink, young lady!
- Bottoms up!
- Cheers!
Bottoms up!
Cheers! Bottoms up!
Come on! Come on, follow me!
Come on, follow me!
Come with me!
I hear they are hiring
at the mill.
I told you already.
I won't work
for the peasants here.
Maybe... I could work there.
Don't be silly, Dad.
Antek, we're living
on potatoes and salt.
I won't work in Lipce.
It's been more than three weeks
since anyone's spoken to me.
You fought with your father.
Don't other men
fight with their fathers?
Maybe, but you're the only one
whose father is Boryna.
Let them spit on me.
You want that?
It's not about what I want,
it's about what we need!
And the old man.
He boils milk for her,
makes her tea,
and brings it to her bed.
He waits on her hand and foot,
but Jagna will go back
to her old ways soon enough.
I heard that she's frisky
toward her stepson.
Nah! All the gossip about them
knowing each other is not true.
I heard that he'd whine
at her door
and she had to chase him off
with a broom.
Many a time
she complained to me.
Wasn't I in her bedroom
more than once?
You're not the first
nor the last to do so.
You're lying.
What did you say?
You're lying, you scum.
Boys!
Stop!
Antek!
Mateusz!
Jesus, he's gone
straight under the wheels.
I'll do the same thing to anyone
else who bothers Jagna.
Mateusz! He's alive?
He's alive. He's alive!
Beautiful!
It's not.
Witek, is the stove hot yet?
I'll bring more wood.
Close the door!
The cold is getting in!
Master Jasio!
Praised be Jesus Christ!
Forever and ever.
I bring the altar breads.
Welcome, Jasio!
Good day.
Back from school already?
Since Sunday, three days ago.
What's new?
Everything is quiet
with us peasants, as usual.
Quiet? What about your wedding?
It was so much fun
that people kept dancing
for three days.
Look at Jagna's cutouts.
Very beautiful.
Truly.
- I ran into Antek.
- Oh, yes?
He's grown so thin.
He looked weary.
Weary indeed.
He wore himself out...
while breaking Mateusz's ribs.
Thank you for your hospitality.
And... Merry Christmas.
Goodbye, Jasio.
God be with you, Jasio.
What happened?
Why were they fighting?
Why, over you, of course.
Like dogs fighting
over a bitch in heat.
You're lying.
I'm telling the truth! Mateusz
was boasting to the peasants
that he spent time
in your bedroom.
So Antek
almost beat him to death.
Don't you worry, dear.
Antek will fight
against the whole world for you.
Maciej, did you see what we
sent you with the farmhand?
Ah, yes. Fine work, Michal.
Thank you.
I see you're wearing
Mother's hat.
It suits you.
Let's go.
Jagna, come to the meadow
one day.
- I have a husband.
- Yes, you do. My father.
Can you change that?
Easy... I come in peace.
You shamed me
in front of the whole world.
You beat me so badly
they even summoned the priest.
But I am not holding a grudge.
Why were you lying to the men?
I only said those things
because I was angry...
Who am I to Jagna?
Welcome!
- Welcome!
- Praised be.
Praised be.
Are they in the alcove?
Come, Jagna.
Forget about it
while you still can.
How can I,
when it runs through my bones
like fire?
I know how it feels.
Didn't I go after her myself?
But she preferred you.
The squire had no right.
Yet, he's sold logging rights
in Wolf Hollow!
Lipce has always
had rights there.
He owns the wood.
But we will seek a compromise.
What compromise?
The forest is already sold.
They marked the trees
and will start cutting them.
Let them mark them.
We won't let him cut them down.
We won't let him.
I wait every day.
You think I can leave?
They watch me.
Play the volta, boys!
And make it lively!
I was only...
I was only dancing.
He'll weep someday...
- Move.
- I was only dancing!
- Move!
- Leave me!
Stupid.
Decorates the house,
but she can't see the dirt.
That's because it's clean.
Has the illness
got to your eyes?
I swear, when I get up,
you'll regret it.
Shush, Jagna!
Go and see if Jozka needs help.
Come on, it's not her fault.
Whose fault is it then?
You left her to go drinking
in the back room.
The music was playing,
everyone was having fun dancing.
What was she meant to do?
Stand in a corner
like some old maid?
Just cure me
and don't give me life lessons.
I know well enough.
Hanka?
Hanka!
For the love of God, Hanka!
Stop by some time.
Even tomorrow.
You drove us out.
So how could I come to see you?
I can't let you
and my grandchildren starve.
Go!
In the cherry orchard
Walked a pretty girl
Searching for her lost innocence
It's the revelers!
The revelers are here!
Fire... Fire!
Fire.
Fire!
People, fire!
Jagna's apron.
Give it to me. Keep working.
They say that Boryna
caught them in the hay
and that's
when the fire started.
Antek did it, for sure,
out of spite.
Did you see it?
Did you see him light it?
Then what are you
blabbering for?
I heard the old man
beat her so badly
that she's still lying ill.
I said it would end like this.
That's enough. Quiet.
I see you've been begging.
Since we live like beggars,
I seek compassion elsewhere.
You have no shame.
Is it from Father?
I told you not to go to him,
damn it.
He invited me, so I went.
The children and I won't starve
because you don't care.
Take it back now.
I don't need anything from him.
But the children do,
and so do I!
Take it back or I'll take it
and shove it down his throat!
He can choke on his charity.
I dare you!
Touch it and you'll see!
He bought you cheap.
With a crust of bread...
like a stray dog.
You've sold us even cheaper,
for a scrap of Jagna's skirt.
Go on! Run to your bitch!
Lipce must fight.
They took our wood today.
If we don't defend ourselves,
they'll come for our land next.
Our homes,
everything that we own.
Slaves of the squire or Boryna,
what's the difference?
Goodness, stop this nonsense.
It's no wonder
he's punishing you now.
He's made of flesh and blood,
not paper like your cutouts.
He's your husband.
I did not choose him.
Do you love me?
Haven't I said so?
Because I don't come
every time you call?
You love me indeed.
Like some mad dog that can bite
and you can't shake off!
I have to go now.
If I've gone mad,
it is because of you.
Because I loved you.
You understand?
You love me?
You only take it out on me.
What?
You need another man already?
You think I ever wanted you?
Boryna's farmhand?
People, we have suffered
an injustice.
An injustice we cannot tolerate.
We have rights in Wolf's Hollow.
The forest is ours
and the squire is cutting it.
We complained in vain.
We took the squire to the court.
Justice was denied to us.
But enough is enough.
They are cutting down our wood!
- Are we going to let them?
- No!
We must defend what's ours.
Look, it's a mob.
Fetch the horsemen.
Don't be afraid, people.
It's our right,
our will, our justice.
All together, people.
Follow me, people!
To the forest!
Don't just stand there! Attack!
Jagustynka, take the women
and smash their shacks.
How many times do we have to...
Traitors!
Horsemen!
Watch out, men!
Come on, men!
Rally round, don't give up!
Son of a bitch.
Get the horses!
Boryna!
Jesus!
- Is he dead?
- Is he breathing?
Father.
Show me Anton Boryna!
Soldiers.
Father.
Is that you, my son?
It's you...
He was defending his father.
Justice is on our side.
You're all... under arrest!
Us? Arrest them!
Take everyone except women!
Father. I'm sorry...
Stand up.
- You're coming with me.
- Maciej, no...
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be Thy name,
Thy kingdom come.
Thy will be done on earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us this day our daily bread
and forgive us our trespasses
as we forgive those
who trespass against us.
I thought only peasants
are up at this hour.
Blacksmiths don't need
to get up at dawn.
With Father ill, and Antek
and the rest in jail...
I thought I'd check in on you.
No need, thanks.
I'm keeping my eye on things,
as Father asked.
Four eyes can see more than two.
I'll wait until Jagna's up.
Wait all you want.
Get out, Hanka.
Quiet. There's a sick man here.
Not that you care.
He could be starving to death
and you wouldn't lift a finger,
heiress.
My husband is my business,
not yours.
The whole farm would go to ruin
if you were to run things.
That's why Father
put me in charge.
And go feed
that whining cow of yours.
Has he said anything?
Jesus, Michal.
Sorry, Jagna.
I didn't mean to scare you.
I came to see
how Father is doing.
Did he say anything?
No.
The organist told me
that Father has a lot of money.
He probably hid it
in the storeroom.
Let's split the money evenly
before Hanka steals everything.
Just give me the key, Jagna.
Hanka has the keys now.
Don't turn your back on me
when I'm talking to you.
You're running errands now?
It'd probably
be easier for you...
if they let Antek out?
I can make inquiries.
I have influence.
Come.
Sit down with me.
We'll figure it out.
If you have such influence,
why are the men still in jail?
- For defending what's theirs?
- Don't get upset, Jagna.
I am on your side.
I can help Antek.
Keep cranking.
Hanka!
Why are you yelling?
You hung that thing over my bed.
- That was the only place for it.
- Isn't it convenient for you?
If you get hungry,
you can rip a piece off,
since you always take
what others worked for.
Let her go
if she wants to fight.
I dare you.
I'll scratch that pretty face
so even your own mother
won't recognize you.
Hanka!
Hanka...
throw them out.
Are you in pain?
Throw them all out.
Come, come, now.
In the storeroom. In the wheat.
Inside the wheat barrel...
you'll find some money. Hide it!
So they don't take it from you.
Save Antek.
Don't let them take it.
It's yours.
All yours.
You said you could help Antek.
All in good time.
Come, Jagna, come.
Let's rest here.
- Look!
- There's nothing to see here.
Come here, Jagna. Come now...
I'm sorry. I got carried away.
Touch me again, you pig,
and I'll tell everyone.
Tell them...
As if anyone would believe you.
Per eundem Christum,
Dominum nostrum.
Amen.
O, happy day is upon us
Our prayers were not in vain
For Christ has risen today
Hallelujah, hallelujah!
Heavenly King we praise
Yearn for His beauty and grace
For He has conquered death
Hallelujah, hallelujah!
Come, farmer.
Farmer.
Time to sow.
Time to sow...
Time to...
sow...
Dear God, giver of salvation
and forgiveness.
We ask for your mercy
to take Boryna, your servant.
By the grace of the Virgin Mary
and all the Saints.
To you, with eternal blessing.
For Jesus Christ,
our Lord. Amen.
Come to me.
So, what's new, Hanka?
Everything is as usual.
Plenty of work to be done.
As usual?
You took Father's money?
You would steal it, so you think
everyone is like you?
What you've stolen is yours.
But the land must be divided.
I won't give it up.
I'm just minding
my husband's property.
I have no rights here.
Now that Father's dead,
Antek is in charge.
It's all up to him.
In charge
of his prison cell maybe.
But honest people
will make the decisions here.
"Honest." Look at him.
You only want to grab
as much as you can.
Oh, poor little thing.
Sitting on six acres of
our finest land, looking pretty.
You're right, Hanka.
Let's wait...
for Antek to return.
He can take it up
with this harlot.
I wish I'd broken my legs
before I entered this house.
No one's tied you down.
You were free to leave anytime.
Don't complain
after what I've suffered.
What have I done?
Have I stolen anything?
Killed somebody?
You went after him
like a bitch in heat
when you knew he had a family.
I went after him, did I?
You don't see his faults?
How he'd stand by my door
even to get
a glimpse of my shoe.
It was he who befuddled me
and did as he pleased.
You want to know the truth?
However, you may regret it.
If I wanted, he'd kick you out
and follow me anywhere,
no matter what you do.
Don't you dare
compare yourself to me.
Get out of this house now!
Get out!
Don't let Antek
turn away from us again.
Here. Is this what you want?
Take it then and I hope
you choke on it to death!
Jagna.
Don't touch me.
Say what you wanted
to say to me.
Don't be afraid of me, Jagna.
I hardly recognize you.
I'm the same person
I was when you left me.
I never left you.
I've been thinking about you
day and night.
Maybe you had
something else on your mind?
Yes, I did. I was thinking
about how you disgraced me.
How I disgraced you?
Did I ask you
to become my stepmother?
Did I force you
to fool around with the mayor?
Jagna, would you
run away with me?
Antek, no!
An owl sits in the grove
And listens to people talk
Day by day, night by night
There was hunger
There was passion
And listens to people talk
What a drought.
We were so worried about you.
Luckily, Hanka bailed you out.
Worried, were you?
Of course.
You are the first farmer now.
Two sacks for you, ma'am.
Hanka?
How easily the inheritance
passed on to you.
You only need to kick Jozka out
and all will be yours.
Got your eye on Jagna already?
She's just become a widow.
It's not that. Just saying Hanka
had no right to kick her out.
- It was Jagna's home.
- It wasn't.
It's back where it belongs,
with the family.
Are you sure?
Her mother has filed
Jagna's claim at court.
They'll get her property back.
We'll see.
Jagna.
People are complaining
about you in the village.
Let them bark.
They're hot and moody
and it makes them angry.
You know...
The men... are already
lining up to bring you vodka.
Let them drink it themselves.
Not all men are alike.
Maybe it would...
help you in the village...
if you chose someone.
It'd stop people's tongues
from wagging.
I don't need help from men.
I've had enough
of their help already.
Jagna, my dear child.
Haven't you slept?
Why did you reject Mateusz?
He's a good carpenter.
Wasn't that Jesus's profession?
He has his past,
but so do you now.
I don't want Mateusz.
I don't want any man.
Don't talk like that!
You need to go to confession.
You can do penance
and with time,
people will forgive you.
I won't go to confession.
Fear the Lord, child.
Praise be to God.
Praise be, Hanka.
I'm going on a pilgrimage.
Please forgive me for any sins
I committed against you.
God bless you
for your kind words.
But what's done is done.
I ask you from my heart
for forgiveness.
I don't hold a grudge
in my heart.
I'll pray for you.
Jagna?
Don't you recognize me?
How could I not recognize you?
It's just that you look
so elegant now, so different.
You're coming back
from your travels.
Right now, I came here
from home to get some peace.
- And you?
- Just wandering around.
Is that a holy book?
No, it's about
faraway countries and oceans.
Jesus! About oceans!
Have a look!
Look.
See this pyramid?
It's taller
than five of our churches
stacked on top of each other.
It must be like a mountain.
And what are these?
They look like my cutouts.
I saw your beautiful cutouts
when I visited you at Christmas.
Not even in the Warsaw markets
have I seen cutouts
as beautiful.
They've been looking for you,
Master Jasio!
- All over the village.
- I better go.
Interrupted your prayers,
have I?
Goodbye.
A secluded place,
far from people's eyes.
May your foul tongue shrivel.
So I rush off to look for him,
I look around, and...
Excuse me, Jasio lost his book.
What a nerve.
Get away from here.
Never show your face here again!
I'll not shed tears
because of you,
like Hanka
and the mayor's wife did.
I'll teach you not to flirt.
You'll remember me, you hussy.
Go to your kennel, bitch!
I heard that Jagna
is now after the organist's son.
Has your time in prison made you
hungry for gossip?
I'm only repeating what I heard.
Tell me who said so,
and I'll set them straight.
I won't give a single zloty!
Five thousand is missing
from the district's treasury.
They're taking
the whole farm from them.
And if that wasn't enough,
Lipce has to pay for the rest!
I'm not going to pay anything!
People!
Don't you know
how the mayor spent this money?
- On Jagna.
- That's right! Of course!
That's twiddle-twaddle.
You saw that, did you?
You think I don't know?
You think I'm not ashamed
- to have a whore in the family?
- Do something.
True, she is a debauchee.
I will not pay for her.
She bewitched my man.
He'd buy her anything.
Everyone saw it!
Where did she get those dresses?
Because she was Boryna's wife!
She got all the fancy clothes
from him!
What do you care?
Why are you on her side?
Mother of God, save us.
She even tried
to seduce my Jasio.
Oh, my!
The innocent boy ran
and told me everything.
That's horrible.
Not even a priest is safe!
Look at the poor harvest
we've had.
Surely, a whore like that
has brought God's wrath
upon the village.
- It's all her fault.
- Time to end it.
There's only one way.
Banish her.
Exactly!
That's how it must be.
Everyone has agreed to banish
Jagna from the village.
Yeah, banish her.
Say your piece, Antoni.
Banish her. That's right.
Well, Antoni,
we're all listening.
With your father gone,
you're our first farmer now.
We can't decide without you.
Quiet now.
Quiet.
I live in this village
and I stand with its people.
You want to expel her,
then do so.
You want to put her
on the altar? Then do that.
It is all the same to me.
So, we banish her.
Antek!
Now we must sort this out.
You know
what they'll do to Jagna.
The law... is on their side.
To hell with the law.
What they're accusing her of...
it's not true.
Will you stand
against the whole village?
- Are you on their side?
- I'm on no one's side.
But I care for her as much
as I care for dirt.
Jesus!
That you should...
dare to kick out
a person like...
a rabid dog.
Antek!
Your word means something.
It's too late.
Mother, the whole village
is coming for her!
Quick! Close the door.
Take her away!
Hide!
I won't hide from anyone.
- What are you doing?
- Take it.
Together, men! One, two, three!
Hold it!
Jagna! Jagna!
People! People! Move back...
What are you doing here?
What are you doing...
- Leave Jagna alone!
- Out the way, Mother!
Mother!
- Grab her!
- Yes!
Take her!
Come here!
You'll pay for everything.
You'll pay, you whore.
Whore!
What now, hussy?
Not so pretty anymore.
- Right in that painted face!
- Take her out!
You've had your fun?
Shame on you now!
Take her to the soldiers!
Feel the same shame
you made us feel!
The holy ground
would spit you out!
The bitch deserves it.
Go to hell, slut!
Get her down! Bitch!
Get her on the cart!
Tie her up!
That's enough!
Come back to the village
and we'll set the dogs on you.