(Clock ticking)
(indistinct)
(Horse neighing)
(Sighs)
(Flies buzzing)
- All right. Off you go.
- (Girl) Happy Christmas, teacher!
- Happy New Year.
- Thank you, Dave.
Give my love
to your girlfriend in Sydney, sir.
I'll do that, sir, thank you.
Have a happy holiday, sir.
And you, Chris, thank you.
Enjoy yourself.
- For your collection, sir.
- Thank you very much, Lou.
Bye-bye.
S0 I'll see you next year, mate.
(Sighs)
(Charlie) Shut up!
(Flies buzzing)
A middy, please, Charlie.
Having one yourself?
Yeah.
You've, uh...
got snakes in your pocket,
have you?
(Chuckles)
(Coins rattling)
Mmm...
Keys.
Will you be wanting your room
when you come back?
Where else would I stay?
(Chuckles)
But if you get a flood of tourists
0r anything, Charlie,
I can always stay
in the schoolhouse.
(Chuckles)
(Parrots squawking)
(Train horn sounding)
See you in six weeks, huh?
Not if I can rob a bank.
- Sure, Ned Kelly.
- Mmm.
(Train horn sounding)
- (Charlie) See you, then.
- Uh-huh.
(Chuckles)
(Door closes)
(I Passengers singing)
(I Passenger playing harmonica)
Excuse me, please.
- Oi, fella, come and have a beer with us.
- N0. N0, thanks.
Come on,
come and have a beer.
(Train horn sounding)
(I Passengers singing drunkenly)
(Children shouting)
(I Drunken singing continues)
(I Quietly singing along)
New to the Yabba?
Yes.
Staying W18?
N0, just tonight.
Oh, that's hard luck.
Want to see a bit more
of the Yabba than that.
You think it's worth seeing?
(Chuckles)
It's the best place in Australia.
- Everybody likes the Yabba.
- (John) Why?
(Driver)
Well, it's a friendly place.
Nobody worries who you are
0r where you come from.
You're a good bloke,
you're all right.
You know what I mean?
(Exhales)
Excuse me.
D0 you have a room for John Grant?
I made a booking by letter.
Oh, I'm only staying the night.
I'm flying to Sydney in the morning.
You have to pay now.
I think we can manage that.
It'll be $4.
There's $1 deposit on the keys.
You'll get that back
when you bring the keys back.
Thank you.
Could you tell me
where room seven is, please?
Up the steps and down the corridor
to the right.
(People clamouring)
Hey. Shut it, mate.
We're closed.
Excuse me.
(I Men singing drunkenly)
You're new to the Yabba?
Well, I just dropped in for the night.
I'm flying to Sydney in the morning.
Uh-huh.
- Come far?
- Tiboonda.
Ah, nice little place.
D0 you like it?
Paradise on Earth.
Yeah.
What do you do out there?
Oh, I'm a bonded slave
of the Education Department.
I'm a school teacher.
Oh, yes.
You took over from old Murchison,
didn't you?
McDonald, his name is.
Of course.
And you're, uh...
- Grant.
- Yeah, that's right.
Well, I'll be blown.
Crawford's the name.
Jock Crawford.
- John Grant.
- I'm pleased to know you, Jack.
What about another beer?
Thanks, Mr Crawford.
- Here you are, Jack.
- Thanks.
You, uh...
You say you're a slave.
What do you mean by that?
You wouldn't know
how our educational authorities
get teachers for the outback?
Wouldn't have a clue, mate.
Now, a new teacher
has to post a bond for $1,000.
That 1,000 guarantees
you'll serve out your contract
wherever they send you.
Oh, well. I suppose
they know what they're doing.
You clever blokes never like to stop
in the one spot long, do you?
- Depends on the place.
- (Laughs) Yeah, that's right.
Well, never mind, Jack.
You can always come to the Yabba
for your holidays.
Good luck.
Yes, that's something
to look forward to.
N0, thanks,
I'll be running along.
Police have much to do
in Bundanyabba?
N0. N0, not really.
We sort of...
We just sort of
keep an eye on things.
Honestest little town in Australia,
this is, mate.
But, mind you,
there are not too many game enough
to try anything around here.
You see, we're so isolated,
there's nowhere to go.
We get 'em, and quick.
Sounds like an easy life.
Yeah, not bad.
Of course,
we do have a few suicides.
Yeah?
Yeah. Yeah,
they reckon it's the heat.
Me... (Laughs)
I like the heat.
Yeah, it's one way
of getting out of town.
What is?
Killing yourself.
Hey, that's good.
I like a bloke with a sense of humour.
(Laughs)
Oh... Killing yourself.
Two more, Kate.
(I Band playing
"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer")
Have you ever been
anywhere else?
Yeah. Did three months'
training in the city.
Didn't like it.
A couple more?
Here, give us your dough.
I'll get 'em quicker than you.
IThen one foggy Christmas Eve
ISanta came to say
lRudolph,
with your nose so bright
IWOn't you guide
my sleigh tonight?
IThen all the reindeer
loved him... J'
(People cheering)
Here you are.
I slung your change to the steward.
Told him it was yours.
D0 you a bit of good
when you come back again.
(Chattering stops)
Get up, get UP-
(Man on loudspeaker)
'Ladies and gentlemen,
'let us pay a tribute
to our fallen comrades.
'They shall grow not old,
as we that are left grow old.
'Age shall not weary them,
nor the years condemn.
'At the going down of the sun,
and in the morning,
'we will remember them.'
(All) We will remember them.
'Lest we forget.'
(All) Lest we forget.
'Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.'
(Chattering resumes)
N0, as long as they close
before the show, they're shut...
(Laughing)
Come on,
the beer's real good here.
Oh, no, Jock.
N0, I'll pass out if I don't eat soon.
Well, it's easy to see
you're not a Yabba man.
A Yabba man!
A Yabba man...
You're the Yabba man, Jock.
The Bundanyabba man.
(Laughing)
All right, all right.
Come on, I'll show you
where you can get a real good steak.
(Jock) This is a mate of mine, John Grant.
You can let him in anytime.
He's all right.
(Man) How's it going there, Jock?
(Jock) Oh, not too bad, Jim.
- How's it with you?
- Great.
Hey, Joe.
Put a steak on for me mate, will you?
Yeah, lovely.
Hey, Tim. One steak, mate.
- Oh, rare, please.
- Yeah, all right.
How's the missus?
Oh, she was a bit crook last week.
She all right now, Jock.
- And the kid?
- Oh, this kid's gold.
You tell him to stop missing school
or I'll have you.
All right, mate.
Come on, I'll show you inside
while we're waiting.
All right.
Biggest two-up game
in Australia, Jack.
(People chattering)
Right on, fellas.
I want 100 in the middle.
- The spinner's the bloke with the kip.
- Kip?
Yeah, the bit of wood
they put the pennies on.
He's just dropped
$100 in the centre.
That's got to be covered
before they can spin 'em.
Now it's been covered,
they can all get in for a side bet.
(All clamouring)
- Heads, heads, heads...
- Tails. Tails.
- Who wants to go on the heads?
- (Man) Put 50 on heads.
You know, the little fella with the kip's
a fella named Charlie Jones.
Comes in here every Friday night
with his pay packet.
Bets are closing.
Clear a space.
Quiet! Hey!
(Shushes)
Settle down, settle down.
What do you think it is?
(Man) Fair go, chaps.
- Heads!
- (All clamouring)
D0 you get the idea now, Jack?
Well, you just bet on whether
the pennies come down heads 0r tails.
Yeah, that's right.
(Scoffs) You think this crowd will be
at each 0ther's throats when they settle?
Ah, there's hardly a fight.
Each man knows what's coming to him,
he just goes and gets it.
Heads, heads, heads...
Tails, tails, tails...
- (indistinct)
- Sixty on tails...
(Whispering)
(Shushes) Fair go.
Watch your feet now.
Watch yourself there.
Wait for it.
Wait for it now.
(Man) Heads!
(All clamouring)
Four hundred, Charlie,
what do you wanna do?
Put the lot on.
Yeah, Charlie always goes
for 8000r bust.
You gotta throw
four heads in a row to do it, too.
(Man) Come on now, hurry up.
Get 'em on.
And what does he do
with the winnings?
Well, nothing.
(Controller) Simmer down, boys.
Settle down.
(Man) Put 'em on, Charlie, now, come on.
(Controller) When you're ready, Charles.
(Man) When you're ready.
(Controller) Fair go.
Fair go.
(Controller) Heads.
(Man) Beauty, Charlie.
You're casting
a spell around here.
There's a nice
simple-minded game.
- My steak's probably ready.
- (Jock) Yeah, come on.
Here you are.
That'll be a dollar, son.
There's a clean place here, Jack.
Oh.
Well, I'll have to be pushing along.
Oh, thanks, Jock.
Thanks for showing me around.
Oh, that's all right.
And that'll be the best dollar's worth
you'll ever have in your life, matey.
All the little devils are proud of hell.
- (Man) Two heads.
- (Crowd cheering)
D0 you mean you don't think the Yabba
is the greatest little place on Earth?
- It could be worse.
- How?
The supply of beer could run out.
Hey, aren't you going to eat that?
N0.
- Why did you say that?
- Say what?
Well, about them being proud of hell.
Discontent is a luxury
of the well-to-do.
If you gotta live here,
you might as well like it.
Why don't you like Crawford?
Jock?
The touch of his hairy hand
offends you.
I'm just bored with it.
The aggressive hospitality,
the arrogance of stupid people who insist
you should be as stupid as they are.
It's death to farm out here.
It's worse than death in the mines.
D0 you want them
to sing opera as well?
And what do you do?
Idrink.
This beer's gone warm.
- (Man) Heads.
- (Crowd clamouring)
Here you are, Doc.
Thanks, Joe.
It's a spinner's night,
nearly two-to-one on heads.
- Good on you, Doc.
- Good on you...
Mate.
You want to bet on tails, son?
Fifty for the guy in the jacket
over there, Slim.
Fair go.
When you're ready there, Brian.
N0 betting when I say fair go.
Fair go, Brian.
Fair go.
(Controller) Two tails!
(Man) Anybody seen
a bloke with a coat on?
Where's that bloke in a coat?
Here! Here.
Thought I lost you, mate.
Move over!
Sit down here, son.
How many heads up?
Heads, heads! I bet on heads.
Anyone betting 0n tails?
N0, on heads.
- Tails, 100!
- You're covered!
- A hundred for you?
- Yes.
- You're on a head.
- Any more tails?
(Controller) Will you place your bets
and take your seats?
Sorry, son.
Be quiet!
(Shushes)
When you're ready for it.
Fair go.
They're UP!
- Play for now.
- Hold it!
- Heads!
- All right.
When you're ready.
Don't forget, every Wednesday,
Thursday and Friday night!
Early start
Christmas Eve, boys!
Bring your own money,
anybody's girl.
Leaving it all on heads, mate?
Two hundred on tails.
- I'll have 100.
- You're on.
- What are you backing, mate?
- Tails.
You're set.
I'll back a head.
I'll back... You're up?
Thanks, mate.
You're too noisy!
Fair go, spinner.
When you're ready.
One of each,
which is no result.
Fair go.
Fair go!
Tails, they are!
Whoo!
(Exhales)
(Sighs)
(Books crash)
$1,000.
Just...
Just one more spin...
and you're out of it.
Out of teaching.
Out of Tiboonda.
(Clamouring)
(Controller) Toss, Terry?
Toss, Paulie? Toss?
Toss, Mal?
Who wants to toss?
Yes!
Here you are, son.
How much you tossing for?
$400 on tails.
You can't spin for tails, mate.
The spinner always spins for heads.
- Heads.
- On a head.
Four hundred, Charlie.
(Clamouring)
Watch out, imbecile!
Watch where you're going, you mug.
(Controller)
When you're right now.
Come on,
out of the ring, you blokes.
Fair go, son.
Heads.
Settle down!
N0, son. You gotta put 'em
above your head and spin it, all right?
I'm sorry.
When you're right now.
Wait for it now.
When you're right.
Fair go.
Tails, two tails.
What, still here, Jack?
- Hmm? Mmm.
- How goes it?
Well, Jock.
Look, um, will they
cash a check for me in this place?
Yeah, for how much?
Two hundred and ninety dollars.
- Gonna try the game, eh?
- Yes.
(Laughing)
- Two-ninety on heads.
- (All laughing)
Well, he's on heads now.
(indistinct)
What are you betting on, mate?
- Two-ninety on heads.
- You're on.
(Chickens clucking)
Can you... Can you tell me
where the labour exchange is?
Turn left as you go out,
second street, turn right,
next street,
turn left, it's on the right.
(Statue laughing)
(Tyres screeching)
(Horn honking)
Yeah, so I say to this mug, I said,
"You better get out.
You're barred from the pub.
"Every time you come in here,
you put on trouble."
And then, all of a sudden,
he turned it on.
I grabbed him by the scruff of the neck
and I hit him.
Done the knuckle in.
Knuckle's squished up back here.
Yeah, it's been six weeks.
All these mugs I get in here.
They want to try you out.
They all come from far and wide
to try you out.
(Man) Hot?
Hot.
- New to the Yabba?
- (Sighs)
New to the Yabba.
Like the old place?
N0, I think it's bloody awful.
- You don't like the Yabba?
- N0.
Will you have a drink?
N0, I'm toying
with this one, thanks.
Well, drink it down,
I'll buy you another.
Look, I'm flat broke
and I can't afford to drink!
What's that got to do
with it, man?
I said I'd buy you a drink!
You don't have to buy me one!
Now, drink it down!
Two middies, Keith.
Don't forget the tomato juice.
I'm Tim Hynes.
John Grant.
Hey. Good shot.
Are you a Mason?
What? N0!
You're in the Buffs.
- In the what?
- In the Buffs.
The Buffs?
Are you a member
of the Buffalo Lodge?
(Laughing) N0.
Never heard of it.
- Not a Mason, not a Buff.
- N0.
Ah, you'll be
a Roman Catholic, then.
Oh, no, I'm not.
Well, what are you going to do?
You're not a Buff?
Iam not a Buff.
Poor old John.
Well, we better
have another beer.
Hey!
I was just checking your oil.
(Laughing)
Now, come on, John.
Hey, Keith,
a couple of beers!
(Laughing)
(Tim) Well, here we are, John.
- Home, sweet home.
- (John) Uh-huh!
(Exhales)
(Grunts)
Grab yourself a seat, John,
I'll tell Janette we're here.
Janette!
Put these in the fridge, will you?
Oh, I brought a friend back,
so set another place for lunch, will you?
Oh!
(Chuckles)
How do you do?
Fine.
How are you?
I really must apologise
for landing on you like this.
Mr Hynes more 0r less insisted.
He usually does.
Oh, my name's John Grant.
I'm Janette Hynes.
Oh.
Thanks.
(Toilet flushes)
(Tim vocalising)
Over the teeth and round the gums,
look out belly, here it comes!
(Laughing)
Just a little quickie before lunch.
Lunch is ready now, Daddy.
I know.
But firstly, John and I
must have an apéritif.
(Laughing)
Ah.
John, old man,
about your troubles,
a terrible thing,
you losing all that money.
You have no idea...
N0, it was somewhere
between the train and the hotel.
Hmm.
I could put a call
through to Sydney.
N0, there's no one there
I could borrow from.
John, I'd love to lend you some...
N0, no. No, no, no.
I wouldn't, really, I'll be all right.
Ah, you're a good bloke.
We'll think of something.
Now, don't you worry, lad.
- Right.
- And drink up.
Drink up.
(Snoring)
(Horn honking)
- (Whistling)
' (Man) l say!
- (Car horn honking)
- (Banging 0n door)
- (Man shouts) Wake up, Tim!
- (Men laughing)
Well, that's... That's Dick and Joe,
couple of old mates of mine.
I want you to meet them.
Come on in, boys.
Come 0n in. (Laughing)
- Am I glad to see you!
- You look bloody awful, mate.
- I feel bloody awful! (Laughing)
- Hey!
T00 much of the old booze.
Oh, cut it out, boys, will you?
Stop it!
Hey. Let's all have a drink.
- Hey. Hey, hey, hey.
- What, what?
- Who's your mate?
- Who? Oh, he... Oh, that's John.
- This is, uh, Dick and Joe.
- You're an ignorant bludger.
- G'day.
- How are you?
- G'day, John.
- (Crushes hand)
- (Laughs)
Uh, you're new to the Yabba,
are you, John?
- Yes. Yes.
- Hmm.
(Wolf whistling)
G'day, Janette.
Pretty as ever, eh?
(Laughing)
Missed me.
Tim, I'll be moving off now.
Thanks for your hospitality.
Moving off?
Where would you be going, lad?
Well, I've...
- Well, I've gotta look for work.
- On a Saturday?
Look, why don't you just
hang around?
We'll fix you up.
Look, just drink your beer,
sit down.
Stop worrying, huh?
John's got a bit of trouble,
but nothing to worry about.
Should be all right, mate.
Drink up.
- Cheers.
Hey.
(Chuckles)
- Hey, Tim.
- Yeah?
I got news for you, mate.
What do you think?
- You got piles.
- (Laughs)
N0, no, no, no.
You know Stanley's brindle bitch?
- Yeah.
- Sold her to me. English bred.
- You're a liar.
- It's the truth.
She's got a broken leg.
I'm not ribbing you, mate,
he sold her to me.
A great dog. A great dog!
A great dog.
- Good dog.
- (Dick) Come off it, mate.
This'll be one of the best bloody dogs
I've ever seen after roos.
Eh?
(Tim) You've gotta be kidding!
- (Joe laughing)
- What makes a good dog?
Can I help you?
(Tim) S0, we let this ferret
go down the rabbit's burrow...
(John) I studied
history and literature.
And what can you do with that
if your parents are nobody
and you have no money?
Oh, I know I can teach, but...
I'd really like
to get to England.
Well, this is bad enough,
but even Sydney, it's...
(Sighs)
I'd really like
to get to England.
What would you do there?
Journalism.
- D0 you have a girl?
- Yes, in Sydney.
What's her name?
Robyn.
What's she like?
Would you take her
to England with you?
Yes.
(Tim burping)
- Ooh! Bells of St Mary's.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Yeah?
What's the matter with him?
He'd rather talk to a woman than drink?
School teacher.
Oh.
(Tim) Then we agreed, before
the game started, there was a $5 limit.
- (Laughing)
- (Joe) N0, there was no agreement, mate.
- (Dick laughing)
- (Tim) Wait, wait, was that...
Look, what's the matter with you?
(Dick) There was
no agreement made.
(Joe) G0 on, you blokes, just...
(Dick) Was there any
bloody agreement made?
(Joe) I don't know.
(Dick) N0.
(Tim) I hate to remind
you this is my house...
(All arguing at once)
(Joe) You're always
bloody interrupting.
It's got nothing to do
with whose bloody house it is.
Doc Tydon, you old bastard.
- How do you know that?
- (Laughing) Great to see you.
Hi, boys.
Have yourself a beer,
I got five aces coming up.
If you're playing cards with this lot,
you'll need a doctor before the night is out.
(Banter continues inside)
Why do you stay
in Bundanyabba?
N0, I'm surprised,
I mean, you're...
pretty and...
And there's a shortage
of pretty girls in this town.
(Sniffs)
Ah, it's beautiful. Smell that.
Peppercorn.
(Chuckles)
ls it because of your father?
Sorry.
The moonlight like snow
upon the desert's dusty face.
(Chuckles)
All right, Dicky boy,
let's hear from you.
- What've you got?
- Three jacks, mate.
Ah-ha! Well, just hold it,
hold it, hold it.
- Daddy?
- Flush.
Daddy?
John and I are going for a walk.
Well, come on, come on, come on,
get me while I'm hot, boys.
An inside showing all the time.
(Janette breathing heavily)
(Moaning)
(G ru nting)
(Retching)
(Vomiting)
(Coughs)
(Laughing)
(Doc) It's not the gravity.
It's not the gravity
that makes the beer go down.
- It's peristalsis.
- Perry who?
- Perry Mason.
- (All laughing)
Peristalsis. It's the contraction
of the muscles of the oesophagus.
Come on, Doc, get up, man!
Come on.
(Laughing)
Whoa, whoa!
(Squirting)
(Chuckles)
(Man) It'll be a week for sure.
(Tim) Hey, Doc, Doc?
Come in over here.
Look, Doc, when is she
gonna whelp, huh?
I tell you what,
I'll give you five it's a week, Joe.
Listen to the Doc.
She's not pregnant.
(Laughing)
Cut it out, Doc, come on.
When's she gonna whelp?
- Who's the father?
- (All laugh)
It's a dog, not a sheep.
(All laughing)
(Bleats)
She'll have pups by morning.
- Beauty!
- N0 way, I bet it'll be a week.
I don't feel anything.
Come on, put your money out.
Five, right?
- Five.
- You're on for five.
Let's have a second opinion.
Before morning.
- It'll be a week.
- You heard me say that.
I didn't.
Who is the father, anyway?
I don't know.
She's a slag, this little mutt,
she'd try anything.
(Laughing)
(Fly buzzing)
(G roans)
(Flies buzzing)
(I Opera music playing)
You drank yourself under the table
after your little episode with Janette.
Get out.
Don't get upset.
We've all had
our little episodes with Janette.
(I Opera music continues playing)
What a doll.
Better.
You need a drink.
Oh, no.
Water, please.
Yabba water's only for washing.
Come on, drink it up.
It's a bit flat.
Come and get it.
Oh, no, thanks very much,
but I don't... (Chuckles)
N0, I'm sure you don't.
But you'd better eat it
just the same.
Come on, sit down.
SirJohn.
Not too bad.
Kangaroo.
Want some sauce?
What time did the, um...
the, uh, party finish?
About dawn.
And what time is it now?
Round about four o'clock.
Four?
Look...
Look, uh, thanks
for the hospitality.
I'd better be going along now.
You see, I'm the school teacher
at Tiboonda.
And, um...
Well, I lost all my money.
Gambling.
Yeah, I know.
Why did you have to lie about it
to Tim Hynes?
That's no disgrace here.
Well...
Well, in any case,
I can't stay in your, um...
cabin, indefinitely, can I?
It isn't mine.
L'vejust lived here
for five years.
Anyway, you're better off here than
trying to sponge 0n men like Tim Hynes.
- Sponge?
- Yeah,sponge.
Sit down and eat your grub.
You're gonna need it.
We're going hunting
with Dick and Joe.
Kangaroo.
- Hunting?
- Yeah, you were...
(Fly buzzing)
- ...boasting in your cups, and said...
Good shot.
You said you won a silver medal at school
for target shooting.
- Huh?
- Remember?
You wouldn't have
an aspirin, would you?
N0, I've got something better.
This ought to
kill your headache
and pep you up
a little bit as well.
Wash it down
with some beer. Here.
Oh, I'm allergic to...
Ah, there's nothing in there to hurt you.
G0 on, man, swallow it down.
What a voice.
She just opens her mouth and...
And notes come floating out.
Oh, sorry,
I don't smoke.
Would you like to try it?
N0.
You've been here five years?
Shall I satisfy your curiosity?
I'm a doctor of medicine.
And a tramp by temperament.
I'm also an alcoholic.
My disease prevented me
from practising in Sydney,
but out here it's scarcely noticeable.
Certainly doesn't stop people
from coming to see me.
I charge no fees
because I'm not interested in money.
Anyway, I'm unreliable.
But I'm accepted socially
because I'm an educated man...
of character.
(Closes fridge)
I get my food from my friends.
My requirements in beer.
Which, with some measure of self-control,
is the only alcohol I allow myself.
And you get along
without money altogether.
It's possible to live forever in the Yabba
without money.
As you probably noticed,
some of the natives are very...
hospitable.
Take Janette for instance.
Now there's a very interesting
biological case.
If she were a man,
she'd be in jail for rape.
(Chuckles)
If I were to marry,
Janette's just the sort of girl...
Excuse me.
Uh, can you tell me
where the, um...
Toilet?
Yes.
Outside.
I wouldn't recommend it.
D0 it out here in the open.
(Bird chirping)
NO one around to see.
If I were ever to marry,
Janette's the sort of girl
I'd like to marry.
She likes sex.
She likes to experiment
and she likes variety.
We thought about
getting married once,
but neither of us could live
with one person for very long.
Still, she visits me
from time to time.
When I want her.
And when she gets bored
with them.
Beer?
What's wrong with a woman
taking a man because she feels like it?
- I really don't know.
- Because there's nothing wrong with it.
Sex is just like eating.
It's a thing you do
because you have to.
Not 'cause you want to,
but most people are afraid of it.
You seem offended
by my little discussion ofjanette.
In the circumstances,
I thought you'd be interested.
Well, I'm not.
You're probably a little puritan.
Like the rest of these people.
They think Janette's a slut.
The women who'd like
to act like her...
and the men
she has given a tumble to.
Janette and I are alike.
We break the rules.
But we know more
about ourselves than most people.
(Exhales)
(Horn honking)
(DiCk) Hey, Doc! Doc!
- Come on!
- Make a bit of noise, boys, will you?
- Hi, Dick.
- (Both laughing)
(Doc) Hey, Joe.
(Joe) In the back, fellas.
Get back there.
(All chattering)
Hey, John.
I got a gun here for you.
A bit old, probably
blow your head off.
(Tyres screeching)
(Man) Whoo-hoo!
Look at her go there, boys!
(Yelling)
(Gun firing)
(Laughing)
Watch out the dog
doesn't leak on you, Johnny.
(Man shouts) Roos!
G0 on!
Get the bludgers!
(All clamouring)
(Engine revving)
(Dick) Look at him go!
Get him!
Hey!
G0on!G0on!
He's got him, he's got him!
(All cheering)
What are you doing?
You want to take my bloody head off?
(Dick) Look at him go!
Get him! Get him!
(Laughing)
(Dick) Look at him go,
will you?
Look at him go!
(Fires)
Hey, Socrates.
You got a shot in yet?
(Laughing)
(Fires)
(Yelling)
(Laughing)
(Joe) Get out.
Beauty! It's a boomer.
Knocked him out.
It's no good skinning him, eh?
- Where's the surgeon?
- Here.
Doc eats 'em.
Reckon they're
the best part of the roo.
- Haven't you ever tried them?
- N0.
Better than oysters.
Put lead in your pencil.
(Banging)
- Any damage, sir?
- Ah, couple of dents.
- All right, now, let's go.
- N0, no, let's get a drink.
Uh, Johnny?
(Car horn honking)
(Doc) Why don't you try
driving faster, mate? (Laughing)
Hey, Stubbsy.
Hi, fellas.
Stick it up your arse.
Heya, mate.
- You got any roos?
- N0, mate. Couple of boomers.
- (Coughing)
- You blokes couldn't hit elephants.
- Eh?
- Couldn't hit elephants.
- We'll get 'em tonight with the spot.
- What's a spot?
Spotlight,
it hypnotises them.
- Hey, Stubbsy.
- Yeah?
Stick these in your deep-freeze till tonight,
will you?
(Sighs deeply)
- Hope they're not yours, Doc.
- (Laughing)
(Dick) Fox.
Hey, I hit him!
- (Dick) Hey, John, where you going?
- I hit him!
It's no good skinning 'em, mate.
They're all mangy out here.
Come on and drink your beer.
Give us a tailor-made, Joe.
(Burping)
(John) You need any more drinks?
(Joe) I guess it's my shout.
(John) Oh, no, no.
This last round's on me.
Nobody who's broke
buys beers in the Yabba.
I'm not broke,
I've got a dollar.
Forget it, John, forget it.
- $1.
- Look.
When you got some money,
you can take us on a bash.
' Right?
' (mhn) Right.
- Stubbsy?
- (Stubbs) Yeah.
- Four more and four double whiskeys.
- (Stubbs) Right.
And a packet of smokes
for the teacher.
Three whiskeys, Dick.
- Four.
- Three.
- Four!
- Three!
Four!
(Laughing)
(Cocks rifle)
(Guns firing)
(Man) Hey, you got her fair,
eh, Doc? (Laughs)
Hey, Joe, take a look at this.
It's a beauty.
(Joe) Yeah. He must be
a seven-footer for sure.
(Laughs)
G0 on, Dick.
We better cut up a few for the dogs, eh?
The big fellow
just won't go down, Doc.
Take us over there.
- He kicks you, you're dead.
- Come on, take us over there.
- Righto, mate!
- Let's go.
Get stuck into him,
Joey boy.
N0 worries!
(Laughing)
(Kangaroo growling)
See the way the roo's
trying to draw him in
so he can get back
up on his tail, see?
Yeah, and then he rips his guts out
with his hind legs like...
- (Shushes)
- (Makes ripping sound)
- (Cheering)
- All right!
Yippee, Joey bOV!
Come and get your beer, fella!
(Cheering)
(Winces)
Once you've got her by the tail,
it's as good as dead.
- Have you ever done it, Joe?
- N0.
- Dick?
- Eh?
- Have you ever done it?
- What?
Oh, yeah,
hundreds of times.
- Yeah, of course he's done it.
- I've done it!
Why? D0 you want
to have a go, teacher?
Why not?
It's hard to prove.
I wouldn't do it.
Yeah, it's all right,
Joe, I will.
(Laughing)
(Joe) You will?
(G ru nting)
(All laughing)
What's the matter, teacher?
You scared?
It's only a baby.
It's badly wounded.
Have a go, you mug.
(Others laughing)
(J09) G0 on, Johnny!
(Dick) Come on, Johnny!
G0 get him.
(Grunts)
He's trying to dance with him.
(Joe) Come on.
- Cut him through!
- The throat, Johnny!
(Whimpering)
He's trying to beat
the thing to death.
(Laughing)
Through the throat, teacher.
Come on, Johnny!
(Cheering)
You beauty!
Yippie!
Well done.
Yeah, that's it, Johnny.
Now you're one of us.
(Cheering and applauding)
(Gun shots)
(Glass shattering)
You bloody maniacs!
Bloody maniacs!
I cannot accept your premise,
Socrates.
Affectability?
Progress?
A vanity spawned by fear.
(Whooping)
The aim of what you call civilization
is a man in a smokingjacket,
whiskey and cider,
pressing a bottom of...
a button...
to destroy a planet
a billion miles away,
kill a billion people
he's never seen.
Where are you?
Come on!
What happened?
Hey, what happened
to Socrates?
Where's Socrates?
- What?
- Socrates!
(Laughing)
You bastard!
(Yelling)
(Glass shattering)
N0, Joe!
Stop it, you...
You murdering bastards.
You bastards!
(Doc exclaiming drunkenly)
Beat it, Doc.
You murdering bastards!
Bastard!
You are...
(Exclaims drunkenly)
(Yelling)
(Struggling)
I'll get you.
- OK, you old hippie, get out!
- What's up?
Oh, Stubbsy, you bastard.
It's only a party.
(Stubbs) Bloody maniacs.
What do you want with me, Doc?
(Laughing)
Bloody cow...
You bloody coward!
Whoa!
(Laughing)
(Grunts) Get off.
I need to...
Refrigeration.
(Laughing)
Doc...
Turn it off, turn it off.
(Laughing)
N0.
N0, no... (Laughing)
(lmitates slitting throat)
(John grunts)
(Doc laughing)
(Both panting)
(Flies buzzing)
(Snoring)
(Doc snoring)
(G roaning)
Going?
- Yes.
- Where?
Syd neV-
(Laughs)
Want some...
food before you go?
N0.
How about a drink?
(Exhales)
(Grunts)
Hey, don't forget your gun.
What?
The boys made you
a present of the gun.
Bye.
Better?
Yes, better.
Thanks, mate.
Have another one.
Oh...
N0, I don't really like to.
One more beer,
thanks, Joyce.
Jock, you damn near
saved my life just now,
how about completing the job
by giving me a cigarette, huh?
Thanks.
I thought you were
pulling out of the Yabba on Saturday.
Hmm?
Oh, yes. Yes, I was.
What went wrong?
Oh, I got involved.
Hey, there's my suitcases.
- Yours, are they?
- Yes. I left them here yesterday.
N0.
N0, not yesterday.
- N0, it's the other day.
- They've been here since Saturday.
Look, ifJohn says they're his,
then they're his.
- What's in them, John?
- Oh, it's clothes.
Books.
(Man) Couple of schooners, Joyce.
(Jock) Like he said...
Books!
Not that I doubted you,
of course, John.
Is there anywhere
I can get a shower and shave?
Thanks, mate.
Right, thanks a lot.
- Come and have a drink, mate.
- N0, thanks.
- Come and have a drink.
- Not interested...
It will only take a minute.
Come on,
come and have a drink.
Look, mate,
I've given up drinking for a while.
What's wrong with you, you bastard?
Why don't you come and drink with me?
Ijust brought you 50 miles eating dust,
and you won't drink with me.
- What's wrong with you?
- What's the matter with you people, huh?
You sponge on you...
You burn your house down,
murder your wife,
rape your child, that's all right.
But don't have a drink with you,
don't have a flaming, bloody drink with you,
that's a criminal offence,
that's the end of the bloody world.
You're mad, you bastard.
G'day.
The gent here wants to know
who owns that semi-trailer.
(Man) Who wants to know?
Excuse me.
You, uh...
You own the semi-trailer?
What of it?
Well, nothing, uh...
I wanted to see
if you could give me a lift.
- Where you going?
- Right through.
- T0 the city, I mean.
- Well, I'm going to the city myself.
- Oh.
- How much is it worth?
Iam afraid I'm broke,
that's why I'm begging rides.
Should be worth at least
a couple of dollars.
Well, it would be, yes, but...
but I'm really flat.
Make it $2
and we're sweet.
Look, I've got $1.
I... I've got a rifle.
I'll give you that.
What sort of rifle?
All right,
you ride in the back.
OK. Thanks.
(Flies buzzing)
Hey, you, we're there.
There?
You know...
I thought you said
you were going to Sydney.
Don't know why.
You said city, mate.
Bundanyabba's a city, ain't it?
(Sighs)
Well, at least
the trip cost you nothing.
(Laughing)
(All laughing)
(Panting)
(Sobbing)
- Hey!
- (Gun fires)
(Heart beating)
I, uh, hate to trouble you, John,
but rather than tire you, I thought
I'd write down what had happened
and you could sign it, OK?
"The gunshot wound to my head
was the result of an accident.
"L was visiting my friend,
Clarence F. Tydon, after a hunting trip.
"L dropped my .22 rifle
at the floor of his kitchen butt first,
"believing it to be unloaded.
"It exploded,
and that's all I remember."
That'll be about it,
wouldn't it?
Here.
(Siren wailing)
You'd think a bloke who'd won
a silver medal at target shooting
could hit himself in the head
at a range of three inches.
Give me that.
(Train horn sounding)
Don't wanna miss it.
(Train stops)
(Horn sounding)
Hey, mate.
- You like a beer?
- Oh.
- Thanks.
- Here's cheers.
Hello, Charlie.
Did you have a good holiday?
The best.
(Flies buzzing)