Hello? Who!?
No. I'm sorry, I don't know anyone by that name
No, listen, I get about a hundred customers a night
I can't keep track of them all.
Do you know... well tell me what he likes to eat
Cause I remember people by what they order
Not by their names
"Meat Loaf? "
Well, I know a Meat Loaf with Mashed Potatoes.
I know Meat Loaf who likes
Well, with Cheese Fries, Pouched Egg, Onion Rings
What? He doesn't like potatoes?
Why don't you, well, yeah give me your number
And if I see him, I'll tell him to call you
Yeah, I promise. I will. Ok bye
He's 5'11 with dark brown hair
Sorry, I can't think of any Meat Loafs with Cheese Fries
or Onion Rings or Pouched Eggs
Or Fried Fillet of Fish that match that description
Last time we were here, I think he had the pork chops
Oh why didn't you say so?
That's because we supposedly have the best pork chops in the city
You ever tried them?
No, I haven't
Why not? What, are you religious or something?
Listen, have you seen him or not?
5'11 ". Dark brown hair. Pork chops
I have actually. He came in here for dinner last night
He ordered two pork chops
One with mashed potatoes and one with string beans.
I guess he was hungry
No, he didn't eat both of them.
Our portions are too big for a person to eat two
No, one was for him and one was for his girlfriend
Look! Just get to the point...
Don't... Don't change the subject!
Are you seeing someone else?
Who is she?
I hope you both drop dead!
If someone comes in here looking for me
give him these keys
What do I tell him?
Tell him he's an asshole!
Taxi!
Hey, did he pick up the keys?
No, not yet
Do you have an extra cigarette?
Sure
Rolled it myself
Thanks
You okay?
Yeah
I haven't had one in a while
I only smoke when I get stressed out
Well, you shouldn't worry so much
That way you'll avoid lung cancer
Do you think she's pretty?
Who?
The girl he was in here with
Oh, she was okay I guess... I mean
Not the type I would prefer to have my pork chops with
but "each man to his own", right?
Yeah right
Hello
Hey
I need someone to talk to
Do you think he'll pick up the keys?
I don't know
I've had customers leaving keys here for years
Sometimes they pick them up in a few days
Sometimes it takes a few weeks
Well, what about most of the time?
Most of the time, the keys stay in the jar
Well why do you keep them?
You should just throw them out
No
No I couldn't do that
Why not?
If I threw these keys away
then those doors will be closed forever
And that shouldn't be up to me to decide
Should it?
Guess I'm just looking for a reason
Well, from my observations
sometimes it's better off not knowing
and other times there's no reason to be found
Everything has a reason
It's like these pies and cakes
At the end of every night
the cheesecake and the apple pie are always completely gone
The peach cobbler
and the chocolate mousse cake are nearly finished
But there's always a whole blueberry pie left untouched
So what's wrong with the blueberry pie?
There's nothing's wrong with the blueberry pie
It's just people make other choices
You can't blame the blueberry pie
It's just no one wants it
Wait!
I want a piece
With ice cream?
Leave it to me
Here we go
I hope you enjoy it
Thanks
It's not bad
Really?
You should try some
No, I'm alright. I have my own
Will you tell me the stories behind those other keys?
What for?
I just wondered how they all ended up here
Pick one
Those belonged to a young couple a few years ago.
They were naive enough to believe
that they were gonna spend the rest of their lives together
Well, what happened?
Life happened
Things happened. Yeah, time happened
It's pretty much always the case more or less
Or maybe one of them ran off with someone else
Maybe the feelings just went away
What about these?
Those belonged to a little old lady
Her best friend would pick them up and come to visit her
She dropped them off and I never saw her again
I presumed, I mean, she was pretty old
I presumed she passed away or something
What about these?
These keys used to belong to a young lad
from Manchester England
who made plans and had dreams
of running every marathon in this country
starting in New York
He was going to write a journal about his experiences
and ended up running a cafe.
Later they were given to a Russian girl
who loved collecting keys
and watching sunsets
Unfortunately, she loved sunsets more than the keys
and ended up disappearing into one
Why didn't you go looking for her?
When I was little
me mum used to take me to the park on weekends
She said if I ever got lost
I had to stay in one place so that she'd find me
Does that work?
Not really
She got lost once looking for me
Eh, you want some more ice cream?
No thanks
You sure?
Yeah I'm fine. Thanks
You're late
Same as usual?
No thanks
Can I have my keys back?
Yeah, sure
So...
You two have patched things up then?
Thanks
Lousy bloody camera
Hey!
Alright. Come on. Break it... Alright!
Take it outside. Take it out...
None of your business cupcake!
Don't start with me mate!
Don't you start... Come here!
Right you come here
Get out of my place!
Don't start with me!
Get out!
Hey you haven't paid yet!
Can I have a tissue?
What happened?
Did he hit you?
No!
Well what?
I got mugged on the subway
I thought Pork Chop lived around here?
He does
What were you doing on the subway?
Well...
I just needed some time to prepare myself
I was gonna get off in a few stops
I don't know, I just
The next thing I knew, I ended up in the Bronx
That's a very interesting way to prepare yourself
I've never been very good at confrontation
Some people enjoy it
Not me
Hey, are you alright?
Should we call the police or something?
No
No, he didn't get away with very much
Especially after I kicked him in the balls
You didn't
Wait, what happened to you?
I ate too much chocolate today
What's wrong with your camera?
Oh, I don't know
It's been in a lousy mood these past few days
It doesn't really keep people from stealing, does it?
No
Not really
But I like having it around, 'cause
for me it's like my diary
You know?
Some nights, I watch the tapes back and
I'm amazed at how much I've missed
That's going on right in front of me
You must have a lot of tapes
I don't keep them all
I'm not that weird
Only the highlights
Can I take a look?
Sure
Come around
She left behind her set of keys and disappeared that night
How do you say goodbye to someone you can't imagine living without?
I didn't say goodbye
I didn't say anything
I just walked away
At the end of that night
I decided to take the longest way to cross the street
Dear Jeremy
As you can see by this postcard
I'm now in Memphis, Tennessee
Hey Lizzy, hurry up with those damn pick-ups will ya!
Coming!
Come on hustle it!
It took me a long time to get here
And I'm not sure how long I'll be staying
During the day, I work at a diner downtown
I haven't been able to sleep at night
so I've also taken a waitressing job at a bar
It's kind of a dive, but the tips are pretty good
Working two jobs is exhausting
But at least it keeps me busy
and most importantly, it keeps my mind away from him
Hi girl
Hey Sandy
You going home?
Let me put it this way
I'm getting up out of here
I wish I could go
What's wrong?
That guy at the bar
I don't think he's ever gonna leave
Oh you're talking about Arnie?
Child, don't worry about him.
He probably just lost track of time
But now if you need to get going
You just bring his check to him, have him sign it
Travis runs a tab for him
Well, does he always stay this late?
Always
You stick around here you see for yourself
Have a good night darlin'
You too. Good night
Here's your check
Just eight?
I coulda sworn I had at least nine
No, just eight
Do you have a pen?
Yeah
I don't recognize you
You new around here or something?
I just started a few nights ago
Oh
Have you got a name?
Lizzie
Well, it's been a pleasure getting to know you Lizzie
What do you mean?
You won't be seeing much more of me from now on
Why's that?
Well I don't have much reason to come back here anymore
Tonight was my last night of drinking
Oh
Yeah
So, you just give that to Travis
Tell him I'll cut him a check
Ok
That's for you
Thank you
Bye
Oh, hi
Do you have a twin sister?
No
I wish I did
Yeah? Well, I'm glad I don't have a twin
One of me's plenty
Well, let's see I'm just gonna have the chicken fried steak
and a side of string beans
Ok
Coming right up
Hey! Knock that crap off over there!
This is a restaurant, not a damn dancehall!
How come you're working so hard, Lizzie?
I'm trying to save up for a car
Where are you going?
Well, I don't have any specific destination in mind, but
I'm just gonna go until I run out of places to go
I wish I could do that
Here's your change
You put that towards a Buick
Thank you
Hi
Wait what are you doing here?
What?
What are you doing here?
Oh, I'm celebrating
What are you celebrating?
My last night of drinking!
He's not giving you a hard time, is he?
I think he just wants to talk
That's funny, 'cause he almost never wants to talk
He's not hitting on you, is he?
No. I don't think it's like that
It's too bad
Be nice to see him take an interest in a woman
I thought he was married
Yeah, that's precisely the problem. He still thinks he is
Holy shit
Travis, how's it hanging?
Always a pleasure, Sue Lynne
You always say that to me
and I never know whether you mean it
I'm just dropping in to use the ladies' room
Do I have to buy a beer first?
Your money's no good here, Sue Lynne
Have you got a moment?
I got nothing to say to you
Arnie?
Yeah?
I know its none of my business
but have you ever thought about cutting back.
Have I thought about it?
What are these?
A group I go to sometimes, Lizzie,
has this system.
After a meeting,
they invite the new people to come down and
pick up a white chip.
You take it as a symbol of your intention
to stay sober.
And if you
slip up and drink again
you got to come back and pick up another chip.
This one is for ninety days.
I got that far.
Once.
See all those white chips, Lizzie?
I am the king of the white chip.
Dear Jeremy.
I thought about what Arnie said about the sobriety chips,
how to focus your attention on something else
in order to cure your addiction.
If I was an addict, I'd choose blueberry pie as my chip.
Writing to your boyfriend?
No, just someone I know.
Why not pick up the phone?
Some things are better on paper.
Oh you think so?
What are you doing?
Well, you know
I listened to what you said the other day.
So I'm trying to write a letter to my wife.
We don't talk to each other much anymore
so I thought maybe I'd try your method.
Randy!
Oh my God!
Arnie! Arnie! Stop! Arnie!
Okay I got. Easy now, watch your back.
You'll be alright, man!
Hello, is that the Memphis Bar and Grill?
It is! Great.
Listen, I wonder if you could help me please.
I'm looking for a young woman called Elizabeth.
Yes. I realize that. I'm not calling to order your food.
I'm sure it's delicious.
I wonder, does a woman called Elizabeth work there?
Elizabeth!
Elizabeth.
That's what I said, Elizabeth.
E- L-I-Z-A-B-
No, alright, thank you.
Thank you.
Good God, it's Jeremy!
Yeah it's me!
I never thought I'd hear your voice again.
Well, you see I got your postcard and...
This sounds ridiculous but...
Well I traced every Memphis bar and grill.
There must be at least ninety.
I know its crazy and...
I just wanted to say thanks for staying in touch.
I miss you. I miss your company.
I never thought I'd hear from you again!
It's not really you is it?
No I know you don't know me.
But your name's Elizabeth.
Well, I just... I just wanted
I just wanted to say hello really, and...
I wanted to speak to my friend.
Yeah.
No no, I don't want to order any fried chicken.
Thanks.
Thanks for listening.
Bye.
Goddamn son of a bitch...
I need to talk to you!
Not in here. Let's take this outside.
No! I want to talk about it right here!
So you feel more like a man now do you?
You feel all big and strong.
I mean you could have killed him!
Yeah, no body ever said sleeping with someone else's wife
was a safe vocation.
Oh goddammit Arnie!
We're, we're separated!
I don't live with you anymore!
I don't talk to you anymore!
You are my goddamn wife!
And I am still your goddamn husband!
No, no you're not...
Not anymore.
Well then what am I?
You're nothing.
Nothing to me.
Sue Lynne, please, please, please baby.
Don't do this, don't do this to me.
I love you, I love you so much.
I just, I just need a little more time.
Goddammit Arnie!
No, no you gotta let me go.
I can't do it anymore. You gotta let me go now.
I'm gonna go, I'm restart my life
and I'm gonna get me a job.
You're gonna get a job, right?
Yes I am.
You don't need a job...
What with all those boyfriends of yours.
All you gotta do is just start charging.
You bastard!
YOU GODDAMN BASTARD!
You bastard Arnie!
I'm through with you!
You hear me? I'm through!
I'm through with you! It is over! It is over!
You understand me?
Sue Lynne,
I swear to god, if you walk out of here,
I'll kill you.
Then what?
Arnie, be calm now...
you don't want to do this.
It's over!
It's too much.
Nuh uh.
No no no...
You're saving up to buy a car, right?
Well, I... I don't want you driving around in some
junker.
So some cop can pull you over for a failed inspection.
Thank you.
Wait.
You forgot these.
Yeah... you can just get rid of those.
The police said it was an accident.
He couldn't see where he was going
and he skidded off the road.
Can you give me a vodka?
This is my first drink in six years.
Haven't touched the stuff for six years.
Hey everybody!
Let's all drink to Arnie Copeland.
He was guardian of our highways
and defender of our freedom!
Well, this stuff tastes pretty darn awful.
But I guess nobody drinks it for the taste, right?
Give me another one.
Cheeseburgers?
Whiskey?
This isn't mine.
It's Arnie's tab.
What am I supposed to do with this?
Put it in a frame and hang it on my wall?
Travis wants you to settle it.
Travis!
What are you giving this to me for!?
This is Arnie's tab, not mine!
Why are you giving this to me!?
He was your husband.
Or does that matter at all?
He's dead!
So if you want your money, you better call his lawyer.
Don't give this to me!
Oh God, what a piece of work you are...
God only knows what Arnie saw in you.
I hate you Travis!
I hate you...
Lizzie!
Make sure she gets home safe.
Go on now.
Go on!
Hey Sue Lynne?
Sue Lynne?
It's late.
Come on let me take you home.
I was
seventeen when he pulled me over.
High as a kite.
"You been drinking, Miss? "
So I smiled.
Bat my eyes.
Who'd have thought we'd be married.
In love with a cop,
and stuck in this godforesaken town.
He was so crazy about me.
I couldn't breathe.
So we tried
drinking our way back into love.
But it never made sense in the morning.
So I ran.
And every time I came back,
he was here.
And he was still crazy about me.
You know,
I used to daydream about him dying.
I thought it was the
only way I'd get clear of him.
You must have hated him.
I didn't hate him.
I just wanted him to
let go of me.
And...
now that he has,
it hurts me more than
anything else in the whole world.
This is where we met.
Right here.
Well, I heard you had a day job
I'm saving for a car
Well, I'm leaving town for good so
I wanted to take care of a few things
Arnie's tab came out to eight hundred dollars
I guess you can give it to Travis and
he can mark the debt paid
I'll give it to Travis tonight
Shock might give him a heart attack
I have a favor to ask you
Could you keep his bill hanging?
So they don't forget him too soon?
OK
I guess for Sue Lynne, leaving this town was like dying
I wonder how people would remember Arnie
When you're gone, all that's left behind are the memories
you created in other people's lives
or just a couple of items on a bill
I began receiving postcards from her regularly
Instead of calling strangers, I decided to change my strategy
It was tiring writing the same words over and over again
but all worth it if only one of them reached her
I always had the feeling I could say anything to you.
Enclosed is a bill I've created for you
in memory of our time together
I wonder how you remember me
As the girl who liked blueberry pies
or the girl with the broken heart?
Still rolling your own cigarettes?
You want one?
Yeah
Tastes different
It's probably just been in my pocket too long
It's a shame you can't smoke in cafes anymore
You can't smoke anywhere anymore
You should've changed the place
It's not that much different
I've been meaning to buy new chairs
but I couldn't never find any that match
the tables and the tiles
Shouldn't be hard
Maybe you're just looking in the wrong places or
maybe you're just sentimental
You look lovely
I'm starting to look like my mom
It's better than looking like your dad
I've seen photos of him
You still have the keys?
Yeah... I always remember what you said
about never throwing them away, about never
closing those doors forever. I remember
Sometimes, even if you have the keys
those doors still
can't be opened, can they?
Even if the door is open
the person you're looking for may not be there, Katya
A few years ago, I had a dream
It began in the summer
and was over by the following spring
In between, there was as many unhappy nights
as there were happy days
Most of them took place in this cafe
And then one night
a door slammed and the dream was over
I should be going
I have to catch a flight in the morning
Thanks for the smoke.
You know, I didn't even think you'd still be here
Why'd you come?
I guess I just wanted to see if I could remember
what it felt like
Goodbye, Jeremy
Bye, Katya
Cocktails?
A screwdriver, please
Here you go
Dear Jeremy
I've always been fascinated by card players
They risk everything on their instincts and their luck
I wonder if I would be able to make the same moves
in their position
Or would I just fold?
Sweetheart, do you mind?
Uh-oh look at that
She gets another one this kid
You know Leslie you got that fancy Jag
you working on a Rolls Royce now?
Aloha, you forgot to tip the waitress
Actually I didn't forget dick
Because I never tip
What do you mean you never tip?
I mean Harlan can afford to pay his own people
I don't know why I have to
You can be cheap or you can be lucky
but you can't be both. Not in the long run
Here ya go, toots
That is from Mr. Aloha over there
He's gonna pay me back, he doesn't know it yet
Thanks
Your luck just went south
Who's blinds?
Working long hours in the casino makes you lose track of the time
And I'm never sure whether it's day or night
But at least I don't have to worry about my sleeping problem anymore
Somehow it's gone away
How much you got left, sweet cheeks?
Because that's what I bet
Eighteen-twenty
You on a big draw, Aloha?
Because otherwise you're just about dead
You are on a big draw
Twelve outs twice
You wanna do business?
Make me an offer
How about you take six hundred and I take a thousand
and we gamble for the rest?
I say I need more than that
Doesn't seem fair to you?
I feel like gambling
So what do you want me to do?
You heard the man.
He wants to gamble. Deal
Bet you wish you took that six hundred now,huh Aloha?
Don't get too cocky little girl
Five of hearts still in that deck
Oh come on
We can all dream, Aloha
I wish you luck
Why don't you deal the card?
Fine
Wait, wait, how did you do that?
Ok I swear I wasn't cheating
I had the deck in my hand
Pass it to the sugardaddy here
I'm telling my grandkids about that one
Maybe
A salad. That'd be healthy, right?
I don't think I could get it down though
All that chewing and swallowing
Maybe I'll get some eggs
Protein, right?
How would you like them?
Tied in a knot and nailed to the floor
Or maybe you can just crack 'em over my head
and let 'em trickle down my cheeks
Beth
Why don't I just go ask them right now?
So who is gonna lend me a grand so I can get back in?
Sam, come on, this is me we're talking about
Why can't you just advance me the cash
and I will wire you back the money within 24 hours
You won't even have a chance to miss it
Yeah?
Well fuck you very much!
Rough night, huh?
You could say that
How did you wind up in this hellhole?
The bus just dropped me off here
Where'd you come from?
New York
You came all the way here from New York on a bus?
Sounds awful
Actually, I was on quite a few of them
You must love buses
I wanna get a car but
it's not easy saving money
How much you got?
About twenty-one, twenty-two hundred
Hey Beth
I've got a proposition for you
What kind of proposition?
See, I need a stake
There's a man I could call in Vegas
but I don't want to do that
I'm gonna win that game
I'm a stronger player than any of them
If you give me a chance I'm gonna clean their clocks.
How much do you need?
Well your twenty two hundred would get me back in
And then, once I cash out
you'll get your money back plus a third of my winnings
But what if you lose?
If I lose, you get my car
It's a brand new Jag
This way
whatever happens
you've got your ass covered from here to Houston
You got to give me a minute here
It's been a long night
I got an empty stomach. Just give me a minute
You take your time
I wouldn't want you choking on your food
Shit it's cold!
I know
I'll do it
Oh my, look who's back
I thought you'd be halfway to Vegas in that fancy ass Jag of yours
I figure why not let you pay for my gas
Gotta raise again
Five hundred
Oh one of these days one of us is going to have
something when you raise!
Listen, why don't you just wink at me when that happens
so I know, alright?
Raise
I'm all in
You want to give me a count on that?
Fifteen... Fifteen thirty-five
Too rich for me
I don't know what's worse
That cute smile or that ugly shirt
I'll give you some action
Hey
Hey, what happened?
The car's yours
You've got to give me a ride though
So where we going?
Vegas
She said she knew some people in Vegas who could stake her
get her started again
But she didn't seem to be in a hurry to get there
Hey Leslie, are you asleep?
No
I keep playing old poker hands in my head
You?
Same
Except for the poker
What are you replaying?
Just some stuff that happened back in New York
Hey, the man you told me about in Vegas
that could give you the money
Yeah?
Is he a boyfriend?
No
I haven't had very much luck with boyfriends
I've had a few but
none that I could ever ask for anything, let alone money
Now you want to know who the man in Vegas is
but you're too polite to ask
No
It's not important
He's my father
Taught me how to play poker
He had me figuring odds around the same time
other kids were learning how to count
He used to tell people
that I thought the number that came after ten
was Jack
So I can ask him for money or anything, but
I won't
Trust everyone but always cut the cards
Best thing my father ever taught me
You know what that means?
It means never trust anybody
If you're so good at reading people
Then why did I lose?
Yeah
Because you can't always win
You can beat players but you can't beat luck
Sometimes your rhythm's off
you read the person right but still do the wrong thing
Because you trust them?
Because you can't even trust yourself
Shit
Nobody I want to hear from
Nobody?
Nobody!
How did you get this number?
You know this is the third time this month I've have change it?
Just leave me the hell alone! Stop calling!
Dammit!
Beth, answer it for me
What do you want me to say?
Tell them its the wrong number and not to call again
Okay
Hello?
Sorry, you have-
From where?
Okay
Okay... you sure?
Okay, thank you... bye
It was someone from a hospital in Vegas
They said your dad's there
And they said he's dying
Son of a bitch
That man... always dying
It's a trick, okay?
He's pulled this on me before
Says he has to see me, he's dying
And then
you know how many times I've fallen for that?
But it was someone from the hospital that called it wasn't him
So what Beth?
You think he couldn't pay someone
to make the phone call for him?
I swear, is there anyone you don't trust?
Well he must really want to see you to make up a story like that
Geez, you are just dying to ask me something
What?
I didn't say anything
You didn't have to. I can read you
I can even guess what you wanna ask
You wanna ask
"What if he is dying? " "What if the message is legit? "
Well what if he is?
The thing is Beth
I don't care
He lives, he dies
whatever
I don't fucking care
You're lying
I'm not going in there
What?
I can't. What- what if I go in there
and he's just sitting up in his room
with his dead beat friends playing gin rummy
or, I dunno, detoxing, getting a mole removed
You know it's more serious than that
No, I don't know that and neither do you
Listen, you do me a favor. You go in there for me
Me?
Why me?
Because you are safe. There's no way he can hurt you
Go, c'mon
Fine
I am sorry
You know we tried to phone a couple days
but couldn't seem to reach you
He was-
You should've come earlier
He put you up to this!?
How much he pay you huh!?
Jesus
You're so good at reading people?
Can't you see it in my face!?
Leslie, he's gone!
You're lying
Beth
I can't give you the car
Why?
Because the car
the car belonged to my father
Look, he won big one day in a Hold'em game at the Riviera, and
went out and bought the next day
It was his pride and joy
Til one day I stole his keys, and an hour later I stole his car
I don't know why I did it
Maybe I just
wanted to see what he would do, you know?
Was he gonna report it?
Get his daughter arrested?
He did something better than that
He waited until he found out where I wound up
One morning
a FedEx guy comes with an envelope for me
Inside the envelope's the title and registration of the car
Son of a bitch signed it over to me
So
I'm gonna drive this car until it falls apart
At least until I do
So what am I supposed to?
Well, Beth
I told you I lost everything back at Harlan's, didn't I?
Yeah
Well, that's not exactly how it went down
See, I beat that game on its ass, Beth
I knocked them off their feet
The cards turned just like I knew they would
I read the other players just right
I walked away with all their money
So you lied to me
Maybe I didn't want to share
Maybe I just wanted to see how trusting and gullible you were
Maybe I just wanted company. You know?
It's a long ride, Beth
I didn't want to go alone
Can't do it. Thirty-five hundred's the best I can give ya
Three thousand. That's my top
Can't. Gotta have thirty-five hundred. Sorry
Thirty-two hundred. Take it or leave it
You know what?
I'm sure we can find a better deal someplace else. Let's go
I don't think you will, ladies. Suit yourselves
Thank you!
Don't look back
Beth, where are you going?
I want that car
Beth not at that price!
We can get it for three grand by the time we get to my car
I don't think he's gonna come down
And I think that's the car I want
Have you learned nothing from your time with me?
You have to stop taking people at their word!
Maybe you should start
You're hopeless
You're hopeless too
Dear Jeremy
In the last few days, I've been learning how to not trust people
and I'm glad I failed
Sometimes we depend on other people as a mirror
To define us and tell us who we are
And each reflection makes me like myself a little more
Elizabeth
Hello, Cafe Klyuch
Rent
You still open?
No reason for me to still be here if I wasn't
I heard this place has the best coffee and pie in town
Where'd you hear that?
I get around
You wanna come inside?
It's cold
What are you doing out here? It's freezing
It's a beautiful night. I wanted to get some fresh air
Have a seat
Isn't this reserved?
Reserved for you
Want something to eat?
Yeah, I'm starving
What's good tonight?
What about a steak?
That sounds good
Does it come with home fries?
Or mashed
They both sound good
Half an order of both?
I'll get the home fries with the steak, medium rare
and a side of mashed potatoes
Coming right up
Learning something about me?
There's something different about you
Or maybe it's me that's changed
Where are the keys?
You don't keep them anymore?
Been trying to give them back to their owners
Do you want yours?
No. I don't need them anymore
What about your keys?
I got rid of them
Good night, Jeremy
I'll see you tomorrow
You know I came here the night I left
but I didn't make it past the front door
I almost walked in but I knew that if I did
I would just be the same old Elizabeth
I didn't want to be that person anymore
Hope you enjoy it
Are they still left untouched at the end of the night?
Yep, more or less
Then why do you keep making them?
Well I always like having one around just in case
you pop in and fancy a slice
Do you remember that last night you were here?
When you practically ate an entire pie all by yourself?
Really?
I remember getting really drunk and
having a god awful hangover the next day
Nothing else?
No, nothing else
Or don't you have a tape I can watch?
I do... but...
I've watched it so many times
that the picture started fading to black and white
And now it's completely unwatchable
Must have been an interesting night
It was
Never seen a girl eat so much in all my life
Like this?
No, it was more like this
It's good pie
It took me nearly a year to get here
It wasn't so hard to cross that street afterall
It all depends on who's waiting for you on the other side