Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.OpenSubtitles.org today
INVESTIGATION
OF A CITIZEN ABOVE SUSPICION
Several scenes were filmed at the
Piazzale del Caravaggio
administrative complex of
Beni Stabili, S.p.A.
Any similarity to real persons
or actual events is entirely coincidental.
JUSTICE
SCIENCE
How are you going to kill me this time?
I'm going to slash your throat.
Hello?
Hello.
Police department?
What took you so long?
Are you sleeping or what?
There's been a crime.
Yes, a crime.
Via del Tempio 1.
Not via del Tempo, idiot.
Augusta Terzi.
Apartment number 1.
Did you write that down?
Repeat it to me.
After you.
- After you.
Wait a minute!
- Congratulations, Chief.
- Congratulations.
Congratulations, Chief.
We finally did it.
We couldn't have kept on
without a sense of direction.
We needed a man like you.
The political situation is favorable.
I have lots of ideas.
Don't worry about anything.
See you later.
Piantone, bring me 15 glasses.
- What's wrong?
- A murder, Chief.
- Via del Tempo 1.
- Tempio.
Mrs. Augusta Terzi.
- When did the call come in?
- Ten or 20 minutes ago.
- Ten or 20?
- They didn't specify.
HOMICIDE DIVISION CHIEF
Precise.
We must be precise.
We verified the name and address.
I'm going there now.
Your careless police work gives the suspects
time to come up with their alibis.
You'll realize that once I'm gone.
"Officer Fires Shots."
Who was it?
OFFICER FIRES SHOTS:
WOUNDS FACTORY WORKER
We don't know him.
And, of course, he dropped
the gun and it went off.
That's the most likely story.
Go to via del Tempio.
Congratulations.
Come on, cheer up!
What's with the sad faces?
Don't worry, ma'am.
Your son will get off with 10 years.
I've got nothing to do with it anymore.
I'm done here.
Mantiglia, Cascio,
Mangiaracine, Del Re, let's go!
All of you, let's go!
You're finally free of this leech.
Come on.
Panunzio!
Let's have Panunzio
break open a bottle for us.
- Here he is.
- My deepest congratulations, Chief.
Toruzzo!
You're coming with me.
- Mangani!
- You're coming with me, got it?
Congratulations.
It won't be easy for me
to fill your shoes.
Don't be ridiculous.
What are you talking about?
- And Panunzio? Where is he?
- Here.
There he is!
- Panunzio, eh?
- Should we go in?
So, did you get a confession
out of Proietti yet?
He still insists it was suicide.
Have a drink. The champagne
will help clear your mind.
My mind is already clear!
- I'm innocent.
- We understand.
She killed herself
just to get me in trouble.
- Yes!
- Yes.
Or maybe she lost her balance.
She must have been dizzy.
I don't know!
You pushed her.
No, I was asleep,
just like I was when you found me.
I was asleep.
And besides, I'm a violent type.
I would've strangled that bitch!
Drink up, Mr. innocent.
Drink.
Everybody's innocent here.
There's only one guilty party...
and that's me.
Quiet, please.
I'm not saying this to ingratiate
myself with a superior officer,
who is also a dear friend,
but nobody deserves
this promotion more than you.
In all these years,
we've investigated 102 murder cases,
and only 10 have gone unsolved.
I'm sure that, in this difficult time,
the Political Division will become as efficient
as Homicide was under your command.
I wish you as much success there
as you had here.
I raise my glass to your health
and to your extraordinary career.
Cheers.
Enough ass-kissing.
- The carnival is over. Let's go.
- Via del Tempio 1 is a go!
Via del Tempio 1 is a go!
Mangani, Panunzio, let's go!
I'll meet you there.
Do you have a statement?
- It was her husband.
- Great!
What have you got?
Newspaper clippings of crime stories.
There's a photo of you too. Look.
- Where is she?
- Over here.
Uncover her.
Her jewelry box is empty.
- And that?
- 300,000 lire in cash.
She was a real libertine,
like D'Annunzio.
We haven't found
any undergarments in the house.
- Not even underwear.
- What a mess.
They were in bed, making love.
Any evidence of an orgasm?
Not from my initial examination.
Cover her up.
Collect that bottle and that glass.
Did any of the tenants
see or hear anything?
We're getting their names.
Are you feeling okay?
- Who lives next door?
- A well-known surgeon.
An individual above suspicion.
Whose name is the apartment in?
The victim's.
Who inherits everything?
The husband?
They've been separated for three years.
Find him. Question him.
Look at this.
The victim was posing
for fake crime scene photos.
There's a whole collection of them.
I think it's the work of an amateur,
and quite a childish one.
What do you think?
Lie down on the bed and turn over.
I'll show you how we found
that whore on Viale Coccia di Morto.
- Where?
- That's good.
- Now come with me.
- Where?
A German stewardess had sex with a Turk
during an intercontinental flight.
We found her strangled to death
in the bathroom at Fiumicino airport.
Stay still!
- What do you want to do now?
- Let's do the young singer, the rising star.
Yes. Parioli, 1967.
A young rock-and-roll singer's
throat was cut.
Her body was covered up
with albums of polyphonic religious music.
An erotic and mystical crime.
The killer,
a former seminary student,
was found some minutes later,
complacently listening to the voice
of his victim in front of a jukebox.
Not a seminary student, stupid.
He was an organist.
Don't move.
- Let's do the young revolutionary.
- Yes.
Young student protester. Trento.
She was suffocated
by a tenured sociology professor
with 10,000-lire bills.
She was raped after she was killed.
Hold still.
Spread your legs. That's it.
Don't move.
There.
Doesn't it excite you
to find them like this?
Sometimes.
Once, a particular detail excited me.
A tool.
- What kind?
- No, I'm too embarrassed.
Let me through.
- Chief.
- What is it?
I think he's a complete idiot.
- Who?
- The killer.
Why do you think that?
Not just stupid,
but also superficial and conceited.
He fakes a robbery by taking her jewelry
but leaves 300,000 lire in the dresser.
Then he gets dressed,
has a shower.
He dolls himself up,
uses the victim's French soap.
- And?
- He puts his shoes on.
Then he tramps through her blood,
leaving footprints everywhere.
Helpful for us,
but what an idiot.
No?
He's an idiot.
Let's hope it was the husband.
You can wrap it up quickly.
- Well?
- Naked.
- Was she raped?
- No, she had consensual sex.
She was killed afterwards.
No signs of struggle in the apartment.
Write this down. You breathe in
an atmosphere of sex, pleasure.
It's morbid. it reeks of D'Annunzio.
There's blood everywhere.
Get out. I'm driving.
Did she have a nice body?
Skin like satin, like a true courtesan
of the Roman Empire.
Here's something
for your left-wing readers.
No undergarments
were found in the apartment.
- A fetish?
- No. She just didn't wear them.
I have my headline.
Do me a favor, Patané,
focus on the husband.
Do me a favor.
Commissioner.
You don't know me.
Am I speaking to the famous
and powerful Chief of Homicide?
No, you don't know me.
You've never seen me before.
I don't hang out with cops.
Who am I?
I could be a thief,
a maniac, a murderer,
one of the 30 murderers
still wandering free in this city.
What's my name?
You figure it out.
You're so smart.
You pose for photos and give interviews.
By the way,
try losing some weight.
Chief, help!
Someone's breaking into my house.
I can hear his footsteps.
They've been threatening me for months:
letters, anonymous calls.
It's someone who wants
to possess me, rape me.
He's here!
He has no pants on!
How awful.
I'm all alone, naked.
I'll be raped and killed.
That's my fate. Help!
Always wearing black,
always in mourning.
Don't kid yourself.
You don't interest me physically.
You're an average Italian.
You're too hairy.
You probably sweat a lot.
I'm sure you smell
like shoe polish, don't you?
All policemen do. Admit it.
A policeman is full of secrets,
like a priest.
It's your mind that excites me.
I really admire the police.
I'd love to be a snitch.
What I wouldn't give
to be interrogated by you.
Ask your fucking sister to do that!
- Who is it?
- Police.
Who else could it have been?
A thief or a cop.
Who does this belong to?
A man.
Who are you?
What do you want?
Why did you call me?
Let's get one thing clear.
- I don't pay for my women.
- Nice.
You should have called
the vice squad, not Homicide.
Who do you think I am?
What's your game?
Just having some fun.
How did you meet
all these millionaires?
Did you call them too?
You're good.
Wow, you're quite a cop.
But there's a mistake here.
In '66, I was all alone,
like a dog.
On your feet!
Toruzzo.
How are you?
- How are you?
- Good.
Gentlemen, I hope you appreciate
the novelty of this meeting.
It's American-style!
We don't have enough men
for all the work in front of us.
- That's right!
- We need many more!
Have a seat.
As of today, I've been made Chief
of the Political Division.
You all know that up until yesterday
I was catching murderers,
and with a certain amount of success.
There's a reason why
they chose a man like me,
at a time like this,
to direct the Political Division.
The decision was made
for the following reason:
The difference between common
and political felonies
is dwindling more and more each day.
It has almost disappeared.
Memorize this rule:
Inside every criminal,
an subversive may be hiding,
and inside every subversive,
a criminal may be hiding.
In this city that has been
entrusted to our care,
subversives and criminals
have already spun their invisible web.
It's up to us to tear it down.
What's the difference between
a gang of robbers assaulting a bank
and organized, institutionalized,
legal subversion?
There isn't any.
They both have the same objective.
They just use different methods.
Their objective is to overthrow
the current social order.
6,000 prostitutes on file.
A 20% rise in strikes and sit-ins
in both public and private buildings.
2,000 known whorehouses.
In one year, 30 attempts to destroy
state property as an act of protest.
200 rapes in one year.
50,000 high school students
demonstrating in the streets.
A 30% rise in bank robberies.
10,000 new subversives on file.
600 homosexuals on file.
More than 70 subversive groups
operating outside the bounds of the law.
A 50% rise in fraudulent bankruptcy
and protests of bills of exchange.
An indescribable number
of political magazines urging revolution.
The exercise of freedom
is threatening our traditional
power structure from all sides,
our established authorities.
The exercise of freedom makes
every citizen think he's a judge
and prevents us from executing
our sacrosanct duties freely!
We are the protectors of the law,
and it should be immutable,
carved in stone.
The populace lacks maturity.
The city is sick.
Let others take up the task
of healing and educating.
Our duty is to repress them!
Repression is our vaccine!
Repression is civilization!
Well said, Chief.
Bravo, Chief!
No applause, please.
I barely did anything.
A little restraint, please.
Let's get back to work.
The Communists are in this section.
Then come the partisans,
Trotskyites, Maoists and anarchists.
- And the political parties?
- Over here.
Here we have the various
Catholic movements.
In the back, the Social Democrats
up through the right-wing opposition parties.
With progress, obviously,
all of this will be destroyed,
and we'll gather everything
into two small rooms.
This way, please.
Canes, come here.
I'd like to take a peek
at my Homicide colleagues' files,
as a joke.
For the past two weeks, we've been entering
the data from the archive's files in here.
That's progress for you.
- Let's do a test.
- Let's.
Imagine that the Terzi murder
was political in nature.
- What's the address, exactly?
- Via del Tempio 1.
- What zone?
- Downtown.
We'll ask the computer
if via del Tempio is home to any socially
or politically dangerous individuals.
- How does it work?
- Like this.
What's this?
America has arrived!
It's revolutionary!
One of our old acquaintances
lives at via del Tempio 1.
A socially and politically
dangerous individual.
- Pace, Antonio.
- Yes.
Born in Ravenna, March 24, 1946.
Chemistry student,
student council member.
Subversive, hot-blooded,
fanatical, dangerous.
- Is his line tapped?
- Of course, Chief.
Since May 1968.
The face of a criminal.
I'll put him away.
Chief.
Please come in.
Until next time.
- Your Eminence.
- No, my son, better not.
- Would you like a cigar?
- Thank you.
Here.
Have a seat.
So, are you satisfied?
Well, you know, satisfied...
In 1917, the responsibility for Caporetto's
defeat fell on General Cadorna.
This year's center-left party
could become another Caporetto
for those in charge.
The country is tense.
I'd feel better if I had
a larger team to work with.
I need 100 more men and more funding
to pay my informants better.
I'll discuss it with the minister.
- I would like...
- Go on.
- I would really like to...
- Tell me.
- Listen.
To rent one...
three apartments in a nice, quiet
neighborhood like Prati for my informants
so I can establish a relationship
with them that's more...
- More?
- Informative.
All right.
But officially,
I don't know anything about it.
My office has prepared a new list
of 630 numbers to be tapped.
I don't know if you think
we should request authorization.
- I don't know.
- You decide.
- Is that all?
- Oh, yes.
That woman who was killed
three days ago...
- Who? Mrs. Terzi?
- Exactly. Augusta Terzi.
Beautiful woman.
I saw the photos.
I knew her.
Yes.
I had an affair with her.
How was it?
Good? How was it?
Well, you know.
I wanted to ask you
if you think it's necessary
to inform the investigators
about the situation?
I really don't know.
What do you think?
Bye.
- Bye.
I really don't know.
I think it was the husband.
Send in Panunzio.
Morning, Chief.
I brought you a souvenir photo
of the glorious Homicide squad.
Sit down.
Yes, I know.
My cousin's a Communist
and secretary of a labor union.
But what can I do?
He never sets foot in my house.
Besides, I've never even seen him.
Okay, to be honest, I do see him,
but once a year, at Christmas.
Chief, I've only got two years left.
Don't transfer me.
I have two sons in university.
I need to keep an eye on them,
in every respect.
How's the Terzi case going?
We have an interesting lead.
Underneath the victim's nail,
forensics found a blue silk thread
that seems to have been ripped from a tie.
- Wasn't the murderer naked?
- Yes.
So you think he was naked,
but wearing a tie.
You're right.
No one even thought of that.
Panunzio.
Are you interrogating her husband?
Yes, Chief.
They've been questioning him
since last night.
- Fingerprints?
- Nothing interesting.
Only yours, Chief.
Mine?
Mine!
Yes, on a doorknob.
And on a coffee cup, Chief.
You must have been sleepy.
This one was in the shower,
but we all went in there,
even Mangani, remember?
And also in the kitchen.
There it is.
In the kitchen too.
But we all went in there too.
You must have picked something up
distractedly, without taking precautions.
And on the telephone too.
Where is it?
Here. On the telephone.
No doubt you must have
made a call that night.
I remember it clearly.
And then on a glass.
Here. A liquor glass.
You didn't feel well that night.
Remember?
You had a glass of Fernet.
I poured it myself, remember?
I wrote it down in my notes.
Do you feel ill, Chief?
So, sir...
or should I say ma'am?
Tell us when you first
became a homosexual!
Was it before or after you
and Augusta Terzi were separated?
Why'd your wife kick you out?
Because he was throwing
his money out the window.
It wasn't that simple.
You can't put it that way!
I loved her!
Evening. Perfect timing.
He's done for.
Two or three more questions, my way,
and he'll break for sure.
Are you crying?
Have you made up your mind,
artist, hippie, queen of queers?
- Are you going to talk?
- You'd better. We know everything.
Of course, it's obvious.
You're a queer. She was beautiful,
and you killed her.
- That's what happened.
- That's not true!
- Talk. Be a good boy.
- I want my lawyer!
- We're not in America.
As soon as the law changes,
I'll send him to you.
You're an artist, a sensitive type.
- Try to help us.
- Of course.
Now he'll tell us the whole story, calmly.
Let's start from the beginning.
The Sunday that your wife,
Augusta Terzi, was killed,
what time did you get back
from Fregene?
- I already told you.
- Tell us again.
- At 4:00.
- And then?
I picked up my car
and headed out towards Rome.
There was a traffic jam,
tons of people, thousands.
So strange.
I know it seems unlikely, but...
- He's a real faggot.
- The traffic jam is your alibi.
How convenient!
I told you everything I know
about her, myself, everyone!
Not everything.
Or at least,
not of your own accord.
You used your wife
to advance your own career!
If your colleague hadn't told us,
you'd never have confessed that!
Want to see
if I can wake you up?
Interrogate me.
Let's do something.
Stop sleeping.
Leave me alone.
I like it when you interrogate me.
You're so suspicious.
It reminds me of my father.
Come on, interrogate me.
Interrogate me!
All right, first get off the bed.
Get off the bed!
Now get on your knees.
Straighten up!
I get it.
The silence is intimidating.
Straighten up!
Now try to imagine that
many terrible hours lie ahead of you.
Cruel questions, tricks,
blackmail, everything!
Try to remember
all the things you've forgotten.
Try to recall the most shameful memories.
And remember,
I can find out everything about you
because the government has given me
the means to expose an individual.
- Straighten up!
- Bastard.
I want you to think
I know everything about you.
That is how I will trigger
the guilt-complex mechanism inside of you.
I've had enough.
Interrogate me!
Ask me some questions!
- You want me to interrogate you?
- Yes.
Then talk, talk!
Tell me the most shameful things. Talk.
Only if you confess
all your weakness and shame
will you obtain my forgiveness
and my protection.
I understand.
You treat them like children.
Everyone becomes a child again,
especially in the presence
of the established authorities.
In my presence,
because I represent power.
Straighten up!
The law.
Sit up!
All laws,
both known and unknown.
The suspect becomes a child again...
and I become the father,
the unassailable model.
My face becomes God's face,
the face of your conscience.
It's all staged to touch a deep chord in you,
to expose hidden feelings.
Don't be upset. Here.
I'm explaining this mentality
to you because...
Well, why do you think?
These are the foundations
the established authorities are built upon.
University professors...
heads of political parties,
tax attorneys, stationmasters.
Here.
Now I'll show you how we found
that whore in Mandrione.
In the end, we policemen
aren't that different from criminals.
Same way of speaking, same habits.
Sometimes even the same gestures.
You're like a child,
more than any other man I've ever met.
You shouldn't say that,
that I'm a child.
You shouldn't say that, understand?
Other people are children, understand?
- Will you drop the traffic jam story?
- It's true!
No, wait a minute.
We're going to leave you alone
to think things over.
Think carefully about what
you should say and do, okay?
We're leaving.
- Mangani, you yell too much.
- Thanks.
I yell too much.
I learned it all from you.
That guy's starting to get in the way.
Why doesn't he go do his job?
- You're right, Chief.
- He's impeding the investigation.
Holy shit.
Have some coffee.
If I'm not mistaken,
you decorated the Moroni house?
Yes.
I heard about it.
You found some interesting solutions.
Art Nouveau, isn't it?
Mr. Terzi, when was the last time
you saw poor Augusta?
Three days before the murder.
She was blackmailing me.
I received anonymous calls,
a man's voice.
- It was him.
- Who?
The man who was with my wife.
They were in cahoots.
He was the one calling me.
He had a certain tone of voice,
like he was used to being in charge.
Why would they blackmail you?
They enjoyed watching me suffer,
humiliating me.
What form did this blackmail take?
One day, the man called me and said
he was going to put me on file
as a transvestite.
I think he's somebody important.
A military man, maybe.
Or someone from the tax office.
Augusta liked men with power.
His name?
Give me the name.
I don't know it.
If I knew it, I wouldn't be here.
I think he's the murderer.
It's just a feeling.
You've forgotten his name?
I never knew it.
Don't worry. it'll be okay.
Thank you.
Well?
- I think he's innocent.
- Innocent!
I think he's innocent.
At 4:00 p.m. on Sunday, August 24,
I killed Mrs. Augusta Terzi...
with cold determination.
There is one extenuating circumstance.
The victim systematically mocked me.
I left clues everywhere,
not to sidetrack the investigation,
but to prove...
to prove...
not to sidetrack the investigation,
but to prove...
to prove...
that I am above suspicion.
However...
However,
if you send an innocent man
to prison in your place,
then the fact...
then the fact that you're above suspicion
has not been proven.
POST OFFICE
1 .2 kilograms.
900 lire.
Is this package
really going to police headquarters?
Can't you read?
- I'd like to talk to Patané, news desk.
- Just a minute.
News desk.
- Hello? Patané?
- Who's this?
I can't tell you my name.
Your phone is tapped.
- What kind of joke is this?
- Hello?
Homicide received a package containing
the victim Augusta Terzi's jewels,
the killer's shoe and the razor blade.
This definitively exonerates the husband.
It's no use disguising your voice.
I recognize you.
VIVA MAO
In 1948, we removed 2,000 instances
of graffiti in favor of Stalin,
50 for Lenin, 1,000 for Togliatti.
Thirty for Marshall Tito.
300 for Mussolini.
411 for the Common Man's Front.
But in 1956, Stalin's fell to 100.
A huge drop.
- And Togliatti?
- Stable.
In 1958, we had 100 "Viva Khrushchev,"
50 for Mao Tse,
and 500 "Down with Stalin" also appeared.
I'd like to point out we had orders
not to remove those, obviously.
Last year, "Viva Mao" went up to 3,000.
Ho Chi Minh went up to 10,000,
Che Guevara, 1,000,
Marcuse, 11, both for and against.
And something new.
We found a couple "Viva Sade!"
The Marquis.
This year we expect 10,000 for Mao,
500 for Trotsky, 10 for Amendola
and maybe 500 or 600 for Stalin.
What are those two doing?
Go check them out.
See if they have passes
and where they're going.
Youth, youth!
Writing slogans on walls!
Young students and laborers
prowling around at night,
spouting their revolution on the phone,
in their classes, at their jobs!
Using up tons of red paint
just to insult us!
I know what needs to be done!
It'll take more than whitewashers to combat
this subversive, antiauthoritarian tide!
Pace went to the Homicide Division.
- Who's he talking to?
- Mangani.
MURDERER
We must send
our young officers back to school.
They must infiltrate universities, factories,
grow beards and long hair,
wear greasy overalls.
We must know everything,
control everything!
We'll use our own sons if we have to.
Hello, Chief.
Thanks.
- Antonio Pace's recordings.
- Right away.
- The Terzi case.
- What happened?
Important new developments.
I'll keep you posted.
- Hello, Chief.
- Hello.
Chief, I need your signature please.
Thanks.
- Antonio, where have you been all day?
- The police station.
Is the Political Division
hassling you again?
- No. I was at Homicide.
- How come?
It was about that woman
who was killed in my building.
- They're implicating you?
- No.
They want to know
if the tenants saw anything.
- What did you tell them?
- Nothing, of course.
- Not even that you slept with her?
- Bitch.
Shut up.
My phone's tapped.
Actually, since I'm here, I'd like
to talk to the cop that's on duty now.
Comrade, you have the degrading job
of unlawfully spying
on the birth of the Italian revolution,
but you're being exploited too.
Join us,
or at least ask for a raise.
Turn it off.
- Wait a second, Chief.
- What?
His ideas are truly abominable
except for that last one.
I've been working here 30 years
and still make 140,000 lire a month.
- So?
- If I didn't have culture to fall back on...
- What?
- I sell books in installments.
- What's that got to do with me?
- Nothing.
- I'll report you.
- Chief.
- Just a minute.
- News desk.
- Hello? Patané?
- Who's this?
I can't tell you my name.
Your phone is tapped.
- What kind of joke is this?
- Hello?
Homicide received a package containing
the victim Augusta Terzi's jewels...
Who does he remind you of?
...the killer's shoe and the razor blade.
- One of them is Patané.
- Yes, but the other one?
Did you receive this package?
We got it, but an hour after
this article was published.
So it can't be the husband
because we have him here.
He could have an accomplice.
I think Terzi's husband is innocent
and should be released.
Detective, this is my case.
The husband stays in jail.
All right.
- All right, Biglia?
- We'll keep him in jail.
When will you understand?
The man is innocent.
It's better if we hold him,
at least until the public forgets this story.
You're a bureaucrat.
You're afraid of public opinion.
Don't get upset.
Don't worry.
He's a reactionary, a Bourbon straight out
of the Kingdom of the Two Sicilies.
He just panders to the minister
and public opinion.
He's like an old pair of underwear.
He won't last.
Don't worry.
What do you want?
DRAMATIC TWIST IN THE TERZI CASE
Here you go.
What should I tell him?
- Tell who?
- Mangani.
About what?
He wants to know if I know who called me
about the package and the jewels.
Why ask me?
It was you.
Think about it.
How could I have called you if the package
hadn't arrived at the station yet?
It was you!
You can't go around
saying that I call you.
I don't call you!
I do favors for you,
and you'd better be careful.
This vending machine
makes great espresso.
I know, but I can't drink espresso.
Get a cappuccino.
You want me to get rid
of that vending machine?
Misticò, get back to work!
You too.
Get out of here, please.
Get out of here.
Bye.
I need your advice on something.
What's eating you?
Come along with me.
- If we don't help each other...
- A message.
Now what?
In this city,
they're not just killing prostitutes.
They're killing order and social stability.
Three sit-ins in 24 hours.
Homeless people, students, teachers.
The teachers!
Italians! In six months,
81 million hours' worth of strikes.
- Got an aspirin?
- No.
Chief, do you believe
Terzi's husband is innocent?
Of course I do.
There's only one way to prove
Terzi's husband is innocent.
- We have to find the man with the blue tie.
- We have to find him.
The blue tie you wore
the night of the murder...
- Where did you buy it?
- At Cenci's, near the Pantheon.
He sold two of them.
Yours we can rule out,
and he remembers selling
the other one to a woman.
Augusta Terzi.
So the victim gave the tie
to her murderer.
The victim gave the tie to her murderer.
Given their marriage,
I doubt she gave it to her husband.
That seems logical.
Count him out.
And me?
What can I do for you?
How can I help you?
Maybe you want my blue tie?
You can stop by my place.
Ask for it.
My cleaning lady's there in the mornings.
- Do you have an aspirin?
- I can really stop by your place?
You understand,
three sit-ins in 24 hours.
Students, homeless people, teachers.
Teachers.
- May I go?
- You know what?
- Compared to this, I prefer Homicide.
- Of course.
Thanks, Chief.
So if I need to, I can really
get the tie from your place?
How disgusting.
Take that undershirt off.
I promise your mother will never find out.
And change your shirt.
You look like a Swiss waiter.
You wear short socks like a priest
or a seminary student,
or rather like what you are:
a policeman.
Don't you have any brighter suits,
something happier?
- Something normal even?
- No.
People must change sidewalks
when they see you
because they can tell you're a cop.
You stink of barracks,
file rooms, jail cells.
At least priests smell like incense.
The authorities should hand out
free deodorant to their employees.
I could murder you
with my bare hands.
How brave.
You'd lead the investigation.
Who'd solve the crime?
- Would you do me a favor?
- Yes.
Would you go in there
and buy me all those blue ties?
The ones in the window.
Why don't you go buy them?
They'll think I'm a competitor
and take advantage of me.
- Do me a favor.
- It will cost a lot.
- How much?
- 50 or 60,000 lire.
Okay. Take what you need.
Satisfy my curiosity.
Why do they all have to be blue?
I'm a theater impresario.
- Pre-show stuff.
- I see.
The name of the revue is
"50 Blue Ties For 50 Babes."
Bravo.
Do me a favor.
I'll wait for you down there.
- Where?
- Under the colonnade.
Hurry up.
Here you are.
4,000 lire is your change.
You know what happened?
This is good.
They thought I was a cop.
They gave me a big discount.
One man even called me Sergeant.
Okay, here you go.
Count them. I got 25.
- What do you do for a living?
- What?
- Me?
I'm a plumber.
- A plumber.
- I work when I feel like it.
- Who did you vote for?
- Who'd I vote for?
Why do you care?
- Tell me who you vote for!
- For whoever I want! Why?
I'll keep one of these ties.
You keep the other 24.
What?
What's the meaning of this?
- I want an explanation, sir.
- I'll explain now.
Take these 24 ties
to the police station immediately.
Go to the Homicide Division.
I'm not a theater impresario.
I'm a murderer.
What did you say?
A murderer.
Do you read the papers?
Do you remember the lady
that was murdered on via del Tempio?
I killed her.
What are you saying?
A respectable man like you?
You're pulling my leg, right?
No, I'm not pulling your leg.
You're in trouble now.
Why am I in trouble?
I didn't do anything!
Shut up for a minute!
Let me tell you how it works.
Anyone who comes into contact
with a murderer is in trouble.
Run over to the police station,
Homicide Division.
Give them a detailed description of me.
Give them the time, the place,
the way that we met.
Look at me closely.
Describe me in detail.
You don't stand six inches away
from a murderer every day.
Examine everything.
Remember how I comb my hair,
if I have a mustache or not,
what I'm wearing, if I have a tie.
At least give me time to stop
by my house and see my wife and son.
Go to the police station.
Go to the police station!
- Give me time for a quick shave!
- Stop acting like an idiot!
Act like a citizen!
- Wait, listen.
- Go!
- Listen!
- Go to the police station!
Wait, listen!
Sir!
- Go to the police station!
- Come back.
Go on, run the red light.
You're above the law.
No, what are you asking me to do?
Go on, run it!
Run the red light!
- You want me to run the light?
- Yes, go!
You can do whatever you want.
- Go on, do it.
- I'll do it. Watch out.
- That's it!
- I'll do anything!
I'm going! I'm going!
There, you see?
The traffic cop's coming.
- Show him your nifty police badge.
- Obviously I will.
Show him you're an important man.
He'll be trembling!
Treat him badly.
Driver's license and registration.
Police.
- Hurry, please.
- Sorry, Chief.
You can commit any crime you want.
I'm telling you.
Good. You reminded me
of that decapitated girl in Castel Gandolfo.
Aquatic rape.
Do you think you could kill me here
without getting caught?
Theme: How a policeman commits murder
on a crowded beach without getting caught.
The parking attendant saw me,
the ticket collector,
the lifeguards
and the people in the cabana next to ours.
I'd say the parking attendant
is the most dangerous.
Yeah, right.
A parking attendant
reporting a big shot like you?
Impossible.
You'd have to sign a crime
with your first and last name to get caught.
- Otherwise, who would consider you?
- Augusta, don't tempt me.
It would be too easy for me.
Come on.
Come up with a nice crime.
I'll cut off your head and hide it.
No, I'll throw it in the sea
for the fish.
A lifeguard will find your body
in the cabana at sunset.
The magistrate, a guy from Latina,
won't examine you until the next day,
when you're in an advanced state
of decomposition.
What the...
Bitch!
Augusta!
Augusta, stop joking around.
Come out.
WOMEN
Augusta, let's go!
We need an official mandate
to demolish these brothels.
Augusta!
Use the pads, sir.
Your colleague stopped by this morning,
the young Neapolitan.
- What's his name?
- Who? Biglia?
That's it, Biglia.
- What did he want?
- I don't know.
He was looking for a tie,
but I didn't give it to him.
How could you have?
I'm wearing it.
Then you must have two of them.
I saw the other one stuffed
in your sneakers yesterday.
He wanted to look at your shoes too.
I knew he was a snoop right away.
He asked me loads of questions.
- What did he want to know?
- If you ever have women over.
- Anything else?
- If you have a girlfriend.
- Was that all?
- What you do on Sundays.
- Go in there. I've got work to do.
- I haven't finished, sir.
Finish later.
HOMICIDE DIVISION
Good morning!
- How are you, Homicide?
- How's life in the Political Division?
Morning.
To save you some time,
I brought you my tie.
What's wrong?
- What did he do?
- Murder.
I'd do it again!
He killed his employer.
Can you come in here for a second?
There's this guy...
- What's going on this morning?
- Sorry.
- Will you explain?
- Nothing.
He's probably a psychopathic liar.
This gentleman wants
to ask you a few questions.
Who is he?
- Well?
- Excuse me.
Excuse me, sir.
Maybe...
What am I saying?
I'm sure I've made a mistake.
About what?
- I mistook you for someone else.
- Who?
Earlier, he thought he recognized you.
He says that this morning
a strange man gave him
some money to buy all those ties.
Then he told him
he was Augusta Terzi's killer.
- And...
- Let him talk.
- Go on. Talk.
- Thank you.
Well, that's what happened.
I met this person
who told me to run straight
to the police station.
- Who was he?
- Who knows? Some maniac.
Maybe he was a theater impresario,
or maybe he worked in the cinema.
And I fell for it, of course.
He warned me himself
that I'd be in hot water.
- What do you do for a living?
- Me?
Well, I...
I'm a plumber.
- A tinsmith.
- Plumber.
Plumber?
Tinsmith.
- Tinsmith is an old word.
- Say that you're a tinsmith.
Yes, I'm a tinsmith.
- What did you say?
- As you just said, I'm a tinsmith.
- There's no reason to worry.
- I have your word?
- You can relax now.
- Thank you.
- You're a citizen.
- We respect our citizens.
- Well said. Thank you, sir.
Mangani, come with me, please.
At once.
I'll deal with you later.
- You set up this confrontation...
- No, the tinsmith came to us.
Without even following
proper procedure!
- It was Biglia, not me.
- Mangani, I'll have your head!
- Watch yourself!
- Go back into your offices!
What are you doing?
Go back to work.
- This is my fault.
- And you shut up!
I don't see so well anymore.
It can't be him.
He's wearing blue
and the other man was in beige.
- I have an idea.
- Let go of my arm.
I'm going to hold both of them,
Terzi's husband
and this idiot tinsmith with the ties.
- What do you say?
- You do your job.
I'll do what I have to do.
Now, my dear tinsmith,
you're going to tell me the truth.
You're involved in this,
and I'm going to screw you!
I got the cappuccino,
but it's too sweet.
You're supposed to take half
bitter coffee and half sweet milk.
Misticò, I'll put you back
on the beat in Piazza Navona!
Get that machine out of here!
If anyone asks, I'm not here.
Excuse me, Commander, are you alone?
Yes.
I wanted to ask if you authorized
the investigation of me
as a suspect in the Terzi case?
I'll request a detailed report
from the officer,
and you and I can talk about it
over dinner tonight.
That's not enough.
I demand that the entire Homicide squad
be put under investigation!
I have a powder keg in my office
that could blow up their entire system,
their public and private lives!
I've got dirt on everyone,
and you know it!
- Okay, but at your own risk.
- Of course.
Technician!
I need to withdraw three recordings.
Political Division.
The commissioner gave me orders
not to release anything.
- When did you get the order?
- I can't tell you.
Was it on paper or over the phone?
Please let it go.
What do you care if I borrow
three tapes for a couple hours?
Oh, I care! I'll lose my job.
- We all care about our careers.
- Exactly. In my small way, I care too.
Be patient.
Do me this favor.
That was a bomb!
- Get out of the way!
- Down there!
- It was by the ventilator, Chief!
- Stop!
Go back to your stations! Stop!
- Where was it?
- Down there.
Please, please!
Policemen only.
Everyone else, turn back.
You too. Out, please!
- Over here, Chief.
- Be careful.
- Be careful!
- This way.
This is a serious matter.
- Let me through.
- Let him through.
- Don't touch anything!
- Don't touch!
Don't touch anything.
This time, they really messed up.
Attention!
They're here.
They're coming.
This is the last straw.
It's unbelievable.
I just received the message:
There were two more attacks at 6:30 p.m.
One was at the American Express office,
the other at the courthouse.
- Let him through, please.
- Yes, let him through.
This is where the explosion occurred.
In my modest opinion,
we should act decisively.
We know each
and every one of them.
We have to show them how resolute we are.
They've gone too far!
I'm giving you all carte blanche!
- Is that clear?
- Very.
Good.
Let him through, please.
Let him through!
Death to the man!
Mao, Mao, Ho Chi Minh!
- Chief.
- What do you want?
Get out of here!
Check all their ID's!
No statements to the press for now.
- How many of them are our informants?
- Five.
Leave them all together until tonight.
What do you want?
No, what do you want?
You were looking at me.
Me? I'm half blind.
I'm not looking at you.
Mind your own business!
Hello?
Yes, I'm alone.
I'm in a hurry. What is it?
Alone.
Alone!
You're having a fit of jealousy
over the phone?
Why don't you just tap my phone?
Have me followed.
Hide a camera under my sheets.
You are in charge of 500 men.
Have me followed.
Then you'll know
who I see and what I do.
"I think it's time to end our affair."
Augusta, you can take
your sappy farewell letter
and shove it right between your legs!
You're running away?
I'm not playing the jealous boyfriend.
You can do whatever you want.
You can screw whomever you want.
I don't care.
But you have to tell me these things.
I want to see him.
We have to be accomplices.
You can't do this to me.
I'm a respectable man.
I'm somebody.
I represent power, Augusta.
You should kiss the ground
I walk on, got that, bitch?
Who is this Pace? Bitch!
He's a friend of mine who lives upstairs.
Young, handsome and a revolutionary.
A revolutionary!
- I'll hurt you!
- Get your hands off me, idiot!
You're not at the station.
You're in my house!
Get out!
I'm not one of those poor saps
who fall into your hands, got it?
You make love like a child
because that's what you are!
- Who do you think you are?
- Don't yell.
I bet you still wet your bed!
You're nobody, nobody!
You're incompetent,
sexually incompetent.
- Do you understand?
- Don't hit me!
- You're incompetent.
You're a child, understand?
You're a child!
Don't stand. Stay seated.
Nice sunset.
- We've been on our feet for 16 hours.
- We'll send you back to the barracks soon.
We're exhausted.
- Here.
- Long live the Cultural Revolution!
Chief, they have the same names
they did 30 years ago.
Revolution is like syphilis.
It's in their blood.
- Good evening.
- Evening.
Evening, Chief.
We can't take this much longer.
What a pain!
Murderers! Fascists!
Fascists! Fascists!
Spontaneists!
Even in jail, they fight.
In two hours, they've already
split up into four groups.
It's like a chain reaction.
It's a good thing they're not united,
or we'd have trouble.
I want to question Antonio Pace.
He has training.
But first send me the guy next to him,
the one shouting a lot, with the mustache.
That's what you are!
Servants of the man!
Hands off the floor!
Your entire weight
needs to be on your knees.
You're not a horse
who walks on all fours!
You're a citizen of a democracy,
not a horse.
You're not a horse!
What do you prefer?
Another quart of salt water
or staying on your knees?
I don't know. You decide.
If you decide to get up,
you'd better drink all of it.
You'd better drink all of it.
All of it.
Nothing.
Get back on your knees.
You shouldn't have drunk any of it.
You could leave here within 10 minutes
and drink your fill of fresh, pure water.
Clear, sweet, fresh water.
Student.
I don't want to put you on trial.
We're not the KGB or the SS.
We are the police of a democracy.
We're overjoyed when we can spare
a citizen a harsh sentence.
You're only a kid.
I don't want to ruin your future.
Sit up straight!
You can be a Marxist,
an anarchist, a situationist.
Mao, Lin Biao.
You can read the Little Red Book,
do whatever you want.
You're not a horse!
You're a citizen of this democracy,
and I have to respect you.
But terrorist attacks,
intimidation,
and bombs
have fuck-all to do with democracy!
If you tell me who bombed the police station
and the American Express office,
you'd be acting like a true democrat,
understand?
That's logical.
I know it wasn't you.
But I'm sure you know the name
of the guilty party.
Please give me some water.
We don't want you to rat out your friends.
We want you to act like a true democrat.
You understand me.
Let's talk as modern and civilized men.
What is this democracy?
Let's admit it.
It's the stepping-stone to socialism.
I vote socialist, for example.
Don't be afraid.
I'm your confessor.
Everybody talks here.
Nothing will happen to you.
I'm as silent as the grave.
This whole building is one big grave!
So, will you tell me the truth?
Are you going to tell me?
Will you tell me his name?
It was Pace!
Pace planted the bomb
the day he came to the station!
Did he make the bomb?
Mattone, bring in Antonio Pace.
This one's all done.
Come on. Get up.
It's all over. You're free.
If you ever need something,
just call me.
I didn't mean to.
Canes, Mattone, leave us alone.
Go get a coffee.
Leave me alone with the "comrade."
One of your friends just denounced you.
You don't leave prison with a PhD!
Best case, you leave as a bank robber!
Pace, Antonio.
Born in Ravenna, 1946.
Former chemistry student.
Independent anarchist.
Sentenced to three months in jail in 1968
for resisting the police.
What are you saying?
Do you know who I am?
I think you were the lover
of my downstairs neighbor.
- The one who was murdered.
- By whom and when?
I think you killed her
the afternoon of Sunday, August 24.
What time?
I think you must have killed her
between 5:00 and 7:00 p.m.
That's when we met
at the gate, as you know.
Since you're so sure I did it,
turn me in.
- You'd like that, huh?
- Turn me in!
You're here and that's where you'll stay.
A criminal leading the repression.
- It's perfect! It's perfect!
- Turn me in!
You have to turn me in!
I made a mistake,
but I want to pay for it.
Stop yelling!
Do your job.
- You have to turn me in because I'm...
- You turn me in!
Open up!
Next time we plan something,
I'll call you.
You're mine now!
Come back here.
You're acting like a child.
Let's discuss this.
Please, let's be sensible.
- I want out. Let me go.
- Stop him.
It's nothing.
Let him go. Let him go.
It's nothing. Let him go.
The student.
"You're mine now."
HOMICIDE DIVISION
How are you?
Did they call you in
for the Botta case too?
No, I'm here for the Terzi case.
The gorgeous woman
who was killed with a razor?
Shut up.
I told you both to shut up.
Hello, Chief.
- How's everything?
- Great.
- Pallottella?
- Present.
It's your turn. Come in.
Wait. I'll go first.
Pallottella, let's go.
Close the door.
Come on, Pallottella.
Come forward,
you little kiss-ass.
Move it, you son of a bitch,
piece of shit.
You little bureaucrat, playing cop.
You'll never understand
the full significance of my actions,
of my sacrifice,
with which I hope to reaffirm,
in all its purity, the concept of authority.
- Morons!
- What did I do?
I'm handing Augusta Terzi's
murderer over to you.
Thank you.
Starting now,
I'm at justice's disposal.
When you wish to interrogate me,
you'll find me at home.
- These things happen.
- Well, they shouldn't.
Don't worry. You'll be back
at home before the morning's out.
We'll see.
- This way, please.
- Sir.
From now on, you can safely
tell them you recognize me.
I don't recognize you.
I don't recognize anyone!
Help!
No! Help!
What have you done?
What about us?
What about your colleagues?
Do your duty.
"Article 247:
Cases in which house arrest
may be authorized.
When the circumstances of the crime
and the high moral character
of the prisoner so allow,
the district attorney...
or the judge may make
the following justifiable decree.
THE PENAL CODE
instead of being incarcerated in prison,
the prisoner may remain
temporarily under arrest
in his own home."
HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA
The Dean of the University of Messina
hereby confers...
Chief?
They're in the other room.
Come.
Sir.
Excellency.
I'm sorry to have inconvenienced
so many important people.
Eat this salt.
Where were you, dear colleague,
between 3:00 and 7:00 p.m.
the day of Augusta Terzi's murder?
Excellency, gentlemen,
I was there because I killed her.
Can you prove you were at her house?
I have some bad news.
There is a witness.
Unfortunately, the student Antonio Pace,
a notorious subversive,
saw me enter the building.
That's not true.
The student Antonio Pace
has a watertight alibi.
He wasn't in Rome that afternoon.
I questioned him for hours,
my dear colleague,
and I did it my way!
Excellency, the bloody footprints
discovered in Augusta Terzi's apartment.
Not to interfere in the investigation,
but they came from my left shoe.
My dear friend,
there are thousands of shoes
of that size and model.
I own a pair that's identical.
- So do I.
- Perhaps.
But I left fingerprints
all over her apartment,
even on the shower faucet.
Because, gentlemen, Excellency,
I took a shower afterwards.
Strange.
Everyone left fingerprints on the faucets,
cups and door handles, except for you.
Yes, but the blue thread discovered
under her fingernail comes from my tie.
So, give us the tie
with the missing thread.
- I destroyed it.
- Why?
In that moment I was torn between
confessing and putting you on my trail
or using the little bit of power
I had to cover up my trail.
A split personality, dissociation.
Neurosis.
A disease I probably contracted
from my prolonged exercise of power.
It's an occupational disease,
common to those who hold the reins
of our helpless little society in their hands.
I'm healthy.
Enough psychology!
We need tangible proof of your guilt.
Not just words, but facts.
I made that poor idiot we arrested
buy those 25 blue ties.
That's not true.
He didn't recognize you.
Yes, but we can admit
what happened, between us.
He denied it out of fear
when he started to realize who I was,
a police officer.
I will not tolerate these
opinions and insinuations
against your colleagues,
the force, our institution!
Let's talk specifics.
Your motive.
- What was your motive?
- She made fun of me!
She made fun of me and our institution!
Our institution!
That means all of you, gentlemen!
That's not a demonstrable motive.
Please excuse me, Excellency.
Gentlemen, excuse me.
This is private.
It won't take long.
I rely on your discretion, Excellency.
Every day that I was with her,
my childishness and my inadequacies
became more and more apparent.
Absurd! Impossible!
Science fiction!
Well, then, I murdered her
out of pure jealousy!
- You didn't know her.
- Go on. Prove it.
She wasn't your mistress.
Nobody ever saw you together.
That's right.
Just a moment, gentlemen.
I'll bring you the evidence of my guilt.
I'll be right back.
You killed a worthless person.
Someone else would have killed me.
Sooner or later,
I was destined to die that way.
Do what they tell you.
Think of your colleagues.
Think of your career.
Excellency, gentlemen,
these photos prove the victim
was photographed right here.
Check the furniture, the floor.
Here the victim strikes erotic poses
that perversely imitate crime photos!
I exploited the situation
for my love of amateur photography!
Disgusting!
Look what we've come to.
I'm at my wit's end.
He's an immature child.
I always said he had no team spirit.
- See what things have come to?
- I'll petition the court!
Here's to your health.
I'll do whatever you want.
Well done, son.
Do you have anything to say?
I confess to my innocence.
Now sign here.
Everything's all right.
Calm down.
Gentlemen, colleagues,
let's not forget there's still an enemy
out there who knows the facts.
He'll use them not only against me,
but against all of us,
against power, against God!
That's a score we'll have to settle.
Come in.
Make yourselves comfortable, gentlemen.
"No matter what impression he makes on us,
he is a servant of the law.
Therefore, he belongs to the law
and does not answer to human judgment."
INVESTIGATION
OF A CITIZEN ABOVE SUSPICION
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from OpenSubtitles.org