Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS today
Golshifteh Farahani
Taraneh Alidousti
Shahab Hosseini
Merila Zarei
Mani Haghighi
Peyman Moad
Rana Azadivar
Ahmad Mehranar
ABOUT ELLY
Scenario: Asghar Farhadi
With the participation of A. Jafarian
Editor: H. Safiyari
Image: H. Jafarian
Producers:
A. Farhadi
S. M. Razavi
Written and directed by
Asghar Farhadi
It was funny, huh?
Yes, but I have to pee.
That'll teach you to excite yourself like this.
Stop somewhere if you can.
Honey, you're not at school.
Don't bother poor Elly.
It does not bother me.
I take her to the toilet.
Shall I take this?
- Didn't you tell the others?
- What?
She was there.
I didn't know it myself until last night.
She doesn't even take too much room.
- You okay?
- Yes, thank you.
She's a nice woman.
Wait one day.
and They'll all fall in love with her.
Forget it, I'll do it.
But no, I'm used to.
Peyman!
You drive too fast.
- You drive too slow Amir!
- It's dangerous!
Amir, is there something in the air?
- What?
- That means you don't know?
I swear, I don't know anything.
Sepideh did not tell you
why she brought her?
Not at all.
You must promise me not to say anything
when we are together.
Seriously, Ahmad,
it's a good girl.
You really think so?
She will turn your life upside down.
You have seen this all in just 10 minutes?
Sure. You can see it right away.
Not true, Naazy?
It is natural.
Already three votes.
I said she was kind
nothing more.
Wait until tomorrow, none of you will dislike her.
Don't you worry about it. Let them do what they like.
If you find any other girl like this, keep her for me.
Could someone slap his head for me please?
Manoochehr!
Did you see this, Ahmad?
Well done!
You deserved it.
Oh, really?
Sepideh, does this girl know
that Ahmad was married before?
I don't know.
And that she forced him to divorce her?
Well laugh a little.
Stop, Peyman!
What's her name again? Miss Elly!
-Miss Elly!
-Peyman ...
Elly!
Stop!
You're going to embarrass her, stop!
Here is the charcoal samovar.
Do you know how many years I haven't drunk
this kinda tea! Poor me!
Ahmad, how did you do in
Germany?
I lost my grip!
That's why
your German wife left you.
She told the judge:
"Achtung! Pachtung" This man is mad! "
Peyman!
Am I lying?
Amir could you help me?
I'm going.
So what?
It's not you that I called ...
- Was there a problem?
- Not at all
You know, they are teasing and kidding a lot.
Please don't get anything wrong.
Is that all?
Builds up the group.
Enjoy a few of these three days.
- Three days?
- Of course!
Madam ...
You see I was right
for the address.
For once it's me
that's wrong ...
Good morning.
Could you hand me the key to the villa?
- The Villa in the forest?
- The same as last year.
Bahri?
You were all together?
Yes, in college.
My sister Naazy.
Here Elly.
We already met.
Really? Sure ...
- Is it here?
- No, the key is here.
Accompany them to the villa.
We know the path.
We just need the key.
How are you?
Very well, thank you.
Don't forget about tomorrow evening.
- What?
- To leave earlier.
Because the owner arrives in the afternoon
from Tehran.
so you have to leave in the evening.
But we want to stay three days.
I already told one of on the phone.
It was me.
So we can't do anything about it?
For us, it wouldn't be a problem.
But it is the owner.
He did not know
we wanted to stay for 3 days?
We already told you on the phone.
I thought you had all provided for!
Everything was full. I took it
thinking that we could find something else.
Something else?
At this time of year? That's impossible.
I'm sorry.
It's not your fault madam.
Why didn't you tell me?
If I said it, we weren't here now.
It's okay.
We will find some other place.
At the phone, you didn't tell me that there is no chance.
But if ...
Can't you do anything?
But what?
If it was just us, we would find
some place to camped.
But we have guests with us,
a pair of newlyweds.
May God bless.
The groom is from Germany.
It's something like a honeymoon.
What about the villa of Mr.Mahmoudi?
That is taken.
We would go anywhere.
- And the one at the beach?
- That of Sadeghian?
- It dons' have any good windows or doors.
- you will be very cold at night.
And it is dirty.
We could clean it. Can we see the place?
Go get the key from your uncle.
Thank you very much.
What a beautiful sea!
What else, my mother?
Arash.
Are you sure it's the right key?
Attention don't hurt yourself.
Here we go!
Okay, Ahmad! It's open.
How did you get in, you?
Be careful not to fall.
How filthy!
Be Careful!
Wow it's so huge.
Be careful there's glass on the floor.
The air conditioning works.
Where are the toilets?
It has no locks. Will you watch?
If you use the toilet,
they won't take it back!
Very funny ...
We will spend our time
to do the housework. Careful!
Do not worry!
Hey little boy, are there gas containers here?
- With a vacuum cleaner, This would go faster.
- You go sit down.
Peyman, It will be cold at night.
Just cover the windows with something.
Wait, you're not alone.
I can make a suggestion?
- Tonight ...
- But it is good here!
Just let me say something?
Go ..
We go into the other house tonight
and come back here tomorrow.
We have to moved again then tomorrow!
The toilets are not intimate
but they work!
This is crucial!
It's beautiful here.
Beautiful.
We can't spend
three days just thinking what to do!
- Now what?
- We vote.
Elly, what do you say?
I take care of the cleaning.
And you, Shohreh?
I propose
we go look elsewhere.
A vote against.
And you, Naazy?
I am the voice of my master.
Then her master?
We should stay.
And you, Peyman?
I say no,
as my master.
You're stupid!
Two votes against.
Two against five, we stay!
And me, my vote
nobody cares ...
Oh my!
- Where are you going?
- I get a broom.
Fetch the luggage?
Lets clean up first.
Once we start it will take a while.
Sepideh?
Do you have the keys?
- Hey boy what is your name?
- Omid.
Omid, are there any shops
around here?
- What do you need Ahmad?
- Cigarettes.
I'll handle this.
Thank you.
Put it down, I'll take it.
Arash!
Come in, darling. You're soaked!
Peyman, call your son.
I will spend the whole weekend
looking after him.
Relax! We came
with the whole band.
I can't expect from everyone
not to go  to the sea because of our son.
Come, my darling.
Peyman, look if you find
the water heater.
Isn't it inside?
-No
-Then we have a problem
Cutie!
Yes? What's up?
So?
Sorry
- You scared me.
- Sorry!
I'll throw it away.
- Does it fit through?
- Yes, I think so.
Up.
- It doesn't fit. Wait.
- No, it's locked.
Give me that.
No it doesn't work!
Bend it a little.
You see, it worked!
I come and help.
Wait, you'll cut yourself!
Be careful not to cut yourself.
I'm here, Morvarid.
Sepideh!
Who sleeps where?
Who cares. We do as we can.
Women in the rooms,
and husbands in the living-room.
I am not separating from my wife.
Then you both in the living room.
- Shohreh?
- Yes?
I'm coming.
We will spend a hell of a night!
We'll dance to keep warm.
And those who can not dance?
We'll teach you.
Go get her!
- What?
- Go ahead., Run!
Don't let the opportunity pass!
It won't look good!
Ok leave me. I'll go.
Arash!
Get out of the water, quick!
Go see in the kitchen.
Well, Ahmad, your smokes.
Come back here! Hurry!
Go get him.
I said come here, you rogue!
You're all wet!
Look at that!
Elly!
- Looking for the lady?
- Yes.
She went to phone.
There 's no mobile phone connection here.
Stop screaming.
Hurry.
You have to go buy light bulbs.
Ahmad, listen!
Elly went to phone.
Take her for a ride.
Leave her a little peace.
There is still no hot water.
I put the water heater on. It's coming.
The 3 Days will pass soon
and you didn't do a thing.
What are you looking for?
Ahmad goes shopping.
I told him
to fuel the car.
Here, the keys.
I come back tomorrow.
I'll be there around midnight.
By bus, yes.
Do not worry.
I will be with a colleague.
She's fine.
Mom, if someone calls,
don't say that I left town.
Say you don't know where I am.
Do you still have any pain?
Love.
Yes, I am careful.
We're all colleagues, I say.
Okay.
I'll call you.
There 's no connection here.
We talk later.
Love. Goodbye.
Could  you call?
Yes, thank you.
Was she worried?
My mom is always worried.
She just had a heart surgery.
Recently?
A month ago. The doctor
told her to avoid stress.
If I had called 1 hour later,
she probably would have had a heart attack!
"Hi, Mom.
Yes, I'm fine and you?
"Of course I eat ..."
She thought I was dying of hunger in
Germany.
Once at the airport,
they opened my suitcase.
A jar of pickles
broke!
It reeked of vinegar!
I was ashamed of my life!
She must be happy
that you came back.
She died two years ago.
I'm Sorry.
When I was in the midst of a divorce.
She has suffered, poor one.
I can ask a delicate question?
Is it about my honor?
No.
Go ..
Why did you separate?
From which one?
You are not obliged to answer me.
Why are you Interested?
I do not know.
To find out, anyway ...
To find out anyway ...
One morning we woke up,
we took our shower,
and at breakfast, she said:
"Ahmad,
"Besser ein Ende mit Schrecken ...
"..als ein Schrecken ohne Ende."
What?
Go ahead. Repeat.
- What?
- Besser ...
ein Ende mit Schrecken ...
I can not, sorry!
You want me to stop?
No, I know who it is.
I call back later.
So what does it mean?
A bitter end is much better than
a bitterness without ending.
It's true.
A little music.
- You're so late.
- A little, yes.
Did you have fun, Ahmad?
Good morning.
Arash, help bring these inside, little man?
At night it's cold.
Here is the bed for the newlyweds.
We are all newlyweds!
But the all-new
lovebirds ...
Where are they? Show them to me.
Congratulations!
I wish you happiness!
What are you doing?
You have dinner with us?
No thank you.
Just keep the doors locked.
And your cars
are not protected here.
Dinner is served.
Go. I shut the door.
Eat well, Ahmad.
You will not get this food in Germany.
Especially not for free!
Children, come!
Why are you standing. Go sit down.
Come on, Elly.
Ahmad, make a little room.
- It's ok here.
- Go ahead dear.
Ahmad is going to be sad.
Manoochehr!
Push yourself a little.
Does anyone need anything?
I'm coming.
- I get you some salad?
- I will do it, thank you.
- You are shy.
- No, I am ok.
Here.
Are you crazy?
Don't use it all. It's for the toilet.
Eh, Amir!
- The toilet?
- We're at the table!
And the salt?
It's in the kitchen.
Manoochehr, c'mon.
I forgot the salt?
You've washed your hands, my cowboy?
Please take some.
Congratulations.
Long live the newlyweds
Eat, it cools.
Elly, dear did you find it?
Thank you, how nice.
Who wants salt?
Enough.
Put this on hold.
Why are you guys out here alone?
Ahmad, what are you doing here?
Stand up!
Why?
- How did it go?
- What?
When you were out.
He is already stiff crazy about her.
I'm in love
Passionately in love
Stop it. Seriously.
At the end of the weekend, we will vote.
If the majority says yes,
I'll ask for her hand.
If not, no.
The majority, is them?
We, we all agree.
And you, Amir?
- It's not my business.
- Give your opinion.
- She is a nice girl.
- Is that all?
Yeah.
She is warm, quiet.
I like her.
- Really?
- Yes.
Seriously?
She seems uncomplicated.
And you, Manoochehr?
She is nice.
-Can I say?
- Ok
You laugh at me.
She is great.
- Really?
- I swear.
I'm going, you can talk now.
Can you bring us
two teas please?
Come join your families instead!
No, don't touch it!
Fire! Fire!
What did you do to us?
Stop exploiting my girlfriend.
It's your girlfriend she won't stop.
We like you even if you do nothing.
- Give this it to me.
- I wanted to make some tea ...
I leave it there.
Come on, girls.
We'll do that tomorrow.
- Come, let's sit.
- We will.
- How do you find her?
- She is nice.
A little too reserved, no?
She is embarrassed, poor one.
Four words.
Second word.
Bird?
Flight?
Fly!
Insect?
Bee!
Third word.
Honey!
Bravo!
A honeybee ...
Box?
Beehive?
Television?
Cartoons?
It is a title?
Maya the bee?
The first word?
Baby?
Mother?
The mother of the honey bee!
Two words?
Is it two words, my honey?
Mother?
Child?
Baby?
The second word?
Mustache?
Your daddies mustache?
Boy?
Dad?
The father of the child?
Bravo, my darling!
Five words?
Second word.
Child?
Bigger?
Many?
A bunch of kids?
Third word.
Framework?
Television?
Blackboard?
School?
Fac!
Young people in college?
Fourth word.
Balance?
Justice?
Right!
Fifth word.
Summer? Heat?
Is it hot? Fire?
First word.
The first.
Breathing? Life?
Long live the law school kids!
I go inside, folks.
- Why?
- I have to care of something.
We were about to crush them.
Here we go!
Elly!
We go shopping.
Do you need anything?
Two minutes, I come too.
- Tell me what you need.
- Ineed to get my ticket.
In your dreams!
Shohreh ...
Sepideh ...
Wait ...
Arash.
No, it's impossible
- Close the door.
- There is nobody, come on.
I really have to go back this afternoon.
No, it's impossible
Don't you like it here Elly?
No, Naazy, it was expected.
I said
I would stay just one night.
The guys should clean up.
Arash, you stay beside the water.
What an outfit.
What a short journey for you then.
You won't find a bus.
You'll have to walk home.
- Then I will.
- By foot?
Come on, lady!
My mom is going to argue, my dear.
You come, Shohreh?
Sepideh ...
I would stay if I could.
- You must stay.
- My mother will be worried.
- Naazy, you watch the children?
- Yes.
I tell her
that you have been kept by force.
If it's like that
I'll grab a taxi by the side of the road.
I really have to leave.
If she wants to leave
don't force her, Sepideh.
I wish I could stay.
Sepideh knows why.
We came together.
And we leave together.
- 'Till later
Amir ... keys!
Amir, where are the keys?
On the terrace, with my mobile phone.
Give it, be nice...
Be nice ...
Arash, darling ...
- Don't go further away.
- Okay.
Play a little and go inside.
Naazy, watch him, please.
Don't forget the onions.
What did she say?
To buy onions.
Relax,
we'll make a good soup tonight.
Nice ring.
Thank you.
Elly dear, please watch the children?
I'll clean up a little.
What's up?
Please fix it for me.
Ok.
Come hold it.
I have to go now.
Daddy!
Yes, darling?
Daddy! Arash!
Come here.
Let Arash alone.
Arash ...
Itake care of your dad, here!
Daddy! Daddy!
- Dad, Arash!
- Morvarid?
Arash is in the water!
Arash!
Where is Arash?
There!
My God!
He was in the water?
Who watched you?
Go see
if he is inside!
Arash!
Is he here?
He is in the water!
Amir!
His shoes!
Manoochehr!
Ahmad! Ahmad!
Ahmad!
On the other side!
To your left!
He is there, Ahmad!
He is here!
Look it breathes.
Look if he breathes!
Put him there.
On the side,
to empty the lungs.
Raise his head.
Wake up, my son!
Arash!
You've left the Children like that?
Where were their mothers?
Elly was with them.
Ahmad!
Elly!
- Was she in the water?
-Morvarid was playing, she didn't see her.
Morvarid!
Where was Elly?
- Inside?
- No.
And if she was with Arash?
Elly!
What happened?
Naazy?
What ...
Arash!
Was Elly in the water with you?
Why?
- Hey, was she in the water, too?
- She dissappeared!
Young man, help!
Run! Go ahead. "
What a catastrophe!
Peyman?
Arash?
Don't be afraid.
It's Elly.
Oh no!
She wanted to save Arash ...
Where is my son?
Inside.
Sepideh!
Please help!
Who is in the water?
Elly!
Elly?
Sepideh!
Do not go!
What happened?
- We didn't find her.
- Do not stop!
The sea is rough.
You can't just stop like that.
Wait!
Take me.
She may be trapped
between the rocks.
Let us go!
Take me, I beg you!
You didn't look over there.
That's where they found the child.
We can not leave her like that.
At daybreak
the sea will calm.
Where are you going? I beg you.
She  may still be alive.
We searched
for over half an hour.
Pity! If she is alive ...
She can't be alive anymore.
Did I ask you?
Sepideh! Go inside!
Shohreh, take her!
Peyman, don't let them leave.
The sea will bring back the body.
If you browse the beach tonight
you will find her.
Sepideh!
Sepideh.
They want details
Her identity.
She was playing with her kite
and she saw nothing.
You've seen her go into the water?
- No.
- What did you see?
- Arash screaming in the water.
- And then?
This is my son.
I called my father
to come save him.
Okay. Are you sure the woman
went in the water?
I asked her
to watch the children.
What was her name?
- Elly.
- Elly?
Elham Elnaz, Elmira ...?
The full name.
Don't you know her?
She called Elly.
What was your relationship with her?
It was my daughter's teacher.
My wife invited her.
You don't know the name
of your daughter's teacher?
I will ask.
You bring
someone from Tehran
without knowing anything about her
and we
we have to rely on a child?
What's her name?
I don't know.
You don't know her name?
Unfortunately, she does not know.
Have a look in her bag.
She must have any papers.
I would like the identities
of you.
And your papers, please.
Who is the owner of the villa?
Ahmad!
Her bag is not there!
Just search a little better.
I searched, there is nothing!
Naazy, give me Peyman's bag ...
Shohreh, her bag is not there!
It must be in her room.
What if she left?
Didn't you say she was with the kids?
She was ready to go.
She wanted to go by foot.
Not true, Shohreh?
Would she leave
without saying goodbye?
And why is her purse gone?
My God ...
Sepideh!
What's her number?
- Who?
- Elly.
I'll call her cellphone.
What are you talking about?
- The bag ...
- What?
It is not there.
Maybe she did really go.
Nobody saw her going in the water.
I had to keep it hidden.
I should have let her go.
My God ...
Mom!
God curse you, Sepideh.
We have to notify his family.
Wait and see
if the body shows up tonight.
Maybe she really has left.
Left where?
It's over.
She died.
We should call them tomorrow.
They will not make the road
at night ...
Today will be a lot of traffic.
It's gonna be hell.
Oh my!
Damn!
Amir ...
If she had drowned
we would have found the body.
Wake up,
we must do something.
You've done enough already.
Wake up, I say.
For what?
Well, I'm awake.
LetÂfs go look at the bus station.
I don't know what to tell you ...
Damn me.
Yes damn me.
There may be a chance
that she left.
Listen, I'm talking to you.
I don't want you to talk to me!
You fucked up
and you want to talk?
Listen, I'm exhausted, too.
Why did you invite her?
OK, it's my fault.
So what can we do now?
Nothing more.
You didn't need a consulter
for inviting her?
- I thought that Ahmad ...
- Who are you, for Ahmad?
His mother?
His sister? Who are you?
What's up Amir?
Why should it be her fault?
It's not her fault.
Nothing ever is.
I told her to invite Elly.
You shouldn't have!
Why didn't you ask someone else?
You'll wake the children.
For so many years
you don't know this fool?
Who could have predicted
she would come with us ...
She always takes care!
You want to go to sea
Ask Sepideh!
People want to meet:
You look for a villa:
Sepideh!
You need a ticket:
You wanna get married;
Sepideh!
Go inside, we find a solution.
Solution?
He have to call the parents.
Okay. For now let's go inside.
Kids, the one who tells it the best
will get  a huge gift.
Go ahead and start.
What you did, you?
I was with my kite.
And then?
Arash was in the water.
And where was Elly?
She was up there.
On the terrace.
What were you doing?
I asked her to
set my kite.
She came and played with
the kite. And then I saw Arash.
When your kite was up there
was Elly with you?
Look at me. When you, were there
was Elly staining over there,
where Naazy is standing now?
She was there at the beginning.
And after?
I ran after my kite to
the other side.
And there I saw Arash.
You saw Arash.
Stop it, Arash.
Anita? Have you Elly
leave the villa?
- Look at me.
- I have not seen.
Morvarid, darling,
when your kite
fell into the water,
and Arash was drowning,
was Elly there?
Or was she leaving the house?
- She was there.
- Okay.
When you came to call
and we played volleyball,
you know, when you cried,
Elly was still there?
She was there before that.
Before, how long?
A little.
What is a little sweetie?
1 to what?
1 ... 2 ... 3 ... 4 ...?
1 ... 2 ... 3 ...
I don't know.
And you, Arash, darling?
When you were in the water,
Did Elly come to help you?
Raise your head and answered correctly.
I answered a hundred times yesterday.
Sit down and answer well!
- I'm hungry.
- Get out of here then!
Peyman!
What way is that to behave?
- I was in the water, I saw nothing!
What is wrong with you?
He answers strangely!
Since yesterday evening
you mistreat this child!
That's it, go away and shut up.
I am silent
and take everything?
You let him alone at
the edge of the water!
Has told you not to take
a villa on the beach!
Anita, come.
Any News?
Nothing since yesterday evening.
Why should she gone?
Who knows.
She would have taken her bag.
But Sepideh had hidden it ...
Sepideh,
Could Elly have done such a thing?
What thing?
Leaving without saying anything.
I don't know.
Why you did you hide her bag,
then?
You thought that she could
leave like that.
The other night as she disappeared.
He was looking everywhere.
It was because of her phone connection.
She wanted to make a call.
Without saying a word.
- It's different.
- What?
- Why should she leave?
- In spite.
What?
She may be upset.
Why?
Did anyone notice anything?
Or say anything upsetting to her?
Dad, I'm hungry.
The other night,
When I served grill
and you arrived
the lady brought the beds,
she began to clap and sing.
And you, Shohreh,
you made noises.
It seemed Elly was upset.
Noises? It was a joke.
I just thought.
And for dinner?
When she went to get the salt
we all laughed.
But that was just a little fun.
We all laughed.
She too laughed.
All this jokes, the dancing,
Could that have embarrassed her?
Yesterday morning
she insisted on leaving,
as if she was worried about something.
I told you not to force her to stay!
She was just over there.
You told her as a joke
she should go by foot
and she said: "Ok I will."
Sepideh?
You who know her
Was she such a person?
To be offended and leave?
Take offended by what?
She doesn't even know her name.
How does she know?
Amir, stop quibbling.
We try to move forward.
When we did the dishes,
Sepideh, you said something,
And Shohreh said:
"We like you even if you do nothing."
I think that offended her.
But I didn't mean any harm.
I know. I say that there
may have been a misunderstanding.
Please don't start
blaming me for that too!
I didn't blame you.
She must be very immature
to be offended by a sentence like that!
Calm down, we are just talking!
Did you see how they all look at
my son since yesterday evening?
Nothing you said offended her.
Ahmad, I talk about that!
Even if she was offended,
that's not a reason to leave.
If she is reasonable.
But if she
really just left like that
without saying anything, she really is a. ..
Peyman ...
We were told this place is open
to everybody. And if someone ...
What are you talking here?
Call Tehran,
see if she returned.
It's too early. It's 7:30.
So it is 7:30 !
I can't take it anymore.
Ahmad, come, we'll call.
No, you don't move.
Ahmad, you go alone.
- Why?
- You stay here.
- But how ...
- Don't make it worse!
It is better a woman calls.
Sepideh is the only woman here?
I could go too.
But if they say she's not back ...
Just thinking about it, makes me shake.
- Amir, let me ...
- I said no!
Ahmad, let's go.
I come with you.
It's Okay, I'm going.
Come Manoochehr.
Ahmad ...
Sepideh, you give me her home number?
You want me to go with them?
Ahmad is going.
Go get a breakfast
for the children.
They may stay one day
without breakfast.
For one day, they will not die!
Keys.
What a weekend!
Go ..
No, wait.
The other wheel is also stuck.
Ahmad!
It's stuck in sand.
Come down, we'll make it.
If her mother answers, say nothing.
Why?
The other day she told me
she has heart problems.
I don't wanna shock her.
A foreign person drowned because of
our child. You understand that?
And your only problem,
is to go on my nerves?
Do not talk like that.
I told you  a 100 times not
to talk to me like that in public.
Like what?
I have no other concern now?
How am I talking?
Like you did before.
I have always been the same
since college.
And in twenty years,
I will still be the same shit I am now.
I want to go to Tehran.
- You can not ...
- I want to go.
Shohreh ...
I want to go.
The sound of the sea
drives me crazy.
My son peed his bed.
Everyone disrespects him.
Am more worse than you all.
The image of this girl
does not leave me ...
Sepideh, you have an aspirin?
Take paracetamol in my bag.
Aain her  mother.
Do not hang up this time.
You say it is her heart ...
Just say that you are
a student's parent
and you want to talk with her.
At this hour?
What if this province number shows up?
Say you're the husband of a girlfriend.
Sepideh should have come.
What a honeymoon
I am so sorry ...
Thank you, my boy.
Honk.
Where you going?
I was worried.
- Was she in Tehran?
Get in.
What happened?
Did she have family problems?
Why?
Her mother was very evasive.
She was not back then?
She said she went out for a minute.
Thank you, my God.
No, wait.
At first she said that
I asked if she returned from the trip.
She said: "What trip?"
- What?
- She lied to me.
In addition, she said
that Elly left her mobile phone at home.
But she had it with her.
She asked me ten times
who I was.
Did her family know
she came with us?
Didn't she call her mother,
the other night?
Yes, but her mother ...
His mother ...
She answered really suspicious.
Maybe because we hung up
several times before Éshe was suspicious.
But if she had confidence in her daughter
why be suspecious?
How long do you know her?
Not long.
What happened?
Nobody piked up the phone.
Damn what a bummer!
You should've tried again.
Ahmad ...
We tried ten times.
Sepideh.
Come here.
What's up?
Where is her phone?
Why?
Let's call a number in
her phone.
She's took it with her.
Where's That?
I don't know.
Why are you asking me this?
Come here.
- What is it?
- Tell me what you know about her.
What I know about her?
Whose is that?
It's hers, right?
- Where was it?
- In your bag.
Why is her mobile phone in your bag?
I forgot.
I found it yesterday
by the windows.
Don't lie to me!
What is wrong with you?
Leave me alone.
Stop! Asshole!
What's the matter?
Why don't you speak?
Bitch!
Amir, are you not ashamed?
Get off!
Don't you meddle with it!
Don't you meddle with it, Shohreh.
Get in the car.
You should be ashamed!
Peyman, lets return to Tehran.
She is dead!
Now you want
to kill us, too?
I'm not staying here.
- What did you do?
- She lies to me.
I want to know ...
Why is her phone
in your bag?
What the hell?
You'd better
shut up Ahmad.
Leave it Ahmad.
Nobody said anything here?
You do as you like.
Me, I'm leaving!
You go, Sepideh.
Ahmad!
Go back, please.
Morvarid, go inside, my dear.
Peyman ...
It makes me crazy.
We will send the women
and children in Tehran.
She forced me
to raise my hands on it.
We can't just leave.
Everybody wants to go.
Let's go, Mom.
It's hard for the kids.
You go ..
I've got to stay.
Sepideh,
your presence will not change anything.
I can not, Peyman.
Naazy ...
She's hurt.
Sepideh, listen to me a bit ...
No, Ahmad.
If this girl really just left
silently,
is it worth
you give yourself all this trouble?
For a girl you don't know nothing about?
- Peyman ...
- No, really?
Peyman.
And if she drowned because of Arash,
isn't she worth it?
Who says she drowned
for my Arash?
And I didn't even said
she should watch my child that ...
Let her, if she wants to stay.
We are discussing, Peyman.
Why bother?
Was it me who invited her to the sea
and who kept her from leaving?
No, it was me.
You leave and leave me alone.
Get EllyÂfs phone from Amir.
Amir ...
Give me EllyÂfs phone please.
Thank you.
How can I unlock it?
Call one of the numbers.
What time did I go out
with her the other night?
About ten o'clock I think.
She received a call, she rejected
saying she would call back.
Call this number then
and tell the truth.
I think we should stay, too
If her family comes here and sees 4 guys,
isn't it weird?
Her mother was already very suspicious.
I thought no one answered?
Wait for me. I'll call.
We'll see what happens.
Have you spoken to her mother?
She didn't even know Elly
came on this trip.
Come Manoochehr.
- Where are the keys?
- On the car.
The car.
What a strange girl.
How did we find her phone?
In Sepideh's bag.
Naazy was looking for pills
and  found it.
Wait, Ahmad.
Where are you going?
- Making a phone call.
- Who?
The Number that
called the other night.
- I come with you.
- You know your husband ...
I come.
I call and I'll be back.
Mom, I'm coming too.
Ahmad ...
Go alone.
Shohreh told me to watch
the Children.
Do you remember the pantomime game?
At one time, Elly said:''Gladiolus.''
Like a premonition. She felt
what would happen to her.
All this was written.
Nobody is responsible.
I had a dream.
What dream?
A nightmare.
I can't forget it.
Shall we turn around?
No. Drive a little more.
- She hasn't returned?
- No.
Who did you talk to?
- Her brother.
- You told her?
I described Elly.
I said
I found his number on her Phone.
If he knows where
she is.
He was surprised that
I have her phone.
I asked what their relationship was.
He said he was her brother.
But he doesn't know where she is.
I had to tell him the truth.
- You said that she drowned?
- No, I couldn't.
I said we had an
accident here in the north.
and that she was in the hospital.
He was surprised
that she is in the north.
She didn't tell her family.
That's why
she wanted to return so eagerly.
And now he comes here?
Yes, he will.
He arrives around 16h to Chalous.
How are we gonna tell him?
We have to somehow.
One woman has to come with us.
- A women has to come.
- What?
One of you must go.
Stop, Ahmad. I feel bad.
You haven't eaten anything.
Do you need anything?
Should I take Naazy instead?
It's not his brother.
Who?
One who is coming.
She told me
she was an only child.
So who is this guy?
I think ... her fianc?.
Who's fianc??
Elly's.
What you're saying, Sepideh?
She was engaged?
What have you done?
If you knew she was engaged,
why did you introduce her to me?
She wanted to break up.
She tried for 6 months.
The guy won't leave her.
Oh God ...
I had hidden her phone
so no one could call him.
Is that him?
The one with the bag?
I don't know.
Hello, how are you?
You've arrived?
We are on the spot.
In front of the surgical clinic.
Imam Reza.
The Clinique Imam Reza.
Where? A green sedan?
I don't see it.
On the other side of the bridge?
At the entrance to the ring ...
Yes, very well.
I'll be right there.
We have a Patrol.
Well, see you soon.
- He came by car?
- Yes.
- You drive back with him.
- No.
We have no choice.
I have to drive ahead
and warn the others.
He doesn't know, that we
know he is her fianc?.
Okay.
I drive and tell the others.
You drive with him.
- Be very careful.
- I know.
Good day.
- Are you Ali Reza?
- Yes.
Ahmad. Delighted.
Have you been here long?
Did you have the accident?
No, one of our friends.
In which hospital is she?
- WeÂfll take you there.
- How is she?
- We better hurry.
- Go ..
Could you give me her phone?
It is at the villa.
Tell me about ...
I'll tell you.
Ahmad, you go.
I tell you.
Where do we go?
We take the bypass.
Please talk to me.
We told you on the phone.
Is she alive?
Yes, but she's not doing good.
She is in a coma.
Oh, my God!
She was not supposed to come here.
When was the accident?
We talk on the road.
Madam, stop confusing me.
You've seen her papers.
What is her name?
Elly.
Elly appears
on her papers?
Elly is the teacher of my daughter.
We did not want to scare you.
She came with us
for the weekend and...
What are you waiting here?
And the story of the accident?
I'm sorry. Let's go.
What is it?
I'm not on my plate ...
- Me neither.
- Keep your donkey mouth shut.
- Go away mister!
- Shut up!
Hi, Ahmad!
Good morning.
Amir!
Peyman, Shohreh!
Where is Amir?
Come Naazy, quickly.
Peyman, come.
So, Ahmad?
Hurry, Amir.
Come all.
Hurry. he is coming.
You told him?
He is not her brother.
It is her fianc?.
She has a fianc??
Damn!
What does that mean?
The bottom line is that he believes
we are not aware.
She came here
she dragged with you,
and is engaged?
Pity, Peyman, now is not the time.
How did you know?
One of her girlfriends
called on her cellphone.
I told her about the accident
and the arrival of her brother.
She told me Elly
was an only daughter.
I asked who this man was.
ÂgProbably her fianc?,Âh
she said.
Why did she come with us
if she is engaged?
She didn't look like
such a person.
She did.
It's just us who are ...
naive.
So, if it is,
she did not drown.
Maybe she really just left.
If this guys finds out
why we brought his bride here,
we are in big trouble.
Now what?
We pretend to know nothing.
He is the brother.
Elly is the teacher of Morvarid.
The childs wanted Elly
to come with us.
She agreed. That's it.
I beg you
get a grip of yourself.
What if Elly hasn't drowned?
I don't know ...
Where is Sepideh?
They drive together.
She is aware of everything?
Yes, I told her.
She is supposed to
tell him about the drowning.
What an actresses makes us all
going crazy!
I have to warn the children.
Where are they?
Arash ... Morvarid ...
Children, come here.
Listen to me.
You know why Elly
came here with us?
To watch me
not to go in the water.
- Bravo that's good.
- But no.
- Why then?
- Can I say?
She came to fall in love with you.
Me?
Who told you that?
I saw myself.
No, you're wrong.
It was a joke, all that.
Did you hear that, honey?
That's why she was sad
and she left.
No, my heart,
she was not sad.
She wanted to save Arash
and she drowned.
She is still in the water?
Morvarid listen. You too.
Elly's brother is coming here, ok?
It is a very serious
and is angry man.
You have to promise me.
Kids you have to promise...
not to tell about
our jokes.
- What jokes?
- Those mentioned by Arash.
When we played,
we danced, we laughed.
We used to play pantomime.
Don't say anything.
If he asks a questions,
you say:''We do not know.''
-''We do not know.''
- Bravo.
Can you say that too Anita?
Good.
Did she tell him?
Don't go out.
Wait on a sign of Sepideh.
Come in.
No, okay.
Where did it happen?
There.
- Come, go.
- I want to be alone for a moment.
What a quiet guy.
I swear he knows.
There must be
a reason for everything.
Shhh! Here he comes.
Do you a sedative?
No. Toilets?
This way.
- Thank you.
- I beg you.
Did he tell her parents?
Not yet.
Elly didn't tell you about him?
Amir!
Shohreh, you have a towel?
No, thank you.
Can I be alone somewhere?
This way.
Go ahead. I beg you.
Could you bring him a clean bedcover?
There is no connection here.
But I talked to her the other night.
Must have been
when she was out.
Excuse me ...
just a second.
Did she talk about me?
Yes, she talked a lot about you
and her parents.
What did she say?
That she misses you very much.
She spoke well of you.
She was worried for her mother.
I think her mother ... your mother
is a heart patient?
Naazy ...
- Sorry.
- Are you coming?
It's not his brother. Why do
you she missed him?
She spoke well of him?
I didn't know what to say.
Did he suspect anything?
No ... I do not know.
Don't you want to eat anything?
I just have to make a
call to Tehran.
- I accompany you.
- Okay.
You can leave the bed of the
newlyweds, I'll take it.
Thank you.
Her poor husband was there this morning
but I did not want to bother him.
- The husband of who?
- From the drowned.
Her husband was here this morning?
Madam, could you come here please?
Peyman!
He knows!
The old woman told him.
She said that the bed
was for Elly and her husband.
Damn!
Where is he?
I guess he is coming.
Do something.
There's nothing more to do.
We have to say the truth.
We wanted to pair his wife
with someone?
We didn't know.
It is true that we knew nothing.
The best thing is to tell the truth.
But say what?
She didn't tell us
she was engaged.
Otherwise, we would never
present her to Ahmad.
Don't tell about Ahmad.
What else should we say then?
Among the cops
we'll have to confess everything.
Does he know she came
for Ahmad?
He is not stupid. He understood.
He was suspicious before coming.
Why does he pretend
to be her brother?
- We tell him everything.
- No, I beg you.
So what, Sepideh, lying?
We can't.
He knows anyway.
We have no choice, Sepideh.
- He will find out.
- Elly will be dishonored.
We dishonor her?
I respect the dead
but an engaged woman
looking for a husband.
This means:
1, she fooled us all,
2, she fooled her fianc?.
Fooled?
Obviously.
If you, you have a boyfriend
and your boyfriend
finds a girl better than you
for the weekend,
to play volleyball ...
Where's the harm?
You don't understand.
From our point of view,
there is no harm.
Put yourself in the position of the boy,
and everything is evil.
From the money she has given
to cleaning and staying here!
That was all a show she played for us!
We must decide now.
She gave up that nice boy.
I was ashamed of myself
when I saw him.
The the noise I made the other night ...
Hurry.
Ahmad, tell him
we thought she was single.
She lied to us.
- We say the truth.
- Please don't.
We lie to him
to save the honor of Elly?
The dead have no need of honor.
- I won't let it happen.
- Too late.
- Ahmad, don't let them ...
- Peyman come here.
I knew it.
She had told me.
I swear.
I'm not lying this time.
On the head of my daughter.
I told Ahmad
he was her fianc?.
Ahmad, why don't you tell them?
There is nothing more to say.
I told her
a friend arrived from Germany
and I was asked ...
to submit a woman.
She said she doesn't want
to get married.
That she has a fianc? for 2 years
and wants to break up.
She didn't love him.
He made her suffer.
Her family are against it,
and he also wouldn't let her go.
I offered her to meet our
friend Ahmad during his brief stay.
She said no,  not
until I haven't broken up.
I sent Ahmad a photo of her,
and he liked her.
So, I insisted her to come.
And she said ...?
She was determined to break.
I told her, if my friend
won't return to Iran anytime soon.
You should meet him just once.
She still refused.
Finally, she agreed
provided that it remains a secret
and just for one night.
She had told me.
You insisted her to come.
But she wasn't forced to come?
I begged.
I said that I had everything planned.
My God!
We can at least save her honor.
If we say we really didn't know
she had a fianc?
would he believe that?
Who would believe that?
What does it change
if he believes it?
Anyway,
she did wrong by coming here.
But I insisted.
It's not a reason.
Tell the truth.
You say you didn't know.
Me, I say that I knew.
Everything is my fault.
Come what may.
You're unconscious!
He'll lynch you!
Too bad.
And then he sees us as a whole.
To him we are all acomplices.
Amir, do something.
I can't take it anymore.
Sepideh, just listen
for once in your life.
It is more than you and me.
We should all be together.
Ahmad
What do you think?
We tell him.
We say the truth.
Ok.
And you, Manoochehr?
We really didn't know
she was engaged.
Now we learned too late.
And you, Shohreh?
I have not the heart
to lie to this poor boy.
And you, Naazy?
I bow to the majority.
The majority seems to go
for the truth.
We were not aware.
Me, I was.
But you're alone.
And you just told us a minute ago!
He is coming.
Come, let's go together.
Peyman, watch out.
And the children? Arash?
Stay here, Sepideh.
Come Naazy.
Please don't make the
situation any worse.
What will he think about Elly?
Arash, Anita,
Morvarid, come quickly.
Ahmad!
Let me see, Ahmad!
Asshole!
Raise your head.
You are bleeding ...
I can put my hand on the Quran
to swear that we are telling the truth!
On the life of my children!
Dear Sir
there was no reason to lie to you.
We came here with our families.
We did not organize
a meeting
between your fianc? and our friend.
We're not crazy!
If we had had the slightest suspicion,
we would not permit.
What is this discussion?
- Lets go sit down.
- You shut up!
Shut up, asshole!
- Stop!
- Go back, Ahmad!
That's enough!
We suffer for
two days!
No one has eaten for 2 days!
I ask!
I just want to
be told the truth!
I proposed to call the police.
You will see the report.
To hell with the police.
We can not lie to the police.
This will be a proof.
I don't want it!
It's the law, sir!
- Am I talking to you?
- Do you mind!
Come here, Shohreh, come.
Who brought Elly here?
My wife.
- She know her from the kids school.
- Where is she?
Inside.
I want to talk to her.
She is very ill.
Worse than me?
She sleeps.
We told you already.
I have a question to ask.
We go to the police ...
We'll go, okay.
- I want to talk ...
- She just fell asleep.
Do not be afraid.
I won't get any worse than this!
Where is she?
Madam!
Wait here.
I'm going.
Shohreh, call Sepideh.
I wanna talk to her alone.
Shohreh!
He is not guy you
can tell anything to.
He bashed Ahmad.
I say this for your own good.
Please, Sepideh,
Get up.
Go wash your face,
I call him in.
Get up, darling.
It was you who invited her?
Yes, it's me.
Can I sit down?
When you told her to
come and meet your friend,
she said nothing?
Can I say something,
before?
- Elly ...
- Listen to me.
I just want to know something ...
Sit.
It's yes or no.
- When she knew ...
- But ...
... Didn't she say no?
Didn't she say no?
I can't come, I have a fianc??
Did she?
Listen, really ...
Really, it ...
For me, it's important.
I gave her three years of my life.
You can sit too?
Didn't she refuse?
Yes or no?
No, she did not refuse.
Alireza,
the police called.
They have now found
the body of a woman in water.
You have to go identify her.
They called the house.
Amir!
Mr. ...
Wait, we all come with you.
You recognize her?
My condolences.
I would like my keys.
Will you
tell the family?
Do it yourself.
It would be better if you told them?
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS