1
00:00:28,125 --> 00:00:32,699
CONTEMPT

2
00:00:38,958 --> 00:00:43,122
Based on the novel
by Alberto Moravia.

3
00:00:45,667 --> 00:00:49,706
Featuring Brigitte Bardot
and Michel Piccoli,

4
00:00:52,833 --> 00:00:56,201
Jack Palance and Giorgia Moll,

5
00:00:59,708 --> 00:01:02,291
And Fritz Lang.

6
00:01:06,708 --> 00:01:09,826
Photography by Raoul Coutard.

7
00:01:12,792 --> 00:01:15,910
Music by Georges Delerue.

8
00:01:19,167 --> 00:01:23,331
Sound by William Sivel.

9
00:01:24,958 --> 00:01:28,076
Editing by Agnès Guillemot.

10
00:01:30,458 --> 00:01:35,203
Produced by
Philippe Dussart and Carlo Lastricati.

11
00:01:36,750 --> 00:01:40,368
A film by Jean-Luc Godard.

12
00:01:42,625 --> 00:01:47,370
Shot in Cinemascope
and printed in colour by GTC Labs.

13
00:01:48,792 --> 00:01:53,411
Produced by Georges de Beauregard
and Carlo Ponti for Rome-Paris Films,

14
00:01:53,583 --> 00:01:58,373
Films Concordia and Compagnia
Cinematografia Champion.

15
00:02:05,667 --> 00:02:11,288
Andre Bazin said: "Cinema shows us
a world that fits our desires."

16
00:02:14,042 --> 00:02:17,114
Contempt is the story of that world.

17
00:02:31,583 --> 00:02:34,371
I don't know.

18
00:02:34,542 --> 00:02:39,366
Maybe I'll go to Mum's.
I don't know what I'll do afterwards.

19
00:02:41,417 --> 00:02:47,993
Come pick me up if you want.
At 4 o'clock. At Cinecittà.

20
00:02:51,042 --> 00:02:53,909
I have to talk to that American.

21
00:02:56,042 --> 00:02:58,454
Maybe I will.

22
00:03:01,792 --> 00:03:06,616
- See my feet in the mirror?
- Yes.

23
00:03:08,500 --> 00:03:12,494
- Think they're pretty?
- Very.

24
00:03:14,708 --> 00:03:20,078
- You like my ankles?
- Yes.

25
00:03:22,292 --> 00:03:25,739
And my knees, too?

26
00:03:26,792 --> 00:03:30,239
Yes. I really like your knees.

27
00:03:33,292 --> 00:03:36,000
And my thighs?

28
00:03:37,500 --> 00:03:39,912
And your thighs.

29
00:03:44,500 --> 00:03:48,118
Do you see my bottom in the mirror?

30
00:03:49,792 --> 00:03:52,079
Yes.

31
00:03:54,417 --> 00:03:57,739
Do you think I have nice buttocks?

32
00:03:59,208 --> 00:04:01,575
Yes. Very.

33
00:04:04,417 --> 00:04:08,365
- Shall I get on my knees?
- No.

34
00:04:10,250 --> 00:04:16,121
- No need to.
- And my breasts. You like them?

35
00:04:16,292 --> 00:04:23,414
- Yes, tremendously.
- Gently, Paul. Not so hard.

36
00:04:25,875 --> 00:04:27,957
Sorry.

37
00:04:29,083 --> 00:04:35,409
Which do you like better,
my breasts or my nipples?

38
00:04:38,958 --> 00:04:42,622
I don't know. Both equally.

39
00:04:45,250 --> 00:04:50,666
- And do you like my shoulders?
- Yes.

40
00:04:51,500 --> 00:04:57,121
- I don't think they're round enough.
- I do.

41
00:04:59,667 --> 00:05:02,375
And my arms?

42
00:05:10,250 --> 00:05:12,833
And my face?

43
00:05:15,208 --> 00:05:18,576
- And your face.
- All of it?

44
00:05:18,750 --> 00:05:23,244
My mouth, my eyes,
my nose, my ears?

45
00:05:23,417 --> 00:05:29,868
- Yes, everything.
- Then you love me totally.

46
00:05:30,917 --> 00:05:36,959
I love you totally,
tenderly, tragically.

47
00:05:38,958 --> 00:05:41,450
So do I, Paul.

48
00:05:44,875 --> 00:05:50,325
Hi. How are you?
What's going on? The place is empty!

49
00:05:50,500 --> 00:05:55,040
Jerry fired nearly everybody.
Italian cinema is in trouble.

50
00:05:55,208 --> 00:05:59,953
- Where is he?
- Over there.

51
00:06:39,833 --> 00:06:42,621
Only yesterday
there were kings here.

52
00:06:48,625 --> 00:06:51,037
Princesses, lovers...

53
00:06:54,542 --> 00:06:57,455
All human emotions.

54
00:07:03,792 --> 00:07:06,625
Yesterday he sold everything.

55
00:07:10,125 --> 00:07:13,447
They're going to build
a supermarket.

56
00:07:15,583 --> 00:07:20,999
- It's the end of cinema.
- I don't think cinema will ever die.

57
00:07:27,000 --> 00:07:32,040
He says you wrote <i>Toto against
Hercules.</i> It's doing well in New York.

58
00:07:32,208 --> 00:07:34,916
Not bad.

59
00:07:39,958 --> 00:07:45,203
Don't be modest,
You need pride to make good films.

60
00:07:45,375 --> 00:07:50,040
- Do you know <i>The Odyssey?</i>
- Your film with Fritz Lang?

61
00:07:54,083 --> 00:07:58,657
- It's not working out.
- Why did you hire Lang?

62
00:08:04,250 --> 00:08:10,576
The Odyssey needs a German director
because a German discovered Troy.

63
00:08:10,750 --> 00:08:15,074
What should I do?

64
00:08:27,792 --> 00:08:34,289
He needs new scenes for The Odyssey,
not only more sex, but more...

65
00:08:34,458 --> 00:08:37,905
Like all producers,
he doesn't know.

66
00:08:49,542 --> 00:08:54,161
To know that one doesn't know
is the gift of a superior spirit.

67
00:08:57,042 --> 00:09:00,910
Not to know and think that one knows
is a mistake.

68
00:09:05,000 --> 00:09:08,994
To know it is a mistake
keeps one from making it.

69
00:09:11,125 --> 00:09:13,708
I don't think Lang will accept.

70
00:09:17,292 --> 00:09:24,164
In '33, Goebbels asked Lang to head the
German film industry. Lang left Germany.

71
00:09:36,542 --> 00:09:41,457
This is not '33 and Mr. Prokosch
knows you'll do the job.

72
00:09:41,625 --> 00:09:44,117
Why?

73
00:09:47,375 --> 00:09:53,246
He'll tell you during the projection.
This way.

74
00:10:24,625 --> 00:10:28,698
So... Why?

75
00:10:32,042 --> 00:10:37,867
- Because you need money.
- How does he know?

76
00:10:45,833 --> 00:10:50,282
He was told you have
a very beautiful wife.

77
00:11:07,458 --> 00:11:10,905
Each film should have
a definite point of view.

78
00:11:18,917 --> 00:11:22,035
It's the eternal problem
of the ancient Greeks.

79
00:11:32,542 --> 00:11:36,740
It's a fight against the gods.
The fight of Ulysses.

80
00:12:32,417 --> 00:12:34,829
This is Minerva, isn't it?

81
00:12:36,542 --> 00:12:39,079
She's Ulysses' protector.

82
00:12:41,917 --> 00:12:46,081
And that's Neptune,
his mortal enemy.

83
00:13:29,125 --> 00:13:32,322
Mr. Prokosch likes gods.

84
00:13:35,167 --> 00:13:37,909
He knows how they feel.

85
00:13:51,917 --> 00:13:55,330
Look, that's Homer.

86
00:13:55,500 --> 00:14:01,041
The gods did not create man,
man created gods.

87
00:14:11,708 --> 00:14:14,496
It's a mermaid.

88
00:14:24,833 --> 00:14:28,827
That's art,
but will the public understand?

89
00:14:39,292 --> 00:14:42,580
- Who's that?
- Penelope.

90
00:14:50,083 --> 00:14:53,280
Mr. Prokosch has a theory
about The Odyssey.

91
00:14:53,458 --> 00:14:57,497
He thinks Ulysses' wife
was unfaithful.

92
00:15:14,875 --> 00:15:20,450
O my brothers, who braved
100,000 perils to reach the West,

93
00:15:20,625 --> 00:15:26,496
don't refuse to know, by following
the sun, the uninhabited world.

94
00:15:27,917 --> 00:15:33,037
"Consider your origin.
You were not born to live as brutes,

95
00:15:33,208 --> 00:15:36,655
but to pursue virtue and knowledge."

96
00:15:38,417 --> 00:15:43,366
- Have you heard that before?
- Yes, it's very famous. Dante.

97
00:15:45,500 --> 00:15:48,868
"Night then looked all the stars.

98
00:15:58,292 --> 00:16:02,661
Our joy soon turned to tears

99
00:16:05,458 --> 00:16:08,746
until the sea closed in on us."

100
00:17:11,708 --> 00:17:17,329
- I'm Paul Javal. Mr. Prokosch...
- I know.

101
00:17:17,500 --> 00:17:20,618
It looks swell.
I really like Cinemascope.

102
00:17:20,792 --> 00:17:26,242
It wasn't made for people
but for snakes and funerals.

103
00:17:49,958 --> 00:17:54,282
What's the matter, Miss Vanini?
Is it about the script?

104
00:18:24,458 --> 00:18:28,782
He says it's not the same
on screen as on paper.

105
00:18:43,000 --> 00:18:45,412
I'll just see if my wife's arrived.

106
00:19:00,458 --> 00:19:06,704
...the Nazis used to say "revolver"
instead of "cheque book".

107
00:19:23,917 --> 00:19:27,535
Are you going to accept the job?
Yes or no?

108
00:20:03,125 --> 00:20:08,871
"But Man, when he must, can stand
fearless and alone before God.

109
00:20:09,042 --> 00:20:14,367
His candour is his shield.
He needs neither arms nor wiles

110
00:20:14,542 --> 00:20:18,615
until such time
as God's absence helps him."

111
00:20:18,792 --> 00:20:23,707
- That's Hölderlin, isn't it?
- Yes. <i>The Poet's Vocation.</i>

112
00:20:25,083 --> 00:20:29,327
The final line is obscure.
Hölderlin originally wrote...

113
00:20:33,042 --> 00:20:38,492
- "So long as God is not present."
- And then...

114
00:20:41,583 --> 00:20:44,621
"So long as God is close to us."

115
00:20:44,792 --> 00:20:51,494
The way the last lines are written,
when you've read the other two,

116
00:20:52,458 --> 00:20:55,780
is no longer about God's presence.

117
00:20:55,958 --> 00:20:59,246
It's God's absence
that reassures Man.

118
00:20:59,417 --> 00:21:02,990
Strange, but true.

119
00:21:04,667 --> 00:21:09,491
How do you say "strange" in Italian?

120
00:21:23,792 --> 00:21:26,409
I'll be back in five minutes.

121
00:22:01,625 --> 00:22:05,448
Meet Mr. Prokosch.
Camille, my wife.

122
00:22:14,000 --> 00:22:16,708
- My wife, Camille.
- How do you do?

123
00:22:16,875 --> 00:22:19,663
- Fritz Lang.
- Hello.

124
00:22:19,833 --> 00:22:22,951
He's the one who did
that western with Dietrich.

125
00:22:23,125 --> 00:22:27,323
- It was terrific!
- I prefer M.

126
00:22:27,500 --> 00:22:30,788
We just saw it on TV.
I really liked it.

127
00:22:30,958 --> 00:22:33,791
Thank you. That's kind of you.

128
00:22:33,958 --> 00:22:39,124
I love the scene
when Ferrer leans on the scales.

129
00:22:39,292 --> 00:22:42,865
Thank you.
When I finish The Odyssey...

130
00:22:46,583 --> 00:22:50,907
Mr. Prokosch is inviting you
for a drink.

131
00:22:51,083 --> 00:22:52,915
I don't know.

132
00:22:56,792 --> 00:23:01,207
- He says you know perfectly.
- Me?

133
00:23:05,208 --> 00:23:07,495
Yes, I could have a drink.

134
00:23:13,583 --> 00:23:16,450
Goodbye, I'll phone you.
Madam.

135
00:23:23,500 --> 00:23:25,912
We'll go if you want.

136
00:23:29,083 --> 00:23:32,326
Sit down, madam.

137
00:23:33,833 --> 00:23:37,997
- You won't be comfortable...
- I'll meet you there.

138
00:23:38,167 --> 00:23:41,990
- Mr. Prokosch will come back for you.
- No, I'll grab a taxi.

139
00:23:42,167 --> 00:23:45,330
Let him go on ahead.
We can both take a cab.

140
00:23:45,500 --> 00:23:47,582
Make up your mind.

141
00:23:47,750 --> 00:23:51,618
Come on, you go.

142
00:24:33,292 --> 00:24:35,499
What's the address?

143
00:25:45,583 --> 00:25:50,532
- What did he say?
- My English is as bad as yours.

144
00:25:55,000 --> 00:25:59,745
We've been waiting half an hour.
What kept you?

145
00:26:10,667 --> 00:26:13,409
Nothing. I had an accident...

146
00:26:13,583 --> 00:26:19,124
I was in the cab,
and at the corner of the street...

147
00:26:19,292 --> 00:26:25,288
Two cars, you know...
The whole bumper was hanging off.

148
00:26:25,458 --> 00:26:29,827
Then the two drivers
started shouting at each other.

149
00:26:32,250 --> 00:26:37,245
- I needed another cab. That's why...
- That's why, what?

150
00:26:39,625 --> 00:26:45,325
What? Why I'm late.
I had to walk God knows how long...

151
00:26:45,500 --> 00:26:49,824
From Saint-Ange to Piazza Venezia
to find a cab.

152
00:26:54,083 --> 00:26:56,950
Yeah, it took ages.

153
00:27:03,792 --> 00:27:08,616
Anyway, I don't give a damn.
I'm not interested in your story.

154
00:27:12,875 --> 00:27:15,663
It took me 20 minutes.

155
00:27:19,083 --> 00:27:22,371
- You don't believe me.
- We'll discuss it later.

156
00:27:24,375 --> 00:27:26,867
I'm going for a walk.

157
00:28:06,125 --> 00:28:10,665
- Come tomorrow to sign the contract.
- All right.

158
00:28:13,167 --> 00:28:16,330
Camille, why are you so quiet?

159
00:29:01,667 --> 00:29:06,412
Friday we shoot in Capri.
Come with us.

160
00:29:06,583 --> 00:29:11,373
Answer her.
Why don't you speak?

161
00:29:13,750 --> 00:29:18,324
- What were you doing before I arrived?
- Nothing special.

162
00:29:18,500 --> 00:29:21,618
Why? Did he come on to you?

163
00:29:23,125 --> 00:29:26,948
- Why ask me that?
- Just because.

164
00:29:33,583 --> 00:29:36,200
I should wash my hands.

165
00:29:43,583 --> 00:29:47,531
- Where can I wash?
- Upstairs, on the right.

166
00:29:54,542 --> 00:29:58,957
- What's the matter? You look down.
- Nothing.

167
00:30:01,375 --> 00:30:05,164
Have you been crying?

168
00:30:06,375 --> 00:30:10,994
- Your boss is a hard man.
- He is.

169
00:30:13,833 --> 00:30:16,951
Known him long?

170
00:30:20,250 --> 00:30:26,826
- What did he do before movies?
- I don't want to talk about it.

171
00:30:27,000 --> 00:30:30,948
I was just asking.

172
00:30:31,125 --> 00:30:34,743
It's stupid to be so sweet
and so sad.

173
00:30:34,917 --> 00:30:38,865
Haven't you anything
more amusing to say?

174
00:30:39,042 --> 00:30:41,955
More amusing?

175
00:30:43,542 --> 00:30:46,034
A funny story.

176
00:30:47,333 --> 00:30:50,451
Which one shall I tell?

177
00:30:52,167 --> 00:30:56,957
I know, the one about
Sri Ramakrishna and his disciple.

178
00:31:02,250 --> 00:31:06,824
Ramakrishna was a Hindu sage.

179
00:31:07,000 --> 00:31:12,916
He had this disciple who didn't believe
in his master's teachings anymore.

180
00:31:14,125 --> 00:31:19,165
He decided to study on his own.
So he went away.

181
00:31:19,333 --> 00:31:23,702
After 15 years, he came back
and said: "I've found it!"

182
00:31:23,875 --> 00:31:26,333
Found what?

183
00:31:26,500 --> 00:31:31,995
He tells the sage: "I'll show you"
and takes him to the riverbank.

184
00:31:32,167 --> 00:31:36,957
The disciple crosses back and forth
walking on the water.

185
00:31:37,125 --> 00:31:42,746
And he says: "You see? I can cross
without getting wet, now I know."

186
00:31:44,833 --> 00:31:47,541
So Ramakrishna replies:

187
00:31:47,708 --> 00:31:52,623
"You fool! I did that 10 years ago
with a rupee and a rowboat!"

188
00:31:57,833 --> 00:32:01,952
Feeling better now?
That's good.

189
00:32:03,708 --> 00:32:06,826
- Paul.
- What?

190
00:32:09,000 --> 00:32:13,494
- Call that washing your hands?
- As you can see.

191
00:32:13,667 --> 00:32:18,582
- I was just telling her the joke...
- I believe you already.

192
00:32:18,750 --> 00:32:21,583
You're being an idiot.

193
00:32:21,750 --> 00:32:25,698
- Where can I pee?
- Up there.

194
00:32:35,417 --> 00:32:39,786
It's a book about Roman paintings,
it will help you.

195
00:32:39,958 --> 00:32:42,450
<i>The Odyssey</i> is in Greek.

196
00:32:50,833 --> 00:32:53,541
He knows.

197
00:33:12,000 --> 00:33:15,038
What? About what?

198
00:33:28,375 --> 00:33:31,493
About the money and your wife.

199
00:33:45,250 --> 00:33:48,368
Mr. Prokosch is inviting you
for dinner.

200
00:33:48,542 --> 00:33:51,375
I'm tired, I'd rather leave.

201
00:33:54,000 --> 00:33:56,662
Tell them we're leaving.

202
00:33:59,542 --> 00:34:02,614
We're leaving then.

203
00:34:07,708 --> 00:34:10,496
If you decide about Capri,
call tonight.

204
00:34:10,667 --> 00:34:16,083
- We must get the villa ready.
- Paul will call you.

205
00:34:18,125 --> 00:34:21,288
Why don't you come?

206
00:34:21,458 --> 00:34:24,246
It's my husband who decides.

207
00:34:32,250 --> 00:34:35,117
What interests you about The Odyssey?

208
00:34:35,292 --> 00:34:39,035
I don't know yet.

209
00:34:39,208 --> 00:34:43,372
Maybe because it's the opposite
of today's films which I hate.

210
00:34:45,542 --> 00:34:49,206
I'd like to return to Griffith
and Chaplin.

211
00:34:50,917 --> 00:34:53,875
Like in the days of United Artists.

212
00:35:01,167 --> 00:35:05,206
The wise man does not oppress others
with his superiority.

213
00:35:08,958 --> 00:35:13,077
He doesn't humiliate them
for their impotence.

214
00:35:31,375 --> 00:35:36,950
He's crazy!
Did you see? He kicked me!

215
00:35:37,125 --> 00:35:42,791
You change your mind fast.
Monday you thought he was terrific.

216
00:35:50,250 --> 00:35:55,745
Now I think he's a jerk.
I have a right to change my mind.

217
00:36:02,000 --> 00:36:04,708
What happened in the past hour?

218
00:36:04,875 --> 00:36:08,413
Nothing. If you're happy, so am I.

219
00:36:34,375 --> 00:36:37,663
<i>Rio Bravo</i> is playing in town.

220
00:36:40,250 --> 00:36:43,288
So is Nicholas Ray's <i>Bigger Than Life.</i>

221
00:36:43,458 --> 00:36:46,871
I'm not interested.

222
00:36:47,042 --> 00:36:50,535
- I wrote it.
- I know.

223
00:36:52,333 --> 00:36:55,871
I phoned your mum's at lunchtime.
There was no answer.

224
00:36:56,042 --> 00:37:00,366
We ate here.
I didn't feel like going out.

225
00:37:05,083 --> 00:37:09,122
I like living here.
It's better than a hotel.

226
00:37:09,292 --> 00:37:12,000
See? I was right.

227
00:37:13,792 --> 00:37:16,454
What are they paying
for the script?

228
00:37:16,625 --> 00:37:20,163
10,000 dollars. Six million lire.

229
00:37:20,333 --> 00:37:24,702
We can finish paying off the flat.
Isn't that great?

230
00:37:24,875 --> 00:37:27,537
Yes, it's great.

231
00:37:38,083 --> 00:37:43,203
When will you call your friend
about the curtains? It's annoying me.

232
00:37:43,375 --> 00:37:45,912
Once he's back from Spain.

233
00:37:46,083 --> 00:37:48,791
Roberto said he'd be back on Friday.

234
00:37:54,042 --> 00:37:57,706
Red velvet. It's that or nothing.

235
00:37:57,875 --> 00:38:00,287
Okay.

236
00:38:00,458 --> 00:38:06,613
- Set the table while I take a bath?
- I wanted to take a bath, too.

237
00:38:06,792 --> 00:38:09,830
You go first. I can do some work.

238
00:38:12,792 --> 00:38:15,989
No, I'll go later, while it's cooking.

239
00:38:17,125 --> 00:38:21,369
You're cooking <i>fagiolini</i> again?

240
00:38:22,667 --> 00:38:25,125
Yes, whether you like it or not.

241
00:38:25,292 --> 00:38:29,616
- I can set the table.
- I was just doing it.

242
00:39:08,792 --> 00:39:14,583
I bought myself something today.
Tell me what you think.

243
00:39:14,750 --> 00:39:17,412
What did you buy?

244
00:39:23,250 --> 00:39:24,786
What?

245
00:39:24,958 --> 00:39:29,077
- Don't look yet.
- You want to go to Capri?

246
00:39:37,250 --> 00:39:41,915
- What?
- You want us to go to Capri?

247
00:39:45,583 --> 00:39:48,371
I won't say no,
but I won't say yes either.

248
00:39:48,542 --> 00:39:50,783
It would be like a holiday.

249
00:39:53,083 --> 00:39:57,202
- Anyway, he didn't invite me.
- What?

250
00:39:59,833 --> 00:40:03,371
He invited you, not me.

251
00:40:11,000 --> 00:40:14,118
Where did we put the mirror?

252
00:40:32,000 --> 00:40:35,197
Not at all. We were both invited.

253
00:40:37,000 --> 00:40:39,583
Look.

254
00:40:42,750 --> 00:40:46,914
- Doesn't it suit me?
- No, I prefer you as a blonde.

255
00:40:47,083 --> 00:40:51,031
And I prefer you
without a hat and cigar.

256
00:40:51,208 --> 00:40:55,623
It's just to look like Dean Martin
in <i>Some Came Running.</i>

257
00:40:55,792 --> 00:41:00,912
- What a laugh!
- What is?

258
00:41:01,083 --> 00:41:03,745
You may want to look
like Dean Martin,

259
00:41:03,917 --> 00:41:08,366
but it's more like Martin's ass.
- Who's that?

260
00:41:08,542 --> 00:41:13,332
Never read the adventures
of Martin's ass?

261
00:41:13,500 --> 00:41:18,074
One day he goes to Baghdad
to buy a flying carpet.

262
00:41:18,250 --> 00:41:21,288
He finds this really nice one,

263
00:41:21,458 --> 00:41:24,621
so he sits on it,
but it doesn't take off.

264
00:41:24,792 --> 00:41:27,750
"Hardly surprising,"
says the carpet seller...

265
00:41:27,917 --> 00:41:31,114
- Are you listening?
- Yes.

266
00:41:31,292 --> 00:41:36,412
"The carpet won't take off
if you think about an ass."

267
00:41:36,583 --> 00:41:40,121
So Martin says:
"Okay, I won't think of an ass."

268
00:41:40,292 --> 00:41:45,082
But automatically he thinks of one,
so the carpet doesn't fly.

269
00:41:45,250 --> 00:41:49,073
What's that got to do with me?

270
00:41:49,250 --> 00:41:53,323
- That's my point exactly.
- Well, I don't get it.

271
00:41:58,375 --> 00:42:01,868
Never mind.
Are you finished?

272
00:42:02,042 --> 00:42:06,787
No need to change the water.
I didn't use soap.

273
00:42:14,083 --> 00:42:17,997
You've been acting weird.
What's wrong?

274
00:42:18,167 --> 00:42:23,287
Nothing. I knew you'd say that.

275
00:42:25,417 --> 00:42:28,034
Is it about that girl?

276
00:42:28,208 --> 00:42:33,499
It's nothing, I tell you.
I simply said you were an ass.

277
00:42:39,375 --> 00:42:42,208
Not the same sound all over.

278
00:42:44,458 --> 00:42:48,076
Why don't you want us
to go to Capri?

279
00:42:49,667 --> 00:42:52,580
Because you're an ass.

280
00:42:59,958 --> 00:43:02,450
You scare me, Paul.

281
00:43:03,875 --> 00:43:06,492
And it's not the first time.

282
00:43:06,667 --> 00:43:09,989
So answer
instead of just standing there.

283
00:43:10,167 --> 00:43:14,786
Why did I marry a 28-year-old typist?

284
00:43:14,958 --> 00:43:18,371
It's true. I'm sorry.

285
00:43:22,375 --> 00:43:25,208
So am I.

286
00:43:36,958 --> 00:43:42,032
You go to Capri if you want.
I don't feel like it.

287
00:43:42,208 --> 00:43:47,624
Besides, I don't like
that Jeremy Prokosch. I told you.

288
00:43:47,792 --> 00:43:50,910
Why? Did he do something to you?

289
00:43:52,458 --> 00:43:55,450
Absolutely not.

290
00:44:08,583 --> 00:44:11,541
Why so thoughtful?

291
00:44:12,583 --> 00:44:16,656
Because I'm thinking,
believe it or not.

292
00:44:17,875 --> 00:44:21,618
- Surprised?
- No. Why?

293
00:44:23,125 --> 00:44:27,244
- An idea.
- Come with me. I won't go alone.

294
00:44:27,417 --> 00:44:31,581
You've been acting funny
since we met that guy.

295
00:44:34,875 --> 00:44:37,458
I'm not funny.

296
00:44:42,458 --> 00:44:46,827
- Why would you say that?
- Just because.

297
00:44:47,000 --> 00:44:52,916
We were fine this morning.
Now we're fighting over nothing.

298
00:44:53,083 --> 00:44:56,951
- What's going on, baby?
- I want to have fun.

299
00:44:57,125 --> 00:44:59,958
Nothing's going on, Paul.

300
00:45:00,125 --> 00:45:03,823
I'm afraid I'll get bored there.

301
00:45:04,000 --> 00:45:08,289
I'm not going.

302
00:45:25,917 --> 00:45:29,956
Seen the house being built
across the way?

303
00:45:31,458 --> 00:45:34,371
It's awful.

304
00:45:34,542 --> 00:45:37,989
If you love me, just be quiet.

305
00:45:46,375 --> 00:45:50,744
A husband has a right to know
why his wife's sulking.

306
00:45:52,583 --> 00:45:57,123
- I'm sure it's about that girl.
- Drop dead!

307
00:46:15,250 --> 00:46:18,413
Hello. Good afternoon.

308
00:46:19,417 --> 00:46:22,580
No, Camille isn't here.

309
00:46:23,708 --> 00:46:27,702
I thought you ate in town
and went shopping.

310
00:46:29,583 --> 00:46:34,532
She just walked in the door!
Your mother.

311
00:47:17,375 --> 00:47:20,948
I'll call you tomorrow. Ciao.

312
00:47:21,125 --> 00:47:27,497
You're out of your mind!
Why did you tell her I was out?

313
00:47:27,667 --> 00:47:31,456
- I don't know why.
- I know why.

314
00:47:31,625 --> 00:47:38,122
To find out if she had lunch with me
and if I wasn't lying.

315
00:47:38,292 --> 00:47:43,162
- That's it.
- Try that again and I'll divorce you.

316
00:47:44,833 --> 00:47:50,033
- Get up!
- What are you doing?

317
00:47:50,208 --> 00:47:52,950
I'm sleeping on the couch.

318
00:47:53,125 --> 00:47:59,280
- When, tonight?
- Every night, starting tonight.

319
00:48:09,250 --> 00:48:15,405
Don't be angry. I just can't sleep
with the window open.

320
00:48:15,583 --> 00:48:18,371
We'll close the window.

321
00:48:18,542 --> 00:48:22,615
You always say you can't breathe.
No, we'll sleep apart.

322
00:48:22,792 --> 00:48:27,912
Thousands of couples do it.
They still get along fine.

323
00:48:28,083 --> 00:48:31,451
What did I do wrong? Tell me.

324
00:48:33,458 --> 00:48:37,406
I'm sorry I said you were out.
Is that it? Forgive me.

325
00:48:37,583 --> 00:48:40,951
Let me by.

326
00:48:41,125 --> 00:48:45,870
- Is that why you're in a bad mood?
- Yes, but not anymore.

327
00:48:48,750 --> 00:48:52,368
I'll be just fine here.

328
00:48:52,542 --> 00:48:55,705
I really wonder what I did.

329
00:49:01,625 --> 00:49:04,583
You're so mean all of a sudden.

330
00:49:04,750 --> 00:49:08,368
Me? I'm the same as always.

331
00:49:10,458 --> 00:49:13,576
You're the one who's changed.

332
00:49:18,833 --> 00:49:23,407
Ever since you've been
with movie people.

333
00:49:23,583 --> 00:49:26,621
You used to write crime novels.

334
00:49:26,792 --> 00:49:32,242
We didn't have much money,
but everything was fine.

335
00:49:39,833 --> 00:49:45,988
What's this?
<i>"Partito Comunista ltaliano".</i>

336
00:49:46,167 --> 00:49:50,582
- You never said you joined.
- That was two months ago in Paris.

337
00:49:50,750 --> 00:49:56,871
- Give me that.
- Let go! You'll bruise me.

338
00:49:57,042 --> 00:50:00,740
I'm working for you.
This place is not just for me!

339
00:50:00,917 --> 00:50:05,957
Please, Paul,
I don't want to argue.

340
00:50:14,958 --> 00:50:18,030
I don't want to go to Capri, either.

341
00:50:18,208 --> 00:50:21,451
Why not? Don't be stupid. Go.

342
00:50:27,958 --> 00:50:31,246
Paul, come here.

343
00:50:31,417 --> 00:50:33,954
What?

344
00:50:34,125 --> 00:50:36,708
No, I've lost interest.

345
00:50:36,875 --> 00:50:40,914
When Prokosch calls,
tell him I won't talk to him.

346
00:50:41,917 --> 00:50:45,080
Paul, come here.

347
00:50:48,458 --> 00:50:51,621
Why won't you do the script now?

348
00:50:54,458 --> 00:50:57,576
I'd have done it out of love for you.

349
00:50:59,958 --> 00:51:03,622
But you don't love me anymore.

350
00:51:03,792 --> 00:51:06,580
That's news!

351
00:51:11,667 --> 00:51:15,991
"I had to judge a bottom contest
between three beautiful women.

352
00:51:16,167 --> 00:51:18,955
They chose me as a judge.

353
00:51:19,125 --> 00:51:22,413
They showed me
their dazzling nudity.

354
00:51:22,583 --> 00:51:27,407
The first had a white and gentle
curved back with round dimples.

355
00:51:27,583 --> 00:51:32,908
When the second parted her legs,
her snowy skin grew as red as a rose.

356
00:51:33,083 --> 00:51:36,371
The third was as still as a quiet sea.

357
00:51:36,542 --> 00:51:42,367
Her delicate skin rippled gently,
shivering involuntarily."

358
00:51:46,458 --> 00:51:52,079
We'll just mortgage the flat
when we run out of money.

359
00:51:52,250 --> 00:51:56,949
Something makes you think
I've stopped loving you?

360
00:51:57,125 --> 00:52:00,413
Yes.

361
00:52:00,583 --> 00:52:04,281
What?

362
00:52:06,292 --> 00:52:08,033
Everything-

363
00:52:08,208 --> 00:52:11,326
But what, for instance?

364
00:52:15,625 --> 00:52:20,870
- First tell me if it's true.
- No, you tell me first.

365
00:52:22,208 --> 00:52:25,530
What makes me think
you've stopped loving me?

366
00:52:25,708 --> 00:52:28,700
The way you've been talking to me.

367
00:52:29,583 --> 00:52:33,121
You weren't like that this morning.

368
00:52:38,000 --> 00:52:40,662
Nor yesterday.

369
00:52:43,000 --> 00:52:46,948
It's the way you look at me, too.

370
00:52:53,708 --> 00:53:00,159
"The problem, in my opinion,
is in our conception of the world.

371
00:53:00,333 --> 00:53:03,496
A positive view or a negative one.

372
00:53:03,667 --> 00:53:07,706
Greek tragedy was negative
in that it made Man

373
00:53:07,875 --> 00:53:11,493
a victim of Fate,
as embodied by the Gods,

374
00:53:11,667 --> 00:53:16,241
and abandoned him
to a hopeless destiny."

375
00:53:17,417 --> 00:53:22,787
Why do you say it's the open window?
There's something else.

376
00:53:25,458 --> 00:53:28,325
I think so.

377
00:53:28,500 --> 00:53:33,290
"Man can rebel against things
that are bad, false.

378
00:53:33,458 --> 00:53:39,079
We must rebel when we're trapped
by circumstances, conventions.

379
00:53:39,250 --> 00:53:43,414
But I don't think
murder is a solution.

380
00:53:43,583 --> 00:53:46,496
Crimes of passion serve no purpose.

381
00:53:46,667 --> 00:53:51,867
I love a woman,
she cheats on me, I kill her.

382
00:53:52,042 --> 00:53:57,082
What's left for me?
I lost her love since she's dead.

383
00:53:57,250 --> 00:54:01,790
If I kill her lover, she hates me,
and I still lose her love.

384
00:54:01,958 --> 00:54:05,622
Killing is never a solution."

385
00:54:06,667 --> 00:54:08,658
Look, Camille...

386
00:54:08,833 --> 00:54:14,749
I give you my word,
I can't sleep with the window open.

387
00:54:14,917 --> 00:54:18,410
I need silence and darkness.

388
00:54:20,542 --> 00:54:23,534
I swear it's true.

389
00:54:27,250 --> 00:54:30,823
And you move around too much.
You keep waking me.

390
00:54:31,000 --> 00:54:34,118
I want to sleep alone from now on.

391
00:54:35,542 --> 00:54:38,455
You don't want to make love?

392
00:54:41,625 --> 00:54:44,993
Listen to this jerk.

393
00:54:45,167 --> 00:54:48,956
Is that a mocking smile
or a tender smile?

394
00:54:50,667 --> 00:54:53,455
A tender smile.

395
00:54:55,792 --> 00:54:59,956
- So, answer me!
- If it were true, I'd tell you.

396
00:55:00,125 --> 00:55:03,572
A woman can always find
an excuse not to make love.

397
00:55:03,750 --> 00:55:09,245
- But you're really a jerk.
- Vulgar language doesn't suit you.

398
00:55:10,208 --> 00:55:12,950
It doesn't suit me?

399
00:55:14,750 --> 00:55:17,822
Listen to this...

400
00:55:18,000 --> 00:55:22,119
Asshole. Cunt.

401
00:55:22,292 --> 00:55:24,659
Shit.

402
00:55:25,417 --> 00:55:27,749
Christ almighty.

403
00:55:28,792 --> 00:55:30,908
Craphole.

404
00:55:31,958 --> 00:55:34,996
Son of a bitch.

405
00:55:35,167 --> 00:55:37,829
Goddamn.

406
00:55:42,042 --> 00:55:46,582
So, still think
it doesn't suit me?

407
00:56:10,583 --> 00:56:14,372
Why don't you want
to make love anymore?

408
00:56:22,542 --> 00:56:27,616
All right. Let's do it, but fast.

409
00:56:31,000 --> 00:56:34,038
<i>I'd been thinking
Camille could leave me.</i>

410
00:56:34,208 --> 00:56:39,908
<i>It was a possible disaster.
Now the disaster had happened.</i>

411
00:56:40,083 --> 00:56:43,951
<i>We used to live
in a cloud of unawareness,</i>

412
00:56:44,125 --> 00:56:46,833
<i>in delighted complicity.</i>

413
00:56:47,000 --> 00:56:51,995
<i>Things happened with sudden,
wild, enchanted recklessness.</i>

414
00:56:52,167 --> 00:56:58,448
<i>I'd end up in Paul's arms,
hardly aware of what had happened.</i>

415
00:56:58,625 --> 00:57:03,791
<i>This recklessness was now absent
in Camille, and thus in me.</i>

416
00:57:03,958 --> 00:57:08,122
<i>Could I now watch her coldly,
prey to my excited senses,</i>

417
00:57:08,292 --> 00:57:11,364
<i>as she could undoubtedly observe me?</i>

418
00:57:12,458 --> 00:57:17,498
<i>I deliberately made that remark
with a secret feeling of revenge.</i>

419
00:57:17,667 --> 00:57:20,785
<i>She seemed aware
that a lie could settle everything.</i>

420
00:57:20,958 --> 00:57:26,658
<i>For a while, on the surface at least.
She was clearly tempted to lie.</i>

421
00:57:26,833 --> 00:57:29,951
<i>But she thought better of it.</i>

422
00:57:30,125 --> 00:57:32,207
<i>Paul hurt me so much.</i>

423
00:57:32,375 --> 00:57:35,697
<i>It was my turn now,
alluding to what I'd seen,</i>

424
00:57:35,875 --> 00:57:38,867
<i>without really being specific.</i>

425
00:57:40,208 --> 00:57:45,248
<i>But I was wrong. She wasn't unfaithful,
or at least not obviously so.</i>

426
00:57:45,417 --> 00:57:49,991
<i>The truth remained concealed.
We needed to dig deeper.</i>

427
00:57:51,625 --> 00:57:57,496
<i>I've noticed that the more we doubt,
the more we cling to a false lucidity,</i>

428
00:57:57,667 --> 00:58:04,289
<i>in the hope of rationalizing
what feelings made murky and obscure.</i>

429
00:58:04,458 --> 00:58:07,041
<i>I thought Camille might leave me.</i>

430
00:58:07,208 --> 00:58:11,748
<i>It was a possible disaster.
Now the disaster had happened.</i>

431
00:58:11,917 --> 00:58:17,959
<i>We used to live in a cloud of
unawareness, in delicious complicity.</i>

432
00:58:20,250 --> 00:58:23,697
Don't be like that.

433
00:58:27,083 --> 00:58:31,577
- Don't be like what?
- You know very well.

434
00:58:37,208 --> 00:58:39,916
It's your fault!

435
00:58:48,167 --> 00:58:53,708
You seem to be searching
my expression

436
00:58:53,875 --> 00:58:56,947
to decide the appropriate attitude.

437
00:59:02,875 --> 00:59:07,369
"The private plane awaited
in the blue sky.

438
00:59:10,000 --> 00:59:15,746
Rex noticed something about Paula
that he knew already, her face...

439
00:59:15,917 --> 00:59:21,617
Her harmonious face,
now indecisive, seemed contorted.

440
00:59:21,792 --> 00:59:27,993
Rex knew this trait of hers,
for it seemed that whenever Paula...

441
00:59:28,167 --> 00:59:32,206
Whenever Paula
had to make a decision...

442
00:59:42,208 --> 00:59:45,405
that went against her nature..."

443
00:59:47,250 --> 00:59:51,915
What's got into you?
I love you exactly as before.

444
01:00:07,708 --> 01:00:11,531
What would you do
if I stopped loving you?

445
01:00:11,708 --> 01:00:16,202
- I already told you.
- I forgot what you said.

446
01:00:16,375 --> 01:00:20,744
I wouldn't do the script
and we'd sell the flat.

447
01:00:29,125 --> 01:00:33,665
But I love you.
I find this all so idiotic.

448
01:00:35,292 --> 01:00:40,537
When Prokosch calls,
tell him you'll go to Capri.

449
01:00:53,667 --> 01:00:57,991
- What about you?
- I love you. Don't make me repeat it.

450
01:00:58,167 --> 01:01:01,330
I want to keep the flat.

451
01:01:01,500 --> 01:01:04,743
If you don't want to do the script,
don't do it.

452
01:01:04,917 --> 01:01:09,457
If you think I've stopped loving you,
you're wrong.

453
01:01:12,208 --> 01:01:14,791
Kiss me.

454
01:01:43,917 --> 01:01:46,955
We were just talking about you.

455
01:01:52,458 --> 01:01:56,326
About your movie.

456
01:01:57,417 --> 01:02:01,786
Yes, <i>The Odyssey.
About that guy who travels.</i>

457
01:02:03,500 --> 01:02:08,950
In Capri, can we go swimming?

458
01:02:13,208 --> 01:02:15,870
I don't know.

459
01:02:19,625 --> 01:02:23,038
Here's Paul. I'll put him on.

460
01:02:29,917 --> 01:02:33,330
Mr. Prokosch? Yes.

461
01:02:37,500 --> 01:02:39,582
No.

462
01:02:53,458 --> 01:02:55,074
We're eating out?

463
01:02:55,250 --> 01:02:59,073
I don't feel like
going out for groceries.

464
01:03:04,667 --> 01:03:09,741
Fine. We're to meet Prokosch
and Lang at a cinema.

465
01:03:09,917 --> 01:03:13,865
They want to see a singer
in the stage show. We can eat after.

466
01:03:14,042 --> 01:03:17,034
It'll be late if there's a movie first.

467
01:03:17,208 --> 01:03:20,781
It might give me some ideas.

468
01:03:25,000 --> 01:03:30,040
Why not look for ideas in your head,
instead of stealing them?

469
01:03:30,208 --> 01:03:36,033
- What's got into you?
- Let's get going!

470
01:03:36,208 --> 01:03:41,954
I knew it. Since I said yes
to Prokosch, it's no more tenderness!

471
01:03:42,125 --> 01:03:48,531
Right, no more caresses.
What was the phone call about?

472
01:03:48,708 --> 01:03:52,531
- Our going to Capri.
- What did you say?

473
01:03:52,708 --> 01:03:58,124
- That it was up to you.
- Are you nuts?

474
01:03:58,292 --> 01:04:02,286
You know that it's up to you, not me!

475
01:04:02,458 --> 01:04:06,406
- Then come to Capri.
- No.

476
01:04:06,583 --> 01:04:10,247
Is there something
between you and Prokosch?

477
01:04:10,417 --> 01:04:13,455
You're pathetic.

478
01:04:20,292 --> 01:04:24,911
- Sit down. I have to talk to you.
- What about the cinema?

479
01:04:25,083 --> 01:04:27,825
Camille, I need to talk to you.

480
01:04:30,833 --> 01:04:34,201
All right, I'm listening.

481
01:04:34,375 --> 01:04:39,245
I need... to talk to you.

482
01:04:43,333 --> 01:04:47,372
Earlier, before the phone rang,

483
01:04:48,667 --> 01:04:54,663
I said I didn't want to take this job
if I couldn't be sure of your love.

484
01:04:56,167 --> 01:05:03,198
You said you loved me
and that I should take it.

485
01:05:04,333 --> 01:05:07,121
Yes.

486
01:05:08,167 --> 01:05:10,909
I'm sure you lied.

487
01:05:12,458 --> 01:05:18,739
Why? I don't know.
Out of pity, self-interest...

488
01:05:18,917 --> 01:05:25,823
- What self-interest?
- You holding on to this flat.

489
01:05:26,000 --> 01:05:29,243
How can you know what I think?

490
01:05:29,417 --> 01:05:36,073
In fact, I couldn't care less.
You can sell the flat, I don't care.

491
01:05:36,250 --> 01:05:39,538
You said it was better than a hotel.

492
01:05:39,708 --> 01:05:45,750
Not at all.
I said that to make you happy.

493
01:05:45,917 --> 01:05:52,163
That's beside the point.
I want to know why you lied earlier.

494
01:05:52,333 --> 01:05:54,700
Who said I lied? Stop it!

495
01:05:54,875 --> 01:05:58,413
You did. You've stopped loving me.

496
01:05:59,458 --> 01:06:02,200
What good will
knowing the truth do you?

497
01:06:02,375 --> 01:06:04,992
See? You admit I'm right.

498
01:06:05,167 --> 01:06:09,582
I'm not admitting anything.
Leave me alone.

499
01:06:11,750 --> 01:06:15,493
It's true. I don't love you anymore.

500
01:06:19,042 --> 01:06:22,330
There's nothing to explain.
I don't love you.

501
01:06:22,500 --> 01:06:27,165
Why? Yesterday you still loved me.

502
01:06:27,333 --> 01:06:31,372
Yes, very much.

503
01:06:31,542 --> 01:06:34,989
Now it's over.

504
01:06:35,167 --> 01:06:41,914
- There must be a reason.
- Yes, there must be.

505
01:06:42,083 --> 01:06:44,165
What is it?

506
01:06:44,333 --> 01:06:49,533
I don't know. All I know is
I don't love you anymore.

507
01:06:50,583 --> 01:06:53,371
Since we were at Prokosch's?

508
01:06:53,542 --> 01:06:58,116
When you saw me pat
Francesca Vanini's bottom?

509
01:07:01,167 --> 01:07:07,038
Let's say it was that.
It's over now. Let's drop the subject.

510
01:07:09,833 --> 01:07:13,280
Something's happened
since this morning.

511
01:07:13,458 --> 01:07:19,409
It changed your mind about me,
and therefore, your love for me.

512
01:07:21,958 --> 01:07:26,577
- You're nuts, but you're clever.
- Then it's true.

513
01:07:32,875 --> 01:07:39,121
I didn't say that.
I said you're clever.

514
01:07:40,375 --> 01:07:44,664
Was it something I said or did today
that you took the wrong way?

515
01:07:44,833 --> 01:07:46,619
Maybe.

516
01:07:46,792 --> 01:07:51,207
Don't talk to me like that!
I won't allow it!

517
01:08:00,125 --> 01:08:02,412
Camille!

518
01:08:09,125 --> 01:08:12,914
I despise you! That's what I feel.

519
01:08:13,083 --> 01:08:16,155
That's why the love's gone.

520
01:08:16,333 --> 01:08:20,031
And you disgust me when you touch me.

521
01:08:32,458 --> 01:08:35,655
Wait for me. Don't be so dramatic.

522
01:08:39,958 --> 01:08:44,998
Forget what I said, Paul.
Pretend nothing happened.

523
01:09:48,750 --> 01:09:51,117
Good evening.

524
01:09:58,333 --> 01:10:02,577
- Are you going to Capri, too?
- Maybe.

525
01:10:25,542 --> 01:10:28,079
Are you okay?

526
01:11:31,583 --> 01:11:34,621
Mr. Prokosch re-read Homer.

527
01:11:39,542 --> 01:11:44,207
He found something
he had long been searching for.

528
01:11:50,667 --> 01:11:56,538
Something as indispensable
to the movies as to real life.

529
01:11:56,708 --> 01:11:58,494
Poetry.

530
01:12:00,875 --> 01:12:04,698
- You remember...
- Oh, yes.

531
01:12:06,750 --> 01:12:10,573
They say Ulysses came home
to Penelope,

532
01:12:10,750 --> 01:12:14,038
but maybe Ulysses had been
fed up with Penelope.

533
01:12:14,208 --> 01:12:19,624
So he went off to the Trojan war, and
since he didn't feel like going home,

534
01:12:19,792 --> 01:12:22,375
he kept travelling as long as he could.

535
01:12:22,542 --> 01:12:26,285
Do you think it was
an idea of his or...?

536
01:12:36,250 --> 01:12:40,414
- Why do you despise me?
- Leave me alone!

537
01:12:55,167 --> 01:12:58,614
Coming to Capri with us, Mr. Lang?

538
01:12:59,667 --> 01:13:06,039
"Each morning, to earn my bread
I go to the market where lies are sold

539
01:13:06,917 --> 01:13:10,911
and, full of hope, I line up
alongside the other vendors."

540
01:13:11,083 --> 01:13:14,747
- What's that?
- Hollywood.

541
01:13:14,917 --> 01:13:18,035
From a ballad by poor B.B.

542
01:13:19,417 --> 01:13:22,079
- Bertolt Brecht?
- Yes.

543
01:13:31,750 --> 01:13:35,368
Homer's world is a real world.

544
01:13:35,542 --> 01:13:38,989
And the poet belonged to a civilization

545
01:13:39,167 --> 01:13:45,743
that grew in harmony,
not in opposition, with nature.

546
01:13:45,917 --> 01:13:48,534
And the beauty of <i>The Odyssey</i>

547
01:13:48,708 --> 01:13:55,284
lies precisely in this belief
in reality as it is.

548
01:13:55,458 --> 01:13:58,746
Thus in reality
as it appears objectively.

549
01:13:58,917 --> 01:14:05,698
Exactly. And in a form
that cannot be broken down.

550
01:14:05,875 --> 01:14:10,199
And is what it is.
Take it or leave it.

551
01:14:13,667 --> 01:14:17,285
I shut up because I have nothing to say.

552
01:14:30,458 --> 01:14:35,407
I'm not sure about going to Capri.
Where would we stay?

553
01:14:38,458 --> 01:14:41,871
In Mr. Prokosch's villa.

554
01:14:44,333 --> 01:14:49,078
- With your husband.
- And Mr. Lang too?

555
01:14:53,042 --> 01:14:54,908
That's up to him.

556
01:14:55,083 --> 01:15:00,499
Producers are something
I can easily do without.

557
01:15:00,667 --> 01:15:03,739
- Madam.
- Goodnight.

558
01:15:29,417 --> 01:15:34,116
If you don't want to come,
I'm not forcing you.

559
01:15:34,292 --> 01:15:39,867
It's not you that's forcing me.
It's life.

560
01:16:08,417 --> 01:16:11,455
What are you doing?

561
01:16:14,000 --> 01:16:18,289
- What are you doing?
- Looking.

562
01:16:18,458 --> 01:16:22,281
Don't stay by yourself. Join us.

563
01:16:22,458 --> 01:16:27,157
- What were you talking about?
- The Odyssey.

564
01:16:27,333 --> 01:16:32,703
- I agree with Prokosch's theory.
- What theory's that?

565
01:16:32,875 --> 01:16:37,870
That Ulysses loves his wife,
but she doesn't love him.

566
01:16:39,125 --> 01:16:44,950
Do you really think that?
I'm sure you don't.

567
01:16:51,083 --> 01:16:55,873
- Please, you're in the frame.
- Places, everyone!

568
01:17:35,458 --> 01:17:40,999
Are they going to strip off?
Marvellous business this!

569
01:17:41,167 --> 01:17:46,537
You show women in dresses a camera,
and hey presto! They strip off!

570
01:17:59,208 --> 01:18:02,655
Come with us, madam,
leave them here to talk.

571
01:18:02,833 --> 01:18:05,996
No, I'll walk back later
with my husband.

572
01:18:12,000 --> 01:18:17,200
He says you spend all day
with your husband.

573
01:18:19,625 --> 01:18:22,947
Do you mind if you wife comes with us?

574
01:18:23,125 --> 01:18:28,416
Not at all. Go on, Camille.
Go on.

575
01:18:30,917 --> 01:18:36,287
I don't mind, go on.

576
01:18:36,458 --> 01:18:41,123
I'll walk back with Mr. Lang
to discuss The Odyssey.

577
01:19:15,458 --> 01:19:18,416
The girls are in the water, Mr Lang.

578
01:19:18,583 --> 01:19:21,701
I should have done a scene
at the beginning

579
01:19:21,875 --> 01:19:28,497
in which the gods
discuss man's fate, in general,

580
01:19:28,667 --> 01:19:32,114
and the fate of Ulysses in particular.

581
01:20:08,000 --> 01:20:11,823
A producer
can be a friend to a director.

582
01:20:12,000 --> 01:20:17,871
But Prokosch isn't a real producer.
He's a dictator.

583
01:20:18,042 --> 01:20:23,412
I think it's stupid to change
the character of Ulysses.

584
01:20:23,583 --> 01:20:27,247
He's not a modern-day neurotic,

585
01:20:27,417 --> 01:20:33,117
but a simple, clever and robust man.

586
01:20:33,292 --> 01:20:36,250
I find his idea interesting.

587
01:20:36,417 --> 01:20:39,535
It takes Ulysses
ten years to return home

588
01:20:39,708 --> 01:20:43,531
because he doesn't really
want to return. It's logical.

589
01:20:43,708 --> 01:20:49,784
It's logical, and the illogical
borrows from the logical.

590
01:20:49,958 --> 01:20:54,452
Your Corneille said it
in his preface to <i>Suréna.</i>

591
01:20:54,625 --> 01:20:59,290
Ulysses doesn't rush home to Ithaca

592
01:20:59,458 --> 01:21:03,372
because he was unhappy
with Penelope,

593
01:21:03,542 --> 01:21:08,116
but the trouble started
before he went off to war.

594
01:21:14,208 --> 01:21:17,655
He never would've left
if he'd been happy.

595
01:21:17,833 --> 01:21:21,326
The Trojan war was his excuse
to get away from her.

596
01:21:21,500 --> 01:21:25,494
But he killed her suitors, didn't he?

597
01:21:25,667 --> 01:21:29,956
That can be justified
by the fact that, at first,

598
01:21:30,125 --> 01:21:34,323
Ulysses had told Penelope
to accept their gifts.

599
01:21:34,500 --> 01:21:38,323
He didn't see the suitors
as serious rivals,

600
01:21:38,500 --> 01:21:42,289
and didn't want to cause a scandal
by throwing them out.

601
01:21:42,458 --> 01:21:48,989
Knowing Penelope to be faithful,
he told her to be nice to the suitors.

602
01:21:55,833 --> 01:22:02,455
I think that's when Penelope,
who is a simple woman at heart,

603
01:22:03,625 --> 01:22:06,743
began to despise him.

604
01:22:06,917 --> 01:22:11,912
She found she'd stopped loving
Ulysses because of his behaviour,

605
01:22:12,083 --> 01:22:14,541
and she told him so.

606
01:22:14,708 --> 01:22:19,202
Ulysses then realized too late
he'd lost Penelope's love

607
01:22:19,375 --> 01:22:23,198
because he'd been overly cautious.

608
01:22:24,250 --> 01:22:29,450
The only way to win her back
was to murder the suitors.

609
01:22:29,625 --> 01:22:33,072
Death is no resolution.

610
01:24:07,042 --> 01:24:09,124
Camille!

611
01:25:17,417 --> 01:25:21,490
- What a lovely yellow.
- Thanks.

612
01:25:23,833 --> 01:25:26,621
I found this on the boat.

613
01:25:26,792 --> 01:25:30,490
Children shouldn't play with firearms.

614
01:26:18,292 --> 01:26:20,374
Drink?

615
01:26:20,542 --> 01:26:24,581
I was there, outside. Nothing.

616
01:26:58,667 --> 01:27:02,410
I decided not to write
the script you asked me.

617
01:27:05,083 --> 01:27:07,700
Why?

618
01:27:07,875 --> 01:27:11,118
Can I be frank?

619
01:27:15,125 --> 01:27:17,742
Of course.

620
01:27:21,042 --> 01:27:26,617
I'm a playwright.
Not a screenwriter.

621
01:27:31,958 --> 01:27:37,499
Even if it's a fine script...
I'm only doing it for the money!

622
01:27:43,958 --> 01:27:47,781
That's why I'm in a bad mood.

623
01:27:50,333 --> 01:27:55,407
We all have an ideal.
Mine's writing plays. I can't. Why?

624
01:27:57,583 --> 01:28:02,703
In today's world,
we have to accept what others want.

625
01:28:04,875 --> 01:28:07,833
Why does money matter so much
in what we do,

626
01:28:08,000 --> 01:28:10,958
in what we are, in what we become?

627
01:28:12,667 --> 01:28:16,331
Even in our relationships
with those we love.

628
01:28:25,875 --> 01:28:28,663
He is right.

629
01:28:30,000 --> 01:28:33,948
We either do Homer's <i>Odyssey</i>
or we do nothing!

630
01:28:39,708 --> 01:28:43,702
Mr. Prokosch already said it,
you're wrong.

631
01:28:43,875 --> 01:28:46,993
You aspire to a world like Homer's.

632
01:28:47,167 --> 01:28:50,831
You want it to exist,
but unfortunately it doesn't.

633
01:28:51,000 --> 01:28:54,118
Why doesn't it?

634
01:29:01,042 --> 01:29:03,955
You may be right,

635
01:29:04,125 --> 01:29:09,950
but when it comes to making movies,
dreams aren't enough.

636
01:29:16,833 --> 01:29:19,575
When do we eat?

637
01:29:22,917 --> 01:29:27,707
- In an hour.
- Right. I'm going for a walk.

638
01:29:36,625 --> 01:29:39,083
Mr. Prokosch wants to speak with you.

639
01:29:44,708 --> 01:29:49,999
- Is that an order or a request?
- A request.

640
01:29:56,417 --> 01:29:59,205
One must suffer.

641
01:30:01,208 --> 01:30:03,825
That's for sure.

642
01:30:15,417 --> 01:30:17,624
Camille!

643
01:31:03,958 --> 01:31:06,791
It's me, Paul.

644
01:31:12,792 --> 01:31:17,912
Looking at you just now,
felt like the first time I'd seen you.

645
01:31:29,958 --> 01:31:35,283
- Mind if I stay?
- Stay if you like.

646
01:31:55,083 --> 01:31:58,201
Why didn't you speak up earlier?

647
01:31:58,375 --> 01:32:02,539
I don't get you! You always said
you loved that script.

648
01:32:02,708 --> 01:32:08,659
Now you tell the producer it's for the
money, that your ideal is the theatre.

649
01:32:09,833 --> 01:32:14,703
He's no fool.
Next time, he won't be asking you.

650
01:32:14,875 --> 01:32:19,540
How can you not understand
something so simple?

651
01:32:21,625 --> 01:32:26,290
- I bet you'll do it anyway.
- No.

652
01:32:26,458 --> 01:32:31,373
Yes, you'll see. I know you.

653
01:32:33,583 --> 01:32:35,665
I know you.

654
01:32:35,833 --> 01:32:40,703
If I do it, it's for you.
To pay for the flat.

655
01:32:40,875 --> 01:32:44,664
I'll let you decide
whether I do the script or not.

656
01:32:44,833 --> 01:32:48,497
If you say no, we'll leave.

657
01:32:48,667 --> 01:32:52,991
- You're so cunning!
- Not at all. Why?

658
01:32:53,167 --> 01:32:58,913
- If you regret it, you can blame me.
- Not at all! I'm asking you to decide.

659
01:32:59,083 --> 01:33:01,666
You want me to tell you what to do?

660
01:33:01,833 --> 01:33:05,121
- Yes.
- Then do the script!

661
01:33:05,292 --> 01:33:09,206
You signed a contract,
and you're boring me.

662
01:33:12,083 --> 01:33:16,657
- I saw him kiss you earlier.
- I know you did.

663
01:33:19,958 --> 01:33:24,782
- Why don't you love me anymore?
- That's life.

664
01:33:25,917 --> 01:33:29,581
Why do you despise me?

665
01:33:29,750 --> 01:33:34,039
I'll never tell you,
not even if I were dying.

666
01:33:38,792 --> 01:33:43,787
- Tell me or I'll hurt you.
- Why hurt me more?

667
01:33:47,000 --> 01:33:50,038
I have to know why you despise me.

668
01:33:50,208 --> 01:33:55,578
It's crazy! I don't see why
you expect me to accept, anyway.

669
01:33:55,750 --> 01:34:00,074
We need the money for the flat.
I don't want to go back to typing.

670
01:34:00,250 --> 01:34:05,996
I can't accept that after what happened.
Obviously you do despise me.

671
01:34:22,625 --> 01:34:26,789
You knew we kissed and you were
still ready to change your mind.

672
01:34:26,958 --> 01:34:33,034
I turned the job down for you.
So you'd change your mind about me.

673
01:34:33,208 --> 01:34:37,873
Don't touch me.
I don't love you anymore.

674
01:34:38,042 --> 01:34:42,036
There's no way
I'll ever love you again.

675
01:34:42,208 --> 01:34:45,701
Even if I turn it down,
you'll despise me?

676
01:34:45,875 --> 01:34:51,621
- Yes, I will.
- Why? There must be a reason.

677
01:34:51,792 --> 01:34:57,287
- You're the reason.
- What do you mean, me?

678
01:34:57,458 --> 01:35:00,746
I don't know. You're not a man.

679
01:35:01,792 --> 01:35:07,413
Anyhow, it's too late.
I've changed my mind about you.

680
01:35:08,875 --> 01:35:14,166
I know why you despise me.
The other day, when I took a taxi,

681
01:35:14,333 --> 01:35:19,203
you thought I wanted you
to go in his car with him.

682
01:35:20,708 --> 01:35:24,326
And again on the boat earlier.
Don't be stupid!

683
01:35:24,500 --> 01:35:26,787
I have faults, but that's not one.

684
01:35:26,958 --> 01:35:32,954
I'll never forgive you.
I loved you so much.

685
01:35:35,250 --> 01:35:42,202
Now it's impossible. I hate you
because you can't make me feel.

686
01:35:42,375 --> 01:35:45,493
I can! You're almost in tears.

687
01:35:57,792 --> 01:36:01,330
We're leaving! We'll pack up and go.

688
01:36:01,500 --> 01:36:05,949
I'm staying. You go if you like.

689
01:36:06,125 --> 01:36:09,163
Come on, Camille!

690
01:36:10,625 --> 01:36:14,072
- No.
- Then I'm staying, too.

691
01:36:14,250 --> 01:36:20,371
- But Prokosch will throw us out.
- Don't start again.

692
01:37:01,417 --> 01:37:06,287
<i>Dear Paul, I found your revolver
and took the bullets out.</i>

693
01:37:06,458 --> 01:37:09,871
<i>If you won't leave, I will.</i>

694
01:37:10,042 --> 01:37:15,458
<i>Jeremy Prokosch has to return to Rome,
so PH get a lift with him.</i>

695
01:37:15,625 --> 01:37:19,619
<i>Then I'll probably move
into a hotel alone.</i>

696
01:37:19,792 --> 01:37:23,911
<i>Take care. Farewell. Camille.</i>

697
01:38:02,625 --> 01:38:06,368
What are you going to do in Rome?

698
01:38:08,333 --> 01:38:11,121
Typist.

699
01:38:16,292 --> 01:38:19,034
Me? No.

700
01:38:19,958 --> 01:38:22,541
Typist.

701
01:38:46,625 --> 01:38:51,791
What... do you think... of me?

702
01:38:52,875 --> 01:38:57,164
Get into your Alfa, Romeo.
We'll see about that later.

703
01:38:57,333 --> 01:39:02,328
TAKE CARE

704
01:39:08,792 --> 01:39:13,457
FAREWELL

705
01:40:11,417 --> 01:40:15,035
Nathalie,
I'm leaving for Rome tonight.

706
01:40:15,208 --> 01:40:18,246
Good-bye, then.

707
01:40:59,458 --> 01:41:03,747
Mr. Lang,
I've come to say good-bye.

708
01:41:03,917 --> 01:41:07,285
Good-bye. What will you do?

709
01:41:07,458 --> 01:41:12,157
Go back to Rome, finish my play.

710
01:41:13,292 --> 01:41:16,250
- And you?
- I'll finish the film.

711
01:41:16,417 --> 01:41:20,536
One should always finish
what one starts.

712
01:41:20,708 --> 01:41:23,541
What shot are you doing?

713
01:41:23,708 --> 01:41:28,578
Ulysses' gaze when he first sees
his homeland again.

714
01:41:30,083 --> 01:41:32,199
Ithaca.

715
01:41:33,917 --> 01:41:38,332
- Good-bye, Mr. Lang.
- Bye. I hope we'll meet again.

716
01:41:42,042 --> 01:41:44,659
We're ready, Mr. Lang.

717
01:41:44,833 --> 01:41:47,905
Quiet on the set!

718
01:41:49,542 --> 01:41:52,409
Camera!

719
01:42:44,667 --> 01:42:47,739
Silence!

