Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
I hope you have a nice life.
That’s not it.
That’s...Not it!
That’s exactly it.
Mr. Silva...
May I have a word with you please?
Come in, Francisco.
Pardon me...
I’ve come to tell you that
I can’t come to work tomorrow.
And you tell me now?
I’m going to have to dock you a day.
I know...Thank you very much.
Don’t thank me.
I haven’t agreed yet.
I need you to take some sand
down for me. Everyone else is busy.
Mr. Silva, I have something to take
care of, I can’t tomorrow.
And I have five truckload
of sand to deliver.
You’ll do it in two hours
and then you can go.
In the afternoon then.
I can’t in the morning.
See if you ease your tone, Francisco.
I just gave you the day off.
With five truckloads of sand...
Don’t forget to fill out
the form for the day off.
Will you open?
Weren’t you in...?
I returned...
I sent you a postcard,
didn’t you get it?
Don’t you check the mailbox?
What for?
Every time I check it
I only find bills to pay.
Now I only check it at
the end of the month.
If you sent something
it should be there.
What is this supposed to mean?
What?
This?
That I just need a drink.
It’s getting dark.
You didn’t hear what I said?
It’s getting dark out.
All she ever showed me
was unhappiness.
But she must have been happy.
Always happy.
There’re those who limit
themselves to exist, just that.
You can choose.
Take whatever you’d like.
Where to?
What do I know.
To your life.
Couldn’t you’ve called a moving truck?
I liked to look at things over and
over as if it were the first time.
We spend our lives running
from one thing to another.
Always passing by the same objects
and using them.
And we are very surprised
that they still exist.
But it would be better
if they were a novelty.
But they aren’t.
We try, but they aren’t.
This is a process that destroys,
tires, weighs…
The best thing to do is to give up,
it’s one way to solve things.
I already said: it’s all yours.
Those people there...
What? They’re my things aren’t they?
They thought they’d already seen everything here,
but they hadn’t seen this yet!
Don’t say that, please.
I’ll stay with you.
Are you ok?
Yes.
You don’t have anything
in the fridge.
I don’t need anything.
I’ll go to the supermarket
in the afternoon.
Will you take me?
I can’t.
I’ll go pick you up.
It’s the middle of the week...
It’s a work day.
It’s my day off.
I go by there in the afternoon
but I won't take long.
So where were you exactly?
In Acapulco.
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm