Less murder cases these days.
Nice weather, perhaps?
About the Jilgok District case...
Got to catch one of those two guys...
But the Chief and
Team One won't listen.
Then what?
We should catch them.
- We?
- Yeah.
You and me.
So G-goo came on his own,
wanting a refund of a prepaid
card he bought last year?
Right. We don't normally do that.
But I told him I'd ask my boss,
and then I texted you, Detective.
You did great.
It's been ages since
you showed me the photo,
but I recognized him just like that!
Did he say he'd come back?
OPPA INTERNET CAFE
Do you enjoy ditching me
and driving home for the weekend?
How is this "you and me"?
I've got to get married, too...
You dozed off again?
Why did you stop talking?
Talk more.
This is why you should sleep at night.
It's dangerous!
You're always on a stakeout,
so you can't get enough sleep.
It's not that I can't sleep
because of the stakeouts.
I go on stakeouts
because I can't sleep.
IPO NUCLEAR POWER PLANT
You should've caught G-goo and San-o
three years ago.
YOUNGEST-EVER REACTOR OPERATOR
Do a lot of kids stay at
the dorm on weekends?
He's busy with the Math Olympiad.
He's just a middle school student...
He's a science nerd like me.
I totally understand him.
I'm telling you, just buy sushi.
I don't like eating any old sushi.
At least while I'm home,
I should feed you real food.
Can't you transfer to Ipo?
So I can eat this every day?
I told you about June,
who works next to me.
Pretending to be concerned
when actually putting me down.
June said, "Six out of
ten weekend couples"
"consider getting divorced."
"Are you okay?"
So what did you say?
"I heard 55 percent of sexless
marriages end in divorce."
"Are you okay?"
Decision
Decision To Leave
After climbing up that rope there,
he must've fallen from the top,
bouncing on his way down.
Up there,
then there,
down there,
to here.
Expensive earphones...
10:02, Monday.
We'd better go up.
Is a chopper coming, then?
We could've walked up the back.
Why do it this way?
It's the path the dead man took.
And we're the police!
Then should we bounce down three times,
like he did?
Why does anyone need
to climb rocks like this?
Shouldn't it be illegal?
Damn it!
Thank you.
IDENTIFICATION CARD KI DO-SOO
Ki Do-soo, 60.
Initials on all his things.
Sign of possessiveness?
Drinks whiskey.
Stay away from there!
He used to work at
the immigration office,
but after retiring, he stayed
on as a part-time interviewer.
It's on!
His daughter's a beauty.
Think you'll unlock it that way?
Your father is here.
I am Mr. Ki Do-soo's
wife, Song Seo-rae.
I'm Chinese, so my
Korean is insufficient.
You must be quite shocked.
I worried whenever he did not
come back from a mountain.
Thinking he might've died at last.
At last...
Your Korean's better than mine.
I'd love to know the pattern.
Not shocked at her husband's death.
Quite a shocking wife.
Tell her an autopsy is standard
for an unaccountable
death without witnesses.
Use easy words.
I doubt my wife would
be shocked, either.
She'd say, "I knew it."
"That's why I didn't
want to marry a cop."
When a person dies for no clear reasons
with no one around,
opening the body to
look inside is standard...
No... the usual procedure.
Is that easy enough?
Make it easier.
I told her to report it,
that broken ribs are
no laughing matter.
But then she just laughed again.
He's the neat, orderly type.
He hit her only in places
where it doesn't show.
Wait, let me use the mouse...
What did he look like in the mountain?
Shall I tell it to you in words,
or in photos?
Words.
Okay.
Photos.
We found him with eyes open.
Can you handle it?
A lacerated scalp was
the cause of death.
His head bone was broken.
That's why he died.
He must've bled a lot,
but the rain washed it away,
fortunately.
He perished as he wished.
Isn't "perished" correct?
Did you see her laugh?
He was a very neat man.
Now, I have nowhere to go.
Leave me to die.
So heartless of you.
Am I so wicked?
- We're good, right?
- Yeah.
We've been good all
these 16 years, 8 months?
Are you counting?
Science nerd, for sure.
They say sex is good for blood
pressure and heart disease.
New research says
it's great for cognitive ability, too!
Wow, remarkable.
We need to do it every week.
Even when we hate each other.
- You heartless woman.
I know where your mind was before.
The Jilgok District case?
No.
A young Chinese woman
died on the mountain.
I feel bad for her old husband.
Seo-rae visits a different
elderly person's home
each day of the week.
You said Monday?
GRANDDAUGHTER'S
LOVE CAREGIVING SERVICE
Our patients cannot always
express themselves well,
so we make a call to them
at 9 a.m.
This way!
So we can check if the
caregiver has arrived
and so on.
Song Seo-rae...
On Mondays, it's Granny Hae-dong!
And we called her that day.
Sorry,
but if patients can't
express themselves,
how can they answer the phone?
The caregiver answers!
How is Ms. Song's work performance?
The grannies all talk
about her like this.
"Is she a caregiver
or my granddaughter?"
She was a nurse, so
she's great at injections.
She's our company's ace.
That's a scary woman.
She took her ring off already.
Whereas grief envelops
some like a crashing wave,
there are some to
whom it spreads slowly,
like ink in water.
Tell me when your
poetry book comes out.
I'll buy a copy.
You don't know the bitterness of life.
Sure, weekends with your pretty wife
must be so bitter.
It's hard to spend 12 hours a day
at my desk on illegal entry cases.
But just the thought
of scaling the rock face
makes my heart sing!
They found someone else's DNA
under Ki Do-soo's fingernails.
We'll need an oral epithelial
cell sample from his wife.
"Oral epithelial cell sample"?
How do I make that phrase easy?
Just thinking about it
makes my stomach's
epithelial cells ache.
Go eat lunch.
Nothing too expensive!
Another person's DNA was found
under Ki Do-soo's fingernails.
We need you to come to the
station now and give us your DNA.
I can't.
- Why not?
- I'm working.
Your husband died,
but you're already back at work?
Taking care of living old people
comes before my dead husband.
I see.
But tailing is my specialty.
Your grandmother raised you.
That's why it's your job.
Do it right.
Last Monday, what time did
Song Seo-rae leave your home?
Siri, play me a song.
"The Mist" by Chung Hoon-hee.
Isn't this song great?
Seo-rae put it on for me.
♪ I walk alone ♪
♪ on the street ♪
♪ filled with mist ♪
♪ Is that your silhouette ♪
I didn't think you could come.
Thank you.
Why do you like Seo-rae so much?
Because she's pretty?
Because she doesn't take half
the apple off while peeling it.
I start praying on Friday night
for Monday to come quickly.
And sometimes, Monday
seems to come faster.
Siri, play me a song.
"The Mist" by Chung Hoon-hee.
Isn't this song great?
Seo-rae put it on for me.
We fought.
He said let's go to the mountain.
I said I hate the mountain.
He scratched his wife
for hating the mountain?
I'll call a female officer.
It's okay.
We need to take a photo.
I did it.
Because he just wasn't
understanding Korean.
After you hurt yourself,
did he understand?
At last.
What did he say when you hurt yourself?
You heartless woman.
Do-soo tried to stop me, like this...
So you're saying
that's why your DNA is under
your husband's fingernails?
Do you hate mountains that much?
Confucius said,
"Wise people like water."
"Benevolent people like mountains."
I am not benevolent. I like the sea.
Me, too.
Sorry?
These are the dates you
went to the emergency room?
Did he hit you then
for not going to the mountain?
He was the solitary Korean person
to listen to my story and cry.
What Korean person?
Solitary?
I'm sorry. I shouldn't have laughed.
But your expression was so precise.
When I have no confidence in Korean,
I laugh.
I'll order dinner.
Everything okay?
Thank you. Did you eat?
No.
Isn't that the Shima Sushi
premium dinner combo?
Is that covered?
Damn!
Follow me.
We'll be coming back.
It's waterproof.
"Waterproof" means if it
gets wet, water won't come in.
Caregivers use many
waterproof products.
Be back in that room
by 6:50.
The women's restroom
is that way, on the right.
On August 17th, 2015,
the Coast Guard caught a
group of Chinese nationals
stowed on a cargo
ship at Pyeongtaek Port.
The other 37 were deported,
but only you remained in Korea.
Because I'm different from them.
My grandfather was
Gye Bong-seok of the Korean
Liberation Army in Manchuria.
What?
- Huh?
- Eh?
Thanks to Do-soo,
he got an Order of Merit
for National Foundation.
CONFERRAL OF NATIONALITY FOR
DESCENDANTS OF INDEPENDENCE PATRIOTS
Me.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
G-goo showed up at Oppa Internet Cafe.
Send Ms. Song home,
and check up on Gye
Bong-seok and his medal.
Yup!
OPPA INTERNET CAFE
It puts me at ease
even if I don't use it.
G-goo!
Gye Bong-seok
fought the Japanese colonizers
in southern Manchuria in the mid-1930s.
As commander of the KLO's 3rd company,
he led 200 operations,
earning himself the nickname
"The Leopard Cat of Manchuria."
Once, when they ambushed
the Japanese Army in Yanbian,
Gye felled Commander Hara Renya
by chewing off a part of his neck.
Hey, G-goo!
This is killing me!
Let go!
Let the knife go!
Let it go!
I said let go!
Why do you think it's so dark?
What are you doing?
Get up, now!
Why did you fall down like that?
Get out.
It wasn't you, was it?
Fighting you, I could tell
you can't kill someone.
It was San-o who killed Beom, right?
You guys will never catch San-o.
Why not?
His memories of juvie
are just too beautiful.
He'll kill himself
and a bunch of you
rather than go to jail.
The suicidal type.
Didn't I tell you no brutality
if you work with me?
He injured a police officer!
I injured it while hitting him!
Why carry a gun
if you're too out of shape to run?
And don't do all the talking.
Make them talk!
Don't you listen to
them a little too much?
Take Song Seo-rae.
We should've gotten a search
warrant on her already.
Mee-jee, a true police
officer, checked the CCTV.
Seo-rae was filmed going in and
out of that granny's apartment.
Her alibi is solid.
Mee-jee,
didn't you say San-o
has a lot of women?
Make a list.
When they dated and so on.
And find their current addresses.
Why should such a beautiful woman
marry an old man in Korea?
If she's young,
beautiful, and a foreigner,
does that make her a murder suspect?
So you admit she's beautiful?
It's reverse discrimination.
What if she were not
female, not a foreigner
but just a Korean man?
Wouldn't you be staking her out?
Aren't stakeouts your hobby?
That and preaching.
Leaving the ice cream out,
sleeping uncomfortably
with the TV still on.
Good morning.
Good morning!
What's with the pleasant greeting?
You trying to confuse us?
I slept unusually well.
Another crow?
To thank me for feeding you?
No need for that.
If you must give me a present,
bring me the head
of that kind detective.
That's what I want.
Ice cream for dinner again.
Don't smoke after meals.
Crying... at last.
Good mor...
What?
Good morning, sir.
Are you still stuck on
that Guso Mountain case?
Wrap it up quickly and move
on to something bigger,
like the Jilgok District case!
God, he's frustrating.
You're wrapping up the
Guso Mountain case?
What's this Chinese document?
The investigation's not finished.
But there's no reason to expect murder.
I want to go catch the
Jilgok District murderer now.
Song Seo-rae is suspected of murder.
If she goes back to China,
she'll get a life sentence.
I even got it translated
and sent it to you.
How many of San-o's
girlfriends did you meet?
Meet them all in two
days and write up a report.
Damn it!
Hey!
Look at this. She
killed her own mother!
What were you doing out in the cold?
Thinking how much I like the misty sea?
In Busan, there's the sea.
In Ipo, there's the sea...
I'm just a man of the sea!
Man of the sea, my butt.
You were born in downtown Seoul.
God, I want a cigarette.
Eliminate that dirty thought
before it's too late!
I'll get some bellflower root.
Chewing on it helped you quit.
Hi, June? It's me.
Do you have any bellflower root?
My husband says he feels like smoking.
He must've forgotten
how hard it was to quit.
SONG SEO-RAE
THOUGHTS?
THOUGHTS.
TELL ME YOUR THOUGHTS.
COME TO MY HOME.
ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
You think you can order
a cop to your house?
Don't you come here often anyway?
So you killed your mother?
Homi Mountain
is in your grandfather's
hometown in Korea.
It belongs to him.
Go there,
to your mountain.
After killing me first.
Mom,
the reason I became a nurse was
to care for you professionally.
Now, you want me to
kill you professionally,
as a nurse?
So I did as she wished.
It took just four capsules of fentanyl.
And I kept four for myself.
Where is it? The fentanyl?
Open if you're curious.
Do-soo was suicide.
I KNOW
YOU ACCEPTED BRIBES
FROM ILLEGAL ALIENS
SO THEY CAN GET CITIZENSHIP...
IF YOU DON'T ANSWER,
I WILL REPORT YOU.
Fine.
Mr. Ki Do-soo
stared at people's faces
and stamped passports for 20 years
with a blank expression.
He didn't have a single friend.
Why marry a man...
I spent ten days at sea
in the heat of summer
in a fish storage bin.
My face was like a skull,
smeared with feces.
I was rocking back and
forth like a mad person.
He saw me,
he smelled me,
and he listened to me.
Does your wife know whose home
you stare into late at night?
"I cannot bear to live
with this false charge of corruption."
"Whatever it takes,"
"I will soon prove my innocence"
"and restore my honor."
It reads like a suicide note,
so I should've told the police,
but to expose my former boss...
- I see.
- I'm so sorry!
Suicide, you sure?
We got his suicide note!
You're as bad as those other damn cops!
Come on.
He's our youngest-ever inspector.
If he's as bad as
those other damn cops,
I'll dance a jig.
Of course, killing her mom
isn't proof she killed her husband.
But you said it once yourself.
Killing is like smoking.
Only the first time is hard.
Hello?
My apologies.
Hey, Soo-wan.
Soo-wan! Let's go.
Okay?
Come on, you idiot!
- Oh, hi!
- Get up.
What happened here?
- Let's go.
- Huh?
Our inspector may look like a pushover,
but he's fierce.
- He'll catch you next time...
- Hey, let's go.
So be wary
when you kill your next husband.
- Bro, your bag.
- Never mind that. Just come on!
Were my words easy enough?
I came all the way to Busan
because I respect you.
Don't.
- Let me ask one thing.
- Don't.
Why did you buy her sushi?
Shut up!
Could you...
The case is closed.
You're no longer a suspect.
Are you happy?
Why would I be?
Yes, I'm happy.
Why?
Well, now, we no longer...
We?
Did you eat dinner?
Yes.
Ice cream?
This is the "solitary"
Chinese food I can cook.
I do things at night
because of insomnia.
CHINESE FOR BEGINNERS
"Insomnia" means you can't sleep.
Unresolved cases.
I never know when to take them down...
"Unresolved" means we
didn't catch the criminal.
Unresolved...
Do ants eat people?
Oh, that...
The first to appear are the blowflies.
Whether it's day or night,
they arrive in ten minutes.
They consume blood or excretions
and lay eggs in any wound or orifice.
When maggots hatch,
that's when the ants
arrive to eat them.
After that are the beetles and wasps.
They all feast on the body.
This is Chinese food?
But the taste is good.
This is why you can't sleep.
Because those bleeding
photos are screaming wildly.
That guy Beom was found on a
mountain a month after his death.
The hatchet that smashed
his head was next to him.
San-o. He's the killer for sure,
but we can't find him.
Whenever I have time, I look into him.
After interviewing a
dozen of his ex-girlfriends,
I feel like we're close.
He's been to jail?
Yes, just for a month.
He thought some guy
was seeing his girlfriend,
so he beat him up.
When he fears jail more than death?
You're right.
He beat the guy,
knowing he'd go to jail...
So he loves that woman more than death.
Oh Ga-in?
He went up. Go!
Go!
Bro!
I turned the cylinder!
Oh Ga-in lives far away.
She runs a beauty parlor in Gyeonggi.
Also, she's married.
In Korea, if a person
you love gets married,
does the love cease?
Hey! San-o! San-o!
You didn't kill Beom for money. Right?
I know everything.
During your month in jail,
Beom made a move on Ga-in, right?
Actually, I like a woman, too.
But her husband beats her.
I want to kill that
jerk so much it hurts!
Why is it that women
sleep with such trash?
Though I'm trash, too.
Exactly!
But you're not trash.
You really love Ga-in, right?
You gave up everything for her!
And...
Tell Ga-in...
"I went through hell because of you."
"But without you, my
life would be empty."
Tell her that.
San-o, don't do it!
No need to tell her.
Are you okay?
How could they expect you to drive home
after something like that?
Shall I go to Busan?
No, no need.
- Still, when you're depressed...
- I'm not depressed.
- Really?
- I need to go to the bathroom.
- Okay.
- Bye.
After a two-year search,
he located the woman,
murdered her husband,
and subsequently began living with her.
Who is it?
Honey?
I told you you don't have to...
Why are you here?
To put you to sleep.
Am I one of your grannies?
Will you massage my arms?
What are you doing?
You said you take them
down when you solve them.
I'll burn my husband, too.
This is so dark.
Still, it's pretty.
What did you say I was?
Say it in Chinese.
Pretty.
Your silhouette.
Then let's leave that one.
And this one.
Leave this, too.
This one's better.
Will you sleep soundly now?
I'm not sure.
I have a method.
A method?
The US Navy developed it,
and I improved it.
I served in the Korean Navy.
What did the US Navy develop?
Close your eyes.
Why did you ask the cat for my head?
Your head?
What will you do with it?
I said heart, not head.
Let's start.
Listen to my breathing.
Match your breathing and mine.
Now, you go into the sea.
You go deep.
You are a jellyfish.
You have no eyes or nose.
You have no thoughts.
No joy
and no sadness.
You feel no emotion.
As you push away the water,
you push away all that happened today
to me.
Korean women have
such soft hands, right?
Don't caregivers wear gloves?
It's so calloused.
I liked it from the start,
that my detective was so dignified.
Dignified for a cop, you mean?
Dignified for a Korean?
For a man?
For a modern person.
What era do you come from anyway?
The Tang Dynasty?
Why is it you don't
ask me why I like you?
Scared you'll think of it too much?
From the start,
I knew we were of the same breed.
When you said you'd look
at your husband's photo.
That you didn't want "words."
I always try to look
at things directly, too.
Half the corpses at crime scenes
have their eyes open.
I promise them
I'll catch the killer who
was the last thing they saw.
What scares me are crime
scenes with lots of blood.
Because of the smell.
That's why you carry hand
cream that smells nice?
What else do you carry?
What scares you, Seo-rae?
You're a nurse, so it can't be blood.
High places.
Your pockets...
Twelve on the jacket, six on my pants.
Custom-made at my tailor.
I solved a case for him once,
so I get a discount.
I have to go at once when I get called,
so I wear these even on days off.
People don't stop murdering
on the weekends, you know.
But I don't wear the
same clothes every day.
I have several pairs. I'm...
Clean.
She writes for hours
in a notepad opened alongside a book.
Transcribing?
Looks things up on her phone.
Perhaps translating with a dictionary?
Watching TV again.
Talks to herself while watching.
Is it those historical shows
that make her speech so classical?
Ice cream for dinner again.
Don't smoke after meals.
Crying... at last.
Damn it.
I know you're swearing.
In front of Buddha, no less...
You delete the files
after a case is solved?
Sure.
The day your mother died?
It often helps to remember
numbers related to a case.
Since the case is closed,
I'll forget them.
♪ On this street... ♪
♪ filled with mist... ♪
How do you know such an old song?
Everyone here knows it.
It's about this town.
Twin Folio even did a cover.
They did?
You did it.
How could you?
You smoked!
Soo-wan, that punk.
He smokes so much.
He'll ruin my lungs.
YOU ASLEEP?
SONG SEO-RAE
HOSPITAL. TUESDAY GRANNY IS CRITICAL.
OH...
SHE ASKED FOR ME,
BUT SHE'S UNCONSCIOUS, SO I'M WAITING.
OH, NO...
THEN WHAT ABOUT MONDAY GRANNY?
AH, I'M WORRIED.
I COULD GO CHECK ON HER.
REALLY?
A LIVING ELDERLY COMES
BEFORE A DETECTIVE
DYING OF INSOMNIA, NO?
HAHA, IF YOU'D BE SO KIND...
THEN I'LL...
I CAN CALL THE AGENCY AT 9 A.M.
9 A.M.?
I'LL TELL THEM TO SEND SOMEONE ASAP.
THEN I'LL...
TAKE THE GREEN NOTEBOOK FROM MY HOME
AND READ IT TO HER.
- THEN...
- SHE LIKES THAT.
OKAY.
Thirty leagues to the
east is Oil Mountain.
This mountain's peak
is so deeply hidden.
For those who don't
seek it out, it's invisible.
You're a man,
but your hands are
softer than Seo-rae's.
Seo-rae's hands are a bit rough.
These days, yes.
Her palms used to be as soft as lips.
Sirae, play me a song!
"The Mist" by... who is it?
She doesn't listen to me these days.
The same phone as Seo-rae's.
Sure, we bought them together.
It's not good to have
too many apps open.
FITNESS - FLIGHTS CLIMBED
138 FLIGHTS
MONDAY, OCTOBER 26TH, 2020
Seo-rae was here this Monday?
If it was Monday, she came.
Did you go somewhere with her?
I haven't left this house in ten years.
Granny, what day is it today?
Where do you see a granny, darling?
I don't know what day it is.
Hae-dong, you're a smart girl, right?
Let's say that...
Seo-rae came today.
Then it's Monday.
A.M./P.M.
Set the clock to the exact time
Seo-rae was captured on CCTV
and start walking.
Switching the phones and exiting,
maybe seven minutes.
If she climbs out the back window,
there are no CCTV cameras.
There are two possible routes.
The easy route
and the hard one.
The time it takes is about the same.
I always go up the hard way,
but for the sake of novice viewers,
today, I'll take the easy route!
Song Seo-rae would've
taken the easy course,
so as not to meet her husband.
Yes, Manager. I arrived at work.
Yes, it's okay.
Bye.
At 9 a.m.,
the confirmation call
comes from the agency.
If you slip here,
no need to feel embarrassed.
Bigeum Peak was once called Oil Peak.
Meaning it's as slippery as oil.
Quite a view, isn't it?
If I start Mahler's Symphony
No. 5 at the base,
I arrive as the fourth movement ends.
On the peak, I enjoy the fifth movement
and then descend.
It's perfect.
A perfect hiding place.
Song Seo-rae would've hidden
here and then climbed to the peak.
Before the fifth movement of
Mahler's Symphony No. 5 ended.
The last overhang might pose a problem.
But anyway, you'll see.
Compared to the hard course I take,
this is nothing!
Like popping sushi in your mouth,
just climb up rung by rung,
and then you're on the peak!
Korean women have
such soft hands, right?
Ten in the morning.
I'm at the top of my
beloved Bigeum Peak.
So far removed from the filthy world.
I could die like this.
You said you're scared of high places.
When he beat you,
when he branded you
like some kind of cow,
why didn't you call the police?
Why not trust us?
He said they'd send me back to China.
Is that why you sent him
those threatening letters?
They would've come anyway.
The bribes were all true.
IF YOU DON'T ANSWER,
I WILL REPORT YOU.
Then you must've forged his letter
to the immigration office, too.
The address on the envelope was
in his handwriting.
How did you do that?
SENDER KI DO-SOO
RECIPIENT IMMIGRATION OFFICE
I just fixed the contents of his letter
to give it a feel of a will.
When you said Soo-wan was violent,
that must've been a lie, too.
If a policeman gets drunk
and enters a woman's home,
isn't that violence?
Burning the photos,
erasing my voice recordings.
It must've been so easy.
"Give it a feel" that you like me,
and I do it all for you?
Don't speak about our time that way.
Our time?
What kind of time was that?
The time I spent outside
your home each night?
The time I slept so well
listening to you breathe?
The time I embraced you
and whispered I was happy?
You said I was dignified?
You know where dignity comes from?
From pride.
I was a proud police officer.
But...
I went crazy for a woman
and ruined an investigation.
Now...
I'm completely shattered.
I bought Granny a new phone.
The same model.
She has no idea.
Throw that phone in the sea.
Someplace deep,
where no one can find it.
SHATTERED
1. RUINED OR BROKEN.
THIRTEEN MONTHS LATER
The stress from losing
criminals and so on
can cause sleep disorders.
My first recommendation
is to sunbathe 30 minutes before noon.
You can wear clothes,
but keep your eyes open...
Doctor.
You haven't worked
long in Ipo, have you?
There's no sun in the morning.
Because of the fog.
You still have running water, right?
Of course.
Take a foot bath before sleeping,
and I'll prescribe
dopamine, so take that.
If that still doesn't work,
this instrument helps you breathe
through your nose as you sleep.
This here...
You know pomegranates
can delay menopause?
Won't things be easier
for you after menopause?
That's true, but still...
Since you moved home,
I feel healthier
thanks to your cooking
and these pomegranates.
So why are you withering away?
Withering?
Am I a pomegranate?
June was shocked to see your photo.
Said, "What happened to
your good-looking husband?"
I heard 56 percent of middle-aged
men are at risk of depression.
June knows a guy who
took soft-shell turtle juice,
and it really helped
with testosterone.
I'm really happy with
you here in Ipo...
I'm happy, too.
You need murder and violence
in order to be happy.
Where is your husband?
He ran off without me!
You crazy jerk!
Then what are all these?
How could you buy this stuff
without your husband?
While you two live like this,
my mom cries every day,
begging me to kill her.
What does the doctor say?
That she won't last a month.
If my mom dies,
your damned husband...
I told you I'd bear it
for just ten minutes.
For your mother's sake.
Does she know you go
around beating up women?
Does she know what your nickname is?
If she dies,
I'll put her in the freezer
and hold the funeral
until after I kill your husband!
Those babies meant so much to me...
Don't you worry now.
Our captain here was the
nation's youngest inspector,
an ace even in Busan!
Sir! The stolen goods
are 58 soft-shell turtles.
What's the tally on damages?
The market price is over 3,000 dollars!
What? Why so expensive?
They help with depression
in middle-aged men.
You're a legend, Inspector!
How could you know all that?
- Tell them to turn off the lamps.
- Yes, sir.
Hey, Ji-hyuk!
You're a fool!
I told you not to come,
that you'd die here!
What else can I do?
- This is the sole way to see you.
Honey, pack your bags quick!
Changed your number again?
Hurry up!
Slappy found out your location!
Oh, and next week, meet
with the Chinese clients.
If I don't break through
on the Chinese front,
I'm in trouble.
Wait, I got a message.
He came already?
That's no face to be having
meetings with anyone.
I love you. We're okay, right?
Whatever, let's move.
Yes, we'd better.
Since Slappy found you.
Where should we move to?
- That's smoke, right?
- Smoke or fog.
Even if there's a real fire,
nobody will come out.
Now that we're outside, let's smoke.
People say you came here
after getting depression
because you couldn't
stop a suspect's suicide.
But I heard you recovered...
Do I still look depressed?
It's because I can't sleep. That's all.
He's wearing dress shoes?
If you're not smoking,
why not go back in?
For my sake, since I'm an outcast?
At least the boonies are quiet, right?
Smoke outside, will you?
I love you!
- What are you...
- I moved here.
Why?
There's nothing in this town.
I like the mist.
I'm Song Seo-rae.
I'm Chinese, so my
Korean is insufficient.
Honey, this is the detective
who suspected me.
I'm the next husband. Name's Im Ho-sin.
Jang Hae-joon.
What brings you to Ipo?
I touched a fish.
I moved here, too.
My wife works here.
I'm Ahn Jeong-ahn.
People leave Ipo because of the fog.
They don't come for it.
Once you deal with the mold...
Listen to you.
Actually, we came
because of the reactor.
Really? Why?
- Is it "Red Alert"?
- Yes.
You know the TV series
about the nuclear accident?
So many Chinese women are dying
to visit the shooting location.
And she's a tour guide there.
I realize it's your source of income,
so this may be a bit rude,
but we're not too keen on TV shows
that trade in such
baseless fearmongering.
That's where she works.
It's a sensitive topic.
Nuclear power plants are
actually completely safe.
You were on "Stock
Market TV," weren't you?
You've seen it! I'm a stock analyst.
Not an "analist" who likes rear ends.
You look younger than on TV.
The secret to my youth is a daily swim,
and for my secret to investing,
you can call me.
Can I have your card?
No need to run in this town.
She's pretty, that woman.
Her green dress was pretty.
Wasn't it blue?
Whatever.
A Chinese woman whose husband died...
Did you tell me about that case?
I heard about an old man
whose Chinese wife killed herself.
There was that, too.
Did the husband murder her?
No, I suspected an innocent person.
That woman said you suspected her, too.
Yes, but her husband committed suicide.
You suspect a lot of
innocent people, honey.
That's why people hate us.
Us?
The police.
ASSISTANT INSPECTOR YEO YEON-SOO
Honey! Can you answer this?
Blood.
Hello?
Honey.
Congratulations.
What?
It's a murder case.
Estimated time of death, 11 a.m.
Stabbed 17 times.
Thirteen times in the
stomach and chest.
Four times in the back.
The wounds in the back were
while running away, I guess?
Can a person run after
being stabbed 13 times?
And anyway, why is the
corpse in that position?
The wife was the first to find him.
Shall I bring her?
The suspect is left-handed.
Write this down!
Is this why you came to Ipo?
Am I such a pushover?
Am I so wicked?
Listen to me, Ms. Song.
This time, your alibi
better be solid as a rock.
You think the wife killed him?
Why?
Because there are no signs
of forced entry or theft?
Because he was stabbed
haphazardly from the front,
suggesting a crime of passion
by an acquaintance?
Because the wife didn't
seem very shocked or sad?
That's because there are some
to whom grief comes crashing...
Why are you so inquisitive with me
and not with the others?
I know her from another
case, last year in Busan.
Her husband died then, too.
She killed him?
Sorry, the question just popped
into my head.
It was ruled a suicide,
but now, another husband died,
in my jurisdiction again!
But she's right-handed.
So we need to figure out
how she can be the murderer!
They said come to the station.
Can I get my handbag?
You went out for a walk,
but you left your phone
behind, so it can't be traced.
No way to prove your alibi, then?
It seems so.
You don't seem worried at all.
Did anyone hold a grudge
against your husband?
He did a lot of investing
with other people's money.
Recently, there were losses.
But he lived in a luxury villa.
He said to raise money, you
have to spend it visibly.
Why did you marry a man like that?
It was so I could make the decision
to leave another man.
Did you come to Ipo because
of any connections here?
Because we have no connections here.
If we did, creditors would find us.
You chose your husband
not for reasons of love.
That husband received various threats
and then died.
Just the same as last year.
What?
That husband was suicide,
and this husband was murder.
Fine.
In the same detective's jurisdiction,
but quite far apart from each other,
two husbands died
of suicide or murder.
If someone told me that,
I'd probably respond like this.
Wow, what a coincidence.
How would you respond?
Wow,
what a poor woman.
She had different clothes.
It was a blue dress.
With no coat.
You sure it was blue?
Not green?
Thank you.
It's blue all right.
What was she doing down there?
Why did you move here, really?
Why do you keep asking?
Is it so important to you
why I came?
Why is it important?
What else can I do?
This is the sole way to see you.
What did you wear on
your walk by the sea?
This.
That's a lie.
Where's the blue-green dress?
That looks blue one moment
and green the next?
With the sparkling buttons.
You looked so closely.
Where can it be?
Sorry I'm late!
Hello.
Did you see this?
Wow, a murder in our town!
I'm sleepy already. How
will I stay up all night?
FAMOUS STOCK ANALYST FOUND DEAD IN IPO
I came back from my walk,
and the blood smell was strong.
I thought of you.
You would come here,
and you would be scared.
Ms. Song.
You just admitted
to destroying evidence.
I'm putting you
under emergency arrest for murder.
I didn't want the police to
step on my husband's blood.
We've got her smartwatch, right?
Open up the voice recordings.
They must be in Chinese,
so find a translator.
Are you a male?
No.
Have you ever killed a person?
Yes.
Did you kill your husband Im Ho-sin?
No.
Inspector?
What are you doing here?
The transcript of the
smartwatch recordings.
And you asked us to check
the plates of cars near the villa
in recent days.
One of them was a man
defrauded by Im Ho-sin.
And he's been arrested
twice for assault.
His name is Sa Cheol-seong.
I've never heard of that last time.
Let go!
You okay? What are you doing?
Call me.
Call me, Mom!
Left-handed, right?
270,000 dollars.
That's what my mom earned
running a food cart for ten years
and then running her own Chinese
restaurant 18 hours a day.
She gave that money to Im Ho-sin.
At first, it was only 10,000 dollars.
But when dividends kept coming in,
she got excited
and threw it all in.
So that guy takes everyone's cash
and goes around staying in hotels,
gambling,
buying his wife clothes and handbags,
living like a king!
Ten million dollars.
My mom already had diabetes,
but after losing that
money, she collapsed,
and her kidneys gave out.
She couldn't get treated in time,
and they cut off all her toes!
You know why they call me Slappy?
Slap, slap...
my hand can really fly!
Slapping with my palm
hurts a lot less than punching,
so I can keep on hitting!
But...
if I don't kill Im Ho-sin,
can I call myself a man?
Do you know Song Seo-rae?
Did she ask you to kill him?
Give me a break.
I'm not a guy to take
orders from anyone else.
Song Seo-rae was a big help to me.
She must have no idea,
why it is that I found her
wherever she ran...
I took her phone
and installed a tracking app.
What the hell?
Why did you sit him up? That's creepy.
You scumbag,
you want a slap in the face?
Have you lost your marbles?
I'll slap...
Sir, don't you feel happy?
Why should I?
We solved Ipo's first-ever murder case!
Where should we celebrate?
Solved?
Who said it's solved?
Now that we've got the suspect,
we can let Song Seo-rae go, right?
Just popped into my head.
Suspects in the
soft-shell turtle burglary
fleeing on a motorcycle.
Approaching the community
center. Requesting backup.
They're running away!
The turtles!
Hurry up!
Come here, you. Hold the sack!
Get the big ones first!
They've got a temper,
so watch your fingers!
I returned some stolen goods...
If the husband of a woman
my husband knows
calls me twice in the
middle of the night...
Did he call by mistake?
Is he hitting
on a married woman he just met?
I could just ignore it, but...
if he was killed not long after that?
Honey.
Did you kill him?
Did the two of you kill him?
Is your finger okay?
The number for Im
Ho-sin's burner phone.
Check the location on
the day he was killed.
IM FOR "IMPACTFUL INVESTMENT"!
HO FOR "HOT TIPS"!
SIN FOR "SINGLE GREATEST ANALYST"!
Inspector!
Yeah?
While Im Ho-sin was dead at home,
why was his phone being
turned on and off here?
Raise your arm and
lift your hand a bit.
My arm hurts!
Stop!
She threw the phone.
Let's call the divers and search!
Is it deep there?
Will you snap out of it?
We caught the murderer!
We have evidence and a confession!
Will you please stop obsessing
about that woman?
Don't you feel sorry for her?
He's wearing dress shoes?
Stubble?
He used to shave day and night.
Has he grown lazy?
He looks lifeless...
Because he can't meet me?
When he cooked that
bizarre Chinese food,
I smoked right next to him.
This man can't stand cigarettes.
Saying he loves me, empty words...
I remember the nights
he watched me.
It felt like
a trustworthy man
was staying awake to watch over me.
He's coming.
He'll ask me
is this why I came to Ipo.
What do I say?
Why do you keep crying, Song Seo-rae?
Should I answer him?
No...
He may
already know it.
He may not even ask.
Is this why you came to Ipo?
Hello.
What was on that phone? Answer me.
Open the door now!
I'm not there.
Then where are you?
Homi Mountain.
What was on Im Ho-sin's phone
that you had to throw it away?
Don't fall asleep.
Just a little bit farther.
There's no mist here.
Why did Im Ho-sin call my wife?
My mountain-loving mom often told me,
each time I felt upset...
if I go to Korea, my mountain is there.
Be honest with me.
You knew that
Im Ho-sin wanted to
talk to my wife right?
In court, the government
took it from me,
but whatever anyone says,
in my heart, this is my mountain.
Mom, Grandpa.
I brought a very trustworthy man.
Scatter these for me.
You know I'm scared of heights.
Why do I marry such men?
Because commendable men like you
won't marry me.
For such a man to speak to me,
something on the scale
of murder has to happen.
Is this a time for jokes?
After leaving me,
you never once slept soundly, right?
Even if you forced your eyes shut,
you kept thinking of me?
Didn't you feel this way, too?
That night you ran
into me in the market,
suddenly, you felt alive again?
At last.
My hands are soft enough now?
For the past 402 days, I've...
You were...
But that doesn't change the fact
that I'm a cop and you're a suspect.
You know the word "suspect"?
Someone the police are watching.
I like that.
Treat me as you will,
like you always did...
As a suspect.
You're curious
why I like you, right?
Or did you say you weren't?
Seo-rae,
your body is very...
upright.
Few people have such posture
unless they're nervous.
I think it says a lot about you.
What happened to
the four fentanyl pills?
Carrying you all this time
has been heavy for me.
Goodbye, Grandpa.
Goodbye, Mom.
I told you to throw this
where no one can find it!
Re-investigate with this.
Go back to before you were shattered.
Maybe I went to Ipo
to become one of your unresolved cases.
- June!
- Yes?
Your first time seeing him?
June just got divorced.
I'm Lee June. I've
heard a lot about you.
It didn't snow here?
What?
What about that promise of ours?
What promise?
That we'd do it once a week
even when we hate each other.
Step aside, would you?
Are you getting enough sleep?
They did a test
and said I wake up 47 times per hour.
Can you believe that?
I'd like to exchange my sleep with you,
like batteries.
They say it's because I
breathe through my mouth.
They said to use a machine
to breathe through my nose.
There's a machine like that.
It's strange.
I breathe through my nose when awake.
That doesn't mean I snore, though.
I know.
Sunbathing... Vitamin D!
Good to see the sun, huh?
Thirty minutes are up.
I talked to the women
divers by the sea.
Told them to keep an eye out
while diving for abalone.
Think this can be restored?
SEO-RAE
WANTED TO PLAY THIS RECORDING
TO YOUR HAE-JOON'S WIFEY,
BUT SHE'S NOT ANSWERING.
I'LL CALL AGAIN IN THE MORNING.
THE TALKS WITH THE
CHINESE ARE GOING WELL.
YOU WANT TO RUIN EVERYTHING?
I'M A DEAD MAN ANYWAY.
SLAPPY'S MOTHER WON'T LAST LONG.
THAT PRICK FOLLOWS ME EVERYWHERE.
IF NO ANSWER FROM THE
CHINESE IN TWO DAYS,
THIS RECORDING GOES ON THE INTERNET.
THE CITIZENS HAVE A RIGHT TO KNOW
HOW COPS AND SUSPECTS FOOL AROUND.
I'M HAVING LUNCH WITH THE CHINESE
IN TWO DAYS,
SO COME HOME BY 10 A.M.
I'M HAVING LUNCH WITH
THE CHINESE IN TWO DAYS,
SO COME HOME BY 10 A.M.
DELETE ALL
VOICE RECORDINGS - NO FILES
On the day your mother died,
you met Song Seo-rae?
She visited the hospital
early in the morning.
She said she felt so bad
about my mom's condition
as a fellow Chinese.
Did she bring any pills?
Something for her diabetes?
Blue-green capsules.
I don't know,
but she sure knew
how to treat a patient.
She massaged her here and there,
and my mom cheered right up.
So I left and went out for breakfast.
When I got back,
she was gone,
and my mom was lying back
comfortably with her eyes closed,
talking about how she felt so sleepy.
Then not long after...
Did her massage have anything
to do with my mom's passing?
Didn't Slappy say
he put a tracking app
on Seo-rae's phone?
Hae-joon.
We restored your husband's phone.
But there's no voice file.
It was Slappy who killed your husband,
but you killed Slappy's mother.
Because he said
he'd kill your husband
if his mother died.
Your husband
and Slappy's mother...
They both died because of me, right?
She'd have died soon anyway.
Why give her the fentanyl?
She thanked me for it.
What was the recording your
husband threatened to share?
Don't worry about that.
I'm not asking because I'm worried!
You've got the original?
What's the recording?
Your voice.
What?
Telling me you love me.
Me?
I liked it so much. I listened often.
But my husband found out.
When did I say I loved you?
When was it?
The moment you said you loved me,
your love ended.
And the moment your love ended,
my love began.
Tell me in Korean.
Seo-rae...
Hae-joon.
The phone you took from the sea,
throw it back.
Throw it in a deeper sea.
Why don't you answer me straight?
This is so frustrating!
Seo-rae, where are you going?
Seo-rae?
Hello?
Seo-rae!
VOICE RECORDINGS - "RUINED OR BROKEN"
RUINED OR BROKEN
Burning the photos, erasing...
erasing my voice recordings.
It must've been so easy.
"Give it a feel" that you like me,
and I do it all for you?
Don't speak about our time...
Throw that phone in the sea.
Someplace deep,
where no one can find it.
Throw that phone in the sea.
In the sea...
- Someplace deep...
Where no one can find it.
Maybe I went to Ipo to become
one of your unresolved cases.
Put my photos on your wall,
stay awake all night,
and think solely of me.
Seo-rae!
Seo-rae, where are you?
Put out an urgent search
for Song Seo-rae.
I'm at Lion's Rock Coast.
It's almost high tide.
Bring everyone you have!
She abandoned her car and vanished.
If we hurry, we'll find her.
She can't have gone far!
Don't waste time with questions!
It's going to be dark soon!
I went crazy for a woman
and ruined an investigation.
Now...
I'm completely shattered.
I bought Granny a new phone.
The same model.
She has no idea.
Throw that phone in the sea.
Someplace deep,
where no one can find it.
Throw that phone in the sea.
Your voice.
Telling me you love me.
Seo-rae!
Decision To Leave
Directed by Park Chan-wook
Tang Wei
Park Hae-il
Lee Jung-hyun, Park Yong-woo
Ko Kyoung-pyo, Kim Shin-young
Jung Young-sook, Yoo Seung-mok
Park Jeong-min, Seo Hyun-woo
♪ I walk alone ♪
♪ On the street filled with mist ♪
♪ Is that your silhouette ♪
♪ My dear beloved? ♪
♪ What's the point ♪
♪ In reminiscing about the past? ♪
♪ But I still yearn for you ♪
♪ Where have you gone, my love? ♪
♪ - In the mist ♪
♪ - All by myself ♪
♪ I walk away ♪
♪ Endlessly ♪
♪ But your low voice pulls me back ♪
♪ When I turn to go ♪
♪ Oh, wind, please ♪
♪ blow this mist away ♪
♪ Where have you gone, my love? ♪
♪ - In the mist ♪
♪ - Open your eyes ♪
♪ - Hide your tears in the mist ♪