In the name of God
Look at you!
What in the world are you looking at?
Can't check out my own fiance?
Put it away, it's embarrassing!
- This one is nice. - Which one?
- The one we took on your roof.
What class!
- Was that your foot?
- No, it was my chador.
I've told you 100 times! Hold onto
your chador! Now what do do?
Okay...
Be careful, you'll rip it.
There's nobody here at this hour.
- Who are you hiding from?
- From you!
- Don't go too fast!
- Alright. Go in already!
- Hi!
- Hello, beautiful bride-to-be!
- Are there many people?
- Lots.
Hitchhiking on that
road is pretty shady.
Especially for a girl.
- They'll find her.
- Find her? Right, dream on.
- Wasn't expecting you.
- There wasn't much snow.
You need money to get married.
If our pay was enough
to get married with,
would've done it
100 times already!
You've already buried
three husbands!
- Didn't take any from you.
- Be my guest!
Well, goodbye.
Hurry up,
have to get back early.
- Sit down, I'm going to try.
- Thank you.
I've brought it for you.
Do you want to try it on?
- Is it our turn yet?
- So, which one of the two should go?
Find a job for my wife and me.
- Hi, granny.
- Hello.
Wait!
Where are you?
Congratulations.
- When is it for?
- Next Friday.
You'll have it by Thursday
and pay what you can.
Thanks a lot.
- Pick any one.
- Are you kidding me?
I'm serious. Go on.
- This one.
- Let me see. Heravi Square.
- It's too far.
- The others are worse.
- Show me.
- Go on.
- Don't come back late.
- You got it. See you later.
- Who is it?
- Excuse me, ma'am.
Your neighbors aren't answering.
Do you know where they are?
Their buzzer's broken. You are...
I'm here to work for them.
Could you let me in?
I'll call them
and they'll let you in themselves.
- Give me the fish.
- Mom!
Be good!
Hurry up!
Be careful, you'll fall.
Where are you going?
- Are you looking for someone?
- Apartment 17.
- Buzz and they'll let you in.
- It's already open.
Don't know what you're doing here.
Go on. Step outside.
Hold on.
- Hello.
- Hello, come in.
Swear, have the tickets already.
You don't know how long I've
wanted to go away with my family.
Yeah, right...
Leave me alone!
Fine, okay. Five minutes?
Know it'll last until midnight!
Okay. Bye.
Miss?
- Yes.
- Stan with this room.
My wife will tell you
what to do afterward
What a mess!
Wait a minute.
Put on these slippers.
There's glass, you might get hurt.
Why do you have my cell?
Why'd you take it?
Have things to do.
have to go.
I've been looking for you
for an hour.
When are you coming back?
- Sir? - Hello, yes?
- The broom and dustpan?
Just a second.
Over there.
It's the cleaning lady called.
Specialized agencies send them over.
So, they'll work together!
She parked in front of the gate again!
- You shouldn't have called her.
- My cell?
- The concierge was
going to help me.
It's been a damn mess
for three days now.
The concierge, the concierge...
- My phone?
- Where are you going?
- Give it to me, have to run.
- Run where?
- To work. What do you think?
- Today?
Mahmud called.
They have some problems.
- We were supposed to talk.
- I'll be back. I'm not running away.
You said we'd talk it over today.
Know did,
but that damn Mahmud needs me.
Don't worry, I'll be back by 5
and we'll take care of everything.
- You said that this morning!
- Yes, did say that. You're right!
But they need me.
That's just great!
You always have time for Mahmud!
- Amir-Ali's not home. - And, so?
- don't want to talk in front of him.
What's the problem of talking
in front of him?
We have to make a decision.
Decide for yourself.
I've already decided.
Then I'm not going tomorrow.
What are you saying?
Mojdeh?
Listen. have the tickets.
I'm not your puppet.
You promised.
Don't go back on your word.
All promised you
was a trip to Dubai.
Kept my promise,
you're full of shit!
- Watch your language.
- Look who's talking.
The guy begged me
to come and help him.
It's urgent and you want me to stay.
- Didn't say anything.
- Yesterday, you said enough.
You're the one who said too much.
You so damn neurotic!
Idiot.
Wait.
I'm speaking to you. If you leave,
I'll take Amir-Ali and go.
- You're a disgrace!
- Disgrace! I'm not moving
Wait! swear I'll take him away.
Why won't you understand?
Mrs. Sabri?
- Hello, ma'am.
- Hello. Call your wife.
- She won't be long.
- She was supposed to help me.
- She's out shopping
for the Razavi family.
- Tell her to come see me.
The management won't allow
my wife to work.
It's none of their business.
When she works, take care of the kids.
They say it keeps me from my work.
Tell her to come up.
I'll take care of it.
- Is your mother home?
- Yes, come in.
Mom, it's Mrs. Samii.
Mojdeh, dear, come in!
- Thanks. ls Sabri here?
- No, why?
- She was supposed to help me.
- The management doesn't
want her to work.
Tell her to see me
when she finishes your shopping.
- Let's keep this between us.
- Okay.
They talked about her
in the meeting.
Well? What happened?
They're going to tell the landlord
to take care of it.
Don't worry about it.
We know nothing. Come in.
- Have to run. Tell her to come up.
- Bye.
Hello, ma'am.
I'm looking for bleach.
Come here.
Didn't see any in the kitchen.
I'm going to do the dishes
in the bathtub.
That way, I'll make some room here.
It's okay. Thanks a lot.
- How much do owe you?
- What? haven't even started yet!
Know. Someone's
coming by to help.
- Then why did you call the agency?
- My husband did.
- What difference does that make?
- don't owe you an explanation.
- I'm sorry.
- I've changed my mind.
Didn't go through your drawer.
Was cleaning in the
room and it just fell out.
Will five thousand Tomans do?
Five thousand? But why?
came all this way!
It's not enough? How much then?
Can't accept this money
when didn't do anything.
Take it. Someone else
is coming to do it.
Did do something wrong?
What happened?
No. Are you going
to take it or what?
She has three days of work here.
- Don't care.
- I'll help you.
You don't want it?
It's up to you.
Close the door behind you.
- Yes?
- Why isn't anyone answering?
- Their buzzer doesn't work.
- Fix it. You're wasting people's time!
- Yes?
- There's a gentleman here for you.
- Who is it?
- The glass cutter.
Tell him I'm coming.
You parked in front of the gate again!
What do you mean?
They want to park a truck?
- Who gave me a flat?
- don't know.
How should know?
Give me the keys.
I'll do it. just want
to see if it's the psycho!
- Saw her come in.
- Their buzzer doesn't work.
- Forget it.
Are you looking for trouble?
- She doesn't scare me.
Don't forget our New Year's gifts.
Mrs. Sami!
Miss?
Someone's calling you.
What's wrong?
- Did anybody call this morning?
- No. Nobody.
When my husband was there?
When got there,
he was on the phone.
- Who was it?
- What do you mean?
- What was he saying?
- don't know, ma'am.
Sorry...
Listen!
Come here!
Said come here.
- Who is it?
- Hello, ma'am.
Hello. May he-[0 you?
wanted to make an appointment
at the salon.
- Your name?
- Ruhangiz Barati
- Is this your first time?
- Yes.
Who referred you?
Madame Rahimi.
I'm busy now.
Can you this afternoon?
- Around what time?
- 5 p. m.
Otherwise, go for a walk
and come back in 30 minutes.
- What about between 2 and 5?
-  can't; I'll be out.
Okay, well then perhaps
in 30 minutes.
- Thanks, it's very nice.
- You're welcome.
- Was good?
- Yes, thank you.
Thank you, God.
The other one is also ?at.
Why is it so expensive?
If you only knew how far
I've come in this cold.
You still haven't taken
the trash down?
You live far from here.
Was busy, I'll do it.
Don't forget our New Year's gifts.
- Should we hang the curtains?
- We can't do it alone.
- Why don't you call your husband?
- He doesn't even reach my waist!
- What is it?
- New Year's gifts for the kids?
Paid twice as much
and you want presents as well?
Why is the water running?
- This bucket is still dirty.
- I'll wash it.
Want the girl to come and help?
Which girl?
- The one that was here.
- The cleaning lady?
- Why is she still here?
- She has an appointment at the salon.
- The salon?
- She's getting married soon.
She's going to have
her eyebrows done.
It's cold outside,
tell her to come up.
Do you know how much
she's going to pay you?
I'm totally lost.
This morning, she gave me five
thousand Tomans and asked me to leave.
- They're strange. Are they fighting?
- We can't take it any more.
Last night, her husband went mad
and broke the window.
Saw the broken glass.
It's always the same thing.
Are you afraid with your husband?
- No, he's not at all like that.
- No offense.
- Is your husband like that?
- God forbid! wouldn't say that.
My husband is madly
in love with me!
Nasser, my cousin,
was also in love with me.
- When's it for?
- One more month.
Is it expensive?
- What?
- The hairdresser.
Simine is very fair.
Explain your situation
and she'll charge less.
Why don't you call Mom...
It's ringing.
Hello? Hi Mom. How are you?
- It's Mahdi.
- Is it for me?
- What are you waiting for?
- You knew wouldn't come up
- Hurry, we have lots to do.
- You have to make up with her today.
Okay. Be careful going down.
- Still not finished.
- No need to take off your shoes.
- Could've picked you up.
- Ahmad is downstairs.
- Who is that?
- She's helping me.
Ahmad is staying downstairs
like always.
- If it bothers you, get him.
- Me?
It's about time! It's been a year!
He got worked up by himself.
He'll come back when he's ready.
Just like kids!
What's this mess?
Still haven't finished?
Heat it up, we'll eat it.
You're the kid.
You never take things seriously.
And what about you, Mrs. Serious?
Have you looked in the mirror?
There's a salon next door!
Excuse me. I'd like to get
my husband's permission.
- His permission? - For the salon.
- No need.
She's getting married.
She wants to get her eyebrows done.
Don't tell him everything...
No tea for me.
Surprise him.
Do as you please.
Didn't get any fruit.
You're so busy!
Will you be ready for Dubai,
with this mess?
- Ma'am, shouldn't call him?
- It's up to you, he's your husband.
You should've picked
a better country.
- He didn't even want Dubai.
- Why Dubai?
- Think about Amir-Ali.
- Amir-Ali will grow up
like other children.
Anyway, I'm not sure we're leaving.
What do you mean, not leaving?
Don't know. We'll see.
Take this when you leave.
- Know how stubborn you can be.
- What do you mean?
You didn't see Amir-Ali sleeping.
You're going to be late.
He was so frightened.
He said he was dreaming about hell.
They lectured the kids on hell
at school for an hour.
He can't even play
without me keeping an eye on him.
Have to take him to school.
I'm turning it off,
the handles are burning.
- One more window and I'll go.
- You'll miss your appointment.
There's danger everywhere.
I'm always worried
when leave the house.
In fact, one of my co-workers
disappeared the other night.
- Don't tell her where you were.
- Why not?
- Mrs. Rahimi referred you.
- Ah, forgot.
You don't need that.
It's right over there.
- Goodbye, ma'am.
- Goodbye.
Why don't you answer?
Don't lie.
What are you doing?
Oh yeah? can see from here.
Listen.
Hello, ma'am.
Come up for a minute.
When do you count on making peace?
They're leaving tomorrow.
What are you doing?
I'm coming.
What's all this about?
What happened this time?
Are you hiding something from me?
Look at me.
- Did Morteza call?
- Poor guy, he was on
the verge of tears.
Why are acting like this?
You're ruining you life!
Mrs. Sabri?
Clean the living room windows first.
Come see.
Mojdeh, you were doing so well
over these past months.
Did something happen?
Didn't know what he was up to!
What are you talking about?
Poor guy!
He works hard day and night
for you and Amir-Ali.
He thinks I'm an idiot.
He's not a fool.
Why would he leave you?
And for whom?
Mojdeh, patience has limits.
One day, he'll leave you alone
with your kid.
To hell with him!
Come on. Go make up with Ahmad.
You'll need a place to
stay if you fight with him.
You don't have anyone besides us.
You're the fool!
Such a sweet and kind husband!
Don't defend him without
knowing him! know my husband!
Wish Dad was here.
Have you noticed anything recently?
- I've heard things.
- From whom?
What difference does it make?
You want to ruin you life
because of gossip?
It's one of our neighbors.
She heard Morteza's voice
on that bitch's answering machine.
Maybe she made a mistake.
- I'm sure of it.
- How can you be sure?
He smells like her perfume.
That's all you needed.
And with someone here!
Behind these walls, under my nose.
Try to think
about your trip tomorrow.
Leave all this till
after the holidays.
Darling, don't get all worked up.
- Have to settle this tonight.
- What are you going to do tonight?
Your brother-in-law keeps honking.
- Go, he's waiting for you.
- can't leave you like this.
Go on.
Don't get yourself all worked up.
It'll be fine.
Give me a kiss.
- Happy New Year, anyway.
- Thanks.
- What's wrong with you?
- I've been waiting an hour for you!
You have good taste. can see
he's mischievous. Isn't he?
It took my father two years
to accept this marriage.
He was so persistent,
my dad finally accepted.
- Hair colon'?
- No. That would be too much for him!
Does he love you?
Let me see.
Do you like it?
Thank you so much.
- Tea?
- I'll make it.
Since when do customers make tea?
- Ma'am'? - Yes.
- What's your perfume?
I'd like to find the same but for men.
It was a gift.
It's the blue bottle in front of you.
Don't get pregnant too soon now!
He's in such a rush, I'm sure
I'll have twins on our wedding day!
Do you have children?
- Hello.
- Hello, come in.
Just wanted to quickly
visit the apartment.
Now?
- I'll explain... Please come in.
- Sorry to bother you.
Here's the kitchen.
There's a terrace in the back.
- Have you already found something?
- Found what?
Can you move out now
or are you still looking?
Don't live here.
It's full of light, Mom.
- Do you want to raise the rent?
- It has nothing to do about that.
- So then?
- have some problems. need the money.
Thank you, Mr. Razaghi.
We'll be in touch.
Just the garage and I'll be right back.
- Thank you, ma'am.
- Goodbye.
- You didn't want to sell it!
- Now do.
Already told you. have worries.
need money.
I'm sick and tired
of all the complaints about you.
- Who has complained?
- The neighbors.
Why don't they tell me?
- This is an apartment. - Yeah, and?
- You've opened a hair salon!
I'll be right there!
Sorry for having bothered you.
Is there a problem with my salon?
don't bother anyone!
- What's the problem?
- The neighbors are complaining.
Too many strangers. Brides...
They don't dare tell you themselves.
They tell me.
Some car stereos
were stolen last week.
- By my customers?
- You don't know all of them.
- For example, do you
know this young lady?
- She's my niece.
Sorry. didn't mean any harm.
Usually speaking...
- Some tea, Auntie?
- Yes, darling.
- Didn't even offer you any teal
- Thanks, but they're waiting for me.
Just a sec.
Tell me who complained.
As soon as a woman lives alone,
people say slanderous things.
Want this to be clear.
don't make any noise in this building.
Okay, won't lie,
last wee had a bride...
and there was a little music.
Not even 10 minutes.
When my neighbors have parties,
never complain.
- We'll talk tomorrow.
- Everyone leaves on vacation tomorrow.
Upstairs they're going to Yazd.
Just across they're leaving at 4.
Everyone will be gone.
Let's settle this now.
This lighter doesn't work.
I'll get in touch with you later.
As if didn't have enough problems.
Ma'am, the lighter doesn't work.
If you don't mind, must go.
- First have some tea.
- No, thanks.
- Don't forget your photos!
- won't. But tell me...
- How much do owe you?
- Keep your money.
We'll worry about that when
you come on your wedding day.
Wouldn't dare come back.
Have you ever seen
a niece pay her aunt?
- It's not done.
- So, it's my New Year's gift.
I'm not really comfortable with this.
But, thanks a lot.
Ma.
am!
- Have you forgotten something?
- No.
That gentleman who was here earlier
asking you to leave...
I'm sorry, but overheard you.
Think your next door neighbor
was involved.
- Which one?
- The one across from you.
- You know them?
- This morning, came to work for them.
- You're the one who buzzed?
- Yes.
- She asked you to come here?
- No, came on my own.
- Didn't Mrs. Rahimi refer you?
- Yes, it was her.
Saw her this morning
having her tires changed.
She was furious.
I'm sure it was her.
Don't know them. They don't
seem to be that kind of people.
Hardly see her. bumped into
her husband. He seems serious.
The lady is kind of strange.
Barely arrived when suddenly
she fired me and paid me.
Why?
She didn't trust me.
She was afraid might steal from her.
Don't know anyone here.
They're all just acquaintances.
But this lady doesn't trust anybody.
When you go home,
try not to upset her.
Don't want to cause any trouble.
Don't worry.
Sabri, come get your child,
he keeps crying.
Take him down.
Hello.
Now you look like a bride.
- Have changed?
- Yes, and you look much better.
- Where is my chador?
- Over there.
It really changes you,
congratulations.
I'm going to make lunch,
put him down and I'll be back.
Don't bother.
The young lady will do the rest.
Goodbye.
That kid was driving me crazy.
Give me a glass.
If I'm staying, let's get to it.
You have time. You can always
come tomorrow. I'm beat.
- But you'll already be gone!
- Tomorrow, before we leave
You're leaving at 4 a. m.
How do you know that?
Who told you?
Simine.
She knew?
These don't have any hooks in them!
Wait, how does she know?
Come here.
Sit down.
She knew we were leaving at 4?
Think so.
- How did it come up?
- don't remember.
- What do you mean?
- We talked about lots of things.
Why did you bring up our trip?
We talked about
the holidays and trips.
She said that lots of people
are going to Dubai.
She said you were also going
early tomorrow morning.
You said at 4.
- Said early.
- You said at 4!
Meant early.
Before 4 is still night for me.
And what else?
She wanted to know your age
and your husband's job.
- Is that all?
- She isn't very talkative.
She did a good job.
She's talented.
She didn't let me pay.
- You didn't say that you were here?
- didn't say anything.
Should also put up the screens?
Go back to work.
Listen, young lady...
don't feel well. I'm going
to take a shower and lie down.
Need you to do something.
At exactly 2 o'clock,
go down this street,
you'll reach the boulevard
and you'll see Martyr
Elementary, "Paknejad".
- Can you remember that?
- Paknejad.
You'll pick up my son from school.
Here's a clock.
You must be there at 2 p. m.
The keys are under the shoe rack.
Don't answer the phone,
don't open the door.
What's your son's name?
Amir-Ali Samii,
he's in first grade.
When you get back, if I'm sleeping
make some sandwiches.
Forget about here for now.
Take care of the balcony.
Pile things into the corner
and then start in the kitchen.
If someone knocks,
don't wake me up.
I'd like to speak with Abdolreza.
I'm his wife, his cousin,
mean...
When's he coming back?
Well, tell him that Rouhi called.
I'll be working late.
I'll come back on my own.
Mojdeh!
Mojdeh, darling?
Ma'am?
Mrs. Simine?
Hello, Mrs. Simine.
Have you seen my chador?
- You had a chador?
- can't find it.
- You weren't wearing one.
- It's not at their place either.
Mrs. Samii must've stolen it!
She's not here. She wanted
to lie down, but she's gone.
She's probably not far.
Just wait a little.
Have to pick her son
up from school.
I'm running late. Goodbye.
Wait, I'll drop you off.
- No, it's okay.
- It's on the way.
Can't imagine how they're
going to be ready tomorrow.
For a pilgrimage to Qom,
we're ready 2 days in advance,
and we're still late for the bus!
Put your seat belt on,
there's a police officer.
4 o'clock in the morning is early.
A little later, they'd make it.
- 4 o'clock?
- That's what you said.
Heard it from one of the neighbors.
Think we're here, sir.
Drop her off in front of the school.
Thank you so much.
It was far.
Why don't they pick up
their own kid like everyone else?
One day it's his aunt
or his cousin or they just forget.
His mother was busy.
Busy? The other parents
aren't unemployed!
Don't see why
should trust you with him.
Sami, do you know this lady?
- Call you mother.
- Nobody's home.
- My mom is at home. - No she isn't.
- She was this morning.
That was this morning.
Find his file,
we'll call his father.
- Tell him a woman has come
to get his son. - I'll do it.
What am going to do
with the two of you?
Haven't already said
not to bring that to school?
Yes or no?
Those firecrackers aren't ours.
- They were in your book bag!
- My friends put them there.
Firecrackers worth 600 Tomans?
And so many!
- They'd just give them to you?
- Those are only 400 Tomans each!
The 600 Tomans ones are different.
Get out of here.
I'll take care of you two later.
Get going!
Give me the matches, let's test them.
These kids, swear!
- How's it coming?
- There's nothing to do.
- You can see her hair.
- Forget it.
- Do you have matches?
- No.
Mr. Nikbakht?
Go out and buy some matches,
we're all out.
Mahmud, it's not working.
What should we do?
She's only 7 years old
and they want to hide her hair.
Was so busy. What am
supposed to do! Close that door.
- Why not after the holidays!
- Sadeghpour insisted.
He harassed me.
He wants it aired on New Year's eve
Tell him to forget it.
Let him talk to the director.
Why doesn't he use my grandma
instead of the little girl!
- What can do ..l - You know him.
He'll ruin our holidays.
Maybe we could do something
on Photoshop.
That's too long.
It's their responsibility.
- He doesn't know howl
- Mr. Morteza, telephone.
Yes?
Yes, it's me.
Ah, hello, how are you?
Who is it?
It's okay, but let me speak to her.
She asked me to come get him.
She went out.
Didn't know.
She didn't say anything.
Your son wants to talk to you.
Hi Dad.
How are you? I'm fine.
Are we still going tonight?
Yes, I'll get you your firecrackers.
Yes, I'll get that too.
You stay with her, okay?
Promise?
Goodbye, son.
Just a drop more and it'll work.
I've driven past you twice and
you kept standing on the sidewalk.
Not all men are cowards.
But many go out of their minds.
Let me go.
It's none of your business.
Everyone out!
You can't lock her up.
She can leave when she wants!
Everyone out!
- Don't want it.
- Come on, it'll calm you down.
- What's wrong?
- She's driving me crazy!
She's already ruined my life
and it's not over!
She spied on me wearing a chador
in the middle
of the New Year's havoc!
And you beat her?
never imagined you doing that!
All she brings me is shame,
at home and now at work.
You could've sent her home
without a all that
and taken care of your dirty laundry!
- don't know what I'm doing.
I'm going crazy!
And we're going on a trip tomorrow!
- Let me got
- You'll just make things worse.
She had the maid pick up my son!
Can you believe that?
- Such bullshit!
- What have you done?
Nothing! can't even remember
the last time she cooked!
When did the neighbors
smell her cooking last?
You must've dove something.
She must have reasons for doing that!
What are you saying?
You've known me for 11 years!
- She suspects something.
- swear don't know!
She's been going on and on
about a trip to Dubai.
It was non-stop:
"When are we leaving?"
"Let's go to Dubai!"
thought it would be good
for all of us.
And then this morning,
she says she's not coming!
She wanted to paint the apartment.
said fine.
"The phone rings:
“How much for your apartment?"
She put out an ad without telling me!
You can't imagine
how she speaks to me!
Feel sorry for her.
You saw how she was treated
in the street!
She shouldn't be standing
around like that!
She is sensitive.
She needs attention.
She also has problems
with her own family!
"“L don't want to see her,
don't like him..."
Get a grip on yourself
Take a look around!
Eighteen...
Eighteen, I'm coming!
Hello, ma'am!
Mom's home, Amir-Ali.
Come out, Mom's home.
Already looked in his room.
He'll come out!
Amir-Ali, come out, enough already!
Don't worry, we were just playing.
Come out, I'm serious now!
Come out.
Why did you come?
What are you doing?
Let go of my arm.
Come on, stop whining!
- Put your shoes on.
- Where are we going?
- I'll tell you after.
I'm seeing the fireworks with Dad.
Put on your shoes and be quiet!
You be quiet, freak!
Put on your shoes!
Calm down, ma'am.
I'm not coming!
Be quiet!
What's going on?
Hello. What's going on?
Pack your things. We're going.
Guess came at a bad time.
Are you going out?
Mojdeh, I've come to apologize.
Just forget about that.
Is Mahsid home?
- Did you want to come over?
- One or two nights.
Does Morteza know?
I'm not coming.
I'm going to tell him.
Let me calm him down,
or he'll never come.
Men never cry!
- What happened?
- Hello, Uncle.
Ma'am, what happened?
- Did you tell him?
- Me? swear didn't.
The school did.
They didn't want to give him to me.
You weren't home.
- Would you like some water?
- You can go now.
Jerk.
- Hello, sir.
- What are you doing there?
My chador is upstairs.
But don't want to go up.
- Is Mojdeh home?
- Who?
- My wife?
- Yes, but they're leaving.
- I'd rather not go up.
- Come on...
Mom says that someone's number
keeps showing up on the phone.
She doesn't know whose it is.
Last night, when was sleeping,
heard a window break,
thought it was a robber.
Saw Dad and Mom fighting.
Dad broke the window
with his hand.
He was bleeding
and went to the hospital.
- He came back late.
- Do you know why they were fighting?
Mom says there's someone else.
That's all she said to me.
Go wash your face.
We'll go to our place.
I'm supposed to see
the fireworks with Dad.
You have to be a good boy.
Dad will be sad if I'm not here.
There's my dad!
Why are you crying, dear?
How are you, Ahmad?
Could be better.
What's wrong with your wife?
- Where does she want to go?
- don't know, she wants to leave.
To our place, think.
Stay with Uncle Ahmad, I'm going to
talk to Mom and then we'll go out.
Don't cry.
I'm not going to hurt her.
Go and be with him, please.
Darling, listen to me,
after you can do as you please.
You can leave with the boy.
Just let me talk.
- Let's all go to my place.
- You know our situation.
Don't leave!
- Want to talk to you.
- Don't touch me, asshole!
It's none of your business, Ahmad!
Come on! The poor guy
has come to make up with you.
His wife forced him to.
I'm sorry, Ahmad. I'm sorry.
Please forgive me.
Go to your room.
I'd like a taxi, please.
For Samii.
We don't want it...
Listen to me, I'm sorry.
Listen for a minute.
Have never laid a finger
on anyone up till today!
But you pushed me...
- It's my fault?
- Yes, it is.
Bastard! It's okay to beat
your wife in the street?
- It's your fault.
- My fault? Just tell my the truth!
- What truth?
- Whose number is this?
- How should know?
- Why does she call you
as soon as I'm out?
What in the world!
- Tell me the truth! - What truth?
- What are you afraid of?
Come here a minute.
Amir-Ali, go to your room.
Come here. Hurry up.
Just give me one minute.
Whose apartment
did you buzz this morning?
Your buzzer didn't work.
buzzed your neighbor.
She called you to open the gate.
And the day before?
She wanted to know why there
were complaints about her.
Told her didn't have any problems.
You defended her at the meeting!
They wanted me to file a report.
refused.
Your voice was on her machine.
Who said that? Just say it
so everything will be out in the open!
You're going out with her!
There's nobody! I'd never make
such a mistake as bringing...
Why did you leave?
We were supposed to talk!
Ask the son of a bitch who called me.
She called to cancel your date!
You think I'm an idiot?
- We're leaving!
- No!
You should be ashamed, Mojdeh!
You put on her chador to spy on me.
How shameful!
- Open, want to leave!
- You disgraced me!
Go to your room, dear.
It's my fault? You didn't have
a date with her between 2 and 5?
Calm down and come here.
Go ask our neighbor
for her answering machine.
Shut up!
All we need is for her to come!
How can prove that you're sick,
that you're imagining this!
My God!
I'm the one who's crazy!
Didn't even know we were
leaving at 4. But she knew!
What do you mean, she knew?
You're asking me?
Swear didn't tell her anything!
Don't get involved!
He's afraid!
I'm the one who got the tickets!
- And I'm the crazy one?
- Nothing is going on between us.
Don't swear, just find some dignity.
You're right, let me go.
Simine gave me the tickets.
She asked me to give them to you.
You were out.
Why did she have our tickets?
Your buzzer is broken.
They were dropped off at her place.
She gave them to me.
put them on the table.
She peeked at them
when she handed them to me.
Calm down, darling.
Why didn't you tell me?
It wasn't my business.
didn't want to bother you.
Put his jacket on.
I'm a terrible person.
can't even look at you.
Had no right to hit you today.
You can't imagine how awful feel.
Forgive me.
Sweetheart...
Please look at me.
Swear on our son's life.
I've never sworn on Amir-Ali's life,
but swear love you.
Love our life,
love you, love our son.
Let's just forget all of this.
We're ready, Dad, let's go.
Why don't you come with us?
No, go. You promised him.
- Come on, Dad!
- We're going.
- Are we going?
- Yes.
Sir, this is yours.
- Come, I'll take you home.
- Thanks, I'll lake the bus.
- You'll be late.
- live really far, sir.
I'll take you to a taxi stand.
- Come see the show with just
- Sorry, I'm running late.
Excuse me, ma'am,
can have my chador back?
I'll pay you back for that.
Goodbye, ma'am.
I'm going to see the fireworks!
Where do you live?
Near the Imam Davoud mausoleum.
Could you wait a little longer?
I'll take you home when we're done.
Can't.
My fiance is waiting for me.
How do you expect to get home?
You'll spend a fortune on a taxi.
Don't want to be a bother.
You won't. It's dangerous at night.
Actually, one of my co-workers
finished late and then disappeared.
They're still looking for her.
People at work think it's the "Bat".
- Who?
- The Bat
But they captured him.
But he's not the only one,
there are more like him.
Amir-Ali, careful!
Could you play with him
for half an hour? I'll be right back.
- Not a half an hour, an hour!
- Okay.
- But, no longer than an hour!
- I'll take you, don't worry.
Just have some errands.
Come here, son.
Listen to whatever she says.
Don't go near any fire or firecrackers.
Not allowed!
Who's Daddy's darling?
Amir-Ali.
Don't go too far, stay in this area.
Give me a box of matches, please.
And a pack of Marlboro.
Since when do you smoke?
Hello, Mr. Samii.
don't smoke.
- What are you afraid of?
- My mom's kind of serious.
Get lost, don't want to see you!
Forget it, who's that loser?
Are you late?
- Can't stay long.
- Why not?
Have things to do.
Thought wouldn't see you
until after the holidays.
- It'll be hard.
- No it won't...
- I'm glad you came.
- What was going on at your place?
- Nothing. It's all okay now.
- You were fighting.
It's over now,
let's not talk about that.
So, why are you in such bad shape?
Keep it as a souvenir.
- So, what's wrong?
- Nothing, said to forget about it.
- What are you doing for the holidays?
- Nothing.
But you try and have a good time.
Take care of yourself,
you don't look good.
Have a good time?
You must be kidding!
Go crazy when don't see you
for one day.
- How can have a good time?
- This isn't what we agreed on.
- Stop, I'm serious.
- I'm serious also.
These situations have nothing
to do with old promises.
Your wife is a wreck.
understand that.
Know. What can do?
Feel so lost.
disgust myself.
This can't go on.
Hit her in the middle of the
street today. In front of everyone.
- Does she suspect something?
- No.
She has no reason to any more.
- Then this is the perfect moment.
- To do what?
For us to stop seeing each other.
Stop seeing each other,
when everything's been arranged?
Arranged?
This can't go on.
It's useless.
Stop talking about that.
Let's go for a drive.
Have things to do.
Then for the few minutes
we have together, let's not talk.
- I've come to tell you that.
- Tell me what?
You're constantly calling me
and now you're telling me
that it's over.
Just like that!
Thank you, Simine.
This can't continue.
But you don't want to understand.
You're ruining your life,
your family.
This is just an affair...
Are you crying?
Let me see, silly.
It's just an allergy.
What happened to your hand?
Are you staying in Teheran?
Forget about it.
We're no longer children.
Don't know what to say.
Your wife would've preferred
seeing you with a whore
than with another woman.
- I'll call you when get there.
- won't pick up the phone.
Why won't you understand? I'll call.
You'll get used to it, honey.
My husband also
was in love with me.
And then one day, he left me.
Please stop...
That's enough.
Think of it as a lovely memory
that is over.
You're going to Dubai.
Maybe even to live there
for a while. You'll get over this.
Forget about me, I'm not worth it.
- Just stay a little longer.
- Don't touch me.
Can't. have to go.
- I'm meeting someone.
- Who?
I'll call you.
Don't get upset if don't answer.
Take care of yourself.
It's over.
Excuse me, sir.
- Are you Simine's neighbor?
- Yes, I'm her neighbor.
Brought our daughter.
She's not here.
How are you?
recognize you.
She sees her before the holidays.
She's been asking to see her for a week!
I'm Samii, her neighbor.
I've just arrived.
- Come in.
- don't want to bother you.
- I'll open the gate.
- No...
You really don't have to.
Thanks a lot. Come in.
My daughter is in the car.
Happy New Year.
- To you and to your family.
- Same to you.
He's sleeping. Can you get out?
Can you carry this, please?
Hurry, before the gate closes.
Put that here.
You don't have to come up.
Wait for me.
I'll put Amir-Ali in bed,
and come back.
Push number 6.
Mom!
Hello, darling.
Be careful not to fall.
- Who gave that to you?
- Dad!
Dad is so nice!
Carry Mom's bag?
- How are you?
- Fine, and you?
You also got
some grass for the holiday!
We'll put a red ribbon on it.
You're still here?
- Can't you say hello, sweetie?
- Hello.
- What is it?
- Nothing.
- Hello.
- Still here?
- Your husband...
- He didn't drop you off?
Morteza,
why didn't you find her a taxi?
He's putting Amir-Ali down,
he's coming.
- Ma'am...
- Yes?
Today, ...
- What, today?
- Quiet, he's sleeping.
Nothing.
Can you take care of the suitcases?
- What did you want to tell me?
- Nothing, ma'am.
If you need help, ask the concierge.
Why'd you come up?
was on my way.
Let's go.
Come home quick.
You would never have been able
to get home alone.
You did a good thing today.
You really helped me out.
Don't understand
why you went upstairs.
- What are you going to tell her?
- Nothing.
You wanted to tell her something
near the door.
- Was it about the tickets?
- No.
You told her Simine gave you
the tickets. Did you lie?
- Yes. - Why?
- Just because.
You don't lie just because.
Mrs. Simine
was very nice to me today.
And?
You shouldn't have come up.
Does she know?
- Drop me off here.
- I'll take you home, it's late.
- Thanks, but I'll get out here.
- Why?
Abdolreza is there.
I'll go by myself.
He must really love you
to wait so long.
- Stop here.
- Okay.
Goodbye.
Can make a U turn up ahead?
- You took long!
- call to tell you was going to be late
The guy couldn't answer me.
Where's your chador?
Let's go.
I'll explain later.
What did you do?
You look even more beautiful.
Went to a beauty salon.
It's at the guy's house
where worked.
Poor guy brought you
all the way here!
- How can thank you?
- Don't mention it.
My wife made me drive her.
Your wife's chador is at our home.
Keep it, it's not a problem.
- Happy New Year.
- Thanks a lot.
It's cold.
- How are you?
- Fine, thank you.
- You really don't want to come up?
- Thank you.
It's cold out, don't be polite.
No, really.
Darling, why are you sleeping here?
Come back to bed.