What's it made of?
Bull's horn
I'll take them
Thank you
Buy the small ones for me, Mum?
Of course, my darling
You want them all!
Put them on me, Mum?
You are beautiful!
You like me?
You are ravishing.
Really?
Honestly. Hey, careful with the hat!
Buy one?
You like it?
I find it obscene.
Obscene? When one can hear Yemaya,
The goddess of the oceans
You want to buy a hat?
Mum!
Oh, what a pretty blonde!
You play dice?
Play with us!
Where's my little girl?
She's having fun over there.
Rebecca!
What happened?
I lost an earring
You are the father?
The
father-in-law.
A pretty girl. Can I buy her from you?
Interesting idea. How much?
A thousand coconuts!
A thousand coconuts?
She is worth much more!
Look at this hair, these eyes,
these teeth. She is healthy.
And wild like you
A thousand coconuts
Fifteen hundred
- Two thousand coconuts minimum
- don't play the fool!
Two thousand coconuts minimum
Who'll give them?
She's gone! You always torment her!
B. del Pramo, who does
not sing any more..
since her 2nd marriage to Mr. Ocana...
has had an interesting offer of...
a role in Mexico.
To work? You have the house
and your daughter to
look after she needs it..
Don't involve Rebecca in this...
I am an artist, not a housewife!
I did not have to get married
I am not the only married actress
We'll talk about it on my return
I do not want to argue,
I'm going to accept
No chance
What?
As long as you are my wife,
you will remain here...
me...
I am not modern like your ex-husband.
That, I know.
Valium...
Ponderil...
Rebecca, are you in there?
Yes, I'm here
Are you insane?
No need to be rude, I'm going
I'll say it again, it is my bathroom
And mother's
Are you off?
Yes
On my return, we will discuss...
evesdropping
OK
Ok mum?
M. Ocana was buried...
this morning...
What a family!
Dad must be happy
Why?
He did not love Alberto either
The very idea!
After the crash, Mr.
Ocana's car caught fire.
The driver fell asleep...
the car left the road and struck a tree
The health of the Prime
Minister is excellent and...
Why go to Mexico?
To work, it is most important now
And the photographs?
Let us speak about
filming, not photographs
My husband has just died
I cannot sell these things. Sorry
And if I went to Mexico.
to make a report on filming?
I do not see a problem
You could join me there
Right, fine
If it's an exclusive,
my newspaper will send me
It is
See you in Mexico?
Dad says you're going
without me, you promised
Impossible, darling
Why?
Because...
Children do not travel so well
It is necessary to study too
There are schools in Mexico
Right, listen.
You're confusing me!
Sorry, treasure
Let's agree that I go to make
a beautiful film in Mexico.
and afterwards, we'll be
together always, promise
I do not believe you!
Do not promise the impossible
That's it! Deal with it!
But you promised
Yes, dear...if Mum doesn't
go, she will be miserable
You don't want that?
Good, leave us, I must speak to Papa
What will I do with her!
You've done enough, leave it to me
Margarita, the guitar!
Pardon...
Mother
It is me, Rebecca...
Let me look at you
You've become a woman!
Mum, I'm 27
I know, Chanel suits you
It is you who is... ravishing
Wait until I have
rested. And your husband?
He had to go
You will see him
This dumpling who hustled
you, is Margarita, my secretary
Delighted. Your mother's
told me lots about you
- Has she?
- Of course
She is a Catalan, daughter of the
famous Dr. Forner, exiled during the war
And my guardian angel for 10 years
What luck!
I'm missing 2 bags, I
leave you the caddie...
Come on, let's get away from the crowd
That's me: always in a crowd!
There's a lot of journalists outside?
Not one, I did not
reveal your date of return
Why? I don't have scabies!
I wanted to avoid the scuffle
It's just
- I'm back after so many years!
I don't often wear this hat!
I expected more interest
I awaited you with much interest
That's true darling, forgive me!
It is the time-lag!
Hotel Miguel Angel...
Not our place?
No, I am independent, and
I do not want to disturb you
But we'll see a lot of each other?
Of course!
My God, how it's changed!
You will not recognize...
It doesn't matter, as long
as the city recognizes me
Marga, do not take notes
Why was she writing?
Apart from everything else,
she's writing my autobiography.
Am I in it?
Of course, you are my little girl! Why?
I do not like my life read about
Is Manuel in it too?
Let's talk about... Manuel
You married him
and I heard about it by chance
Let us forget that...
You did not tell me
I spoke to you about my
marriage on the telephone
Yes, but not with Manuel
I could not!
You told me you were very busy and...
had no time...
I didn't tell you any lies
True, but...
you should have told me
Still!
You can take us along Alamillo Place?
Oh, a turd. It is nothing.
Through the windows...
one could see people's feet
Sometimes that frightened me
I was 5 years old, you
had not been born of course
I bought it, you know?
You thinking of staying in Madrid?
Yes, I will move as soon as possible
Becky, look, it is you!
What did she say?
It hardly looks like
me, the photograph here!
I have one with the
same feathers, same pose
"Letal Woman": the true
Becky. Aren't I the true Becky?
Of course!
That's an imposter who imitates you
And you thought you were forgotten
You've seen him?
Yes, he's a friend... if I
missed you, I was going to see him
I'll await you over there
Forgive my absence
I do not have an excuse, but...
your father did not help...
I know, Mum, quite the contrary
You...
like me still a little bit?
I love you very much
I was afraid that you'd hate me
I did hate you...
but even then...
I still loved you
Ah, I've caught my earring
At last!
You will not believe me!
I had earrings like those
Alberto was alive. I
bought them on an island.
Margarita Island.
You knew?
You bought me these
earrings there the same day
Oh, but of course, what a head I have!
Mum, stop your acting
if not you'll constantly
drop clangers...
The important thing is, we're together
You are right, darling
How grown-up!
I am happy, Rebecca is marvellous
I am relieved
Wait, it's still the
hardest thing for you
Let me come
I'll go alone. It's 15
years since I saw them
Don't be...
a martyr, Becky
I'll try to be kind to her
Look...
She is presenting the news
Let me see...
2 attacks...
were perpetrated this morning by ETA
The 1st led to the death
of Roberto Agalburu...
when a bomb exploded..
under its car
He was a travelling garlic salesman
He was thought to be involved..
with drug trafficking
The attack could have been terrible...
How can she laugh?
...as nearby a creche...
Why am I watching this?
What can I say this evening?
You can go, Lola
It's lovely!
Hang on, you saw the news?
Sorry, I forgot
Too bad... I messed it all up
thinking you were looking...
Hi, Manuel?
Beautiful, isn't she?
She's fantastic
Excuse me one moment.
You're happy directing a TV show?
I can't complain
I knew you'd do well
Why didn't you tell
me you'd married her?
She didn't tell me she was your daughter
And you never asked
her about her family?
She told me her father
had died 2 years ago
And her mother?
That she might as well be, since she...
lived abroad
You've no excuses
You less than she
But I am not on the
warpath... on the contrary
I want to find my daughter,
to try to make her happy
But that depends on both of us
You love her don't you?
Listen...
Why?
She adores you
She is difficult
Don't I know it!
But you did not answer. Do you love her?
When are you performing?
In one month
Of course, TV7
is with you
Thank you, I will need some
This evening is Letal's
last... Are you going?
It is late?
No, in 1 hour.
A tosser
drag queen?
What a liberal!
I don't like it that
my wife's best friend
is a transvestite...
He is right. It's one
thing is to be modern but...
They live such a sordid life.
Letal is different
Your husband will get jealous
Me? Definately not!
It's up to me to be jealous!
Very well...
and very relaxed
No tension
One hour, I think
I am very well, Margarita
A weapon in a show?
Madrid is dangerous
Recently, a transvestite
was killed where we are going
Can I go in such a place?
What?
The Rosa Villa is not
a place for your mother
Shall we stay here?
You stay. Me, I'm going!
Let us not discuss it any more!
I've seen a lot worse!
You too, Manuel...
Let's go!
You changed your mind?
I like to change it
Our story is finishing...
and you will regret...
ending...
a year of love...
If you go away...
you will soon discover...
that the days are long...
and empty without me...
And so the night,
won't feel so lonely...
you will remember...
our happy times together...
the taste of my kisses...
And you will understand...
all at once...
the meaning...
of a year of love...
of a year of love.
You must think about...
what would happen...
what you would lose...
how much you would suffer...
If you left now...
you would never find again..
the happy times...
I brought to your life...
And so the night,
won't feel so lonely...
you will remember...
our happy days together...
the taste of my kisses...
And you will understand...
all at once...
the meaning...
of a year of love.
And you will understand...
all at once...
the meaning...
of a year of love...
Did I annoy you?
Why?
The imitation...
It flatters me and makes me feel young
Let me look at you
Close up, you don't look like
me, but they are my gestures
I have copied your style,
what makes you unique
I used to be like that but I changed
I cannot sing pop any more
I became a lady of song
I know, but I like the old stuff:
the twist, the miniskirt,
your spirit, your style
I don't know whether to
be charmed or insulted
Charmed!
Wonderful!
Forget it, Manuel!
By the way, Letal, this is my husband.
Ah, it is you.
Enchanted
So what is your real name?
As the song says...
Call me what you like.
My friends call me Letal
Is that male or female?
That depends...
For you, I am a guy
Drink?
No thank you, I've things I must do
But I would like a souvenir
An autograph?
No, more personal, your
earrings for example
But, I will be naked!
Mum, give them to him
OK, but give me something...
What you want...
Ask for a falsie
That's it, a falsie...
Which one?
The right one, that of the heart...
That's the left
Thank you for the earrings, Becky
Thank you for the tit, now I have 3!
Will you help me?
Of course
May I?
Help with what?
Manuel, this guy is harmless!
Rebecca never misses an
chance to humiliate me
She recons she has reasons
to be jealous, doesn't she?
You know me.
You haven't changed!
You neither
And I'm delighted
I've changed
It doesn't show, but I've matured
Does it remind you of
anything, this song?
Too many things...
We didn't finish either of them, eh?
How dare you, Manuel? You insult me!
You never were a conventional woman
What sort of woman was I?
A marvellous woman
For 50 years, I have
been a marvellous woman
I want to be a marvellous person
Who says different?
I am the mother of your wife
Not for a long time
I will divorce Rebecca
Does she know?
But she doesn't show it
Pass the lip gloss
Anything else?
Yes, the combs
Put them in the bag
Help me with my zip?
You must struggle with that
To be beautiful, one must suffer!
I suffer as much
without being beautiful!
It disgusts you...
that I imitate women?
No, I adore that you
imitate my mother...
I would like to be more
than a mother to you
Smooth talker!
Ah, what a cheat...
These hips...
Help me with my stockings?
Hold on...
A beauty spot on your nipple!
It's a birthmark...
My dress!
Let go
Help me, with my heels
I could break my ankle
Open your legs and...
you'll get down easier
Leave me alone!
What?
- Open up
- What?
Letal, what are you saying?
Don't tempt me...
because it's four months since I...
Why is she late?
She is unpredictable
She takes after me...
Ah, what a cow!
It was a dream...
Thank you, it is true
that I needed it...
But it will not be repeated
Why?
Because I love my husband
That monster?
Yes,
that monster
I do not know your
name, nor your address
That can be arranged
Here is my address
Things are good this way...
Really, don't complicate matters
Shall we meet again?
Who knows?
I'll call you?
No, I prefer to contact you
Where?
Here
I will not be here any more
Then, good luck
Are you deaf or what?
I am in a hurry
I'm the one in a hurry,
I'm a "working girl", me...
You spoil her
Poor bulls
The notices, nothing interests
me, the weather comes and goes...
Ah, there it is...
Pass the album...
on Becky del P ramo...
Yes, mum
"Her first night in Madrid..."
Are we talking about
Bardot or Mother Teresa?
No, only of Becky
Thanks... you look pale,
you wouldn't be sick too?
We're both fine
Who knows?
With your careless attitude,
you can fool anyone!
Have you had an AIDS test?
Do not start
If you do not do it,
I will... I am tired
Give me those scissors...
darling
First you had leprosy, now AIDS!
Do you know what gives you away?
I know that I am burned out
You do not move!
Precisely, I need to get well
Come on, give me the glue,
don't look at me that way
I have the right to
know if I am HIV positive
You, I don't know, but me,
I cannot live without knowing
Mum, where is it?
On the tele, give it to me, go on...
The test is at the hospital,
you will have to get up,
then you will find out
One day you will regret your cruelty...
and that day will come soon
Becky has aged...
Her daughter looks spooky
Sancho Manuel's corpse is
stretched out on the bed...
showing signs of rigour mortis
Hair dark chestnut
Light chestnut
He's about about 1.80 m...
A little less, 1,78 m...
More
OK, 1.80 m
Dressed in red silk pyjamas
Satin
Garnet-red satin
He has two holes in the
chest, made by a firearm...
causing death
According to the coroner,
he died between 9 and 11 pm
3 women visited him
One made love to him,
One quarreled with him,
The third found him dead
Did one of you kill him?
Not me
Right, none of you
I want to reverify...
your times of arrival... You, first...
Yes
At what time?
At 8:30, and I left a little after 9
When, precisely?
I don't record these things!
You went there?
Before the news, Manuel
called me to ask me to drop in
And you left?
Yes
He promised me a speaking part
I'd had enough of deaf-mutes
People think I'm like
that, but as you see...
What did you do?
I said, we made love
But Manual received a phone call...
and asked me to leave...
I don't like to be treated like that
It was the 1st time?
No...
we did it... err...
We won't listen...
to the sexual exploits
of this young lady
We aren't talking about
someone's love life,
but of a man murdered a
little after having made love
Anyone else? Did you
see anyone else around?
We didn't speak... nor finish
Very well
You may go
I'm going...
This is bad publicity for me
There will be no publicity
Because I sing, I dance and I do jazz...
to sleep with a man is one
thing, to kill him is another...
I will not trouble you any further
You can, but understand that...
I understand, goodbye
It was you who called him to see him
Yes
I arrived just before 9:30
Why did you stop your rehearsal?
I had to
Why?
It is hard to speak about it
in front of my daughter, judge
What I have to say is not new
I did not kill him
One does not kill one's
son-in-law before a premiere!
You believe me, Rebecca?
You must convince the judge, not me
Tell me what you spoke about
I wanted us to break up
You were lovers?
Yes
I wanted to put an end to that madness
You knew?
Do not lie! You knew
it or you guessed it
You said nothing to me and I
do not like to imagine things
I've nothing to do with
the failure of your marriage
Nobody's accusing you,
now talk to the judge
He's asking the questions
Manuel seduced me, I let it happen
Alas, I was always weak with men
With some, anyway
When I found out he was
cheating on me too...
I went to see him to break...
Until when?
I do not know any more...
10 perhaps
The taxi will be able to confirm it
He told us that you were upset
Yes, Manuel had destroyed my
life and that of my daughter!
I would like to leave
OK
You can go
You can call me at home...
If it wasn't Becky,
it happened afterwards
Between 10 and 11
It wasn't her
You are sure?
Before a premiere, it would
be bad business to kill someone
Especially one's son-in-law...
it's a good argument
You said you arrived at 11
The sprinkler doesn't
operate before then
Your husband was alone in the house
No-one else
Why?
There was a violent
argument, in the morning
He wanted a divorce and I had refused
He threatened to leave
me, and I to commit suicide
He left?
Yes, he wanted to be alone
I promised to leave him
- You went there?
- Of course
I returned after the news
I was after my tranquillizers
They were not in their place
I supposed that Manuel
had removed them...
fearing I'd do something stupid
Under this pretext, I went to see him
Try...
to describe accurately your arrival
Remember...
all that you saw, heard
There was wind...
in the leaves of the trees
I can still hear the noise
When I entered...
it was dark, I did not want
to show my tears to Manuel
I sat in an armchair
Manuel had his back to me
I could not see well
I asked him for forgiveness
for the argument in the morning
I said that I would
grant him a divorce...
that I would manage
He did not answer
I thought that he was angry
I had decided to take
my pills on the table
I approached the bed
I must have been blind not to see...
I just thought he was angry...
I cried because of his hardness
I took the pills and
I was going to leave...
but I returned...
I could not leave like that...
Once on the bed,
I rubbed myself against him,
I cuddled him...
but he did not react
And then I realized...
that my hands and dress
were covered with blood
Why wait until this morning?
I really do not know
What did you do?
I went back to the house...
I could not reconcile
myself with his death
And I don't give a damn about dying
I swallowed a stomachful of pills...
but I brought them up again at once...
The morning, I called the police
- for the photographs?
- Yes
Let us see, these are yours
And these
An armchair
It is your armchair?
Yes
They are mine, they were mixed up
This face looks familiar
He was my fiance
He disappeared, did you know him?
You know where he is?
Good evening
Rebecca, my condolences
Thank you
Mine too
We thought you'd take
a holiday
Work will distract me
Of course...
Rebecca!
You are here!
Eh yes, as you see
The usual?
No, more
If you need anything, Rebecca
Rebeca, I feel bad
Don't
I'm sorry and...
It's not your problem...
You don't have to worry
OK, but I wanted to say it
Be prepared
What's she doing?
Are you testing the sound?
Yes
Good evening. The
Agricultural Demonstrations
A great quantity of corn was thrown...
by the farmers in front
of the U.S. embassy
It is the agricultural
organization "PIENSO" that...
organised this demonstration. Yes?
Good evening... The
Agricultural Demonstrations...
Corn...
this morning was thrown...
How can she work?
The agricultural
organization "PIENSO"...
demonstrates thus against
American corn importation,
because Spain is increasing its quotas
This afternoon, Manuel
Sancho Bermejo was buried,
assassinated 3 days ago...
between 9 and 11 in the
evening, in his country house
Dedicated as always to communication,
he was directing TV7
at the time of its death
Various celebrities from the show...
as well as family and friends
rendered a last homage to Manuel
Forgive my familiarity...
he directed this series and...
was also my husband
Cut, if...
Manuel...
had lately received death threats
Unfortunately, he took no notice
Prepare the next
One day he asked me:
If he gave me something,
would I say it on TV7?
I answered no
Well Manual, here I am...
I'm tryimg to do it
Judge Dominguez is running
the investigation...
and is right off track at the moment
According to the autopsy, the victim...
had just made love...
But it was not with me
If you continue, I'm leaving
At 11, this Thursday,
I went over there...
I found his corpse
Wait!
Do not cut!
And I know who committed the crime
It is I
I killed him
She killed him!
Rebecca...
Judge Dominguez...
Go immediately to TV7
and arrest Rebecca Giner
As for the gun...
I had to throw it
I do not remember too well
Yes, I returned...
and I was overcome
I could not call anybody,
nor knew what to do
I was never going to see Manuel again...
and that made me suffer dreadfully
I don't know why,
to fight this anguish,
I started to photograph...
our common memories:
his office...
with his papers, neatly arranged,
his sports bag,
His bed,
His dressing gown,
His cupboard with his costumes,
His armchair from where
he watched me on the TV...
I even photographed
some ravishing clothes
that I had just bought...
and now useless
Then I realized that I was alone...
and that while I had killedManuel,
I had not killed my love for him
Madam...
Come with us!
Wait, I haven't finished
That is all
Remember...
that at 20:30...
in the 2nd edition of
the News, you will see...
the latest news in draft form
As always, thank you for watching...
and goodbye
Sorry, Xavier...
You have the right to remain silent...
and not to incriminate yourself
You have the right...
to a lawyer
You may inform whoever...
of the fact and of the
place of your detention
Enter
The next time, pay
attention to the weapon
Sit down
Why not tell me?
Why on television?
So what?
I admitted it, didn't I?
That is not enough...
It is not so easy to be guilty
Proof is required
Look for it!
And you will help us
If you decide to tell the truth!
I have just done it
When?
You have two versions
One here this morning,
and one on television
Which should I believe?
Which is true?
Both
Both?
This morning, you...
were looking for pills...
without mentioning the revolver...
and that is significant
The revolver was beside the pills,
it was Manuel's
What did you do with it?
Come!
Take off her handcuffs
To help you, I need you
To help me? Why?
You had no need to kill him
You had to only divorce...
OK, let us suppose
that you did not do it
And these death threats?
These anonymous messages?
Manuel couldn't give a fuck
Who was the author?
Yes... Me
Shit!
Let us suppose that it was not you...
Who could want his death?
I do not see...
Forgive me...
you have a lover?
Does that concern you?
Yes, it is my inquiry
No, I do not have one
Never unfaithful?
Never once?
No!
That's a lie
Oh yeah?
When your mother returned,
to the Villa Rosa,
you misled your husband
right under his nose
How do you know?
Who are you trying to protect?
Nobody
Anything to add?
OK,
then, it is prison
You can telephone
You need clothes and...
a lawyer... apart from anything else
Good evening, Madrid
It was hard to get here...
but I am happy
This evening,
my only daughter sleeps in prison
It little matters what she did,
like all mothers, my heart is broken
Allow me to dedicate
to her my first song
If your sorrow is heavy,
think of me,
if you want to cry,
think of me
You can clearly see...
that I adore your divine face,
your child's mouth...
that taught me to sin...
Think of me...
when you suffer,
when you cry,
also think of me
That's your mother, it
is beautiful, isn't it?
Stop
Why?
I cannot
The poor thing
Close your ears!
Luisa!
I'll buy it from you
10,000 pesetos
It cost me 15000!
17,000, sorry
I've just been robbed, I
will give them to you tomorrow
We will see tomorrow, then
Sorry, but it is her's
When you cry
why...
think of me
When you want...
to capture my life
I do not want to any more
It's nothing...
it's no good for me...
without you
Hello, Paula will
take you to the nursery
Clotilde is sick
Hello, Myriam
My name is Paula, I
am a welfare officer,
I am here to help you
We know each other...
you remember?
At the photographer's...
I was moved when you showed
photographs on the tele
I photograph things too...
I understood you so well
When you took them out of your bag...
commenting on them, I started to cry
Me too
Yes, I saw
Listen, I'm pressed for time
here, I cannot speak, but...
if I can help you...
I need sleeping pills...
- sleeping pills?
- Yes
We'll see...
You're concerned about Rebecca...
so, I made inquires
No point, mum
I will speak to her mother
She is hiding something
That, I well know
Look at that
You recognize him?
It's the dead man
Formerly, he was the mother's lover
Look, there...
Who is that?
Judge Dominguez
Enter
Astonished that I live in a basement?
To tell the truth, yes
My parents were in digs
I was born here
Why return so much later?
It is difficult to say
Thank you, put that there
I ran out of time the 1st year
And then 15 years
passed... A little tea?
Thank you... my mother knows
the same type of inertia
She's an artist?
Something like that
She is sorry about your
daughter and your son-in-law
When did you meet him?
Who?
Manuel... on your return?
Yes
I was invited to the
wedding but I could not go
Recognize anyone?
That's despicable!
Answer me
Yes...
I recognize us
It's been a long time...
Manuel made a living from
the artists he interviewed...
Me included
You lied?
I have the right to forget
You speak like a guilty person
I am not one
You are thinking of your daughter?
I am not thinking of anything
I am suffering too much to think
This will astonish you...
I want to help you
Help who?
Not me...
You are free
Prison would not be worse...
And if you want to help Rebecca...
remember that she confessed
I do not believe that
she told everything
She said enough!
You could speak to her
She will not lie you
You're dreaming!
You are not anxious for her?
Of course I am!
Why do you not want to see her?
I neither want to speak to
her, nor to reopen my wounds
I could help you avoid bureaucracy...
and go to the prison
Thank you
But I am afraid of Rebecca
Fear of having to face her
Every morning...
my only desire is to
get through to evening
to do what I know how to do:
to perform...
I cannot do more
OK, leave me alone
I would like to keep the clipping
I must return it...
Leave!
She is beautiful!
She was arrested with me...
She is a whore
She tossed a brick at a
cop to join her girlfriend
She's got guts...
Hang on, sleeping pills...
You are stoned!
Useless to shout it!
I told you not to sell to her! Bitch!
Shit, stop!
I will kill you!
Why did I almost kill this guy?
Just to see you!
Who's is this blouson?
Mine of course
Can I see something?
Let go!
You're lying I bought
this for my boyfriend
- It is mine
- Yours?
Ok, you can keep it...
but where did you get it?
On a stiff, we shared out his stuff
A dead man? Are you sure?
The person I'm talking
about, was a grass
Hugo, a grass?
He was a dealer, you weren't
friendly with this son of whore?
He was not a son of
whore, leave me alone!
Cool it
Listen, look at this
It is him?
Yes
- Sure?
- He's bad news...
- So?
- Let me go
What's happening?
My boyfriend is dead
I am sorry
Is this him?
She told you that?
I bought him the red blouson
If I were you, I would
get more information
We lived together just a few months
He left time and again, like all junkies
He was one?
Yes
I tried to help him
Although I loved him, I
wouldn't let him lie to me
One day, I said to him: "just go!"
He never returned
And these photographs?
From then on
When I'm blue, I photograph
what he left behind:
The photographs... look, his cock
A beauty spot on the nipple?
Do not study his head...
What counts, is the tail...
And she told me he was a grass
You believe it?
Many junkies are, you know...
And I remember...
Hugo questioned me a
lot about the prison
Rebecca Giner, come to the gates
Go ahead, Rebecca!
Remove her handcuffs
How is that?
Ready to talk?
About what?
Letal, I must find him
More jokes, Judge!
He's your grass
Untrue
Who told you we'd fucked? Nobody else
Tell me where he lives lives
I've no idea
I saw him at the Villa Rosa
He never gave me his address
One moment
Go over there, I have a surprise for you
Close the door
The judge wanted us to talk
Where are you going?
I'm putting out my cigarette
Why did you do itt?
I did not kill him!
But you admitted it yourself
To kill would have been
reasonable, but it was impossible
I was avenged by this false confession
Why do I torture you?
Because I slept with him?
Exactly!
Don't be stupid
You were not the only one
What?
In The Autumn Sonata,
a pianist has an untalented daughter
Rather like us...
The mother comes to see her daughter...
who also plays the piano
She asks her to play for her
The girl is embarrrased,
but ends up accepting
and nervously plays some Chopin
Her mother congratulates
her for her performance,
but cannot resist criticising
Nothing could be more
humiliating for the girl
For her mother says
to her: you are lousy!
How dare you play this sublime score?
You think I would put up with this?
You are too crude to copy my stlye
Even if you wanted to
you could not even be my understudy
Your imitation is not
a homage but an insult!
What are you talking about?
I always imitated you
I always wanted to beat you
Without ever succeeding, except once!
With Manuel!
- We were both losers there
- Yes, but he married me, me!
You wanted to prove to
me that you could have him
I knew it, but it was
necessary that you knew it!
Forgive Me, Rebecca
I acted badly
What can I do?
You can listen to me
Alright
I've weighed you down from childhood...
However, I tried to be useful...
because I adored you
The day when Alberto died...
Yes...
I heard you talking
You were trapped,
there was only one solution
He took downers and uppers
I swapped the tablets
Yes, a moment
He fell asleep at the wheel
If I had not killed him, he would
have refused you a divorce...
and you would not have sung,
nor made films, nor loved
I wanted to set you free...
You had promised me
to share everything...
but you did not keep your promise...
I will never forgive you...
Here, Miss
Who is it?
Rebecca, listen
That's it, she is throwing up...
She's eaten nothing
Alright?
Shall we take her to the infirmary?
Let's take her...
Come, Rebecca...
It is nothing, you are pregnant...
Pregnant? Impossible!
Yes, the tests prove it...
You'll have to take
better care of yourself,
to eat more,
not to smoke,
to live a healthy life, without drugs...
and without drink
For the rest, be happy, all is well
What now?
Lead a healthy life and wait...
Attention...
Rebecca Giner please
go to the visiting room
I repeat
Rebecca Giner is awaited
in the visiting room
Well, Rebecca!
It is you being called
on the loudspeaker!
Go!
Who are you?
A legal agent
I have your release
Certificate of release
Then I am free?
Yes
I do not have a pen
Here, sign
What do I have to do?
The govenor has signed,
get your things... Good luck
Thank you
- Yes?
- It is Judge Dominguez
I have just rung you at
home, without success...
The bell frightened me
In the prison, I was
told that you are pregnant
On the level, eh?
It's true, OK?
I'll come up
No, not now... Tomorrow
I'll come up immediately, just a moment
Sorry, I have to shake you down
I thought you would
You're not here to guard me?
I'm after Letal... He's
at Villa Rosa this evening
Who told you?
He telephoned me at the office
What a stroke of luck!
I get out, he shows up
Being pregnant
Sometimes things happen like this
Shall we sit?
With pleasure
Why?
It was his armchair
Here, can I?
Letal wants to see you this evening
Why?
He must want to speak to you
You too I imagine
You imagine wrongly
I have nothing to say to him
And nothing he has to
say, could interest me
Will you go?
Me, I'm going
It interests me to listen to him
And you deny he's your grass?
How aggressive you are!
Without me, you'd be rotting in prison!
Perhaps I should thank you?
I believed that you had released
me because you thought me innocent
Sometimes I doubt it
You've never told me you are
I am innocent
Why the TV business?
I was desperate...
I felt guilty...
That might convince
a psychiatrist, not me
One can feel guilty without
being it... Understand?
Yes, but you I do not understand
Me neither
That makes two of us!
Why help me?
Why, if you doubt so much?
Not your innocence
That should be enough
Well it isn't
I would like to ask
you so many questions
But I do not have the
right, even if I am the Judge
We agree on that
Yes
I must go
Goodbye
Judge...
You have a cigarette?
It's bad to smoke
True... you have a light?
Excuse my...
welcome, I was nervous
Goodbye
Mum, I am free
Sorry about yesterday's scence
I would like to see you tomorrow...
to kiss you and tell you I love you
I adore you as always...
Your little Rebecca
My child...
If your sorrow is heavy,
think of me
If you want to cry,
You can easily see...
that I worship your divine face...
your child's mouth...
that taught me to sin
Letal!
I'm just coming!
Thank you for coming
You!
The Judge too?
Yes
Can you explain all this?
That's what I'm here for...
and to ask you to marry me
Marry whom? Hugo, Letal, the Judge, who?
All 3
The police are investigating, but...
I have created a character
to unravel one of my cases
That's gone, I started again
I invented my clean...
informers...
It is true?
Yes... also true that
you're expecting my child
Ah yes?
You did not screw Manuel
I was able to lie to you, I too can lie
I know
If the child were not mine, you'd
have gone to see your mother, not me
- Give me
- Hold
What was Letal after?
He worked on the assassination
of a transvestite,
but I did not find anything
In short yes, you
My mother's warehouse: my den
What a brothel!
You are the 1st person
I've brought here...
Oh, Rebecca
Do we fight or do I put on my beard?
Put on your beard... The
state my head is in...
Relax...
Don't
I'm taking off my sweater
to put on the beard...
You put it on at your mother's?
Of course
She suspects?
No, she is insane and
never leaves her room
What a family!
How can you lie to everyone?
Everyone, except you and me
And those you leave behind...?
Paula, who fell in
love with your character
Now, there's just me
Letal has explained
everything to you today
How can I believe you?
How do I know you're not a murderer?
And you, that you are
not a queer or a junkie?
Let's not complicate life with that
We are imperfect
With this confession,
you could destroy me
I do not want to
Marry me, then!
You're crazy!
It must be settled now,
we have started a family
Letal, don't confuse me more
I am called Eduardo
I have to get married and I
have only just learned your name
Oh yes
This song always makes me cry
It is beautiful
Becky del Paramo has just
been rushed to hospital,
following an infarction...
at the theatre where she
was playing successfully...
According to Dr. Tavora,
the artist suffers...
with angina that she hid...
Rebecca, at last...
What?
She's unwell, she asked for you
Do not speak to her too much
I am the Judge
Sit down
Rebecca, come her
My daughter
At last you are free!
For lack of evidence
Protect yourself!
But to me, you owe the truth
Tell me the truth
I do not want to die in ignorance
I killed him
You are not the only culprit
Do not say that
Why keep your illness hidden?
That would have been blackmail
It is as if I had killed you too
Don't feel more guilty, one is enough
Listen...
Tell the Judge to come in
Why?
I must speak to him
She wants...
Forgive me, I was called
Yes, Father
Enter, please
Come closer, Judge
There is little time
I wanted to tell you
You were right
I killed Manuel
Rebecca confessed to protect me
But it was me
I knew it
And how?
With his revolver
But no more details
There is no time
I need proof
What more proof do you need?...
I am square with human justice,
there remains that of God
Rebecca, call the priest
Yes, mum
Do not cry any more, daughter
She wants to confess
It is madness!
It is natural to want to confess
What can I say? My last
confession was a long time ago
The introduction is
a little long, in fact
I believe that this will be enough
No confession since when?
I was a child
Let's do it like when you were child
Holy Mary...
Conceived without sin
I confess to all that I have lied
I admited I killed my
son-in-law and that is false
It was not me
Why lie?
To save my daughter
If your daughter committed
so serious a crime...
it is up to God to save her, not you
I am her mother, God will understand
My life was no use to her
My death will do her some good
You repent your lie?
No
I am glad to have done it
Your intention is good...
but for God to exonerate
you, you must repent
I repent all the misfortune
that I have caused
Tell me all
Don't be morbid
No, my daughter...
but the Judge is not very convinced,
I fear he will question me
Ok
Let us see
When I arrived, Manuel was sleeping
How could he sleep after my visit?
Nevertheless, he slept
My pills were beside his revolver
The noise of the drawer awoke him
I asked him how he
preferred I commit suicide...
A bullet or an overdose?
And then?
He said he couldn't give a fuck
Ah, men!
We started to argue
Tell me the worst, he will ask
The distance when you fired...
on which side of the bed he fell...
I do not want to be short on detail
Do not worry, I will tell you all
Do not tire yourself
Listen...
I decided to kill myself,
when Manuel dared me...
Then, I lost my temper and I fired
not at me but at him
He fell...
but I could not look at,
his surprised expression...
and I turned him over towards the right
But, in spite of his
bad treatment of us...
I was sad...
because nobody deserves to die like that
You must learn how to manage
your problems with men better
Yes, mum
Teach me
Never mind, I'll go
- Well?
- The same
Rebecca
I must speak to you
First, I must see her
She's waiting for you
Put the bag in her room
I am leaving the case
I will ask for another
But it is solved!
I am too involved...
This nightmare will never end
I do not have any evidence against
her... And now is not the time
I will give you, evidence, myself
Mum, I brought my things
That's good
We're living together again
And the revolver?
I have it there
Give it to me
Mum, are you sure you want to do this?
Yes
Not like this
I did it like this
Thank you
Open the windows
I want to see the street
As a child, when we lived together...
I could not get to sleep
without hearing your heels...
far away...
fading away in the corridor,
after you had passed to see me
It didn't matter how late...
I stayed awake...
for the sound of your heels...