Advertise your product or brand here
contact www.MY-SUBS.org today
I'M STILL HERE
DURING THE MILITARY DICTATORSHIP
Go, Marcelo! Go.
It's doing well!
Great, Eliana!
Go, go!
Yeah!
That's great!
Let's go! Yes!
That's good, team!
Whose cur is this?
Guys, take him away.
Take the dog.
Is he yours?
Marcelo!
Hold him.
He's messing up the game.
- He is cute.
- Beautiful.
- You should stay with him.
- I cannot.
Hold on.
Do you know what that
boy’s name is? Ah, Marcelo!
Look how cute our new puppy is.
Mom will not let him stay.
He's a flea-ridden.
- Where's she?
- I don't know.
Give me some.
She'll kill us if we get tanned
at the ballet, isn't, Nalu?
That's why rice poweder is for.
Let's go, come on!
Be careful on the street, Marcelo!
Let's go, let's go!
Excuse me, excuse me.
Oh, no, guys.
Please, clean your feet.
I just swept the floor
of the house.
He's cute. Let me hold it.
- What does that mean, boy?
- Our new puppy.
A filhty dog, Marcelo.
Does your mom know about that?
Is my Dad here?
In the office with Mr. Bocayuva.
Don't bother him, Marcelo.
- It's urgent.
- Wait... Don't go, Marcelo!
It was crazy that we accepted a
project of the size.
If it was easy we wouldn't
take it, would you?
- You would take it, I know you.
- Ah, I would take it.
- Dad?
- Come in.
No, no, no.
Dog in the house, no.
- No, no way.
- Can we stay with him, please?
- What did your mother say?
- She said to ask you.
What's this got to do with me?
Look at this.
Can you take it with you?
Me? No way.
I have a tunnel to build.
And Dalal will kick me out of house.
I think this little rascal here.
Will be called...
- Pimpão!
- Let me see it.
I know how do it.
Wait, guys.
What is this?
Drop it. Hide it.
- Lean against the wall, I command.
- I've already given you my IDs.
- What more do you want?
- Shut up!
You in the yellow car!
Park here.
Stop here, here.
To wall, fuck!
Hand in the wall!
Turn off the engine.
Put that fucking camera down.
Come on, get out of the car.
To the wall.
Put your hand on the hood.
Let's go, hairy one, to the wall.
- Shit, man! That's not necessary.
- Be quiet there, girl.
Turn around.
Where are your IDs?
- Wait, no need to push him.
- Be quiet!
I'll get them, they're in the car.
Can I take them?
Move! Move!
Get your hair out your face.
TERRORIST KILLERS
WANTED
Twice, yes.
Babiu, the first is silver.
What time will Veroca arrive
from cinema?
Calm down, she's coming. They went
to drop the kids off at home, ok?
Cuchimbas, turn up the sound.
Giovanni Bucher has his car
intercepted on the way to the embassy
shorty before 9am today.
The kidnappers captured the diplomat
after injuring his security guard,
who was shot in the back of the head
and is hospitalized in serious condition.
In a quick and violent action,
eight men and one woman used
a Willys Aero model car
to block his car in the Laranjeira
neighborhood, in the South Zone...
- Didn't they let this guy go away?
- No, darling, that was the German.
- This one's Swiss.
- ...People nearby said,
after they heard gunshots, they saw a
two-door Volkswagen passing very fast
heading towards Flamengo.
Pamphlets were left at the
scene of the action, signed
by responsible organization
for the kidnapping,
that calls itself
"National Liberation Alliance".
- Ah, he's cute.
- But you won't take care of him.
- What is this?
- I'm still shaking. It was fucked up.
What happened, girl?
Watch your mouth, Veroca.
Where were you?
I went to drop Helena off at home
and we were stopped by the police.
The cops were agressive,
searching everyone.
It was awful.
Another ambassador
was kidnapped.
- Another?
- Yes. We saw on TV now.
Oh, Mother of God.
Luckily, Pimpão has his
father's BBA card in the car.
What is BBA mean?
That's why is good to have a
lawyer in the family.
- I wish I had that luck.
- It's Brazilian Bar Association, honey.
- Want me to fix your dinner?
- No Zezé, I'm not hungry, thank you.
- Mrs. Eunice, this girl is not eating.
- You're screwed.
Listen, go to talk to your
dad, he was worried.
Gimme.
This ambassador situation is crazy.
Veroca, Veroca.
Look! Dad call him Pimpão.
- Don't tell him.
- Did he leave already?
He promised me a
ride in the Dodge.
- Another day.
- Oh, Wallaby. No.
You're not going to be riding
in that playboy's car, no.
Funny, I thought playboys drank
whiskey and smoked cigars all day...
No, sweetie, I'm the guy who
pays for your mid-afternoon film.
What did you go to see?
Blow-Up.
The sound was shitty.
Your mom got nervous when
you disappeared like that.
Dad, what do you intend to do?
Lock me inside the house?
Notify us.
It's not my fault if many
soldiers is catching...
Who want coffee?
Dad, how many prisoners
did they ask for now?
- I don't know.
- Everyone go to bed. Now.
No, I wanna finish
watching the news.
No, no, no. To bed.
Marcelo, the dog goes in the garage.
I'll call Dalva to see if Helena
arraved well. Sounds like it wasn't pretty.
Today, Dalva insisted again that
we go to London with them.
But then she offered to
take only Veroca.
It's good ideia.
- Do you think?
- I do.
Next year, she'll start college. So...
What?
Do you think there is no chance that
Veroca won't get involved in trouble?
The way she is.
Let's wait. Let them settle down first.
Then we'll see. No rush.
No rush?
Why are Gaspa and Dalva leaving?
Gaspa's paranoid.
Thinks he's being watched.
Let's send her to there.
At least until this phase is over.
It'll pass soon.
Do you remember her in
the macrobiotic phase?
Lasted two weeks.
Yeah, but no one gets arrested
for being macrobiotic, Rubens.
You're right.
I will talk to Gaspa.
- Yeah?
- Yes, it's gonna be okay.
- Hello?
- Hello. It's Rubens Paiva?
- Yes.
- I came to deliver a delivery.
Work, I'll go pick it up in my office.
Do you hang up for me, please?
...Belfim Moreira, 80.
Exactly.
No, you can leave this at the office.
Exactly, in the Downtown.
Do you know the address?
I know, you'll want know a lot...
Alright, I'm turning off.
What is this squirrel doing awake?
- I smelled your cigar.
- A better nose than Pimpão.
What is this for?
This is for doing math,
measuring a liar's nose.
Who were you talking to?
Dad's on a secret mission.
Do you know what it is?
I conclude that you have no chance
of winning against me at Foosball.
Your chances are zero.
Can I prove that you're wrong?
- Do you want to try it now?
- Come.
Won't cry so as not to
wake all in the house.
- Wallaby, come please.
- I will.
If you're going to cry,
cry quietly.
- Cry? I will not.
- Keep voice down.
- 1 vs 1. Dad?
- Let's go!
It's Brazil. Brazil knows.
Fuck, Marcelo!
Go to sleep!
It's the beginning of the
turning point. Come on.
Wash him properly, Marcelo.
Wow, it's easy, guys.
Now he'll smell good.
You didn't answer me, eh?
Under your bed it's disgusting.
Because you slept with him dirty.
So, you slept...
You can meet an English boy.
Fall in love with the next John Lennon.
Guys, I'm going back
to study Sociology.
But you don't have to decide now,
do you, sweetie?
Travel, enjoy it and when
you come back, decide.
I've already made up
my mind, Mom.
Rum raisin for my
Mediterranean.
Very good.
What did you call Mom?
Son, it's a mix of Italian,
Spanish, Greek, and Turkish.
Your mother, the most beautiful
woman in the world.
Me.
Veroca, Veroca.
Find me an English boyfriend.
- You can't date yet.
- Of course, I can date.
Veroca, will you miss me?
Of course I'll miss you, my love.
- And me?
- No.
Oh, dear. Veroca.
Poor boy.
I will, I will.
- This one is for you.
- Thank you, Dalva.
Veroca promised not to give
you any trouble.
She'll be no trouble at all.
I can always go in her place.
It's easier for me to take
the whole family there.
When our house is almost renovated,
we will travel there.
Oh, please, Eunice. Once you move into
that house, you'll never leave Rio.
- Is this one for Babiu?
- Yeah, for Babiu.
And this one, I chose for you.
Wow.
It's getting too
dangerous here, Rubens.
I won't wait to see it.
You should do the same and come with us.
I'm sending Veroca first to
see if it's not a scam.
Offering shelter to an entire
family in London?
Hey, what is this?
You are all my family, too.
You'll be back soon. To reopen the
bookshop and publishing house.
It won't be long, you'll see.
Son of bitch.
- I love you, man.
- I love you.
Are you taking that all?
Just this one.
- Take it.
- Seriously?
Just don't let Eliana touch it.
Vera?
Yay.
Don't spend on disks, ok?
There you can buy a boot, as good
boots are essential for the cold.
Thank you.
Mom, do you still have
that brown coat?
- Which one?
- The fur-lined one.
- This one.
- But it's so old.
- It's new yet.
A gift from your dad.
Honeymoon in Bariloche.
Can I borrow it?
You'd better behave there.
Dalva has enough on her mind.
I can take care of myself, Mom.
All right. Take cara of my coat,
then, I'll want it back.
I promise.
Don't run off right away.
I'll make a soufflé for you, young lady.
Nalu!
Come on! Come on!
Goal!
It's a goal!
Look at him.
Do you know if someone's
interested in this house?
You, right?
I'm looking for a place like
this, here, in South Zone.
Rubens hasn't even started the new house.
But I can introduce you to a great realtor.
I want to. Our townhouse can't
handle the new students.
I don't know how Dalal manages
to run a school alone.
I don't have five
children, right, Eunice?
- She has six if we count...
- Rubens.
What a delicious smell. How do
you keep it from sticking to the pan?
Beatriz I told you. You run a knife around
the edge, put it in a very hot ove and
don't open it, that's it.
- I can't believe.
- It's true.
Look how sweet the girls are dancing.
It's good they don't understand French.
- Did you see your sister?
- Isn't she in her room?
- Take your hand off your mouth.
- It's already falling.
Let it fall on its own.
Is anyone up there?
No.
Brasília is a ticking time bomb.
The military will hit hard.
Seventy prisoners for an
ambassador, they're playing with fire.
How are the things at
the newspaper?
Worse by the day.
I've never see a lot of people
exchanged for an embassador.
If they let these people go,
are they going to kill him?
No, honey.
I bet right now the
ambassador is comfortable.
- And he is.
- With a Moët & Chandon.
Soufflé's in the oven.
Who's hungry?
Soufflé with Swiss cheese.
Eliana, wet bikini in the couch?
Go change.
- It's too hot.
- No.
- I told her. She don't listen.
- Veroca is not here.
Never mind.
Yesterday I nearly broke my arm.
When I was playing with them.
- I fell on my arm.
- Son, your stories are long and confusing.
Tell this story for your father's honour.
I'll ask for a blessing.
This girl is calmer, but
this one I will...
Have you ever repeated.
Maybe I'll have to ask
my old man to go.
Dad, isn't this my party?
I get to pick the music.
What is this peace and love
girl complaining about?
You'll get tired of foreign
music. Shall we dance?
Can I dance with this young lady?
- Why are you asking him?
- I'm asking. Shall we dance?
No way.
Can you believe our Veroca's
going away, alone?
Soon it'll be just you and me.
My tooth fell out!
Babiu! Babiu!
Dad, what if someone finds it?
Baby, not a chance. Look at
the size of the beach.
What if we don't find it?
We will. I counted the steps
from home to here.
Get ready, let's take a photo.
Babiu! Babiu!
C’me, let's take a photo.
Come here, Rubens.
Get closer. Closer.
Go, Rubens.
Let's go, let's go.
C’me here, c’me here.
Eunice, no, no.
Let me do it.
You have to be in the photo.
- Really?
- Sure.
Let's go.
Attention, get ready.
Nobody serious, okay? Go.
Attention. "Ditch the Ditchtators"!
One, two, three, and...
I'll take it, Zezé.
Hello?
He's not at home.
Who is it?
Hello?
Rubens, someone left this for you.
- Thank you.
- Welcome.
TO RUBENS PAIVA
FROM VERA LENNON
"Guys, this is not just a letter, is a sensory
experience like the Mutantes concert."
"This is our street, it's very funny
like Blow-Up. All the houses are similar."
Me and the chimney.
"Just the doors are different. It's kind
weird to spend Christmans without a beach."
"But we discovered that there
are how to have fun in the cold."
"We even made a snowman."
- Look, it's Dalva!
- "Remind you of someone?"
"And how about this street?
It was so exciting."
"Nalu. Can you believe my feet touched
the same ground as John Lennon?"
"Hard to believe the Beatles
ever recorded here..."
The bus, watch out!
- Look, my English boyfriend!
- You don't speak English, right?
"Look at this musical shop.
I could camp out here."
"We stayed until closing.
I only bought one single, okay, Mom?"
"It's not for me. It's for...
Pimpão".
- If it's any consolation.
- "He will enjoy this glam rock stoff".
"I hope you're all well. Kisses,
miss you all, Vera 'Lennon'."
- Put it on again.
- Again?
Wait, I'll rewind the tape.
It's rewinding.
Wait. Okay. It's done.
- Can I read this time, Dad?
- Yes, darling. Sure.
- Ready?
- Can I go?
- Wait, I'll turn it off here.
- Can I start?
"This is our house, it is very funny
because it's the same as others."
"Really similar, like that ones in
Blow-Up. Just the doors are different."
Wait, just a second.
Get out of the way.
"It's kind weird to spend
Christmas without the beach."
"But snow is cool, too.
We even made our first snowman."
"Remind you of someone?"
"And how about this street?"
If I don't organize these photos
I'll end up confusing myself.
Love, can't we put air conditioning
in the kids' room?
No. The house will be breezy.
There's a cobogó wall, a big varanda.
- Pick it up, honey.
- I'm playing.
Hello?
That's right, at the corner of
Almirante Guimarães.
We'll be here all afternoon.
Thanks.
Is there a good movie at the Pax?
No. We have dinner at Dalal's.
Boca didn't say it?
We can go to the movies afterward.
- Ready for backgammon?
- I'm always ready.
- Where are you going?
- I'll prepare lunch.
Mr. Rubens?
There are some men here...
What's going on?
Congressman Rubens Paiva?
There must be some mistake, I haven't
been in Congress for years now.
There's no mistake, sir,
you're coming with us.
- Where to?
- To give a deposition.
It's routine.
A deposition about what, Rubens?
It's all right.
- I just need to change.
- Of course.
Go with him.
Anyone else at home?
Just my children. They're upstairs.
There's no need for weapons.
- Hi, Mom.
- Hi, honey.
Where's Daddy?
He's in the bedroom.
I'll get a glass of water
in the kitchen.
I'll get it for you, Cristina.
Good morning.
- Dad?
- Hi.
- Here.
Can I borrow this?
Sure. Take it.
Give me a kiss.
Where you going all dressed up?
Up to the office for a bit.
But it's a holiday.
I'm just going to help these
gentlemen. I'll back soon, sweetie.
Okay.
Honey, I changed my mind. Sleep
at Cris's house and tomorrow
you can go to ballet
together, right?
Thank you.
Cristina, tell to
Sebastião show up later.
I will.
- Can I go with him?
- Your husband will be home soon.
I'll be back in time
for the soufflé.
Where's the deposition?
I don't have that information.
And what about you all?
We'll keep you company, ma'am.
- Mom?
- Hi, son. Did you sleep well?
Who are these guys?
They're from pest control.
Are you hungry?
C'mere, eat something.
Chocolate?
Is my Dad at the beach?
He went out for a bit.
He will back soon.
Mrs. Eunice, I'm a bundle of nerves.
Where's the extension?
One in the office and another upstairs.
If it's for your husband,
say that he's out of town.
Hello?
Hi, Dalal.
Yes, but today won't work. Cuz'
Rubens has to travel at the last minute.
No, it's not serious. It's a family
matter, he'll be back tomorrow.
Okay. Give Boca my best.
We haven't been introduced yet.
I am Eunice.
Schneider.
Are you gentlemen staying for lunch?
No need to bother.
I insist.
...This wave of car thefts that's
taking over the city.
A car with an open door is
an invitation to crime.
Babiu, eat it.
What exactly do you do,
Mr. Schneider?
I'm a parapsychologist.
A parapsychologist?
Mom, why's the house all closed up?
Eliena, go take a shower,
and then have lunch.
After the game.
I came to get the ball.
No, not now, sweetie.
- What is this?
- No one leaves til your dad comes back.
Where did Dad go, Mom?
Let's go to your room.
But Mom, they're waiting
for me at the net.
- You can play later.
- Mom, I literally have the ball.
No, Eliana.
Mom, what is going on?
Who are these guys?
- Why can't I go out?
- Eliana, they took your father.
- Where to?
- I don't know, sweetie.
They said he had to answer a
few questions. I don't know where.
- Are they policemen?
- I think they're from the army.
Calm down, honey.
Do you know if
he's okay or not?
It'll be okay.
Just don't tell the little ones.
Babiu. Can you help me
here in the kitchen?
Yeah.
That's enough, Marcelo.
I'm going.
Go to room, your sister
is already in bed. Go.
- Tomorrow we'll finish.
- Tomorrow, these gentlemen won't be here.
You won.
Is there anything else I
can do for you gentlemen?
There' food in the fridge,
if you're hungry.
We'll get by all right, thank you.
Could you call and check when
Rubens will be back?
It's getting late and I'm worried.
I can't do that, unfortunately.
Let's go up to sleep.
- Mom, they're armed.
- I know, darling.
- Can I sleep in your bed?
- Best stay with your siblings.
Please.
Just a shift change, Mrs. Eunice.
You can go back to bed.
I'm not tired.
Eliana?
Sweetie.
Is Dad back?
No, honey. We will make
a deposition, too. Okay?
Me too?
Yes, honey. Wear this clothes.
Don't worry, we'll be back soon.
Stay with the children
for me, please.
Put this on, please.
Where is my daughter?
Eliana's outside.
Sorry about the hood, Mrs. Eunice.
Do you accept this?
Where is my husband?
CONFIDENTIAL SUBJECT
MARIA L. EUNICE FACCIOLLA PAIVA
How long have you
been married?
I want to see him.
Here it says eighteen years.
Was your husband already an ally
of the communists when you two met?
My husband was in the Labor Party.
I'd like to call my lawyer.
No need. These are just
routine questions.
I'll only answer after I've seen
my daughter and my husband.
He's upstairs. He's already told us
everything he knows.
- He's waiting for you to confirm.
- To confirm, what?
That he left the country in '64 for
conspiring against the revolution.
Rubens was a congressman.
He was ousted and had to go into exile.
But since he came back to Brazil, he
hasn't been involved in politics.
So why is he still fraternizing
with terrorists?
He's not...
Motherfucks, you're gonna kill me!
We've been keeping an eye on
comings and goings at your house
for a while, Mrs. Eunice.
We like to receive friends at home.
And are any of those friends here?
No.
Mrs. Eunice, I'm trying to make sure
you can keep taking care of your home.
Driving your children to school
and playing your backgammon.
That's my job.
How's Vera doing in London?
Did you do something
to my daughter?
- Did she do something wrong?
- No.
So, there's no need to worry.
Shall we try again?
Who is this here?
Rubens.
See? It's not difficult.
Who else do you know?
Look carefully.
Martha, my daughters' teacher.
I don't know what she's doing there.
Martha was intercepted
at the airport, yesterday.
Her son provides logistics for the
subversives fleeing to Chile.
It can't be the same person.
She brought letters to Rubens.
I want to know how he gets
those letters to the terrorists.
I already told you. Rubens
has no connection to terrorists.
Mrs. Eunice, you need to
rethink your behaviour.
Am I going to see my
daughter now?
- What is this?
- It's protocol.
But you said that if I answered
I'd see my family...
We're not done yet.
Is my daughter here?
- Is my daughter here?
- Mom?
- Eliana!
- What's going on?
- Sit down. Be quiet.
- They'll ask you a few questions.
- Then we'll return to home.
- Ma'am.
She's my daughter!
She's just a child.
Just a child.
Don't let them do anything
to my daughter.
Be quiet. Otherwise you'll
annoy them more.
Eliana, your turn.
Name?
How long have I been here?
Say your name.
Eunice Paiva.
Full name.
Maria Lucrécia Eunice
Facciolla Paiva.
I want to talk to my husband.
Look one more time.
I told you, I don't know.
I just wanted to
change my clothes.
One more time.
My daughter.
Where is she?
I don't have that information.
Do you recognize anyone else?
- Eliana?
- Don't talk, be quiet.
Eliana?
Your daughter is not
here anymore.
She only stayed one night.
And how long have I been here?
- Five days.
- My husband...
His name is Rubens.
Did you see him?
Shut the fuck up!
A doctor.
They need a doctor.
Stop. For God's sake.
I don't know anything!
I'm afraid!
Full name.
Maria Lucrécia Eunice
Facciolla Paiva.
Where am I going?
I just want you to know, ma'am,
that I don't agree with it.
Sweetie.
Come here.
Where were you?
Calm down.
Do you want to eat something?
Your mom, just need to sleep a bit.
Okay? Tomorrow we'll wake up
and eat together.
Mom, what's happening?
Eliana?
- What?
- Mom is back.
- And Daddy?
- No.
Is she in her room?
She asked no one to come in.
Can I sleep with you?
Yes.
I wanted to wait for you there,
but they wouldn't let me.
Sorry.
Did they do something to you?
They asked a lot of questions,
but I said I didn't know anything.
Did you see your dad there?
It's in the paper that he escaped.
Escaped?
But Lino said it was a lie.
- Was Lino here?
- No, I heard it at Boca's house.
I go there every day after school,
we were trying to find you.
Don't, Mom.
It's better not to use the telephone.
Let's go, I'm gonna with you.
No, Eliana. You will go to school.
- But Mom, I want to know what...
- Eliana, you will go to the school.
- Mom, I'm already helping them.
- Your mom is taking care of this now.
- Mom!
- Mommy!
My babies.
Where's Daddy?
TERRORISTS RESCUE PRISONER
This headline was created, Eunice. At least
now they can't deny that he was arrested.
Did they deny Rubens' arrest?
They said has nothing to
do with the army.
Same thing happened to the
Pasquim guys, and they're fine.
Exactly. Vanished for two
months, then released.
The international community is
watching closely.
What about a photo?
Of the family without the father?
It's good, sure.
Put it on the cover.
- We can't do that.
- Why not?
The newspaper is getting worse, guys.
Only what the military wants comes out.
I'm thinking The New York Times,
Le Monde. How's your French?
- I don't know what to say.
- Tell them about your arrest.
- Eliana, too.
- Didn't she want to come today?
- No, I send her to school. Is she fine?
- Yes. She's fine. A little scared.
Calm. Rubens is a former congressman.
Nothing will happen to him. Okay?
We need to keep showing
that we're watching them.
We need to do more.
Yeah, but without any concrete
evidence that he was arrested
there's not much
else we can do.
- And his car?
- What?
His car is parked in the army lot.
I saw it yesterday.
Mrs. Eunice, Mr. Lino arrived.
Should I put some coffee on?
No, I'm already leaving.
I'll pick the kids up at school.
Just take care of lunch, please.
- What would you like me to make?
- Whatever there is.
...Shoot some tear gas
in the middle of the mob
Ain't be no oxygen
folks are gonna drop
An incendiary grenade
a fire-thrower flashes
That troublemaking mob
gonna trample on its ashes...
This is a change of clothes and medicine.
My husband is diabetic, he needs this.
I told you, there's no Rubens here.
Can you tell us where
he's been taken?
For that, you've got to put in
a request to the federal police.
Okay, thank you.
Can we have the receipt, please?
Where do we make that request?
No use, they'll just deny it. We'll
have to go through the courts.
At least now, with this,
I can file the habeas corpus.
I would like to read it.
Can I keep it?
It's worse than Greek.
Are you sure?
Yes.
I'll pick up the children at school,
then I'll stop to the office to return it.
No need, I have a copy.
If there's any news,
I'll let you know. Okay?
I didn't know Rubens was diabetic.
He is not.
I only found out who the letters
were for when I met your husband.
So. Did you see Rubens there?
We were put in the same car.
- Where did they take you?
- I don't know.
- They covered our heads with a...
- A hood. They did it to me, too.
What's so hard about putting them
back where they came from?
Martha, you've got to make
a statement to the police.
But it was the policemen
who arrested us.
I know, but now they're
saying they didn't.
Look Eunice, I'm sorry.
I can't get involved in this.
You're the only person who
saw Rubens there.
You've got to help me.
If I don't prove that
I was arrested...
You've got to leave, please.
My husband's in danger, Martha.
Everyone's in danger, Eunice.
- I can walk there, Mom.
- No, that's enough, Ana Lúcia.
Why did Daddy's car
come back, but he didn’t?
- 'Cause he's still on a trip, my love.
- Isn't this his bag?
Leave that bag there, Marcelo.
I've been missing ballet
for two weeks now.
- Cris said I can go with her.
- No.
From now on, you come straight
home from school.
And nobody goes out on
their own anymore.
- What about Eliana's volleyball?
- I quit the team.
Why?
I don't feel like practicing.
...The search for the terrorists
who carried out the kidnapping...
Mom. They're talking
about the ambassador.
That's not for children's ears, honey.
Zezé, get inside.
Do you know where
the key to this gate is?
Does it have a key?
Let me see if it's here.
Pimpão, come here.
Come here, you rascal.
You rascal, you cannot leave.
Don't. Huh.
Zezé, what about that car
with those men in it?
It's been there for days, Mrs. Eunice.
But do they do anything?
They just sit there.
Staring over here all day.
Your apron's frayed. I told you
should buy a new one.
The cash ran out. I had to use it to
buy groceries while you were away.
There wasn't enough for a new one.
Of course. I will go to the bank and
withdraw some money and replace it.
Mrs. Eunice?
Could you see about my pay, too?
I know you've got
an awful lot on your plate,
but Mr. Paiva only paid
me through December.
- I'm sorry, Zezé. I'll sort it out.
- Thank you.
- Have a sit.
Rubens can call to authorize
the withdrawal.
There's no telephone
in the mountains.
He had to stay longer to
monitor the works.
Is there really no way that
you can help me, Ritor?
I understand, but without his
signature there's nothing I can do.
How's Miriam doing?
She's doing well.
We need to arrange
to see each other sometime.
Let's arrange it, yes.
Well, I brought some dollars and
pounds I had at home.
Can you exchange them
for me, Ritor?
For sure, Eunice. Just a minute.
I'm gonna call someone to help you.
- Thanks.
- Excuse me.
Mom?
- Hi.
- Do you know where Mom is?
- No.
Can I have a drag?
- Please.
No.
You meddler.
Gilda called again today.
She managed to get Vera on the
waiting list for a flight next week.
By the way, a letter from Veroca.
I think it'd be better if she
stayed a while longer.
Do you know how much the ticket is?
I'll deal with Rubens later. He'd
better come back soon, to fix this mess.
Ah, son of bitch.
Ok.
Everyone in my house
doesn't see their friends.
Why did they arrest Rubens?
I don't know.
The politicians have no chance.
They're chasing anyone.
You're not going to do
that to me, are you?
I've been to that place.
I saw it.
I deserve to know what
Rubens was doing.
Don't you think?
I do.
Eunice, there's no way
to just stand by.
Especially us. We know many people.
Who has the means to
help those in need.
So me, Rubens, Gaspa, Raul...
One talks to the foreign press, another
one provides shelter to people on the run,
and deliver letters to
families without news.
Everyone does what they can.
But we're not involved in the armed
struggle. Much less Rubens.
So you decided not to say a word
to me, to Dalal, to Dalva.
- To protect us.
- Of course.
And do you think Rubens
will be released?
I do. He'll be back soon.
Come have dinner in my house.
Dalal will be glad.
I'm not really in the mood.
Too many kids to raise.
Thank you.
"These photos are on the subway.
One out front, one inside the train."
"On the day I was going to
a party at the Arraes' house..."
Pass it on, Marcelo.
"You won't believe who was there."
- Who, Mom?
- Guess who?
Caetano?
Gil.
Gilberto Gil!
"He was wearing polkadot velvet pants."
"A Bob Marley song started playing,
and he asked me to dance."
- No way.
- Such a liar.
"It was amazing."
"I miss the beach, the soufflé, and
you all. I miss everything, Vera."
- Is that it?
- That's it.
Can I see it?
Everyone stay here.
Marcelo!
Pimpão!
What are you looking at?
What do you want?
Where is my husband?!
Go away! Get out of here!
Go away!
Get out!
Zezé, get me a blanket.
Please.
"The Brazilian exiles were asking
about Dad, Mom, and Eliana."
"I didn't know what to say.
I got this awful feeling."
"Why don't you tell me anything?"
"I found out about your arrests
from the papers. What's going on?"
"I want to go home soon."
Why didn't you read the rest, Mom?
Give me that letter, sweetie.
No. You skipped the part
about Dad and me.
Everyone's talking about us.
Vera doesn't know what's going on.
- Give me that letter!
- You are lying to us!
Go to your room.
SUPERIOR MILITARY COURT
HABEAS CORPUS
EUNICE PAIVA IS RELEASED AND LAWYER
ASKS SPECIAL PRISON FOR RUBENS PAIVA
HE IS NOT AT THE
DESIGNATED LOCATION
"I still can't describe the excruciating
hours I spent in prison,
but I can guarantee you that
I was there with your husband."
"Although I couldn't see him, I heard
him say: Rubens Beyrodt Paiva."
"Before I was transferred, I heard
his voice one last time, asking for water."
"I pray that the family
will be reunited soon."
"Give my best to my former students
Vera, Eliana, and Ana Lúcia."
- Lino?
- Who is it?
It's me, Lino. I'm sorry
about I'm calling late.
We have proof that
Rubens was arrested.
I think there's still time for a swim.
Anyone?
It's kind of late. I'm hungry.
Zezé, no need to cook.
We're going for ice cream.
- Look at this.
- Any chocolate?
- C'mon, Marcelo.
- I want French fries.
I want a strawberry sundae.
Mom!
"Died in combat", Médici said.
That's all.
Can you publish that?
No. Not yet.
They won't admit it officially.
We have to talk to Lino.
He'll know what to do.
There's nothing we can do now, Eunice.
What do you mean?
We have to force them to admit it publicly.
A subpoena, a court order.
We think we need to continue
to ask for Rubens' release.
As if we didn't know
nothing about him.
What?
To have someone parked outside
my house all day long?
So my phone will keep on
being tapped?
You're not alone.
What about the body?
I have nothing more to say.
But what do you think they did?
Say it.
I've heard it all, Eunice.
They bury in the forest, dropped into
the sea from a helicopter, mass graves.
It's all rumors. There's no way
to know, 'cause nobody will talk.
They're afraid of disappearing, too.
Do you mind if I don't
walk you out?
I'm sorry, I wish I were
the bearer of better news.
I know.
Bye, bye, guys.
What were you talking about?
I came to bring something for
your mother, that's all.
Did you find out where
my Dad is?
Not yet. Take care, okay?
So boring.
You're boring, go play
with your doll.
- You stupid.
- Oh, Marcelo?
Mom?
What, sweetie?
Mommy, Marcelo broke my doll.
Sit down here.
Were you crying?
No.
I fixed.
Shall we have some ice cream?
- Yeah.
- Tell your siblings to get ready.
- You?
- P.
G.
- S?
- No.
- Say, Babiu.
- R?
Are you sure?
If you wait till the deed is in order,
we can get a much better price.
I've got too much to do.
I prefer it this way.
I can loan you money,
that's no trouble.
That piece of land is a gem, and
you can still build the house there.
Thanks for managing to sell it
without the proper papers
I'm sorry.
I wish I could've done more.
It wasn't your fault.
If you need anything, anything at all,
for you or for the kids, just tell me.
Of course.
- Is that a deposit?
- It's withdrawal.
Thanks.
- Hi Zezé.
- Hi.
- Can I come in?
- Of course.
Lass?
I missed you.
You've grown up.
- Hi, honey. I missed you.
- Me, too. So much.
Do you know that
Pimpão has died?
- What?
- The dog.
Ah, poor puppy.
- Can I keep the brooch?
- Of course. As many as you want.
Where are Nalu and Eliana?
They stayed home to wait for
the reporters from Manchete.
What do the staff of this
magazine want at home?
They'll take a family photo
for the next edition, honey.
Look, I'll work some magic.
Pay attention.
Mom.
What, honey?
I left your coat in London.
Helena insisted on keeping it.
So, I left it with her.
All right.
- Really?
- Yeah.
She'll need the coat more
than me in London.
Are you all right, Mom?
I am, honey.
I'm all right.
Have you heard any news?
Verinha.
In London, it's in all the papers.
Hasn't this been published anywhere?
Sweetie!
Get be closer, get closer
to each other, please.
- Is everyone in the picture?
- Yes. Get closer to each other.
Closer. Yeah.
Ready?
Let's go.
Three, two, one…
You don't have to smile.
Why not?
- The editor asked for it.
- For what?
He asked for a photo that's more...
A photo less happy.
He wants a sad one?
No, he doesn't want a sad one.
He wants a photo without smiling.
He wants a sad one.
We going to smile.
Smile.
How about serious?
Can we get serious for a second?
Smile.
Look here, please.
Smile!
Three, two, one.
Another one.
I really don't understand,
how in a country with a allegedly
functioning justice system,
someone break into my house, take my
husband, a family father, an engineer away.
Throw him in jail, and
then simply say "he's gone".
The inquiry was recently
archived, right?
My lawyer has filed a request
to reopen it.
It is unacceptable for the State
to act in this way,
which is protected by a
system of false news
designed to cover up the unlawful
acts committed by its own agents.
Is Zezé off today?
She doesn't work here anymore.
- Why?
- We can't afford to pay her.
She works at Dalal's school now.
Let me help you, then.
No need. Tomorrow you can
start on the rotation.
Let me get the dishes for you
today, Eliana.
If you insist.
How are you?
I heard that they took
you along with Mom.
Eliana, what's going on?
Nobody tells me anything.
We can't talk about that at home.
I wish I could've made a
welcome-home soufflé, honey.
No need.
But there was no time.
Shall we have lunch?
What are we going to do that
Veroca is back, now? I'm in her room.
I don't care.
Eliana can stay with
Marcelo and Babiu...
- No way.
- But you're already there.
There's stuff in another room,
I can't put it in mine.
Hey, there's no point in arguing.
Nobody's going to have a
room of their own anymore.
- Why?
- What?
We're going back to São Paulo.
- Are you serious?
Yes, I am.
Grandma and Grandpa
are there, and your cousins.
And you can stay with them now and then.
Because I'm going back to college.
- What?
- I'm not going.
- Eliana.
What about the new house?
It'll have to wait a little,
sweetie.
What about Dad?
Your Dad is a long process
to understand.
I know it's hard to understand, but
you'll just have to be patient.
And what if he comes back and
we're not here anymore, Mom?
This house is already rented out.
It's going to become a restaurant.
I want each of you to pack your
things, and on Friday,
a moving truck
will pull up out front.
We're going back to São Paulo.
Marcelo, hand me the salt.
- Bye, Wooden leg.
- Bye, João.
Bye, Luquinhas.
- Keep this for me?
- You'll be back, rascal?
How did you find it?
Only Daddy knew.
I know a lot of things, too.
Let's go.
Nalu, have you seen Eliana?
No.
Eliana?
Eliana!
Sweetie?
25 YEARS LATER
CLASS OF 1977
You got in early.
Hi, honey. I rescheduled my flight.
That's good.
I'm going to eat out with Daniel.
Do you want to come?
I can't, Babiu. I'll just heat
something up. Thank you.
Was that recent?
I can't handle you in those little
airplanes.
By land, it's impossible.
It takes three days and the area
is swarming with land grabbers.
I thought you kicked
them out last time.
Me, too.
When do you leave tomorrow?
Manuela will pick me up at six-forty.
I haven't even started
preparing my speech.
I'll wake up early so we can
have breakfast together.
The legal tools we have to try to prevent
the illegal occupation of these areas,
and the entire region affected by
the Transamazonian highway, are:
First, file for the annulment of fraudulent
contracts by land grabbers,
which Manuela and I did for the Pataxós.
Second, enforce the 1988's Constitution,
it requires the State to guarantee
Indigenous peoples' rights to their land.
There's an urgent phone call for you.
Hello?
Couldn't you comb your hair, Marcelo?
I already put on a tie, Mom.
Do you have the documents there?
Yes.
- Good morning, Marlon.
- Excuse me.
Let me introduce you my
children. Marcelo and Beatriz.
And your little one?
Is he fine?
- He's fine and back at school.
- That's great.
- Give Ivone my best.
- Sure.
And ma'am, congratulations.
C'mon, Marcelo.
- So is it really here?
- Yes, ma'am.
Cristiane, can you get
Mrs. Eunice file, please?
- Yes, I can.
- Thank you.
Marcelo, sorry to bother, but when
your mom said you'd be coming in...
- Do you mind signing it?
- Yeah, of course.
- It's Carla, right?
- Yes, Carla.
- Did you like it?
- I cried a lot.
Really?
It was supposed to be funny.
The story of your accident moved me.
HAPPY OLD YEAR
Was there too much swearing?
- No?
- No.
See? She's the only one who gets on
my case about my language.
DEATH CERTIFICATE
RUBENS BEYRODT PAIVA
The press is here, Mrs. Eunice.
Can I let them up?
Yes.
It's weird to feel relief
with a death certificate.
How did you deal with the void
left by your husband?
Forced disappearances were one of
the regime's cruelest acts.
A person is killed, and this condemn all
the rest to eternal psychological torture.
Don't you think that after
the return of democracy,
the government have more
urgent issues than fixing the past?
No. I think it's necessary
to compensate the families.
And do the most important thing:
Clarify and judge all crimes
committed during the dictatorship.
Otherwise, they will continue to be
committed with impunity.
A picture!
Mom, not the cheap stuff, eh?
Is this good?
After the third round,
who can notices it?
Now that this is finally over, how
about you get retirement?
- Retirement, Marcelo?
- Take a break.
Come visit me and Daniel
in Bern, take a little rest.
The rest I want is on the beach.
Then go for it.
Mom, you did it.
The rum is good.
- It's good.
- I told you.
- You're not opening that now.
- I'm already opening it.
- No, I still have to organize this mess.
- The paper asked for a photo of Dad.
I'll call Vera. The kids
must be back from school.
- Send my love.
- And my best to Jorge.
Look, Pimpão and Zezé.
Do you remember when that was?
Was the on... Nalu's birthday?
No, Dalva and Gaspa aren't in it.
You, me and Daddy.
When did you bury him?
What do you mean?
The day you realized he
wasn't coming back?
I think it was when I saw Mom
donating his clothes.
About a year and a half later.
Really?
What about you?
I think it was when we left Rio.
That soon?
I think so.
Seeing the house all empty.
Vera sends her love.
Shall we take a photo
for your sisters?
Yup.
- When was that?
- That?
I think it was Vera's birthday.
Did you teach her how
to use the timer?
We're about to find out.
Smile.
Do you need help, Mom?
Check it, I think it's all in order.
As soon as I get the grant,
I'll pay you back.
It's all set out here.
Let's go, I don't want to
get stuck in traffic.
Mom, you really don't need to.
- Daniel's coming to pick me up.
- Oh, okay.
Call me when you get in?
I will.
Are you going to see the doctor?
No.
I'll miss you.
Me too, honey.
Go get ready.
SUPERIOR MILITARY COURT
HABEAS CORPUS
WHO KILLED RUBENS PAIVA?
RUBENS PAIVA'S CASE:
JOURNEY INTO THE WORLD OF TORTURE
DEATH CERTIFICATE
DECEMBER, 1970
Blow a kiss to Daddy.
You not.
Joaquim.
Marcelo, I have the one
from Manchete, the one at the beach...
I think I have the ones from college.
And from Brasília, are there any left?
I don't think so. None survived.
- But there’s the one with the pigeons.
- That one it's great for the cover.
That's up to the publisher.
I'll check what I have, scan
and send it to you.
Eliana, put them on a
pen drive for me, please.
The soufflé!
Guys, a total failure, it deflated.
Watch out, it's hot. No jokes, okay?
A sorry sight, eh, Mrs. Eunice?
- If Mrs. Eunice had left the recipe...
- It's Mom's fault now.
Are you satisfied? Babiu brought
your chocolate ice cream.
Chico? Do you want to, right?
- I want it.
- I want it, too.
Joca.
- ...In the holiday, we've talked about it.
- When is the holiday?
- Raquel, can you bring Mom? Please.
- Okay.
It's here.
You'll get me drunk.
Thank you.
Mom seems less irritated,
doesn't she? She's calmer.
Yeah. I think so.
Joaquim does her good.
We've been together for four months,
but I don't know if we're dating.
Juca said she has the
best kiss in the town.
- What, Juca?
- It's a criteria.
- What do you mean, man?
- Did you have a date with this girl?
No. I'm joking.
It was just him.
Tell me how she spent
this week.
There are days when she's fine.
There are days when she's out of mind.
...Twenty one years of military regime
in Brazil and the countless crimes
committed against those
who opposed it.
The Commission heard over
twelve hundred witnesses,
including State officials
and victims of the dictatorship.
The article reveals systematic torture and
murder that victimized over 20.000 people
and left hundreds more missing.
The report identifies 230 locations
where these crimes were committed,
such as army barracks, as well
as areas used for disposing bodies.
Such as Marambaia, in Rio de Janeiro.
Some of these victims became icons of
resistance against the military regime,
like the journalist Vladimir Herzog,
the student Stuart Angel
and Congressman Rubens Paiva.
Rubens Paiva's body, like those of at least
two hundred others, has never been found.
Shall we take our picture?
Let's go, guys! The photo!
Our traditional photo.
Come on!
Let's go, guys.
The picture of the year! Let's go!
Are you all right?
Joaquim, where are you?
Okay, get ready, everyone.
Here, Mrs. Eunice. Here.
Mom, there.
Let's do this folks. Smile!
THE BRAZILIAN GOVERNMENT ADMITTED
THAT RUBENS PAIVA WAS MURDERED
INSIDE THE BARRACKS OF THE
1ST ARMY DIVISION IN RIO DE JANEIRO
BETWEEN 21 AND 22 JANUARY 1971.
IN 2014, FIVE MILITARY OFFICERS WERE
REPORTED FOR HIS TORTURE AND DEATH.
NONE OF THEM HAVE BEEN
ARRESTED OR PUNISHED TO DATE.
EUNICE PAIVA GRADUATED IN LAW AT
THE AGE 48 AND HAS DEDICATED HER CAREER
TO DEFENDING HUMAN RIGHTS.
SHE HAS BECOME ONE OF THE FEW
SPECIALISTS IN INDIGENOUS RIGHTS
AND A CONSULTANT FOR THE FEDERAL
GOVERNMENT, THE WORLD BANK AND THE UN.
EUNICE DIED IN 2018,
AGED 89, IN SÃO PAULO,
AFTER LIVING WITH ALZHEIMER'S
DISEASE FOR FIFTEEN YEARS.
Translation and adaptation by
Mr. Brazilian.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS.org