Use the free code JOINNOW at
www.playships.eu
Then the Gods said that, truly,
this Demon can't be fought with.
Brahma had given him
such a boon that...
...no God was able to defeat him.
Then Vishnu... Then Vishnu
flew into a rage.
An aura emerged from his face,
an aura emerged from...
...the face of Shiva as well.
And auras emerged...
...from the faces of
the various Gods.
All those auras converged
together and created this...
...Goddess, Durga! This
Durga has 10 hands.
And with 10 kinds of weapons
in the 10 hands...
...astride a vehicle...
- What's her vehicle?
Vehicle? Her vehicle is a lion.
Durga's vehicle is a lion,
Ganesha's, a mouse.
Karthik's, a peacock.
Lakshmi's, an owl.
And Saraswati's vehicle is a swan.
The Goddess fought with
Mahishasura, on this lion.
Is this all true?
- How do I falsify it, dear?
The sages have written about it.
Everything is true.
Mahishasura is true...
...Hanuman is true, Digpal is true,
Varunadev is true...
Uncle! The dacoits have come.
Is Ghoshal there?
- Who are you? - Is he there? - Yes.
Tell him that Maganlal Meghraj
has come to meet him.
You tell me what you
want, I'm there.
Your introduction?
- I'm Bikas Singh.
Are you related to him?
- No. I stay in this house.
What's the matter?
You've come suddenly
after so many days?
Sit.
How many days has it
been since we met?
I had passed out in 1950.
And you, in '51.
You'd failed one year.
Tell me, what's the matter?
I had last seen you at the temple...
...so I thought, why not
come and meet you?
We come here every
year for the Pujas.
Father is here, uncle is here...
- And your Ganesh? - Ganesh?
You still remember that!?
It's there. Why won't it be?
It has become divine due
to our worship and care.
Will you show it to me?
- It's kept in father's trunk.
And the key of that trunk
is in father's garage.
Doesn't your father
show it to anybody?
Showing it to anybody and showing...
...it to you, aren't the same thing.
You're very popular in the market.
You tend to get defamed
if you have money.
You earn money like me, you,
too, will get defamed.
But you also have to see
how you earn that money.
I heard that you're
selling off the...
...sculptures of the country
to the foreigners.
And the Americans are giving
you fat money for that.
I'm offering you Rs. 20000,
I've brought it along with me.
What?
- You haven't seen that thing yet.
Without seeing it, you're
offering such a high price!
Gold figurine, a diamond
in the crown...
...rubies and emeralds at the base...
...it's of Nepali origin.
- How did you know so much about it?
I haven't told you anything.
This has been written by Father.
I haven't seen it yet.
Rs. 25000, cash.
I know about your business.
I also know how much money
you owe in the market.
If I have to sell that
Ganesha to you...
...then I've to learn
the art of stealing.
The question of selling
it doesn't arise.
Rs. 30000. I don't ask for
things from everyone.
If needed, I just snatch it.
It saves my money, too.
I'm openly transacting with you.
No, brother. Sorry.
Is this your final verdict?
Yes.
Who is it?
Rest your head on your arms,
else it'll ache.
Do you know how many temples
are there? - How many?
How many temples are there?
- 33 crores.
Just sign here.
Is there a bathroom facility
in your house? - Yes.
Look, I'm very particular
about bathrooms.
Everything in my house...
Are you Mr. Chakraborty?
- Yes.
I'm Lal Mohan.
- Welcome!
This is Paras Mitra.
- Ok. - And this is Tapas Pal.
My assistant had given me a detailed
introduction about you.
Do we have to sign?
- It's just a negligible formality.
You're the eldest, you've to do it.
You just write your
names and sign here.
I'll take care of the rest.
Your assistant is related to me.
That's what I was thinking that...
You're the one with the
synonym Jatadhar...
Not 'Dhar', but 'Yu'.
I'm writing a new novel,
Kaalgombhir.
O really!? Send the
luggage to room no. 3.
I'm giving you a 4-bedded room.
Please sit for a while,
I'll be back. - Ok.
What arrangements do you
have for water? - What?
You'll get running water
all throughout the day.
Hot water will be given to
you whenever you want it.
Wow! Quite good.
- It's good, even...
...though it is not like the Jodhpur
circuit house, but will do.
Decide where all of you
are going to sleep.
Do you want the window-side bed?
Is it facing the road?
- Yes.
No. This one is good for a writer.
You will get a healthy person
besides you. - Healthy?
Yes.
- See what's hanging there.
Seems to be a person with taste.
It seems that this has also
come with that person.
You mean he has brought
this big mirror with him.
Must have a use. Mere shaving
is not the only purpose.
You mean he shaves the hair
on his chest. - Bodybuilder.
Very good! Did you see how my
assistant is being prepared?
This place goes straight
to Dasharsadan.
Dasharsadan!? That's a great place.
The name's place creates
devotion in our hearts.
Will that help you in your
job? You would not...
...be writing a novel on devotion.
It's all because of the
thrill of that place.
In my hotel, a 26 year old one,
this is the first time that...
...3 famous people are
staying together.
3 people!?
Famous historian, popular
novelist and in room no. 4...
...Bishosri. - Bishosri?
That famous body builder?
Have you seen him?
- Yes. On TV.
You won't believe,
I saw him eating...
...he bend his hands like this...
...and his wrist was
bulging like this.
17 inches
- 17 inches?
That's what he said.
What about you? - My shirt
collar size is 12 inches.
Come, sit. I've ordered tea for you.
And yes! Do you know
inspector Tiwari?
The one at Mahamayatala?
- Yes. He's at the station.
Yes, I think he has helped
me with some case.
I met him on the road, today.
I told him about you...
...he has asked you
to visit him.
Isn't there anything exciting
in your hotel?
I don't know whether
it's exciting or not.
But there's a powerful sage here,
he's said to possess...
...magical powers, his
name is Machlibaba!
Machlibaba!?
- Yes.
He has swam from Kashi to here.
What're you saying?! From Kashi!?
I'm not saying so, that person
claims to have done so.
This is ridiculous!
He gives sermons at the
banks of the river...
...there's a devotional gathering,
then there's a...
...session of devotional songs.
And if the Baba shows mercy...
...on someone, then he gives him
a Shalka talisman that day.
What's a Shalka!?
- You're so vague.
Shalka is a fish's gill.
Do you want, sir?
- What? - A Shalka talisman?
That sage has a radiance
on his face...
...you've to accept it,
whatever you say.
Is there any member of the public
among these devotees?
Or are all of them
his paid devotees?
What're you saying, sir!? They're
all the cream of Kashi.
There. The one on the front,
wearing a black coat...
...he's an agent of
the Allahabad Bank.
He's a learned man. A great scholar.
And the one with the bald head,
he's the professor...
...of Benaras University.
And the greatest devotee...
there he comes.
Give me your binoculars.
Madanlal Midraj. Haven't
you heard his name?
The one whose house was raided
a few days back in Kolkata.
He visits this place regularly.
- Does he have a house here?
What're you saying, sir!
He has a house, farm...
...charity home, everything!
This place is Baba's favorite
resting place.
Nothing unexpected! Thieves
tend to like such places.
It seems he's taking a gift.
The Baba doesn't ask for all this.
The Baba doesn't stay at one
place for a long time.
Then is his next stop at Patna?
- I don't know, sir.
Will the Baba dive into
the Ganges from here?
One Brahma, one sun, one moon.
He's amazing. I don't know whether
he's a great saint...
...but he's a great personality
for sure.
Two hands. Two legs.
Two eyes. Two ears. Three
generations. Three periods.
Four seasons. Four senses.
Five elements. Five fingers.
Five limbs. Five Pandav.
One, two, three, four and five.
The Baba has a Vimano
Ulki in his hands.
You've amazing eyesight, sir.
I've come here before, but
I couldn't figure it out.
See for yourself.
He seems similar. I've seen
such a ulki with Keshto...
...in our colony.
- Let me see!
Just a minute!
Shall I introduce you?
He's a great detective.
He's the most popular writer.
Do you stay in Benaras?
- My father stays here.
We come here for the Pujas.
He's been here for 60 years.
Are you staying in Calcutta lodge?
Yes. In my place.
Is it about some case?
- No. Just a holiday.
I was asking you, because
I may need you.
I mean, the problem is that there's
been a theft in my house.
My father is a bit upset.
- Didn't you inform the police?
My father doesn't have much
faith in the police.
But he's here. - That's why I
was thinking that I shall ask...
...Father about it, if he agrees,
then I shall call you up.
Alright.
- Ok. Then we shall leave now.
As we've to go that side for...
I've heard of you. But I haven't
seen you till now.
There's a program on Saptami day.
You can attend.
Are those bubbles on your
arms, truly 17 inches?
See.
Touch it.
Oh God! I don't get the feeling
that I'm touching a human body.
It's just as I had told you.
These are the triceps, feel it.
Those were the biceps and
these are the triceps?
Is there anything above triceps?
Yes, quadriceps.
What a great thing. A total build
up of muscles. - 400 here...
...400 here. When you stretch like
this, that is also a muscle.
You open your mouth.
That is a muscle. You
chew that's a muscle.
For every movement there
is a muscle coordination.
Does every muscle have
a separate name?
Write it down. It'll
help you in future.
Really. We know so little.
No! I wouldn't have believed
it, hadn't I seen it.
What a practice! - It needs
discipline. - That's true.
What're you seeing? I shall change
your body in just 2 months.
What? Do you want to change?
- No. I don't need it.
Do you bend rods?
Yes. We've to do it.
Do you lift people?
- No. I don't do that.
Whom do you want me to lift? You?
- No!
You've got a telephone call.
- What's this? So soon?
Did you see?
Do something. They're
killing those birds.
They won't listen to us.
Let's go inside.
Welcome! Are you Produshocho?
- Yes.
Mr. Ghoshal is expecting you.
Come.
Sit. I shall come.
What a painting!
How do you feel?
Brother, they're modeling
the idols of Gods.
Wow! This God is like
the one in Kolkata.
Kashi is the second
home for Bengalis.
1.5 lakh Bengalis stay here,
in Kashi. - 1.5 lakh!
Sarojda is coming by Doon express.
Sister is also coming same day by
Amritsar mail. Receive both of them.
Greetings. - We were looking
at the idols here.
Come on. Come inside.
Father is a great follower
of detective stories.
That's why he agreed when
I told him about you.
Does he read a lot?
- All the time.
Only English or also Bengali?
He leaves nothing.
I wanted to know something.
Was that boy, your son?
Who? Nopu? He's just another
boy in the family.
He was standing at the edge
of the terrace wall.
And was also killing the birds!
Bikash!
Send for him. He's on the terrace.
Tell him that Father is
calling him immediately.
Leave it.
Let me come to the point.
The thing that has been stolen,
is an idol of Lord Ganesha.
It's quite tall, made of gold.
It's embellished with rubies,
emeralds, diamonds, etc.
Its price... must be around a lakh.
To which place does it belong?
- It belongs to Nepal.
It was brought from there.
That picture is that
of my grandfather.
He was the housekeeper of the Rana.
Once, he rescues Rana from one
of the attacks of his enemies.
Then the Rana gets pleased
and gives it to him.
Since he got the Ganesha, Grandpa
sees small incidents...
...and creates a belief
in the family...
...that the Ganesha is very lucky.
Did all these incidents
take place in Nepal?
No. Radhanath came down to
Kashi within a few days.
He has his practice here, and
earns a lot of money and fame.
In fact, this house too,
belongs to him.
A few days before this idol is
stolen, a man offers to buy it.
And offers up to Rs. 30000.
- What's the name of that person?
Maganlal. Maganlal Meghraj.
Did you know him?
Yes. We studied in the same college.
Did you refuse to
sell it to him?
That thing doesn't belong to me.
It was brought by Radhanath.
It's with my father,
in his trunk, now.
And I stay in Kolkata.
- And what was Maganlal's reaction?
I obviously can't say that
he felt happy about it.
When did the theft take place?
It took place, exactly the
next night of his visit.
Father came back the
next day and saw...
...that the key was hanging
on the trunk...
...and the idol isn't there.
Is there any reason to doubt
anyone in the house?
The servants, who're there,
are all old and reliable.
And there's just Grandpa, Father,
me, my wife and Bikash.
Here's your son.
Did you climb the terrace walls?
Why? What if you had fallen?
Don't you know that
you shouldn't do so?
Captain Park climbs the walls, too.
Who!?
He's a character in a mystery series.
He climbs upside down.
- Yes. His head at the bottom...
...and his legs on top. Isn't it?
Who's giving him such books? You?
These days, all the boys...
You won't do any such thing. He'll
read all such weird books...
...and get clouded with such
ridiculously dangerous ideas.
If I hear again that you've
done any such thing...
...then I shall lock
you up in your room. Go!
Who's Bikash? - Bikash
just stays in our house.
He's the son of one of the
employees of my father.
He lost his parents
while he was young.
Since then, my father
brings him up himself.
What does he do? - He takes
care of the household chores.
And does some ordinary job in
a Hindi publication company.
If we could meet your father...
Yes. He's waiting for you.
One thing. Father is a
little short tempered.
And yes! Father doesn't know
about Magalal's visit.
Take care.
- Ok. Take care.
It seems that a gramophone
is playing.
It's my grandfather. He's 84.
Once upon a time, he was
very fond of music.
Now, the only thing that he
does is key the gramophone...
...and change the records.
Father, they've come.
- Let me see.
How great a detective are you?
Are you 6 feet tall?
- Yes.
And he?
- I'm 5.5.
I've no interest in your height.
Detectives in novels have
a person with them.
Like Holmes had Watson. The
other one had Hastings.
Our Byomkesh had Ajit.
Are you like that?
This is my friend. You can
call him my assistant...
...my cousin brother, Tapesh.
Looking at your appearance, it
doesn't seem that you're dumb.
That too, when the three of you
won't be working together.
Come. Let's sit in my
room and discuss.
I've kept records of everything.
This is my family's photo.
Beautiful! - Not only beautiful,
it's a work of art.
It isn't a small thing. That's the
reason I don't believe that...
...small things can't
change a man's life.
Now see, detective sir.
Watch carefully.
This is the key of my trunk.
Here, I'm opening it.
Here's the key.
Come. Come.
Here's my trunk, I'm opening it.
Here, I twisted my wrist.
Here's the drawer.
Here's where my Ganesha was kept.
The Ganesha isn't there. - How
was the trunk, when opened?
The drawer was open, the trunk...
...was open, and the key was hanging.
This is my bed.
I slept at 10.30 that night.
Do you sleep soundly?
- Not quite soundly.
I have a habit of consuming opium.
When I sleep, I don't
have much awareness.
But that night, while sleeping,
I heard a noise.
I thought that it was just another
noise, and dozed off.
Look at all this.
Can you say what all these
are, assistant sir?
Detective novels.
I've swallowed every book.
So, cunningness won't work with me.
If you're able to catch the thief,
then you'll be well rewarded.
Or else, chili powder.
I've 2 questions.
- What?
Why did you call me?
You could've done this yourself.
Had I been of your age, and
possessed your strength...
...then I wouldn't have called you.
Then second question is,
do you doubt anybody?
No one from the viewpoint
of a father.
I won't say anything more than that.
The rest is your job.
I had warned you earlier.
Can I go to the terrace?
- Of course.
You can tour the house.
I'll send Bikash with you.
You can tell him if
you need anything.
Ok. C'mon.
Is this the house of Captain Spark?
If there's Spark, then there
must surely be an assistant.
He's there.
- Raxit? - Yes.
Khudiram Rakkhito. That
Rakkhito is Raxit.
The Ganesha was stolen despite...
...the presence of Captain
Spark, in the house?
How did this happen? Did
this happen for good?
It's with a king.
Which king?
An African king.
How did you know?
- Captain Spark knows it.
Can't it be taken back
from that king?
Spark will do it.
- Will he?
Else it'll go back to Atlantis.
The secret city under
the ocean? - Yes.
It seems this boy has swallowed
all detective novels.
Atlantis has been mentioned in
one of the detective books.
Can I see Captain Spark's house?
Here!
Are you a detective?
Do you have a harpoon?
An extra gun?
Then what do you have?
What I have, isn't with me now.
The revolver that shoots?
How many bullets?
Six.
I can show it to you, only if
you promise me that you...
...won't climb the terrace
walls, again.
I've another weapon.
It can't be seen.
What?
- Intelligence. It's kept over here.
Sometimes, it suddenly enters
a person's mind, and learns...
...all that is stored there.
It's saying that Captain Spark
likes to talk in Hiyali.
Do you know Hiyali?
'It is a strange thing. You
chew it and it tastes good'.
Do you know Hiyali?
'Five brothers are together,
eating rice with fish'.
'There are five more.
How do you do? '
'Five brothers are together,
eating rice with fish'.
'There are five more.
How do you do? '
Ok. I shall leave now.
Your grandfather has given us a job.
If we aren't able to do it,
then we'll be defamed.
What's your name?
- My good name is Captain Famous.
And real name is Pradosh Mitra.
Come. Tea has been ordered
for you. Come.
What's Rukku's good name?
- Rukmini Kumar.
Are you Raxit?
- What?
Captain Spark's assistant.
I'm won't be surprised
if I'm made one.
Because last year, he was Tintin,
and I was Captain Haddock.
Since when did the painting start?
Since when did the painting start,
sir? - Since Saturday.
Does he stay here?
- No. He comes from Ganeshmohalla.
It's Shashti, the day after. Will
your job be over by then?
Yes. It'll be over.
Come. Let's go to your room.
Were you there when Maganlal came?
Yes. I was in my room.
- How long was he here?
Around a half hour.
Were you at home?
- Yes.
What where you doing?
I was listening to music.
Radio?
- Yes, classical.
Which station?
- Lucknow.
Since when are you here?
- Since years. From '57.
Do you like it?
- I've got used to it.
I think you're aware of
your weak position.
There's nothing to
be aware of.
I'm no one here. Just seeking
shelter in Ghosh's house.
Had I had any interest
in the Ganesha...
...then I could've done so,
a long time back.
I've had no recent developments
requiring any money as such.
Has that happened to anybody else?
Forgive me. I won't be able
to comment on this matter.
If commenting on that improves
your position...
...then refusing to comment,
would be foolish.
Don't forget. You had
both the reason...
...and the opportunity to steal.
Reason?
- Freedom from staying here.
If you have anything
to say, then say it.
Deciding whether it's true
or false is my duty.
Mr. Ghoshal's business
isn't going well.
You'll come to know of it,
if you investigate.
And you also have that opportunity.
Bikash! Tea!
C'mon.
Is everything alright?
- Yes. Everything's fine.
The salt, spice, etc...
- I didn't know that...
...you could get such
a huge fish in Kashi!
I've arranged for it with
great difficulty, sir.
Don't give up, at least
as long as we are here.
And yes! Don't worry if your
job doesn't end...
...within 10 days.
I've already booked 3 beds for you.
Thank you. But the job will
end in 10 days...
...else it never will.
No! Don't say such a thing,
in Kashi, that too, in my...
...Calcutta lodge, one of your
adventures should be remembered.
Let's see.
He isn't saying anything.
Despite the presence of Jatayu...
...Captain Spark took
away his attention.
How can he refuse that?
- You're right.
It means that you aren't the only...
...popular detective novelist in
the country. You've a rival.
Yesterday's brat! The one
that stays in Darjipada.
He writes under a synonym. I
wrote an edition in 3 days...
...and he hasn't finished
one in 3 months.
Is he the creator of
the character Spark...
If he gets an idea, then a spark
flashes from his forehead.
Understood?
You've got a phone call,
shall I ask him...
...to call back after 10 minutes?
- No. I shall attend to it.
Is this Mitra?
- Yes. - I'm Maganlal Meghraj.
Oh! Greetings!
I saw you at the ashram
of Machlibaba yesterday.
How did you recognize me?
I have my own methods. There're
people to show me.
I can understand that.
What are you doing this afternoon?
- Why?
Come over to my place. I've
something to talk to you about.
But I don't know your house.
Do you know Gyanvapi?
- Yes. I know.
My man will be at Gyanvapi. Blue
shirt, his name's Manohar.
He'll bring you along.
But there'll be two
more people with me.
Your own people?
- Yes, my own people.
Then bring them along, too.
I'm waiting.
- Ok.
Have you done the right thing?
I haven't compelled you to come.
No. I mean that meeting such a
person, will it be suitable?
That's why we've come.
If he talks nonsense, then
I shan't remain quiet.
Why? - Who knows, what
kind of a person he is.
Oh God! Where are you?
- I'm here. I'm in front of you.
No. It's just that...
- Sit. Sit on the mattress...
...or if you want, then on the sofa.
I had a wish to meet you.
I've heard of your job.
Even I've heard of your fame.
Why are you saying fame? Say
defame, tell the truth.
Is that boy your brother?
- No. A cousin.
My uncle's son.
- And him?
Uncle?
- He's my friend.
All are Lal!
Bring cold drinks.
We ate before we came. Lunch.
So what if you've eaten?
You've walked from that...
...Calcutta lodge to our house.
That food must've gotten digested.
What're you saying?
- It's your wish. What shall I say?
Have you come to Benaras
for a holiday?
That was my intention.
- If that was your intention...
...then why did you change your mind?
It's my mind, after all. Where's
the restriction of changing it?
There's no restriction, but why
are you wasting your time?
Go and visit the various temples.
I've my own boat, you can
visit all the 80 banks...
...and it won't cost you
even a single penny.
Your mind will be refreshed breathing...
...the air of the Ganges...
...instead of doing all
this, why are you...
...wasting your time at
the Ghoshal's house?
You're forgetting that I'm
a professional detective.
Mr. Ghoshal has given me a job.
The question of refusing
it doesn't arise.
What's your fee?
- It depends on the job.
It's Rs. 2000. Take the money
and stop your job.
I don't charge any money,
without working for it.
Work? What'll you
achieve by working?
You won't be able to do anything
after catching the thief.
Why?
- The thief is your client, himself.
What are you saying?
Do you know that Mana Ghoshal
has stolen the...
...Ganesha from his father's trunk...
...and sold it to me for Rs. 30000?
Do you know how weak
he is, financially?
Do you know how much
he has to repay?
Will you go and tell his father
that his son has stolen the...
...Ganesha from his trunk?
He had refused you.
He changed his mind, after refusing.
After changing his mind,
the next day...
...he gave me the idol at
the ashram of Machlibaba.
And I had given him
300 Rs. 100 notes.
We visited the ashram, as well
as did our job. That's it.
You're an intelligent man, Mitra.
Not ordinary intelligence, but
extraordinary intelligence.
If you come to know the truth...
...then it'll be a problem
for both of us.
So you take that money,
and give up this job.
This is my request.
Then the Ganesha must be with you.
- Yes.
Can I see it?
What are you saying, Mitra? My
house in Calcutta was raided...
...why would I keep the
idol in my house?
To know whether you're telling
the truth or not...
I've to have a look
at the idol first.
Am I lying?
The opposite of true is false, Maganlal.
You do not believe my words?
There's Rs. 2000 there. Take
and enjoy your holidays.
Take a tour with your uncle.
I don't accept bribes, Maganlal.
Then you'll continue with your work?
Send for Arjun.
Bring box no. 13.
What, Halwamohan? Didn't
you like the juice?
Don't worry, Mohan. That
juice isn't poisoned.
I feel that poison is
a very bad thing.
Yes.
Poison is useful for other things.
A collection of knives!
Are you feeling well?
- Just a little fever.
It's alright.
- Will you perform today?
Have you seen knife throwing, sir?
The king of Harbanspur
had a private circus.
The knife thrower of his circus
now performs in mine.
Ok then, shall we go?
- Where will you go?
It's already 2.30...
- So what?
You've to rest a bit.
- No! First, Arjun...
...will perform, only
then will we go.
Are you ready?
- Oh yes! - Then start.
Come, Uncle.
- What is your intention?
Uncle stand in front of the board,
and Arjun will perform.
What do you think of yourself?
Hey fool! I shall break your bones!
I had told you to shoot, only
when he pulled out his pistol...
...who told you to shoot now?
Forgive me, sir.
- Is this your aim?
I'll penalize you for this mistake.
- Forgive me, sir.
I made a mistake.
Two pistols, two bullets
have been pointed at you.
Don't dare to disobey me!
By not believing me,
you've insulted me.
If you be obedient today,
then nothing will happen.
Not even to Uncle.
But if you investigate
Ghoshal's house again...
...then I won't be able to
guarantee your safety.
I'm clearly warning you.
Get up, Mohan! Get up!
What happened?
Just a minute. Let
me drink the juice.
What have you added to the juice?
I'm feeling amazingly strong.
Arjun, are you ready?
- Yes.
Where do I have to stand? Here?
- Yes. There.
Means, here?
- Yes.
Just a minute.
Here, take my watch. My wallet.
Ready Arjun?
- Yes.
Just a minute.
Hail Baba Vishwanath!
Wow! That's great!
You're a lion!
Amazing! Good!
Your salary will be increased!
Great!
Wow! Look at it!
I had told you, Mitra.
Arjun is excellent!
Uncle! Come out. The game's up!
Come out!
Lalan Uncle!
Get some milk and nuts for Uncle.
How much?
- What's it normally, for you?
72.
- Then it has to reduce by 25 more.
It'll reduce now.
Immediately reduce.
I'm feeling relived now.
Understood? A lot!
I'm so relieved now!
My head was bursting.
You hadn't seen it. It was
like living 5 lives in one.
They don't say it for no reason...
...that truth is stronger
than fiction.
Go ahead with the case,
I'm with you.
What happened? Hello? Are
you planning to give up?
I'm responsible for what
happened to you, today.
No! What are you saying!
This is just my fate. It's
written in my fate.
But I'm still alive!
Hale and healthy!
Forget what happened, today.
Either I'll take revenge
for this...
...or I'll give up my profession.
What happened?
Are you leaving?
You've a show, the day after.
What happened?
This is dangerous, sir. I
can't stay here any longer.
What happened?
- Don't ask. See.
Beware!
From where did you get this?
It was near the window.
Someone must've left it.
Are you afraid of such threats!?
You would've known, had
you been in my place.
This is a police case. Who wants
to get involved in it?
You've a 17.5 inch tricep...
- Bicep!
And you're afraid of this
ordinary threat?
You aren't able to understand
the matter.
I'm not a coward.
- Then why are you leaving?
Have you seen Angelo's David?
That one? That's something great.
Our body is a work of art. A temple.
And the muscles on that
are the designs.
Did you hear that?
- Amazing.
Did you understand? - Means you've
to take care of your temple.
Isn't that so?
- I can tell you one thing.
You aren't the one who
has been threatened.
I've been threatened.
Your introduction?
His is about this. About
mind and intelligence.
He isn't into building muscles
here and there. Am I right?
I guarantee on thing to you. Even
if something happens here.
Your body will be safe.
- What are you saying?
100% true.
Don't feel afraid. - But don't
let the Bengali club sink.
Everyone sees the Bishwanath
temple in Kashi.
But how many see the
Bishosri temple?
A bowl full of blood.
Did you think of mother Durga
as an ordinary woman?
She hurls the trident into his
chest, and blood spurts out.
Yes.
Did you call for me?
Sit.
I hadn't told you something.
As it can't be said.
But I'm telling it to you.
That day, even if I hadn't seen
someone entering the house...
...I had seen one leaving.
He was a gentleman.
There just two gentlemen in this
house, me and Bikash, Father.
You have hidden your conversation
with Maganlal from me.
Maganlal had offered you money...
...I came to know about it
through someone else.
I didn't feel that it was important
for you to know that.
Maganlal had asked for the Ganesha,
but I had refused him.
However if it gets proved that...
...you had opened my trunk...
...then the appropriate
punishment for that...
...you have to face it.
Maganlal hasn't got the Ganesha yet.
He hasn't!?
Had he got it, then he wouldn't
have offered me so much...
...money to stop my work.
- Then where's the Ganesha?
I believe... the Ganesha is
still in Ghoshal's house.
That means Umanath hasn't sold it?
Umanath, had he stolen it, wouldn't...
...have recommended us to his father.
And Raxit?
- Had Bikash stolen it...
...then he wouldn't have stayed here.
That's right. But where
did the Ganesha go?
Who opened the trunk,
why did he do so...
...and why is Maganlal interested
in that idol...
...only mother Ganga knows
about it, till now.
Mr. Mitra!
How are you?
- Fine. How are you?
Fine. I heard that you've started...
...working, even after coming here?
- What to do? There's no one...
...to pay us a salary. We've
to keep doing something.
Will you drink tea?
- Yes.
Tell me.
- Will you take my advice?
First, let me hear
what the advice is.
Have you heard of Maganlal?
Not only have I heard of him...
...I spent an hour
with him yesterday.
What? You didn't tell me about it.
He showed me the performance
of his private circus.
Offered me a drink.
What's your opinion?
- An extraordinary scorpion.
Do you know? There was a theft
in Benaras, a few days back...
...in Mr. Badrinarayars house.
A Nataraj idol.
And Maganlal had been to that
house, 4 days before the theft.
Then what? Search his house,
you'll get the idol
Maganlal isn't such
a foolish person.
Is it your intention to
promote his cunningness?
Forget about the threat to
my life, just tell me...
...will I get your help,
when I need it?
You know that. You've seen
it before in Allahabad.
Lakhan!
Take this.
It's 10:30.
- Were you thinking of eating out?
No. It's the bylanes of Kashi.
A historical feeling.
Moreover, I just wanted to
feel the cold atmosphere.
C'mon.
Is there any African king in
any of your stories? - Yes.
Gorillar Gograj. In it,
King Mahanto. - What?
Have you brought a
gorrilla from there?
That's nothing. Read
my latest book...
...you won't get a chance to look up.
What? How is the story?
Excellent! Especially, the part
where he hides the diamond.
He steals a huge diamond,
and hides it in the front...
...I mean, the front portion
of his robe, with cellotape.
Can't it be seen,
even when he moves?
That's the technique, sir.
Even people are shocked
on seeing him.
And this man sees the stone,
and as soon as he does...
Excellent!
I would've been happy,
had there been any noise.
This is too lonely.
Has your stock of courage lessened?
No! Do you know what the problem is?
I have the courage.
But not the muscle.
Bagchi's biceps. He has a lot of
it, but doesn't have courage.
Courage is a very special quality.
Are you going home?
I'm going because you're here.
Otherwise, in this street at night?
Have a look at those courtyards,
every house is haunted.
Go inside, and you can see bats
hanging from the ceiling.
I won't be surprised
if I see a vampire.
The bat says that you'll see
something amazing tonight.
Tonight, bats and vampires shall
come, and everyone will die.
Sir!
The Ghoshal house has no connection
with the death of Shashi.
He has been murdered by his son.
It's such that the son had gone
for a movie at late hours.
There was a cold war going on
between the father and the son.
In fact, it's being said
that the son had...
...even threatened his father.
I feel that if I pressure a bit,
then the truth will come out.
Don't mistake me. But
after your arrival...
...the crime rate in
Kashi has increased.
There has been a murder in
Chaukammatha, yesterday.
What's needed now,
is just a brain wave.
You don't believe in all this, sir.
Just take a dip in the river...
...tomorrow morning, you'll see that
your brain has been cleared.
I didn't believe in it for 30 years.
I was troubled by gastritis.
Allopath, homeopath, jinxes...
...ayurveda, I didn't miss anything.
Then I thought one day, what's
the harm in trying it?
Then I woke up at 5, and had a dip.
That's it.
Faith has an effect to some extent,
not in everything.
Is there any program?
- Yes. Akhtar's music show.
Is it today? - No. It was supposed
to be on Saturday...
...singers were supposed
to come from Lucknow.
Don't you change the towels?
What happened? You're
looking tense.
Won't you have your breakfast?
I'm being drawn towards one thing.
Drawn!?
Africa's king, Shashi's
and Akhtar's song.
Huh! The dot, the cat's hobby,
and Gopal's mother.
Is that 'Singh', a Punjabi surname,
or a Bihari surname?
Or is it the horn of a cow, goat,
deer, or anything else?
What's the first thing that hits
your mind on hearing of Africa?
Jungle.
- And jungle? - Animal.
And king of animals?
Where's Rukku? He isn't to be seen.
He has been sitting in the room
on the terrace, since morning.
Why? - The idol was being
established, and he tripped over it.
And naturally it was...
I've brought a revolver,
won't you see?
Where's the revolver? - Open the
door, and I'll show it to you.
Here, see it. This
is a real revolver.
Its name is Colt. It has 6 bullets.
The king of Africa is the vehicle
of Goddess Durga, the lion.
And you have hidden the Ganesha
in the lion's mouth...
...with chewing gum.
Isn't it so? - Else, Gondariya
would've taken it away.
He had told father that
he would take it way.
Gondariya is Captain Spark's enemy.
You had heard it.
- Yes. - What happened after that?
After that, I went to Raxit.
Raxit, a man has come, downstairs.
He's saying that he'll
buy your Ganesha.
He's saying that he'll buy it?
- Yes.
Who is that?
- Dacoit Gandariya alias Maganlal.
He's talking to Father. He'll
give him a lot of money.
He's saying that he'll
give a lot of money?
It isn't sounding good,
Captain Spark.
C'mon. Let's hide the Ganesha.
Where do we hide it?
That day, you told me a story
that a man had hidden a...
...diamond, within his
crocodile skin dress.
Similarly, we, too, will hide
it in the mouth of the lion.
Lion!? - The vehicle of
Goddess Durga. - Ok.
And if he asks you, then tell him...
...that it's with the king of Africa.
Ok. - And we shall remove it
on the day of the immersion.
Else, it'll sink along with the
idol, into the deep waters.
Did you hear the old man's antics?
- Yes. I did.
But the one who is acting
behind your back... - What?
Let me introduce him to you.
Know him.
No one's imagination
can match that of his.
He's the writer of 'Kamal
Kanya', Jatayu.
Jatayu! Are you Jatayu?
He's just exaggerating things.
I'm nothing of that kind.
Then, my Ganesha was
saved because of you.
But the Ganesha isn't there.
- What?
There's nothing in the lion's mouth.
Only the chewing gum is there.
You had called for me, to
catch the thief, isn't it?
That's true. There was
nothing in the trunk...
...when the thief came.
But we've to see who fiddled
with my trunk.
The one who has the
wrong intentions.
Not only wrong intentions, but he
has also taken wrong actions.
I had sent Bikash to buy sweets.
- Where?
You can find him, if you go, now.
What do you think?
- About what?
About Bikash's status.
- Bikash is a lion.
Tell me, Mitra. Where? Ram temple?
Ok. Alright.
Good morning. I was
searching for you.
Me? - I had to talk to you
about something. - Now?
It's important. It
can't be told here.
Let's find a lonely place.
But, I was...
- You can buy the sweets later.
C'mon now. We shall come back.
- Ok.
The thing tickling your
hips, is a fire weapon.
Don't try to escape!
Sit.
The one whose lie has been caught,
he can't be trusted anymore.
You weren't listening
to the radio that day.
You were listening to Maganlal's
conversation.
Isn't it so? Tell me.
Tell me what happened next.
If you lie, you'll get
trapped further.
Speak up.
Maganlal saw that I was listening
to him, secretly.
After that?
- He sends for me the next day.
He gives me an advance of Rs. 500.
Says that he'll give me another
Rs. 500 if I steal the Ganesha.
And a job in Kolkata.
I don't have any future here.
Believe me! - After that?
What happened after that?
I opened the trunk, but
the Ganesha wasn't there.
Then, last evening, I was in my
room at that time, suddenly...
I haven't committed any sin, sir.
I swear on God.
Believe me!
- Where did you get it?
It was... it was in front of
the idol. On the floor.
I don't know who kept it there.
This... give this to Mr. Ghoshal.
I went to Maganlal with the
Ganesha, that very night.
Sit.
Where did you get this?
It was in front of the
idol, in our house.
I didn't find it.
- You didn't find it?
Shashi Babu.
- Shashi Babu?
Our sculptor, he gave it to me.
He won't tell anyone.
He's a very good person.
Moreover, he isn't that
kind of a person.
Where is he now?
He is a very good man.
I mean, coolheaded. He
is about 70 years old.
Where is he now? In his house?
Do you know his house?
I won't be able to...
I know what you can do
and what you can't.
You just show it to us,
the rest will...
...be taken care of by someone else.
I haven't committed the murder.
Believe me, Mitra. I haven't
committed the crime.
It would've been alright hadn't
you told about that.
You wouldn't have been
able to do that thing.
Come, Tiwari. As of now,
he's your guest.
He's just a part of the plot.
There're many more to come.
Come. Come with me.
Is this that thing?
- Yes.
Tell me the spelling.
Now write, deltoid.
Wow! Is it deltoir?
- No. Deltoid.
Its 'd' not 'r' ?
- No.
Call for you?
- For me?
Listen, you've some work
to do. Listen carefully.
This evening at 5,
you and Jatayu...
...will come to Machlibaba's ashram.
Exactly at 5.
- And you? - I'll meet you.
It's something serious.
- I've understood.
And at around 3, a member of the
Bengali club, Shushanto Ghosh...
...will visit your place with
makeup and dresses. - Ok.
And take care that Lal Mohan
doesn't act over smart.
It's something serious. And
bring something to eat.
I haven't eaten anything all day.
I understand, but...
Hail Shiva!
What's this?
- Eatable.
He'll come on time. Keep quiet.
Look back.
You've just seen a bullet, Maganlal.
But you haven't seen a noose.
Arrested! - You've been
caught red-handed!
Now, you've to see the performance
of my private circus.
How much money do you want?
How much? Tell me.
Those who kill innocent people,
with the help of thugs.
Those who eat out of the
treasures of the country.
They won't be freed,
by coughing up money.
Come, Mr. Tiwari.
- Come, Mr. Meghraj.
Here, I've given my autograph.
- Ok.
I shall send two more books
after reaching Kolkata.
Do you know him, dear?
- Who?
He's Captain Falu's assistant.
What's the name?
- Captain Taxit.
I understood all that. But why
hasn't Captain Falu arrived yet?
He'll come. He'll come
within an hour or two.
He has to change his dress,
and remove the makeup.
But he doesn't go back on his word.
But I haven't come to know whether...
...I got back the Ganesha or not.
- Are you still unsure?
Don't misunderstand. I got delayed...
...as I had to attend to another job.
Here, take your Ganesha.
- Ganesha!
Thanks God!
What you showed, can only
be read in books.
Will you let me see it?
- Here, have a look.
You're incomparable.
Let me put it back in its place.
- Yes.
It's an old treasure of mine.
Go back to your house. Go
back to your house, O Lord!
Let us have some sweets
to celebrate.
I've work.
You'll refuse if I give you
anything more than your fees.
Before you write the
check, I would...
...like to show you something else.
You can. Why do you need
permission for that?
Then see. See carefully.
Here, I opened the garage.
This is the key.
Now, I open the trunk.
Here's the result of my action.
What was your action?
You may be reading a lot
of detective novels...
...but I'm a detective myself.
It isn't easy to fool me.
I've investigated. The price of
this can't be more than Rs. 1000.
Had this been the real Ganesha,
then you wouldn't...
...have hidden it in the lion's
mouth, along with your grandson.
Am I right?
- You're a genius.
Your actual Ganesha is
in the bank, isn't it?
Yes. Of course. Everyone
wants to see it.
And I've to open the trunk
for that, every time.
It's such a costly thing.
A work of art.
Did you hear it, Captain Spark?
Your grandfather had hidden
the actual Ganesha.
That's why, I'm taking
this fake Ganesha. Ok?
Is this the fruit of your actions?
- Yes. My fruit.
What do you say?
You're a genius. The one
who's so intelligent...
...he can't be fooled easily.
But how did you get it?
- I know.
By his intelligence.
Synchronisation by Subransu
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS.org