A Myung Film Production
Director: PARK Chan-Wook
Starring: LEE Young-Ae
LEE Byung-Heon
SONG Kang-Ho
KIM Tae-Woo
SHIN Ha-Kyun
Three days have passed
since the hostilities at JSA.
Efforts to hold a joint investigation
between the Koreas have failed...
but negotiators recently
achieved a key breakthrough.
Authorities from both countries
have agreed this afternoon...
to collaborate
on the investigation with NNSC.
While tensions have been running high...
amid suspicions
of North Korea's nuclear programme...
and advance of US naval vessels...
into the East Sea.
Spokesmen from both Koreas
have commented on the necessity...
to resolve this issue
with caution in a reasonable way...
so as to avoid having this trivial conflict
escalate into a war.
The subsequent agreement has
the NNSC dispatch judiciaries...
with investigative experience
from Switzerland and Sweden.
Scheisse!
If a battle starts, then
shoot the bastards.
You couldn't kill even one?
You call yourself a soldier?
I thought my primary mission was
to rescue Sgt. Lee.
- So...
- So?
So that's why you couldn't aim straight?
Was your order to shoot down trees?
My order was to scare them off
and give cover to the rescue team.
What? Hey, hey.
- You sure you weren't the one scared off?
- I didn't want to start a war, sir.
What? A soldier afraid of war?
You stupid...
What is it?
Reporting, sir!
War doesn't break out that easily.
Dismissed.
Yes, sir!
This incident...
isn't it rather obvious?
Some commies kidnap our soldier...
and claim he crossed over voluntarily.
- Am I right?
- Correct, sir!
Our boy... What's your name again?
- Sgt. Lee Soo-Hyuk, sir!
- Right, Soo-Hyuk.
Let's wrap this up quickly
so Soo-Hyuk can take a leave of absence.
Our boy here took out two of the bastards.
He's a hero!
Wouldn't you say, Maj. Jean?
Your opinion will be noted
in the investigation.
The NNSC will now be taking custody
of the suspect.
No South Korean military officials
may enter without my permission.
Neutral Nations Supervisory Commission?
There are two kinds of people
in this world...
commie bastards,
and the commie bastards' enemies.
Neutral has no place here.
You have to choose sides.
You're from law school, right?
I trust you'll make a wise choice.
I'm Maj. Sophie Jean from Switzerland.
This is Capt. Persson from Sweden.
He's still in shock.
He was hit with a blunt object.
That bruise pretty much proves
that he was kidnapped.
Deposition
He looks like one of ours!
Get down! Soo-Hyuk!
South Korea's hostile provocation...
to our North defence camp in JSA...
Right over the Military Demarcation Line.
Doesn't it seem a bit acted out?
This is where Lt. Choi's body was found.
And that's where Pvt. Jung fell.
A bunker...
Puppet soldiers of the South,
stop intruding into the North.
Pvt. Jung was a talented artist.
He even won a prize in a national contest.
He was popular among the soldiers
for drawing their girlfriends.
Abundant Rice is Communism
As soon as Lee Soo-Hyuk left our post...
Southern soldiers stormed in as if on cue.
It's very lucky that Sgt. Oh has survived.
Otherwise the South
would have been spouting lies...
shamelessly blaming it on us.
That's exactly what they're saying now.
Who's going to believe it?
We have a witness.
Don't get up.
This is Maj. Jean from the NNSC.
Are you okay?
No big deal. It's nothing.
This is from a terrorist in Libya.
Sliced me with his knife.
Once in Egypt, I had to scrape out shrapnel
with a bayonet.
Wanna see?
Really?
Shall we take a look?
I'm glad you're okay.
Now then, can you tell me about that night?
It's all in my deposition.
You mean the deposition you made
and signed while in a coma?
Stupid wench.
What did you just say?
Why is it you all have depositions,
but nobody will talk to me?
Lieutenant, tell us about your vacation.
It was the same as any other.
- Come on!
- It was nothing special.
Get down!
Shot twice.
Once in the right chest...
crushing the ribs
and passing through the lung.
But that wasn't the fatal shot.
The second one was the real killer.
Judging from the angle,
it was shot at point blank.
As for the next one...
a total of eight shots.
Unbelievable.
Shot from such a close range,
they went right through him.
The first shot hit his face,
probably killing him instantly.
The rest were just shot into a dead body.
Go ahead.
Lee Soo-Hyuk.
Now there's a man.
I can see that.
Once while he was on duty...
those guys over there cursed our president.
Soo-Hyuk heard it.
He took a rock and smashed their window.
So I rounded up my men and then told him:
"All right! Way to go!"
Once he got left behind
on a search mission.
Man, the squad was in uproar.
Four hours later, he shows up again.
Says he stepped on a mine
and had to dismantle it.
Damn!
Anyway, I knew then.
This guy, he's unique.
Nerves of steel, I tell you.
Nam Sung-Shik...
you were on duty with Sgt. Lee
on the day of the incident.
- Right?
- Yes, ma'am!
I'm not deaf.
Why did Sgt. Lee go out alone?
An urgent call of nature.
Can a soldier leave his post for that?
He said people with constipation...
should seize a chance when it comes.
These are blanks.
Please load the gun as you would normally.
So you refuse to say anything?
I visited Kaesong City and saw the corpses.
If you just wanted to escape,
why'd you shoot a man eight times?
I brought photos of the bodies.
Do you want to see them?
No.
I don't want to see them.
You've got a nice voice.
Your platoon says
you're very quick with the gun.
Are you really that fast? Will you show me?
It's not the speed
that's important in a battle.
It's about how audaciously
you are carrying on in calm.
That's all.
All right, then.
Can you load the gun again,
just like before?
Are you really a Swiss soldier?
Does Sgt. Lee talk much about army life?
He tries to, but I don't let him.
Has he ever talked about, for example...
how he went on any missions...
or if he got special training?
Special training?
Can you zip me up?
Soo-Jung, you don't worry about Sgt. Lee?
We're not really that serious.
What kind of person is he, in a word?
Well...
Oh, you can tell by
how he treats my brother.
My brother never had many friends,
ever since we were kids.
But after enlisting, things got
much better, thanks to Soo-Hyuk.
He's very warm-hearted.
Probably because he grew up poor, like us.
Wait a second.
Your brother?
You didn't know?
Pvt. Nam Sung-Shik,
they're in the same platoon.
He kept asking me to meet Soo-Hyuk,
so I did.
What?
Is there something on my face?
No, not at all.
There were 11 bullet wounds
on the three North Korean soldiers.
Ten bullets were recovered at the scene...
but one was never found.
It's a missing bullet.
There were five left in your gun.
If you add these up, 5 and 10 make 15.
Since you aren't in the habit
of loading an extra bullet...
fifteen matches the number you had
to begin with.
Then...
what's this one bullet?
It was neither shot by you
nor recovered later.
Yet it pierced through a soldier's body.
If someone hid the bullet...
it means he's afraid it might reveal
whose gun fired it.
In other words, there was someone else,
a fifth person at the scene.
What do you think of my theory?
Sometimes they set fires on the DMZ
for good visibility.
One night we burned a reed field.
And all the mines blew up like fireworks.
Then, another time...
Was Pvt. Nam with you then, too?
This is the Beretta you had
when you were rescued.
Everyone assumed that this was your gun.
I requested an inquiry
on the serial number.
This gun belongs to Pvt. Nam.
Pvt. Nam said his gun broke
during the rescue and fired only once.
The Beretta M9 is an automatic...
so the slide cocks back after each shot.
It broke right here.
You know all this, right?
You're the weapons expert.
I inspected the gun registered to you
that Pvt. Nam returned.
An antimony-barium reaction
on the gun revealed...
more than just gunpowder.
Bloodstains.
After the first shot,
the slide retracted and then stuck.
And blood from the body
splattered right here.
...and blood splattered right here.
The analysis results matched
with Pvt. Jung's blood sample.
The bloodstains right here...
weren't visible,
and so they weren't wiped off.
Sgt. Lee, have you heard
of the Keeler Polygraph?
Also known as a lie detector.
Yes?
Our people are to protect
our one-of-a-kind Communism...
Diamond Mountain is our mountain.
Our leader...
would give all to our people...
Thank you.
Here's Checkpoint 2.
And this is Checkpoint 3...
What are the coordinates here again?
If we're here...
we're at Checkpoint 3, sir.
Those coordinates aren't on the map.
Are you saying we crossed over?
Give me that.
We're fucked.
Retreat quickly, five o'clock!
Sgt. Hwang!
Lt. Choi!
Help me.
Snow base, snow base. 3-2, 3-2!
3-1, 3-2!
Shit!
I told you not to bring that damn dog,
you stupid shit!
- I didn't bring him!
- You shut up.
I'm stepping on a mine.
We could all die.
Watch out! Careful, there.
Don't come any closer!
One more step, and I'll trip the wire.
Hey!
Hey, shitheads!
You're just gonna leave me here?
You told us to go.
I told not to come closer.
When did I tell you to leave, you fuckers!
Would you save me?
A grown man, crying like a baby...
Sgt. Oh!
What if...
Let's just go.
Okay?
Take it. It's a gift.
- Let's go.
- You, too, puppy.
Watch yourself now.
- About that mine...
- Don't live like that.
- Why?
- Just out to save yourself.
Well, it was just...
Rabbit.
Rabbit!
We got your rabbit's dick over here!
How can we ever let our land
fall under foreign imperialism?
MP
Our Communist party is the greatest.
Our commander is the greatest.
Hey.
Your shadow's over the line.
Watch it.
You writing to Soo-Jung?
Yeah.
I didn't thank you enough
for your help last time.
It was rude of me, brother.
Oh, can I call you brother?
I've always wanted a brother.
After hearing "comrade" all the time...
it's nice to be called brother.
My hobby is baseball.
I was a pitcher in high school.
I'm enjoying the tape you sent me.
Han Dae-Su was hard to take at first,
but I like it now.
Kim Hyun-Shik is good, too.
But don't you have any
female singers down there?
I didn't mean it.
I thought I'd write to him, too, as a joke.
I never thought he'd actually come.
What kind of a crazy fool would...
Goodbye, then.
Wait, I didn't mean for you to go.
You've done a great thing.
After half a century of division...
you have breached our tragic history
of agony and disgrace...
broken the dam to reunify our country.
Comrade Lee Soo-Hyuk, we welcome you.
Sorry.
You got a promotion?
Thanks to me,
you've lived to become sergeant, right?
If I died,
I'd have moved up to staff sergeant.
Imagine if I'd had the guts
to remove my foot?
I'm the one who saved your lives.
You're full of shit.
Move your army out of the way.
Then we can go ahead
and beat those damn Yankees.
Only two years and two months?
Damn, we served for 13 years!
I'm pretty quick with the gun.
I'm bored all the time so I practice a lot.
That water pistol?
Just quit pissing your pants around mines.
Yeah, you're pretty fast.
But have you...
ever shot a man before?
No.
- I have, several times.
- All right.
Okay, I got it. Put it down.
Our comrade's been everywhere...
Africa, the Middle East...
He trained soldiers for 10 years!
You didn't know, did you?
That's right, huh?
Hey, Sgt. Lee.
It's not the speed
that's important in a battle.
Combat skills? No such thing.
It's about how audaciously
you are carrying on in calm.
That's all.
Then, what's a great soldier...
like you doing guarding this post
at your age?
Very calmly, of course...
Hey!
You still have that mine fuse I gave you?
Don't lose it.
Hold onto that
and even bullets will pass you by.
Whoa!
Why do you always go crazy
over American things?
Try it, and you'll see
why Yankee stuff is so great.
Must have been expensive.
It's also good for picking stuff
out of your teeth.
What the hell...
Lay down.
I said lay down!
See?
I told you about this American shit.
What are you doing there
away from your post?
- It's not that, we were...
- You idiot!
You think you're something
'cause you've been abroad?
You think this is a playground?
You're at the very frontline
of our republic! The frontline!
Take that damn dog to the butchers.
- Lunch for tomorrow.
- What?
Our people count on us.
Don't let them down, got it?
Take care of yourself.
Go on.
Watch out for land mines.
Go!
I said go!
Hey!
There's more food on the other side!
That guy's so funny.
- Sgt. Lee.
- Huh?
You're really handsome.
Tell me something I don't know.
Spit it out.
You expect me to read your mind?
Must be nice.
Only three months left to serve.
Nope, 87 days.
I'm worried about the rest of my time here.
You want me to introduce you to
some friends?
Who?
No.
Forget it.
Do I have to go?
What?
After half a century of division.
Overcoming our history
of agony and disgrace...
we're gonna open the dam
to reunification, okay?
Could we maybe open it later?
I've heard a lot about you.
I'm Oh Kyung-Pil.
Hey, Pvt. Nam.
You feel warm.
Feels warm.
- Sgt. Lee.
- Yeah?
Come on.
What's wrong with people
of the same blood...
getting together and playing some games?
Is that such a sin?
I mean, did we commit adultery?
Or give up military secrets?
We don't even know any secrets.
Exactly!
Yes.
- Yes.
- Wow.
Southern army, out of the way!
That's it!
Oh, yeah!
Damn, I told you we should use pebbles!
What's so hard about this?
Wow! It's erect!
Brother.
Payoff time.
My father died young.
So I'm the only man in the house.
Wow.
She's pretty.
Is she really yours?
Don't you have anyone, brother?
Come on, show us!
Holy cow!
What? Don't be ridiculous.
But you remember what
that defected soldier said?
Guards at the border are trained
to draw us to their side.
You're wrong.
He saved my life.
Target US Army every day!
Here we go. One, two, three...
Brother.
Why can't our republic make
a Choco-Pie like this?
Brother!
What?
I was just wondering...
You want to come down to the South?
You can eat Choco-Pie till you burst.
I mean, only if you want to.
Lee Soo-Hyuk.
I'm only going to say this once,
so listen well.
My dream is...
that one day, our republic...
makes the best damn
sweets on this peninsula.
Got it?
Till then, all I can do is...
dream about these Choco-Pie.
Forget it. You've got a fancy mouth.
What? Stop it.
Don't!
Sung-Shik, stop these commie bastards!
You're breaking my balls.
You don't need to rub it.
Just wipe it on with this.
Take them off.
First, shake it well like this.
Then you just spread it on.
This is how you do it. Like this.
Then after it dries, do it again.
Alert! Wake up call!
Emergency!
Hurry up. Stand your post!
Move your asses!
This way!
Get your ass down quick!
What the hell are you waiting for?
Hurry up!
- Supply unit!
- Yes, sir!
At 2:35 a.m...
we obtained word...
that Northern troops are massing
along the entire border.
We're at Defcon 3.
You chicken?
Keep your cool, okay?
Just think of it as shooting off a round.
That's all it is, all right?
Mines
Sung-Shik...
let's not go over anymore.
It'll be Jung's birthday soon.
And you're almost out.
We should at least say goodbye.
After I discharge...
don't ever go there alone.
Got it?
Brother! That day...
was the North really going to attack?
How would I know?
The Yankees were about to bomb us.
We're supposed to just sit there?
So don't make any nuclear arms or missiles.
Do I make them?
Why are you getting angry?
Stop talking about war.
Everyone just write a
letter to your parents.
And one to Soo-Jung, too.
If war really broke out...
would we have to shoot each other, too?
How about we write each
other certificates or something?
"We hereby certify
that Nam Sung-Shik served the republic.
"Signed, Sgt. Oh Kyung-Pil
and Pvt. Jung Woo-Jin."
Something like that.
- Yeah, good idea!
- Right!
What a load of bullshit.
If Yankee bastards play their war games...
border guards will be obliterated.
Zero chance of survival.
Three minutes into the war,
both countries would be destroyed.
A total wasteland. Don't you get it?
I get it now.
Man, this song reminds me of my mom.
Tell me...
why did this singer have to die so young?
Hey!
Let's have a toast...
to singer Kwang-Suk.
Oh Kyung-Pil:
2 Chollima Street, Pyongyang.
Jung Woo-Jin:
3 Yaksan, North Pyongyang Province.
I can't get the right angle.
What?
Oh, nothing.
Squeeze in a little.
Perfect.
Aren't you going?
Yeah.
Let's go.
You idiot.
I taught you how to do it,
and you still screw it up?
No matter what I do,
I can't get it to shine.
Let me see.
A soldier's got to get
it right the first time.
I can't do this for you forever.
Oh, wait.
Happy birthday.
Thank you, comrade.
Brother.
Oh... damn.
You're crying.
I can't help it.
I have something for you guys, too.
Yeah?
Where did it go?
What is it?
What the hell did you eat?
Open the door. Open it!
Yes.
What?
Why does he want to postpone
the cross-examination?
Then tell this to Gen. Pyo.
Whether Pvt. Nam takes a leap...
or Sgt. Lee falls into shock,
it's not my concern.
I don't have time to pamper the suspects.
Understood?
Here are your depositions.
Read it and tell me if you want
to change anything.
Oh! I'm sorry.
This is correct.
Yes.
You recognize this? It's the crime scene.
Lt. Choi Man-Soo.
Sgt. Oh Kyung-Pil.
And Pvt. Jung Woo-Jin.
How many Southern soldiers
attacked the post?
Only one.
Are you sure?
I'm sure.
All right.
This is Sgt. Lee Soo-Hyuk.
Do you recognize him?
A Southern puppet.
What is this?
What is going on here?
This is another soldier presumed
to have been at the scene.
He's in a coma,
so he couldn't make it today.
"Presumed"?
With what evidence?
During his interrogation, when told
he would take a lie-detector test...
Pvt. Nam attempted suicide on the spot.
We have no choice but to consider this
as a confession.
Therefore, I propose we start
the investigation all over again.
We didn't come here to
listen to your stories.
Please, stop!
You son of a bitch!
You capitalist bastard!
You know how long I've waited for this?
- Sergeant!
- Damn puppet!
- You know how long?
- Comrade!
Take your hands off!
I'll show you the power of our republic!
You capitalist pig!
Son of a bitch! Traitor to the people!
- Yankee puppet!
- Sergeant, Kyung-Pil!
Long live the Chosun Labour Party!
Our honoured leader...
long live Supreme Commander Kim Jong-ll!
Goodbye, sir!
Panmungak
Adieu, mademoiselle.
I'm sorry to make you come.
I know you're still ill.
This states my dismissal from
the JSA case from midnight tomorrow.
I heard about your father.
So you heard my father was
a North Korean general?
How does that make you feel?
Like a friend.
I still have a bruise...
but you seem okay.
Your grip must be stronger than Sgt. Oh's.
All right, the real show starts now.
Watch carefully.
As soon as I met Soo-Jung,
I knew I had seen her face before.
And it wasn't hard to figure out
who she was.
This is a picture drawn by Pvt. Jung.
And this...
This picture was found
on Pvt. Jung's body.
If the missing bullet
broke Pvt. Nam's alibi...
then this missing face...
proves that the four soldiers
must have been friends.
So?
These are two completely different reports.
Which one I submit is up to you.
If you tell me the truth...
I won't leave my successor
any of this information.
Is that a threat?
It's a deal, rather.
I don't care whether
I go to jail or get a medal.
So what can you offer me...
if I tell you the truth?
Something you tried to
protect till the end...
Sgt. Oh's safety.
Comrade Choi, please calm down.
- I'll explain everything.
- What is this?
What's going on here?
Please, put the gun down.
You, too, Soo-Hyuk!
You bastard!
I put you on guard and you
screw around with these puppets?
Arrest them now!
They came here to discuss coming up North.
I'll take care of everything.
Jung Woo-Jin, this is a direct order.
These scumbags are our enemies.
Disarm them now.
Shoot them!
I'll take full responsibility. Don't move!
Do what I say now...
and I'll overlook this treasonable act.
Do it now!
Comrade Oh, I'm sorry.
Soo-Hyuk...
put your gun down.
There's no other way.
No.
I'll help you come to the North.
You can live with us in our republic, okay?
All right?
Put the gun down first and we'll talk.
Fuck that!
You know better.
This asshole can't be trusted.
You said it yourself.
He's an ambitious prick.
He'll kill us both
and say we infiltrated enemy territory.
I promise I'll protect you.
You still don't trust me?
Sung-Shik, you trust me. Talk to him.
Could this be a trap?
Soo-Hyuk, brother!
You remember when Comrade Oh
saved you from the mine?
Don't you?
Please put the gun down, okay?
Fuck it!
Fuck this "brother" shit.
We're enemies, after all.
You said I was chicken, right?
Fine, see if I can kill
this bastard or not.
Just watch.
Hey, Soo-Hyuk!
We're all going to die this way.
Let's start over.
Put your guns down together.
You, too, Woo-Jin!
Just put them down.
Down.
Something's not right.
Guard unit, respond! I repeat, respond!
Sung-Shik!
Listen carefully.
Say you were kidnapped and then escaped.
And you were never here. Got it?
Now go. Hurry, there's no time!
Go.
Soo-Hyuk...
Who the hell's that?
He looks like one of ours!
Sung-Shik!
Get down!
Flare bomb!
Soo-Hyuk!
Cover us! You bastards!
Burn them down!
Open the door! Get the door!
So that's how Pvt. Jung
ended up dying on his birthday.
I don't think about the dead.
Do you think you can forgive Pvt. Nam
and Sgt. Lee?
May I have one?
If this had happened at a Southern post...
I would have shot first.
I heard you're being discharged.
How does it feel to leave Panmunjom?
Sgt. Lee is being sent
to Yongsan Hospital today.
Do you have any messages for him?
He's made good use of it.
He said he's going to quit smoking.
You know that missing bullet?
Sgt. Oh threw it into the reservoir
with the cassette player.
I guess I've left a stain on your career.
It doesn't matter.
That's what I chose.
There was one inconsistency
in Sgt. Oh's testimony.
He said Pvt. Nam didn't kill Pvt. Jung.
It was you.
It all happened so quickly...
you must have remembered it wrong.
Or Sgt. Oh made a mistake.
But what does it matter
who shot a second quicker or later?
I hope you get well soon.
Thank you.
Director: PARK Chan-Wook
Producer: LEE Eun
Editor: KIM Sang-Beom
Music: JO Yeong-Wook
Director of Photography: KIM Seong-Bok