[Script Info]
;SrtEdit 6.3.2012.1001
;Copyright(C) 2005-2012 Yuan Weiguo

Title: 
Original Script: 
Original Translation: 
Original Timing: 
Original Editing: 
Script Updated By: 
Update Details: 
ScriptType: v4.00+
Collisions: Normal
PlayResX: 384
PlayResY: 288
Timer: 100.0000
Synch Point: 
WrapStyle: 0
ScaledBorderAndShadow: no

[V4+ Styles]
Format: Name, Fontname, Fontsize, PrimaryColour, SecondaryColour, OutlineColour, BackColour, Bold, Italic, Underline, StrikeOut, ScaleX, ScaleY, Spacing, Angle, BorderStyle, Outline, Shadow, Alignment, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Encoding
Style: Default,Arial,18,&H00FFFFFF,&H0000FFFF,&H00000000,&H00000000,-1,0,0,0,100,100,0,0,1,2,3,2,20,20,0,1

[Events]
Format: Layer, Start, End, Style, Name, MarginL, MarginR, MarginV, Effect, Text
Dialogue: 0,0:00:49.15,0:00:50.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請進
Dialogue: 0,0:00:50.44,0:00:51.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,打擾了
Dialogue: 0,0:00:53.23,0:00:54.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請坐
Dialogue: 0,0:00:57.48,0:01:01.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請說你的名字和年齡和生日
Dialogue: 0,0:01:02.98,0:01:04.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我叫野野宮慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:01:04.64,0:01:05.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今年六歲
Dialogue: 0,0:01:06.10,0:01:09.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,生日是7月28日
Dialogue: 0,0:01:10.81,0:01:15.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多像爸爸還是媽媽？
Dialogue: 0,0:01:15.77,0:01:20.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他待人溫和有禮的地方像我太太
Dialogue: 0,0:01:20.89,0:01:23.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他的缺點是什麼？
Dialogue: 0,0:01:24.60,0:01:27.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,缺點跟優點差不多
Dialogue: 0,0:01:27.18,0:01:32.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,個性太溫和，輸了也不會計較
Dialogue: 0,0:01:32.31,0:01:35.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,身為父親我希望他能更有骨氣
Dialogue: 0,0:01:36.14,0:01:38.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多喜歡的季節是？
Dialogue: 0,0:01:39.06,0:01:40.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,夏天
Dialogue: 0,0:01:41.06,0:01:43.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你今年夏天做了什麼事？
Dialogue: 0,0:01:44.56,0:01:49.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我跟爸爸去露營，放了風箏
Dialogue: 0,0:01:50.31,0:01:53.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸很會放風箏嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:01:53.77,0:01:55.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,非常厲害
Dialogue: 0,0:02:58.68,0:03:03.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,片名：我的意外爸爸\N（三區台版官方字幕）
Dialogue: 0,0:03:10.35,0:03:11.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,變很多嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:13.85,0:03:15.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,感覺賺了很多錢
Dialogue: 0,0:03:16.64,0:03:18.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前操場沒有那種燈
Dialogue: 0,0:03:19.43,0:03:20.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小聲點啦…
Dialogue: 0,0:03:27.64,0:03:28.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回來了
Dialogue: 0,0:03:28.97,0:03:30.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你回來啦
Dialogue: 0,0:03:31.09,0:03:34.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,各位家長，參觀日到此為止
Dialogue: 0,0:03:35.01,0:03:36.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,回家路上請小心
Dialogue: 0,0:03:37.26,0:03:38.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝老師
Dialogue: 0,0:03:40.22,0:03:41.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,開心嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:44.64,0:03:45.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:03:48.18,0:03:51.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你沒有跟爸爸去露過營吧
Dialogue: 0,0:03:51.64,0:03:53.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼要那樣回答？
Dialogue: 0,0:03:53.22,0:03:55.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,補習班老師教的
Dialogue: 0,0:03:57.30,0:04:00.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,升學補習班真有一套
Dialogue: 0,0:04:00.43,0:04:03.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最喜歡媽媽做的愛心蛋包飯也講了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:07.80,0:04:08.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,開心嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:08.55,0:04:09.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:04:10.80,0:04:12.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你做了氣球？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:13.22,0:04:14.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可愛的怪物
Dialogue: 0,0:04:14.63,0:04:16.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你做了可愛怪物？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:37.38,0:04:38.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被你發現了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:38.72,0:04:40.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真難得看到你加班
Dialogue: 0,0:04:40.72,0:04:43.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我本來想趁你來之前回去
Dialogue: 0,0:04:45.13,0:04:47.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這個CG做的很好
Dialogue: 0,0:04:47.84,0:04:49.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,被退了3次貨
Dialogue: 0,0:04:50.92,0:04:52.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你可以的
Dialogue: 0,0:04:52.42,0:04:54.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不打擾你了
Dialogue: 0,0:04:54.63,0:04:58.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我一下就好，要不要去喝一杯？
Dialogue: 0,0:04:58.42,0:05:01.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉，我跟老婆要去銀座看電影
Dialogue: 0,0:05:01.67,0:05:03.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一旦有了優秀的下屬
Dialogue: 0,0:05:03.46,0:05:06.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,主管就忙著應付家人
Dialogue: 0,0:05:06.96,0:05:07.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,加油囉
Dialogue: 0,0:05:08.05,0:05:09.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,辛苦了
Dialogue: 0,0:05:10.30,0:05:12.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這邊是南，這邊就是北
Dialogue: 0,0:05:12.76,0:05:15.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對，太陽從這邊來
Dialogue: 0,0:05:15.63,0:05:18.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,公園上多加一點親子互動
Dialogue: 0,0:05:18.59,0:05:19.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還有遛狗的？
Dialogue: 0,0:05:19.46,0:05:20.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這不錯
Dialogue: 0,0:05:20.46,0:05:21.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多一點居家溫馨感
Dialogue: 0,0:05:21.96,0:05:23.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,各位
Dialogue: 0,0:05:23.63,0:05:26.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天老大請客，想吃什麼？
Dialogue: 0,0:05:28.25,0:05:31.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,披薩或蓋飯？
Dialogue: 0,0:05:35.29,0:05:38.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我認為公立的也可以
Dialogue: 0,0:05:38.88,0:05:42.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是良多說寧願現在努力\N也不要將來吃苦
Dialogue: 0,0:05:47.59,0:05:48.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有電話，下次再聊
Dialogue: 0,0:05:49.13,0:05:50.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:05:50.21,0:05:53.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯，下次再商量婆婆的事
Dialogue: 0,0:05:53.46,0:05:55.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 喂？    - 好，再見
Dialogue: 0,0:05:58.67,0:06:00.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸問你晚餐吃什麼
Dialogue: 0,0:06:33.63,0:06:35.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我以為你會忙到更晚
Dialogue: 0,0:06:39.79,0:06:41.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,練過鋼琴了嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:06:41.58,0:06:44.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,剛考完入學考，今天放鬆一下
Dialogue: 0,0:06:45.17,0:06:46.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你太放縱他了
Dialogue: 0,0:06:47.04,0:06:48.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這種東西停一下就要…
Dialogue: 0,0:06:48.63,0:06:51.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,花三天才能補回來
Dialogue: 0,0:06:53.37,0:06:54.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:06:55.79,0:06:56.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來練鋼琴
Dialogue: 0,0:06:56.79,0:06:57.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:06:58.62,0:07:00.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來，好了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:00.29,0:07:01.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,加油喔
Dialogue: 0,0:07:05.62,0:07:08.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你吃過飯了吧，洗澡水燒好了
Dialogue: 0,0:07:08.91,0:07:10.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只吃了一塊披薩
Dialogue: 0,0:07:10.83,0:07:13.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不早點傳訊跟我說
Dialogue: 0,0:07:13.79,0:07:14.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有吃的嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:07:16.54,0:07:18.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以簡單做個烏龍麵
Dialogue: 0,0:07:19.04,0:07:21.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,三村先生從香川寄來的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:22.25,0:07:24.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就你幫我煮一碗
Dialogue: 0,0:07:24.37,0:07:26.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我麵條要硬一點的
Dialogue: 0,0:07:27.21,0:07:29.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不會再煮爛了啦
Dialogue: 0,0:07:31.87,0:07:35.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚上不能加雞蛋，膽固醇太高
Dialogue: 0,0:07:35.33,0:07:38.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一顆又不會怎樣，慶多你評評理
Dialogue: 0,0:07:38.58,0:07:39.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不行！
Dialogue: 0,0:07:42.12,0:07:44.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼不行？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:06.95,0:08:09.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再彈一次，來
Dialogue: 0,0:08:21.20,0:08:24.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道三村先生適應新工作了沒
Dialogue: 0,0:08:25.45,0:08:26.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還可以吧
Dialogue: 0,0:08:27.33,0:08:29.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他本來就適合待在鄉下
Dialogue: 0,0:08:29.99,0:08:33.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好無情喔，虧你以前那麼疼他
Dialogue: 0,0:08:33.91,0:08:37.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我哪來的時間去擔心放棄的人
Dialogue: 0,0:08:39.03,0:08:42.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,放棄又礙到你了喔
Dialogue: 0,0:08:44.12,0:08:45.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他睡了？
Dialogue: 0,0:08:45.16,0:08:49.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯，緊張過頭容易累
Dialogue: 0,0:08:50.20,0:08:52.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們已經盡力幫忙了
Dialogue: 0,0:08:52.28,0:08:54.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,接著全看慶多自己的努力
Dialogue: 0,0:08:54.87,0:08:58.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他很努力，還說想像爸爸一樣
Dialogue: 0,0:09:01.91,0:09:03.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他最近越來越堅強了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:04.20,0:09:05.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:09:05.95,0:09:08.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像也敢開口拒絕大地了
Dialogue: 0,0:09:10.70,0:09:12.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就好
Dialogue: 0,0:09:13.82,0:09:16.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,現在太溫和是會被欺負的
Dialogue: 0,0:09:16.78,0:09:19.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在面試時明明說這是優點
Dialogue: 0,0:09:19.62,0:09:21.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,偶爾多誇獎他一下
Dialogue: 0,0:09:21.24,0:09:23.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,總不能沒人當黑臉
Dialogue: 0,0:09:28.78,0:09:29.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,咚咚
Dialogue: 0,0:09:39.70,0:09:41.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝你抽空過來
Dialogue: 0,0:09:42.37,0:09:44.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多也很高興
Dialogue: 0,0:09:45.45,0:09:48.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我希望至少週日能陪你們
Dialogue: 0,0:09:51.28,0:09:54.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這個案子忙完會比較有空
Dialogue: 0,0:09:55.57,0:09:59.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你這句話已經說了六年
Dialogue: 0,0:10:00.61,0:10:01.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:01.74,0:10:03.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的
Dialogue: 0,0:10:05.74,0:10:09.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對了，今天前橋醫院打電話來
Dialogue: 0,0:10:10.61,0:10:11.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,醫院？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:12.78,0:10:14.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多出生的那間醫院
Dialogue: 0,0:10:15.07,0:10:17.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有事嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:17.74,0:10:21.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像有事要告訴我們
Dialogue: 0,0:10:21.28,0:10:22.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什麼事？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:22.78,0:10:24.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他們希望見面談
Dialogue: 0,0:10:26.74,0:10:28.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,會是什麼事？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:31.86,0:10:34.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,希望不是什麼麻煩事
Dialogue: 0,0:10:48.61,0:10:50.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱錯嬰兒？
Dialogue: 0,0:10:51.11,0:10:53.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是我們出生那年代才有的事
Dialogue: 0,0:10:53.78,0:10:54.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對
Dialogue: 0,0:10:55.36,0:10:58.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大多數發生在60年代
Dialogue: 0,0:10:58.65,0:11:02.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,本院也記取當年的教訓
Dialogue: 0,0:11:02.28,0:11:05.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,從1969年開始取消了
Dialogue: 0,0:11:05.48,0:11:08.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在嬰兒腳底用魔術筆寫名字
Dialogue: 0,0:11:09.82,0:11:12.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼現代會發生這種事？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:13.11,0:11:18.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對方家的男孩子他…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:18.57,0:11:23.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是的，他上小學的健康檢查
Dialogue: 0,0:11:23.28,0:11:25.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,發現血型與雙親不合
Dialogue: 0,0:11:25.48,0:11:28.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們家沒有血型的問題，對吧？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:30.19,0:11:31.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們確定弄錯了嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:33.61,0:11:37.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多真的不是我們的孩子嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:11:38.52,0:11:42.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,同時間有三個孩子出生
Dialogue: 0,0:11:43.94,0:11:48.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們想檢驗各自的DNA
Dialogue: 0,0:11:48.90,0:11:50.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然後再評斷…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:53.40,0:11:53.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還有兩根…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:53.52,0:11:55.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（恭喜慶多考上小學）\N還有兩根…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:55.36,0:11:55.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（恭喜慶多考上小學）
Dialogue: 0,0:11:55.48,0:11:59.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（恭喜慶多考上小學）\N最後一根…
Dialogue: 0,0:11:59.94,0:12:00.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（恭喜慶多考上小學）
Dialogue: 0,0:12:00.94,0:12:02.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,預備
Dialogue: 0,0:12:02.56,0:12:06.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,恭喜慶多考上小學
Dialogue: 0,0:12:07.44,0:12:08.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,吹吧
Dialogue: 0,0:12:08.23,0:12:09.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快點
Dialogue: 0,0:12:11.77,0:12:12.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好棒
Dialogue: 0,0:12:12.65,0:12:13.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真厲害
Dialogue: 0,0:12:14.77,0:12:16.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,番茄好好吃
Dialogue: 0,0:12:16.61,0:12:17.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吃嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:19.73,0:12:22.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真乖，多吃點
Dialogue: 0,0:12:23.27,0:12:26.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還有炸蝦
Dialogue: 0,0:12:28.31,0:12:29.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拍到沒？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:29.94,0:12:30.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拍到了嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:31.02,0:12:32.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拍得很棒
Dialogue: 0,0:12:32.65,0:12:34.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好厲害
Dialogue: 0,0:12:34.56,0:12:35.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,笑一個
Dialogue: 0,0:12:38.06,0:12:39.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好了
Dialogue: 0,0:12:39.81,0:12:40.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要看嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:40.31,0:12:41.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如何？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:41.52,0:12:42.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是按這個沒錯吧？
Dialogue: 0,0:12:45.19,0:12:47.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,按這裡會跳回去
Dialogue: 0,0:12:47.48,0:12:49.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的，那再拍一次
Dialogue: 0,0:12:50.81,0:12:52.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要按這裡
Dialogue: 0,0:13:02.77,0:13:04.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相親相愛
Dialogue: 0,0:13:05.64,0:13:07.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相親相愛
Dialogue: 0,0:13:07.69,0:13:09.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相親相愛
Dialogue: 0,0:13:14.85,0:13:16.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相親相愛
Dialogue: 0,0:13:53.47,0:13:54.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嘴巴張開
Dialogue: 0,0:14:12.18,0:14:15.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,資料1野野宮良多
Dialogue: 0,0:14:16.51,0:14:19.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,資料2野野宮綠
Dialogue: 0,0:14:20.93,0:14:23.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,與資料3的野野宮慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:14:24.47,0:14:26.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在生物學上並無親子關係
Dialogue: 0,0:14:26.81,0:14:30.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鑑定結果如上
Dialogue: 0,0:14:47.76,0:14:49.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是這樣啊
Dialogue: 0,0:15:13.43,0:15:15.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我早就說過了
Dialogue: 0,0:15:15.76,0:15:17.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鄉下的醫院不可靠
Dialogue: 0,0:15:17.93,0:15:19.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我自己是在那邊生的
Dialogue: 0,0:15:20.51,0:15:21.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我家哥哥姊姊也是
Dialogue: 0,0:15:21.47,0:15:22.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那又怎樣
Dialogue: 0,0:15:22.89,0:15:27.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你工作那麼忙，我又容易緊張
Dialogue: 0,0:15:27.68,0:15:29.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,才想找我媽方便去的地點
Dialogue: 0,0:15:35.34,0:15:37.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我怎麼都沒注意到呢
Dialogue: 0,0:15:40.55,0:15:42.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,明明我是母親…
Dialogue: 0,0:16:20.72,0:16:22.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請進
Dialogue: 0,0:16:22.76,0:16:23.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們遲到了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:23.97,0:16:26.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,昨天就叫你先去加油
Dialogue: 0,0:16:27.42,0:16:28.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他們來了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:29.22,0:16:32.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起，讓你們久等了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:32.42,0:16:38.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,都怪她出門前還在嫌毛衣不好看
Dialogue: 0,0:16:38.97,0:16:39.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們好
Dialogue: 0,0:16:40.09,0:16:41.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是齋木先生
Dialogue: 0,0:16:41.92,0:16:42.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好
Dialogue: 0,0:16:43.38,0:16:47.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這件事太令人意外了
Dialogue: 0,0:16:47.92,0:16:50.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是他太太，我叫由加里
Dialogue: 0,0:16:50.42,0:16:52.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 這位是…    - 我姓野野宮
Dialogue: 0,0:16:52.42,0:16:54.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,內人，野野宮綠
Dialogue: 0,0:16:57.38,0:16:58.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他叫琉晴
Dialogue: 0,0:16:59.09,0:17:00.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他叫慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:17:01.67,0:17:05.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是今年夏天去遊樂園的照片
Dialogue: 0,0:17:06.13,0:17:08.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒有更清楚一點的嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:15.30,0:17:16.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這張呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:17.17,0:17:17.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這張是哪裡？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:18.09,0:17:19.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,烏川
Dialogue: 0,0:17:19.92,0:17:24.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對，溪裡有好多鱒魚
Dialogue: 0,0:17:28.13,0:17:30.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們看
Dialogue: 0,0:17:30.30,0:17:34.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,正中間拿水槍的是琉晴
Dialogue: 0,0:17:42.54,0:17:43.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他的生日是？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:45.42,0:17:47.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,7月28日
Dialogue: 0,0:17:48.25,0:17:49.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是同一天
Dialogue: 0,0:17:51.29,0:17:54.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們在這裡有見過嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:17:55.38,0:17:57.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我產後身體狀況不好
Dialogue: 0,0:17:58.09,0:17:59.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一直昏睡靜養
Dialogue: 0,0:18:01.34,0:18:04.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那一天天氣很好
Dialogue: 0,0:18:04.92,0:18:08.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我跟她說好像沖繩的夏天
Dialogue: 0,0:18:08.25,0:18:13.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以取名琉晴，琉球的晴天
Dialogue: 0,0:18:14.25,0:18:17.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,通常這種狀況到最後
Dialogue: 0,0:18:18.13,0:18:22.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,雙方100％會選擇交換孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:18:23.00,0:18:24.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為了孩子的未來著想
Dialogue: 0,0:18:25.08,0:18:27.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,建議各位及早做決定
Dialogue: 0,0:18:28.25,0:18:30.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最好能在上小學之前
Dialogue: 0,0:18:30.33,0:18:32.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這也太突然了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:32.37,0:18:35.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還有半年就是四月要開學了
Dialogue: 0,0:18:36.92,0:18:39.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,又不是小貓小狗
Dialogue: 0,0:18:39.12,0:18:40.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,貓狗也不能這樣
Dialogue: 0,0:18:42.71,0:18:43.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也對
Dialogue: 0,0:18:45.12,0:18:48.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,連寵物都沒人會交換
Dialogue: 0,0:18:49.33,0:18:53.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在談這件事之前
Dialogue: 0,0:18:53.92,0:18:57.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們難道不該表示什麼嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:18:57.41,0:19:02.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有的，正在跟律師討論賠償事宜
Dialogue: 0,0:19:02.92,0:19:07.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,身為孩子的父母，想必很難接受
Dialogue: 0,0:19:08.04,0:19:13.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過請務必優先考量孩子的未來
Dialogue: 0,0:19:23.96,0:19:26.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們兩家要不要辦一次聚會？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:26.83,0:19:28.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,說得也是
Dialogue: 0,0:19:28.33,0:19:30.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也想見見慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:19:31.08,0:19:32.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就保持連絡
Dialogue: 0,0:19:48.75,0:19:50.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等你好久了
Dialogue: 0,0:19:50.24,0:19:51.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起
Dialogue: 0,0:19:51.33,0:19:52.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒關係
Dialogue: 0,0:19:53.20,0:19:56.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如何？對方人好嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:19:56.16,0:19:58.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他是水電工
Dialogue: 0,0:19:58.16,0:19:59.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是喔
Dialogue: 0,0:19:59.37,0:20:00.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對
Dialogue: 0,0:20:00.41,0:20:01.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,進來吧
Dialogue: 0,0:20:02.08,0:20:05.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽，剛才忘記先給你了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:05.29,0:20:08.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝，這不是和果子嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:20:08.74,0:20:10.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,重量感覺是羊羹
Dialogue: 0,0:20:10.54,0:20:12.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 猜對了    - 媽你好丟臉
Dialogue: 0,0:20:13.08,0:20:14.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,羊羹有什麼好嗨的
Dialogue: 0,0:20:14.83,0:20:17.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你這樣講羊羹會生氣喔
Dialogue: 0,0:20:17.87,0:20:18.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:20:18.70,0:20:20.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他睡了
Dialogue: 0,0:20:20.29,0:20:22.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,剛才一直在玩Wii
Dialogue: 0,0:20:22.58,0:20:24.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我看我明天會肌肉痠痛
Dialogue: 0,0:21:16.99,0:21:18.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我現在才敢說
Dialogue: 0,0:21:20.95,0:21:26.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,隔壁的山下太太剛看到慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:21:27.78,0:21:29.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就說過他跟你們兩個不像
Dialogue: 0,0:21:30.28,0:21:37.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我記得是…前年的時候
Dialogue: 0,0:21:46.28,0:21:54.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,良多跟我們家調性不太合
Dialogue: 0,0:21:55.28,0:22:00.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外面有很多看不順眼你們的人
Dialogue: 0,0:22:00.90,0:22:04.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以才會招來…
Dialogue: 0,0:22:04.40,0:22:05.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別講了
Dialogue: 0,0:22:06.07,0:22:09.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們又不是做壞事被陷害的
Dialogue: 0,0:22:10.49,0:22:12.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,秀秀…
Dialogue: 0,0:22:21.36,0:22:25.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們很榮幸在此介紹\N新宿車站西口重劃的重點
Dialogue: 0,0:22:25.61,0:22:29.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,新宿螺旋塔的提案內容
Dialogue: 0,0:22:34.36,0:22:36.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是天外飛來的災難
Dialogue: 0,0:22:37.74,0:22:41.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我會小心不影響到工作的
Dialogue: 0,0:22:41.53,0:22:43.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你自己想怎麼做？
Dialogue: 0,0:22:44.57,0:22:45.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,交換嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:22:47.57,0:22:50.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我還沒想好
Dialogue: 0,0:22:52.82,0:22:55.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,乾脆兩個都收下吧
Dialogue: 0,0:22:58.32,0:22:59.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,收養兩個？
Dialogue: 0,0:23:03.07,0:23:04.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這主意不錯吧
Dialogue: 0,0:23:20.36,0:23:21.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎麼了？
Dialogue: 0,0:23:22.23,0:23:24.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不想見親生兒子嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:23:24.52,0:23:31.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不，我怕事情會像醫院預言的
Dialogue: 0,0:23:31.23,0:23:34.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不用怕，放心交給我辦
Dialogue: 0,0:23:43.90,0:23:44.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思
Dialogue: 0,0:23:45.31,0:23:50.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我老婆出門又拖拖拉拉
Dialogue: 0,0:23:50.61,0:23:53.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好，我是齋木琉晴
Dialogue: 0,0:23:53.15,0:23:54.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是大和
Dialogue: 0,0:23:54.90,0:23:56.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是美結
Dialogue: 0,0:23:57.81,0:23:58.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你也自我介紹啊
Dialogue: 0,0:23:58.81,0:24:01.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們好，我是野野宮慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:24:01.73,0:24:02.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好
Dialogue: 0,0:24:03.61,0:24:06.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,久等了，這是飲料的部份
Dialogue: 0,0:24:07.10,0:24:09.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,餐點請等候三號叫號
Dialogue: 0,0:24:09.98,0:24:10.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝
Dialogue: 0,0:24:10.56,0:24:11.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小琉！
Dialogue: 0,0:24:12.44,0:24:14.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天吃得比平常好
Dialogue: 0,0:24:16.52,0:24:19.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,總共是6030圓
Dialogue: 0,0:24:19.35,0:24:20.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我來
Dialogue: 0,0:24:20.40,0:24:22.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 沒關係    - 不行不行
Dialogue: 0,0:24:23.19,0:24:23.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,給我收據
Dialogue: 0,0:24:24.02,0:24:25.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:26.06,0:24:29.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請開前橋中央綜合病院
Dialogue: 0,0:24:29.40,0:24:30.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的
Dialogue: 0,0:24:32.10,0:24:32.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這也一起
Dialogue: 0,0:24:32.60,0:24:34.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝
Dialogue: 0,0:24:43.94,0:24:46.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你太會吃了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:25:01.69,0:25:03.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我吃飽了
Dialogue: 0,0:25:05.98,0:25:07.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們去玩吧
Dialogue: 0,0:25:08.06,0:25:10.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也要去玩
Dialogue: 0,0:25:11.23,0:25:12.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去吧
Dialogue: 0,0:25:14.69,0:25:16.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 美結，帶大和一起去    - 小琉
Dialogue: 0,0:25:17.06,0:25:18.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看好美結和大和
Dialogue: 0,0:25:34.85,0:25:36.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小孩子長真快
Dialogue: 0,0:25:39.93,0:25:45.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,話說我們能拿到多少賠償金？
Dialogue: 0,0:25:48.22,0:25:52.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這件事的起因比錢重要吧？
Dialogue: 0,0:25:52.43,0:25:55.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,當然，我也很在意起因
Dialogue: 0,0:25:56.06,0:25:59.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過醫院如果要表示誠意
Dialogue: 0,0:26:00.06,0:26:02.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還是避不了要談錢吧
Dialogue: 0,0:26:02.39,0:26:04.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒錯，避不了的
Dialogue: 0,0:26:04.68,0:26:07.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們有認識的律師嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:26:11.89,0:26:15.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那這件事就交給我辦吧
Dialogue: 0,0:26:15.81,0:26:18.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我有個要好的大學同學是律師
Dialogue: 0,0:26:20.22,0:26:21.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就麻煩你了
Dialogue: 0,0:26:23.64,0:26:25.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,0:26:44.05,0:26:45.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我去打個電話
Dialogue: 0,0:26:55.76,0:26:56.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,脖子好痛
Dialogue: 0,0:27:00.35,0:27:01.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的天啊
Dialogue: 0,0:27:06.76,0:27:10.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只有他不像我們
Dialogue: 0,0:27:12.80,0:27:16.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,朋友故意開玩笑說我紅杏出牆
Dialogue: 0,0:27:17.39,0:27:19.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我還氣他嘴巴太壞了
Dialogue: 0,0:27:21.89,0:27:24.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒想到是這樣
Dialogue: 0,0:27:38.38,0:27:41.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，拜拜，再見
Dialogue: 0,0:27:53.22,0:27:53.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是什麼？
Dialogue: 0,0:27:54.84,0:27:55.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,由加里的電話
Dialogue: 0,0:27:55.93,0:27:57.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她說有事可以找她商量
Dialogue: 0,0:28:00.43,0:28:02.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,商量什麼啊
Dialogue: 0,0:28:03.09,0:28:05.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她憑什麼一付長輩的樣子
Dialogue: 0,0:28:06.26,0:28:07.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他們才需要幫忙吧
Dialogue: 0,0:28:08.09,0:28:10.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們說不定需要打一仗了
Dialogue: 0,0:28:11.67,0:28:12.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,打仗？
Dialogue: 0,0:28:17.34,0:28:21.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉，地院臨時召開記者會
Dialogue: 0,0:28:21.26,0:28:22.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我才抱歉讓你抽空來
Dialogue: 0,0:28:22.92,0:28:25.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,目前交涉的進度很順利
Dialogue: 0,0:28:25.30,0:28:26.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,萬事拜託了
Dialogue: 0,0:28:26.46,0:28:28.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比起金額我更在意起因
Dialogue: 0,0:28:29.05,0:28:31.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過對方請的是鄉下律師
Dialogue: 0,0:28:31.51,0:28:34.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,平常光處理債務糾紛
Dialogue: 0,0:28:34.17,0:28:35.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我跟他有點難溝通
Dialogue: 0,0:28:35.92,0:28:37.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,辛苦你了
Dialogue: 0,0:28:38.63,0:28:39.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,吃個東西
Dialogue: 0,0:28:42.05,0:28:45.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想找你討論的不是官司
Dialogue: 0,0:28:46.01,0:28:49.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想瞭解有沒有方法\N可以同時領養兩個小孩
Dialogue: 0,0:28:51.80,0:28:53.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你真敢想
Dialogue: 0,0:28:55.05,0:28:57.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你當得了那孩子的父親嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:28:57.96,0:28:59.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想先帶他進家門
Dialogue: 0,0:28:59.92,0:29:02.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,畢竟是親生骨肉，感情可以慢慢培養
Dialogue: 0,0:29:02.46,0:29:05.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什麼親生骨肉，你的作風真老派
Dialogue: 0,0:29:05.71,0:29:06.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老不老派不是重點
Dialogue: 0,0:29:07.00,0:29:09.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,身為人父就是這樣
Dialogue: 0,0:29:09.30,0:29:11.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以我才說老派啊
Dialogue: 0,0:29:11.17,0:29:13.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我記得你以前就是個爸寶
Dialogue: 0,0:29:13.88,0:29:15.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要亂講
Dialogue: 0,0:29:17.42,0:29:21.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這份資料上說在英國
Dialogue: 0,0:29:22.05,0:29:25.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,若是公家判斷該戶無撫養資格
Dialogue: 0,0:29:26.09,0:29:29.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可褫奪親權，將小孩送到收容所
Dialogue: 0,0:29:30.00,0:29:34.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,案例是家人嗑藥或母親在家賣春
Dialogue: 0,0:29:35.92,0:29:37.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他家母親愛破口大罵
Dialogue: 0,0:29:37.29,0:29:39.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父親感覺無所事事
Dialogue: 0,0:29:40.05,0:29:43.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那種程度不構成家暴的條件
Dialogue: 0,0:29:43.38,0:29:45.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,親權比你想像中強勢
Dialogue: 0,0:29:45.21,0:29:49.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我願意支付相當的酬勞\N只要對方點頭
Dialogue: 0,0:29:49.46,0:29:51.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對方不會點頭吧
Dialogue: 0,0:29:51.71,0:29:53.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,先提案看看沒有差吧
Dialogue: 0,0:29:56.33,0:29:58.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你還是一樣強硬
Dialogue: 0,0:30:00.83,0:30:06.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我身為律師會在官司上\N與你合作無間並肩作戰的
Dialogue: 0,0:30:19.50,0:30:22.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,各位覺得呢，已經見四次了
Dialogue: 0,0:30:23.75,0:30:29.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,差不多該進展到過夜了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:30:30.54,0:30:33.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小孩適應環境很快的
Dialogue: 0,0:30:35.04,0:30:37.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我樂見進展到那一步
Dialogue: 0,0:30:39.00,0:30:41.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,畢竟相處跟官司不能混為一談
Dialogue: 0,0:30:41.50,0:30:42.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你說得沒錯
Dialogue: 0,0:30:44.37,0:30:49.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,齋木先生，你認為呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:30:50.83,0:30:56.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過這樣見面也很快樂啊
Dialogue: 0,0:30:58.17,0:31:00.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,第四次又怎樣
Dialogue: 0,0:31:00.54,0:31:02.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你這種說法，我覺得很有問題
Dialogue: 0,0:31:02.62,0:31:05.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,的確聽起來不太舒服
Dialogue: 0,0:31:06.21,0:31:08.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,說不定事情會進展得很順利
Dialogue: 0,0:31:09.08,0:31:11.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,畢竟你們之間有血脈相連
Dialogue: 0,0:31:12.79,0:31:16.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,親子關係會舒緩現在的抗拒吧
Dialogue: 0,0:31:16.45,0:31:18.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們還有大和和美結
Dialogue: 0,0:31:18.87,0:31:20.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不想太急著解決問題
Dialogue: 0,0:31:21.25,0:31:23.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒錯，我們不急
Dialogue: 0,0:31:25.45,0:31:27.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,野野宮先生呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:31:29.41,0:31:33.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,先從週末開始試試看如何？
Dialogue: 0,0:31:33.41,0:31:35.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比如說週六交換過一晚
Dialogue: 0,0:31:41.95,0:31:44.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大人在講話，你過去那邊玩
Dialogue: 0,0:32:34.70,0:32:37.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，彈鋼琴開心嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:32:40.37,0:32:42.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不開心不用勉強
Dialogue: 0,0:32:42.83,0:32:45.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可是爸爸會稱讚我
Dialogue: 0,0:32:48.16,0:32:50.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那就努力練習吧
Dialogue: 0,0:32:50.20,0:32:51.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之後還有發表會
Dialogue: 0,0:32:51.32,0:32:52.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:32:52.95,0:32:54.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,加油
Dialogue: 0,0:33:09.91,0:33:12.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,糟糕，爸爸好弱
Dialogue: 0,0:33:13.24,0:33:15.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太好了，我贏了
Dialogue: 0,0:33:17.87,0:33:19.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他對蒿麥沒有過敏
Dialogue: 0,0:33:23.20,0:33:25.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我還沒讓他吃過生魚
Dialogue: 0,0:33:26.86,0:33:32.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，你明天早上十點要出發
Dialogue: 0,0:33:34.82,0:33:36.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然後就留在那邊…
Dialogue: 0,0:33:36.53,0:33:37.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,白色
Dialogue: 0,0:33:38.86,0:33:43.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,週六晚上留在琉晴家過夜
Dialogue: 0,0:33:43.20,0:33:44.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:33:44.91,0:33:45.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:33:45.70,0:33:46.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:33:47.65,0:33:54.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是訓練你變強的任務
Dialogue: 0,0:33:58.03,0:33:59.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是任務，懂嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:33:59.95,0:34:00.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:34:00.86,0:34:02.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的？
Dialogue: 0,0:34:02.78,0:34:09.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是慶多變強變壯的大作戰
Dialogue: 0,0:34:44.07,0:34:47.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這也太…
Dialogue: 0,0:34:53.86,0:34:56.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 早安    - 你們好
Dialogue: 0,0:34:57.15,0:34:58.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,早安
Dialogue: 0,0:34:58.44,0:35:00.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,麻煩你們了
Dialogue: 0,0:35:07.40,0:35:08.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴坐後面
Dialogue: 0,0:35:53.90,0:35:54.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的天哪
Dialogue: 0,0:36:05.11,0:36:06.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,忠次？
Dialogue: 0,0:36:25.52,0:36:30.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，你知道蜘蛛人是蜘蛛嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:36:37.60,0:36:39.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大哥，好冷呀
Dialogue: 0,0:36:39.48,0:36:41.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老鍋，最近好嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:36:42.19,0:36:43.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很好
Dialogue: 0,0:36:43.27,0:36:44.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想買廁所的燈泡
Dialogue: 0,0:36:44.19,0:36:48.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,廁所嗎，那60瓦就夠了
Dialogue: 0,0:36:48.56,0:36:50.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，把門關上，會冷
Dialogue: 0,0:36:52.02,0:36:54.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還是你要買LED的？
Dialogue: 0,0:36:54.64,0:36:57.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,燈太亮會害我尿不出來
Dialogue: 0,0:36:59.52,0:37:02.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那你用40瓦的就好，190圓
Dialogue: 0,0:37:05.14,0:37:08.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你下週日早上六點有空嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:37:08.73,0:37:10.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,又要打棒球？
Dialogue: 0,0:37:11.14,0:37:13.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你都幾歲了還真硬朗
Dialogue: 0,0:37:13.14,0:37:14.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我可以讓你當投手
Dialogue: 0,0:37:14.98,0:37:15.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我打不動了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:15.85,0:37:18.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,五十肩提早來找我報到了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:18.31,0:37:19.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你看，手抬不起來
Dialogue: 0,0:37:20.02,0:37:22.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你才幾歲
Dialogue: 0,0:37:22.27,0:37:23.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你自己加油
Dialogue: 0,0:37:23.98,0:37:24.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再見
Dialogue: 0,0:37:24.89,0:37:25.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝啦
Dialogue: 0,0:37:29.52,0:37:30.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,煎餃嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:37:30.98,0:37:32.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是煎餃喔
Dialogue: 0,0:37:32.43,0:37:43.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,3，4，5，6，7，8，9，10
Dialogue: 0,0:37:44.56,0:37:48.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 11，12    - 好香喔
Dialogue: 0,0:37:48.31,0:37:53.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,13，14，15
Dialogue: 0,0:37:53.18,0:37:54.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,煎餃好香
Dialogue: 0,0:37:54.97,0:37:56.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,煎餃來了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:56.18,0:37:57.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,久等了
Dialogue: 0,0:37:58.22,0:38:00.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,開動！
Dialogue: 0,0:38:03.68,0:38:04.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,餓死了
Dialogue: 0,0:38:05.89,0:38:07.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好好吃
Dialogue: 0,0:38:10.06,0:38:11.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,噎到了
Dialogue: 0,0:38:12.22,0:38:14.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不快吃會被搶光喔
Dialogue: 0,0:38:16.06,0:38:17.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,剛出爐的最好吃了
Dialogue: 0,0:38:19.26,0:38:20.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吃
Dialogue: 0,0:38:27.89,0:38:31.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸只能吃一顆蛋
Dialogue: 0,0:38:32.93,0:38:35.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,壽喜燒哪有人只吃一顆的
Dialogue: 0,0:38:35.76,0:38:36.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不對？
Dialogue: 0,0:38:43.05,0:38:44.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 吃慢一點    - 好吃嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:38:45.39,0:38:47.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太燙了，還沒吃下去
Dialogue: 0,0:38:59.72,0:39:00.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好吃
Dialogue: 0,0:39:00.84,0:39:02.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 好好吃    - 好吃嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:39:02.72,0:39:03.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太好了
Dialogue: 0,0:39:04.39,0:39:07.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴，你拿筷子的方式怪怪的
Dialogue: 0,0:39:09.22,0:39:10.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣？
Dialogue: 0,0:39:12.30,0:39:13.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來
Dialogue: 0,0:39:14.30,0:39:16.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看好叔叔的動作
Dialogue: 0,0:39:19.05,0:39:22.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣拿，這樣動
Dialogue: 0,0:39:27.09,0:39:28.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你試試看
Dialogue: 0,0:40:36.26,0:40:37.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:40:39.67,0:40:41.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以幫我拿給神明嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:40:42.30,0:40:43.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:40:45.96,0:40:46.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在那邊
Dialogue: 0,0:40:50.76,0:40:52.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,起床！
Dialogue: 0,0:40:53.05,0:40:54.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快起來
Dialogue: 0,0:40:56.13,0:40:58.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以敲敲嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:40:58.38,0:41:00.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 可以    - 早啊
Dialogue: 0,0:41:00.30,0:41:01.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,早安
Dialogue: 0,0:41:07.63,0:41:08.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你有拜過嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:41:09.38,0:41:10.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在外婆家拜過
Dialogue: 0,0:41:11.13,0:41:12.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外婆家？
Dialogue: 0,0:41:13.59,0:41:18.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家坐好，早安
Dialogue: 0,0:41:18.17,0:41:23.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽，他是慶多，請多照顧他
Dialogue: 0,0:41:27.63,0:41:29.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小心很燙喔
Dialogue: 0,0:41:38.67,0:41:39.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,冒煙了
Dialogue: 0,0:41:43.04,0:41:44.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這不就修好了嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:41:45.84,0:41:46.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,電池
Dialogue: 0,0:41:51.88,0:41:53.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,開看看
Dialogue: 0,0:41:55.79,0:41:57.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好厲害
Dialogue: 0,0:42:18.83,0:42:19.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哪個？
Dialogue: 0,0:42:19.96,0:42:20.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那個
Dialogue: 0,0:42:21.83,0:42:23.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晴空塔
Dialogue: 0,0:42:23.38,0:42:24.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對吧
Dialogue: 0,0:42:40.29,0:42:42.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的天哪，又輸了
Dialogue: 0,0:42:44.17,0:42:45.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,現在幾點？
Dialogue: 0,0:42:47.58,0:42:49.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,2點45分
Dialogue: 0,0:42:58.33,0:42:59.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們回去吧？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:00.16,0:43:00.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:43:00.75,0:43:01.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想回家嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:01.46,0:43:02.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想！
Dialogue: 0,0:43:13.41,0:43:14.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回來了
Dialogue: 0,0:43:15.33,0:43:16.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴
Dialogue: 0,0:43:18.04,0:43:21.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,寶貝你回來了
Dialogue: 0,0:43:21.87,0:43:23.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有沒有乖乖？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:23.16,0:43:24.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,0:43:25.91,0:43:27.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思，讓你大老遠送來
Dialogue: 0,0:43:27.95,0:43:30.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不會，我老家也在這裡
Dialogue: 0,0:43:30.33,0:43:31.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 是喔    - 你先生呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:32.08,0:43:34.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他有重要的會要開
Dialogue: 0,0:43:34.95,0:43:36.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他真熱愛工作
Dialogue: 0,0:43:36.45,0:43:39.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我多希望你學學人家
Dialogue: 0,0:43:39.25,0:43:44.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是「明日事今日不畢」主義
Dialogue: 0,0:43:44.37,0:43:45.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好啦
Dialogue: 0,0:43:45.58,0:43:48.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的人生都浪費在說廢話上
Dialogue: 0,0:43:48.50,0:43:51.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別嚇人，我的人生沒這麼快結束
Dialogue: 0,0:43:53.54,0:43:55.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你怎麼了？
Dialogue: 0,0:43:56.62,0:43:59.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他在附近公園那個啦
Dialogue: 0,0:44:01.24,0:44:03.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我玩鬼抓人摔倒了
Dialogue: 0,0:44:04.37,0:44:06.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 這樣啊    - 小傷口一下就止血了
Dialogue: 0,0:44:09.91,0:44:11.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你流血了呢
Dialogue: 0,0:44:12.08,0:44:13.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,痛痛嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:44:16.49,0:44:19.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家一起洗澡啊？
Dialogue: 0,0:44:20.12,0:44:21.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,浴室好小
Dialogue: 0,0:44:22.41,0:44:24.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是我們家的一半
Dialogue: 0,0:44:28.99,0:44:31.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴的媽媽人好嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:44:32.78,0:44:36.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一開始有點怕怕，但她很溫柔
Dialogue: 0,0:44:37.91,0:44:39.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:44:45.91,0:44:46.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:44:49.28,0:44:51.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們倆去遠行吧
Dialogue: 0,0:44:51.62,0:44:53.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去哪裡？
Dialogue: 0,0:44:54.45,0:44:55.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很遠的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:44:55.49,0:44:57.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多遠的地方？
Dialogue: 0,0:45:00.24,0:45:02.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒有人知道的地方
Dialogue: 0,0:45:08.53,0:45:09.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸呢？
Dialogue: 0,0:45:11.91,0:45:13.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸…
Dialogue: 0,0:45:16.57,0:45:18.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸有工作要忙
Dialogue: 0,0:45:39.70,0:45:40.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴聽話！
Dialogue: 0,0:45:41.82,0:45:42.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大和！
Dialogue: 0,0:45:43.82,0:45:45.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大和
Dialogue: 0,0:45:47.86,0:45:49.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我抓到你了
Dialogue: 0,0:45:52.20,0:45:53.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,頭髮還沒擦乾
Dialogue: 0,0:45:56.15,0:45:57.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,過來，來媽媽這裡
Dialogue: 0,0:45:58.99,0:46:00.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過來我怎麼幫你擦
Dialogue: 0,0:46:00.24,0:46:03.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已經乾了
Dialogue: 0,0:46:03.49,0:46:05.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還是濕的
Dialogue: 0,0:46:06.65,0:46:07.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的乾了啦
Dialogue: 0,0:46:07.99,0:46:09.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,後面還是濕的
Dialogue: 0,0:46:09.19,0:46:10.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,臉會痛
Dialogue: 0,0:46:10.49,0:46:11.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,轉過來
Dialogue: 0,0:46:11.65,0:46:12.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要擦臉
Dialogue: 0,0:46:12.61,0:46:13.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,給我轉過來
Dialogue: 0,0:46:14.11,0:46:17.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家來睡覺囉
Dialogue: 0,0:46:24.32,0:46:29.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,害他受傷連一聲道歉都沒有是怎樣
Dialogue: 0,0:46:30.15,0:46:32.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,誰叫你沒有一起過去
Dialogue: 0,0:46:34.15,0:46:36.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,現在對我發脾氣有什麼用
Dialogue: 0,0:46:37.69,0:46:38.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來貼繃帶
Dialogue: 0,0:46:43.40,0:46:48.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴家說這是OK繃
Dialogue: 0,0:46:52.57,0:46:56.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,貼好了，跟爸爸說晚安
Dialogue: 0,0:46:57.73,0:46:59.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸晚安
Dialogue: 0,0:46:59.82,0:47:00.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚安
Dialogue: 0,0:47:10.32,0:47:11.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚會很盛大嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:47:14.61,0:47:17.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小薰在大學交了男朋友
Dialogue: 0,0:47:17.82,0:47:19.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,部長難過得要命
Dialogue: 0,0:47:21.48,0:47:23.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別人怎麼講我的？
Dialogue: 0,0:47:24.48,0:47:25.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯？
Dialogue: 0,0:47:26.90,0:47:29.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,說我明明是母親怎麼認不出小孩
Dialogue: 0,0:47:31.69,0:47:33.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒有啊
Dialogue: 0,0:47:36.94,0:47:39.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你自己心裡也想過吧
Dialogue: 0,0:47:42.11,0:47:43.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我沒有
Dialogue: 0,0:47:43.15,0:47:46.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,騙人，你明明認為是我的錯
Dialogue: 0,0:47:55.11,0:47:58.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下次去琉晴家是什麼時候？
Dialogue: 0,0:47:59.44,0:48:01.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下週六
Dialogue: 0,0:48:01.56,0:48:03.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以帶這個去嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:48:04.56,0:48:05.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以
Dialogue: 0,0:48:06.15,0:48:09.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他爸爸好厲害，什麼都會修
Dialogue: 0,0:48:10.02,0:48:12.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:48:13.81,0:48:18.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請他幫忙修一下壞掉的暖爐好了
Dialogue: 0,0:48:22.27,0:48:25.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽，今天要留下來過夜嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:48:25.35,0:48:28.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我明天有編識教室的課
Dialogue: 0,0:48:28.73,0:48:33.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,而且你家太像飯店，我住不習慣
Dialogue: 0,0:48:35.98,0:48:42.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,戰爭時期有很多人是養子
Dialogue: 0,0:48:42.98,0:48:46.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以才說養育之恩大於生育之情
Dialogue: 0,0:48:46.14,0:48:48.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們還沒決定要交換
Dialogue: 0,0:48:48.14,0:48:52.43,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不然你為何要跟對方見面？
Dialogue: 0,0:48:52.56,0:48:54.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是因為…
Dialogue: 0,0:48:54.77,0:48:57.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們想討論出雙方都接受的結果
Dialogue: 0,0:48:57.64,0:48:59.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那真是抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:48:59.35,0:49:02.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老人家我多嘴了
Dialogue: 0,0:49:02.18,0:49:05.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不會，謝謝媽媽寶貴的意見
Dialogue: 0,0:49:05.23,0:49:06.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝你
Dialogue: 0,0:49:06.60,0:49:08.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,穿好了
Dialogue: 0,0:49:08.52,0:49:11.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真帥，哪來的小王子
Dialogue: 0,0:49:11.81,0:49:13.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快來拍張照片
Dialogue: 0,0:49:14.98,0:49:15.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來了
Dialogue: 0,0:49:19.73,0:49:21.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,早安
Dialogue: 0,0:49:23.56,0:49:24.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我來了
Dialogue: 0,0:49:27.31,0:49:28.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是齋木先生
Dialogue: 0,0:49:30.35,0:49:31.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好
Dialogue: 0,0:49:32.18,0:49:35.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有人幫我出新幹線票錢才來的
Dialogue: 0,0:49:36.06,0:49:37.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請進
Dialogue: 0,0:49:37.85,0:49:39.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝，這個
Dialogue: 0,0:49:39.35,0:49:40.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝你
Dialogue: 0,0:49:43.97,0:49:46.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然跟琉晴形容得一樣
Dialogue: 0,0:49:46.89,0:49:48.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這裡好像飯店
Dialogue: 0,0:49:52.18,0:49:53.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:49:55.81,0:49:58.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看看你，怎麼這麼帥
Dialogue: 0,0:49:59.76,0:50:02.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是哪來的王子？
Dialogue: 0,0:50:02.47,0:50:05.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好，我是慶多的…
Dialogue: 0,0:50:05.81,0:50:06.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,外婆嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:50:07.18,0:50:08.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好
Dialogue: 0,0:50:12.14,0:50:13.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你真是年輕
Dialogue: 0,0:50:14.01,0:50:16.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你稱讚我也沒有好處的喔
Dialogue: 0,0:50:16.72,0:50:19.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,什麼嘛，早知道就不講了
Dialogue: 0,0:50:29.26,0:50:29.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要幫忙拍嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:50:30.01,0:50:31.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒關係
Dialogue: 0,0:50:33.89,0:50:35.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，那是什麼？
Dialogue: 0,0:50:35.89,0:50:38.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,給我看看
Dialogue: 0,0:50:38.55,0:50:40.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好漂亮，花瓣
Dialogue: 0,0:50:40.47,0:50:42.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 花瓣    - 嗯？
Dialogue: 0,0:50:45.80,0:50:49.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 我來拍    - 沒關係
Dialogue: 0,0:50:49.30,0:50:51.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我這樣拍好了
Dialogue: 0,0:50:55.43,0:50:56.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,霞木真緒
Dialogue: 0,0:51:01.14,0:51:02.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,霞木真緒
Dialogue: 0,0:51:02.39,0:51:03.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有
Dialogue: 0,0:51:06.34,0:51:08.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,野野宮慶多
Dialogue: 0,0:51:08.51,0:51:09.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有
Dialogue: 0,0:51:14.22,0:51:15.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,矢野心
Dialogue: 0,0:51:15.89,0:51:16.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有
Dialogue: 0,0:51:17.22,0:51:18.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真是不可思議
Dialogue: 0,0:51:19.80,0:51:23.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我當初看著慶多的臉取名琉晴
Dialogue: 0,0:51:26.84,0:51:29.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是他長得就是「慶多」啊
Dialogue: 0,0:51:44.30,0:51:45.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,野野宮先生
Dialogue: 0,0:51:46.01,0:51:47.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,良多先生
Dialogue: 0,0:51:47.68,0:51:49.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,阿良
Dialogue: 0,0:51:50.59,0:51:52.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,換手換手
Dialogue: 0,0:51:52.38,0:51:53.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,換你來
Dialogue: 0,0:52:02.80,0:52:03.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來吧
Dialogue: 0,0:52:08.92,0:52:10.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我真的不行了
Dialogue: 0,0:52:11.63,0:52:12.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好累
Dialogue: 0,0:52:16.13,0:52:20.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,早知道就在40歲之前生小孩
Dialogue: 0,0:52:22.76,0:52:25.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你比我年輕這麼多
Dialogue: 0,0:52:25.63,0:52:29.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,勸你多花點時間陪陪孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:52:30.96,0:52:34.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,每個家庭相處的方式不一樣
Dialogue: 0,0:52:36.09,0:52:37.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,聽說你不會跟小孩洗澡
Dialogue: 0,0:52:38.63,0:52:41.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的教育方針是培養他獨立
Dialogue: 0,0:52:42.46,0:52:46.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果是教育方針那就沒辦法
Dialogue: 0,0:52:46.38,0:52:48.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過千萬別嫌麻煩
Dialogue: 0,0:52:49.80,0:52:55.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我這半年和慶多相處的時間\N已經比你陪他的時間多了
Dialogue: 0,0:52:56.96,0:52:58.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,時間不能代表一切
Dialogue: 0,0:52:58.96,0:53:01.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別傻了，時間就是一切
Dialogue: 0,0:53:01.63,0:53:03.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,孩子的時間不能等
Dialogue: 0,0:53:05.13,0:53:07.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有些工作非我不可
Dialogue: 0,0:53:11.63,0:53:15.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父親也是無人能取代的工作
Dialogue: 0,0:53:26.79,0:53:29.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快過來
Dialogue: 0,0:53:30.92,0:53:32.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們要走囉
Dialogue: 0,0:53:32.71,0:53:34.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他們已經像親兄弟了
Dialogue: 0,0:53:34.63,0:53:35.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是啊
Dialogue: 0,0:53:36.92,0:53:39.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請問可以外帶一份咖哩豬排嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:53:39.92,0:53:41.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好的，請稍等
Dialogue: 0,0:53:44.50,0:53:47.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他爸在家裡餓肚子等著
Dialogue: 0,0:53:48.46,0:53:50.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他有點痴呆，返老還童了
Dialogue: 0,0:53:50.71,0:53:52.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我好像有四個小孩在家
Dialogue: 0,0:53:53.08,0:53:56.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是五個，還有一個更難搞的
Dialogue: 0,0:53:57.83,0:53:58.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我嗎
Dialogue: 0,0:53:59.96,0:54:03.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那你願意把兩個孩子都給我嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:54:05.63,0:54:06.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,兩個？
Dialogue: 0,0:54:07.08,0:54:09.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多和琉晴
Dialogue: 0,0:54:12.46,0:54:13.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你認真的嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:54:14.67,0:54:17.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對，不行嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:54:24.29,0:54:25.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你怎麼講這種話
Dialogue: 0,0:54:25.71,0:54:27.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你太失禮了吧
Dialogue: 0,0:54:28.96,0:54:30.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是考慮孩子的幸福
Dialogue: 0,0:54:30.79,0:54:32.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,當我們的孩子很不幸嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:54:32.50,0:54:34.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我願意支付高額賠償金
Dialogue: 0,0:54:35.46,0:54:38.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有些東西是用錢買不到的
Dialogue: 0,0:54:39.58,0:54:41.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想用錢買小孩嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:54:42.79,0:54:45.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們自己不也說過誠意要用錢表示
Dialogue: 0,0:54:45.79,0:54:49.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起，外子不太會說話
Dialogue: 0,0:54:50.41,0:54:52.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,孩子們都在場
Dialogue: 0,0:54:53.33,0:54:55.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您的咖哩豬排包好了
Dialogue: 0,0:54:59.75,0:55:05.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒輸過的人就是缺乏同理心
Dialogue: 0,0:55:13.95,0:55:15.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎麼辦？
Dialogue: 0,0:55:15.83,0:55:16.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯…
Dialogue: 0,0:55:17.87,0:55:20.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你在那種地方當玩笑話講出來
Dialogue: 0,0:55:20.62,0:55:22.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我真是太傻眼了
Dialogue: 0,0:55:22.29,0:55:23.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,任誰都會生氣的
Dialogue: 0,0:55:23.66,0:55:26.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不要講了，我正在思考
Dialogue: 0,0:55:27.79,0:55:30.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家好不容易才熟的
Dialogue: 0,0:55:31.58,0:55:35.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼我要被水電工教訓？
Dialogue: 0,0:55:35.45,0:55:36.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你又在講這種話
Dialogue: 0,0:55:37.62,0:55:39.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你回來啦
Dialogue: 0,0:55:40.12,0:55:41.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽媽你的拿鐵
Dialogue: 0,0:55:41.41,0:55:42.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝你
Dialogue: 0,0:55:45.29,0:55:46.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸的無糖
Dialogue: 0,0:55:47.45,0:55:48.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝
Dialogue: 0,0:55:53.54,0:55:55.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 這是零錢    - 謝謝
Dialogue: 0,0:56:03.33,0:56:04.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來了來了
Dialogue: 0,0:56:05.24,0:56:05.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有了
Dialogue: 0,0:56:06.03,0:56:07.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好厲害
Dialogue: 0,0:56:09.53,0:56:10.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你打偏了
Dialogue: 0,0:56:10.62,0:56:14.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多你不能打出去
Dialogue: 0,0:56:14.91,0:56:17.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要打進正中間
Dialogue: 0,0:56:18.70,0:56:20.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你記得有個護士姓宮崎嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:56:21.12,0:56:21.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不記得
Dialogue: 0,0:56:23.37,0:56:25.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看到臉應該有印象
Dialogue: 0,0:56:25.41,0:56:26.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想說什麼？
Dialogue: 0,0:56:26.87,0:56:29.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想醫院方可能會說明
Dialogue: 0,0:56:29.28,0:56:33.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她當時的出勤狀況沒有問題
Dialogue: 0,0:56:34.07,0:56:37.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她又在該出門時弄什麼熨斗
Dialogue: 0,0:56:37.16,0:56:39.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拜託你不要在這種時候開玩笑
Dialogue: 0,0:56:39.62,0:56:41.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,上次的事非常抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:56:44.95,0:56:45.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉
Dialogue: 0,0:56:45.57,0:56:48.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不會，我們也有錯啦
Dialogue: 0,0:56:49.45,0:56:50.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,宣誓
Dialogue: 0,0:56:51.07,0:56:54.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我憑良心講述事實
Dialogue: 0,0:56:54.32,0:56:58.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,保證不隱藏，不撒謊
Dialogue: 0,0:56:59.20,0:57:00.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,齋木由加里
Dialogue: 0,0:57:00.41,0:57:01.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,野野宮綠
Dialogue: 0,0:57:02.03,0:57:03.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,宮崎祥子
Dialogue: 0,0:57:04.36,0:57:08.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,即使醫院程序上有出錯
Dialogue: 0,0:57:09.28,0:57:13.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,身為母親難道都沒有發現嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:57:15.95,0:57:18.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果是正常的情況也許會發現
Dialogue: 0,0:57:19.49,0:57:21.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,但是我產後嚴重出血
Dialogue: 0,0:57:21.78,0:57:25.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多日處於昏迷的狀態
Dialogue: 0,0:57:27.66,0:57:30.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今後能夠順利交換孩子嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:57:31.70,0:57:32.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不知道
Dialogue: 0,0:57:33.78,0:57:35.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就算順利交換了
Dialogue: 0,0:57:36.11,0:57:38.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之後也不見得會好過
Dialogue: 0,0:57:40.15,0:57:44.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們的經濟負擔並非一時的問題
Dialogue: 0,0:57:46.03,0:57:49.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,之後仍會處於很辛苦的環境
Dialogue: 0,0:57:51.90,0:57:54.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想詢問你的出勤狀況
Dialogue: 0,0:57:55.28,0:57:58.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你當時連續多天值大夜班嗎？
Dialogue: 0,0:57:59.94,0:58:05.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不，我們的勤務比其他醫院輕鬆
Dialogue: 0,0:58:05.69,0:58:10.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那你認為導致意外的原因是？
Dialogue: 0,0:58:14.32,0:58:15.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這不是意外
Dialogue: 0,0:58:18.24,0:58:19.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是意外？
Dialogue: 0,0:58:20.82,0:58:22.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是什麼意思？
Dialogue: 0,0:58:25.36,0:58:28.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,野野宮一家看起來太幸福了
Dialogue: 0,0:58:29.78,0:58:31.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我故意把小孩換掉的
Dialogue: 0,0:58:43.44,0:58:46.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我當時才剛再婚，帶小孩帶得很煩
Dialogue: 0,0:58:47.90,0:58:50.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以遷怒到別人的孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:58:53.32,0:58:56.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,野野宮太太住在最高級的病房
Dialogue: 0,0:58:57.02,0:58:59.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,先生在知名企業工作
Dialogue: 0,0:59:00.27,0:59:02.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,身旁圍繞著喜悅的家人
Dialogue: 0,0:59:05.40,0:59:10.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我跟他們比起來…
Dialogue: 0,0:59:12.32,0:59:15.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你換掉小孩時的心情是？
Dialogue: 0,0:59:17.90,0:59:20.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,說實話，心情很舒暢
Dialogue: 0,0:59:20.61,0:59:23.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不幸的人不是只有我
Dialogue: 0,0:59:26.98,0:59:33.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為何你今天願意坦承事實？
Dialogue: 0,0:59:36.11,0:59:39.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我懷了現在的老公的孩子
Dialogue: 0,0:59:40.85,0:59:44.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,開始恐懼自己做過的行為
Dialogue: 0,0:59:45.73,0:59:49.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想彌補自己的罪行
Dialogue: 0,0:59:52.52,0:59:54.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的非常對不起
Dialogue: 0,0:59:55.56,0:59:57.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我做錯了
Dialogue: 0,1:00:00.77,1:00:04.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小孩再煩也不該做這種事吧
Dialogue: 0,1:00:05.94,1:00:09.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她再婚之前就知道對方有孩子了
Dialogue: 0,1:00:09.90,1:00:11.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還說心情舒暢
Dialogue: 0,1:00:11.81,1:00:14.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這難道跟順手偷個東西一樣嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:00:14.19,1:00:17.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她不懂自己犯的罪有多重
Dialogue: 0,1:00:18.15,1:00:20.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她說現在生活幸福美滿
Dialogue: 0,1:00:21.10,1:00:23.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,誰要聽她講這些啊
Dialogue: 0,1:00:23.48,1:00:28.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過這樣賠償金會增加吧
Dialogue: 0,1:00:28.60,1:00:30.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那是當然的
Dialogue: 0,1:00:31.98,1:00:36.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這要跟鈴本律師問清楚喔
Dialogue: 0,1:00:37.98,1:00:38.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:00:40.56,1:00:42.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以把她告到進監獄吧
Dialogue: 0,1:00:43.31,1:00:44.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那還用說嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:00:44.77,1:00:46.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,五年十年之類的？
Dialogue: 0,1:00:46.44,1:00:48.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這還算便宜她了
Dialogue: 0,1:00:49.60,1:00:52.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,聽說時效已經過了
Dialogue: 0,1:00:53.85,1:00:55.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,時效？
Dialogue: 0,1:00:56.43,1:00:58.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,鈴本跟我說
Dialogue: 0,1:00:58.35,1:01:03.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,未成年略奪罪的追溯期是五年
Dialogue: 0,1:01:04.48,1:01:06.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以她道個歉就沒事了？
Dialogue: 0,1:01:06.77,1:01:07.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哪有這麼好的事
Dialogue: 0,1:01:07.93,1:01:09.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小聲一點
Dialogue: 0,1:01:09.48,1:01:12.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我沒有辦法接受
Dialogue: 0,1:01:13.60,1:01:15.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們的痛苦不會結束
Dialogue: 0,1:01:15.93,1:01:17.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,時效只對她起作用？
Dialogue: 0,1:01:19.60,1:01:23.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她算好時效過了才坦白的吧
Dialogue: 0,1:01:23.81,1:01:25.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一定是這樣
Dialogue: 0,1:01:26.97,1:01:31.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我一輩子不會原諒她
Dialogue: 0,1:01:33.43,1:01:33.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（跟父親說謝謝）
Dialogue: 0,1:01:33.68,1:01:35.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（跟父親說謝謝）\N沒有錯
Dialogue: 0,1:01:35.43,1:01:35.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（跟父親說謝謝）
Dialogue: 0,1:01:35.77,1:01:36.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,（跟父親說謝謝）\N這樣嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:01:36.06,1:01:36.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:01:37.02,1:01:38.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家看這邊
Dialogue: 0,1:01:40.43,1:01:45.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小惠還做了刺，好厲害
Dialogue: 0,1:01:48.93,1:01:49.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老師
Dialogue: 0,1:01:49.76,1:01:50.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來了
Dialogue: 0,1:01:53.60,1:01:57.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很棒很棒
Dialogue: 0,1:01:59.56,1:02:02.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,聽說他在吃降血壓的藥
Dialogue: 0,1:02:03.43,1:02:04.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,第二次發作？
Dialogue: 0,1:02:04.93,1:02:06.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,第三次
Dialogue: 0,1:02:06.56,1:02:09.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還好有信子陪在他身邊
Dialogue: 0,1:02:09.14,1:02:10.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對
Dialogue: 0,1:02:11.22,1:02:15.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你回家時別忘記叫她「媽媽」
Dialogue: 0,1:02:17.72,1:02:18.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我沒有嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:02:22.43,1:02:24.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過爸爸主動說想見兒子
Dialogue: 0,1:02:24.80,1:02:26.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看來他真的變弱了
Dialogue: 0,1:02:28.10,1:02:29.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣不是正好嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:02:29.43,1:02:31.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,軟弱一點對我們比較好
Dialogue: 0,1:02:32.55,1:02:35.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他看到這個會哭出來吧
Dialogue: 0,1:02:40.68,1:02:42.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 這是找零    - 好
Dialogue: 0,1:02:42.26,1:02:44.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝惠顧，請再度光臨
Dialogue: 0,1:02:44.43,1:02:45.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,辛苦了
Dialogue: 0,1:02:52.09,1:02:54.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這附近只有這種店
Dialogue: 0,1:02:56.72,1:03:00.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的病已經好了嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:03:01.26,1:03:04.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不說嚴重一點你怎麼會回來
Dialogue: 0,1:03:04.76,1:03:07.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我上次說過不會再給你錢了
Dialogue: 0,1:03:08.18,1:03:09.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不缺錢
Dialogue: 0,1:03:10.09,1:03:13.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我現在在三輪的公寓當管理員
Dialogue: 0,1:03:14.43,1:03:17.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她也有在打工賺錢
Dialogue: 0,1:03:18.09,1:03:19.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不要再玩這東西了！
Dialogue: 0,1:03:19.68,1:03:20.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,良多！
Dialogue: 0,1:03:21.93,1:03:23.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我記得大輔喜歡吃鮭魚卵
Dialogue: 0,1:03:24.09,1:03:25.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別客氣，多吃點
Dialogue: 0,1:03:27.26,1:03:31.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我很想吃，但正在飲食控制
Dialogue: 0,1:03:34.01,1:03:35.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,今天破戒一下好了
Dialogue: 0,1:03:44.84,1:03:47.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可惡，蛋也太好吃了吧
Dialogue: 0,1:03:51.55,1:03:53.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,賽馬有賭贏嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:03:55.84,1:03:58.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你一臉輸很慘的樣子
Dialogue: 0,1:04:00.63,1:04:05.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽媽也沒選對人，這麼辛苦
Dialogue: 0,1:04:05.76,1:04:07.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你壓不對馬了
Dialogue: 0,1:04:08.09,1:04:10.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我沒有賭博的天份
Dialogue: 0,1:04:11.01,1:04:13.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看來我是跟媽媽像
Dialogue: 0,1:04:15.42,1:04:19.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒辦法，誰叫我跟他是夫婦
Dialogue: 0,1:04:22.09,1:04:24.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不用什麼都自己來
Dialogue: 0,1:04:24.51,1:04:26.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣跟看護有什麼兩樣
Dialogue: 0,1:04:26.88,1:04:30.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,看護時薪要一千圓
Dialogue: 0,1:04:30.26,1:04:33.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,混帳，比我賺得還多
Dialogue: 0,1:04:39.67,1:04:45.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他彈了三年都是這首歌
Dialogue: 0,1:04:46.92,1:04:48.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,吵得我沒辦法睡午覺
Dialogue: 0,1:04:48.75,1:04:50.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對方會聽到啦
Dialogue: 0,1:04:50.75,1:04:52.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我故意的
Dialogue: 0,1:05:02.17,1:05:04.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你見到他了嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:05:06.88,1:05:09.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的親生兒子
Dialogue: 0,1:05:10.05,1:05:11.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,見到了
Dialogue: 0,1:05:11.42,1:05:13.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,長得像你嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:05:15.09,1:05:16.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一定很像吧
Dialogue: 0,1:05:18.25,1:05:20.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,父子就是這麼一回事
Dialogue: 0,1:05:21.04,1:05:23.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不住在一起也會相像
Dialogue: 0,1:05:25.04,1:05:26.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拜託你饒了我們吧
Dialogue: 0,1:05:27.54,1:05:28.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不對
Dialogue: 0,1:05:30.17,1:05:32.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,聽著，這就是血緣
Dialogue: 0,1:05:34.25,1:05:37.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,人和馬一樣，血統很重要
Dialogue: 0,1:05:38.88,1:05:41.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他會跟你越來越像
Dialogue: 0,1:05:43.46,1:05:49.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多會跟那家人越來越像
Dialogue: 0,1:05:51.13,1:05:57.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們趕快交換，別再相見了
Dialogue: 0,1:06:00.88,1:06:02.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,事情沒有這麼簡單
Dialogue: 0,1:06:10.79,1:06:12.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小心地會滑
Dialogue: 0,1:06:13.25,1:06:16.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我看得見，少囉嗦
Dialogue: 0,1:06:17.42,1:06:18.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是女人嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:06:18.92,1:06:20.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是好心提醒你
Dialogue: 0,1:06:21.79,1:06:23.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你小心被討厭
Dialogue: 0,1:06:24.83,1:06:26.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他已經被討厭了
Dialogue: 0,1:06:31.41,1:06:34.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別聽你爸說那種話
Dialogue: 0,1:06:34.17,1:06:40.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,長久相處的感情也會讓人相像的
Dialogue: 0,1:06:40.83,1:06:42.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比如說夫婦就是這樣
Dialogue: 0,1:06:43.66,1:06:46.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,當然父子也會一樣的
Dialogue: 0,1:06:48.08,1:06:55.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這才是我想教給你們的
Dialogue: 0,1:07:00.41,1:07:01.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有空再回來
Dialogue: 0,1:07:01.66,1:07:04.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大輔，我會去看愛美的拼布作品
Dialogue: 0,1:07:04.83,1:07:05.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我等你
Dialogue: 0,1:07:06.70,1:07:07.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再見
Dialogue: 0,1:07:10.70,1:07:14.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下次別帶花，帶酒回來
Dialogue: 0,1:07:19.75,1:07:21.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,幸好爸爸沒有大礙
Dialogue: 0,1:07:21.70,1:07:23.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我完全中了他的招
Dialogue: 0,1:07:23.29,1:07:24.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,害我硬是跟公司請假
Dialogue: 0,1:07:26.29,1:07:28.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他有提到慶多的事嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:07:29.20,1:07:30.74,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒有
Dialogue: 0,1:07:32.66,1:07:34.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，爸爸回來了
Dialogue: 0,1:07:35.08,1:07:36.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你回來啦
Dialogue: 0,1:07:36.91,1:07:38.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回來了
Dialogue: 0,1:07:43.04,1:07:45.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在學校做的父親節禮物
Dialogue: 0,1:07:53.08,1:07:56.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，謝謝你
Dialogue: 0,1:07:57.58,1:08:01.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那支要給琉晴的爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:08:01.24,1:08:03.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因為他幫我修好機器人
Dialogue: 0,1:08:07.41,1:08:08.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣啊
Dialogue: 0,1:08:10.58,1:08:12.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多真是個好孩子
Dialogue: 0,1:08:42.53,1:08:44.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,難道不能維持現狀嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:08:46.57,1:08:48.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們都當作沒這件事
Dialogue: 0,1:08:51.49,1:08:57.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多會越來越像你們家的人
Dialogue: 0,1:08:58.74,1:09:04.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴也會跟我越來越像
Dialogue: 0,1:09:07.16,1:09:11.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你能夠像以往一樣
Dialogue: 0,1:09:14.28,1:09:16.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,疼愛沒有血緣關係的孩子嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:09:16.49,1:09:18.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,當然可以
Dialogue: 0,1:09:20.24,1:09:25.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,只有跟孩子沒有實際親情的男人
Dialogue: 0,1:09:27.07,1:09:30.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,才會去計較什麼長相
Dialogue: 0,1:09:34.61,1:09:39.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,繼續拖下去只會越來越痛苦
Dialogue: 0,1:09:41.61,1:09:46.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不管是我們還是孩子
Dialogue: 0,1:09:50.94,1:09:52.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們玩這個
Dialogue: 0,1:09:53.65,1:09:55.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，幫我看好他們倆
Dialogue: 0,1:09:57.28,1:09:58.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我出門了
Dialogue: 0,1:10:00.15,1:10:05.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,路上小心…
Dialogue: 0,1:10:08.03,1:10:09.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,您的便當好了
Dialogue: 0,1:10:18.23,1:10:19.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,一共400圓
Dialogue: 0,1:10:21.40,1:10:24.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多的多加了一份炸雞塊
Dialogue: 0,1:10:25.61,1:10:27.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小心拿回家喔
Dialogue: 0,1:10:27.48,1:10:28.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:10:28.53,1:10:29.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,掰掰
Dialogue: 0,1:10:34.57,1:10:36.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,掰掰
Dialogue: 0,1:11:01.69,1:11:07.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等夏天到了，在這裡放煙火
Dialogue: 0,1:11:08.23,1:11:13.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去游泳，然後劈西瓜
Dialogue: 0,1:11:15.36,1:11:16.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多也一起來玩
Dialogue: 0,1:11:26.15,1:11:26.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:11:27.06,1:11:28.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好好笑
Dialogue: 0,1:11:30.02,1:11:31.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回來了
Dialogue: 0,1:11:33.19,1:11:34.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他好像回來了
Dialogue: 0,1:11:34.98,1:11:38.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝你的幫忙
Dialogue: 0,1:11:38.65,1:11:39.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,下次再聊
Dialogue: 0,1:11:44.27,1:11:45.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你回來啦
Dialogue: 0,1:11:47.73,1:11:48.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴呢？
Dialogue: 0,1:11:50.23,1:11:51.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在洗澡
Dialogue: 0,1:11:56.23,1:11:57.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,已經這麼晚啦
Dialogue: 0,1:12:00.94,1:12:03.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉，事情都丟給你做
Dialogue: 0,1:12:05.90,1:12:07.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我明天空下來了
Dialogue: 0,1:12:08.31,1:12:12.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒關係，我習慣了
Dialogue: 0,1:12:18.10,1:12:19.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你跟誰講電話？
Dialogue: 0,1:12:20.73,1:12:22.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,由加里
Dialogue: 0,1:12:22.56,1:12:27.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,雄大先生說他50歲之後\N要開一間衝浪店
Dialogue: 0,1:12:27.39,1:12:30.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可是他自己不會衝浪
Dialogue: 0,1:12:35.06,1:12:37.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我勸你們保持一點距離
Dialogue: 0,1:12:37.77,1:12:41.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽媽之間交換消息有什麼不對
Dialogue: 0,1:12:41.60,1:12:43.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你是不會懂的
Dialogue: 0,1:13:35.31,1:13:36.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他彈真好
Dialogue: 0,1:13:36.85,1:13:37.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對啊
Dialogue: 0,1:13:42.01,1:13:43.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不會不甘心嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:13:45.72,1:13:49.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不想進步的話就沒有意義囉
Dialogue: 0,1:13:51.26,1:13:53.92,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不是所有人都像你是拼命三郎
Dialogue: 0,1:13:56.18,1:13:58.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要把努力講成是壞事
Dialogue: 0,1:13:59.14,1:14:02.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的意思是有些人力不從心
Dialogue: 0,1:14:04.51,1:14:07.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多這點像我
Dialogue: 0,1:14:28.68,1:14:29.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他睡了？
Dialogue: 0,1:14:37.72,1:14:39.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我按照你說得去做
Dialogue: 0,1:14:40.89,1:14:43.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,結果卻要離開慶多
Dialogue: 0,1:14:45.26,1:14:47.67,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你明明說放心交給你的
Dialogue: 0,1:14:48.72,1:14:50.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你這騙子
Dialogue: 0,1:14:53.01,1:14:55.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也沒想到會變這樣
Dialogue: 0,1:14:55.39,1:14:57.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你一開始就做好選擇了吧
Dialogue: 0,1:14:59.18,1:15:02.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,血緣比相處六年的慶多重要
Dialogue: 0,1:15:03.09,1:15:05.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我沒有
Dialogue: 0,1:15:05.39,1:15:06.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,老公
Dialogue: 0,1:15:11.09,1:15:13.71,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,發現慶多不是親生的時候
Dialogue: 0,1:15:14.88,1:15:16.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你記得你說了什麼嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:15:16.38,1:15:17.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我當然記得
Dialogue: 0,1:15:24.59,1:15:26.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我說你怎麼會沒發現
Dialogue: 0,1:15:31.76,1:15:34.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我願意道歉
Dialogue: 0,1:15:34.22,1:15:37.25,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你錯了，不是這句
Dialogue: 0,1:15:40.42,1:15:42.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你說的是
Dialogue: 0,1:15:43.30,1:15:45.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,「果然是這樣啊」
Dialogue: 0,1:15:46.88,1:15:48.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,果然是怎樣？
Dialogue: 0,1:15:52.88,1:15:54.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請你解釋一下
Dialogue: 0,1:15:57.63,1:16:01.58,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你打從一開始就不相信
Dialogue: 0,1:16:01.71,1:16:03.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因為慶多不如你那麼優秀
Dialogue: 0,1:16:06.96,1:16:08.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的那句話
Dialogue: 0,1:16:10.76,1:16:12.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我一輩子忘不了
Dialogue: 0,1:16:24.34,1:16:25.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,轉囉
Dialogue: 0,1:16:31.46,1:16:32.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,轉好快
Dialogue: 0,1:16:41.17,1:16:42.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好厲害
Dialogue: 0,1:16:44.13,1:16:45.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,笑一個
Dialogue: 0,1:16:49.79,1:16:51.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也要拍
Dialogue: 0,1:16:56.38,1:16:57.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,按這裡
Dialogue: 0,1:17:06.00,1:17:09.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那台照相機送你
Dialogue: 0,1:17:12.84,1:17:15.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？不想要？
Dialogue: 0,1:17:15.63,1:17:17.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我不要
Dialogue: 0,1:17:19.96,1:17:21.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是喔
Dialogue: 0,1:17:27.46,1:17:28.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，聽好了
Dialogue: 0,1:17:30.04,1:17:31.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你過去之後
Dialogue: 0,1:17:31.92,1:17:35.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要記得改叫叔叔阿姨\N「爸爸媽媽」
Dialogue: 0,1:17:37.13,1:17:39.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,就算寂寞也不可以哭
Dialogue: 0,1:17:39.79,1:17:41.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不可以打電話回來
Dialogue: 0,1:17:42.08,1:17:43.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,聽懂沒
Dialogue: 0,1:17:44.21,1:17:45.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是任務？
Dialogue: 0,1:17:46.42,1:17:48.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯，任務
Dialogue: 0,1:17:51.17,1:17:52.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,到什麼時候？
Dialogue: 0,1:17:54.54,1:17:55.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還沒決定
Dialogue: 0,1:17:58.87,1:18:04.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你也許不懂為何要挑戰任務
Dialogue: 0,1:18:05.92,1:18:09.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,等到十年後，你就會明白了
Dialogue: 0,1:18:10.54,1:18:14.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在琉晴家也要練鋼琴嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:18:17.21,1:18:18.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你自己決定
Dialogue: 0,1:18:19.66,1:18:22.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你想練的話就繼續吧
Dialogue: 0,1:18:22.25,1:18:24.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽媽會跟他們說的
Dialogue: 0,1:20:02.99,1:20:05.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這裡好像不能放風箏
Dialogue: 0,1:20:06.70,1:20:08.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,河裡的魚有保育類的魚
Dialogue: 0,1:20:09.78,1:20:13.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,防止鳥類飛來，四處拉了防護線
Dialogue: 0,1:20:16.20,1:20:18.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不能放啦
Dialogue: 0,1:20:19.28,1:20:20.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴
Dialogue: 0,1:20:31.49,1:20:33.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,想我們小時候…
Dialogue: 0,1:20:35.32,1:20:37.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我比你老一點點
Dialogue: 0,1:20:38.53,1:20:43.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我爸會用竹筷和紙做風箏
Dialogue: 0,1:20:44.57,1:20:48.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,風箏尾巴是報紙撕下來的
Dialogue: 0,1:20:52.82,1:20:55.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,現在的風箏很好放
Dialogue: 0,1:20:55.70,1:20:58.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前的那種很難升空
Dialogue: 0,1:21:02.36,1:21:07.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我父親不會陪小孩放風箏
Dialogue: 0,1:21:11.74,1:21:17.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不需要學習你父親
Dialogue: 0,1:21:21.20,1:21:24.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請陪陪琉晴放風箏
Dialogue: 0,1:21:28.32,1:21:29.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:21:38.70,1:21:42.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,火車開過去了
Dialogue: 0,1:21:44.90,1:21:47.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那孩子其實很膽小
Dialogue: 0,1:21:49.61,1:21:52.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前晚上不敢去上廁所
Dialogue: 0,1:21:53.53,1:21:55.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,每次都要我陪
Dialogue: 0,1:21:58.07,1:22:01.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,當了哥哥突然就長大了
Dialogue: 0,1:22:03.90,1:22:05.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他還答應我說
Dialogue: 0,1:22:06.32,1:22:10.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以後負責陪大和去上廁所
Dialogue: 0,1:22:16.90,1:22:22.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多一直吵著要弟弟
Dialogue: 0,1:22:25.28,1:22:30.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可是我生不出來了
Dialogue: 0,1:22:33.94,1:22:42.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,所以換一種方式讓他有弟妹
Dialogue: 0,1:22:44.65,1:22:49.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想他一定也很高興
Dialogue: 0,1:23:24.81,1:23:25.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,1:23:28.19,1:23:33.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不用怕搬過去
Dialogue: 0,1:23:35.40,1:23:40.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴的爸媽都很喜歡你
Dialogue: 0,1:23:44.19,1:23:45.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比你喜歡嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:23:52.23,1:23:53.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比我喜歡
Dialogue: 0,1:23:58.94,1:24:02.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來，大家來拍紀念照
Dialogue: 0,1:24:02.89,1:24:03.35,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:24:03.69,1:24:04.72,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好了嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:24:25.27,1:24:26.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,站好
Dialogue: 0,1:24:32.27,1:24:33.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,笑一個
Dialogue: 0,1:24:34.77,1:24:36.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大家都要笑一個
Dialogue: 0,1:24:38.27,1:24:38.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:24:38.98,1:24:40.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,準備好了沒
Dialogue: 0,1:24:41.35,1:24:44.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,按下去囉
Dialogue: 0,1:24:52.48,1:24:53.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,大和
Dialogue: 0,1:24:55.68,1:24:56.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有什麼好笑的？
Dialogue: 0,1:24:57.02,1:24:57.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有什麼好笑的？
Dialogue: 0,1:24:58.10,1:24:59.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒有好笑的
Dialogue: 0,1:24:59.43,1:25:00.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是不好笑啊
Dialogue: 0,1:25:07.56,1:25:09.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要咬吸管
Dialogue: 0,1:25:10.68,1:25:13.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,每天練習英文
Dialogue: 0,1:25:14.31,1:25:16.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,坐著上廁所
Dialogue: 0,1:25:16.56,1:25:20.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,自己一個人安靜洗澡
Dialogue: 0,1:25:20.68,1:25:25.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,電玩一天能玩30分鐘
Dialogue: 0,1:25:25.89,1:25:28.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要叫爸爸和媽媽
Dialogue: 0,1:25:28.43,1:25:29.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:25:33.18,1:25:35.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你又不是我爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:25:35.35,1:25:36.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我爸爸不是你
Dialogue: 0,1:25:38.64,1:25:41.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以後叔叔就是你爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:25:41.43,1:25:42.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:25:47.72,1:25:48.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不為什麼
Dialogue: 0,1:25:49.85,1:25:50.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:25:54.01,1:25:55.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,然後…
Dialogue: 0,1:25:56.56,1:25:58.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那不然…
Dialogue: 0,1:26:03.14,1:26:04.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣好了
Dialogue: 0,1:26:06.01,1:26:09.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸和媽媽跟原來一樣
Dialogue: 0,1:26:10.51,1:26:11.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不用改口
Dialogue: 0,1:26:12.51,1:26:16.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可是叔叔跟阿姨
Dialogue: 0,1:26:16.64,1:26:19.22,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,可以叫爸比和媽咪嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:26:19.35,1:26:20.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:26:21.97,1:26:23.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不為什麼
Dialogue: 0,1:26:23.68,1:26:26.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我聽不懂
Dialogue: 0,1:26:32.26,1:26:33.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你以後就會懂了
Dialogue: 0,1:26:34.01,1:26:35.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:26:36.18,1:26:37.84,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不為什麼
Dialogue: 0,1:26:39.18,1:26:41.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼不為什麼
Dialogue: 0,1:26:48.43,1:26:49.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你說為什麼呢？
Dialogue: 0,1:26:49.68,1:26:50.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:27:16.80,1:27:17.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,去刷牙
Dialogue: 0,1:27:19.55,1:27:20.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拿去
Dialogue: 0,1:28:00.76,1:28:03.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎麼啦？
Dialogue: 0,1:28:10.84,1:28:12.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你壞掉了嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:28:13.00,1:28:17.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來，阿姨來幫你修修
Dialogue: 0,1:28:19.96,1:28:21.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這裡？
Dialogue: 0,1:28:28.63,1:28:29.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還是這裡？
Dialogue: 0,1:28:31.09,1:28:34.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這裡…
Dialogue: 0,1:28:35.21,1:28:36.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,修好了沒？
Dialogue: 0,1:29:08.67,1:29:11.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,調去宇都宮的研發部？
Dialogue: 0,1:29:12.67,1:29:13.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對
Dialogue: 0,1:29:15.50,1:29:18.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什麼是我？不是野原？
Dialogue: 0,1:29:21.08,1:29:24.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,畢竟你有官司纏身
Dialogue: 0,1:29:25.83,1:29:29.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請不要誤會，我不是被告
Dialogue: 0,1:29:29.96,1:29:32.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這個我知道
Dialogue: 0,1:29:33.92,1:29:38.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你一直踩滿油門衝刺至今
Dialogue: 0,1:29:39.42,1:29:41.75,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是該踩一下煞車了
Dialogue: 0,1:29:41.87,1:29:44.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你也是踩油門才衝到上位的吧
Dialogue: 0,1:29:44.58,1:29:46.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,時代不一樣了
Dialogue: 0,1:29:47.79,1:29:50.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,多花點時間陪家人
Dialogue: 0,1:29:54.25,1:29:56.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有藍色和紅色的
Dialogue: 0,1:29:59.08,1:30:00.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你喜歡哪一個？
Dialogue: 0,1:30:00.50,1:30:01.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我選紅色
Dialogue: 0,1:30:03.67,1:30:05.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,紅色是醬油口味？
Dialogue: 0,1:30:06.37,1:30:07.36,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:30:07.50,1:30:08.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道
Dialogue: 0,1:30:15.91,1:30:16.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂？
Dialogue: 0,1:30:30.62,1:30:34.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸還沒回來，我們偷偷講
Dialogue: 0,1:30:41.91,1:30:43.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,為什要畫這種畫？
Dialogue: 0,1:30:45.37,1:30:46.91,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,媽媽難過到哭囉
Dialogue: 0,1:30:49.33,1:30:52.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你有沒有道歉？
Dialogue: 0,1:30:57.33,1:31:00.69,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,算了，去睡覺吧
Dialogue: 0,1:31:01.91,1:31:03.65,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚安呢？
Dialogue: 0,1:31:04.99,1:31:06.82,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,晚安
Dialogue: 0,1:31:42.49,1:31:45.11,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你太吵了，安靜點
Dialogue: 0,1:31:49.24,1:31:50.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我叫你安靜！
Dialogue: 0,1:32:30.82,1:32:35.48,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這個已經壞掉了
Dialogue: 0,1:32:36.66,1:32:38.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,叫媽媽買新的給你
Dialogue: 0,1:32:42.57,1:32:45.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我下次回家叫爸爸幫我修
Dialogue: 0,1:32:45.45,1:32:46.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴
Dialogue: 0,1:32:54.95,1:32:57.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不會再回去那個家了
Dialogue: 0,1:32:59.11,1:33:01.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你要一直住在這裡
Dialogue: 0,1:33:04.57,1:33:06.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我才是你真正的爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:33:12.40,1:33:13.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,給我看看
Dialogue: 0,1:34:52.98,1:34:55.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我特地來跟你講捷報
Dialogue: 0,1:34:55.86,1:34:57.44,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你看來不怎麼高興
Dialogue: 0,1:34:58.11,1:35:00.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我沒有贏
Dialogue: 0,1:35:01.73,1:35:06.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,官司本來就沒有絕對的贏家
Dialogue: 0,1:35:08.15,1:35:10.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我說的不是這個意思
Dialogue: 0,1:35:12.65,1:35:14.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真不像你的作風
Dialogue: 0,1:35:15.61,1:35:17.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣子我比較喜歡
Dialogue: 0,1:35:20.48,1:35:22.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我一點都不想被你愛上
Dialogue: 0,1:35:23.48,1:35:25.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不然你想被誰愛上？
Dialogue: 0,1:35:25.73,1:35:28.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,越來越不像你了
Dialogue: 0,1:35:29.77,1:35:32.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對了，我差點忘了
Dialogue: 0,1:35:34.81,1:35:35.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這包
Dialogue: 0,1:35:37.15,1:35:41.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那個護士另外賠了一筆錢
Dialogue: 0,1:35:43.48,1:35:47.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是她表示誠意的方式吧
Dialogue: 0,1:35:58.31,1:35:59.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來了
Dialogue: 0,1:35:59.73,1:36:00.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好
Dialogue: 0,1:36:01.81,1:36:03.02,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你好
Dialogue: 0,1:36:05.85,1:36:09.34,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這個還給你
Dialogue: 0,1:36:10.48,1:36:12.01,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你的誠意
Dialogue: 0,1:36:13.60,1:36:14.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我很抱歉
Dialogue: 0,1:36:17.69,1:36:22.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你害我家庭四分五裂了
Dialogue: 0,1:36:26.06,1:36:27.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,阿輝
Dialogue: 0,1:36:28.98,1:36:31.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,跟你沒關係
Dialogue: 0,1:36:31.77,1:36:33.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,當然有關係
Dialogue: 0,1:36:34.77,1:36:36.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,她是我媽媽
Dialogue: 0,1:37:44.22,1:37:47.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂，我是野野宮
Dialogue: 0,1:37:47.97,1:37:49.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我是良多
Dialogue: 0,1:37:50.18,1:37:53.17,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是阿良啊，上次謝謝你回來
Dialogue: 0,1:37:54.26,1:37:55.13,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,1:37:56.64,1:37:57.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那個…
Dialogue: 0,1:37:58.39,1:37:59.88,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你找你爸嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:38:00.64,1:38:01.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不
Dialogue: 0,1:38:05.26,1:38:06.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想說對不起
Dialogue: 0,1:38:08.76,1:38:12.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不用啦，家人別這麼嚴肅
Dialogue: 0,1:38:14.14,1:38:14.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我以前…
Dialogue: 0,1:38:15.64,1:38:19.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,以前的事早忘了，別再提了
Dialogue: 0,1:38:19.72,1:38:22.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我比較想跟你閒話家常
Dialogue: 0,1:38:22.64,1:38:27.33,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,比如說誰戴假髮，誰去整形
Dialogue: 0,1:38:30.51,1:38:31.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,也好
Dialogue: 0,1:38:35.14,1:38:38.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你爸說要你戒酒
Dialogue: 0,1:38:42.47,1:38:43.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,嗯
Dialogue: 0,1:38:44.89,1:38:46.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:38:47.84,1:38:48.96,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我知道了
Dialogue: 0,1:38:57.13,1:39:00.00,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,屋頂綠化的年度用水量
Dialogue: 0,1:39:00.13,1:39:02.87,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,在有效利用雨水之後大幅減少
Dialogue: 0,1:39:03.97,1:39:08.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,景觀植物澆水量與備用水源
Dialogue: 0,1:39:08.93,1:39:12.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,總計是42.6立方公尺
Dialogue: 0,1:39:35.30,1:39:39.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我原本跟你一樣是建築師
Dialogue: 0,1:39:43.01,1:39:47.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這裡是專門用來研究的人工林
Dialogue: 0,1:39:57.01,1:39:57.83,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這是…
Dialogue: 0,1:40:00.01,1:40:01.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這裡生長的？
Dialogue: 0,1:40:02.13,1:40:02.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對
Dialogue: 0,1:40:04.96,1:40:08.20,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,從外面飛來也不是難事
Dialogue: 0,1:40:09.67,1:40:12.50,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,蟬在這裡產卵
Dialogue: 0,1:40:13.42,1:40:17.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,幼蟲出土到羽化
Dialogue: 0,1:40:17.63,1:40:19.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,總共要歷時15年
Dialogue: 0,1:40:20.30,1:40:21.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這麼久
Dialogue: 0,1:40:26.59,1:40:27.79,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很久嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:41:55.04,1:41:56.03,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,喂？
Dialogue: 0,1:42:09.79,1:42:12.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好意思，我是野野宮
Dialogue: 0,1:42:15.33,1:42:17.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,抱歉，我來晚了
Dialogue: 0,1:42:18.04,1:42:19.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,請進
Dialogue: 0,1:42:21.04,1:42:24.23,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他說他想放風箏
Dialogue: 0,1:42:25.04,1:42:26.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,風箏？
Dialogue: 0,1:42:26.54,1:42:29.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他跟著陌生人跑進車站了
Dialogue: 0,1:42:30.37,1:42:33.16,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他只有這種時候特別聰明
Dialogue: 0,1:42:35.33,1:42:37.19,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這有什麼好稱讚的
Dialogue: 0,1:42:37.58,1:42:39.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你應該好好教訓他
Dialogue: 0,1:42:40.12,1:42:43.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,那要不給他吃飯，把他趕走嗎
Dialogue: 0,1:42:43.95,1:42:45.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我們不會做這種事
Dialogue: 0,1:42:46.04,1:42:47.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這我當然明白
Dialogue: 0,1:42:49.83,1:42:52.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,如果你那邊有什麼困難
Dialogue: 0,1:42:52.62,1:42:54.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你可以先把琉晴送回來
Dialogue: 0,1:42:54.41,1:42:59.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對，我們完全不介意\N同時收養慶多和琉晴
Dialogue: 0,1:43:02.66,1:43:04.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你們多慮了
Dialogue: 0,1:43:05.62,1:43:07.32,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我會自己想辦法的
Dialogue: 0,1:43:11.12,1:43:12.28,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴！
Dialogue: 0,1:43:13.49,1:43:14.98,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,琉晴回家囉
Dialogue: 0,1:43:29.79,1:43:35.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你不用急著叫我們爸爸媽媽
Dialogue: 0,1:43:49.53,1:43:50.99,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,別玩了，洗好就出來
Dialogue: 0,1:43:51.12,1:43:53.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:44:06.16,1:44:07.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,1:44:32.20,1:44:33.73,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,這樣摸他
Dialogue: 0,1:44:36.49,1:44:37.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,感覺很像
Dialogue: 0,1:44:40.11,1:44:41.40,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,很像你
Dialogue: 0,1:44:46.66,1:44:48.61,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我也曾經離家出走
Dialogue: 0,1:44:53.78,1:44:55.77,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,因為太想念母親
Dialogue: 0,1:45:03.95,1:45:07.51,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,結果馬上被我爸抓回家
Dialogue: 0,1:45:47.32,1:45:48.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,接著是爸爸！
Dialogue: 0,1:46:12.15,1:46:13.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我的天啊
Dialogue: 0,1:46:15.78,1:46:18.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小琉！小琉你沒事吧！
Dialogue: 0,1:46:18.23,1:46:19.94,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小琉！
Dialogue: 0,1:46:20.73,1:46:21.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小琉
Dialogue: 0,1:46:27.94,1:46:30.52,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸，你還好嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:46:30.77,1:46:31.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:46:32.65,1:46:33.68,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要啊
Dialogue: 0,1:46:54.90,1:46:56.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你還領先喔
Dialogue: 0,1:46:57.61,1:46:58.39,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好了
Dialogue: 0,1:46:59.19,1:47:00.10,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,太好了
Dialogue: 0,1:47:01.61,1:47:02.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,找到了？
Dialogue: 0,1:47:02.81,1:47:03.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:47:05.27,1:47:06.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,最小的給你
Dialogue: 0,1:47:06.69,1:47:07.64,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好小
Dialogue: 0,1:47:09.44,1:47:10.30,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,謝謝
Dialogue: 0,1:47:10.69,1:47:12.85,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,預備
Dialogue: 0,1:47:12.98,1:47:14.56,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,拋竿
Dialogue: 0,1:47:19.15,1:47:21.06,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 你釣到爸爸了    - 朝那邊才對
Dialogue: 0,1:47:23.06,1:47:23.60,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來，琉晴
Dialogue: 0,1:47:23.73,1:47:25.09,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,再一次
Dialogue: 0,1:47:25.60,1:47:26.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎麼了啦
Dialogue: 0,1:47:34.65,1:47:36.05,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,來囉
Dialogue: 0,1:47:41.27,1:47:43.18,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不要啦
Dialogue: 0,1:47:50.56,1:47:52.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,巨蟹座，天蠍座
Dialogue: 0,1:47:52.64,1:47:53.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,雙子座
Dialogue: 0,1:47:55.94,1:47:57.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 天蠍座    - 盾牌座
Dialogue: 0,1:47:58.27,1:47:59.47,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,是天秤座
Dialogue: 0,1:48:00.77,1:48:03.80,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,水瓶座，處女座
Dialogue: 0,1:48:03.94,1:48:05.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有流星
Dialogue: 0,1:48:07.14,1:48:08.38,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快許願
Dialogue: 0,1:48:17.60,1:48:19.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小琉許了什麼願望？
Dialogue: 0,1:48:20.48,1:48:23.76,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我想回去有爸爸媽媽的家
Dialogue: 0,1:48:25.39,1:48:26.63,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,小琉
Dialogue: 0,1:48:31.60,1:48:32.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起
Dialogue: 0,1:48:36.35,1:48:37.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,沒關係
Dialogue: 0,1:48:39.77,1:48:40.97,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,真的
Dialogue: 0,1:49:05.60,1:49:06.55,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,怎麼了？
Dialogue: 0,1:49:10.81,1:49:13.26,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我開始對琉晴有感情了
Dialogue: 0,1:49:18.22,1:49:21.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不好嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:49:23.93,1:49:29.59,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我覺得好對不起慶多
Dialogue: 0,1:49:32.93,1:49:35.42,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好像背叛了他
Dialogue: 0,1:49:39.43,1:49:41.46,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道他現在…
Dialogue: 0,1:51:23.84,1:51:25.45,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,早餐想吃什麼？
Dialogue: 0,1:51:32.88,1:51:34.21,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,要吃嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:52:23.54,1:52:24.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,歡迎光臨
Dialogue: 0,1:52:25.30,1:52:27.78,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,買燈泡？你要幾瓦的？
Dialogue: 0,1:52:29.09,1:52:29.62,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我回來了
Dialogue: 0,1:52:29.75,1:52:32.29,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,- 小琉，怎麼啦？    - 你回來啦
Dialogue: 0,1:52:33.09,1:52:33.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,1:52:36.17,1:52:37.12,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多！
Dialogue: 0,1:52:37.38,1:52:38.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多！
Dialogue: 0,1:53:23.08,1:53:24.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多
Dialogue: 0,1:53:26.46,1:53:27.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起
Dialogue: 0,1:53:29.29,1:53:30.37,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:53:32.96,1:53:34.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我好想見你
Dialogue: 0,1:53:35.46,1:53:37.54,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,我打破約定來找你了
Dialogue: 0,1:53:38.25,1:53:40.41,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸不像爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:53:44.87,1:53:46.08,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你說的對
Dialogue: 0,1:53:47.50,1:53:51.57,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不過這六年來
Dialogue: 0,1:53:52.75,1:53:54.66,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,爸爸一直都是你的爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:53:56.71,1:54:00.07,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,雖然表現很差，但還是你的爸爸
Dialogue: 0,1:54:06.71,1:54:08.04,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你送我的玫瑰花
Dialogue: 0,1:54:12.58,1:54:14.24,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起我搞丟了
Dialogue: 0,1:54:19.62,1:54:20.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,對不起
Dialogue: 0,1:54:26.50,1:54:27.70,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,相機裡…
Dialogue: 0,1:54:30.54,1:54:32.49,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,有好多你拍的照片
Dialogue: 0,1:54:43.62,1:54:44.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,還有鋼琴
Dialogue: 0,1:54:48.58,1:54:50.86,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,其實爸爸也是中途就放棄了
Dialogue: 0,1:55:01.91,1:55:06.95,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,慶多，任務可以結束了
Dialogue: 0,1:55:58.99,1:56:00.15,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,他們來了
Dialogue: 0,1:56:08.57,1:56:09.53,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,回來啦
Dialogue: 0,1:56:19.03,1:56:20.31,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,哥哥
Dialogue: 0,1:56:34.07,1:56:34.81,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,進去吧？
Dialogue: 0,1:56:36.28,1:56:37.14,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,好
Dialogue: 0,1:56:49.03,1:56:49.89,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,進去吧
Dialogue: 0,1:56:50.03,1:56:51.27,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,快進去
Dialogue: 0,1:56:54.74,1:56:57.90,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,你知道蜘蛛人是蜘蛛嗎？
Dialogue: 0,1:56:59.07,1:57:01.93,Default,,0000,0000,0000,,不知道，現在才知道

