Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Corinthians, my life
Corinthians, my story
Corinthians, my love
Kick-off at the Morumbi stadium!
- Delivery for apartment 14.
- Wait in the cage.
Your autograph here, man.
Thanks.
And it's a rough foul
for the Sâo Paulo team.
Asshole!
It's as if it were
a penalty shot.
Corinthians fans are on edge here.
The team could be relegated.
It's a great suffering
for the fans.
A moment of great anxiety...
Oh Lord, Almighty...
Keep working miracles
in our homes...
Thank you, Father...
I was troubled, I was lost...
Hallelujah!
Let us praise the Lord
With a hymn...
Amen, Lord. Glory be to Jesus.
I want to tell you
that you are
so important to God
suffer not your anguish and pain
stop feeling inferior
stop saying
you're no one
I am here to speak
of the strength you have within
the love you have within
the Holy Spirit moves inside you
Felipe!
Good morning, everybody.
Good morning, coach.
Before we start, listen
to what I'm going to say.
Any idea how many kids are after
a place here?
Hundreds of thousands...
But this is not the street.
Out there
it's dog-eat-dog.
But not here...
We've got rules here.
You show off, you get cut.
You hog the ball, you're out.
Rough fouls, you're out.
Understood?
Yes, sir.
Soccer is team work.
Go, son!
Fucking shit!
Over here!
Pass the ball!
You wanna play by yourself,
play solitaire!
Ball-hog!
Everything alright?
Fine.
This kid inside...
Doesn't wanna get off.
He's made four rounds with me today.
Got no family.
They let them
wander around loose...
If you paid attention
to what I said earlier, you'll get it.
I really hope next time
you have better luck. Okay?
I'm only keeping three today.
This kid here, him and the goalie.
You others are free to go.
Thanks. Good luck!
Shower!
And you, pal.
You like to hog the ball.
You should eat three balls
before you come to the field.
You play well, but with that attitude,
you won't go far.
May
- Come on, dude.
- Fuck off.
If they had tryouts
for the elderly, huh?
I'd make the cut for sure!
- The Ace is back.
- The ball, Ace.
Dickhead.
The Ace is all violence.
The Ace holds the ball.
Dario stands up...
Come on, pony-tail.
To Denis.
Back to Dinho.
To Dario.
To Dinho.
Denis traps the ball...
To Dario, maybe...
Dinho traps it, turns
and it's a goal!
And what a goal!
"Cidade Líder" is delirious.
This goal is for Jesus.
- Sure, Athlete for Christ.
- Pure luck, son-of-a-bitch.
If I'm a son-of-a-bitch,
you are, too.
- Are you fucking crazy, dude?
- Sorry, man. I missed the shot.
Missed it?
Fucking asshole.
It's a goal!
- Where you been this late?
- None of your business.
Show respect
to your older brother, man.
Brother, my ass.
I'm no son of a cuckold.
Son-of-a-bitch!
Who's the son of a cuckold, huh?
Say it!
Say it, you fucking bastard.
- Go look for your daddy, twerp.
- Stop!
- Speak up, little bastard.
- Your daddy's the cuckold.
- Stop!
Enough!
- Where you been out so late?
- Here and there.
- You have a home, you know?
- Yeah, I know.
Corinthians in Minor League, bro.
Worse: Corinthians in Mini-League!
You looking for a beating?
You don't think it's funny?
Asshole!
Reginaldo! watch your mouth!
Pain in the ass, dude.
Let it go, Denis.
Dario!
Let him be, Mom.
He's pissed off because of the tryouts.
Fucking peg-leg.
Leave me alone!
He's blacker than me, isn't he?
If I'm this black,
he must be black as coal.
Give me that. I'll finish it.
Go to bed, go on.
Hey, check out the dude, bros.
Dinho, what's with the suit, man?
Don't speak to the sinners no more?
Hey dude! I'm talking to you.
Hey, fuckhead.
You a bible boy now, huh?
Once a lowlife, always a lowlife, bro.
Butthead.
Quiet, Gandhi!
Reginaldo!
You all alone again?
You poor thing!
And the little brother,
When's he due?
Prick.
Cleuza! Should I push you,
or can you fall out yourself?
God forbid, Dona Estela!
Don't say that!
Aren't you asking for it?
Don't you want your windows cleaned?
Sure, but I don't want anyone killed.
Climb down, Cleuza, please.
Whatever you say...
Didn't I buy you a squeegee?
- No, you didn't.
- Odd...
I thought I'd told you
I meant to buy a squeegee.
Age has its advantages.
Name one, Arlindo.
- At 18, you can...
- Go tojail.
That, too.
I wish I were 18 now, kid.
- 18 is the end of the line.
- Don't say that!
Okay, the tryouts are over.
But soccer's no exact science.
Garrincha started playing
for Botafogo at 19.
Garrincha...
Ah, tell Cleuza I can't make it
to your party.
What party?
Shit...
Fucking shit.
Dinho!
What's that in your ear?
You a playboy now?
You deaf?
Sorry, I was listening
to the commentary.
The soccer wrap-up?
Don't waste your time, man.
Santos is going to blast
you off the field.
Tell them I said so!
- I was just going inside to close up...
- Good. Put that shit away.
Hey Bible boy!
Soccer belong to God, too?
Sure.
So who did Jesus
root for, then?
Get back to work.
Need help?
No, it's okay.
Hey, help yourselves to snacks.
I'll serve the others.
Dario will be here soon.
Do it, bro.
They're sick of being faithful,
sick of being wives.
They'd rather be the other one.
You rot.
Tell me what you want.
I want to be the other one!
You're the wife.
You're bored.
Beautiful!
I want to be the other one!
Surprise parties are tricky.
Sometimes they backfire.
I must have spent
a hundred bucks on this party.
A hundred?
I bought the pastries from Luzia
and she gave me the cake.
Don't forget my snacks.
Were you planning to charge her
for this shit?
Hello.
Hey, Dario!
For the love of God.
Dario's here!
Happy birthday!
Lights out!
Come on, Dario.
Happy birthday to you
Happy birthday to you...
Show this to the assistant.
Tryouts in 30 minutes.
Next.
- What's your name?
- Douglas da Silva.
- Year of birth?
- 90.
- Position?
- Left midfielder.
- Next.
- Wendel Silva.
- Year of birth?
- 91.
- Position?
- Full-back.
- Next.
- Eduardo Silva.
- You're from?
- Minas Gerais.
Next.
Jonathan Venâncio.
Vinicius Rocha.
Carlos Mathias.
Next.
- Position?
- Striker.
- Winger.
- Left midfielder.
- Midfielder.
- Center forward.
- Sweeper.
- Winger.
- Striker.
- Fullback.
- Goalkeeper.
- Next, please.
Name?
Jonas.
- What year?
- 90.
Take this form.
Good luck, Jonas.
All right?
- Name?
- Dario Costa Alves.
- What year?
- 90.
- Perfect. Position?
- Deep forward.
- Where you from?
- Cidade Líder.
- Where's that?
- Here in Sâo Paulo.
Show this to the assistant.
Tryouts in 30 minutes.
- Good luck.
- Thanks.
Next.
Look, shithead.
Fuck!
- Fill'er up, dude.
- The money?
- In my pocket.
- Can I see it?
Don't trust me, bro?
Got 10,000 gallons in there.
Come on... just two, three.
No.
Chicken shit.
Guys,
change fast.
Let's go, move it.
The next group now, you all ready?
I wanna see some soccer!
I've seen nothing yet.
The tryout is on...
all I've seen is garbage.
And the fucker misses it...
- Zero skill...
- That's bad, man.
Let's get this over with.
Lay out thejerseys.
Red here, blue there.
The coach will talk to you.
Hey, thanks for the effort
but unfortunately
I can't keep anybody.
God bless you
and good luck.
Now, you, come on over.
Split up in groups.
Reds over here. Blues over there.
Blues over there.
You all know what
you're here for, right?
Try to play as a team even
though you don't know each other.
I want to see the best
of you! Good luck!
Turn, turn the game.
Turn, turn...
Go, go!
Where's the defense?
- Beautiful goal.
- That kid is good, pony-tail.
Círio...
Come on, kiddo. It's your dad,
not the boogieman. Shit!
I thought the kid
had seen the devil.
Very funny!
Can I come in?
Come in.
- Your mother there?
- No, she's at work.
Hey, you got a pen?
No pen?
A courier without a pen!
That's funny!
Gimme a break, Bianca,
it fell out of my pocket.
A pen: It's basic, no?
Where do I sign?
Sig-na-tu-re!
It's been two months
since you left a cent, you know?
In three months I pay off the bike
and I'll bring in some cash.
If they don't steal this one too.
Get off my case, dude.
Bring the kid to say goodbye,
I gotta split.
Better not. He was up all night
With a fever.
If you want,
I'll take you to the clinic.
It's taken care of.
I'll kiss him for you, OK?
- The worse is you still kiss good.
- I am good.
What about a motel?
I'd rather you left money
for the kid's medicine.
It's raining cats and dogs.
I'm broke, I'm late.
What you mean, stalling?
You make eight reais an hour?
I only make five, dude.
You've got a lot of nerve, kid!
Throw this ID away
or you'll end up injail.
You saw me play.
Give me a chance, coach.
You play well, but there's lots
like you and they're only 15!
Time is tough on an athlete.
Mechanic.
One year experience.
Assistant Accountant.
Kitchen Help.
Three year experience.
June
- I was just going to get them.
- No problem.
I found this money
in Bruno's pockets.
Thank you, Cleuza,
put it in his bedroom.
- Care for some coffee?
- Sounds good.
- Here it is, nice and hot.
- Good!
I was peeking...
Bruno's playing in the rain.
He'll get sick.
He's a big boy.
Besides, he's the one
who'll enjoy the flu, not me.
Thanks. Sit down, Cleuza.
Come on, sit down.
Excuse me.
Hey, kid, watch out.
- Anything wrong with my work?
- I didn't say that.
I just thought it'd be better for you
to stay home.
Three months after the baby is born
you can come back.
Dona Estela, don't do this to me.
Oh, God! I have a patient in 20 minutes.
I have to go.
Hey, dudes!
Hi, Gloria.
You disappear. Not a word.
You rich, now?
I'm fucking broke, babe.
I need more work!
Anything, anywhere.
Just say the word, I'll go.
Okay, I'll see.
Babe?
Ain't I your favorite?
Go wait out there
With my twenty other favorites.
Great.
What's up?
Cool?
Wake up, dickhead.
Stop it, Bruno.
I don't know if he can.
He has practice...
I'm desperate, Cleuza.
I promised the guys.
It's for the championship!
I know what you want.
There. Take it.
One more.
Now go do your homework,
'cause soccer's not your thing.
Sometimes we waste so much time
dreaming of foolish things...
We'd like to own. Things...
that keep us away from Jesus.
For example, we spend 12 months
paying for... a sofa!
Isn't that true?
Who hasn't done that, right?
Every month we pay
for a sofa we hardly ever sit on.
That's why I ask you, sister.
Does your house belong to you?
No.
- Who does it belong to?
- To Jesus.
This land isn't ours, brothers.
This land belongs to... Jesus!
Hallelujah.
- Who came in?
- The star.
Dario, how did the tryouts go, son?
Jesus, Reginaldo!
What's with your hair!
You look like a bum!
- Can you fix nigger hair?
- Of course you can.
- Can you fix his hair too?
- I'll get the belt right now!
- At least he left his belt!
- You uppity little nigger.
Come back here, Reginaldo!
You warming up the engine?
What?
- You warming up the engine?
- No, loading the compressor.
I've seen you on my bus.
You ride the bus a lot.
- I like it.
- Takes all kinds.
- Why do you start in second?
- What?
What's the low for,
if you always pull away in second?
Low is too short, it's tiring.
Can you show me how to drive?
Step on the clutch.
Right there. Harder.
Now shift into low.
Low or second?
First you learn it right,
then you do whichever way you want.
Low, back to second, forward to third,
back to fourth,
and fifth here on the right.
Rear, you shift into neutral
and pull it towards you.
Good job, kiddo!
Great fit! Perfect.
Keep the cleats, dude.
And we're all even.
Won't your mom be pissed off?
She doesn't give a shit, dude.
Really?
Cool, man.
Good ball, good ball!
Pass the ball.
Bruno!
That's fucking unfair.
Dario!
You fucking crazy, dude!
I'll get my maid's kid
to play for our team, too.
Son-of-a-bitch!
Motherfucker!
Shit!
What an asshole, this Raul.
All set. wanna check
the oil and water?
Sure, go ahead.
- Hey, Dinho.
- I'm working, Denis.
Come on, bro, just a sec.
Dude, I'm short on cash.
There's this babe. Can you lend me some?
Everything all right, sir?
Yo, if you plan to fill up, okay.
Otherwise get lost.
- Easy, bro, I wasjust.
- I'm not your "bro", man.
Just move, you're in the way.
You dissing me, dude?
This is no motorcycle stop, man. Out!
I'm no bum.
Fill up the fucking tank.
Can I pay?
Take the man's card, go!
Get lost, beat it.
Say again, bro?
Sorry, sir.
- Could be worse, could be 0-0...
- This tournament sucks, man.
- Corinthians down to Minor?
- Don't say that!
Lmagine me paying to see Corinthians
play against...
sorry ass team!
Corinthians versus Hawaii.
God forbid! I miss...
the good old days.
That was a team!
Sweet Dr. Socrates!
Cheers, Doc!
- Aren't you coming home, Mom?
- Hey, Reginaldo!
Go see if I'm out on the corner.
Come on, you've had enough.
You go ahead, I'm coming, OK?
You got it from the corner gas station?
That gas is pure water, dude.
Bruno?
- 23rd. Avenue is close, right?
- Sure. why?
I could get off there.
And catch the Beltway.
No, we party tonight, dude.
How long has it been?
You kicked ass,
now it's time to get some ass, dude.
I can take you home later.
Come on, bro...
Sorry.
Good evening.
- Nice to meet you, I'm Dinho.
- Dinho, Gloria.
- Denis has done the honors?
- He sure has.
- Some water, sister?
- Cut the crap, she's no church-goer.
But I respect those who are.
We're having some booze.
To Jesus.
- Reginaldo been through here?
- Yes.
I came with him.
The dudes are making serious money
selling fake acid.
There's a sucker born every minute.
Plain paper and they get real high!
What's up, dudes?
Take your seat, bro.
I'm a genius, I'll get the Nobel Prize
for chemistry with this.
The formula: Ecstasy, LSD, and Viagra.
The Holy Trimix!
You can fuck all night with that!
Dario, a smaller hit for you,
for your first time.
Go on, Dario. Trust me.
I'll have a snack.
You know, I was reading
something, so beautiful.
"Thejoy of having a shepherd... "
Give us a break, OK, bro?
I'lljust go on in, then.
Our house is yours.
We're poor but we like to share
What we have.
Why, thank you.
Good night.
- Is the sofa free, dickhead?
- No, mofo.
You saw the babe, man.
Hit me with some cash, bro, please!
You fuck me up with the boss
then you ask me for money?!
Your boss is an asshole.
The asshole pays me.
And I'm the only one helping mom here.
Soon as I pay off the bike,
I'll chip in too.
Lend me some cash, man.
For the love of Saint Jesus!
Look the other way.
Shit, bro.
- I've got 20.
- 20, bro?
What kind of dump motel
can I take her with 20 bucks, man?
- You taking her to a motel?
- No, to church!
- Freed up the sofa already?
- Sure, bro.
- I love you.
- Now you love me, son-of-a-bitch.
Where'd you get that money?
- None of your business.
- Yes it is.
- You know the girl?
- The "ho" from hisjob?
Shhh! You know her?
You all hot
for your brother's slut?
Shut up, dickhead.
I'm heading for my sofa.
Fuck!
You crazy, dude!
Dario! Man, look at me.
Dinho!
- What's happening?
- Come here, bro.
Look at me!
Wake up, look at me!
What's up?
Look what a mess he's in.
Get up, bro.
Hey Dario?
Let's get him into the shower.
Get up!
Keep it down.
Or mom will wake up.
Puke in the bathroom, man.
Dinho, do this for me, okay?
I've been up all night.
Head up.
You better?
Let's get you up.
Look up.
What's going on?
What is this?
Dario's feeling sick, Mom.
Feeling sick?
You been drinking, Dario?
No.
How did you get these?
It's a present.
A present?
You took money from my drawer
to buy those shoes?
I work my fingers to the bone
for you to steal my money?
- Put this deadbeat to bed.
- Sure, Mom!
Isn't there a man in this house
to unclog this goddamn drain?
I'm in doubt.
I'm a failure.
You know I'm slipping away.
I'm no one.
I'm weak.
In God's peace, brother.
Jesus hears your prayers.
I don't think he wants
to hear me, Pastor.
Don't say that, Dinho.
When you accepted Jesus,
Jesus accepted you.
You know, brother.
Three years of struggle
and I've never seen the church so empty.
With the "franchise" church on the corner,
they're alljumping ship.
And what for?
To hear washy sermons?
To believe Jesus is nice?
Jesus is not nice.
Never was, never will be.
I still serve the Lord
in this house, Pastor.
Until when?
Shall we pray for those
Who will abandon us?
August
- Good morning, Rosa.
- Morning, son.
- In God's peace.
- Amen.
I brought a psalm for us to read.
That's good.
"How long wilt thou
forget me, O Lord?"
"How long wilt thou hide thy face
from me?"
"For my days are consumed
like smoke. "
"And my bones burn
like glowing embers. "
"My heart is smitten,
and withered like grass;
"so that I forget to eat my bread. "
"My days are like the evening shadow;
"I wither away like grass. "
This dog, 15 reais.
Pass the ball.
Reginaldo, pass the ball.
Pass it now.
Pass the fucking ball!
Ball-hog! Let it go!
See what you did, dude?
Little nigger bastard!
- You're the bastard!
- Fuck off, dude.
Pull them away!
Stop with this obsession.
I'm going to call the school
every day to make sure you're there.
You better be there.
All I need is a summons
from Juvenile Court because of you.
If that dumbass calls you a bastard again,
beat the shit out of him!
My little Mike Tyson!
What?
It was me who took the 50 bucks, okay?
From your drawer.
You're a pain, you know?
What for?
I bought the sofa.
You bought the sofa?
A garbage collector
can make up to 600 reais a month.
For the 11 days of sign-ups,
even applicants with college degrees
Wait in line, day and night.
The 100,000 applicants
have to take three tests...
In the fruit bowI, Reginaldo.
More attacks on buses
in South Side Sâo Paulo.
Three buses burned.
The atmosphere is tense...
Scram!
You scram, dude.
Dario, you've been on that sofa
since morning!
Get ajob,
do something with your life!
I've got a hot tip for you:
The sparkplug trick.
Break the tip off, lick it
and hit the windshield.
It shatters pronto, dude.
That's such bull, bro.
What bull, giant Mop-Head?
The dude may be a mop-head
but he ain't a dork like you.
Who's a dork, dick-face?
You!
What, dude?
Are you two making out?
- No, I'm fucking your sister, that slut.
- Fucking my sister, my ass.
Surely not your ass.
Hey, your back's burning, bro?
Dude, this is true love.
He's "punching in" every day.
In due form...
He'll be the boss in no time!
Yes, sir.
Sure, boss.
Mop-head boss.
You crazy, twerp?
Can't you see me?
Go watch your cartoons!
I was watching porn, dickhead.
Don't even know what that is.
Hey, blubber-butt.
I've got a hot tip for you.
A scout is coming to the sandlot.
Arlindo said to tell you.
When?
Now you wanna know.
- Spit it out, man!
- Apologize first.
I'm listening. I'm listening...
Fuck off. Nigger son-of-a-bitch.
Butthead.
Day after tomorrow, deadbeat.
But you have to fix your ID.
Second.
Third.
Clutch.
Fourth.
Go for it, Reginaldo.
Hello!
Hello.
So, the lady, the missus...
What's her name again?
- Estela.
- Right
She told me to introduce myself.
I'm Almerinda.
She told me your name too, but I forgot.
- What's your name again?
- Cleuza.
Right! Cleuza.
So, she said you needed a hand
With the belly and all.
- When's the baby due?
- Not for a long time.
Bitch!
She hired somebody else.
Never signed my work papers.
But I'll get a lawyer
and sue her fucking ass!
Don't curse, Ma.
So you're a saint now?
Some fat saint you are.
Think I've forgotten
the trouble you've caused me?
I've accepted Jesus, Mom.
Jesus, my ass.
Maybe if you had accepted Jesus,
you wouldn't be as you are now.
Come again?
- You heard me.
- Say it again, I dare you.
Another child whose father
is a mystery to us.
You shut your mouth.
I'm mother and father to you.
Hear? That's me!
Go, kid.
Check out number 8.
Dario.
What a steal! See that?
Go, kid, go!
What a goal!
Watch him! Me, here.
End of the second half.
And still hustling, look!
And a team player, see?
With him it's always like that, man.
- Well done, Arlindo! Your kid can play.
- I've trained him since he was little.
He's at his prime!
Don't miss the chance.
You know it's notjust up to me, right?
So, Arlindo, how did the talk go
With the man?
If you "tip" him, it's a deal,
if not, you're out...
How much of a "tip"?
- Quite a bit
- How much is a bit?
- Three!
- Three what?
Three thousand.
Take it or leave it.
If you pay, you have a deal.
If you don't...
Three thousand?
Three months' pay,
and you're all even.
I'm fucked.
- Good evening.
- Looking good, huh!
Had a stool test?
Police HQ has still not released
the identity of the victims.
Condition, still unknown.
Is this an isolated case,
or another wave
of attacks on urban buses?
Public transportation
in Brazil's largest city
is in a state of chaos.
Fleets are taking their buses off
the streets tonight.
The city is once again...
I'm sick of all this.
I'm going back to the country.
To do what? Plant sugar cane?
You're caught between a rock
and a hard place.
I'll kill you!
You were on the bus?
I was awake all night
because of you, son of a bitch!
I'll kill the son of a bitch!
Easy, Mom! You'll hurt him!
- Morning, Cida!
- Morning, Cleuza.
- Everything okay?
- Yes, and you?
- So, you watch him for me?
- Of course.
He doesn't leave
for school until noon, okay?
We'll watch cartoons,
right, Reginaldo?
He loves cartoons.
Don't let him go near the dog.
Don't worry.
Bye, I'm late already.
Don't you touch anything!
- Bye, Cida.
- Bye.
Go in!
Go!
Gandhi!
Can't you see us?
We're not invisible!
Look, look!
Bastard ran the red light.
Ran the fucking red light!
Son of a bitch!
Look what you did, motherfucker!
Fucking shit!
Mom.
What, Denis?
- Look what I brought you.
- For me?
A gift?
- Where you going, Reginaldo?
- To the bathroom.
Don't even dream of
going out tonight, you hear?
This is beautiful, son! God!
All these pockets.
That's like a coin purse, right?
And for documents here.
What's this?
It's like, I found the bag.
- No stolen stuff in my house.
- I didn't steal the bag!
I just wanted you to have it.
This bag has an owner.
It shouldn't be hard to find.
It is now yours, Dona Cleuza.
Bi?
Bi!
- Who is it?
- It's me, open up!
You confuse me, Denis.
September
Give me a hand. With this crazy weather,
thejerseys won't dry.
Sâo Paulo, man.
How's the story
With the man's down payment?
I spoke to my Mom.
She said she'll work it out.
Her employer will give her
an advance or something.
It's not the total, but.
It's something, I guess.
You realize that without the money,
no deal, right?
Lt'll work out. Don't worry.
And on Thursday
We'll fuck up those dorks, right?
- That's my ace talking.
- We going to kick some ass, man.
I really need this, bro.
It's a man'sjob, dig?
Then how do you do it?
I pretend, dude.
We can take a drive,
but not on my bike or yours.
Dig it, Valentino Rossi?
Hey...
You still doing the babe there?
Why, you in line, bro?
If she's available,
got to do thejob, right?
- I'd say you could bang her once.
- Once?
- She's kind of weird.
- Weird, what, a transvestite?
You fucking with me, bro?
Be prepared, dig?
- Take some boxing gloves.
- Boxing?
I love boxing, dude.
Check out the clinch!
If thou givest with joy
Thou shalt reign in heaven.
Reign in heaven!
If thou givest with joy
Thou shalt reign in heaven.
What is the difference...
between faith...
and necessity?
Necessity, brothers and sisters,
is man's will.
And faith...
Faith is God's will!
And when you have faith,
When your heart is full of faith,
the Lord makes miracles!
- Isn't it true, brother Dinho?
- It's true. Praise God.
Brother Dinho, bring sister Rosa here.
Brother Mateus,
move your chair please.
Come, sister Rosa.
Oh! Beloved Lord,
light the way for sister Rosa,
give her strength.
Let Jesus lift up your legs, sister.
Have faith,
and you'll walk, sister Rosa!
Hallelujah!
Very often we think
we're 100% faithful to God.
Remember our conversation
about being "100% faithful"?
But we're not.
A little bit of faith is missing.
And this little bit of faith
means a lot to God.
Let's pray for sister Rosa
and praise the Lord.
Here, for your work.
I don't want anything, Pastor.
It's not a handout, brother.
This is your payment.
- It's not much, but it can help.
- Thanks, but you owe me nothing.
I have to go.
- Praise the Lord.
- Praise the Lord, brother.
What's up?
My man here, Japs.
What can I do for you two?
A bike, dude.
Like what?
This one good?
This bike rocks, right?
Dude fell off, bent the sidebars,
I traded the parts.
It's in perfect shape.
I can give you a good deal.
What about a lease?
Hey, Julio, you see this?
This professional team thing
is kind of complicated.
Without an indication from the top,
nothing happens.
- Arlindo explained it to me.
- So we are okay? We got a deal?
His mother's working on it.
She's a serious woman, hear?
She knows more about soccer
than you and me together.
Did you bring some... bread?
No. I mean, not today.
But don't worry. It's a sure deal.
Just a few more days.
My mom is working on it.
Next time I come I'll bring you some.
Which can be Saturday,
We have a big game then.
I can put you on the bench.
Can you stand a few minutes
in the second half?
Asshole! Fuck you!
- Evening!
- Dude.
Fill 'er up, bro.
Look here, bro.
Listen, compadre. What I want
is what's in your pocket, man.
- You'll fuck me over, man.
- None of that, mofo.
The cash, pronto.
I just want the fucking cash.
What a dork, man.
I'm working here. Dickhead.
Take that fucking hose out.
You out of you mind, mofo?
Look back again.
Go ahead, tough guy.
Wanna die? Look now.
Thanks, dork!
You don't speak to me no more,
Reginaldo?
God, what did I do
to deserve sons like these?
I hope this time I get a little girl
to rescue me from you!
Where you going?
Look for my father.
Stop that, Reginaldo.
Go back to your sofa.
Mr. Jefferson, he had a gun!
Gun, my ass. It was your brother.
Don't say that, I'm an honest man.
God is my witness!
You talk about God?
You fucking thief!
You don't know what you're saying.
I'm no thief.
You're a thief,
your brother's a thief.
Go fuck yourself.
You bible bastard.
I give you a decentjob,
you go and steal on me!
Stop!
Edson!
It's Dinho.
Let's get him inside.
I'm going to the game.
No way.
- Of course I'm going.
- No you're not.
It's too far to go with this belly.
I take the bus everyday,
belly and all. No problem.
- You don't go so far.
- Genaro will come with me.
- I'll be on the bench.
- What if he puts you in?
- He won't.
- Imagine if your father could see this?
I can't miss this, son.
- Don't look so disgusted!
- You're really stubborn, dude!
Don't worry. If I go, I go.
But I'm going.
Dinho?
Wake up.
We're going to the baptism.
Come on. wake up.
Reginaldo?
Reginaldo!
I'm going,
'cause I gave the man my word.
But with no money, it's hopeless.
Don't worry, my mom will be there.
- Her word is as good as gold, right?
- Good as gold.
Careful!
Don't let him shoot.
We'll react.
We have plenty of time.
Let go, son of a bitch!
Move, move!
Thief!
Fuck!
Gosh, what happened?
Are you hurt?
How can you drive like that
in the city?
Fuck off, asshole!
Look how you drive, bastard!
Get in the car, dude.
Go, go! Are you deaf, asshole?
A monkey?
A monkey.
Show it to mommy.
And that's a doggy.
- Can they see us inside here?
- No, the glasses are dark.
Up there, turn right!
Turn right, dickhead!
Turn right. Right!
Man, I said turn right!
There was a truck behind me.
Why you buy this fucking car for?
To go 15 miles an hour?
- How much time left?
- Fifteen minutes.
Tell the subs to warm up.
Come on, everybody.
Dario, I don't see your mother.
Wellington! Come here.
Brother Jonathan,
do you take Jesus
as your one and only Savior?
I baptize you in the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Turn right here, dude!
Do it, man! Ain't nojoy ride!
Easy, easy.
Down now, down.
Do it, man, you dissing me?
Fucking old chicken shit!
Stop the car right there.
Turn the engine off.
Turn it off, dickhead!
Take my wallet,
my Palm, cell phone, everything...
- But let me go!
- Look at me, motherfucker!
Do you see me?
What?
Do you see me, asshole?
Get the hell out of here!
Out of here, motherfucker!
Come here, it's your chance.
Bless us over these waters, Lord.
Will you accept Jesus
as your one and only Savior?
I baptize you in the name of the Father,
the Son and the Holy Spirit.
Hallelujah, Lord!
Leandro, bring sister Rosa.
Rosa Assunçâo,
do you take Jesus
as your one and only Savior?
I do.
I baptize you in the name of the Father,
the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Glory, Lord!
Sister Rosa, let's now allow Jesus
to change your life?
Straighten your legs.
Have faith, sister Rosa.
Come on, sister Rosa.
Steady...
You will leave here walking, Rosa.
Dinho...
God knows
What he does, Rosa.
He knows how to hit us
Where it hurts.
They put all the pressure on us.
Wait a second, wait.
What are you doing there, kid?
- Get out!
- I'm loading the compressor.
What the hell?
Get down, kid!
Get down!
Stop, kid!
Stop!
Penalty!
Son of a bitch!
Walk.
Subs. riped by bluciano for
www.clan-sudamerica.net
Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext