Good evening.
As you see, my name is Henri Verdoux.
For 30 years, I was a bank clerk,
until the Depression of 1930,
when I found myself unemployed.
Then I became occupied in liquidating
members of the opposite sex.
It was a strictly business enterprise
to support a home and family.
Let me assure you, the career of
a Bluebeard is by no means profitable.
Only a person with undaunted optimism
would embark on such a venture.
Unfortunately, I did.
What follows is history.
Jean?
- What?
- Postman. Might be from your sister.
Yes, it might.
Can't you put that book down and see?
I can't.
Don't talk that way to your sister.
Close your mouth. It causes a draft.
- Do as you're told!
- He won't do a thing, Phoebe.
- He should have to!
- Who'll make me?
If your father was alive,
he'd make you.
Keep your big feet to yourself,
not all over the floor.
What about your two submarines?
Get up. Do as you're told!
Get your husband up. I'm reading.
Don't bother. I'll do it, Carlotta.
There. Now, look what you've done!
If you'd gone,
it wouldn't have happened.
Alright, I'll answer it.
- Hold this.
- Phoebe, be more careful.
It was an accident.
- Look where you're going.
- You should both look!
- I did. Lena got in the way.
- Alright, don't shriek.
Hey, what the -
- You old fool!
- Don't insult me. I'm not your wife.
No, one's enough in this family.
If you don't like this family,
you can go.
Don't worry, some day I'll do it.
- What is it, anyway?
- From the Paris National Bank.
- I knew it.
- Now what?
- The bank returned our letter.
- Letter?
To Thelma. She's closed her account
and left no address.
- We should tell the police.
- Why?
It's not like Thelma
to cut herself off from her family.
Thelma can take care of herself.
A woman of 50 flitting off to Paris,
marrying a man she's known two weeks?
- Don't run to the police.
- We've had no word in three months.
So what? She's on her honeymoon.
Hah! Honeymoon.
Who'd honeymoon
three months with Thelma?
I don't like her withdrawing
all her money. That's not Thelma.
- He's got it all by now.
- He'd have a job to get it from her.
Look what he's done already.
She's left home, sold her business
and married him, all in two weeks.
He must have a way with women.
I'd like to know his technique.
You're condemning a man
you haven't even met.
If he were honest,
he wouldn't avoid us.
Something terrible's
happened to Thelma!
You make me tired, all of you.
No letter,
so she's been robbed or murdered.
- Nobody said she was murdered.
- We hope.
We ought to go to the police now!
You'd better wait.
You're all hysterical.
I think Pierre's right.
Let's wait a day or two.
If we don't hear from her,
we'll go to the police.
Hey, we have a picture
of that husband of hers. Where is it?
I've got it... right here.
Funny-looking.
Must be a good salesman
to sell anything with that face.
How long's he going
to keep that incinerator burning?
It's been going for three days.
I haven't been able
to put my washing out.
Oo-la-la!
You'll be stepped on. Be careful.
There.
- Good morning, Monsieur.
- Good morning.
I have a registered letter
for Madame Thelma Varnay.
Thank you.
Oh, no.
Madame will have to sign for it.
Oh, I see. Just a moment.
Thelma, darling. A registered letter,
my dear. You must sign for it.
Don't bother to get out of the bath.
Just dry your hands.
There. Here's a pencil.
There, that's it.
Be careful now you don't catch cold.
There.
- Thank you, Monsieur. Good morning.
- Good morning.
"Madame, enclosed is 60,000 francs
as requested,
which terminates
your account at this bank."
"Thank you for your patronage.
Banque du Midi et de Marseille"
Long distance, please.
I want Balong & Company,
Paris Stock Exchange, Reaumur 65 72.
Good morning, Monsieur.
- From the Dupont Employment Agency.
- Ah, yes. Come in, come in.
- Your references?
- Oui, Monsieur.
- You know it is only a day or so?
- Your name?
- Louise.
Start by cleaning out the drawers
and dusting.
Before you dust, take down
the curtains and pack them in there.
Leave everything on the sideboard.
I'll inventory it later.
Go on with your work. I'll answer it.
Hello? Balong & Company?
This is Monsieur Verdoux.
I'll buy at opening prices
tomorrow,
500 shares of Continental Gas,
500 shares of Consolidated Copper
and 100 shares of Central Carbine,
the same 20-point margin, yes.
I'm wiring the money.
It'll be there in the morning.
Correct. Au revoir.
She no sooner married him
than she disappeared completely.
Do we have
any way of identifying him?
We had a photo of him, but Lena
threw it in the fireplace by mistake.
Too bad.
- I'd know him if I ever saw him.
- So would I.
I believe
we have all the particulars.
If we get anything,
we will let you know.
Merci, Monsieur.
- Good day, Mesdames.
- Good day, Monsieur.
- Monsieur.
- What's on your mind?
- Funny.
In three years, 12 women have
disappeared from these cities.
The history of each case
is similar to this one.
How?
They are all middle-aged,
with a small income or property.
They nearly all married
the same type of man.
- He's the husband of all of them?
- It looks that way to me.
Looks like he was married
to several at once.
He's the proverbial sailor.
With him, it's a wife in every port.
- What's his racket?
- I don't know.
- Insurance?
- No, he's too smart for that.
- None of these women has shown up.
- Murdered them?
That's just it. He's a "Bluebeard".
A mass killer,
operating all over the country.
Hold on. Before you tell the public
that, you'd better get more facts.
- M. Varnay?
- At your service, Monsieur.
M. Nutal, the real estate agent.
Mme Grosnay, M. Varnay.
- How do you do?
Madame would like to see your house,
if it's not inconvenient.
By no means. Won't you come in?
You'll pardon me,
I'm all disheveled.
I haven't had time to brush up
or do a thing.
- Oh, what lovely roses.
- From my garden.
Oh, they're divine.
- Louise.
- Oui, Monsieur.
Will you wrap these roses
for Mme Grosnay?
- You'll find paper in the drawer.
- Oui, Monsieur.
Oh, no,
you'll want them for yourself.
Madame, I want them appreciated.
I therefore give them to you.
This way, please.
The sitting room, solid oak doors
and floors, mahogany wainscoting.
- It's perfect, architecturally.
- Thank you.
We have a lovely view
of the mountains and the sea below.
Oh, those beautiful hills.
The work of the Supreme Architect.
I'm afraid
we can't compete with that.
There's the garden - 175 feet by 85.
Three apple trees, two pears, one
plum and a mulberry, and my roses.
Quite an atmosphere.
My wife put so much of herself
in this house.
We were supremely happy here.
I think one feels that.
Yes, indeed.
May I offer my condolences?
- Pardon?
- The loss of your wife.
Ah, yes. It was very sudden.
A heart attack while visiting family.
That's why I must give up this house,
get away from the memory of it.
You will pardon me, I trust.
We'll get it for nothing.
Call again. I'm very busy.
This way, please.
The dining room
and to the left, the library.
Cozy, hm?
Yes.
Uh, this way please, upstairs.
It's small
and requires very little to keep up.
We never had a servant,
but there's a maid's room.
I have a maid and a cook.
An extra bed in the maid's room
if they're females
or one of the rooms upstairs,
unless you want it for your family.
- No family.
- Just you and your husband?
No, my husband has been dead
for many years.
Indeed?
This way, please.
- M. Varnay?
- Yes?
Telephone for M. Nutal
from his office.
- Will you excuse me?
- Plaisir.
This was my wife's bedroom.
We called - uh, pardon me.
Yes, we called it our Sans-Souci.
Ah, she loved this room.
- She spent most of her time here.
- Very sunny.
We loved sun.
Some don't like it in the bedroom.
- Oh, I do.
- Scorpio.
- I beg your pardon?
- Your astrological sign.
- No, Aries.
- Ah, yes, of course.
Sky and sun - a dreamer.
It's in your eyes.
Deep pools of desire that can never
be fulfilled or understood.
- Very interesting.
- You are very interesting.
I'm also Aries. I know all about us.
We are old souls.
Strange you should come on this day.
I feel it's destiny.
- Indeed.
- If I knew you better, I'd explain.
Please do.
- However, you never married again?
- No.
Singular.
A woman of your temperament.
Why?
Because companionship
is so essential to Aries.
Oh, it's too late for that now.
Nonsense. You're on life's threshold.
One never begins to live
until one is past...
What difference does age make?
A great deal to a woman.
I venture that you were never
as attractive as now.
- You're very kind.
- No, I'm frank.
No doubt, you were extremely
beautiful as a young girl,
but your youth
could not compete with your age.
Your ripeness, your luxuriousness.
Besides, you have more character now,
more experience, more...
More everything.
- You flatter me.
- Why not?
Why shouldn't I respond to beauty
as you did to the flowers?
"What lovely roses," and impulsively
drew them near to your lips.
Lucky roses.
I wish I had the courage
to act upon my impulses.
However, life is that way. We can't.
You are divine. You are lovely.
Words are so futile.
I feel I've known you all my life.
- You must -
- This is ridiculous.
No, it's inevitable.
We can't help ourselves.
Your loveliness inspired it.
Blame your loveliness for it.
- Don't be silly.
- Try to understand.
Don't embarrass me.
Silly conventions.
This is more than a convention.
I hate to be obvious, really.
Oh, yes, there it goes. It's a bee!
Hold still, I'll get it!
Isn't that silly?
Are you hurt?
- I must have slipped.
- No doubt.
- I think we'd better go.
- I think we had.
- Will you see the other rooms?
- No, thank you. We've seen enough.
That is, unless Madame
would like to see more.
- No, thank you.
- Very well.
When Mme Grosnay decides,
we'll be in touch.
Yes, I'd like to send you a book
on astrology, if you're interested.
Don't bother.
No bother
if I know how to get in touch.
- Through our office.
- As you wish.
Ah, your roses!
Don't forget your roses.
Thank you. I'd rather not.
Madame, I shall be deeply grieved
if you don't accept them.
Thank you.
- Au revoir, Madame.
- Oh. Au revoir.
- 'Voir.
Flowers? Boutonnières?
Mme Yvonne. So nice to see you.
- Flower, Monsieur?
- Give me that one.
- Well, well, M. Verdoux!
- How do you do, sir?
It's been ages. What do you know?
- I don't even suspect anything.
- Merci.
- You are finished?
- Sit down.
Merci. M. Lavine, M. Verdoux -
an old friend of mine.
- How do you do?
- We worked together.
He was a bank cashier.
- In the good old days.
- Not so long ago.
- About three years ago.
- What do you do now?
A bit of everything -
real estate, stock market.
You must have made a killing.
- Yes.
- The market's low now, isn't it?
Buy now when everybody's selling.
- Can I offer you something?
- No, merci.
- Then if you'll pardon me.
- Of course.
- Good day, gentlemen.
- Good day.
Oh, Monsieur, don't forget this.
Merci. Merci.
Poor old Verdoux.
Seems to be doing well.
- He got a pretty raw deal.
- What do you mean?
Was with us for over 30 years.
Along came the Depression
and he was one of the first to go.
Yes, after 30 years.
Well, well, there you are.
Let's see what we have for you.
Henri Verdoux, Furniture Dealer.
Balong & Company.
We've been trying you for an hour.
The market's dropped.
We need 50,000 francs.
- When?
- In the morning, at market opening.
50,000 francs by tomorrow morning?
If not, you'll be wiped out.
I'll see what I can do.
Oh, dear.
Oh, me. Oh, me.
Ah, Lydia, the City of Corbell.
Let's see,
in Corbell the banks close at four.
C, C, C.
Corbell.
If I leave now, I can catch the 2: 15
and be there by 3:30.
That gives me half an hour.
The banks close at four.
Lydia!
I thought you were in Indochina.
- I was, my dear, I was.
- Don't "dear" me.
Three months you've been away
and not a word.
Didn't you get my letters?
I wrote you almost every day.
I got a telegram three months ago.
Running off and leaving me alone.
I have to travel for business.
I'm an engineer.
Too bad I didn't know that
before I met you.
Lydia.
Well, what do you want?
- Nothing, my dear.
- That's unusual.
I thought you might be pleased
to see me, that's all.
Is that all?
I only see you
when you want something.
Lydia... I refuse to quarrel
with you, it's too ugly.
Life can so easily degenerate
into something sordid and vulgar.
Let us try to keep it
beautiful and dignified.
We are not young anymore.
In the sunset of our lives,
we need companionship,
love, tenderness.
Most of all we need each other.
Ah, Lydia.
We've had such beautiful,
inspiring moments together...
and we can have many more.
I'm getting too old
for that nonsense.
There you go - age again. I thought
I'd cured you of that complex.
I'm cured of you,
running off like you did.
- Lydia -
- Sit down.
What were you doing in Indochina?
Building bridges, my dear.
We ran into a lot of trouble.
The super-structure was all wrong.
We had to draw up new plans.
Then they cancelled our contract
due to the crisis.
What crisis?
- The financial crisis.
- What do you mean?
The worst catastrophe in years.
Banks will collapse everywhere.
It isn't in the newspapers.
They're trying to keep it quiet,
but we were tipped off.
Bah! I don't believe it.
Don't bother your little head
about such matters.
What do you mean, a financial crisis?
Tomorrow there'll be a run
on every bank.
Fiddlesticks. It's all nonsense.
It's of no consequence to you, but
I'm vitally interested, that's all.
- So am I.
- You have nothing to worry about.
Every penny I have
is in ready cash in the bank.
- You know that, you fool.
- What bank?
The Mutual Trust.
That's the worst of all! Get it out!
What time is it?
- Are you mad?
- Every bank will be closed tomorrow.
- What will I do with it?
- Decide later.
I don't want 70,000 francs
lying about.
How much? Never mind.
Don't talk. Hurry up. Quick.
It's a lie.
You're losing time!
The banks close at four.
Quick, hurry! Come on, dear.
I must be out of my mind to do this.
You wait and see.
- The cashier said it was nonsense.
- You expect him to say otherwise?
I'd sooner believe him than you.
Why couldn't I leave it
in my safe deposit box?
A revolution might happen. New
government would confiscate it all.
The best thing is to have it here,
where you can lay your hands on it.
Where you can lay your hands on it.
Lydia, you're very tired.
What you need is a good night's rest.
I need my head examined.
I've never heard of such a thing...
Emptying my safe deposit box.
Burglars might break in.
What nonsense.
Good thing we haven't any servants.
It's perfectly safe tonight.
Should have been left where it was.
Very well, if you're uneasy about it,
put it back.
- You can do that in the morning.
- I certainly will.
- Turn out the lights.
- Yes, my dear.
- Did you lock the doors?
- Early this evening.
Latch the kitchen window?
Everything's attended to.
- Well, did you?
- Yes, my dear.
- What a night.
- Yes, a full moon.
How beautiful,
this pale, Endymion hour.
What are you talking about?
Endymion, my dear -
a beautiful youth
possessed by the moon.
Forget about him and get to bed.
Yes, my dear.
"Our feet were soft in flowers..."
Hello? Hello?
Long distance, please.
Paris Stock Exchange,
Reaumur 65 72. Thank you.
Hello, Balong & Company?
This is M. Verdoux.
I'm wiring 50,000 francs.
Is that enough?
I won't be in Paris for some time.
I have matters to clean up here.
Very well, I'll keep in touch.
Goodbye.
Daddy!
- Mama!
- What is it, Peter?
- Look!
- Henri!
- Many happy returns, Mona.
- Happy returns?
You haven't forgotten our wedding
anniversary? 10 years ago today.
Good heavens. Of course.
I have more sentiment
about these things than you have.
Henri.
10 years, wonderful years.
Thank you, my dear.
- Did you bring her a present?
- Peter!
Well, women like those things.
However, I did bring her a present,
and here it is.
Henri, this is wonderful.
- They will never take it from us.
- What did you get, Mama?
The deed to this house and garden.
Peter? Peter?
Here's Jeannette.
Run and get ready for supper.
Mama, can't I dine
with you and Daddy?
Tonight, yes.
What a relief to get away
from the jungle fight.
The jungle fight.
- You're tired, Henri.
- I suppose I am.
Well, two more years at this business
and with luck, we can retire.
If it means losing your health,
I'd sooner live in one room again.
That, you will never do again.
- We were happy then.
- Not now?
- Of course, but...
- But what?
In the past three years,
ever since you left the bank,
you've been under a terrible strain.
Have I?
You worry me.
That's the last thing I wish to do.
It's your state of mind.
What's wrong with it?
You're so desperate about everything.
These are desperate days, my dear -
millions starving and unemployed.
It's not easy for a man of my age
to make a living.
I know it. It's terrifying.
However,
when the world looks grim and dark...
then I think of another world -
you and Peter -
all that I love on this earth.
There.
May I help?
Get the paper
and your father's slippers.
They're here.
I got them before Daddy came home.
Do I smell meat cooking?
- Yes. You wanted company for dinner.
- Of course.
Why don't we eat meat, Daddy?
Because we are vegetarians, my son.
Are the Bottellos coming?
- Yes.
- Good.
- Who are the Bottellos?
- You know the Bottellos.
The man who owns the drug store -
my good friend.
Oh, yes.
The Turners want you to officiate
at Wednesday's Church Bazaar.
Sorry, I'm leaving for Lyons
in the morning.
So soon?
Business is business, my dear.
Peter, where did you put the paper?
You're sitting on it, Daddy.
Oh, so I am.
- Give it to me. Rest your eyes.
- Thank you, my dear.
Just read the headlines, that's all.
"Depression Worldwide -
Unemployment spreads in all nations."
Enough. It's too depressing.
Just think, Henri,
how fortunate we are. You have a job.
Yes, I have a job.
If I lose one,
I can always find another.
Peter, don't pull the cat's tail.
You have a cruel streak.
Where do you get it?
I'm only playing with him.
He likes it.
He doesn't. You play too rough.
Remember, violence begets violence.
The Bottellos.
Peter, take Papa's shoes to his room.
Ah, Martha, my dear,
let me take your things.
And Maurice, delighted to see you,
upon my word, to be sure.
Go inside. Go inside.
Thank you.
You're quite a stranger, Henri.
Yes.
- Dear Martha.
- How do you do?
- Maurice.
- Mona.
- How is your cold?
- I'm over it.
- Did you take those pills?
- Well -
No you didn't, but you should.
They're analeptic -
to restore strength.
Maurice, you know how she is
about taking medicine.
Dinner is served, Madame.
I give them to Martha all the time.
- She's the guinea pig of the family.
- Ah, yes.
- Tell me, how's business?
- As usual. And yours?
Very busy these days, very busy.
Martha, at my left, please.
I hope you'll be with us
a little longer this time.
No, Maurice, I am leaving
by the first train tomorrow morning.
- Best one yet.
- Like 'em rough? I'll go further.
That's far enough, brother.
That's a Lulu. I must tell it
to the captain when he comes.
- When's he here?
- At six on the Lyon Express.
It's almost time. We'd better blow.
What's your hurry?
Let's have another drink.
What's happened to that maid?
Annette? Pardon me a moment.
- Are you deaf?? I was shouting.
- I didn't hear.
You didn't want to hear.
Lamb chops?
Where's the fish from lunch?
I threw it out. There wasn't much.
Enough for you -
throwing food away in hard times.
I'm sorry, I can't eat fish.
There are plenty who can,
so pack up and get out.
Lamb chops for dinner.
Next it'll be steak.
- Lamb chops and steak!
- What's the trouble?
- These servants.
- They're a problem.
This one's gone. Now the captain's
coming home and I haven't a servant.
Look, Annabella, we'd better blow.
What's your hurry?
You haven't told my fortune.
Well, we'll stay till he comes.
- Alright, now cut 'em three times.
- Yeah.
- How long's the captain ashore?
- Just a week, then off another six.
Six weeks?
I bet that has its good points.
I haven't got to that stage yet.
Look at that girl's luck.
No wonder she won a lottery.
- Do I win another?
- I wouldn't be at all surprised.
Wait a minute.
Ace of spades. That ain't so lucky.
If you slipped on a banana peel
with a bad back, the fall would help.
The captain!
- Louis, my pigeon.
- Annabella.
- Why are you so late?
- Sorry.
A southwester blew up
and landed us on a mud bank.
We had to wait for high tide
to get off.
Oh, you look so fresh and salty.
Do I, darling?
I want you to meet some friends.
Vicki, Captain Bonheur.
I forgot your married name.
- Darmond. Call me Vicki.
- Joe Darmond, her husband.
How do you do? Well, we'll blow.
I beg your pardon, I mean beat it.
- Pleased to meet you, Captain...
- Bonheur.
Bonheur.
Well, then all I can say is bonsoir.
- Pigeon.
- Who are those people?
Friends I met at the races.
Be careful. You're too accessible.
You can stoop and pick up nothing.
- Never mind. Have you been good?
- What a question.
- Fooling around with native girls?
- How could you think it?
When you're away,
I think of all sorts of things.
You see, all I think of is you.
No kidding?
Every moment - in the cabin,
on the bridge, even on the poop deck.
You're always in my mind -
wondering what you do, whom you see.
Oh, pigeon.
Then alone at night,
under a canopy of tropical stars,
with the soft strains
of a Viennese waltz from the salon...
- Music, on a cargo ship?
- Oh, yes, we have a radio.
Oh, yes.
Now you've interrupted my thought.
- You were thinking of me, pigeon.
- Yes, you.
I would think of these adorable arms,
these little hands.
and this delightful little wisp -
let me kiss you there.
I wish you didn't have to go back.
I'd much prefer to stay
and look after you.
- Why don't you?
- You know.
I can't stay home and do nothing.
It'd be different
if I could manage your business.
Uh-uh. I can manage
my own business affairs.
You don't trust me.
- I do trust you but -
- You don't! You don't.
That hurts.
That's what mars our happiness.
You trust everyone but me.
Strangers can sell you anything.
Any proposition and you'll bite.
But, what do you know about business?
Emphatically more than you do,
my dear.
Last time, you told me
all the banks were going broke,
getting me all horsed up
about bringing my money home.
- Well, it's a good thing I didn't.
- Very well, we'll forget the matter.
- Don't be mad, pigeon.
- I'm not angry, my dear.
I'm saving you from squandering
your money on these enterprises.
- Worthless stocks.
- They're not.
All of them.
Well, I still have faith
in the Pacific Ocean Power Company.
- What's that?
- I've told you about it.
It's a machine that floats on waves.
Wheels that make electricity.
What does it make when it's calm?
Don't be a pessimist.
That's what I mean. Wasting
your money on sheer nonsense.
Inflation.
Very soon money will be worthless.
- What have you done?
- What do you want to do?
Invest wisely, safely at least.
Land, houses or jewelry. I knew
a friend who has some antique -
- That's funny.
- What?
- Just what I did.
- I bought jewelry, diamonds.
- Where?
Don't get excited. From Joe, Vicki's
husband. The people who just left.
My dear, that's not the way
to buy jewelry.
He's a fence. He deals in hot stuff.
I got a bargain, diamonds that big.
180 karats worth for 20,000 francs.
- You couldn't buy glass for that.
- I did and not glass either.
- How do you know?
- Are you crazy?
- Let me see.
- If they double-crossed me, I'll -
I'll tell you whether
you're double-crossed or not.
Just as I thought, phony, fake.
- What?
- Glass you silly ass, glass.
- I must catch that 8: 15.
- You just got here an hour ago.
I'm the captain. I can't stay away
while it's in repairs.
- Repairs?
- It's up in dry dock.
I'm here alone without a servant.
- I can't help that.
- Why did you come home?
To save you from crooks, swindlers,
people who are trying to rob you!
I'll put them in jail.
No, you won't. You thought
you were buying stolen goods.
That's what you get
for being dishonest.
200,000 francs you've spent.
And what have you to show for it?
Nothing, not a thing of value
but this house.
They'll take this,
with the legal complications.
- They won't.
- They will.
They won't. I put it in your name.
The first sensible thing you've done.
They tried to attach my account.
- Attach your what?
- Don't worry, they didn't get it.
I took my money out
and I have it hidden away.
Here in the house?
Why...
It doesn't matter where.
Nobody will find it. Not even you.
There you go,
you're always suspicious.
I'm not. It's just my defensive
mechanism, as you call it.
I hate to leave you alone
in this house tonight.
- Stay.
- I could leave early in the morning.
Why don't you?
We could go places and do things.
Captain or not,
I'm not leaving you alone tonight.
Pigeon.
Two ounces of chloroform, please.
- How much?
- 75 centimes.
M. Challain.
My husband, Captain Bonheur.
I am president of
the Salt Water Fuel Company.
- What?
- Here's 5,000 francs.
- I'll send the rest.
- Thank you.
- What is this?
- This is a personal matter.
It might interest you.
A device for turning salt water
into gasoline.
- Give me that money!
- How dare you!
Don't you do that.
Don't you ever dare humiliate
me again in public.
I tried to stop you
making a fool of yourself.
I'm not so dumb. I won a lottery.
Of all the effable nonsense,
turning seawater into gasoline.
If it's a success,
we'll own the ocean, that's all.
Preposterous.
Oh, go to bed.
I want to get some sleep.
Very well, my dear.
- Who are you?
- I'm the maid.
- What do you want?
- I hoped to sleep here tonight.
- You were discharged.
- I've nowhere to go.
- Who is it?
- It's the maid.
- What does she want?
- She wants to stay.
I promise you,
I'll leave in the morning.
Oh, alright, let her stay.
Merci, Madame.
I don't know what happened
to that bedroom.
It looks like a cyclone hit it.
Was I mad at you?
No.
- Coffee?
- No, thank you.
- I thought you've fired her.
- Changed my mind.
- Why?
- That's me. I haven't the heart.
I can never find anyone else
to work as cheap.
- I must get back.
- I won't see you
- for six weeks?
- I'll return before she sails.
Goodbye, my dear.
Mme Grosnay. Mme Grosnay.
G.
Ah. Gro... Gro... Gro...
Ah, here we are, Mme Grosnay.
Passy 3211.
Hello, Passy 3211, please.
Hello, has Mme Grosnay
returned to town?
Oh, she has?
This is Benedict, the dressmaker.
Oh, she's out now?
When will she return?
12:30? Thank you.
No, there's no message.
Mme Grosnay.
151 Avenue Victor Hugo.
Ah, 151... 151...
Mme Grosnay. Captain Bonheur.
Who?
I said I had the honor of meeting
you in the south of France.
I'm M. Varnay.
You came to look over my house.
- Oh, yes, I remember.
- Ah, yes.
I wanted to send an astrology book
but couldn't find your address.
- Quite so.
- Quite so. Quite so.
I realize I embarrassed you then,
but if you'll only allow me
to explain.
I don't think that incident requires
any further explanation.
Good day, M. Varnay.
- Good morning.
I want to order three dozen roses,
half a dozen orchids,
and send them to Mme Grosnay,
151 Avenue Victor Hugo.
Merci, Monsieur.
- A card?
- Yes. Five or six.
Oui, Monsieur. As many as you wish.
I want to repeat it
twice a week for two weeks.
Oui, Monsieur.
- How much will that be?
- Let me see.
That'll be five orders altogether.
2,500 francs, Monsieur.
Oh, la, la.
Very well.
These things have to be done.
- Keep the change.
- Merci, Monsieur.
- Cordial, Martha?
- Yes, thanks.
- Maurice?
- Oh, thank you, Mona.
I hope we'll be seeing you more.
He must be on the go every minute.
One gets caught up
in this monoxide world
of confusion.
I look forward to
these quiet evenings together,
with your edifying talks
on theurgic matters,
the legerdemain of the apothecary.
You should have been a chemist.
Chemistry, my fellow, is the material
manifestation of the metaphysical.
Ah, you're a mystic.
Do you remember discussing a humane
method of killing dumb animals?
- Very distinctly.
- A lethal veterinary formula.
No pain, no convulsions,
absolutely tasteless.
The creature drinks it
and in an hour,
curls up into a comfortable sleep
and dies.
What a memory you have.
You were experimenting
with three elements as I remember.
Exnide, ethna bromide
and something else.
Yes, it was very interesting,
pharmaceutically.
The ethna bromide induces asphyxia,
but in order to delay
the erodent action of the exnide,
C2HC was added.
C2HC?
A freezing agent.
When swallowed,
tissue changes are gradual.
In an hour, the action
of the exnide takes place.
Its effect is like heart disease -
a systolic cramp and poof!
- What have you done about it?
- Nothing.
It's banned.
- Why?
- Too dangerous for public use.
In the post-mortem, not a trace
of the poison can be found.
Can you imagine such a weapon
in the hands of an arch criminal?
Think of the money
from the insurance companies.
Quite an idea. We'll incorporate
and go into business.
Insure people and have them die of
heart failure - we'd make millions.
I'm not sure but I think the poison
might show up in a man.
- Why?
- Different metabolism.
We could find out.
- How?
- Simple.
You say it takes an hour
for the poison to work?
Pick a derelict, poison him
then send him to a hotel.
When a person is found dead
in a public place,
there's an autopsy.
You'd know the result
without taking the slightest risk.
What a diabolical thought.
However, such experiments, we had
better leave to the arch criminal,
don't you think?
C2HC.
And now for the experiment.
- Quite a shower.
- Yes, it is.
- Can I escort you anywhere?
- Oh, thank you.
Allow me.
- You're from Belgium?
- I came after the war.
A refugee?
- Where do you live?
- Hotel Lausanne, off Montmartre.
- Just a few doors away.
- Yes.
Good. Why don't you take off
your coat?
Allow me.
- What's that?
- A kitten, poor thing.
- I picked it up in the doorway.
- You like cats?
Not particularly,
but it was all wet and cold.
I don't suppose you have any milk.
On the contrary, I do. The prospects
are not as gloomy as you think.
- Do I sound that pessimistic?
- You do but I don't think you are.
- Why?
- To be out on a night like this.
You're an optimist.
- An optimist, I'm anything but that.
- Up against it, eh?
Remarkable faculties of observation.
Indeed.
How long have you been
in this predicament?
- Oh, quite a long time.
- How long?
Three months.
- I don't believe you.
- Why?
You would have done better.
Thanks.
Now tell me the truth.
You're just out of a hospital
or a jail. Which is it?
- What do you want to know for?
- I want to help.
- A philanthropist, eh?
- Precisely.
- I ask nothing in return.
- What is this, the Salvation Army?
If that's the way you feel,
you're at liberty to go your way.
If you must know,
I'm just out of jail.
- What were you in for?
- What's the difference?
- Larceny, they called it.
- Larceny?
Pawning a rented typewriter.
Couldn't you do better than that?
- What did you get?
- Three months.
This is your first day out of jail?
Yes.
I see.
Poor dear. Oh, well.
Nothing is permanent in this world,
not even our troubles.
- Are you hungry?
- Frankly, yes.
Then while I tend to
the culinary operations,
you can help to bring in
a few things.
Come.
- Can I adopt your little kitten?
- Please do.
We'll set the table for one.
- Aren't you having any?
- No.
Oh, then all we need
is a knife, fork and napkin.
Here they are.
Well, you will take them in there,
make yourself at home.
- Merci.
I don't know whether this will
appeal. Eggs, toast and red wine.
- Wonderful!
- Be seated.
Thank you.
You're tired. So right after supper,
I shall take you to your hotel.
You're kind. I don't understand
why you're doing all this.
Why not? Is a little kindness
such a rare thing?
I was beginning to think it was.
- The toast! Pardon me.
- Can I help you?
No, no, stay where you are.
I can manage.
- Voilà.
- You're funny.
- Am I? Why?
- I don't know.
However, you're hungry.
Please go ahead.
- What book is that?
- Schopenhauer.
- Do you like him?
- So, so.
Have you read his treatise
on suicide?
- Wouldn't interest me.
- Not if the end was simple?
Say you went to sleep,
and there was a sudden stoppage.
Wouldn't you prefer it
to this drab existence?
- I wonder.
- The approach of death terrifies.
I suppose if the unborn
knew of the approach of life,
they'd be just as terrified.
- Yet life is wonderful.
- What's wonderful about it?
Everything, a spring morning,
a summer's night, music, art, love -
- Love?
- There is such a thing.
- How do you know?
- I was in love once.
- Physically attracted by someone?
- It was more than that.
Women are capable of something more.
You don't like women?
On the contrary,
I love but don't admire them.
Why?
Women are of the earth, realistic,
dominated by physical facts.
What nonsense.
Once a woman betrays a man,
she despises him.
In spite of his goodness, she will
give him up for someone inferior,
if that someone is more,
shall we say, attractive.
How little you know about women.
You'd be surprised.
That isn't love.
- What is love?
- Giving, sacrificing.
What a mother feels for her child.
- Did you love that way?
- Yes.
- Whom?
- My husband.
You're married?
I was. He died while I was in jail.
I see. Tell me about him.
That's a long story.
He was wounded in the war,
an invalid.
An invalid?
That's why I loved him.
He needed me, depended on me.
He was like a child.
But he was more than a child to me.
He was a religion. My very breath.
I'd have killed for him.
No, love is something
very real and deep.
I know that.
- However.
- Pardon me.
I believe there's a little cork
in that wine.
Let me get you another glass.
A penny for your thoughts.
Oh, no.
- More wine?
- Thank you, no more.
Come, it's very late
and you're tired.
Here.
This will tide you over
for a day or so.
- Good luck.
- Thank you.
Oh, this is too much.
Silly, carrying on this way.
I was beginning to lose faith.
Then this happens and you want
to believe all over again.
This is a ruthless world and one
must be ruthless to cope with it.
That isn't true.
It's a blundering world
and a very sad one,
yet kindness can make it beautiful.
You'd better go before
your philosophy corrupts me.
You can go out this way.
Goodnight and thank you.
- Good morning. Do I have a message?
- Not yet.
How many orders
has Madame received?
- Two. One every three days.
- Good. There's still a week to go?
- Oui, Monsieur.
- I see. Oh, well.
- We must hope for the best.
- Oui.
- Good morning.
- M. Verdoux?
- Oui.
I'm Detective Morrow
from Police Headquarters.
- I'd like to talk to you.
- Won't you come in?
- This way, please.
- Nice pieces you have here.
- Quite a collector, eh?
- In a modest way.
This is amusing.
An old galleon figurehead.
- What's that?
- From the bow of a boat.
Very nice. Pardon me.
- What's that?
- I don't know where that came from.
- Be seated, Monsieur.
- Merci.
- A drink, Monsieur?
- No, no, merci.
Then you'll pardon me?
Well?
- I want to ask you a few questions.
- Oui, Monsieur.
- How long have you sold furniture?
- Approximately three years.
- Do you know a Mme Thelma Varnay?
- I beg your pardon?
Thelma Varnay.
I do not, Monsieur.
Or Lydia Floray?
Floray. Floray?
Oui, Monsieur. Lydia Floray
from the City of Corbell.
I'm afraid I don't, Monsieur.
- You're married?
- Yes.
- You have a wife and child?
- Quite so.
Your relationship with Mme Bonheur?
Bonheur?
I don't understand, Monsieur.
It's no use, Captain. The game's up.
I've been shadowing you
for two weeks.
You've been a pretty busy fellow,
traveling around the country.
What you need is a pair of skates.
Does my wife know?
No, Monsieur. No one knows anything,
not even Police Headquarters.
- I wanted to make sure I was right.
- What are your charges?
Bigamy.
14 counts of murder.
Congratulations, Monsieur. With the
murder charges, you won't succeed.
We'll see.
- There is corpus delicti.
- Don't worry, we'll find the bodies.
I don't think you will, Monsieur.
However, we'll hold you for bigamy
until we do. Let's go.
Listen. You have no evidence
of murder and you know it.
If you let me see my wife before
arrest, I'll sign a confession.
That's a bargain.
It'll be an hour and 20 minutes
before we get there.
I never felt so tired.
- Pardon me, if I take forty winks?
- As many as you like.
I'm sorry. I must take every
precaution. Do you mind?
Of course not.
I never felt so sleepy.
It must have been that wine.
Hello.
- How do you do?
- Don't you remember me?
Ah, yes, yes.
How's the world treating you?
I could complain, but I won't.
I need a good manager.
Do you know anybody that wants a job?
No, I don't.
I can't keep on doing this sort
of business all the time.
- I don't want any money.
- What do you want?
Nothing, I just wanted to say hello,
that's all.
You don't believe me?
However, take this.
- No, I don't want your money.
- Take it. Don't be a fool.
Will I see you again?
You go on about your business.
That's my call.
Hello? Annabella?
This is your pigeon.
I'm flying home. I've been
at the shipping office all day.
No, the boat's still up on the ways.
The damage was more serious.
They're still scraping her sides.
You would say something like that.
We won't be ready for days,
so I'm coming home.
Immediately.
Goodbye, dear.
- Good afternoon, Captain.
- Good afternoon.
Will you take this up to my room?
Thank you.
- Pigeon.
- Annabella.
- What's that?
- Pretty?
It's for the woman next door.
I'm worried about the deed to this
house. I want it back in my name.
- Why, of course.
- We can go to the lawyer's now.
- Today?
- I want it done and over with.
Oh, not now! I've only just arrived.
Besides, I want this day to be ours.
Just you and I,
alone in the waning twilight.
If you talk like that,
I'll put it off.
Good! We'll dine alone. We'll prepare
it ourselves and let the maid go.
If I knew it was going to be
this kind of an evening.
- Annette!
- Oui, Madame?
- You may have the afternoon off.
- Merci, Madame.
- Drink?
- Bordeaux'd be nice, pigeon.
Bordeaux?
What are you up to?
- Oh, nothing, Madame.
- Did you break something?
No, I was just closing the window.
Do it more carefully next time.
- Corkscrew.
- There's none here.
It must be in the living room
somewhere.
- Dinner'll be ready in a half hour.
- You deserve a little drink.
I certainly do.
What are you drinking?
- Sarsaparilla.
- Sarsaparilla?
Doctor's orders, my dear.
I can see how this evening will be.
Playing dominoes.
It's good, nice and dry. I like it.
It makes me so thirsty.
I've finished this whole bottle myself
and you ain't touched yours yet.
You've done nothing
but stare all evening.
We were going to enjoy
the waning twilight.
Be careful.
Be careful of the furniture.
Oh, honey, you're always complaining.
Here, drink your drink.
I don't see how you can drink
that vile stuff.
Very good, just like wine
and very dry too.
You're drinking my wine!
Pigeon! Pigeon!
No! No!
Pigeon! Pigeon, let me in!
- Pigeon, darling!
- Milk!
- Qu'est-ce que c'est?
- Woman, leave me alone!
Let me help you, please, darling!
Annette!
Come down, quickly! Hurry!
What happened? Tell me, darling.
I'm poisoned! I'm dying.
- Telephone my wife.
- I'm here.
- Oh, dear! Here, take some wine.
- Take it away!
Poor darling, let me open your tie.
- Leave me alone.
- What's happened to that maid!
- Yes, Madame?
- What happened to you?
I don't know.
I was bleaching my hair,
- and it fell out.
- What's that?
- You'd better get two doctors!
- Take it away!
Calm, my love.
There's nothing to be worried about. If it's poison,
he'd certainly rid of it
after using the stomach pump.
Keep on taking the medicine
for two or three days.
How is the maid?
She feels OK but doesn't look good.
Strange you didn't have any effects.
Nothing affects me, I'm lucky.
A few days in the country
will do you both good.
- Thank you.
- Goodbye.
He said we should go away
in the country
just you and I, alone.
Wouldn't that be fun?
Wonderful.
Oh, pigeon, not a soul anywhere.
Perfect.
- Why didn't we think of this before?
- Yes.
Oh, it's lovely.
- What's that?
- That's an anchor, for fishing.
We should catch scads of them here.
Oh, I see one, it's a monster!
Oh, no, it's me.
Isn't that silly? My own reflection.
I wished I could swim.
I'd love to go in.
- Would you?
- I'm just in the mood.
- We'll see what we can do.
- Will you teach me?
I'll do my best.
- There's a fish. Give me the rod.
- Now don't get excited, my dear.
If I had the rod,
I would have caught him.
- The hook must be baited.
- Bait it.
- Alright. Don't get...
- Shush! Shush!
- Give me, quick! It's a big one.
- Just a minute.
The rod, quick! Come on!
Gimme the rod!
- You must wait.
- Don't be a fool!
By that time, the fish'll be gone.
Where's your common sense?
What's that?
You're not baiting him with that?
You don't expect them to eat this?
- What are you doing?
- Putting a worm on the hook.
- A worm?
- Of course!
Disgusting! You don't expect me
to eat fish that's been eating worms.
Very well. We'll fish without them.
Good.
- You're not angry, pigeon?
- Me? No.
Don't be mad because
you're wrong once in a while.
You can't be right all the time.
I can see scads of them.
They're smelling the hook.
- You know... Is something wrong?
- Hm?
They're wonderful.
There's millions of 'em down there.
You know...
Be careful. You'll go overboard.
- Are you seasick?
- No.
Shame on you! A man who's lived
at sea all his life. Oh, Captain!
Shush!
I've got one. I've got one.
Ooh, I got... This is a whopper.
I've got... Pigeon, I've got one.
Hey, don't lie there asleep,
give me a hand!
What on earth's the matter with you?
It's gone. If you'd been on the job,
I would have caught him.
Are you drunk?
Oh, a solo drinker, huh?
Hmph, carrying a bottle!
They're still smelling the hook.
Big ones!
Just look at those fish.
There's a wise one.
No, he won't...
What are you going to do with that?
- Lasso him.
- Don't be silly!
You can't lasso a fish.
You can. All you have to do is
to place it over its head like that
and you pull it tight like this.
- What's that?
- A yodeller.
- Oh, that ruins everything.
- It certainly does.
Too bad we couldn't be by ourselves.
It certainly is.
- After all the plans we made.
- Yes.
He's looking at us through
field glasses.
We'd better take this off.
He'll think you're murdering me.
There's a whole gang.
They're going to have a picnic.
I give up, I'm going back to my boat.
- We've just arrived.
- I can't help that.
- Oh...
- What are you doing?
I got one... I've got a beaut...
Don't be a fool! Doesn't matter!
- Don't push.
- Who's pushing you?
- Don't be an idiot!
- Help!
- Sit down.
- I can't.
- Stand still.
- I'm trying.
Pigeon. Help! Help! Help!
You Idiot! Haven't you any more sense
than to stand up in a boat?
What's come over you,
you're acting strange.
Where's my hat?
- Mme Marie Grosnay?
- Oh, dear, dear, dear. Thanks.
I thought you were going
to the south of France.
I couldn't find anything
that suited me.
- More flowers, Madame.
- Put them over there.
Oh, Marie. Mm, how wonderful.
Who sent them?
That awful man who keeps pursuing me.
How thrilling.
I'm dying to know what he's written.
Always the same thing.
Just two words, 'Please, please'.
I've never known such aggressiveness.
That's not aggressive. Whatever
he wants, at least he's asking for it.
- Why don't you call him?
- That old roué?
Well, as long as he's not too old.
I don't know the man. Besides,
I don't have his telephone number.
Send a letter care of the florist.
- Good morning.
- A letter for you.
- Merci.
- Did you deliver the flowers?
- The last has gone.
Repeat it for another two weeks.
- Oui, Monsieur.
- Oh, wait.
You better cancel it.
May I use your telephone?
- Oui, Monsieur.
- Thank you.
Hello? Give me Passy 3211, please.
Hello?
This is M. Varnay.
I should be very angry with you,
but I have no more resistance.
- Good. When can I see you?
- Why are you so persistent?
- Simple because I love you.
- You hardly know me.
I've always known you.
When we met, I knew there was
a deep understanding between us.
It was in your eyes, Marie.
They are beautiful,
like the loneliness of distant stars.
- I wonder, who are you in the dark?
- I don't quite understand.
I can't express it,
only a symphony could say it.
The music of the spheres.
I'm not as ethereal as all that.
You are everything.
Saint, sinner, snake and gazelle.
I can't forget you. Every look, tone,
gesture is engraved in my mind.
I must see you, Marie.
Immediately. Now. Good.
I'll be right over. Mm-hm.
How much is that?
One franc, Monsieur.
Keep the change.
Marie. My own beloved.
I beg your pardon,
whom did you wish to see?
- Mme Grosnay.
- This way, please.
This way.
I am Mme Lasalle,
Marie will be down in a moment.
Of course.
How do you do?
- Yvonne, this is M. Varnay.
- Yes, we've just met.
I'll see you at my house
for dinner at 7:30.
- Yes, at 7:30.
- Oh, don't bother, darling.
Goodbye. Goodbye.
- Well, you wicked man.
- Wicked?
Yes, very wicked.
- Sit over there.
- Thank you.
- Tea?
- Milk and sugar?
- No, thank you.
Now that Yvonne is gone,
I'm a little afraid of you.
Afraid? Why?
You know what happened
the last time we were alone.
I'm sorry. I allowed my emotions
to get the better of me.
- It will never occur again.
- Oh, don't say that.
That's one of the ironies of life,
doing the wrong thing
at the right moment.
Or shall we say, the right thing
at the wrong moment.
- Marie.
- Oh, don't...
I never spilled a drop.
Marie. Oh, my dear.
- Oh...
- No, please...
Whoever thought
this would happen to Marie.
- All so sudden, too.
- Yes, yes.
- John.
- Yes.
We must give them a drink.
The minister will be late.
He has a burial first.
He should marry them then bury them.
Marie's having trouble
with her trousseau.
- Bridegroom?
- Not here yet.
He hates this sort of thing.
They wanted a quiet affair,
but you know how these things grow.
Yes.
- What was that?
- I've never seen her before.
M. Bismo brought her along.
I'll tell that to the captain.
Have you heard the one
about the old couple...
Ah, good afternoon.
Ah, meet my old friend, M. Carno.
And what are you doing here?
Weddings, funerals,
I attend them all.
- As I was saying...
- Are you a bridesmaid?
- I'm just a stranger.
- Mme Bonheur is a friend of mine.
She was in Paris,
so I brought her along.
- Henri, dear. How are you?
- A little shaky.
I know you wanted a quiet wedding,
but I had to do this for Marie.
I'm sorry to put you through this
but now you must meet my friends.
This is the bridegroom,
M. Varnay
and this is Mme Cornet.
M. Simon. M. Delage.
Mme Bremer. Mme Voselli.
M. Contrepaire. M. Potis. Mme Voulon.
- And of course, my husband.
- Monsieur.
There. I'll introduce the rest
after the ceremony.
- Aren't I nice?
- You are kind.
No, no, I don't mean that
in a derogatory sense.
- Oh, I beg your pardon.
- Granted.
- A drink?
- I'd love one.
- Oh, Claire.
- M. Varnay, how do you feel?
Very abstract.
Pull yourself together.
The worst is yet to come.
That's true. What am I saying?
This is my day of faux pas.
- Oh, let's hope not, Monsieur.
- I didn't mean that, either.
I beg your pardon.
At funerals one's inclined to laugh
and at weddings, weep.
Evidently,
somebody disagrees with me.
- Who on earth can she be?
- Well, you should know.
Oh, yes, a Mme Bonheur.
I think she's from Lyons.
That's good luck. That means you're
going to be pleasantly surprised.
Pardon me.
- What's wrong?
- I think it's the cocktails.
I'll have a beer.
Thank you. Where's Bismo?
Excuse me.
M. Varnay.
Is there anything wrong?
No. I was just admiring your flowers.
Oh! Well, over on this side
we have our lovely bluebells.
- Ah, the campanulas.
- And over here are the primroses.
Of course, the genus Oenothera.
- Oh, what's wrong? Are you ill?
- Cramps.
They attack me ever since India.
Oh, well. Let me get you something.
- It'll pass soon.
- The minister's here.
- Tell him to wait. Can't I help?
- No, no. Please.
- Bismo.
- Hello.
- Mme Bonheur.
- Pleasure.
- Take good care of her.
- Well, you just leave that to me.
Oh, John. Oh, how do you do.
The minister's arrived and Henri's
taken with cramps. Look after him.
Well, let's see what we can do
for M. Varnay.
He isn't here.
He must have recovered.
Possibly you'll find him
at the punch bowl?
Come on, we'll go see.
- What are you lookin' for?
- Huh?
- Have you lost something?
- I dropped my sandwich.
- What kind was it?
- Just an ordinary sandwich.
A slice of bread between some meat.
- White or rye?
- Er, yes.
Stay here
and I'll get you another one.
Thank you.
- He isn't here.
- Oh, there he is.
Excuse me. Stay right here.
- What's the matter?
- Cramps.
The worst attack I've had in years.
- I'll take you into the house.
- I prefer to stay here.
Friends.
The great moment has arrived.
Please come into the house.
You can't go through a ceremony.
I'll take you inside.
I'd like to stay in the garden.
The air will do me good.
Ah, there you are.
I didn't quite understand.
Did you want white or rye?
Rye.
You certainly have
a beautiful place here.
- Wonderful.
- Thank you.
I'm comin'.
I'll have them delay the ceremony.
If you lie down
maybe the pain will go.
- You go and tell them.
- I'll get you into the house.
- I'm feeling better.
- I'm not going to take any chances.
Come along.
I wish you'd let me stay
in the fresh air.
No, no.
Ten minutes rest will do you good.
The thing is muscular.
It attacks the serratus magnus.
- What was that?
- Nothing at all. Go ahead.
Varnay.
- Henri.
- Beloved. See you later.
Varnay.
M. Varnay.
Varnay!
This M. Varnay seems to be
our man alright,
but he must have several aliases.
I can't believe it.
It's too bad he didn't jilt Thelma.
You're to be congratulated.
I knew it was the same man
the moment we read it in the papers.
We don't even have a photograph.
- But I'd know him if I ever saw him.
- So would I.
- What was his last address?
- The Hotel Splendide.
He moved.
I know. He seems to have
moved from everywhere.
What business was he in?
He said he was an explorer
working for the International
Geographical Society.
It would be a good idea
to call them up.
He's on his way to the North Pole
by now.
There is no such organization.
However, we must keep a lookout.
This is to be confidential.
Not a word to the press,
as it would jeopardize
our investigation.
Hello? Hello?
Yes, yes, yes. What?
I said, we have to foreclose.
You can't. My wife and child.
We need the money. We can't wait.
Listen, give me ten minutes.
Just ten minutes.
Good. I'll call you back.
Reaumur 6572.
Hello. Balong & Company.
This is Henri Verdoux.
Sell everything I have at once.
Are you mad?
You were wiped out hours ago.
Come here.
Yes, you.
- Hello, Mr Philanthropist.
- Philanthropist?
You took me to your apartment
one rainy night.
- Really?
- Yes. After feeding me
and giving me money,
you sent me on my way
like a good little girl.
- I must have been a fool.
- Hey.
- Oh, shut up. Where are you going?
- Nowhere.
- Get in.
- Thank you.
To the Café Royal.
Now I shall ask you to feed me again.
I'm afraid that will be difficult.
I'll have the pleasure
of feeding you.
Thank you.
I wanted to meet you again.
I even went to your store,
but you had moved.
I haven't lived there in ages.
I still think you don't remember me.
But why should you?
There is every apparent reason
why I should.
The night we met
I was just out of jail.
Shush, the chauffeur.
Of course. Your invalid husband.
- Oh, you remember that?
- Something I shall never forget.
But you, and all this. What happened?
The old story, from rags to riches.
My luck changed.
I met a munitions manufacturer.
That's the business
I should have been in.
Yes, it will be paying
big dividends soon.
It's nice seeing you. You'll never
realize what your kindness meant.
Kindness is a convenient thing
at times, my dear.
However, tell me about yourself.
I prefer to talk about
something pleasant.
- You for instance and this...
- And what?
What sort of a chap is your friend?
In many ways, very kind and generous.
- But in business, quite ruthless.
- Business is a ruthless business.
- Do you love him?
- I thought you didn't believe in it?
Everyone needs love.
Something's happened. You seem to
have lost your zest for bitterness.
Perhaps I have no more use for it
since I've given up the fight.
There's always something
to fight for.
- For me, there is nothing.
- Nothing?
Soon after the crash,
I lost my wife and child.
Oh, I'm sorry, I never realized.
However, they're much happier
where they are...
than living in this world
of uncertainty.
You have changed. I can see that.
Since the loss of my family,
I seem to have awakened from a dream.
- What do you mean?
- I was a bank clerk once.
My existence
a monotonous rhythm.
Day in and day out, counting money.
Then the rhythm was broken.
I lost my position.
What followed was a numbed confusion.
A nightmare in which
I lived in a half dream world.
A horrible world.
And now I've awakened.
I wonder if that world ever existed.
You went through a bad ordeal.
Don't allow it to take hold of you.
It hasn't. Despair is a narcotic.
It lulls the mind into indifference.
But that's giving up life.
We must all give it up
sooner or later.
- Yes, but not before our time.
- Why?
Must you know the reason
for everything?
It might help a little if we did.
Life is beyond reason.
That's why you must go on.
If it's only to fulfill your destiny.
My destiny!
Why would anyone want to go up
in the Eiffel Tower at night?
That was Phoebe's idea.
She has her way.
- How many?
- There'll be five.
This way, please.
- I'd like to eat now, I'm hungry.
- We'd better wait.
They'll be hours yet.
We can have a drink.
What do you want?
Vermouth.
- Two Vermouth.
- Oui.
Let's dance.
- What?
- Thelma's husband.
- Where?
- Behind you.
You're right. It is.
- You're stepping all over my feet.
- I can't help it.
Oh, Thelma. Poor Thelma.
Pull yourself together.
I'm phoning the police.
- Don't leave. He'll murder me.
- Keep your eye on him.
Don't let him out of your sight.
If he leaves, follow him.
You look tired.
You need someone to look after you.
- I must take you in hand.
- You're very kind.
Merci, Madame.
Thank you.
Cab, sir?
Car number ten.
- They're leaving.
- Take down the number of the car.
I haven't got a pencil. Go get one.
Pardon me.
- Do you have a pencil?
- Try the office around the corner.
- Thank you.
Open up. Open up this door.
- Let me out.
- Help, help.
- I shall say goodbye to you.
- What are you going to do?
I'm going to fulfill my destiny.
Here's my card.
Be sure to let me hear from you,
soon.
Merci.
- Tomorrow?
- Tomorrow.
Alright, sir.
Your positions. One on each corner
and two at the back.
The rest come with me.
- Victor, you remain here.
- Yes, sir.
Here. Break it up. Around this way.
- Come on. Let these men through.
- Help! Help!
Help! Help!
- There he is.
- That's not him! That's my brother!
What have you done?
That's my witness.
Get him a glass of water.
My poor brother.
You!
- Make way, please.
- Step aside.
What is it?
- I've just seen him.
- Where?
- There.
- Don't let anyone leave.
- Jacques, Henri, guard the entrance.
- Yes, sir.
Thank you. Ah!
There he is! That's him!
- Henri Verdoux?
- At your service.
Never in the history of jurisprudence
have such deeds
been brought to light.
Gentlemen, you have before you
a cruel and cynical monster.
Look at him!
This man, who has brains,
if he had decency,
could have made an honest living.
Yet, he preferred to rob
and murder unsuspecting women.
He made a business of it.
I ask for the protection of society.
For this mass killer,
I demand the extreme penalty.
That he be put to death
on the guillotine. The State rests.
M. Verdoux,
you have been found guilty.
Have you anything to say
before sentence is passed?
Oui, Monsieur, I have.
However remiss the Prosecutor
has been,
he at least admits
that I have brains.
Thank you, Monsieur, I have.
And for thirty-five years
I used them honestly.
After that, nobody wanted them.
So I was forced to go into business
for myself.
As for being a mass killer,
does not the world encourage it?
Is it not building weapons
of destruction
for the sole purpose of mass killing?
Has it not blown unsuspecting women
and little children to pieces.
And done it very scientifically.
As a mass killer,
I am an amateur by comparison.
However,
I do not wish to lose my temper,
because very shortly,
I shall lose my head.
Nevertheless...
Upon leaving this spark
of earthly existence,
I have this to say.
I shall see you all...
very soon... very soon.
- No pictures.
- Oh, Max, how is he?
He's nuts! Talks like he's a saint.
Twist everything with half-truths.
Says you can't have good
without evil.
Evil being the shadows
cast from the sun.
- He's kidding us.
- Alright, you can go in.
- So long, Max. See you later.
- Hope you get a better break.
No pictures.
Well, well, well. Verdoux.
You'll have to admit,
crime doesn't pay.
- No, sir. Not in a small way.
- What do you mean?
To be successful in anything,
one must be well organized.
You're not leaving
with that cynical remark?
To be idealistic at this moment
would be incongruous.
What's all this talk about
good and evil?
Arbitrary forces. Too much of either
will destroy us all.
We can never have too much good.
The trouble is, we've never
had enough. We don't know.
I've been your friend all through the
trial. Give me a story with a moral.
You, the tragic example
of a life of crime.
I don't see how anyone can be
an example in these criminal times.
You certainly are,
robbing and murdering people.
- That's business.
- Others don't do business that way.
That's the history of
many a big business.
Wars, conflict,
it's all business.
One murder makes a villain,
millions a hero.
Numbers sanctify, my good fellow.
- Father Ferro to see you.
- By all means, show him in.
You'll pardon me,
but my time is limited.
Is there anything else
you'd like to say?
Yes, goodbye.
Alright, Father.
Well, Father.
And what can I do for you?
Nothing, my son.
I want to help you, if I can.
I've come to ask you
to make peace with God.
I am at peace with God.
My conflict is with Man.
- Have you no remorse for your sins?
- Who knows what sin is.
Born as it was from heaven
from God's fallen angel?
Who knows the ultimate
destiny it serves?
After all, what would you be
doing without sin?
Exactly what I'm doing now,
my son.
Trying in my humble way
to help a lost soul in distress.
They're coming. Let me pray for you.
As you wish. But I don't think these
gentlemen want to be kept waiting.
May the Lord have mercy on your soul.
Why not?
After all, it belongs to Him.
Henri Verdoux, the Criminal Court
of Justice of the French Republic,
sentenced you to die.
It is now the order of the court
the sentence be carried out.
- Merci.
- Cigarette?
Thank you.
Here.
- What's that?
- Rum.
No, thank you. Oh, just a moment.
I've never tasted rum.