Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS.org
Presented and produced by
SHOWEAST
In association with
EGG FILMS
What?
I said
I want to tell you my story.
What the hell?
Why are you talking like that?
Who the fuck are you?
My...
name is...
Oh...
..Dae-su.
Stop flirting with his girlfriend.
Hold on.
- Mr Oh Dae-su!
- Was I flirting with her? Was I?
OK! OK!
Sit down, Oh Dae-su.
You've had too much to drink.
I need to piss first.
I wasn't even flirting!
Motherfucker!
Arsehole!
Sit down!
I'm so sorry.
Fuck, I really need to piss.
- Isn't she cute?
- Very. Now sit down.
It's my daughter's birthday today.
I got her a birthday present.
A little cloud
floating in the sky
A pleasure boat
sailing on the river
My name, Oh Dae-su, means...
.."getting through
one day at a time."
That's what "Oh Dae-su" means.
But...God...
Why can't I get through today?
Let me go!
- Shut the fuck up!
- Let me go!
Let go!
Get away from me!
Grab him!
He should be locked up.
I'll make sure he doesn't get drunk
and cause trouble again.
Have a nice day, Officer.
He's usually a nice guy.
Let's go.
I'll come back and see you soon.
Don't bother.
- That's up to me, arseholes.
- Hey!
Yeun-hee, it's Daddy...
Daddy's got a present
for my little Yeun-hee.
I'll be home soon with your present,
just wait a bit longer...
Let me talk to her.
- Good girl.
- Give me the phone.
Yeun-hee,
Joo-hwan wants a word with you.
You remember Joo-hwan, don't you?
Hold on.
Hello, Yeun-hee.
It's me, Joo-hwan.
So it's your birthday today?
Happy birthday!
I'll buy you
a nice treat tomorrow.
Hello? Oh, hello, Ja-hyun.
I'm sorry. I know it's very late.
Dae-su is on his way home.
I'm sorry. Yes?
Hold on.
Dae-su, it's your wife.
Dae-su!
Your wife says you should hurry home!
Dae-su, let's get going!
Stop messing around!
Sir, sir.
Wait, come here.
Come and talk to me.
I won't ask you to let me go again.
Just tell me why I'm here, please.
I have a right to know why.
God, I've already been locked in here
for two months.
Sir, wait, come here.
Sir, wait. What is this place?
Please sir, just tell me how long
I have to stay here.
Sir!
Fuck you!
Come here, you arsehole!
Son of a bitch.
I saw your face, arsehole.
You're dead if I get out.
I'm sorry!
I won't swear at you again.
Just tell me how much longer.
One month? Two? Three?
Don't go!
I'm sorry.
Just tell me how long,
you son of a bitch!
I said tell me how long,
you arsehole!
Son of a bitch!
You fucking arseholes!
If they had told me then
that it would be 15 years...
..would it have been
easier to endure?
Or harder?
LAUGH,
AND THE WORLD LAUGHS WITH YOU.
WEEP, AND YOU WEEP ALONE.
When the music begins,
gas is released.
When the gas is released,
I fall asleep.
Later on, I found out
that it was the same valium gas
that Russian soldiers used
on Chechen terrorists.
When I wake up,
my hair has been cut.
I don't really like the style.
But they change my clothes
and clean the room.
Generous bastards.
One!
Two!
Three!
It's too spicy.
I don't want spinach. You eat it.
I won't eat spinach.
Mrs Kim Ja-hyun's body was found
with stab wounds to the neck.
This was a cold-blooded murder.
As nothing of value was taken,
police suspect a personal motive.
The victim's husband, Oh Dae-su,
disappeared a year ago
and is still at large.
Witnesses say
Oh Dae-su was a heavy drinker,
who fought constantly with his wife.
Neighbours also frequently argued
with Oh Dae-su.
Blood samples found at the scene
match those of Oh Dae-su.
Oh Dae-su's fingerprints have been
matched to those found on a cup.
Sources claim that Oh Dae-su
definitely visited his wife recently.
The only missing item
was a family album,
which backs the police theories.
After three years,
many wrinkles form on a man's face.
If you stand
outside a phone box on a rainy day...
..and meet a man whose face
is hidden by a violet umbrella,
my advice is
that you make friends
with television.
The television
is both clock and calendar.
It is your school, home, church,
friend...
..and lover.
But...
..my lover's song...
..is too short.
Today at 7.:50am
the middle of Seoul's Sangsu Bridge,
50 metres in length,
suddenly collapsed...
I wrote a list
of all the people I had offended,
quarrelled with and hurt.
This was both my prison journal
and the autobiography
of my evil deeds.
I thought I had lived
a normal life...
..but there was too much wrong-doing.
All I could think at that moment
was that the man in the next room
probably only had one chopstick.
But...
Who had imprisoned me?
Was it Yoo Heung-sam?
Lee So-young or Kang Chang-suk?
Whoever it was, wait.
Just you wait.
I'll rip your body limb from limb,
and your remains will never be found.
Because I will swallow
every last bit.
One line for each year.
When I start doing this,
I am already six lines behind.
So next year will be easier.
The more tattoos I have,
the shorter the chopstick becomes.
The shorter the chopstick becomes,
the bigger the hole in the wall
becomes.
Anyway...
..time passes well.
Nine years.
10 years.
11 years.
EX-PRESIDENT CHUN DOO-HWAN
ARRESTED
HONG KONG HANDOVER CEREMONY
PRINCESS DIANA'S FUNERAL
OFFICIAL APPROVAL OF IMF FUND
12 years.
PRESIDENTIAL INAUGURATION
PRESIDENT KIM DAE-JUNG
VISITS NORTH KOREA
WORLD CUP IN KOREA
13 years.
ROH MOO-HYN ELECTED PRESIDENT
14 years.
I'll be out in a month.
I'll be out in one month.
I'll be out.
I'll be out in one month's time.
I'll be out of here.
I'll be out in a month.
In exactly one month.
I'll need money when I get out,
so what should I do?
Should I steal or rob?
What shall I eat first?
Kimchee soup? Barbecued eel?
Anything but fried dumplings.
But where am I?
With all the car horns,
it must be the city.
The most important thing
is what floor I'm on.
What if I break through the wall
and I'm on the 52nd floor?
Even if I plunge to my death,
I'll still be getting out.
I'm getting out.
In one month, I'm getting out.
Picture yourself
lying in a field.
When you hear the bell...
..you will turn your head...
..and look down.
You will see
an endless field of green grass.
The sun is shining brightly...
..there's a cool breeze.
It's a human being.
Don't stop me!
Mister!
Even though...
..I'm no better than a beast...
..don't I have the right to live?
Mister.
Even though...
..I'm no better...
..than a beast...
..don't I have the right...
..to live?
Yes.
The alley with the phone box
was just here.
Now there's a block of flats.
So he releases me onto the roof.
What a fool.
I want to tell you my story.
Die later.
What?
What the hell?
I see.
Now I'll tell you my story.
The reason...
..I want to die is...
Hey!
That's a female human being.
Laugh,
and the world laughs with you.
Weep,
and you weep alone.
My home is gone.
I cannot call
my friends or relatives.
Because they say
I murdered my wife.
I am a fugitive.
You dickshit!
Dickshit...
A new word.
Television doesn't teach you
swear words.
Can 15 years' worth of
imaginary training be put to use?
Apparently, it can.
Rock Bream.
Oplegnathus fasciatus.
Lives in the warm waters
of coastal reefs.
This fish has weak reflexes,
but can resist powerfully
when caught in a hook.
In the Kyungsang Province,
its offspring...
What is that smell?
Don't bother
asking me any questions.
I don't know anything.
Yes?
I said... I want to eat...
a living thing.
Oh... right.
Long time no see.
This is my first time here.
Maybe I'm wrong.
But she looks familiar.
You look very familiar.
Have we met before?
"Search for the Best Chef."
"Thursdays at 6:30 on MBC."
"The youngest female chef
of Japanese cuisine."
Oh, that?
They said the ratings are low,
but someone must watch it.
Women's hands are usually warm,
so they cannot make sushi.
Well, you certainly know your stuff.
Who are you?
Do you
like your clothes?
Why?
- Why did you imprison me?
- Who do you think I am?
- Yoo Heung-sam?
- Wrong.
- Did Lee So-young pay you?
- Wrong again.
Lee Jong-yong?
Kang Chang-suk?
Hwang Joo-yeun? Kim Na-sung?
Park Jin-woo? Im Duk-yoon?
Lee Jae-pyung? Kuk Su-ran?
- Who the hell are you?
- Me?
I'm a sort of scholar.
And my field of study is you.
A scholar studying Oh Dae-su.
An expert on Oh Dae-su.
Who I am isn't important.
What's important is "why".
Think hard.
Study your whole lifetime.
School has finished,
now it's time for your homework.
Keep this in mind.:
"Whether it be a grain of sand
or a rock,
in water they both sink alike. "
Let me ask you one thing.
You hypnotised me in there,
didn't you?
What did you do to me?
I miss you.
Come quickly.
Here you are.
It's alive, OK?
I'll go and slice it up for you.
I must be a different breed of woman.
My hands are very cold.
What is she doing?
Sir.
Sir, wake up.
Keep this in mind.
"Whether it be a grain of sand
or a rock...
..in water they both sink alike. "
Are you awake?
Is all this true?
That fever remedy works well.
Why did you faint if you've done
so much physical training?
A lack of vital sunlight leaves one
depleted of vitamins A and E.
Thus, one's immunity to influenza
is weakened.
Do you always talk like that?
The lock on the bathroom door
is broken.
Don't get any bright ideas
or I'll gut you like a fish.
What's this?
Suppositories. You fainted, so
how else could I give you medicine?
Can 15 years' worth of
imaginary training be put to use?
Apparently not.
That was an unforgivable sin.
I brought you back here
and then turned you down.
I can see why you're angry.
I really can.
You know, I brought you here
because I like you.
But...
You don't even know my name yet.
It's Mido.
You see...
..later on...
..when I'm really ready...
..I swear on my life
that I'll go through with it.
That song in your diary, The Face
I Want to See , that will be the sign.
When I sing it,
get ready.
I may try to resist you again
in the heat of the moment.
But no matter what, don't stop.
Just give it to me!
Give it...
..to me.
The ants...
Do you still see them?
Do you still feel that way?
Yeah, if you're alone, you see ants.
People I have met who are very lonely
have all hallucinated about ants.
I tried once to work out why.
Ants move around in groups,
you know.
So I suppose very lonely people
keep thinking of ants.
Although I have never done that.
She called from overseas
five or six years ago,
asking if her dad had come back.
She doesn't even know
that he killed her mother.
She has hardly any relatives,
so she calls us.
Her Korean has got worse.
I think her Swedish foster parents
are both doctors.
You journalists must know...
Dae-su...
Is he really still on the run?
Your daughter's address
is on the front
and on the back is a map of
your wife's grave.
Eva...
Stockholm...
Do you want to call her?
Shall I call her?
Shall we visit the grave tomorrow?
No, first I have to kill
that bastard.
BLUE DRAGON
Well?
I haven't tasted it yet.
BLUE DRAGON
So?
Did it taste the same?
I could taste food from
100 restaurants...
..but I will never forget
the food I tasted for 15 years.
BLUE DRAGON
Shall I create an ID for you,
so you can log in?
Do you have
a favourite film or song?
I've already been talking...
..to him...
"The Count of Monte Cristo"?
There's no one by that name here.
HOW'S LIFE IN A BIGGER PRISON,
OH DAE-SU?
Who are you?
THE LONELY PRINCE IN THE HIGH
TOWER.
Who is he?
I don't know who he is.
I just chat to him sometimes.
We talk about sushi.
Where are you going?
You are not to be trusted.
- VIOL...
- BLUE DRAGON
Violet Blue Dragon...
What does that mean?
Why did they order
from a place so far away?
I've already passed
five Chinese restaurants.
I think my lungs are
on the verge of exploding.
You there, tell your cooks
to put less scallions
in the dumplings.
OK.
- Leave it there and go.
- Yes, sir.
We don't take on anyone
who uses bodyguards.
Some companies specialise in that.
You should go to them.
We just take the small fry.
If the stay is over six months,
transportation is free.
Yes, of course.
Why did you imprison me, you...
..dickshit.
In our business on floor 7½
client confidentiality
is our livelihood.
I am going to avenge myself
for all 15 years.
Each tooth I extract
will age you by one year.
Keep still.
Do you want to talk?
I don't know...
I didn't see his face...
I made recordings...
OH DAE-SU
All those who are blood-type AB,
raise your hand.
Go. Shoo!
He has lost a lot of blood.
Piece of shit.
Is he dead?
I can't seem to
get through today either.
Now I have become a monster.
When my vengeance is over...
..can I return to Oh Dae-su?
Mister, are you alright?
Look at all this blood.
What happened to you?
Saewoon Apartments, Eung-am,
building 8. Take care of him.
Thank you.
Not at all.
Well, then...
Farewell, Oh Dae-su.
Farewell...
..Oh Dae-su.
Farewell.
The bastard you hate,
but don't dare kill.
The bitch you detest,
who deserves a fate worse than death.
We are at your service.
Won't he go crazy
if he's locked up for a long time?
Well, if you don't want that,
we can drug his drinks.
There's a thing
called 'Risterdal solution'.
It's a reliable drug
used to treat schizophrenia.
But it depends on the length
of the treatment,
so how long will he...
15 years.
Is that possible?
What did he do?
Oh Dae-su, you see...
..talks too much.
Go to sleep.
Tomorrow, you will visit
Joo-hwan's internet cafe.
Sit wherever you like.
Joo-hwan.
Oh Dae-su, you see...
..talks too much.
Have you heard this voice before?
Who loathes me this much?
Those 260 women you've had...
I don't know the names
of their husbands...
LOGON: MONSTER
MIDO.
Who's Mido?
A little girl who cries a lot.
Joo-hwan...
Did I...
..really talk too much?
My friend...
Maybe you should...
..look for the criminal
among people you're close to.
SEARCH: EVERGREEN
CHAT TO EVERGREEN?
CONGRATULATIONS, YOUR CASE WAS
AUTOMATICALLY DISMISSED
YESTERDAY.
But please remember this...
Open quote.
Like a gazelle
from the hand of the hunter...
Like a bird
from the snare of the fowler...
Free yourself.
Close quote.
Who are you? You bastard!
I decided when I was a prisoner
that if I got out,
I would trust no one.
If I met anyone suspicious,
I would invent a secret,
only known to the two of us.
That ID, Monster, is a trap
I designed to catch him.
You let a stranger into your home.
Who are you?
Who's Evergreen?
I tracked down that Evergreen ID
and found the owner's details.
- Are you ready to jot it down?
- Go ahead.
It's Su Dae-oh.
Does the surname 'Su'even exist?
- Address?
- Saewoon Apartments in Eung-am.
Building 7, flat 407.
Actually, life in a bigger prison
does not suit me very well.
Evergreen.
Who are you?
Is that what you wanted to ask?
No. You must find that out
for yourself.
Come on, it's a game.
First " who?"
Then "why?"
When you know the answer,
come and see me.
I'll mark your work.
You have until July 5th.
Oh no, only five days left.
Too short?
Chin up.
If you succeed,
I'll kill myself instead of Mido.
That's right, Mido.
I'm going to kill
every woman you love until you die.
Well, you're notorious
for not protecting your women anyway.
Wow, you're strong, Mr Monster.
Yes, you are the monster
that I created.
But you will never
find out why
if you go through with this.
You have been curious for 15 years...
Are you still going to kill me?
Sit down there.
Ah, the tooth torture!
You won't have enough time.
I have a pacemaker
for my weak heart.
When it was put in...
..do you know
what I said to the doctor?
"Dr Hopkins,
give me...
..a remote control
to turn my motor off."
"Pardon? Why?"
"So that I can kill myself. Easily.
At any time."
"I'll pay you an extra $100,000
for this."
What a dilemma.
You want to kill me right now,
but then you won't know
why you were imprisoned.
You want to torture me,
but I say I'll kill myself first.
Revenge? Or the truth?
What a problem for you.
I've been watching over you
for 15 years.
I've faired well thanks to you.
I wasn't bored or lonely.
Seeking revenge is the best cure
for someone who has been hurt.
Try it.
The loss of 15 years,
the pain of losing
your wife and child,
all this can be forgotten.
Once again,
revenge is good for your health.
But...
What happens
after you've had your revenge?
I bet that hidden pain
probably emerges again.
Are you there, Oh Dae-su?
Oh Dae-su.
Long time no see.
Hasn't she been tied up too long?
You left her door open.
Save me, Dae-su!
I can't. I'm going to die.
This dentist is very good.
Keep still.
What's his problem?
You see...
..they say that people
shrivel up
because of their imagination.
So do not imagine anything.
You'll become brave as hell.
Now here comes the real thing.
Sir, I'm glad
you told me about this place...
..but I haven't even started yet!
Let's go.
Let's go now.
Let's fight.
- What a tough guy!
- Your hand.
I'll chop off your hand.
You touched Mido's breasts.
Let's get out of this dump.
So do you trust me now, you bastard?
It looks hard to accomplish.
I looked into it.
The reason the bank
refused to pay $270 million
was not due to
any building irregularities.
They have internal problems.
So I don't think
we'll have any trouble.
Chairman Choi's
23 clients' shares are at 25% ...
Dae-su.
Yeah?
Did he really say that he'd kill me?
Yeah.
Because I'm the woman you love?
Dae-su.
What?
Where is my love?
I'm getting lonelier in the nights
The words you send with your eyes
I can feel with my hand
So many nights have passed
My heart is going to you
As I shed my sad tears
You're the face I miss.
They packed up their stuff
and left in a rental car.
Also, Mido called the restaurant
and left her job.
Let's go after this is done.
You should get some rest today, sir.
I can't even sleep.
Because I am lonely.
Mr Han.
Do you really think...
..that Mido has fallen in love
with Oh Dae-su?
Already?
Dae-su!
It hurts so much.
But I'll endure it.
You must understand.
How did you hold out for 15 years?
There's always a way.
Do you like it?
You do like it, don't you?
I want to make you feel good, Dae-su.
You need not worry about the future.
Imagine nothing.
I am grateful for
all those years spent in that prison.
If I was the old Oh Dae-su,
would Mido still have liked me?
He could only have known that I said
I would chop off Mr Park's hand
by putting a bug on us.
And he knew
where we were by tailing us.
I'VE BEEN BUGGED. PLEASE FIND IT.
You know,
maybe he freed you
because he has fun watching you
run wild seeking revenge.
And he'll never tell you why,
so he can toy with you forever.
Is that why?
Evergreen Press,
online printing system.
Evergreen Pasta and Pizza.
Evergreen Services,
for security, parking, cleaning.
Evergreen Tree Garden.
Evergreen Old Boys.
Sangnok High School
alumni homepage.
Evergreen Secret Diary,
Jung Sang-rok's personal site.
Norwegian Wood, Evergreen...
WELCOME TO EVERGREEN OLD BOYS
THE SANGNOK HIGH SCHOOL
ALUMNI HOMEPAGE.
I should be locking up now.
Can I just look at
the records for the class of '79?
It's dark. Put the lights on.
Take your time.
LEE WOO-JIN
Joo-hwan?
Let me ask you something.
Do you remember
Lee Woo-jin from school?
I think he went to study in America.
Lee Woo-jin?
I don't know him.
So is that the bastard's name?
How did you find out?
I looked through
all the school yearbooks.
I need more than just a name.
Got anything else?
Look at the student records.
Do you know Lee Soo-ah?
She was in our year.
Lee Soo-ah?
She died.
- What classroom was she in?
- Room two, I think.
She was in my room.
Next to yours.
So what about her?
Why is there no photo?
She died. That must be why.
How did Lee Soo-ah die?
Yeah, you wouldn't know.
She died after you moved schools.
She went to the Habchun Dam alone
and fell into the water.
She bit the dust.
One week later, they found
her bloated body in the water.
- What was she like?
- Her?
She was a total slut.
On the outside,
she acted like a lady,
but inside she was just
a filthy whore.
The rumour going around school
was that she'd fuck anyone.
I should have got in there.
I also heard that her family
was filthy rich.
Her grades were good, too.
But the worst thing was
that she was a total slut.
God, this is such an old story.
Dae-su, I can't remember
because it was so long ago,
but that Soo-ah, well...
Joo-hwan, what is it?
Joo-hwan, is something wrong?
Oh Dae-su.
My sister...
..was no slut.
You must believe that.
You got rid of your bug so
I had to come all the way here.
To eavesdrop.
That's why Joo-hwan is dead...
..because of you.
OK?
You bastard, I'm coming for you!
I'm going to kill you!
You son of a bitch!
We're not open yet.
Come back in an hour, please.
This place was recommended
by someone with six gold teeth.
Mr Park?
I had to move because of you.
To celebrate the occasion...
..I installed a new TV.
Do you like it?
It's got so many channels.
Great, isn't it?
Some prisoners
don't want to leave at all.
You lived in a place like this
for 15 years, Dae-su?
After 11 years it felt like home.
Come on, I don't need your money.
My enemy's enemy is my friend.
We threw away the hand
because it rotted.
I've missed you.
Bastard. You'll pay for this.
So why did you bring me here?
If I don't return after July 5th,
let her go.
While I was locked up here,
I remember someone visiting me.
What did that person do?
Was it three times?
I put a hypnosis-inducing drug
in your water.
Sodium barbiturate?
He's a genius!
WATERWHEEL HAIR SALON
That's rubbish.
Even though it was a Catholic school,
those rumours wouldn't have
killed her.
There was probably something else.
Could she have been pregnant, maybe?
I really don't think
Soo-ah was like that.
She was such a pure girl.
I know she never went with anyone.
But she did go out
with someone back then.
Do you want to know who he was?
I haven't got a clue!
Choon-shim.
You knew Lee Soo-ah, didn't you?
Who was her boyfriend?
You don't know?
You silly cow.
You don't know
because friendship
means nothing to you.
Shut up.
Who would know?
Who?
Joo-hwan?
What?
Yeah, I know him.
But why would he know?
Yeah?
Really?
OK. I'll call you back in a bit.
Well...
She said it was Joo-hwan
who told her the rumours
and that you should know
more than anyone.
Ring, ring.
Move aside.
You'll get hurt...
..if you get in the way.
OH DAE-SU
Good Lord!
You rascal. Put it out!
I'm leaving today. For Seoul.
So just you leave me alone, missy.
You good-for-nothing!
You're Oh Dae-su, aren't you?
And you are...
I heard
you're popular with the girls.
You know what rumours are like.
I heard you're really funny.
Say something.
It's not good
to be stuck with one image.
OK, there's this father and son.
They went
to the swimming pool and...
See you later.
TAKE CARE FUCKHEADS OF
YEAR 3, CLASS 3.
- Come on.
- Wait.
- Come here.
- No.
Come here.
OK, OK.
Satisfied?
- Lift this up.
- No way.
- Lift it up.
- No.
What?
That tickles.
Give me those.
What are you doing?
Let me see.
- Let me see.
- Stop it!
Go away.
Was it really Soo-ah? Are you sure?
I don't know her name.
I just know that she's in your class
and she rides a red bike.
Have a good trip.
See you in Seoul.
Where are you going?
I've got a date with Choon-shim.
I'll kill you if you blab to anyone.
No way.
You got locked up for 15 years
just for saying that?
Is that such a crime?
"Whether it be a grain of sand
or a rock,
in water they both sink alike."
That's Lee Woo-jin's attitude.
So,
what's the significance of July 5th?
That's the day...
..Lee Soo-ah died.
It's over now.
You were fighting for the truth,
not for revenge, weren't you?
Now, we'll run away
where Woo-jin can never follow us.
I can't end it like this.
Vengeance has become a part of me.
But you don't even know
where he lives.
"Like a gazelle
from the hand of the hunter...
"Like a bird
from the snare of the fowler...
"Free yourself. "
It is taken from the Book
of Proverbs, chapter six, verse four.
And Evergreen...
..said he lives in a high tower.
So six and four...
..must be floors.
Fourth floor.
Sixth floor.
Or the 64th floor?
P?
Penthouse!
Please insert the code.
What would you like me to pray for?
Wrong entry.
Please re-enter.
Wrong entry. Please re-enter.
"Dear Lord...
..please let me...
..meet a younger man next time."
Please make Woo-jin...
..kneel before Dae-su...
..and beg for forgiveness.
You slept with your sister.
Let's go upstairs and talk.
Get him!
Just talk.
That's better.
You slept with your sister.
So refreshing.
And I started the rumours.
That's why your sister died.
Looking in the mirror
reminds me of that day.
How about you?
Erasing my memory and telling me
to find the truth was cowardly.
I won...
..so die like you promised.
Did you think you'd forgotten
that day because you were hypnotized?
Really?
Do you know the real reason
why you can't remember?
It's because...
..you just forgot.
Is that not exciting enough for you?
Well, it's true, you just forgot.
Why? Because
it wasn't important to you.
Your rumour got so out of hand,
that the next rumour
was that Soo-ah was pregnant.
My sister got sucked into that rumour
and began believing it.
So her periods stopped
and her belly began to swell.
Fascinating, isn't it?
Imagine how a girl would feel to
carry both her child and her nephew.
Do you understand now?
Your tongue got my sister pregnant.
It wasn't Lee Woo-jin's dick.
It was Oh Dae-su's tongue.
Is that why you killed your sister?
Imagine how a boy would feel,
fathering both his child
and his nephew?
You were probably afraid.
Afraid that everyone would know
once the baby was born.
After you killed her, you realised it
was a phantom pregnancy...
..so your hating me...
..is understandable.
They said Soo-ah died alone
at the dam,
so who took this photo?
And what about the date, July 5th?
This is no fun.
I'll just finish what I was saying.
Listen carefully.
My story is really exciting.
Ever heard
of post-hypnotic suggestion?
You suggest something
during hypnosis,
then it's performed
in your wakened state.
Still haven't worked it out?
You let a stranger into your home.
Who are you?
What about you, you bastard?
We hypnotized both of you.
One fortunate thing was that,
compared to others,
both of you
were receptive to hypnosis.
Isn't this fun?
One word gets you pregnant.
Another makes you fall in love.
But no matter how receptive
you two were to hypnosis,
and no matter how good
a hypnotist Miss Yoo is,
getting people
to fall in love isn't easy.
Do you know how we did it?
Your first suggestion, of course,
was to go to that restaurant
straight after your release.
Next, to react
to the mobile phone's ringtone.
When you heard this,
you were programmed to say something.
Who are you?
Do you
like your clothes?
And Mido was programmed
to react to the man
who would say this.
When she touched your hand,
your reaction would be...
Your gravest mistake
wasn't failing to find the answer.
If you keep
asking the wrong questions,
you'll never find the right answer.
It's not,
"Why did Woo-jin imprison me?"
It's "Why did he release me?"
Once again...
..why did Woo-jin
release Dae-su after...
..15 years?
LAUGH, AND THE WORLD LAUGHS
WITH YOU. WEEP, AND YOU WEEP
ALONE.
Mr Han.
Mr Han!
Mido...
Mido doesn't know?
Why did you hide her there?
Did you think he'd hate me
just because I cut off his hand?
Didn't you work out
that it was a trap?
How can you protect your woman
with that brain?
I've secretly been raising Mido
since she was three.
What's wrong with you?
Mr Park's hand?
You moron.
Did you see his new prison? I gave
him that building for his hand!
Me!
Dae-su!
In front of me
there's some kind of box.
He's telling me to open it.
It's the same violet box...
No!
No, Mido, don't.
Don't open it, no matter what.
Or something terrible will happen.
What's in it?
You know, don't you?
Mido, just wait a little longer.
Dae-su will be there soon.
I'll be there very soon.
Can't you come now?
I'm scared.
Little Mido, you can wait, can't you?
Yes.
Very good. Good girl.
I'll call you back very soon, OK?
Please.
Don't tell Mido.
What has she done wrong?
You know it was all my fault.
I have...
..committed an unforgivable sin...
..against your sister.
And I also...
..did you wrong.
But...
..please leave Mido alone.
If by any chance...
..Mido finds out the truth,
you son of a bitch,
I'll tear you limb from limb.
And your remains will never be found.
Why?
Because I'm going
to swallow every last bit.
Woo-jin!
Please, sir, I made a mistake.
Please forget what I said.
Sir! Woo-jin!
We're Evergreen Old Boys, remember?
With the energy
of a green pine tree
The Great Sangnok High...
I'll do whatever you want.
I'll do anything. I beg you.
Woo-jin, if you want me
to be your dog, I will!
From this moment on,
I am Woo-jin's dog!
I'm your bitch.
Look, I'm wagging my tail.
I'm a dog. I'll guard your house.
I'll be your slave.
The box...
..just leave it closed.
Now...
..what will I live for?
Dae-su.
It hurts so much.
But I'll endure it.
You must understand.
My sister and I loved each other,
despite everything.
Can you two do the same?
Soo-ah.
Woo-jin.
I know you've always been afraid.
So just let go of me.
Please remember me.
I have no regrets. Do you?
This is the whole adventure
of my life until now.
Thank you for listening
to this terrible story to the end.
I trust that you will understand
my sending a letter
instead of talking to you in person.
This is because
I have no tongue.
To be honest,
there's no reason I should help you.
But there was one thing.
I was touched by this last sentence.
EVEN THOUGH
I'M NO BETTER THAN A BEAST,
DON'T I HAVE THE RIGHT TO LIVE?
The hypnosis may go wrong
and distort your memories.
Do you want to proceed?
If you're ready...
..look at that tree.
The tree...
..is slowly changing
into a concrete pillar.
You're now
inside Lee Woo-jin's penthouse.
It's a dreary night.
The sound of your footsteps
crossing to the window
fills the room.
When I ring my bell...
..you'll split into two people.
One person doesn't know
your secret.: Oh Dae-su.
The one who knows your secret
is the monster.
When I ring the bell again,
the monster will turn around
and start walking.
With each step,
he will age by one year.
When he reaches 70,
the monster will die.
There's no need to worry.
It will be a very peaceful death.
Now, good luck to you.
What's going on?
Look at you.
Who were you with?
I love you...
..Dae-su..
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/6xfr6
Help other users to choose the best subtitles