I'm a good person. I'm a hard worker.
My older sister is the only family I have.
To put me through art school...
she gave up college
and got a job at a factory.
But then she fell seriously ill,
and had to quit.
So I gave up art school and got a job.
But recently I made a decision.
I'm not sure whether to tell my sister
or not.
I'm hesitating even as i write this letter.
If I decide to do it...
I'll be listening to the broadcast
with my sister.
I can't speak with my mouth.
I'm deaf and dumb.
Please read this letter to my sister for me,
since I can't.
Sis, you're listening?
You told me if you die...
you want to be buried by the river
where we used to play.
All right, I'll do that.
But that 'll be in 40 or 50 years' time.
I'm going to save you.
Really, I swear.
Actually,
I registered to donate my kidney today.
I know you said not to...
that you'd rather die than be a burden.
But you know I never do
what I'm told. Ha ha ha.
Why did you lie that your blood type is a?
I'm telling you,
if the blood types don't match...
then we can't do a transplant!
You haven't had a blood test
since grade school, have you?
If you can't pay the hospital bills,
take her home for now.
Until we find a suitable donor.
Until then, just keep coming in for dialysis.
Okay?
Your blood type is b, b!
Organs for sale
- hey, come in!
- What's wrong with you?
"What's wrong with you"? You, bitch.
- You are all very lucky.
- Right, here's one.
Yeah, that's right.
Man, what is that, that fucking... right?
What's wrong? I wasn't going to hit you.
- What?
- Must I hold back?
The real estate guy must have thought
it'd be okay since i'm deaf.
If my sister can't sleep, then neither can i.
Aw, fucking great!
Look here, shit.
Shit, quiet, please.
"The ruling" - by the revolutionary
anarchists' association
we sentence you to death.
I heard that...
this happened in australia.
A man thought...
he had two heads.
Two heads?
Yeah, two.
And he kept getting headaches.
With two heads,
he had headaches all the time.
So you know what he did?
He shot...
one of his heads.
The left or the right?
Aren't you going to lunch?
Come on...
- we have to eat. Let's go.
- Let's go eat something.
You've only got 10 million won?
Well, first of all...
you give us your kidney, then we'll do it.
You give us yours
and we'll get you one for your sister.
For 10 million won.
Got it?
Your blood type's b, right?
21 days later
congratulations! This is great.
Finding a donor this fast...
is simply a miracle.
The surgery's in a week...
so have her admitted in five days.
You have got 10 million won
in your account, right?
Ha ha.
So all your problems are solved.
Isn't it great?
Are you happy now?
You idiot, you stupid fuck!
That money would've saved your sister.
Why not?
Now's not the time to be thinking that way.
There's a saying:
"Is a boiled pig afraid of boiling water?"
Besides...
then what are you going to do?
You've only got a week.
You know how long it'll take
to find another donor?
Is that her?
She's cute.
Must be a friend.
That's the bastard who fired you?
Son of a bitch.
That car's worth 10 years of your salary.
That's why we need a revolution.
So sick people will get free treatment...
and you can get...
any damned organ you need!
The bad image kidnappers get
is because of kids getting killed.
But we're different.
Give us the money,
and we'll return the kid pronto.
Shit, I'm afraid she'll grow too fond of us.
Maybe she won't want to go home.
She'll be playing with us all the time.
What fun!
Won't have to go to school.
What?
It's summer vacation,
so she doesn't go to school anyway.
Hey!
But think about it from
her parents' point of view.
They'll be so happy to see her again.
They'll love her even more,
and the family will be closer.
We really need the money,
so we'll ask for exactly 26 million won.
How conscientious is that, right?
That money's nothing to them...
but for us it's a matter of life and death.
Movement of capital...
maximizes the value of money,
so it's not even a crime.
Don't you think?
In this world...
there are good kidnappings
and bad kidnappings.
A good kidnapping enlists...
the parents' cooperation.
If parents call the police...
the kid dies.
The parents pay up...
and the kid gets returned.
Then nobody finds out about it.
That is why people think
all kidnappings are bad.
Daddy!
What?
Can I go play at yoosun's house?
No.
Then will you buy me
a cell phone like yoosun's?
Hey, president park!
Why do you keep buying her stuff like that?
Have some consideration
for your neighbors.
Oops!
Peng!
President park!
Sir, please help me! My wife ran off...
and my children are hungry.
I'm a founding employee.
In six years I never missed a day of work.
You know the percentage
of faulty goods was 0.008%.
0.008% only!
Peng, what are you doing?
I explained it to you already.
And to come to my home...
is he your staff?
Yes, engineer peng!
I devoted myself to welding.
I gave away my youth
to llshin electronics, you know?
Daddy!
- Are you okay?
- Let go!
- Honey!
- Let go.
- I'll go down with a welder.
- Yoosun!
I devoted my life for llshin electronics.
- Hey, let go.
- Kids are dying of starvation.
- Let go of me and talk.
- What if I let you go?
It's not going to work.
Why?
Look at him.
I was fired by the kid's father.
I'll be the first person the police call in.
Then what do we do?
Defeat the communists
what a big army!
The way for korea is victory
go forward! Go forward!
Take a step forward towards democracy!
Go forward! Go forward!
Put it down!
Defeat the communists
what a big army!
The way for korea is victory
let's go to the victory
let's go to the victory, yeah!
By the way...
how come daddy's friend is so poor?
What?
Uh, that's...
we spent a lot of money because i'm sick.
What hospital is your mother in?
She doesn't know about the car accident.
Her father said not to tell her.
Daddy was too busy...
so they got divorced.
That's why he left me with you.
Mine?
Don't cry.
Stop it!
He wants to trade it for your doll.
Daddy loves yoosun.
Yoosun loves daddy, too.
More than anything.
I kidnapped yoosun.
She doesn't know it.
Send me 26 million won.
I'll be in contact.
Hey.
The people i'm most jealous of...
are those girls...
with mommies to braid their hair.
Then come see me sometime.
Really?
Call me anytime.
I'm all alone, so i get bored.
Go to geumho station,
wait outside exit three.
What a big army!
The way for korea is victory
go forward! Go forward!
Take a step forward towards democracy!
Please stay inside the yellow line
as the train approaches...
a discharge allowance
he never said why
he missed work so often?
Then he never went off for special training?
Yes, last week from monday to thursday.
Hey, toad, let's play hide-and-seek.
Hoy, hoy, hoy! Rock, scissors, paper!
She's washing.
Hey, porori!
Toad...
- you're captured.
- Hey, you!
Give it! I'm watching cartoons!
Really.
- You're captured.
- Hey, porori!
Here, here.
Kidnapping is the worst thing
in the world. How would you...
please send back yoosun asap.
This is my dying wish.
I love you. Bye.
Is anybody out there?
Somebody help me!
Go away! Go away!
Ryu!
Ryu...
ryu...
no! The water's deep, even standing
it's far over my head.
I now know why i thought
the water was deep.
I hadn't gone back since being a kid.
When i was a kid,
it was up over my head. Way over.
Near seomjin river...
have you ever done
anything to provoke anyone?
Please think again.
I always thought i lived an honest life.
That's what everyone says.
Excuse me, but what is your net worth?
I'm a high school graduate...
and i started as an electrical engineer.
When the economy crashed...
my wife left me.
But why i don't understand...
why didn't you call the police?
I thought lots of kids were returned safely.
If i do what they tell me.
Sir, i checked...
and it looks like they
used yoosun's cell phone.
I called but they didn't answer,
so we can't locate them.
This is yoosun's number, right?
My wife gave it to her before she left.
Just a second, please.
Yeah, i'm working.
So an operation will take care of it?
Where would I get 10 million won?
What the hell am I supposed to do?
At least our kid wasn't kidnapped
and killed.
We're lucky, you know. 'cause we are poor.
Saw.
Hold it.
One, two...
three!
Saw.
That's not it.
Lung has gone through its course.
It looks like a woman's handwriting.
Do you recognize it?
Yoosun.
Yoosun, mommy was wrong.
Honey, wake up.
In the summer of 1996,
there was a stir outside.
They captured an image of a spider that
lives in water, not on tree or between rocks.
There has never been such occasion
in this country.
It was discovered in a remote area...
in kyunggi province, near yeonchun.
Daddy...
why didn't you give me
swimming lessons a bit earlier?
I sold the company...
and I put this house up for sale.
That's...
all the money I have.
Well, there's nothing special about it.
A brother and sister lived here.
They don't know where they moved to.
I'll look into it.
Let's go. Nothing more to see here.
You asked if i ever provoked anyone?
Are you the father?
Well, actually...
I am. How is he?
If i were a very optimistic doctor...
i'd tell you...
there was hope.
When did you first know
we'd become like this?
The moment our eyes met.
You're like an ant.
An ant?
They say ants are psychic.
They predict earthquakes and floods.
That was baek hyun-jin's "affection"...
requested by a man who signed
his name as "ryu of doksan-dong."
Any of you remember this guy?
He was deaf.
He sent a postcard two months ago,
saying his sister was sick.
Oh, no. She passed away.
He says, "I'm the one who killed her.
"My life has no meaning now."
You shouldn't say that.
Would she want to see you like this?
Don't forget she's watching you
from above.
I know you can't hear me...
but me and our listening audience...
are praying for you.
Be strong.
To help you out...
I'll send you a new
maybell kimchi refrigerator.
You didn't write an address...
so if anyone listening to
this broadcast knows him...
please let him know.
We're waiting for such touching
stories from you, our viewers.
If there's a story you want to tell,
send me a letter.
Our address is seoul, yeongdungpo-gu...
yeouido post office, box #87...
c/o lee geum-hee.
I kept them
because the pictures were pretty.
I cried so much while reading them.
But is he really a kidnapper?
I shouldn't send him a gift, then.
You haven't sent it, have you?
Don't say anything. Just leave.
Car: Matiz, seoul 3296
color: Orange
he's mentally disabled, not stupid.
President park, this is choi speaking.
Since the autopsy results are out...
and we checked the car...
yes, I know that place.
I'll see you there at 2:00.
Yes.
Yes, I'm calling about the sticker.
Yeah, the kidney transplant.
Yes.
She wouldn't have lived long anyway.
I searched through the hospitals
and found her file.
Yes.
I was lucky to receive an organ
from a brain-dead patient...
but apparently they didn't
have enough money.
President park...
what I really want to ask is...
what are you going to do
to the bastards when you find them?
Kill him.
Dismantle the conglomerates!
Drive out american products!
Destroy the new liberalism
that ruins the lives of the people!
Drive out american products!
Destroy the new liberalism
that ruins the lives of the people!
I understand.
I'll wire you the money tomorrow,
and then call you back.
Destroy the conglomerates!
Drive out american products!
Are you going far?
Hell, yeah.
Shit, you said I could go first!
It's in an artery, chulseung.
Don't take it out!
Mom!
The noodles were all soggy last time,
so i threw it out.
Yeah, hurry.
Huh?
Where is the bastard?
Fuck you.
Where?
Tell me, you bitch!
Fuck!
Next time, please don't order just one dish.
Mister.
We didn't kill yoosun on purpose.
I'm sorry, we made a mistake.
But i have something to tell you.
I'm not just any ordinary person.
If anything happens to me...
my organization, a terrorist group...
they'll kill you.
For sure, 100%.
I gave them your picture.
If you want to live, just leave me.
This is for your sake, honest.
And then...
i'm sorry.
100%, really.
She sat next to the deaf kid in first grade.
Then she's deaf, too?
No.
Then how come she went
to the same school?
What I mean is...
she got expelled when
they found out she wasn't deaf.
She went to college a bit,
and was a left-wing activist.
She sneaked onto a boat once,
trying to reach north korea.
And?
She got caught by some fishermen.
She was caught in the net.
She's part of the
revolutionary anarchists' association.
What?
I mean, she was.
Go talk to intelligence
and bring in a few of them.
The problem is...
she was the only member.
Make way please, excuse me.
Move aside, please.
What's going on here?
Excuse me, we're coming through.
I'm sorry, you can't ride here.
It's c-3.
They found some of cha youngmi's
flyers at a crime scene.
What scene?
Three people were murdered.
The organ dealers are dead!
But their sides are cut open.
You know what that means?
He took the kidneys!
President park,
he seems like a real psycho.
Killed three people by himself.
Is he really human?
Give this up now.
I'll return all your money.
I know you're a good guy.
So you know...
the reason why...
i have to kill you?
Huh?
Right?
Hello?
Inchon central hospital.
This is peng yoonchol's father, right?
He just died at 1.20.
Please come in
to take possession of the body.
The mortuary's on floor b2.
You've got the wrong number.
What?
You guys, why are you...
"the ruling." we sentence you to death.
Mister...
if anything happens to me...
my organization, a terrorist group...
they'll kill you.
For sure, 100%.
I gave them your picture.
Edited by GP Mobiles
gp_mobiles@yahoo.com