Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.MY-SUBS.org
TALK TO HER
The stage is full of wooden
chairs and tables.
Two women come out with robes.
Their eyes are closed.
Like two sleepwalkers.
You get scared... They trip
on everything, poor them.
But suddenly, a man appears.
With a very sad face, the
saddest I have ever seen.
He pushes tables and chairs
out of their way.
You can't imagine how touching
it was.
Someone was sitting next to me.
In his 40s, handsome.
He cried with emotion,
lots of times.
I don't understand why...
It was very beautiful!
I have a surprise for you!
I have an autograph of
Rina Baus for you.
I had to buy the photo.
It is in english and says:
I hope you surpass all
the obstacles...
...and start dancing.
- She has her period.
- It's early.
Good evening.
Benigno, can you
stay tonight?
My sister can't,
and I don't have anyone else.
Why did you come?
You should have called.
I am not taking advantage of you.
This week you did 3 nights.
Don't worry. A free afternoon
is enough for me.
I have to see the house
workers. It's a mess.
And to frame a photo.
My condition is not improving.
The hospital will decide.
Your husband left you
and the children.
Just come the nights you can.
We will be ok.
Thanks a lot.
- You cut off the intestinal food.
- She couldn't take it.
- We will try again tomorrow.
- Yes, go now.
And keep the spirits up!
Six bulls and a woman.
Wednesday at Briuega.
Lydia P Gonzales will
fight six bulls.
Why such a drastic decision?
It's my job. 2 bulls, or 6.
Whatever they say.
People say a lot of bullfighters
won't fight with you...
...because you are a woman.
People can say what they want.
Too much chauvinism in bullfighting,
but there are exceptions.
Nino Valencia was happy to share
billing with you for several months.
Do you think he did it
to promote himself?
And when he succeeded that,
he abandoned you?
I told you, I don't want
to talk about this!
But by talking about
certain problems...
...is the first step
towards their solution.
- Nino Valencia...
- Enough!
My dear Lydia, let me
finish the question.
I am not discussing this.
I told you earlier.
You didn't say anything earlier!
It's bad what you are saying!
They will think
it's a fixed interview.
And I am on of the few who
dare say the truth...
...and you should dare accept
...that Nino Valencia
took advantage of you.
He shared with you not only
the fame, but sex as well.
And he left you when
time was right.
Juan Luis, Marco here...
How are you?
I want to ask you something.
I would like to do an article
about Lydia Gonzales.
Yes, I see it too...
I would like to do something
deep.
For the Sunday issue?
Great...
- The woman has gone crazy!
- She dedicates it to you.
She would let the bull injur
her, just so that you see it.
You shouldn't have come,
especially you.
Don't tell me anything.
I know what I am doing.
Nino should concentrate.
He doesn't want any more worries.
Nothing to worry about. He should
just come to pick up his stuff.
- Or tell me where to send them.
- Send them at my place.
He, himself, should say so.
This is nothing to do with you.
You can leave whenever you want.
- Good evening.
- Scotch on the rocks, please.
- What glass do you prefer?
- A tall one.
Can I talk to you for
a minute, please?
Forget it. When something is
over, it's over.
- What are you saying?
- Can I talk to you?
If you take me to Madrid,
we can talk on the way.
It will be my pleasure.
- Who named you Lydia;
- My father.
It's as if he sealed your destiny.
He always wanted to be a bullfighter,
but stayed a banderillero.
He is the one that was there
for me, more than anyone else.
But he died last year.
I am sorry.
'El Pais' wants me to do a profile
on you for their Sunday issue.
Do you write on bullfighting?
I don't know your name.
To be honest,
I know nothing of it.
But I know a lot about
desperate women.
And who told you I am
desperate?
- This is the impression I have.
- Bullfighting doesn't interest you.
You are interested in my
relationship with Nino Valencia.
Tell El Pais to leave me alone!
- Take me from here!
- What's going on?
Take me from here! There is
a snake in the kitchen.
- Give me the keys.
- The door is open.
Calm down.
And stay there.
My purse.
Take me to a hotel.
I am never coming back to
this house.
- To which hotel?
- To Eurobuilding, lets say.
Don't tell anyone about
the snake, please.
Only my family knows.
I always respect other
people's phobias.
After what you have done, how
can I say no to the profile?
Think about it again. I will
call tomorrow, tell me then.
Thanks for everything.
Do you want me to stay? I can
sleep in the sofa.
No, I need to get used to
being alone.
Do you wash her?
What do you think?
- How was the night?
- Normal.
- Give it to me. I will do it.
- I am going now.
- Good bye.
- Bye, Matilde.
It's so hot!
- Lets cut her hair.
- short, it's more practical.
We will leave it as it was
when she came here...
...so that she is not surprised
when she wakes up.
After 4 years, it will be great.
I believe in miracles.
So should you.
- Why me?
- Because you need them.
One might happen to you,
and you will not know.
So hot!
I took something from the
drugstore...
...to help stop the perspiration
stains on my uniform.
My armpits are ok,
but look at my face.
- What's it called?
- Perspirex.
It's Marco...
Remember me?
- Sure.
- How are you?
- Naked.
I need to buy some clothes.
That's all I've got.
I can bring you some
from your place.
I don't want anything from there.
Maybe another time.
- Where are we going?
- To Sybilla.
- You think I am crazy.
- Why?
- Because I don't want to go home.
- No, I understand.
When I separated, I couldn't
sleep in the same bed...
I was sleeping in the sofa,
in the living room.
For a week. Until I finally
bought a new bed.
So, you are separated.
I am alone.
AFTER A FEW MONTHS
Marco, we should
talk afterwards.
- We've been talking for an hour.
- You have, not me.
Indeed.
Did you read about the nuns
that got raped by the misionaries?
Priests, themselves!
It's horrible!
Yeah, they've gone bad too!
Where are we heading to?
First they raped the locals.
Then, due to AIDS, they started
raping nuns.
And I admired them so much!
Not all of them are rapists,
for sure.
No, some of them are
pedophiles.
- What's that? Everyone loves fucking.
- Antonio, you are an animal!
- How do the bulls look?
- Good, but fat.
- How much do you think?
- Over 500 kilos.
I am going to the bar. And don't
forget, we are eating home.
If the kids don't see their aunt,
there'll be hell to pay.
Don't cry, my love.
- How is it?
- Very bad.
It tore her apart.
The father will be happy now!
'Not the little one!', we kept
telling him, my mother and I.
And yet, she became like him.
Don't be upset.
What time is it?
It has been four hours.
AFTER THREE WEEKS
Are you going to Cordoba?
Yes... I would like to stay,
but I can't.
We can't do anything extra.
The bar's been closed for 20 days.
The kids are with the neigbhour,
and I've neglected the other one.
If something happens, can
you be here in 2 hours?
- Rest assured for that.
- We have to have faith.
I light some candles...
...but I find it very
difficult to have faith.
When can we put her medals
back on her?
Not yet.
With all these...
wounds, the tracheotomy...
She never took them off.
I will get a vase.
I have to go to the US
for three months.
It is very important,
says my agent.
And yet... the way things
stand here...
...I don't want to go.
Can you get out for
a moment, please?
No smoking here.
Did she talk to you that day?
- Or rather, I talked.
- And what did you say?
Things that concern me.
Did she tell you anything
about me?
Honestly, Lydia hadn't talked
about you for a long time.
- It's my fault for what happened.
- No, it's my fault.
Caetano made me
freak out.
Marco, I've always wanted
to ask you something.
Why did you cry that night,
after you killed the snake?
It brought me lots of memories.
Years ago, I had to
kill another snake.
We were in Africa.
She had the same phobia as you.
She was waiting outside the tent,
terrified, defenseless...
...and totally naked...
...because she had seen the snake,
while we were asleep.
Was it the same one who made
you sleep in the living room?
I hate that woman.
- I haven't seen her for years.
- Even worse.
What can I do to make you
forget her?
Exactly what you are doing now.
You were sound asleep. We didn't
want to wake you up.
- Is Dr Vega here?
- He is in his office.
Rosa, close the door.
There's a draft.
- She opened her eyes.
- That gives me the creeps!
- And when she yawns?
- I shit myself!
Good morning, doctor.
I want to talk to you.
How are you? Did you sleep well?
I will buy you coffee.
How long for might Lydia
stay like that?
Months... years...
maybe for the rest of her life...
There is no hope?
As a doctor, I have to say
no... However...
RESUSCITATION
Meryl Moon wakes up after
15 years in a coma.
She went into a coma during
childbirth.
Meryl was a PVS, persistent
vegetative state, like Lydia, for life.
Her recovery contradicts
everything I am about to say.
That is, that there is hope.
I insist. Scientifically, no.
But if you want to have faith,
OK.
Is she opening her eyes?
Or I imagine this?
She does, but that doesn't mean
she is aware of anything.
Her brain cells has been
completely destroyed.
However, it can control
the automatic functions...
such as breathing, sleeping,
waking up and intestinal functions.
She opens her eyes,
but mechanically.
Her brain is dead. She has
no ideas and feelings.
Come in, please.
- My name is Benigno.
- Marco Zuloaga
This is Alicia.
Was it your first night here?
The first one is the worst.
Then you get used to it.
Why these boots?
They prevent her feet from
twisting or falling.
- They look like 'Ibiza' boots.
- I've never been to Ibiza.
- I know you.
- From my books?
It was in Café Muller...
We happened to be sitting together.
And at some stage,
you started crying.
I told you about him.
He cried watching "Café Muller".
I have to go.
That fast?
We barely talked.
- Maybe another time.
- Will you come in the afternoon?
Come to see us. I am always here,
even during the night.
I am a 'veteran' here.
If you need something...
- Should I call Dr Vega;
- Carry on with what you are doing.
The other day, while browsing
my notes...
...I found some
from your visit.
I wrote a topic to be discussed
during the second visit...
...that never took place.
- What about?
- Your sexual orientation.
- My sexual orientation?
- Yes, your sexuality.
Whether you like men or women.
During your visit, you said
you were still a virgin.
Answering your question
somehow...
...I think I look for men,
mostly.
- Is this why you came to see me?
- I can't remember now.
I guess that's it...
But I am very well now.
Do you have a partner?
More or less. I am not alone
anymore. I don't have a problem.
I hope you were not offended
by my question.
Was her father here?
He asked me if I am a fag.
He used an american expression,
more subtle.
- What is my orientation?
- And what did you say?
- That I like men.
- Really?
No, you fool. I lied.
How can he dare ask whether
I like men or women?
- What does he care?
- I am glad I found out.
Did he ask the head nurse or you
if you like bestiality or coprophagy?
No, you are right. They don't
ask such things.
I might go on a trip, and I won't
be able to come and see you.
But, in Geneva, they've
offered me a creation...
...a chorography
that thrills me.
An old idea for a ballet.
I call it 'Trenches'.
It is about the first
world war.
I will need a lot of dancers...
...because in the war there
are a lot of soldiers.
But everyone dances in Geneva.
It is great.
I want female dancers too, because
the soldier when dying...
...lets his soul
get out of his body...
...the ghost of which
will be a female dancer.
With a white classic skirt
like 'Giselle'...
...but with red stains of blood.
Very good!
Alicia loved it.
It's good because life emerges
out of death.
the female emerges from
the male.
And from the earthly emerges the...
The beach?
The water?
The ethereal.
The ethereal...
the imperceptible, the spirit.
I have the music. It is from
Kristof Penderesky.
It was written for the victims
of Hiroshima, but it's OK.
Of course. Alicia remembers
it perfectly well.
It's music for the battle.
It's wild and beastly.
And regarding the music during deaths
I have a masterpiece...
...which you will listen to,
right now.
It will drive you crazy.
Alicia, my dear.
Good bye, my dear.
Good bye, Katerina.
And you look beautiful.
- You should go ahead with 'Trenches'.
- I will.
Look... We will place you
next to the window.
You will be able to see your
friends dancing.
I love this room.
I will order everything.
Come in and shut the door...
How are you?... Sit down.
Alicia, look who's here.
We're just getting some air,
reading magazines...
Who was the lady that just left?
Katerina, Alicia's teacher.
Dancing teacher.
Nice character, Katerina.
She has a dancing school somewhere
here. Alicia was her student.
And Katerina loves her like
her daughter.
FOUR YEARS AGO
Benigno, you have been standing
at the window for half an hour.
I am coming, mother.
What's the matter? Are you
following me?
This is yours, I think.
It must have dropped you.
Is everything there?...
I didn't touch anything...
- Where are you going?
- Home.
Can I accompany you?
I have nothing else to do.
- Yes, but I am going home.
- Of course... It will do me good.
Dancing is my life.
I love dancing shows.
- Do you like dancing?
- Yes, of course
But I don't follow it.
What else do you do,
besides dancing?
I travel and watch old movies.
Silent Cinema is attractive
to me, in particular.
- Where do you go when you go out?
- I don't.
You should go out.
I was taking care of my mother,
but she passed away 2 months ago.
I am sorry. Mine died too,
years ago though.
Here we are...
Thanks for the wallet.
Dr Roncero, psychiatrist.
7th left.
Twenty three.
I was waiting for her by the window,
but that day she didn't come.
But I knew her address and that
her father was a psychiatrist.
Dr Roncero's office.
I would like to make an
appointment.
- Is it tomorrow at 5 OK?
- Isn't earlier possible?
No, tomorrow at 5.
Your name?
- What do you want?
- I have an appointment at 5.
Come in. Don't stand there.
Benigno Martin?...
I need some information.
I just wanted to see Alicia,
but I was there, at a psychiatrist.
I decided to tell him I missed
my mother.
I started when I was little.
And all those 15 years
you took care of your mother?
I was always next to her...
I was studying to be a nurse.
I was only going out to the
classes.
I was also studying aesthetics,
make-up and hairdressing.
But those by post.
So you did those on your mother?
Of course, and I cut her hair,
dyed it, did her nails.
And I scrubbed her down well,
front and back.
My mother wasn't disabled, or mad.
She was only a bit lazy.
She was a beautiful woman
and I didn't want to let herself go.
- What did your father say?
- Nothing. What could he?
- Is he dead?
- God, no.
He is in Sweden, I guess.
I haven't heard from him for years.
Doesn't he come to see you?
He has his own family there,
after he left my mother.
We are not in touch.
Why did you come to see me,
Benigno?
- What's your problem?
- Me? Nothing.
You must have since you came
to see a psychiatrist.
Loneliness, I guess.
Have you had a sexual
relationship with a woman?
- With a man?
- No, neither.
I will see you in a week.
- Am I not well doctor?
- That's not it...
However, your adolescence was
kind of special.
- It wasn't special.
- It was. Very special.
And we must analyse it in depth.
Yes, lets analyse it.
- Should I come in a week?
- Very well.
I am glad.
- What are you doing here?
- I was just going. Don't be angry.
I just wanted to see you...
But I am harmless.
Dr Roncero's office...
Hi, Lola...
I just had a shit of
huge dimensions.
Can you be in charge?
Alicia never came back. I
didn't want to scare her again.
After a week I went to her
place, to see her father.
It was raining during that
whole week.
Next time I saw her was here.
What happened to her?
A car accident,
during a rainy day.
Her father didn't want her to
be alone, not even for a moment.
He asked for the best nurses.
And I have a good reputation here...
So they suggested me...
And when he saw me, he remembered
me, and hesitated for a moment.
But in the end, he took
Matilde and me, exclusively.
And this was four years ago...
And here we are now...
Right, Alicia?
I started going to the ballet,
when I had a day-off.
And to the film library to watch
silent movies.
German, American, Italian
films, everything.
And afterwards I would tell her
about all that she had seen.
The four most complete years
of my life.
I take care of Alicia...
I do what she would, except
the trips, of course.
With me and Lydia
it's the opposite.
I can't touch her.
I don't recognize her body.
Neither can I help the nurses
turn her around.
And I feel I am lousy.
Talk to her. Tell her that.
I would like to,
but she can't hear me.
How are you so certain
about this?
Her brain is dead, Benigno.
The woman's mind is a mystery,
especially in such sickness.
You must look after the woman,
talk to her...
...don't forget that she's alive
and that you love her.
This is the only therapy.
I know from experience.
And what do you know
about women?
Benigno, what do you know
What do you know about women?
A lot. 20 years next to one,
4 with another.
I like the bullfighter's boyfriend.
He has style.
How do you know? You saw him?
Of course not, but I can tell
from his face.
And his bulging trousers.
He is a good friend of
Benigno, right;
- Is he gay too?
- No way. What are you saying now?
- Is Benigno, you think?
- Rumours say so!
- You are wrong.
- Dr Vega told me so as well.
- And where did he find out?
- From Alicia's father.
I don't like the intimacy
he has with the patient...
...but Vega told me not to
worry, because he is gay.
I am going and I'll let you
carry on talking crap about him.
- She likes Benigno.
- She is not in her senses.
I have the day off.
I am going to the film library.
- Are you coming?
- I will see my publisher tonight.
I have to go back to work soon.
This woman is not well.
You know what I mean.
Her skin is dry.
Let's see... Here...
- Did you talk to her?
- No, and don't insist.
Hi, Lydia. You must be
patient with him.
Have a good time at work.
'Shrinked lover'.
Rosa has the flu.
I hope you didn't get it from her.
I am glad you feel well,
but I will massage you...
...and I will rub you with
a rosemary lotion.
No, nothing is happening to me.
Last night I saw a movie that
shook me a lot.
It was the love story...
...of Alfredo, a nice young
guy, but a bit fat...
...and a friend of Amparo,
who is a scientist.
Amparo prepares a new
experimental diet...
...that will revolutionize
the food industry.
What egoism! You only
think of yourself!
I found it!
It might be dangerous. I never
gave it to a human before.
You still think I act
with selfishness?
It has done miracles for you!
Don't worry, my love!
I will find the antidote!
Time was passing by...
...but Amparo couldn't find
the antidote...
...and poor Alfredo,
day by day, shrank in misery.
I will always love you.
So that Amparo doesn't suffer...
...Alfredo leaves and goes
to find his mother.
He hadn't seen her for 10 years,
beacause he was lousy.
He hadn't told Ambaro
where his mother lived.
Lots of things going on
in this movie.
But the most important
thing is...
...after years full of
regrets and studies...
...Amparo finds the address
of his mother.
And goes there.
Hotel Yukali.
Room 15.
- Sleep, my darling.
- And what if I be a burden by mistake?
And Alfredo...
...stays inside her...
...for ever.
AFTER ONE MONTH
Come on, put your hands
correctly... This way...
It's quite cool...
It's great...
It's nice here by
the balcony, right?
Lydia likes to sit by
the balcony as well.
Did you hear that?
She likes it a lot.
Look at them... It's as if
they are talking about us.
What do you think they say?
They have no shame.
Women talk about everything
with each other.
Lydia would tell her she has
completed two months of sickness.
Benjamin and Angela...
...will you bond in marriage,
with your own will?
Join your hands together...
...and declare your wish
in front of God.
I, Angela,
take you, Benjamin...
...to be my lawful husband...
I will love you
in happiness and in sickness...
...so long as we shall both live.
The Lord that joined you in love...
...let him accept your declaration
of love today.
May your love last eternally.
What are you doing here? We
were gonna meet at the hotel.
I changed my mind.
I've always liked weddings.
Weren't you gonna see
your sister before the game?
I called her.
She will come to the hotel.
I promised her we will eat at
the restaurant tonight.
As you wish.
- Nice ceremony, right?
- Excellent.
- I didn't expect her so young.
- You don't trust me right?
We can't have another day
passing by without talking.
Don't worry. Finish with Angela,
I have proof.
For example, at the ceremony
I didn't cry, you did.
- Right.
- And you shouldn't have.
Don't you believe me?
I needed 10 years to get over
it. I finally made it.
Lydia, trust me,
it's over.
I travelled with Angela.
The excuse was to write
a travel guide.
In reality, I wanted her
out of Madrid and drugs.
Madrid is hell. Our relationship
functioned outside it.
After five trips,
I brought her to her parents...
...who kept her away
from drugs and from me.
Did you still love her?
I cried not being able to share
things with her.
It's terrible to leave
a person you love so much.
What a sad story!
Love is a sad thing when
it ends...
...as the song says.
Marco, we need to talk afterwards.
- We've been talking for an hour.
- You have, not me.
You're right.
My leg needs two months of therapy,
said the doctor.
But you know what? I am glad
that bull hit me.
Now I can stay with you until
you wake up.
No one will take me away from you.
We got back together,
a month ago...
Lydia would tell you at the
wedding. She didn't in the end.
It was you she cried for.
She called me to tell me
she cried for me.
Last time we spoke.
Now that I don't fight
due to injury...
...I would like to stay
near her during the night.
Like at your place.
I am alone again.
You were looking at her breasts.
Difficult to avoid it.
They grow by the day.
Benigno, I am thinking of taking
a trip... I have to work.
And Lydia?
She doesn't need me anymore.
Did you break up?
You can call it that.
I expected this, Marco.
Don't ask why, I just did.
There was something in your
relationship that didn't function right.
When are you going?
Soon, but I'll see you before
I go.
I am so sorry you are going.
I am leaving, Benigno.
I'll see you soon.
She didn't have her period yet?
I am looking at the month's report.
She should have had it.
Yes, it's a bit late.
Two weeks. That's a lot.
Are you sure she had it last month?
I personally dealt with it.
It was when you had the flu.
She seems a bit swollen.
They often have abnormalities.
For example, Lydia
doesn't have a period anymore.
Anyway, we should tell Dr Vega.
I brought some of my guides
for Alicia and you.
I said goodbye to Lydia.
I went to see Alicia, but they
didn't let me enter the room.
Is there something wrong?
No. Just some infection
that Alicia got.
Can you drive me home?
I am done with work.
- It's not serious, I hope.
- I don't know.
They do some medical examinations,
but they haven't told me anything.
Brazil...
...Turkey, Cuba.
- I will read them to Alicia.
- They are guides.
Yours. They must be good.
- Are you travelling alone?
- Yes.
I would like to talk to you
about this before you go.
- About what?
- Loneliness.
I want to get married.
- Alicia, of course!
- Benigno, you are nuts!
We will get along better than
most couples.
- Why shouldn't I marry her?
- Because she is in a coma!
Because she can't say 'yes'
in the church!
Because, she is virtually dead!
Get in the car!
- What are you talking about?
- Get in the car!
Your relationship with Alicia
is a crazy monologue!
We often talk to PVS,
but we don't marry them.
Incredible what you are saying.
I had a different opinion of you.
Don't say or think about it
ever again!
Promise!... If you say that to
anyone else, you will be in trouble!
If that calms you down,
then I promise.
- Regardless of how much you like her...
- You like her too, right?
Of course I like her.
- She likes you too.
- She is virtually dead!
She has no feelings about me,
you, or herself!
Understand that!
Our patient Alicia Roncero
was raped and is pregnant.
Before I tell her father
I want you to tell me...
...which bastard did it!
Everyone is upset.
You are responsible. Alicia
was on your floor.
Then allow me to explain the
situation.
Rosa, please.
Alicia's period stopped
two months ago.
I thought it was one month
initially, but I was wrong.
It wasn't in last month's report.
It says it was dealt with normally.
I was down with flu
during that week.
You wrote that.
Right, Benigno?
- It is your typewriting.
- Yes, it was me.
Why did you lie?
I didn't want it to become a problem.
On other occasions, the patients'
periods have also stopped.
How come no one noticed?
Where is the night person?
She can't come today.
She phoned.
Didn't see notice anything strange?
She has problems at home.
A lot of nights she doesn't come.
And who replaces her?
I will tell Roncero
that his daughter...
...is day and night with
a nutcase?
Lets calm down for a bit.
Benigno, do you realise you
are the prime suspect?
Why did you hide the first delay?
What explanation do you have?
Would you ever harm Alicia?
Definitely not!
Last night I was
at the parking lot...
...and overheard a discussion
between Benigno and Marco.
Benigno said he wanted to
marry Alicia.
Marco tried to change his mind,
but in vain.
Lots of couples, he said...
...don'r get along
as well as him and Alicia.
JORDANIA, AFTER EIGHT MONTHS
It was Lydia Gonzales' funeral
yesterday, at Almudena.
The thirty-year old bullfighter
was in a coma since...
Can I speak with
Benigno Martin?
He doesn't work here anymore.
- Are you sure?
- Positive.
- And sister Rosa Lazaga;
- Who are you?
- Marco Zuloaga.
- I will put you through.
- Who is it?
- Marco Zuloaga.
I am calling from Jordan.
I found out about Lydia.
I am sorry, Marco.
You should have called me.
We had a lot of problems here.
What happened? Benigno isn't
there anymore, I was told.
Benigno is in jail.
He is accused of raping Alicia.
Help him. He has no one
the poor guy.
Did you go see him?
After what he did, I can't.
However he does need help,
and you are his friend.
- What prison is he in?
- In Zegovia.
Wait for me here.
- I want to see a prisoner.
- In the visting section.
Through this door, on the left.
I want prisoner Benigno Martin.
It isn't a visting day,
but I will see whether...
I am sorry, I can't hear you.
It isn't a visiting day.
And the lodger didn't ask
for a visit.
He doesn't know I am in Madrid.
I came today.
- Are you a relative?
- A friend.
- Marco Zuloaga is my name.
- Can I see your I.D.?
- Can I call him?
- He will call you.
I have changed number. Can you
give him the new one?
And remember.
Visiting days are Saturday
and Sunday.
But the lodger should ask for
the visit.
If he doesn't want to see you,
there is nothing we can do.
And something else. We don't
have prisoners here...
We don't have prisoners here,
we have lodgers.
Marco, is that you?
I am glad to hear your voice.
I asked your visit on Saturday.
- Where are you?
- Outside the clinique.
Dr Vega told me everything.
How could you do it?
Did you come back to Spain
to get on my back?
Do you need anything?
What should I bring you on Saturday?
I need information.
What do you know about Alicia?
They wouldn't say anything
from the clinique.
She is in a different one.
They don't know where.
- I don't believe this.
- Neither do I.
But I am not surpised they
won't tell us.
- Are you still my friend?
- Of course. Since I am here.
Then find out about Alicia.
Whether she's alive, whether she gave
birth, whether the baby is alive...
I need to know, Marco...
You understand, right?
I will try to...
Talk to you on Saturday...
- Did you find out anything?
- I will. Be patient.
I was, until the day she would
give birth. One month ago.
You must wait.
- What do you do during the day here?
- I work in the recovery room.
It's a new prison, few people.
It's quiet in here.
- It doesn't look like a prison from outside.
- The problem is elsewhere!
That I don't see Alicia.
The doctor  Dr Roncero
say I am a psychopath.
This is good for the trial, they say,
but I don't care about the trial.
I need to see Alicia,
to find out how everything went.
If this goes on, I don't
know what I am capable of doing!
I am a psychopath, they say?
Then I will act like one!
Don't say that, Benigno!
And find me another lawyer.
The one I have despises me.
I will rent my place so that
I can pay him.
I will rent it.
I am currently homeless.
Great. I am glad you will be
my tenant.
I was thinking about you a lot,
especially during the nights.
- Why during the nights?
- Because I study during the nights.
I read all your guides.
Like travelling with you
next to me...
...telling me things.
I liked Avan's the most.
I became one with those people...
...that have nothing
and invent everything.
And you describing
the Cuban girl...
...in front of her window
by the sea...
...waiting in vain...
...for something that will
never happen.
I was thinking that woman is me.
Good morning. I am Benigno's
friend.
You are Marco, the Argentinian?
Benigno called me.
Will you take his appartment?
It will be dirty. He wouldn't
let me in to clean it.
- And I didn't want any money...
- It's OK, I will take care of it.
Shall I give you the key?...
I will go look for it...
Did you see him?
- How is he?
- Well.
Poor guy, he wasn't even lucky
during his imprisonment.
No publicity!
No TV, no reporters.
No one came here.
They didn't condescend!
And they show such garbage!
I would give them an interview!
The media is shit in this country!
You are right.
The keys...
Anyway... Do you know why
Benigno is in prison?
He is very quiet. He didn't say
a word last time he came.
- Benigno is innocent.
- Yes, I know.
- Innocent about what?
- I don't know.
You do, but you don't want
to tell me.
If you need something,
you know where I am.
I was glad you stepped in
by yourself today, without crutches.
- How did the exercise go today?
- Very well.
- Were you tired?
- A lot.
It doesn't matter. We will
do some extra exercises.
We will do some stretches.
- But I already did 100.
- We'll do a few more.
I have an appointment with
Mr. Sainz.
The boy was born dead.
Alicia recovered.
Benigno hasn't found out.
In his condition,
he could do something crazy.
I can't lie to him.
He is my only friend.
I will tell him.
I have no problem.
Alicia is still in coma and
the baby dead, I will say.
But you don't tell him anything.
- Can he bail out?
- Very difficult, and expensive.
- You are wet.
- A little.
Be careful not to catch a cold.
Drink hot milk with honey.
Since I am here,
I like rainy days.
Dld you see the new lawyer?
He was here...
he told me everything...
- I will loose, right?
- Frankly, yes, you will.
At least nothing happened to
Alicia during birth.
It's the only thing that consoles
me and gives me hope.
Are you ok, Benigno?
I would like to hug you
so much, Marco.
But I have to ask for a meeting
face to face.
I tried.
They asked me whether you are
my lover.
I didn't dare say 'yes' since
that would annoy you.
It wouldn't annoy me at all.
You can say whatever you want.
I have hugged very few people
in my life.
Message!
I was very happy to see you
and say goodbye today.
They won't let me get
out of here...
...or they will put me
somewhere else
I don't want to live
without Alicia...
...without being able to hold
not one pin of hers.
Therefore I will escape.
I didn't tell you so that you
won't stop me.
I hug you firmly, Marco.
In Zegovia...
Yes, in prison...
I urgently need to see Benigno Martin.
It's a matter of life and death.
The warden is waiting for you
in his office.
Me? Where is his office?
The guard will accompany you.
Empty your pockets, please.
Wait, don't run.
In there at the end.
Good morning. I am
Marco Zuloaga.
Benigno Martin left this
letter for you.
Dear Marco...
It's still raining, and this
is a good sign.
When Alicia had the accident,
it was raining too.
I am writing to you a few
minutes before I escape.
I hope, with all these,
to fall in a coma as well...
...and to be near her.
You are my only friend.
I am leaving you the house
I prepared for me and her.
Wherever they take me, come to
see me and talk to me.
Tell me everything, without
hiding anything.
Goodbye, my friend.
I took these from him and these
I found at his cell.
You must sign here.
Benigno, it's me.
Alicia is alive...
You woke her up.
I got your message and ran
immediately to tell you...
...but it was too late.
I put a pin of Alicia
in your pocket.
And a photo of hers.
And a photo of your mother.
So that they can be with you
in eternity.
Like wild waves. The male on top,
the female below.
I will bring some water.
Are you ok?
I don't know...
I am much better now.
Come on, let's go inside.
You tremble.
Why?
- What did you tell her?
- Nothing.
I saw you talking.
She asked if I am ok, and I
thanked her.
You will see me around.
I live near the dancing school.
In Benigno's place?
- Why do you stay there?
- Benigno is dead.
One day, we should talk.
Yes, and it will be simpler
than you thought.
Nothing is simple.
I am a dancing teacher, and nothing is simple.
and nothing is simple.
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.MY-SUBS.com ]=-