For 15 years, everybody believed
Jean-Marc Faure.
His wife, his parents, his friends.
The one thing worse than being exposed
is not to be exposed.
This film is based on a true story.
Christine?
L'Adversaire (The Adversary)
- Where is this house?
- Outside the village, towards Gex.
Three bedrooms on the top floor.
A bargain for sure.
- But there's no garden.
- Yes, with a cherry tree.
- Could you have a look?
- Yes.
Hurry up kids! - Vincent,
Finish your corn flakes!
- I'm not ready yet.
- Hurry up then!
Let's get going.
Bye.
- Do I pick you up tonight?
- I have a busy schedule. I'll call.
Bye.. Be nice!
- Late again?
- You can never foresee the traffic.
- Didn't shave today?
- Peritonitis at 04:00!
Did you see the fresco the kids made?
The solar system with angels as mules.
I'll watch it tomorrow.
A pair of radiologists have moved in
and they want to meet you.
They didn't know about the local genius.
We'll invite them for dinner...
I'll call Christine. Bye.
- She told me you're looking for a house.
- Don't you start too.
In HIV-ridden countries we notice
an increase of tuberculosis.
It now seems as if HIV is a bigger
threat than tuberculosis
If this tendancy persists,
countries where HIV is...
The auditorium is booked for a meeting
and is open for the public again at 5 o'clock.
Mister, We are closing.
Have you washed your hands?
Let me see... Are you sure?
- Don't do that, She's a slut.
- Who taught you words like that?
You have to visit Baptiste
at the hospital in Gex.
- Is it an odontologial surgery?
- Yes, you have to assist.
I got his name. Dr Zurcan.
Are you listening?
I'll go.
- What is it?
- A japanese colleague gave it to me.
"I have nothing", studdered Lina.
"I didn't know about the three magic gifts"
"I just wanted some fireworks"
- Go to sleep.
- I can read in the dark.
I want to say initially... this...
to you, Christine, and the kids,
because I love you.
Because you mean everything to me.
The years have passed.
I thought I had it all figured out.
That there was an eventual way out...
I'll try to explain, to myself,
when all this started.
Our religion states that it's never
too late, that forgiveness is possible.
But it also states that you don't
have to right to take your own life.
Everything I've done,
good or bad...
- Have you seen the house yet?
- No, but it has to be renovated.
- Doctor?
- An apricot pie for ten.
- Sure.
- Thanks.
People will start to think you're a
cheapskate or that you have a mistress.
You can't expect your family to be happy
living on 50m2. How long will they cope?
You're not going to the expo, are you?
- Well, Where were we?
Good.
- When is the wedding?
- 12:th of may.
Where are we having lunch? La Rabette,
or at Girard's in Annecy?
You decide, but La Rabette is nice,
by the lake, and the food is better.
- Yes, he is right.
- Jean-Marc has spoken.
- His mind is set on a Mercedes.
- You want to brag...? For whom?
Nobody. It's a regular car,
not a Rolls Royce.
- A Mercedes...
- Can I get a key to it?
I have to talk to you.
I have to withdraw some money.
100 000 franc
for the first deposit.
I can tell you.
I went for the coupé model.
I want it for Xavier's wedding.
We have to go the bank in Genèva.
If you say so...
I don't handle the finances. From what
you told me, it's about 2 years interest.
I don't want to get another loan
with all the paperwork and extra charges.
What's going on?
I'll call you.
We'll arrange a meeting with the bank.
Did you fall?
You're always in a hurry. We have to
find a solution for the constant overdraw.
I guess a person like you got other accounts.
Do you have time to talk right now?
- No, I'm off to Dijon.
- Then you have to visit me soon.
See you soon then.
I'd like to withdraw 5 000 franc
from my parents' account.
- Do you have the authorization slip?
- Of course.
- Sorry, I'm new here.
- No problem.
- Are you off to Bourg-en-Bresse?
- No, to Lyon.
Jean-Marc...
Jean-Marc Faure.
- You don't remember me? Michel Philiooot.
- Of course, How are you?
I wasn't sure it was you.
Are you on holiday?
- I had some errands in Lyon.
- Come visit my clinic just next door.
- Aren't you getting that?
- Yes.
- I hear you teach at Besancon.
- Dijon.
Then you must know Lentier. He's the
professor in neurology in Dijon.
- We've met.
- Funny, We share practise.
I took over my dad's old clinic.
We handle minor depressions.
You're from the country, right?
You've been teased alot?
- What did your father do?
- He was a forest warden.
Your parents must be proud.
I'm sure I still have a photo
of you from the time we studied.
Tarar, Benel, Luc, Arbousier.
I don't see you on this.
Do you know Jean-Marc Faure?
He teaches at Dijon.
We went to medical school together,
except for the practise period.
- I don't think we have...
- You work together with Zylberstein.
I have been confined to the side building,
since the flooding last year.
We can't even get into
Rue Tisserand anymore.
- Not even the library or the archives.
- Oh well, it's one big mess.
- Doc, mrs Perrin is here.
- We'll meet soon again i presume.
This is me.
Where have you been? Your beeper
was off, so I nearly called WHO.
She was very worried.
WHO is not exactly Fort Knox!
- A drink?
- Yeah, I'd love a whiskey.
Wasn't it this secrecy that got you
interested initially?
Maybe so.
Maybe I was too straight forward?
- Are you staying for dinner?
- No thanks.
How did it all happen?
I don't recall.
At the end of the summmer you were
engaged, and I...
Jean-Marc, I guess that's dad.
He's called twice already.
He's obsessed with the
Mercedes plans.
Answer!
Did you notice the massacre at Juzy?
They even cut down young trees!
Have to be some idiots with fancy
diplomas without any knowledge in forestry.
- I intend to write to Gex!
- There's no need.
I bought it for you in Holland,
Forgot to bring it last time around.
Beautiful!
I couldn't find Rotterdam on the map.
It's there.
- I'm in a hurry.
- Of course.
- Are you getting the extra pension?
- Yes.
We don't see Christine very often.
We don't see the children either.
She doesn't like the forest.
We'll drop by in september.
When it's turning colder.
You never want to go anywhere.
How long is he going to sleep?
You needed some rest.
- What time is it?
- Almost four.
Don't you have to call work?
- Has somebody been in my room?
- No.
Yes, I forgot.
We changed the wall socket over there.
But we didn't go through your stuff.
The years have passed so quickly.
I thought I would have time....
That there would be a way out...
But everything is moving slowly
when you are alone with a dark secret.
You have reached Marianne Malartre.
Leave a message after the beep.
Marianne?
Are you there?
Answer. Please....
Aren't you there?
I don't know what happened.
I don't know why things have turned
out like this.
Don't be afraid of me.
I didn't mean to hurt you at all.
- Marianne, more wine?
- Thanks.
I'm at the pharmacy on thursdays.
- Yes, you can see the arteries more clearly.
- Angioscintigrafh replaces the arteriografh.
That would reduce the examination time.
- My kids are not going to a religious school.
- The subject is not mandatory.
Freedom first!
The principal is special, Maletras.
No authority!
A normal development...
- The number of cases could be checked.
- It's possible, I don't research myself.
- I'll have a cigarette.
- In the past, when we were barbarians,
I used to sting them here.
- What a nice top! Is that silk?
- Yes, I wanted it in black.
X-ray symposium, Chicago, in november!
When it's that cold you stay and listen.
- You won't find nice clothes here.
- And... you can wear it like this.
- It stays up.
- What are you doing?
Getting undressed like that.
You are provoking us young men.
Anyway, it suits her.
- Are you getting used to living here?
- Well, when the night comes, I'm scared.
Soft version! The version I get is:
"You have buried me alive in this pit"
- I wanted to go to Paris this monday.
- My wife leaves the house and seduces men...
There are some nice places to visit here.
We'll show you.
- I like Divonne.
- And the casino!
- I always stop at 2 000 Francs down.
- And I take her patients too!
Shut up! That's a dumb thing to say.
Well, that was a bit dumb....
- I'll put on some coffee.
- No, I'll do it.
I'll help you.
You never saw the pictures from the picnic.
When we go for a swim with the priest.
Your wife is pretty.
By that, I don't mean you're ugly.
Do you know why you can't live with
the women that turn you on?
You simply don't reflect....
You just follow a predicted straight line.
- Is there anymore white wine?
- Yes.
WORLD HEALTH ORGANISATION
Yes?
I'm here to see my son-in-law.
Dr. Faure.
- Come again?
- Faure, F... a... u.
- Are you sure that...
- Sorry, my meeting ended late...
- I started to get worried.
- Let's go somewhere for a drink.
An ethnic place!
- Christine's never been here?
- No.
Did you get my message this morning?
- We had an appointment. I was there.
- The guy that handles the account is in Zürich.
- I'll call him tomorrow.
- He said I could get the money anytime.
Yes, but we have to sign the papers.
Too bad doing it now, when it's up 18%.
- I thought the money was for the children.
- I don't steal! I'm upset, Marc.
Oh well, I won't raise my voice.
- What's that?
- A fishing magazine for you.
Tomorrow then?
- Tomorrow there's a masquerade at school.
- Then we'll do it tuesday.
I don't know what the weather is like in Oslo.
I'll pack two sweaters.
The children will be disappointed.
Why didn't you tell me about this before?
The guy handling the paperwork
has family problems...
- You haven't prepared?
- No, but I'll do it on the plane.
Do you know which hotel
you'll be staying at?
No.
They are picking me up at the airport.
Why are you bringing this much stuff?
I was supposed to meet your father this week.
Tell him... I'll phone him when I'm home.
Good day, Mrs. Faure.
Good day.
You are a better swimmer than me.
I don't like pools.
I like the ocean, and the salt water.
I have only been to the ocean twice.
- Do you never travel with your...
- Jean-Marc?
Not often.
Isn't he uncomfortable
leaving you alone by yourself?
No,
It's rather me who does the worrying.
- That he won't come back?
- No, but...if he gets lost.
Come now, children, have a break.
Luc!
The impregnable fortress.
I don't like the trunks.
We'll get him some tangas.
He hasn't left his room for two days.
I'm off soon.
Can I clean the room now?
You can stay if you want.
Good day.
Are you going to Norway?
Yes.
I visited the museum, and then I went
back to the hotel. Did Alice get her shot?
No, Oslo is beautiful. They have a
famous area here called "Karl Johan".
Really nice, but very noisy.
Do you hear me?
I can't hear you properly.
Waht are you doing? Come on in!
I don't have the money.
I wanted a grey metallic, but the
waiting list is at least 6 months.
So i took a blue-coloured one,
a dark-blue nuance.
We have an appointment at 4
with the salesman.
I don't have the money.
In about two years I can build a pool
for the kids, when the money has accumulated.
Come on...
Look at this? Almost done up there,
but I had to reinforce the whole shell.
There's time...
Come, let me show you.
They will have their workroom down there,
and I can work in peace up here.
Come and see, I'm putting two windows here
next month. I've ordered them.
Walk carefully. Not on the left side.
They never clean up.
You have to look after Christine & the kids.
Why do you say that?
We can't go get the car.
Don't start again!
Why not?
What's the matter?
Are you ill?
I don't have the money.
What do you mean?
Did you lose them betting on something?
Did you lose the money?
What are you up to?
Where are you? I can't see you.
Jean-Marc.
Right eight times,
left six times.
No, left ten times.
- Daddy, Alice's pushing me.
Stop it, Vincent!
- How many kilometers have we been driving?
- Seven, eight...
Isn't this house too expensive?
- We're passing a tennis court.
- Vincent's cheating.
- Where are we, Dad? In Saint-Martin?
- I won't tell.
Vincent!
Christine!
Anybody home?
- Jean-Marc!
- I'll go to the other side.
They cut down the cherry tree.
The remote works from the kitchen.
- Is it expensive?
- Dunno. It was there already.
- When are we going to see the donkey?
- I don't know, sweetheart.
- Do they never wear you out?
- They are just a little exhilarated.
- Can we go see the donkey now?
- It's in the meadows, going nowhere.
We'll go there in a bit.
- What a beautiful lamp. Is it crystal?
- Jean-Marc's boss gave it to us.
- I can't choose. Which one do you like?
- I like this one.
Don't you think mum's looks better?
When she's around people it's alright.
When she's alone, she just cries for hours.
I call her every night.
Why did Jean-Marc suddenly
decide on this house?
We had been thinking about it for a long time.
He thought that time was running out.
- Too bad we didn't keep the house in La Frette.
- It was you who wanted to sell it.
We really couldn't keep the house
where daddy died, could we?
But he spent alot of time fixing it.
1.300.000 with 18% interest.
Sorry to bring it up, but...
- What does that come to? 240.000 a year?
- Approximately.
You placed it, you should know.
- The amount dad put in is still there, right?
- Yes, It's untouched.
- We never see anything, not a single paper.
- Would you like to place it, be my guest.
You know very well I don't know
the first thing about that kinda business.
We aren't leaving already, are we?
- Let's have a final drink.
- We all have work tomorrow.
Me too.
What's the rush?
A bad play and now this......
Stop it.
Being turned down is one thing, but
being on a date with couples is
pure masochism....
- Get a hold of yourself!
- I can't stand you guys.
- Where is he going?
- Rémi!
- We can't leave him.
They have discussed the separation
alot, and now he is unhappy.
- Have you answered her letter?
- Did I tell you she wrote?
I think she's enjoying Paris.
- Why are you taking this road?
- More scenic for a change.
There's a light on at your place.
Your office is on the third floor, right?
There's a light on.
I guess they're cleaning.
The jewelry he gave you during the
relationship...
I got this ring too.
After the divorce I stayed in Paris.
He and his wife visited me.
We had tea at my place.
I mainly talked with her,
with Christine.
I was close to her,
but I hardly remembered him.
- But one day I got a big bouquet of flowers.
- When was this?
After ten days. Really nice flowers.
I was really surprised,
and he took me to dinner.
I'm here to with Mr. Faure.
This way please.
Good evening.
- Good evening.
- I don't remember doing this already.
Thanks for the lovely flowers.
I thought we could dine on the terrace,
but the weather is too bad. Are are ok?
- Yes. Christine's not here?
- No.
- Do you live here? The symposium is on...?
- Connective Tissue Surgery.
It's big business
and they need sponsors bad.
Ministers begging...
If you're into philosophy, it might be
interesting eventhough it may appear shocking.
It's the market.
It's the same all over the world.
But you meet interesting people.
Take Kouchner for example.
He's doing a remarkable job.
- Do you know him?
- Yes, We have become...
friends might not be the word,
but we meet alot.
He's controversial, but today
you have use media to be seen and heard.
- I have always liked him.
- If you want to meet him, I can arrange it.
I didn't know you were involved
in this line of work,
and that you knew those kind of persons.
This was fantastic.
In Ferney, you were always so shy,
so discrete.
- Another bottle of Champagne?
- We already emptied this one.
- Maybe half a bottle.
- We don't have that.
A bottle then.
- It's warm in here.
- Yes.
- You're sweating. A cigarette?
- No, thanks, I have my cigars.
Thanks.
Maybe we could go to an `
exhibit together?
I don't have much spare time. I work
'til 8, and I have the kids.
But if I understand this correctly,
you have alot of time.
- What do you have planned for the holiday?
- I don't know.
Rémi has the kids for 3 weeks.
I decide the last minute where to go.
I love you.
I didn't catch that.
I enjoy seeing you like this,
eating together, but...
- You're right.
- I'm friends with Christine.
- Is this the reputation I created for myself?
- Don't be silly.
- For you.
- What is it?
- An apology.
- No, no.
- Yes, Have a look.
- No, but...
No, no, no.
Sure, it's beautiful,
but I couldn't accept it.
Up 'til then there hadn't been
anything between us.
He often visited me in Paris,
and we dined in expensive restaurants.
But he was always discrete.
Sometimes he brought presents.
He is interested in alot of things,
and we talked about various subjects.
But he never tried to...
I'm totally wasted.
The drinks just kept coming.
This was good,
but Jamain was more high class.
Tomorrow, diet...
- Hi. Everything ok?
- They fell asleep early.
- Here you are. See you tuesday.
- Yes.
- Good night.
She thinks of course that we...
Well, never mind!
- Will you stay here after all?
- I hope so. It's my aunt's apartment.
Are you driving all night?
I can't see you doing it.
Promise me you'll stop if you get tired.
Call me next time you come to Paris.
Take care.
Can I sleep here?
If you want. There's another bedroom.
I don't know if there're blankets.
Oh that's right, in the cupboard.
Help yourself.
- What time is it?
- Six.
- Have you been sleeping?
- No.
I get the feeling I can tell
you anything.
I don't recall any conversations
with other men.
- So that's where you got to know him?
- Yes, in Lyon, in medical school.
And you became friends.
One could almost say that you became...
...the best of friends.
What was he like back then?
Did he act weird? Was he...?
Reserved. Intelligent.
Shy at times. You wanted to protect him.
I always wanted to protect him.
- You went to the same class the second year.
- Yes.
He never graduated.
Do you remember if anything strange
happened during that 2:nd year?
No.
Maybe some problems with Christine,
but nothing that lasted.
You took the same courses, but he never
passed any tests, and you didn't realize that?
No.
He signed up again and again
and you...
You didn't even took the time to check
if his name was on the exams list.
No, We studied together and he was good.
Better than me even.
So why not believe him? We weren't in the
same group. Everybody believed him.
- What kind of work did he do for WHO?
- Head professor in cardiology.
- How did he get that job?
- He applied for it...
...through an old colleague
who was the head for the laboratory.
You are a doctor yourself, but you
never visited him at WHO.
I suggested it a couple of times.
He said yes, but he later chickened out.
Never any questions.
you never noticed anything?
Maybe I was a bad listener.
I feel like I'm dying, and you
tell me all is well.
- I can give you a ride to the hospital.
- No, I guess you're right.
- I guess I'm fine.
- Keep it down, the kids are asleep.
Do you have anything to drink?
Any booze?
You seem so worried.
Maybe so, but there are surely
good reasons for me feeling this way.
- Do you want to talk about it?
- Yes, Of course I want to talk about it!
But... I warn you, hold on tight,
because you're gonna faint when you hear it.
It's almost two and I'm a total wreck.
I have been wanting to say this for a while.
It was during the 2:nd year. Just after...
...after exam, the results. You were in
classroom B. There was music, Sangria...
- Do you remember?
- Why are you mentioning this now?
I walked down the corridor and you went:
"Did you pass?"
Christine and I had just broke up.
She didn't want to see me.
- We...
- Is it a woman?
- No, It's not a woman.
- But you always travel to Paris.
Don't tell me it's... Marianne?
Is it her?
- Is it her?!
- Why not?
She is the kind you sleep with
and then forget about.
- You don't know what you're saying.
- Don't ruin everyhing for a slut like that.
- I know her, I know.
- Don't speak to me like a 10-year old!
I don't want your moral lectures!
What gives YOU the right?
What makes your lifestyle so perfect?
- You'll be unhappy.
- It's the only thing in my life that feels right.
What do you want me to say?
"You'll experience the great passion.."
It won't happen...
Break it up now while you can.
Don't tell me she loves you,
'cause I won't believe it.
Talk to Christine about it.
She's intelligent, she'll understand.
It will help you get over it.
What's going on in there?
What was all that about the party
in classroom B?
Nothing.
Amandine, How...
...at the end of the second year
of medical school.
I had passed some tests. That morning
I was supposed to take a physiology test.
Suddenly I felt something inside...
...that collapsed and fell.
I could hardly stand up.
I couldn't, so I never went to the test.
I'm not a doctor.
I don't work at WHO.
When I leave my house,
I go nowhere.
I drive around,
stopping, waiting.
And now when I no longer exist, I don't
know if my death can save us.
- They're looking for you. They want to go.
- Sure, honey, I'm on my way.
- Another one?
- Last one!
- Three whiskey with ice. - And you?
- A Malibu.
- Can you fix it?
- I think so.
Why does he have to fix your necklace?
I met Marianne when I picked up
the kids. We are talking again.
She is the same old Marianne,
She has a crush on a wealthy dentist.
I can tell when she's in love.
Her neck is always moist.
- You slep with her too, right?
- No, I never did I'm afraid.
A Malibu for me too...
She has another lover.
Also a doctor....
She sticks to men in the same line of work.
Although he's dull and bores her, she told me.
There, this should do the trick.
I didn't want to come at first,
but I know you'd appreciate it, but...
...we have to stop seeing eachother...
...like this I mean.
I can't go on. It's all over.
You are so moody.
- I'm not. Not with you.
- Yes, you are trying hard not to.
But there's something about you.
Something dark and depressing.
You're kind, you take me to
fine restaurants-
- but I can't be with anyone
that sad all time.
I'm not strong enough.
We can go for a boat ride if you want.
I don't know if the guys who rents
them is there today.
- What's the matter?
- I had an accident.
Where? Tell me about it.
A guy hit me, I ran off the road
and was thrown out of the car.
The car flipped over three times.
- But the car is right there!
- It was the WHO car.
They flew me with a helicopter
to the hospital in Lausanne.
Why didn't you call?
I lost my cell phone.
- Did they have a look at you? You're bleeding.
- It's nothing.
Did you pick up the car at WHO?
That looks like scratch marks.
Or maybe it's from the grabble.
Or maybe from when the windshield
was shattered?
I'll fix you up.
Hurry. Otherwise we'll be late.
- Is daddy still sick?
- No, he's resting.
Emmeline, will you look after them?
I'll be right there.
I'm off.
You haven't given me the check
for the school lunches.
Tomorrow.
Christine...
What are you looking for?
I don't know.
You have to leave tonight...
I just have a few minutes now.
But I appreciate you coming
on such short notice.
Give this to Lange, please.
- Coffee?
- Yes, please.
So, you don't have time to eat?
Too bad.
My big brother...
You look ok.
I had a rough period, but now
I'm much better.
Let's sit here.
- And the dentist?
- It's over.
- Are you angry?
- You know perfectly well I'm not.
- Do you still see Rémi?
- Not that often.
- We just sold the clinics in Ferney.
- Did you get a good price?
Yes, I got 900.000 franc.
I wanted to talk to you about that.
- Do you have a clue why?
- No.
Well..
No, please.
- Do you have a cigarette?
- Watch it, Cavalier comes at 2 p.m.
- What you talked about, in Genèva.
- No.
Why not? Do me that favour.
Please...
- My contact there has moved.
- But your family's money is still there?
I don't deal with that stuff no more.
I have quit.
Just for a short while.
I could use that kind of money.
As soon as I decide to buy.
- How will you pay?
- First payment cash.
Please verify that it's 100.000 franc.
Vincent, don't!
- New or used?
- New.
I didn't like the idea.
Where is the dog?
Is that you?
No, you did the right thing.
I was away.
It's a bit complicated withdrawing
money with a high interest like that.
That's the standard procedure.
I'll fix it tomorrow.
Ah, it's you. Thanks for calling.
No, I haven't slept.
No, don't say that. I didn't mean
to hurt you last night.
I don't recall, but if you say so,
I believe you.
Let's forget the whole thing.
Yes, I will.
I'm meeting a person.
Yes. Yes.
No, I am alone right now.
Home with her mother.
Playing in the garden.
Is it dark already?
I don't hear you that good.
Marianne...
Were there any signs?
When did he begin to act strange?
I don't know. The last three months
we didn't meet at all. We had a fight.
- Fight over what?
- Just a stupid thing.
Our children go to a private school.
Catholic.
The principal turned out to be a problem.
He ran the school very poorly.
And on top of that, he had an affair
with a first grade teacher.
They went at it in the principal's office.
Right or wrong, but we got rid of him.
We took a vote, and Jean-Marc
also voted for his removal.
The next day however, Christine
started a petition in favor of the principal.
And you?
Very well, thank you all.
See you on monday.
- Did they fire him?
- Yes.
Without any insight
in a man's potential problems.
The whole thing made me think
about Job's chapter in the bible.
"They judge, and a head will fall"
"But what gives them the right to judge"
- Did you express your thoughts?
- Yes, but I was alone.
I'm not in on this. How rude!
Luc is a prick!
- I should fight this. Was Emmeline there?
- No.
It's Christine. We have to talk. I'm furious
over a matter that concerns us all.
In school today, everybody voted for
Maletras dismissal. Everybody except Jean-Marc.
We can't agree to that.
Let's start a petition.
- Are you still on bad terms with Luc?
- Sad, but I don't want to give in.
- I never anticipated this uproar.
- How many have signed the petition?
- 50 or more...
- Not bad.
- It's like civil war.
- Bye for now.
- Mrs. Faure...
- Yes.
We have met, but I've never really
spoken with you. I'm Mrs. Xinning.
My husband works at WHO.
So does your husband, I have heard.
My husband has tried to get ahold of
Jean-Marc, but he can't find him in the registry.
- That's why I'm here.
- The registry?
I don't know.
We're in the phone book.
Please call us.
- Do you want anything while you're here?
- No.
Then please excuse me.
- Do you like it?
- Yes.
- When? We have to set a date.
- Beginning of January.
The beginning of January?!
I can't go to Paris on week days.
- We ate here the first time.
- Friends shouldn't argue about money.
I lost my apetite.
When, then?
Kouchner has a dinner party on a
saturday. Wanna come?
- Where?
- Countryside, near Paris. Fontainebleau.
Who will be there?
It's not a big thing, pretty intimate.
His wife for sure, and maybe 2,3 friends.
- Which date is better? 16:th or the 9:th?
- 9:th.
"CHRISTMAS"
Christine!
- Get in the car. I'll be there shortly.
- Are you getting rid of some papers?
Come on, sweet mother Mary.
Someone has to inform you that you have
two ugly wrinkles popping up when you smile.
Alice!
My house will be packed at lunch.
- Is the master of depression alright?
- Yes, He's picking up his parents.
He's a funny guy. He could have told
me directly that he didn't agree.
- He told you, right?
- No, that's the weird part.
- He didn't want to remove Maletras.
- He did, He voted as everybody else.
That's why I didn't get it.
Never mind, it's all forgotten by now.
What's the matter?
Then he lied to me.
He lied to me.
What's wrong?
- Are there any oysters left?
- We have to throw them out like last year.
- Need any help?
- That won't be necessary.
- Do your cousins want onions?
- Dunno, they're watching pictures right now.
Let me do it. I'd be glad to do it.
Don't we have any lemon?
- There was a small accident.
- Stop it!
- They've opened them all.
- I strictly told them: "After lunch".
Vincent, stop that,
or go to your room right now.
- Won't Luc be here this year?
- No.
- But he's alright?
- Yes.
I met him this morning.
- Alot of food! Watch out..
- I'll move that.
Stand closer together!
Jean-Marc isn't here.
Jean-Marc! Jean-Marc! Jean-Marc!
Stand next to Christine.
Give her a kiss.
- And now....?
- Merry christmas!
C-H-E-E-E-S-E!!
- Do you know where Jean-Marc is?
- We haven't seen him for a while.
Alice, go get Dad.
Everything I've done, good or bad,
I did for you.
Because I love you.
Because you mean everything to me.
But now, when I'm not around anymore,
I don't know if my death will save us.
They're looking for you, Dad.
They're leaving.
Yes, honey, I'll be there.
But, Mom?
40.000 less? That's impossible.
- You have had all the time in the world!
- I just forgot the "t's".
- Alice, are you done?
- Almost!
It has to be a computer error.
Don't you worry. I'll go there myself.
Yes!
Yes, now.
Let's see, two tear gas cartridges.
- Ammunition. One or two boxes?
- One.
- Do you know how to handle this?
- Yes, I think so.
Can I get it all in different
gift wraps?
Yeah, you can.
If that's what you want..
- I don't have any fancy wrapper.
- A silencer too, to a .22 rifle.
He's depressed.
Doctor Bertier mentioned surgery.
Glaucoma.
- Will you have lunch?
- No time.
- Eat something at least.
- A quick bite maybe.
We received a letter from the bank.
The account is still on minus.
It's the same mistake. I've told
you I'm gonna handle it.
I'm getting some books.
Jean-Marc?!
I'm busy, but do come in.
Hélène had a daughter in Génève this morning.
I'm looking after the kids.
- Isn't Luc here?
- Stop it, kids!
That's the third time today.
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Shall I tell Luc that you were here?
Yes.
And tell him that...
I'll go.
Do you think Dad's at the Pizzeria
already?
No.
What's wrong with mummy?
"The prince was still in the well"-
- "but the walls were so slippery
that he couldn't get out."
"He was devastated, but suddenly he
saw the fox staring down from the edge."
Sleep tight.
Your mother is too lonely.
- Why aren't you in the  WHO catalogue?
- She could come here for a couple of days.
What catalogue?
I don't know. Apparently there's
a catalogue for the WHO employees.
Stop drinking like that.
You never take us anywhere.
We have never seen the WHO christmas tree.
You let us live like savages.
Something is wrong here.
Why aren't you in the catalogue?
And all the money you spend.
Buying a car that's worth a fortune!
- It's all for you.
- I don't give a damn about all that.
- The account is empty!
- Who told you that?
- If you've been fired, then tell me.
- Why should I've been fired?
Misconduct.
Have you been fired or not?
I don't know.
- It's true that the winter's been rough.
- You're not answering.
I can't go on like this.
I'm starting to get afraid.
Why didn't you tell me
you voted for Maletras' dismissal?
I was ashamed when Luc told me.
- You're putting me in a tough position.
- Well. maybe I wasn't clear on that.
Sometimes I don't remember.
Do you want me to leave?
- Why aren't you in the catalogue?
- Maybe that would be the best thing?
What's going on, Jean-Marc?
You don't miss anything. I have always
seen to it that you've had it all.
You're not answering.
That's irrelevant in comparison
to my love for you.
Why aren't you in the catalogue?
It's too late.
Tomorrow..
I don't want us to separate.
I love you.
I love you too.
Yes.
Hi, Emmeline.
She's still sleeping.
Do you want me to wake her up?
Yes, I'll tell her.
- Be quiet, mummy's still sleeping.
- Could you put on a cassette?
This one.
She approached the large table
but it was to high...
Red.
Green.
Yellow.
Your hand is cold.
Let me get a ruler.
No, stay here.
You're warm.
You have a fever. Let's check.
Lie on your stomach.
Here, you know what to do.
- For how long?
- Count to 200.
Or sing the song....
"Pirouette, Cacahuète."
There's nothing wrong with me.
I want to watch the ending.
Come up here,
I want to check your temperature.
Hi, Jean-Marc!
So, you're bringing it back?
The ventilation in your room isn't
working. I think it's the filter.
There's alot of strange smells
in that room.
- Some more?
- No thank you.
I took some sage from the garden.
- What's wrong with the ventilation?
- The repair man can't come 'cause of the snow.
Why do I have to go up here again?
I checked it this morning already.
We have to get the repair guy here.
I unplugged it, to keep it from
shorting out.
Let's check the grating.
Stubborn, eh?
I'm telling you, it doesn't work.
Want me down on my knees do you?
You have to change it.
They'll be here on monday.
I'm in here.
What's the matter, boy?
What are you doing in here?
- Did you exchange the photos?
- What photos? We haven't changed anything.
Jean-Marc, what are you doing?
- Did you get it for christmas?
- Yes.
Stop it, Manuel.
- Turn it down!
- No.
What do you think?
Too dressed up?
I'm changing my belt.
Do we have time?
- I'll help you with that.
- Thanks.
Could you come in here?
- How many cars do you think?
- Four, five.
The hair like this, alright?
Fine.
- Any news about my money?
- I promise you'll get them on monday.
I will go there when they open.
If I take the executive role for INSERM
it means I'll go to Paris.
- I don't understand this map.
- I'll get the fifth floor in the building.
I discussed it with Christine
and we agreed.
We are going to separate.
Probably the best thing to do.
I'm gonna miss the children.
That's the hardest part.
Not going to see them as often...
You'll never leave Christine.
Make a right here.
We already drove passed this.
I recognize that roundabout.
- We are just driving in circles, aren't we?
- No.
We haven't even seen a sign
saying "Neuville" yet.
Stop here! There's a pay phone over there.
Otherwise this will take all night.
- Go over there and make the call.
- I don't have the number.
You don't have the number?!
You're joking!
What are we supposed to do know?
Where are we? We are lost.
I think I have the number
in a bag back in the trunk.
This can't be happening.
- Come here, I have a surprise for you.
- Not now. Call them!
- I have a present for you.
- Cut it out! This is ridiculous!
Come out just a minute, please.
- Close your eyes.
- I must be dreaming.
No!
Think about my kids.
My kids.
What's happening to us?
What got into you?
You attacked me.
You hurt me.
You started it.
Why would I hurt you?
Me?
I think so.
Don't you remember what you did?
Sorry. I have been feeling bad lately.
Sometimes I get lost in the moment.
- Look at me! We can't go there now.
- Yes we can.
- Give me a ride home.
- Yes, It's starting to get late.
Drop me off at a gas station.
I'll grab a taxi from there.
Maybe I should call them
to tell them I'm sorry.
Good evening, this is Jean-Marc Faure,
We can't come, we're lost.
Hi, you have reached
Alice, Vincent, Mum and Dad.
We are not home.
Leave a message after the beep.
Christine...
He's alive.