(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(CAWING)
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
(CHIRPING)
(TWITTERING)
(SQUAWKING INTENSIFIES)
(CABLE CAR BELL DINGING)
(SQUAWKING CONTINUES)
(BOY WOLF WHISTLES)
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
Hello, Mrs. MacGruder.
Oh, hello,
Miss Daniels.
Have you ever seen
so many gulls?
What do you suppose it is?
There must be a storm
at sea. That can drive
them inland, you know.
I was hoping you'd be
a little late. You see,
he hasn't arrived yet.
Oh, but you said 3:00.
Oh, I know.
I know. I've been
calling all morning.
Oh, Miss Daniels,
you have no idea.
They are so
difficult to get.
Really, they are.
We have to get them
from India,
when they're just
baby chicks, and then...
This one won't be
a chick, will he?
Certainly not.
Oh, no, certainly not.
This will be
a full-grown mynah bird.
Full-grown.
And he'll talk?
Well, yes,
of course he'll...
Well, no, you'll have
to teach him to talk.
I guess maybe
I'd better phone.
They said 3:00.
Maybe it's the traffic.
I'll call.
Would you mind waiting?
Well, maybe you'd
better deliver him.
Let me give you my address.
Oh, well, all right,
but I'm sure
they're on the way.
Would you mind
if I called?
No. All right.
MITCH: I wonder
if you could help me.
What?
I said, I wonder
if you could help me.
Yes. What is it
you're looking for, sir?
Lovebirds.
Lovebirds, sir?
Yes. I understand there
are different varieties.
Is that true?
Well, yes, there are.
Well, these are for my sister
for her birthday, you see,
and as she's
only gonna be 11,
I wouldn't want
a pair of birds
that were
too demonstrative.
I understand completely.
At the same time,
I wouldn't want them
to be too aloof, either.
No, of course not.
Do you happen to have
a pair of birds
that are just friendly?
Oh, I think so.
Now, then, let me see.
Aren't those lovebirds?
No. Those are red birds.
I thought they were
strawberry finches.
Yes. We call them that, too.
Here we are. Lovebirds.
Those are canaries.
Doesn't this
make you feel awful?
Doesn't what
make me feel...
Having all these poor,
little innocent creatures
caged up like this?
Well, we can't just let them
fly around the shop,
you know.
(CHUCKLING)
No, I suppose not.
Is there
an ornithological reason
for keeping them
in separate cages?
Well, certainly.
It's to protect
the species.
Yes, that's important,
especially during
the molting season.
That's a particularly
dangerous time.
Are they molting now?
Oh, some of them are.
How can you tell?
Well, they get a sort
of hangdog expression.
Yes, I see.
Well, what about
the lovebirds?
Are you sure
you wouldn't like to see
a canary instead?
We have some very
nice canaries this week.
All right.
May I see it, please?
Oh! Oh!
Oh, what is it? Oh!
MITCH: There we are.
Oh, there.
Wonderful.
Back in your gilded cage,
Melanie Daniels.
What did you say?
I was merely drawing
a parallel, Miss Daniels.
How did you
know my name?
A little
birdie told me.
Good day,
Miss Daniels. Madam.
Hey, wait a minute.
I don't know you.
Ah, but I know you.
How?
We met in court.
We never met in court
or anyplace else.
That's true.
I'll rephrase it.
I saw you in court.
When?
Don't you remember
one of your practical jokes
that resulted in the smashing
of a plate-glass window?
I didn't break
that window.
Yes, but your
little prank did.
The judge should've
put you behind bars.
What are you,
a policeman?
I merely believe in
the law, Miss Daniels.
And I'm not too keen
on practical jokers.
What do you call
your lovebird story if not...
Oh, I really wanted
the lovebirds.
Well, you knew
I didn't work here.
You deliberately...
Right. I recognized
you when I came in.
I just thought you
might like to know
what it's like to be on
the other end of a gag.
What do you
think of that?
I think you're a louse.
I am. Good day,
Miss Daniels. Madam.
And I'm glad
you didn't get
your lovebirds.
Oh, I'll find something else.
See you in court.
Who was that man?
I have no idea.
(INAUDIBLE)
They said the mynah bird
would be here
later this afternoon,
if you care to come back.
No, you'd better send him.
May I use this phone?
Why, certainly.
Daily News?
It's Melanie Daniels.
Could you get me
the City Desk, please?
Just a minute,
Mrs. MacGruder.
Hello, Charlie. Melanie.
I want you to do
a favor for me.
No, this is a small one.
Pressure you?
Why, Charlie, darling,
would I try to pressure you?
Would you call the Department
of Motor Vehicles for me?
Find out who owns
this license plate,
W-J-H-0-0-3.
Yes, a California plate.
No. I'll stop off
in a little while.
Is Daddy in his office?
No, I don't want to
break in on a meeting.
Tell him I'll see him later.
Thank you, Charlie.
Do you have any lovebirds?
Well, no, not in the shop,
but I can order them for you.
How soon?
Well, when would
you want them?
Immediately.
Well, I could
probably have them here
by tomorrow morning.
Would that
be all right?
That would be just fine.
(CHIRPING)
Miss, is that
for Mitch Brenner?
Yes.
He's not home.
That's all right.
He won't be back
until Monday, I mean,
if those birds are for him.
Monday?
Yes.
I don't think you should
leave them in the hall,
do you?
Well... Where did he go?
Bodega Bay.
He goes there
every weekend.
Bodega Bay.
Where's that?
Up the coast,
about 60 miles
north of here.
Sixty...
It's an hour and
a half by freeway,
or two hours if you
take the Coast Highway.
Oh.
I'd look after them myself,
but I'm going away, too.
I'm awfully sorry.
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(BELL DINGS)
Good morning.
I wonder if you
could help me.
I'll try my best.
I'm looking for a man
named Mitchell Brenner.
Do you know him?
Yeah.
Where does he live?
Right here, Bodega Bay.
Yes, I know, but where?
Right across
the bay there.
Where?
Now, see where
I'm pointing?
Yes.
See them two big
trees across there?
On the other side
of the bay? Yes.
And the white house?
Yes.
That's where
the Brenners live.
The Brenners?
Mr. And Mrs. Brenner?
No. Just Lydia
and the two kids.
The two kids?
Yeah,
Mitch and the little girl.
Oh, I see.
How do I get down there?
You follow
the road around the bay,
and that'll take you
right to their front door.
The front door.
Is there a back road
I can take?
No. That's the only road.
You see,
I want to surprise them.
Oh.
I don't want them
to see me arrive.
Oh.
It's a surprise, you see.
Well, you could
get yourself a boat
and cut right across
the bay to their dock.
Where would I get a boat?
Down by the Tides Restaurant.
Did you ever handle
an outboard boat?
Of course.
Want me to
order one for you?
Well, thank you.
What name?
Daniels.
Okay.
(SHOP BELL DINGS)
(DIALING)
I wonder if you
could tell me...
Yeah. Just hold it
a minute, please.
The little girl's name?
The little Brenner girl?
Yes.
Alice, I think.
Harry, what's the little
Brenner girl's name?
HARRY: Lois.
SHOPKEEPER: Alice, isn't it?
No, it's Lois.
It's Alice.
Are you sure?
Well, I'm not positive,
if that's what you mean.
I need her
exact name, you see.
Oh, just hold on one
more minute, please.
In that case,
I'll tell you
what you do.
You go straight through town
till you see a little hotel
on your left.
Then you turn
right there.
Now, you got that?
Yes.
Near the top of the hill,
you'll see the school,
and just beyond,
a little house
with a red mailbox.
That's where Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher, lives.
You ask her about
the little Brenner girl.
Well, thank you.
Save yourself
a lot of trouble.
Name's Alice for sure.
Can I have the boat
in about 20 minutes?
How much for
the phone calls?
Oh, it's nothing.
Thank you.
(CHILDREN TALKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(DOORBELL RINGS)
WOMAN: Who is it?
Me.
Who's "me"?
Miss Hayworth?
Yes.
I'm Melanie Daniels.
I'm sorry to
bother you, but...
Yes?
The man at
the post office sent me.
He said you could
tell me the name of
the little Brenner girl.
Cathy?
The one who lives
in the white house
across the bay?
That's the one.
Cathy Brenner.
He seemed sure
it was either
Alice or Lois.
Which is why the mail
never gets delivered
to the right place
in this town.
I'm sorry. Smoke?
Thank you.
Did you want to see
Cathy about something?
Well, not exactly.
Oh.
Are you a friend
of Mitch's?
No, not really.
You know, I've been
wanting a cigarette
for the last 20 minutes.
I just couldn't
convince myself
to stop.
This tilling of the soil
can become compulsive,
you know.
It's a very
pretty garden.
Oh, thank you.
Well, it's something to
do in your spare time.
There's a lot
of spare time
in Bodega Bay.
Are you planning
on staying long?
No, just a few hours.
Then you're leaving
after you see Cathy?
Well, something
like that.
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to
sound so mysterious.
Actually, it's
none of my business.
Well, I better
be on my way.
Thank you very much.
Not at all.
Did you drive up
from San Francisco
by the coast road?
Yes.
Nice drive.
It's very beautiful.
Is that where
you met Mitch?
Yes.
I guess that's where
everyone meets Mitch.
Now you sound
a bit mysterious,
Miss Hayworth.
(CHUCKLES)
Do I?
I don't mean to.
Actually, I'm an open book,
I'm afraid.
(CHIRPING)
Or, rather, a closed one.
Oh, pretty.
What are they?
Lovebirds.
I see.
Good luck, Miss Daniels.
Thank you.
Can I get out this way?
Go right around.
It'll take you
back to the main road.
Thank you.
(STARTS ENGINE)
(SEAGULLS CAWING)
Do you have a boat
for Miss Daniels?
Yes, ma'am.
It's the one
right below.
(CHIRPING)
(MOTOR STARTS)
(MOTOR STOPS)
(MOTOR CRANKING)
(MOTOR STARTS)
Are you all right?
Yes, I think so.
What do you suppose
made it do that?
That's the damnedest
thing I ever saw.
I don't know.
It seemed to swoop down
at you deliberately.
Oh, you're bleeding, too.
Let's take care
of that. Okay?
That's a girl.
Come on.
What happened, Mitch?
Gull hit her.
A gull?
Let's try up
at the restaurant,
all right?
Might need
a tetanus shot.
I had a booster before
I went abroad last May.
(PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY)
What happened?
Hello, Deke.
Young lady cut herself.
Shall I call a doctor?
No, I don't think
it's that serious.
Let's see.
Helen, get some cotton
and antiseptic.
You cut yourself
outside, miss?
Don't worry, Deke.
She did it in a boat.
Well, I had a man
trip and fall
in the parking lot once.
Sued me before
I could bat an eyelash.
I don't think Miss Daniels
is gonna sue anybody.
Here.
Well, you're
the lawyer.
Thank you.
What's that?
Just some peroxide.
I'll clean
out the cut.
So you're a lawyer.
That's right.
Of course,
I usually defend people,
Miss Daniels,
but if I were
prosecuting...
Do you practice here?
Uh-uh. San Francisco.
What are you doing up here?
What kind of law?
Criminal.
Is that why you want
to see everyone behind bars?
Oh, not everyone,
Miss Daniels.
Only violators
and practical jokers.
That's right.
Ow!
Oh, sorry.
What are you
doing up here?
Didn't you see
the lovebirds?
Oh, you mean,
you came all this way
to bring me those birds?
To bring your
sister those birds.
You said it was
her birthday.
Besides,
I was coming up anyway.
What for?
To see a friend
of mine. Careful.
Oh, sorry.
Who's your friend?
Annie Hayworth,
the schoolteacher.
Annie Hayworth.
Well, small world.
Yes.
How do you know Annie?
We went to school
together, college.
Did you? Lmagine that.
How long are you
staying up here?
The weekend.
Well, I think
the bleeding's almost stopped.
Why don't you hold that on?
So you came up
to see Annie, huh?
Yes.
I think you
came up to see me.
Now, why would I want
to see you of all people?
I don't know,
but you must've gone
to a lot of trouble
to find out who I was
and where I lived.
It was no trouble at all.
I simply called my
father's newspaper.
Besides,
I was coming up anyway.
I've already told you that.
You really like me, huh?
I loathe you.
You have no manners.
You're arrogant,
and conceited, and...
I wrote you a letter
about it, in fact,
but I tore it up.
What did it say?
None of your business.
I can't say I like your
seagulls much, either.
I come all
the way up here to...
But you were coming
up anyway, remember?
Mitch?
I thought I saw your car.
What are you doing in town?
I had to
acknowledge a delivery.
Of what?
Mother, I'd like you
to meet Melanie Daniels.
Miss Daniels, my mother.
How do you do?
How do you do, Miss Daniels?
Acknowledge a what?
A delivery.
Miss Daniels brought us
some birds from San Francisco.
For Cathy
for her birthday.
Where is she?
Across at Brinkmeyer's.
As a matter of fact,
Miss Daniels is staying
up here for the weekend,
so I've already invited
her for dinner tonight.
Well,
you did go to the trouble
of bringing those birds.
MELANIE: Oh,
I couldn't possibly.
You did say birds?
Yes, lovebirds.
Oh, I see.
MITCH: So we couldn't
let you get away
without thanking you
in some small way.
And you haven't met
Cathy, and you are
staying the weekend.
Well, yes, but...
Well, you are,
aren't you?
Certainly, but...
MITCH: Then
it's all settled.
What time is
dinner, Mother?
7:00, the same as usual.
I'll pick you up.
Where are you staying?
With Annie, of course.
Oh, of course.
How stupid of me. 6:45?
Annie may have
made other plans.
I'll have to see.
Besides,
I can find my own way.
You're sure now?
You won't hire
a boat or anything?
I'm sure.
MITCH: 7:00, then.
Maybe.
We'll be waiting for you.
How's your head?
Much better, thank you.
A gull hit me,
Mrs. Brenner, that's all.
(RINGING)
Oh, hi. Did you
find her all right?
Yes, I did.
I was wondering...
That sign there.
Do you suppose
I could have the room
for just a single night?
I was planning
on renting it
for a longer time...
I would appreciate it.
I've tried
everywhere in town.
They're all full.
Well, all right.
Got your bags
in the car?
(CHUCKLES)
Well, it's utilitarian,
I'll say that.
I just picked up some
things for the night
at the general store.
You see, I hadn't planned
on staying very long.
Yes, I know.
Did something
unexpected come up?
Yes. May I use your phone?
I'd like to call home.
I just put some
coffee on the stove.
(SEAGULLS CAWING)
Don't they ever
stop migrating?
(CAWING)
(RINGS)
Hi!
Miss Daniels?
Yes.
Oh, they're beautiful!
They're just what I wanted.
Is there a man and a woman?
I can't tell
which is which.
MELANIE: Well,
I suppose so.
MITCH: Hello there.
Annie had no plans, huh?
MELANIE: No.
Fine. We're very glad
you could come.
You hungry?
Reasonably.
Dinner's just
about ready.
We've been out back
looking at the chickens.
Something seems to
be wrong with them.
There's nothing
wrong with those
chickens, Mitch.
I'm going to call
Fred Brinkmeyer
right now.
What good's
that gonna do?
The chickens won't eat.
He sold the feed
to me, didn't he?
Caveat emptor, Mother.
"Let the buyer beware."
Whose side are you on?
Merely quoting
the law, dear.
Never mind the law.
This won't take long,
Miss... Hello, Fred?
Lydia Brenner.
I didn't interrupt
your dinner, did I?
How about a drink?
Thank you,
I'd love one.
Fred, that feed
you sold me
is no good.
The chicken feed.
Well, it's just no good.
The chickens won't eat it.
They're always hungry.
I opened a sack for
them when I got home,
and they just
wouldn't touch it.
You know chickens
as well as I do,
and when they won't eat,
there's something wrong
with what they're being fed.
That's all.
No, they're not
fussy chickens.
Who? What's he
got to do with it?
Is that your father?
Mmm-hmm.
Please sit down.
Fred, I don't care
how many sacks
of feed you sold him.
My chicken...
Oh, I see.
Dan Fawcett.
This afternoon?
Well, that just proves
what I'm saying!
The feed you sold us...
Oh.
Well, maybe I'd better
go over and see him.
You don't think
there's something
going around, do you?
No, never!
No, Fred, they don't
seem sick at all.
They just won't eat.
Uh-huh.
Well, I'll try to
go over and see him.
Maybe he...
Uh-huh.
All right. Thanks.
He had a call
from Dan Fawcett
a while ago.
His chickens
won't eat either.
It's what you said, Mom.
Mr. Brinkmeyer's feed
is no good.
No, Cathy.
He sold Mr. Fawcett
a different brand.
You don't think
they're getting sick,
do you, Mitch?
I still don't understand
how you knew
I wanted lovebirds.
Your brother told me.
Then you knew Mitch
in San Francisco?
Is that right?
No, not exactly.
Mitch knows
a lot of people
in San Francisco.
Of course,
they're mostly hoods.
Cathy!
Well, Mom,
he's the first
to admit it.
He spends half his day
in the detention cells
at the Hall of Justice.
In a democracy, Cathy,
everyone is entitled
to a fair trial.
Your brother's practice...
Oh, Mom, please!
I know all that
democracy jazz.
They're still hoods.
He has a client now
who shot his wife
in the head six times.
Six times!
Can you imagine it?
I mean, even twice
would be overdoing it,
don't you think?
Why did he shoot her?
He was watching
a ball game
on television.
What?
His wife changed
the channel.
Are you coming to
my party tomorrow?
I don't think so.
I have to get back
to San Francisco.
Don't you like us?
Oh, darling,
of course I do.
Don't you like
Bodega Bay?
I don't know yet.
Mitch likes it very much.
He comes up every weekend,
you know,
even though he has
his own apartment
in the city.
He says San Francisco's
like an anthill at
the foot of a bridge.
I suppose it does get
a little hectic at times.
Well, if you do decide
to come, don't say
I told you about it.
It's supposed to
be a surprise party.
You see, they've got this
whole complicated thing
figured out,
where I'm going
over to Michele's
for the afternoon,
and Michele's mother
will say that
she has a headache.
Would I mind very much
if she took me home?
Then when I get home here,
all the kids will jump out!
Oh, won't you come?
Won't you please come?
I don't think so.
She's a charming girl,
isn't she, Mitch?
MITCH: Hmm? Yes.
Certainly pretty.
Mmm-hmm.
How long have
you known her?
Now, I told you, dear,
we met yesterday.
In a bird shop.
She was selling birds?
No, no. I just led her into
believing that I believed
she was, and then...
Well, it's all
very complicated.
But she did buy
the lovebirds,
and then drove all
the way out here.
Mother.
Yes?
Where did you
go to law school?
Forgive me.
I suppose I'm just
naturally curious
about a girl like that.
She's very rich, isn't she?
Yeah, I suppose so.
Her father's part owner
of one of the big newspapers
in San Francisco.
You'd think he could manage
to keep her name out of print.
She's always mentioned
in the columns, Mitch.
Yes, I know.
She is the one who jumped
into a fountain in Rome
last summer, isn't she?
Yes.
I supposed
I'm old-fashioned.
I know it was supposed
to be very warm there,
but...
Well, actually,
the newspapers said
she was naked.
Yes, I know, dear.
Of course,
it's none of my business,
but when you bring
a girl like that...
Darling?
Yes?
I think I can handle
Melanie Daniels by myself.
Well, as long as you know
what you want, Mitch.
I know exactly
what I want.
Be able to find your
way back all right?
Oh, yes.
Will I be
seeing you again?
San Francisco's
a long way from here.
I'm in San Francisco
five days a week
with a lot of
time on my hands.
I'd like to see you.
Maybe we could go
swimming or something.
Mother tells me
you like to swim.
How does Mother know
what I like to do?
I guess we read
the same gossip column.
Oh, that. Rome.
Yeah, I really like to swim.
I think we might
get along very well.
In case you're interested,
I was pushed
into that fountain.
Without any clothes on?
With all my clothes on.
The newspaper
that ran that story
happens to be a rival
of my father's paper.
You were just a poor,
innocent victim
of circumstances?
I'm neither poor
nor innocent,
but the truth of
that particular...
The truth is, you're running
around with a pretty
wild crowd, isn't it?
Yes, that's the truth,
but I was pushed
into that fountain,
and that's the truth, too.
Uh-huh.
Do you really
know Annie Hayworth?
No. At least I didn't
until I came up here.
So you didn't go
to school together?
No.
And you didn't come
up here to see her?
No!
You were lying!
Yes, I was lying.
What about
the letter you wrote me?
Is that a lie, too?
No, I wrote the letter.
Well, what did it say?
It said, "Dear Mr. Brenner.
"I think you need
these lovebirds after all.
"They may help
your personality."
That's what it said.
But you tore it up?
Yes.
Why?
Because it seemed
stupid and foolish.
Like jumping into
a fountain in Rome.
I told you what happened!
You don't expect me to
believe that, do you?
Oh, I don't give a damn
what you believe!
I'd still like to see you.
Why?
I think it might be fun.
That might've been
good enough in Rome,
but it's not good enough now.
It is for me.
Well, not for me.
What do you want?
I thought you knew.
I want to go through life
jumping into fountains naked.
Good night.
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(CHIRPING)
Miss Daniels,
is that you?
Yes.
Hi.
Is something wrong?
Is that cut beginning
to bother you?
No, it's not the cut
that's bothering me.
Would you like
some brandy?
If you have some,
I'd love it.
I'll get it.
Why don't you sit down,
Miss Daniels?
Oh, would you like a sweater
or something, a quilt?
No. No, thank you.
Won't you
call me Melanie?
All right.
Thank you.
Gets a bit chilly here
at night sometimes,
especially if you're
over near the bay.
Well, how did
your evening go?
Did you meet Lydia?
Or would you rather
I changed the subject?
I think so.
Well, how do you
like our little hamlet?
I despise it.
(CHUCKLES)
Well, I suppose
it doesn't offer much
to the casual visitor,
unless you're thrilled
by a collection of shacks
on a hillside.
It takes a bit of
getting used to.
Where are you from
originally, Annie?
San Francisco.
How did you happen
to come up here?
A friend invited me
up for a weekend
a long time ago.
Look, I see no reason
for being coy about this.
It was Mitch Brenner.
I guess you knew that anyway.
I suspected as much.
Well, you needn't worry.
It's been over
and done with
a long time ago.
Annie, there's nothing
between Mr. Brenner and me.
Isn't there?
Well, maybe
there isn't.
Maybe there's never
been anything between
Mitch and any girl.
What do you mean?
I think I'll
have some of that.
I was seeing a lot of him
in San Francisco.
Then one weekend,
he invited me
up to meet Lydia.
When was this?
Oh, four years ago,
shortly after
his father died.
Of course, things
may be different now.
Different?
With Lydia.
Did she seem
a trifle distant?
A trifle.
Well, then perhaps things
aren't quite so different.
You know, her attitude
nearly drove me crazy.
When I got back
to San Francisco,
I spent days trying to
figure out exactly what
I'd done to displease her.
Well, what had you done?
Nothing.
I simply existed.
So what's the answer?
A jealous woman, right?
A clinging,
possessive mother?
Wrong.
With all due
respect to Oedipus,
I don't think
that was the case.
Then what was it?
Lydia liked me.
That's the strange part.
Now that I'm no
longer a threat,
we're very good friends.
Then why did
she object to you?
Because she was afraid.
Afraid you'd take Mitch?
Afraid I'd give Mitch.
I don't understand.
Afraid of any woman
who would give Mitch
the one thing
Lydia can give him, love.
That adds up
to a jealous,
possessive woman.
No, I don't think so.
You see, she's not afraid
of losing Mitch.
She's only afraid
of being abandoned.
Someone ought to tell her
she'd be gaining a daughter.
(CHUCKLES)
No. She already
has a daughter.
Well, what about Mitch?
Didn't he have anything
to say about this?
Well, I can understand
his position.
He'd just been through
a lot with Lydia
after his father died.
He didn't want to risk
going through it all again.
Oh, I see.
So it ended.
Not right then, of course.
We went back to San Francisco,
saw each other now and then,
but we both knew
it was over.
Then what are you doing
here in Bodega Bay?
I wanted to
be near Mitch.
Oh, it was over
and done with,
and I knew it, but...
I still wanted
to be near him.
You see, I still like him
a hell of a lot,
and I don't want to
lose that friendship, ever.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
No, no, no,
I wasn't asleep.
Yes, just a little while ago.
Sure. Hold on.
It's Mitch.
For you.
Hello? Oh, yes,
this is Melanie.
Fine, thank you.
No, no trouble at all.
I simply followed the road.
Well... there's no need
to apologize.
I can understand.
That's very kind of you.
No, I'm not angry.
Well, I couldn't.
I have to get back
to San Francisco.
No, I wouldn't want
to disappoint Cathy, but...
I see.
All right.
Yes, I'll be there.
Good night, Mitch.
He wants me to go
to Cathy's party
tomorrow afternoon.
I said I would.
It should be fun.
I'll be there,
too, to help.
Oh, it seems
so pointless.
Well,
I think I'll go to sleep.
It's been a busy day.
My luggage.
That's pretty.
Where'd you get that?
Brinkmeyer's?
Mmm.
Do you think
I should go?
Well, that's up to you.
No, it's really up
to Lydia, isn't it?
Never mind Lydia.
Do you want to go?
Yes.
Then go.
Thank you, Annie.
(CLATTERING)
Oh.
Wonder who that can be.
Is someone there?
Who is it?
Look.
Poor thing. Probably
lost his way in the dark.
But it isn't dark, Annie.
There's a full moon.
(CHILDREN CHATTERING
AND LAUGHING)
ANNIE: Cathy, that's
very good. Very good.
Okay. Here we go.
Attagirl. Come on.
Don't let him get you.
(INAUDIBLE)
No, I really
shouldn't have any more.
I'm driving.
Well, actually,
I'm trying to get you
to stay for dinner.
A lot of roast
beef left over.
No, I couldn't possibly.
I have to get back.
All right.
Cheers.
Seriously, why do you
have to rush off?
What's so important
in San Francisco?
Well, I have to get to work
tomorrow morning,
for one thing.
You have a job?
I have several jobs.
What do you do?
I do different things
on different days.
Like what?
Well, on Mondays
and Wednesdays,
I work for the
Travelers' Aid
at the airport.
Helping travelers?
No, misdirecting them.
I thought you could
read my character.
On Tuesdays, I take
a course in General
Semantics at Berkeley,
finding new
four-letter words.
That's not a job, of course...
You mean, you don't have to...
And on Thursdays,
I have my meeting
and lunch.
In the underworld,
I suppose.
I shall disappoint you.
We're sending
a little Korean boy
through school.
We actually
raise money for it.
You see, Rome...
That entire summer,
I did nothing but...
Well, it was very easy
to get lost there.
So when I came back,
I thought it was
time I began...
Oh, I don't know,
finding something again.
So, on Mondays
and Thursdays,
I keep myself busy.
What about Fridays?
Fridays? They're free.
I sometimes go to
bird shops on Fridays.
I'm very glad you do.
A nice, innocent,
little day.
Oh, yes.
I have an Aunt Tessa.
Have you got an Aunt Tessa?
Mine is very prim
and straight-laced.
I'm giving her a mynah bird
when she comes
back from Europe.
Mynah birds talk,
you know.
Can you see
my Aunt Tessa's face,
when this one tells us
one or two of the words
I've picked up at Berkeley?
You need
a mother's care, my child.
Not my mother's.
Oh, I'm sorry.
What have you got
to be sorry about?
My mother?
Don't waste your time.
She ditched us when I was 11
and ran off with
some hotel man in the east.
You know what
a mother's love is?
Yes, I do.
You mean it's
better to be ditched?
No. I think it's
better to be loved.
Don't you ever see her?
(VOICE BREAKING)
I don't know
where she is.
Well, maybe I ought to go
join the other children.
ANNIE: All right.
Here we go. One...
Two...
Three...
There you go.
(CHILDREN SQUEALING EXCITEDLY)
(CHILDREN LAUGHING)
BOY: Look! Look!
Hey! No touching allowed!
(SQUAWKING)
Oh!
(BIRDS SQUAWKING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(LOUD POP)
Help me get
the children
into the house.
There you go.
(SOBBING)
Have they gone, Mitch?
I think so.
LYDIA: Is anyone hurt?
WOMAN: Jenny got
a scratch down her cheek,
but it's nothing.
That makes three times.
Mitch, this isn't
usual, is it?
The gull when I was
in the boat yesterday,
the one at Annie's
last night, and now...
Last night?
What do you mean?
A gull smashed into
Annie's front door.
Mitch, what's happening?
I don't know.
Do you have to go
back to Annie's?
No. I have my
things in the car.
Stay and have something to eat
before you start back.
I'd feel a lot better.
Would you like some
mustard with that?
MELANIE:
No, thank you.
Why didn't Annie
stay for dinner?
Said something
about going home
to take a call
from her sister
in the east.
(CHIRPING)
What's the matter
with them?
with all the birds?
Where did you
want this coffee?
Here on the
table, honey.
Hurry up with
yours, Mitch.
I'm sure Miss Daniels
wants to be on her way.
I think you ought to
stay the night, Melanie.
We have an extra
room upstairs
and everything.
That road can be
a pretty bad
one at night, too.
If I go across
to Santa Rosa,
I'll come out on
the freeway much
earlier, won't I?
Yes, and the freeway
is much quicker.
But she'll be hitting
all the heavy traffic
going back to San Francisco.
(LOUD CHIRPING)
CATHY: Just listen
to those lovebirds.
(CHIRPING STOPS)
(TWITTERING)
MELANIE: Mitch.
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
Cover your faces!
Cover your eyes!
That's a sparrow,
all right.
We know what
it is, Al.
Did you have a light
burning or something?
Yes, but there
wouldn't have been
that much light
going up the chimney.
'Cause sometimes
birds are attracted by light,
you know.
Sure is a peculiar thing.
Well, all right,
but we've got to do
something about it!
I don't think
I get you, Mitch.
Do about what?
MITCH: Well, the birds
invaded the house.
AL: What's more likely,
they got in the room
and was just panicked.
That's all.
MITCH: All right,
I'll admit a bird will panic
in an enclosed room,
but they didn't just
get in. They came in,
right down the chimney.
AL: My wife found a bird
in the back seat
of her car once.
Tell him about the party.
That's right. We had
a party here this afternoon
for Cathy, for her birthday.
AL: How old is she?
MITCH: Eleven!
In the middle
of the party,
some seagulls came
down at the children!
Miss Daniels was attacked
by a gull only yesterday.
AL: Yeah. Were the kids
bothering the birds
or something?
'Cause if you make any kind
of a disturbance near them,
they'll just
come after you.
Al, the children
were playing a game.
Those gulls attacked.
AL: Now, Lydia, "attack"
is a pretty strong word,
don't you think?
I mean,
birds just don't go
around attacking people
without no reason.
You know what I mean?
The kids probably
scared them, that's all.
These birds attacked.
You got quite
a mess here,
I'll admit that.
Maybe you ought
to put some screen
on top of your chimney.
You want some
help cleaning up?
MITCH: No.
I can handle it.
(GASPS)
It shouldn't be
too much of a job.
I'll take Cathy up to bed.
I think I should
stay, don't you?
MITCH: It would be
nice if you could.
My things
are in the car.
Do you want
to go with me?
All right.
AL: Well, anything
else I can do, Mitch?
MITCH: No, thanks, Al.
We'll be all right.
Good night, Lydia.
Sure is peculiar.
(SHOVEL GRATING)
LYDIA: Mitch.
Mitch. Mitch!
MITCH: Yes, Mother?
LYDIA: I'm going to
drop Cathy off now.
I'll probably drive over
to the Fawcett farm.
MITCH: Okay.
(VEHICLE STARTING)
MAN: Morning.
Good morning, George.
Is Mr. Fawcett around?
I think so, ma'am.
Ain't seen him this morning,
but he ought to be in there.
Thanks.
Dan, are you home?
(GASPING)
(CHOKING)
(STARTS ENGINE)
(SOBBING)
Mother!
What is it, dear?
What's the matter?
Al Malone,
the deputy,
just called.
He wants me over
at the Fawcett place.
Some detectives
from Santa Rosa
will be there.
Will it be all right?
Yes.
I was just taking
your mother in some tea.
Oh, be careful, please.
And you be careful.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
(KNOCKING)
LYDIA: Mitch?
No, it's me,
Mrs. Brenner.
I thought you
might like some tea.
Oh. Thank you.
Where's Mitch?
Al Malone wanted him
out at the Fawcett farm.
Why? Didn't Al
believe my story?
He was calling
from the farm.
Then he saw.
Oh, he must have.
They sent for
the Santa Rosa police.
What good will they do?
Do you think Cathy's
all right at the school?
Yes, I'm sure
she's fine.
Do I sound
very foolish to you?
Oh, no.
I keep seeing Dan's face.
And they have
such big windows
at the school.
All the windows are broken
in Dan's bedroom.
All the windows!
Try not to
think about that.
I wish I were
a stronger person.
I lost my husband
four years ago,
you know.
It's terrible how
you depend on someone else
for strength, and then
suddenly all the strength
is gone, and you're alone.
I'd love to be able
to relax sometime.
I'd love to be
able to sleep.
Do you think
Cathy's all right?
Annie's there.
She'll be all right.
I'm not like this,
you know? Not usually.
I don't fuss and fret
about my children.
When Frank died...
You see,
he understood the children.
He really understood them.
He had the knack
of entering into their world
and becoming part of them.
That's a very
rare talent.
Yes.
Oh, I wish, I wish,
I wish I could be like that.
I miss him.
Sometimes, even now,
I wake up in the morning
and I think,
"I must get
Frank's breakfast."
And I get up, and
there's a very good reason
for getting out of bed,
until, of course,
I remember.
I miss talking to him.
Cathy's a child,
of course, and Mitch...
Well, Mitch
has his own life.
I'm glad
he stayed here today.
I feel safer
with him here.
Would you like
to rest now?
No.
No, don't go.
I feel as if I don't
understand you at all,
and I want so
much to understand.
Why, Mrs. Brenner?
Because my son seems
to be very fond of you,
and I don't quite
know how I feel about it.
I don't even know
if I like you or not.
Is that so important,
your liking me?
Well, yes.
I think so.
Mitch is important to me.
I want to like
whatever girl he chooses.
And perhaps if you don't?
Well, then I don't think
it'll matter very much
to anyone but me.
Oh, I think it would
also matter to Mitch.
Mitch has always done
exactly what he wanted to do.
But, you see,
I don't want to be
left alone.
I don't think I could
bear to be left alone!
Oh, forgive me.
This business
with the birds
has upset me.
I don't know what I'd do
if Mitch weren't here.
Why don't you try
to sleep now,
Mrs. Brenner?
I wish
I was stronger.
Do you think
she's all right?
she's all right
at the school?
Would you like me
to go for her?
Oh, I couldn't ask it.
Oh, I don't mind, really.
Would you?
I'd feel so much better.
I'll go right now.
Melanie?
Thanks for the tea.
(CHILDREN SINGING)
I married my wife
in the month of June
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
I brought her home
by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
She combs her hair
but once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
With every stroke
She shed a tear
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Rustical quality
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
I brought her home
by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
She combed her hair
but once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
With every stroke
She shed a tear
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
She swept up her floor
but once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
She said that brooms
were much too dear
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
She churns the butter
in her dad's old boot
Ristle-tee, Rostle-tee
Now, now, now
And for a dash
She'd use her foot
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
The butter it came out
all grizzle-y gray
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
The cheese it took
legs and ran away
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
She let the critter get away
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
I asked my wife
to wash the floor
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
She gave me my hat
and she showed me the door
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Now, now, now
I married my wife
in the month of June
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Now, now, now
I brought her home
by the light of the moon
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
She combed her hair
but once a year
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
Hey, donnie-dostle-tee
Knickety-knackety
Rustical quality
Willow-tee, wallow-tee
Now, now, now
Ristle-tee, rostle-tee
ANNIE: All right, children.
Now, please put
your song books away,
then stand up
alongside your desks.
We'll go out for recess
as soon as
everybody gets ready.
We are not going
into the playground
until everybody
has quieted down.
Close that door.
Quickly. Please.
What?
What is it?
Look.
We've got to get
the children out of here.
(CHILDREN TALKING
INDISTINCTLY)
(SHUSHING) All right,
children. Now, quiet.
Quiet. Miss Daniels
would like to see
how we conduct ourselves
during a fire drill.
(EXCLAIMING IN PROTEST)
I would like you
to show her how quiet
and obedient you can be.
Oh, we're going
out of school now.
CHILDREN: Leave school?
We want those of you
who live nearby
to go directly home.
CHILDREN: Home?
I want the rest of you
to go down the hill
all the way to the hotel.
Now, is that clear?
CHILDREN: Yes,
Miss Hayworth.
Melanie?
I want you to go as
quietly as possible.
Do not make a sound
until I tell you to run.
Then run as
quickly as you can.
Now, does everybody
understand?
CHILDREN: Yes,
Miss Hayworth.
All right, John,
you lead the way.
(LOUD FLUTTERING)
(BIRDS SHRIEKING)
(CHILDREN SCREAMING)
(CAWING)
(SCREAMING)
(SQUAWKING)
Cathy! Cathy!
(CRYING)
(HONKING)
Well, Daddy, there
were hundreds of them.
No, I'm not hysterical.
I'm trying to tell you this
as calmly as I know how.
All right, Daddy.
Yes, Daddy.
Well, just now.
Not 15 minutes ago.
At the school.
No, I don't. Just a minute.
What's the name
of the school?
Just the Bodega Bay School.
The Bodega Bay School.
Well, I don't know
how many children,
30 or 40.
No, the birds didn't attack
until the children
were outside the school.
Help you,
Mrs. Bundy?
I need some change,
Mr. Carter.
Crows, I think.
Well, I don't
know, Daddy.
Is there a difference
between crows
and blackbirds?
There is very definitely
a difference, miss.
Thank you.
They're different, Daddy.
Well, I think
these were crows.
Well, yes.
Hundreds of them.
Yes, they attacked
the children.
Attacked them!
Well, I don't know when,
but I simply can't
leave now, Daddy.
All right.
Yes. Good-bye.
They're both
perching birds, of course,
but quite different species.
The crow is
Corvus brachyrhynchos,
and the blackbird
is Euphagus cyanocephalus.
Thank you.
You have the number
at the Fawcett farm?
Right here in
this book, miss.
I can't see that
it makes any difference,
Mrs. Bundy.
Crows or blackbirds,
if the school was attacked,
that's pretty serious.
I hardly think
that either species
would have
sufficient intelligence
to launch a massed attack.
Their brainpans are
not big enough to...
I just came from
the school, madam.
I don't know
anything about
their brainpans, but...
Well, I do.
I do know.
Ornithology happens
to be my avocation.
Birds are not aggressive
creatures, miss.
They bring beauty
into the world.
It is mankind,
rather, who...
WAITRESS: Sam! Three
southern fried chicken.
Baked potato
on all of them.
Yes, may I speak to
Mitch Brenner, please?
Yes, I'll wait.
It is mankind, rather,
who insists upon
making it difficult
for life to exist
upon this planet.
Now, if it were
not for the birds...
Mrs. Bundy,
you don't seem
to understand.
This young lady said
there was an attack
on the school.
Impossible!
Oh, Mitch?
Oh, I'm glad
I caught you.
Something terrible has...
It's the end
of the world!
Two Bloody Marys, Deke.
What actually
happened at the school?
Bunch of crows
attacked the school kids.
It's the end of the world.
"Thus saith the Lord God
"unto the mountains
and the hills,
"and the rivers
and the valleys.
"Behold I, even I,
"shall bring
a sword upon you,
"and I will devastate
your high places."
Ezekiel, chapter six.
WAITRESS: "Woe unto them that
rise up early in the morning,
"that they may
follow strong drink."
Isaiah, chapter five.
It's the end of the world.
I hardly think a few birds
are going to bring about
the end of the world.
These weren't
a few birds.
I didn't know
there were many crows
in Bodega Bay
this time of year.
The crow is
a permanent resident
throughout its range.
In fact, during
our Christmas count,
we recorded...
How many gulls
did you count,
Mrs. Bundy?
MRS. BUNDY:
Which gulls, Mr. Sholes?
There are several varieties.
The ones who've
been playing devil
with my fishing boats.
Have you had
trouble with gulls?
One of my boats did,
last week.
This young lady
was hit by a gull
only Saturday.
Deke, I'm still waiting
for those Bloody Marys.
DEKE: Coming right up.
Could you ask them
to lower their voices,
please?
They're frightening
the children.
A whole flock of gulls
nearly capsized
one of my boats.
Practically tore
the skipper's arm off.
You're scaring the kids.
Keep it low.
All right.
Yeah, well,
he's scaring me, too.
Are you trying to
say that all these...
Nah, that sounds
impossible, Sebastian.
Deke, look, I'm just
telling you what happened
to one of my boats.
The gulls were after
your fish, Mr. Sholes.
Really, let's be
logical about this.
What were the crows
after at the school?
What do you think
they were after? Miss...
Daniels. I think
they were after
the children.
For what purpose?
To kill them.
Why?
I don't know why.
I thought not.
Birds have been
on this planet,
Miss Daniels,
since Archaeopteryx,
140 million years ago.
Doesn't it seem odd that
they'd wait all that time
to start a war
against humanity?
No one called it a war.
Scotch, light
on the water.
You and Mr. Sholes seem
to be implying as much.
Who said
anything about a war?
All I said, some gulls...
WAITRESS: Want
some more coffee?
No.
...came down on
one of my boats.
They could have
been after the fish,
just like you said.
The Captain should
have shot at them.
Huh?
Gulls are scavengers,
anyway. Most birds are.
Get yourselves guns
and wipe them off
the face of the Earth!
(CHUCKLES) That would
hardly be possible.
Why not,
Mrs. Bundy?
Because there
are 8,650 species
of birds in the world
today, Mr. Carter.
It is estimated that
5,750,000,000 birds
live in
the United States alone.
The five continents
of the world...
Kill them all.
Get rid of
the messy animals.
...probably contain
more than 100 billion birds.
It's the end of the world.
Those gulls must have
been after the fish.
MRS. BUNDY: Of course!
Hurry up, children.
Finish your lunch.
Are the birds
gonna eat us, Mommy?
Hell, maybe we're
all getting a little
carried away by this.
Admittedly,
a few birds
did act strange,
but that's no reason
to believe that...
I keep telling you,
this isn't a few birds.
These are gulls,
crows, swifts...
I have never known birds
of different species
to flock together.
The very concept
is unimaginable.
Why, if that happened,
we wouldn't have a chance!
How could we possibly
hope to fight them?
We couldn't,
you're right.
You're right,
Mrs. Bundy.
What's the matter?
Something wrong out here?
We're fighting
a war, Sam.
A war? Against who?
Against birds!
I'm glad you all think
this is so amusing.
You've frightened the children
half out of their wits.
If the young lady said
she saw
the attack at a school,
why don't you believe her?
What attack?
Who attacked
the school?
WOMAN: Birds did. Crows.
You're all sitting
around here debating!
What do you want
them to do next?
Crash through that window?
GIRL: Mommy!
Shh. Put on your coat.
Why don't you all go home,
lock your doors and windows?
What's the fastest
way to San Francisco?
The freeway, ma'am.
How do I find it?
I'm going out
that way, lady.
You can follow me.
WOMAN: Well, then
let's leave now.
Haven't finished
my drink yet.
I got here
as fast as I could.
Where's Cathy?
She's with Annie.
She's all right.
Al, why aren't you
over at the school,
where the attack was?
'Cause I just got back
from Dan Fawcett's place,
that's why.
He was killed
last night by birds.
What?
Now, hold it, Mitch.
You don't know that
for a fact.
What are the facts,
Mr. Malone?
The Santa Rosa Police
think it's a felony murder.
They think a burglar broke in,
killed him.
How do you explain
the dead birds
all over the floor?
Santa Rosa Police
figure they got in after
the old man was killed.
Were the Santa Rosa Police
at your school today?
Are you coming?
Now take it easy, lady.
There isn't a bird
anywhere in sight!
"Look at the birds of the air.
They do not sow or reap.
"Yet your heavenly Father
feeds them."
Say, something
like this happened
in Santa Cruz last year.
The town was just
covered with seagulls.
Will you please
finish your drink?
That's right, sir.
I recall it.
A large flock of seagulls
got lost in a fog,
and headed into the town
where all the lights were.
They made some mess, too,
smashing into buildings
and everything.
They always make a mess.
The point is
that no one seemed
to be upset about it.
They were all
gone next morning,
just as though
nothing at all
had happened.
Poor things.
I'm leaving!
Are you coming?
All right,
all right!
Well, hope you folks
figure this thing out!
It's the end
of the world!
I better get back
to the cannery.
What do I owe you, Deke?
Sebastian,
hold it a minute.
I don't want to be
an alarmist about this...
No one ever said
you were, Mitch.
I think we're
in real trouble.
I don't know how
this started, or why,
but I know it's here
and we'd be crazy
to ignore it.
To ignore what?
The "bird war"?
Yes, the "bird war."
The bird attack, plague...
Call it what you like,
they're massing
out there someplace,
and they'll be back.
You can count on it.
Ridiculous.
Come here.
Unless we do
something right now,
unless we get Bodega Bay
on the move, they...
Look, Mitch.
Even if this is true,
even if all the birds...
Don't you believe
it's true?
No, Mitch,
frankly I don't.
There's no reason. I...
Well, it's happening.
Isn't that a reason?
I like Bodega Bay as
well as the next man...
Fine, then help me.
You're an important man
in this town.
If you help, they all will.
SEBASTIAN: Help how?
What do you want to do?
MITCH: Mrs. Bundy
said something
about Santa Cruz.
(GULL CAWING)
About seagulls
getting lost in a fog
and flying in
towards the lights.
SEBASTIAN:
We don't have fog
this time of year!
MITCH:
Make our own fog!
SEBASTIAN: How do you
figure to do that?
MITCH: We can use smoke pots,
the way the Army uses them.
MELANIE: Look!
(SEAGULL CRYING)
They're attacking again.
Melanie, you stay in here.
Come on, Al!
(SEAGULLS CAWING)
Look out!
Look at the gas.
That man's lighting
a cigar!
Hey, you! Watch out!
Don't drop that match!
Get out of there!
Mister, run!
Watch out!
Look out! Look out!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(PEOPLE CLAMORING)
(CALLING)
(SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
MAN: Hey!
(SIREN WAILING)
(SHRIEKING)
Why are they doing this?
They said when you got here,
the whole thing started!
Who are you?
What are you?
Where did you come from?
I think you're the cause
of all this.
I think you're evil! Evil!
(GASPS)
Oh, God!
I think
they're going!
We can get Cathy
at Annie's now.
The crows again.
Shh!
(CAWING)
Come on.
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
Oh, no. Stay here.
Stay here.
(GASPS AND SCREAMS)
(SOBBING)
Cathy! Where's Cathy?
(CATHY SOBBING)
Mitch, don't!
Oh, don't leave
her there, Mitch.
(MELANIE SOBBING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(WHISPERS) Come on.
(SOBS)
Shh!
(LOUD CAWING)
(STARTS ENGINE)
When we got back from
taking Michele home,
we heard the explosion
and we went outside
to see what it was.
All at once
the birds were everywhere!
she pushed me inside,
and they covered her!
Annie...
She pushed me inside!
(HAMMERING)
Give me another one, darling.
How long have they
been gathering there?
Oh, about 15 minutes.
Seems like a pattern,
doesn't it?
They strike, then disappear,
and then start massing again.
Doesn't look so very
different, does it?
A little smoke hanging
over the town, otherwise...
You want to try
your father again?
No, I tried
a little while ago.
The phone's dead.
Still got power,
haven't we?
Yes.
LYDIA: Mitch, I'm getting
something on the radio.
Come on.
I can't get any of
the local stations.
I think this
is San Francisco.
MAN ON RADIO:
"...and the work of a team
of professionals." End quote.
In Bodega Bay
early this morning,
a large flock of crows
attacked a group of children
who were leaving the school
during a fire drill.
One little girl
was seriously injured
and taken to the hospital
in Santa Rosa,
but the majority of
children reached safety.
We understand there was
another attack on the town,
but this information
is rather sketchy.
So far,
no word has come through
to show if there have
been further attacks.
On the national scene today,
in Washington...
Well, is that all?
I'll have to get
some more wood in.
Mustn't let this fire go out.
Did you get the windows
in the attic, Mitch?
Yes, I got
them all, dear.
When do you
think they'll come?
I don't know.
If there are
bigger birds, Mitch,
they'll get into the house.
Well, it's just
a chance
we'll have to take.
Maybe we ought
to leave.
No, not now!
Not while they're
massing out there.
When?
We'll just see
what happens.
Where will we go?
I don't know.
I think we're safe
here for the time being.
Let's get
the wood in now.
What happens when
you run out of wood?
I don't know!
We'll break up
the furniture.
You don't know!
When will you know?
When we're all dead!
If only your
father were here...
(CATHY SOBBING)
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Mitch.
Make yourself
some coffee,
won't you?
"In assuming
the tasks of the presidency,
"I said that few
generations..."
Where are they heading?
Somewhere inland.
Santa Rosa?
Maybe.
Come on.
Let's get the wood.
Mitch? Can I bring
the lovebirds in here?
No!
CATHY: But, Mom,
they're in a cage.
They're birds,
aren't they?
Let's leave them
in the kitchen,
huh, honey?
Mitch, why are they
doing this, the birds?
We don't know, honey.
Why are they trying
to kill people?
I wish I could say.
(SHUDDERING SOFTLY)
I'm sick, Melanie.
I want to...
I'll go with you.
(CATHY COUGHING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(BIRDS TWITTERING)
(WINGS FLUTTERING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(LOUD CAWING)
(HIGH-PITCHED CHIRPING)
(BIRDCALLS INTENSIFYING)
(GLASS SHATTERING)
(LOUD SCREECHING)
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(RUMBLING)
(PECKING)
(BIRDS SHRIEKING)
(PECKING CONTINUES)
(BIRD SCREECHES)
(SOUNDS DIMINISH)
They're going.
(SCREECHES FADING)
(CAWING STOPS)
(WINGS FLUTTER)
Mitch?
(GASPS)
(SCREECHING)
(WHIMPERING)
(MOANING)
Oh, Mitch!
Get Cathy and
Lydia out of here.
MITCH: Melanie! Melanie!
(BIRDS SHRIEKING)
Melanie!
Oh, poor thing!
Poor thing!
Listen,
get some water, bandages,
and antiseptic. Quickly!
Bandages. It's terrible.
Cathy, get some brandy.
No, no, no!
No, no, it's all right.
No, it's all right,
it's all right,
it's all right.
It's all right.
It's all right. No.
(GASPING)
(SHUSHING)
Cathy, get the lamp.
(SIGHS) We've got to
get her to a hospital.
We can't, Mitch.
There's no place
we can go.
There's San Francisco.
We'd never make it.
We have to try.
We'll go by way
of Bay Hill Road.
Then we don't have
to go through town.
We can't stay here.
She needs help!
I'm frightened.
Terribly frightened.
I don't know
what's outside there.
We better get started
before another attack comes.
We'll take Melanie's car.
That'll be faster
than the truck.
Can you finish
the bandaging?
I'll try.
All right.
LYDIA: Mitch?
See if you can get anything
on the car radio.
(SOFT COOING)
(FLUTTERING)
(CAWING)
(LOW CLATTER)
(SWITCHING STATIONS)
ANNOUNCER:
The bird attacks have subsided
for the time being.
Bodega Bay seems
to be the center,
though there are
reports of minor attacks
on Sebastopol and
a few on Santa Rosa.
Bodega Bay has been
cordoned off by roadblocks.
Most of the townspeople
have managed to get out,
but there are still
some isolated
pockets of people.
No decision has been
arrived at yet as to
what the next step will be,
but there's been
some discussion as to whether
the military should go in.
It appears
that the bird attacks
come in waves,
with long intervals between.
The reason for this
does not seem clear as yet.
(STARTS ENGINE)
(MOTOR TURNING OVER SLOWLY)
(SHUTS OFF MOTOR)
(HAND BRAKE CLICKS)
Did you hear
anything on the radio?
It's all right.
Come on.
(TURNS DOOR KNOB)
(GULL CRYING)
No. No!
(HUSHING)
Mitch?
Shh.
Stay there.
Can I bring the
lovebirds, Mitch?
They haven't
harmed anyone.
All right.
Bring them.
(STARTS ENGINE)
(BIRD CAWING INTENSIFIES)