Shahab Hosseini
Taraneh Alidoosti
Produced by
Alexandre Mallet-Guy
Asghar Farhadi
Get out!
The building's collapsing!
What's happening?
What are you doing there?
We have to evacuate!
Rana!
Hurry up.
- What is it?
- No idea. We have to evacuate.
Rana!
Quick!
Go down! Hurry up.
- What's up?
- No idea.
Emad! I need help for my son!
Coming.
Put that on and go down.
- I'll come up with you.
- No, get out.
Everyone, in the street!
Where's Hossein?
He won't listen to me.
Hossein...
Get up, son.
Get up, the building's collapsing.
Get up, Hossein.
Emad, come down!
Get out! Get everybody out.
We have to evacuate the building.
What are they doing?
My glasses.
I'll take them.
The Salesman
Written and directed by
Asghar Farhadi
Hey, guys,
don't load yourselves down.
We've got all you need.
Okay.
I can't find it.
Look hard.
I'll take this?
Yes, please.
- Only your toothbrushes, remember...
- Got them.
- Did you lock the car?
- Yes.
Give me the keys.
Hey, guys.
Hi.
Still alive, then?
I thought we'd have
to dig you out of the rubble.
Look at that!
It smells like gas.
Since last night.
We shouldn't hang around.
- Shalom.
- Why did you come up?
- Cut the electricity. There's a leak.
I can't find the card.
Did you look through the papers?
Not there, it's dangerous.
Jeez!
"One could only hear the sobs
of the woman sitting with her lamp
"on the barn roof,
"and inside, the lowing of a cow. "
Sir, is it a true story?
Not really.
But in Saedi's writing,
the atmosphere and
characters are realistic,
very close to reality.
A man turning into a cow?
Look in the mirror!
You're hilarious.
How can you turn into a cow?
Gradually.
Sir, can we see the film?
Good idea. I'll bring it next time.
- Yes? - When can we
come to your play?
We open next week.
- I'll invite you soon.
- Thanks.
- What's it called?
- Death of a Salesman. Who's read it?
Nobody!
Seriously, anybody read it?
Who wrote it?
Arthur Miller.
I haven't read that one.
Good.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Hello.
I can't talk. I'm in class.
Can you call me in 10 minutes?
Stick shift, yes.
Silver, that's right.
You're welcome.
He's selling his car.
Who do you play, sir?
The salesman.
What do you sell?
Potatoes!
You'll see.
What model is it?
- What?
- Your car.
Why?
Are you selling it or not?
His father works in the traffic office.
He can cancel your tickets!
You never get tickets!
Why do Iranians say "BMV" for "BMW"?
Pardon?
Calm down.
Eh, eh, eh.
No harm in asking questions.
I don't know the answer.
So,
for next time...
...write a summary of the novel.
And no lame excuses,
like sleeping in or family gatherings.
Would you mind not spreading out?
Can I switch places with the young man?
- Dad?
- Hmm?
Somebody in there?
No, that was next door.
Somebody got in your bathroom.
No.
It's the next room, there's a party.
Can I come in?
There's something in the bathtub, Willy.
It's moving.
Miss Francis,
you better go back to your room.
I've got to get dressed. I can't.
Yes, you can. Go back.
Biff, this is Miss Francis,
my neighbor.
They're painting her room.
She asked if she could take a shower here.
I let her.
Go back.
But I'm not dressed.
Please, get out of here.
You promised me stockings.
I don't have any here.
You had two boxes of size 9 for me,
and I want them.
Go on, take them.
For God's sake, will you get out?
Get out.
I hope there's nobody.
Going out naked...
Uh...
Say,
are you
football or...
Shut up!
Siavash!
What's up, Mommy?
It's worse and worse.
Sadra, we're off.
Sanam, forget it.
Just because I'm playing a hooker,
he thinks he can disrespect me.
You're making fun of me!
Shut it!
Leave her alone.
Come on, it's the final rehearsal.
Sorry, I'm sorry.
I drag my kid across the city
every night in the cold for this.
It's a pleasure working with you.
Leave him!
Sanam, stop it.
Leave him, I said!
I was kidding.
It was a joke.
She comes in, in her raincoat
and says, "I can't go out without clothes. "
"I can't... "
It's funny.
Go and get her. She's going to quit.
Oh, no, don't send me out naked.
I can't go out like that.
Sanam!
What an idiot!
You find anything?
650 square feet, 3rd floor walkup, 40,000.
- Where?
- Amir Atabak.
- What're you looking for?
- Temporary.
Otherwise, we'll be sleeping here.
You free tomorrow?
- Why?
- I've got something to show you.
Okay, let's do a complete run-through.
You okay?
What are you doing here?
Kitty...
Whose is he?
It's nice here.
- Babak?
- Hmm?
Is this a closet?
Where?
Not at all.
It's the other bedroom.
Eh?
- Too small?
- It's two bedrooms.
Will it do?
More than enough for two people.
Careful what you say.
There might be three of us soon.
Rana, is he serious?
No.
- Wouldn't think so.
- Why?
Is it locked?
The last tenant left her stuff here.
Don't be scared, kitty.
- How long has it been empty?
- Three weeks.
Oh!
What a disaster, this town.
If we could only level it
all and start again.
They did, and look at the result.
- Good old Willy.
- Babak!
God save us, Charley.
- When will the room be free?
- Very soon, she promised.
There's no parking space.
You'll have to park outside.
We'll do without.
We're selling the car to pay the deposit.
- Who said anything about money?
- Even so.
Hello, Mr. Salimi.
Mr. Shahnazari, the best neighbor ever.
How are you?
Pleased to meet you.
Babak, where's the cellar?
Over there.
- Mr. Salimi?
- Yes?
It's open.
Careful who you take in this time.
- I know them.
- Last time, too.
Don't worry.
- What do they do?
- They're in the arts.
All the better.
It's okay for a few months,
but we have to pay,
I don't want him to do us a favor.
For once, it looks like we're in luck.
Go up carefully.
- You need a hand?
- Go and get the rest.
Careful with the ceiling light.
- Thank you.
- My pleasure.
- She kept the key?
- Of this room, yes.
Easy does it.
Where's Ali?
Put that down.
Ali...
Leave it. I'll call an electrician tomorrow.
- It's okay, I can do it.
- Leave it.
She could've said.
She seemed so sure she'd come by.
I didn't think she'd let us down.
- What does she say now?
- Nothing. She doesn't answer.
Try with another phone.
Rana, your phone.
We really need the room for our furniture.
That's right.
Okay.
He's here. Can I put him on?
Seems she already told you everything.
So?
She was meant to sign a lease yesterday.
The landlord stood her up.
She's looking for somewhere else
before coming for this.
She doesn't want you to touch her things.
Or speak to her.
So?
Nothing.
I'm coming, Kati.
- Ali!
- Ali.
You got a screwdriver?
What a mess!
I expected only a couple of things.
- Sure this is okay?
- I'll take responsibility.
We'll make room in the corridor.
- Where?
- On the left.
Clear all that.
Put that on the other side.
Rana?
There's lots of personal belongings.
Those are her clothes...
She's been giving us the runaround.
What if she complains?
She should've kept her word.
Let's get rid of it.
I'm not taking anything heavy.
I'm performing this evening.
Come and eat.
Rana.
Could you plug that in?
Go get the boxes.
Hello, everyone.
Is it the cash for the car?
Leave it at the office
and call the librarian.
Learn the poem by heart for next time.
Goodbye, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Goodbye.
- Can I speak to you, sir?
- Sure.
I was very upset the other day.
What day?
The day that woman accused you in the taxi.
She accused me?
She wanted to switch places with me.
When you got out,
I told her you were our teacher,
and that we liked you a lot.
- What's your name again?
- Amin.
Amin, you can be sure
that a man behaved badly
in a taxi to that woman, and now
she thinks they're all the same.
But nobody died, so off you go.
- Goodbye, sir.
- Goodbye.
I don't know what to do with her.
Who?
That woman.
I called her and she got on her high horse
and threatened me.
With what?
"Don't touch my personal things.
I'll sue you. "
I spent the night trying
to protect her things from the rain.
Her problem's different.
You mean the woman?
When's she coming?
When she's found a place.
Sadra, come and see Mommy.
Hurry up. The doors open in five minutes.
Emad.
They're coming back after the performance.
Three passages might still be censored.
Can you stay and talk to them?
- Tonight?
- Yes.
If it'll help...
Otherwise, the show risks a suspension.
- How many passages?
- Three.
I won't stay.
Won't you wait for me?
No, it'll last till midnight.
Take the car.
- Where's the apartment key?
- In my pocket.
- Have a good show, honey.
- You, too.
Will you get us something
for breakfast from the supermarket?
If it's open, I said.
And liquid soap.
I'll take a shower, meantime.
I look horrible.
I haven't even removed my makeup.
I'll be quick.
It won't take long.
Love you.
See you later.
- Anything else?
- No, thanks.
- By card?
- No, cash.
- Good evening, madam.
- Shalom.
I'm your upstairs neighbor.
We've just moved in. Could you let me in?
Thanks.
Rana?
Rana.
Rana, what happened to you?
Please go out, sir.
- Wait outside, we'll call you
for the scanner. - Rana...
Please stay outside.
- Look at me.
- No worries. We'll call you.
Go on.
You should change
the lock first thing tomorrow morning.
Did someone come into our place?
I thought she'd fainted.
We don't know what happened.
We heard cries from upstairs.
A whole series of cries.
I told my husband to go and see.
He thought it was a domestic fight.
But then we heard running on the stairs,
and I understood there was a problem.
Who was it?
By the time we got out,
he was already in the street.
His foot must be cut,
given the blood on the stairs.
If I'd have caught him,
I'd have skinned him alive.
We went up
and found your wife unconscious,
blood on the floor, I dressed her.
That's enough talk.
Thank God it wasn't anything more serious.
Maybe you could go to the ER,
to see if there's any news.
- Sorry...
- You don't look well.
Sit down for a bit.
Has anything been taken?
I didn't notice.
Why would a burglar go into the bathroom?
Who was it, then?
A client of that woman.
What woman?
The one there before you.
She lived a wild life.
I think the guy came for her.
Don't close it, Ali's coming.
It's okay, go ahead.
Can you pull my sleeve?
Thanks.
Wait, I'll take your scarf.
- Do you want another pillow?
- No.
- Turn out the light.
- No, leave it.
- Do you want anything?
- No, thanks.
Where are you going, Emad?
Where?
Nowhere, I'm here. Do you want something?
Leave the door open.
If ever she feels faint, call me.
Okay, thanks.
Watch her blood pressure.
- Thanks for everything.
- You're welcome.
- I'll make you breakfast.
- No, we're going.
- I insist.
- Forget it.
You must be hungry.
Why don't you stay with them?
Would you like some soup?
You sure?
You go and get some rest, too.
- Call us if you need anything.
- Don't hesitate.
- Okay.
- Bye, then.
Thanks for everything.
Here, this is yours.
Kati, thanks.
Iron and aluminum doors,
good price paid.
Come here, I want to go to the bathroom.
What are you doing?
Leave it, I'll wash it.
Come, do it.
Okay, cut the water.
Come and clean, so I can go.
Someone may come to inspect.
Yes?
Okay, sorry.
Who is it?
The neighbor.
- What does he want?
- I'll be back.
Sorry.
I'm sorry for the trouble last night.
Don't mention it.
Call the police.
They'll find him, thanks to the pickup.
I will. I'll find a place to park,
in the meantime.
We thought we'd got rid of her.
Do you know who the pickup owner is?
The woman had too many visitors.
I may ask you to testify,
if a detective comes.
Sure. Do you want my number?
- Yes, please.
- I'm off.
Thanks again, madam.
You're welcome. Those people
deserve to be publicly humiliated.
It's 912...
What are you doing out here?
Go inside.
I'm scared on my own.
Where were you?
I went to thank the
neighbors for last night.
- What did they say?
- Nothing.
They asked after you.
You didn't tell the troupe, I hope?
No.
I'm going to the police.
We have to lodge a complaint
so they'll find him.
How will they do it?
He left his pickup.
He also forgot his phone,
but the line's cut.
Who was it?
The neighbors say the old tenant
was promiscuous.
That jerk must have been a client of hers.
Do you remember his face?
No.
Didn't you see him?
Come inside, it's cold.
Let me serve you.
Who got me out of the bathroom?
A neighbor.
Which one?
I have no idea. Who cares?
Have your breakfast and go to sleep.
I can't. As soon as I close my eyes,
I see it all again.
How did he get in?
I let him in. I was waiting for you.
I came out of the bathroom,
buzzed the door open and went back in.
I was washing my hair.
I felt someone had come in.
He stroked my hair, I thought it was you.
Then I saw his hands
and I can't remember anything else.
Rana.
Darling,
eat a little.
My Rana.
My love.
And tonight's performance?
I had it canceled.
- Call to say I'm coming.
- In this state?
I can't stay here.
Let's go to the police.
It could be a while.
- No, let's not go.
- We can't do anything.
I don't want to have to tell it
in front of everybody.
Did something happen?
No.
Then say nothing. I'll do the talking.
- Come on.
- It's too hard for me.
I'm not joking, Linda.
I know it when I walk down the street.
They seem to laugh at me.
Why?
Why would they laugh at you?
They just pass me by.
They ignore me. I'm not noticed.
Linda!
How long are you going to keep
darning those socks?
You know it drives me crazy!
Can't you stop while I'm talking to you?
Okay, let's talk about something else.
Let's talk about my income.
My income that never changes.
It's ridiculous.
What's wrong?
Why don't you say something?
Willy,
darling, you're the handsomest man
in the whole world.
You always tell me that, Linda.
You tell me, but it doesn't help.
I can never satisfy you,
for I'm just a simple salesman.
I'm nothing, Linda.
But I tried...
Why are you crying?
Wait, where are you going?
Linda, come back.
I'm sorry.
We have to interrupt the play.
My partner and wife is ill.
We'd like a 10-minute break,
and we thank you.
Can you go on?
You see she can't.
Find some way to cancel.
Do you want to lie down next door?
Come on, let's leave her to rest here.
Sanam.
Coming.
Do you need anything?
Kati,
go and announce it's canceled.
What will I say?
What happened to you?
The gaze of one member
of the audience bothered me.
They've come here to look at you.
He had the guy's gaze.
You said you didn't see him.
I'm not well at all. I need help.
Babak, can you come here?
Coming.
We'll talk later.
Is she better?
I meant to say...
You didn't think to tell me
who lived there before us?
- Why? - You're supposed
to be my friend.
What happened?
What's it got to do with you?
The whole neighborhood
knows that apartment.
Who said that?
No one.
Why doesn't she come for her stuff?
But I wanted to help you.
Did you forget you were about
to come and sleep here?
Was that a reason to hide who she was?
What do you mean, "hide"?
Did you warn me?
About what?
Should I have repeated gossip
so you'd go there unwillingly?
What happened?
I'm going, Babak.
Coming.
Go and see Rana,
you'll know what happened.
They told me she slipped in the shower.
We even spoke about having a child there,
and you told us nothing.
You were joking.
Otherwise, you'd have told us?
Told you what? What's got into you?
Babak, put yourself in my shoes.
Imagine how many men
have passed through our bedroom.
Don't feel obligated.
I haven't cashed your check.
Once you find a place with
a previous tenant to your liking, leave.
Do what you like.
- Hello.
Mrs. Shahnazari,
be careful not to slip on the stairs,
they're wet.
In fact, I almost called the cleaner
to tell him to come earlier this week.
But I thought you'd go to the police,
and we had to leave the traces.
Nothing serious happened.
It's obvious you're not the one
who found your wife the other day,
otherwise you wouldn't say that.
When Mr. Alimoradi opened the door,
he thought your wife had had it.
Give her my regards.
Get up, I took the bread out.
- I'm going.
- Wait.
I'll get ready and come, too.
Where? I'm going to school.
I'll stay in the car.
It'll be a while.
Then don't go.
- What?
- Don't go today.
And tomorrow? And the day after?
It's not a solution.
I can't stay here alone.
I don't want to be here alone.
What can I do?
Do you want to go to your parents
for a few days?
Looking like this?
I decided this morning.
Either we go to the police,
or we forget this whole story.
Okay, let's forget it,
but we look for an apartment today.
We'll go.
But in the meantime, you should...
You could pull yourself together.
You think it's up to me?
Yes, you could take your pills
and not ruminate all night long.
Couldn't you? Go take a shower.
I'll stand outside, come on.
Not in that bathroom.
- We'll go to a friend's, then.
- I show up for a shower?
What should I do, then?
You blow hot and cold.
At night, I can't come near.
During the day, it's, "Don't go. "
- Tell me what I should do.
- Go.
We won't find a place right away.
But you won't shower till then,
with your wound?
Darling.
Tell yourself it could've been worse.
If you'd injured your eye,
or hit your head harder,
what would I have done?
I wish I had hit myself harder.
Don't say that, honey.
Move a bit.
Good morning, Mr. Etesami.
- Hello.
How are you?
Mr. Yeganeh said
to give you back these books.
Silence.
What's so funny?
Why?
He says they're inappropriate
for the students.
Silence! Hey!
Mr. Yeganeh said that?
Put them in the trash.
- Why?
- Because.
- Your phone.
- I don't have one.
- Give it to me.
Hold on, sir.
Give it to me.
- I didn't film you.
- I want to see.
I deleted it.
Give it to me.
I've got personal photos.
Hands off.
It's not fair.
Mr. Etesami.
It's private, sir.
I deleted it, sir.
I swear.
Put it online.
It's better than your film.
You be quiet, or you're out.
- Forgive him.
- Silence.
I'm talking to him.
I deleted it.
Please.
Call your father
to come and see your photos.
His father's dead, sir.
Hello, Daddy.
Did you buy me a surprise egg?
Sorry, couldn't find the key.
No problem.
To keep from bothering you each time,
you could leave it next to the boiler.
I'll tell my husband to park it better.
I'm saying that to keep you
from coming down each time.
Take my space for a couple of hours.
No, we'll find somewhere.
As you like.
Leave it, I'll park it.
My wife said you're not going to the police.
No.
You're right. What's the point?
You'll have to justify
letting him in.
There would be a trial
and all kinds of stories.
For nothing.
He'll end up coming for his pickup.
You'll let me know?
I want to see that jerk.
I'll move my car out
and come and park yours.
I'll do it.
Thanks. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
- How's it going?
- And you?
Is Rana there?
- She's not with you?
- No, on her own.
Any news of the guy?
What guy?
Your neighbors spoke to Babak.
- Is he here?
- Babak?
Yes, inside.
- Hi.
Why didn't you tell me?
- What?
- That the guy came to your place.
How's Rana?
The neighbors told you.
Poor things are worried.
Say nothing happened.
Why did you keep his pickup
in the parking lot?
Tell them we're looking for a place,
and we're leaving soon.
You think I'll let you leave?
Can you arrange a meeting with your tenant?
- Why?
- I want to speak to her.
I want to know why she did it.
Did what?
What she did.
She sent that guy to us.
Why would she do that?
You said she threatened you.
She's not like that.
It's just that
she's got nowhere for her things.
She said that because she was mad at me.
- Hi.
Feeling better?
Fine, thanks.
Did you tell them?
No.
How do they know?
A neighbor called Babak.
I don't know.
Emad, makeup's waiting for you.
My costume isn't there.
Kati's replacing you.
And you said nothing?
What could I say?
She's the director. It's her choice.
If you feel okay, go to makeup.
I'll talk to her.
Don't bother.
Did you see any apartments?
No, I'll go.
When I have time.
When you have time?
Do you know what I'm going through?
You did nothing.
You won't let me go to the police.
You said you'd find a replacement at school.
I couldn't find anyone.
Hmm.
Rana?
Yes?
Why aren't you playing tonight?
I don't feel well.
Why did you come, then?
I was bored at home.
What?
At home, I'm bored.
I'm bored here.
Want to come to my place?
Do you have SpongeBob?
No, but we'll buy it.
You have to come back tomorrow.
It's a mess. Everybody's screwing up.
Why?
We're all upset.
You're better, you can come back.
- Mommy, can I go to Rana's?
- No, sweetie.
Let him come, I'm all alone.
He'll be back tomorrow.
I can't.
His dad's taking him tomorrow night.
He can pick him up from our place.
- Do you want to go?
- Yes.
Will you be good?
He will.
Tell Emad we took the car.
I'll get his things.
- I need to go to the bathroom.
- Go, quick.
Whose bike is that?
A child's.
Where is he?
He's gone away.
Where?
Where did he go?
Another house. And the bathroom?
- I'm going.
- It's there.
The other side.
But...
It's all dark.
I'm coming.
It's scary in there.
Come on.
I don't want to now.
I'll come with you.
No, go away.
I'll do it myself.
Are you shy?
Can you do it yourself?
I'm coloring in his mustache.
Yes?
Come up, honey.
Who is it?
Emad.
If it's my daddy, say I'm not here.
Why?
Because it's Mommy I like.
Okay.
- Rana?
- Hi.
The pickup's gone.
I parked it outside.
Why?
I was fed up having to move it.
Hi.
Hey, big guy.
- Where's the key?
- Where you left it.
How's it going? Good to see you here!
Make yourself at home.
- Don't go and get it.
- I'll be back soon.
Emad...
Just let it be tonight.
I made a nice dinner.
Get changed and come and eat.
Come on, sweetie.
Ready for takeoff,
ladies and gentlemen.
Yay.
Sadra.
Yes?
Emad, it'll get cold.
Coming.
Go and wash your hands.
But my hands are clean.
Wash them again.
What a feast!
It looks delicious.
A real cordon bleu.
Hands off!
Rana, where are you?
Sadra, come quick!
Here I am
So, you two hit the town without me?
We went for a walk and did some shopping...
But we didn't find SpongeBob.
Too bad.
"Don't worry, Patrick!
"One fine day, we'll meet again,
"you and me. "
"You see that, SpongeBob?
"Rana made us pasta!"
- More?
- No, thanks.
You can have more later.
Thanks.
Yummy, pasta.
- Enjoy yourself.
- Eat up.
- What a cordon bleu.
- You're right.
How was the performance?
It was really
crappy.
Pathetic.
Yeah, sure.
That's how it is, without you.
Did you find the card?
No.
- How did you pay?
- With the money you left.
What money?
In the drawer.
What? Don't you like it?
It's not very good?
Don't eat it.
Why?
It's that bastard's money.
- Sadra, sweetie?
- Mmm.
Tell me...
- ... do you like pizza?
- Yes.
We'll order one. Don't eat that.
It's not good.
You want fries, too?
And ice cream?
Hi, call me when you can.
Hello, Mommy?
Mommy?
When are you...
Hello, Ahoo?
Are you there?
This is my third call.
Ahoo, darling, it's Babak.
Ahoo...
Are you there?
You're not there.
Okay.
Call me when you get home.
Even late.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Go to bed.
That's two nights now.
I can't sleep.
Why did you open her letters?
That's private.
I want to know who he is.
What for? He'll say it was a mistake.
A mistake?
He buzzed, I opened.
He must've thought it was her.
And when he realized his mistake,
why did he stay?
Because there was a woman in the shower.
- How would he know?
- Your clothes on the bed.
If I'd answered the damn intercom
and asked who it was,
he wouldn't have come up.
Okay, so go to the neighbors and explain
you should've answered.
- What business is it of theirs?
- They know.
That's all that matters?
What do you mean?
- The pickup's gone.
- What?
Sorry.
Where was it?
There.
Sorry.
- Where did you park it?
- There.
- There?
- Where the Peugeot is.
He's taken it.
I have to find that guy.
Asshole!
Okay, slow down.
You'll catch cold.
Don't be stubborn,
we can go to the public baths.
I'll be quick. Stay there.
- Hassanpour.
- Hello.
Hello, sir.
How are you?
Your father's at the
traffic office, isn't he?
He's retired now, why?
A guy ran over my wife and fled.
- Nothing serious?
- No, luckily.
Given the pickup's number,
could your father find his address?
His colleagues could. Give me the number.
But you have to report it first.
It's not too serious.
I don't want the police involved.
I'll call my father right away.
Get me a pen and paper.
Why don't you work for me?
What's the matter with you? I've got a job.
Why walk in here every week?
If you don't want me to walk in here...
I'm offering you a job.
I don't want your goddam job!
Move, Charley.
When are you going to grow up?
God damn you, Charley.
You big ignoramus.
How dare you?
If you say that to me again,
I'll rap you one.
To hell with your money!
Dirty rat!
What got into you?
What?
Making up lines.
Like what?
If something's wrong, tell me.
Instead of calling me a rat on stage.
It's not improvising, it's insulting.
You upset?
Absolutely.
Next time, I'll answer in public.
The rat's the one who insults.
I didn't know.
Excuse me.
The Bakery
Shalom.
Yes?
Two baguettes.
- Sliced?
- Yes, please.
- Is that your pickup?
- Why?
They're handing out tickets.
Majid, move the pickup,
or we'll get a ticket.
Soheyl, give me the keys.
Goodbye.
Goodbye. Here.
I'll take some water.
Hello, is this your pickup?
Yes.
Could you do a small move?
It's for deliveries.
Not now, later.
It's not my job.
- How about this weekend?
- I'm busy.
There's rental places nearby.
It's for books and paintings.
I don't want something open.
It's better with a cover.
I won't have time.
Name your price,
as long as it arrives safely.
I can't.
Majid, do him a favor.
Give me your number, I'll call you.
I'd rather it was you.
Go on, Majid, fix it for him.
Be careful.
What are you doing there?
Come here.
Be careful. Go easy.
Tell them to come for some tea.
That's nice of you.
Drink it while it's hot.
Where will you take it?
My parents' garage, for the time being.
She's not coming, then?
She's got problems. She can't find a place.
Babak's here for her things.
So?
Have you fallen out?
No, get him to take them, that's all.
Rana?
Majid? It's Mr. Etesami.
Are you free?
And Friday?
Who's there?
Come up.
Hello.
Hello, sir. How are you?
Is it here for the move?
Majid sent me.
Yes, come in. He's not with you?
He's busy. He sent me instead.
After you.
He didn't mention the stairs.
I've got a bad heart.
If I'd known,
I'd have said the elevator was broken.
I can't take elevators either.
May I have a glass of water?
Is there any help?
No, it's just a few boxes.
I was going to do it with him.
He's too busy, poor thing.
- He's your son?
- Son-in-law.
But it's like he's mine.
I'm sorry, we've just moved,
there's no glasses.
No problem.
Where are the boxes?
In the bedroom.
We'll see if we need a hand.
Call him. If he's nearby,
I'll go and get him.
Who?
Your son-in-law.
They've gone shopping for the wedding.
There's no janitor?
No, it's empty.
Some walls collapsed. We had to evacuate.
It's not going to fall on our heads?
Let's look and see if we need any help.
Sir?
Have a seat, I need to talk to you.
Listen, it's not my job.
Majid said you insisted,
and I agreed to come.
Give me whatever you like.
It's not that.
Sit down, I need to tell you something.
Nothing serious, I hope.
How long have you known him?
- My son-in-law?
- Yes.
- Why?
- To see if you know him well.
He's been courting my daughter
for two years.
Have you made inquiries about him?
Do you know Majid?
Tell me anything you know.
My wife and I moved into a new apartment.
And the previous tenant
was a woman
with lots of acquaintances, as it were.
One night I hadn't got back yet,
my wife was alone.
Some bastard,
thinking he was going to see her,
came into my home.
My wife was in the bathroom and he went in.
Who?
Your son of a bitch of a son-in-law.
How do you know it was him?
My wife started yelling,
and he ran off, forgetting his pickup.
I tracked him down
and went to the shop where he works.
I almost grabbed him in
front of his buddies,
to humiliate him in public.
But...
I couldn't do it.
- Other people use the pickup.
- That's why I want to see him.
I want to know if it was him
or somebody else.
Majid's not like that.
If I find out it was him,
I'll cancel the wedding.
How is your wife?
That's bad.
I'll talk to him this evening.
Call him and tell him to come.
I want to ask him who it was.
He's buying wedding stuff
with my wife and daughter.
Well, call him
and ask him who had the pickup that night.
When was it?
Two weeks ago.
Okay, let me speak to him tonight.
But I want to speak to him...
Wait. I want to speak to him.
Call him.
I don't have his number.
I've got it.
I want you to tell him to come,
so I don't have to go to his shop.
First, let me make sure it was him.
I need to speak to him...
Otherwise I'll call myself.
Shall we do that?
I'll call.
Majid? Hello, son.
Where are you?
Yes, at the gentleman's.
Who are you with?
Call me when you're alone.
We need to talk.
At my number.
I don't know it. Ask Mojgan.
Okay.
Nothing serious.
Bye.
He'll call when he's alone.
What do you do?
I work with Majid's pickup.
I sell clothes by the roadside
in the evenings.
I don't go out during the day
because of my heart.
Tell me something,
how come you don't have
your son-in-law's number?
Well, I don't.
I don't have many numbers.
Have you just changed phones?
No.
How come he doesn't have your number?
You told him to ask somebody, didn't you?
I don't know...
I'm so upset, I don't even know who I am.
- Wait.
- It's locked?
Wait for a bit.
Could you take off your shoes?
What for?
I want to see your feet.
I could be your father! Let me go!
Fine, no need to get excited.
Take them off and I'll let you go.
Why should I? Open this door!
Come here.
Please. Come here.
Sit, and take off your shoes.
Sit down.
Go on, sit.
- Take them off.
- I don't feel well.
I'll help you.
I'll do it.
The other one, too.
Okay.
The socks.
- What do you want with me?
- Take them off.
I'll do it for you.
Let me do it.
Yes, Siavash?
No.
I'm busy.
What's the time?
I won't be long, don't worry.
She'll make her own way.
She's got things to do.
Yes, I'm fine.
See you later.
I swear I didn't want to bother anybody.
Did that woman ask you to come?
She'd been texting me for a month.
"If you've got the pickup, drop by,
I've got a favor to ask. "
And I replied, "Ahoo, dear,
"sorry, I'm sick, I can't come. "
She got annoyed.
She wouldn't answer my texts or calls.
She was sulking.
That night, I wanted to make up...
You didn't know she'd left?
No, on my children's heads.
You went into the apartment,
you must've seen it had changed.
I saw the mess, the bike I got the kid...
I thought she was moving.
Tell the truth and you can go.
If I'd have thought you moved in,
I'd have been afraid a
man was in the shower.
My wife's clothes were on the bed.
I saw nothing.
You saw there was a woman alone,
and she let you in...
I didn't see any clothes.
It happened really fast.
I came in, there was no one.
And your wife had just let me in.
Why did she open the door?
She thought it was me.
I'm telling you straight.
I went to the bathroom door
and called the kid.
Then she started screaming.
- I took off.
- You went in.
I didn't.
- How did you cut yourself, then?
- No idea.
Downstairs, my foot hurt.
I guess I cut myself on the stairs.
- So my wife's lying?
- She says I went in?
If she'd not flung herself
at the glass in fear,
what would you have done to her, bastard?
I swear to you,
I fled when I realized my mistake.
Ask your wife.
I'll stay here, bring her.
To say what?
She's already said it all.
It's your wife's turn.
Call her and tell her to come.
- Why?
- You can repeat it all to her.
I swear I didn't go in the bathroom.
Okay.
Explain to your wife why you were there.
Call her.
Get your phone out.
Get it, I'm telling you.
Don't humiliate me in front of my family.
Call her.
- My daughter's getting married.
- She should know her father.
I'll tell your son-in-law everything
so he knows his father-in-law.
I don't need you, get lost.
I'll call your son-in-law to tell him...
Leave me alone!
Help!
Shut it.
Open the door!
I'm dying.
- Don't make any noise.
- Open up.
I'm going to faint.
Open up.
I'm claustrophobic.
Please, open up.
At least, turn on the light.
My dear,
forgive me,
I can't cry.
Why did you ever do that?
I don't understand it, Willy.
Help me.
It's like you're on another trip.
I keep expecting you.
Willy,
I made the last payment on the house,
today.
And there'll be nobody home.
We're free and clear.
We're free at last.
Lock the door and take the key.
Get up.
Up.
Wait.
Sit here.
Go into the bedroom.
You see how upset you've made her?
There's my wife.
Are you still saying you didn't go in?
Forgive me.
Answer me.
I behaved badly.
Why did you go in the bathroom?
I was tempted.
Emad.
What are you going to do to him?
His family is on the way.
I want his wife to know.
Emad.
You're taking revenge.
Let him go.
I know what I'm doing.
Just stay there.
Where are you going?
I feel really sick. Let me go.
They're coming.
Your son-in-law called. I told him to come
with your wife.
They're coming, sit down.
Please, let me go.
Repeat it to them and you can go.
I'm begging you...
Madam,
forgive me.
Let me go before they arrive.
We've been married for 35 years.
Go on, sir, leave.
Sit down.
Let him go.
He's going.
He'll leave with his family.
- Stay seated.
- Pity...
- Go.
- Stay seated.
My children...
- Leave him.
- Don't interfere.
Sit down.
Sit down, I said!
Sit there.
What do you want?
My God!
Emad!
Is there some
medicine he can take?
Nothing in his pockets.
Where are you?
No, come as fast as you can.
Fine.
- That's the ambulance?
- No, his family.
Can you hear me?
Can you find a pulse?
Is his heart beating?
Calm down, please.
- Where are you going?
- To look for pills in his car.
Sir...
Can you hear me? Open your mouth.
Can you hear me?
Feeling better?
Breathe.
Do you feel better?
Don't be scared, he's better.
You didn't call an ambulance?
No, I was afraid he was dead.
Wait...
If you talk to his family,
it's over between us.
The elevator doesn't work.
Come on, Mother.
Go ahead. I can't go up quickly,
it's too sore.
My dear.
In here.
Father...
How are you?
- Majid...
- Yes, come on.
Daddy...
He's fine, thank God.
You okay, Daddy?
You look okay. You gave us quite a scare.
Where's Mom?
- Coming.
- Majid, tell her not to come up.
We're going soon.
Majid, let her come up.
It'll reassure her to see him.
Good evening. Sorry, in all the
panic we didn't greet you...
Stay seated, don't get up.
I want Mom to see you, then we'll go.
There's no rush.
Let him get his breath back.
We're very sorry.
Daddy, stay seated.
Can you manage?
Yes, it's okay.
Sit down.
Majid...
Yes, Mother, we're here.
Luckily, Father is here, safe and sound.
What's up, Daddy?
Hmm?
Nothing, sweetie, it's fine.
- Mother?
- How is he?
He's fine.
I told you not to go.
See what you do to us.
My God...
Thanks be to God...
I prayed all the way
to hear his voice again.
Thanks be to God.
I told you not to go.
I don't want you working anymore.
Don't work anymore.
You said, "It's for Majid,
I'll be back soon. "
Now look.
You should thank these people
for helping him.
He was lucky.
We don't know how to thank you.
Thanks so much, madam.
Excuse us.
This man is my whole life.
Thank you very much.
You've given me back my life.
He's everything to me.
Stop it, Mom.
Come on, let's go.
Sorry.
Have you got everything?
Your phone?
The car keys.
- And his glasses, where are they?
- I've got them.
Come, I'll give them to you.
- I'll take them.
- Go on.
He has to come himself.
We have an account to settle.
Come.
What account?
You saved his life.
We gave you so much trouble...
...you don't owe us anything.
Please come.
I can come, if you like.
No, it should be him.
Come, please.
Go on down.
Majid, leave me.
How much did you leave the other night?
How much?
I didn't count it.
What's wrong?
What's wrong with you?
My God...
He's not well again.
What's this?
Where did that come from?
Is it your heart, Daddy?
Take my bag.
Sit there.
He's going to sit down.
It's not good.
Majid, come quick.
We're almost there.
I'm here, dear.
- Esmat...
- Mother.
Easy.
Be careful, Majid.
Esmat.
I'm here, dear.
Stretch his legs out.
Can you hear me, Daddy?
Help!
Can you hear me?
Where are his pills?
Search his pockets.
Breathe.
See if his pills are upstairs.
Lie down.
Wait.
Madam!
- What is it?
- Are his pills there?
He collapsed on the stairs.
Do a heart massage,
till the ambulance arrives.
Please, sir, come quick.
Do what I said.
Arms straight on the chest.
Okay.
Lay him on his back.
He's on his back.
One hand on the other,
on his chest, your arms straight.
- His face is blue.
- Please, sir!
If you're tired,
have someone take over.
He's not moving.
No, no reaction.
- Arms and legs?
- Nothing.
Should we give him his pills?
No, nothing.
Keep doing what I said.
Arms straight.
Hurry, please.
- Where is he?
- Inside.