THE PASSION OF JOAN OF ARC
In Paris, the library
of the Chamber of Deputies
holds one of the most extraordinary
documents in the history of the world:
the minutes of the trial
of Joan of Arc,
a trial which ended
in her sentencing and death.
In it, the judges' questions and Joan's
answers are meticulously recorded.
Reading it, we discover Joan
as she really was.
Not the Joan in helmet and armor,
but simple and human.
A young woman who died for her country.
We witness an astounding drama:
a young, deeply religious woman
attacked by a horde of blinded
theologians and experienced lawyers.
I swear to tell the truth,
the whole truth...
nothing but the truth.
In France, they call me Joan.
In my village,
they called me Joanie.
How old are you?
Nineteen. I think.
Do you know the Lord's Prayer?
Who taught it to you?
My mother.
Would you recite the Lord's Prayer?
You claim to have been sent by God?
To save France.
That's why I was born.
So you think
God hates the English?
I know nothing of God's love or hatred
for the English...
but I know the English will
all soon be driven out of France...
except those who die here!
You said Saint Michael appeared to you.
What did he look like?
Did he have wings?
Was he wearing a crown?
How was he dressed?
How could you know
if it was a man or a woman?
Was he naked?
Do you think
God is unable to clothe him?
Did he have long hair?
Why would he have cut it?
Why do you wear men's clothes?
If we give you women's clothes,
will you wear them?
When the mission God gave me
is finished,
I will wear women's clothes again.
So it was God who commanded you
to wear men's clothes?
And what reward do you hope
to gain from Our Lord?
The salvation of my soul.
You blaspheme God.
This is disgraceful.
To me, she is a saint.
Did God promise you anything?
That has nothing to do
with your trial.
Shouldn't we let
the judges decide that?
Would you like
to put it to a vote?
Well, then!
What did God promise you?
Perhaps he told you
you'd be freed from prison?
When?
I know neither the day...
nor the hour.
She doesn't want to make a confession,
so we must use wiles to get it.
Fetch a letter bearing
King Charles's signature.
I will dictate the letter.
I have such compassion for you!
Can you recognize
your king's signature?
I have a letter from him
for you.
I don't know how to read.
"To our dear, beloved Joan...
I make ready to march upon Rouen
with a great army.
I send you this devoted priest.
Trust him."
As Jesus is God's son,
do you consider yourself God's daughter?
Now will you recite
the Lord's Prayer?
Did God tell you
you'd be freed from prison?
Yes, through a great victory!
Did God promise
you'd go to heaven?
So you are certain
of your salvation?
Be careful,
that's a dangerous answer.
So if you are sure of your salvation,
you have no need of the Church?
Are you in a state of grace?
Well, now! Answer!
If I am,
may God keep me there.
If I am not,
may God bestow His grace upon me!
Sir...
allow me to hear Mass.
Joan, if we allow you
to hear Mass...
will you lay aside
your men's clothes?
So you prefer your men's clothes
to hearing Mass?
That immodest garb...
abominable to God.
You are no daughter of God.
You are a servant of Satan!
Prepare the torture.
She sure looks
like a daughter of God.
In the torture chamber.
Look at your judges.
Are not these learned doctors
of the Church wiser than you?
But God is wiser still!
Listen, Joan, we know your revelations
do not come from God...
but from the devil.
How do you tell a good angel
from a bad angel?
You kneeled before Satan,
not Saint Michael!
Don't you see it's the devil
who has confused you...
tricked you...
and betrayed you?
I think she's ready to sign
the letter of abjuration!
The Church opens its arms to you.
If you refuse, the Church will abandon you
and you will be alone.
Alone!
Yes, alone.
Alone with God!
Even if you tear my soul from my body,
I will renounce nothing.
And if I do say anything, afterward,
I'll say you forced it out of me!
She must not die
a natural death.
She is very weak.
She is feverish.
She must be bled.
Be careful, she could kill herself.
She's very cunning.
Get the Sacraments.
You have nothing to say to us?
I fear I'm in great danger of dying...
and if I do,
I ask to be buried in holy ground.
The Church is merciful.
It always welcomes its lost sheep.
Joan, we all want to help you.
You see,
I've sent for the Holy Sacrament.
I am a good Christian.
Don't you know that what you refuse
is the Body of Christ?
Can't you see that you offend God
with your stubbornness?
I love and honor God
with all my heart.
You say that I am sent by the devil.
That is not true.
It is you who are sent by the devil
to make me suffer.
And you.
There's nothing left to do.
Summon the executioner!
For the last time,
let us try to save this lost soul.
I'm speaking to you, Joan.
And I tell you
your king is a heretic!
My king is the most noble
of all Christians.
This woman's arrogance is outrageous.
Never has France seen
such a monster.
I never hurt anyone.
If you don't sign,
you'll be burned alive.
Look, the executioner awaits.
You don't have the right to die.
Your king still needs your help.
Joan, sign...
and save your life!
Joan, we have such pity for you.
Sign, Joan!
In the Lord's name.
Amen.
As you have admitted your errors, we free
you from the bonds of excommunication.
But because you have rashly sinned,
we condemn you...
to perpetual imprisonment with the bread
of sorrow and the water of affliction.
You have done well this day:
You have saved your life and your soul.
She made fools of you!
Long live Joan!
Fetch the judges!
I repent. I lied.
Hurry!
I've done something very bad.
I betrayed God to save my life.
But, Joan, before the people
you admitted
you'd been led by the devil.
So you still believe
you are God's chosen one?
That answer is her death sentence.
I only confessed
out of fear of the flames.
Do you have anything else
to tell us?
We have come
to prepare you for death.
Is it time... already?
How am I to die?
At the stake.
I'll get the viaticum.
Tell me, how can you still believe
you were sent by God?
God moves in mysterious ways.
Yes, I am His child.
And the great victory?
My martyrdom!
And your freedom?
Death!
Do you wish to make confession?
RELAPSED HERETIC,
APOSTATE, IDOLATER
Joan, be brave.
Your last hour is near.
Sweet God,
I accept death gladly...
but don't let me suffer too long.
Will I be with You
tonight in paradise?
Jesus!
You have burned a saint!
The protective flames surrounded
Joan's soul as she rose to heaven.
Joan, whose heart
has become the heart of France.
Joan, whose memory
will be honored by the French forever.
THE END
This film was restored in 2015 by Gaumont
with funding from the Centre national
du cinéma et de l'image animée.
The restoration was based on a copy
printed by the Cinémathèque Française
for reconstruction of the film in 1985.
As the original negative was lost,
it was printed from a nitrate copy
conserved at the Danish Film Institute.
The Danish intertitles were translated
into French by Maurice Drouzy.