Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
ACKNOWLEDGEMENTS
Maharaja of Burdwan, Mr. Amiya Haldar
Lady Ranu Mukherjee, Mr. Rabindranath Halder
Mrs. Krishna Kejriwal, Dr. Mihir Mitra
Mr. Nawal Kishore Kejriwal, Mr. Kamal Ghosh
Mr. Amiya Mukherjee, Mr. Asit Choudhury
Mrs. Manjul Banerjee, Mr. Parimal Ray
Mr. Sourish Roy, Mr. Nilmani Roy
Mr. Suvo Thakur
Mr. Prashanta Roy
Dr. Adi Gajdar, Mr. Dipankar Sarkar
Mrs. Roshon Gajdar, Mr. Gaur Kishore Ghosh
Mrs. Chitra Pal Chawdhury
Mr. Dijendranath Basu, Mrs. Gopa Ghoshal
Mrs. Parimalhasini Ghosh, Mrs. Phyllis Bose,
Bourne and Shepherd, Mr. Kamu Mukherjee
Zoom Sixteen, Mr. Joy Mitra
Mr. Ajit Ghosh, Mr. Udit Roy
The lmambara of Metiabruz, Mr. Sudipto
Chattapadhaya, lndian Tobacco Co.
Calcutta Police Training School
Subdivisional Officer, Diamond Harbor
District Magistrate, 28 Parganas
Chakdighi Panchayat Samiti
District Magistrate, Bankura
Jamalpur Panchayat Samiti
District Magistrate, Burdwan
Somsar Panchayat Samiti
Residents of Somsar, Goho,
Chakdighi and Jamalpur villages
The National Film Development
Corporation of lndia presents
THE HOME AND THE WORLD
A film by Satyajit Ray
from the novel by Rabindranath Tagore
with Soumitra Chatterjee,
Victor Banerjee, Swatilekha Chatterjee
Gopa Aich, Manoj Mitra,
Jennifer Kapoor
Bimala Chatterjee,
lndrapramit Roy
Cinematography by Soumendu Roy
Art Direction by Ashoke Bose
Film Editing by Dulal Dutta
Makeup by Ananta Das
Screenplay, Music and Direction
by Satyajit Ray
I have passed through fire.
What was impure in me
has been burned to ashes.
What remains, I dedicate to him,
to the man who accepted aII my faiIings
in the depths of his stricken heart.
Now I know there is no one eIse Iike him.
It was 1 0 years ago when I first met him.
He was the son of a nobIe famiIy,
and I was his bride.
I heard that my husband
was of a gentIe disposition.
I considered myseIf fortunate.
Not every bride is so Iucky.
When I joined the famiIy, my sister-in-Iaw
was aIready a widow, wearing white.
Though it was never mentioned,
I couId see that she had never enjoyed
the pIeasures of a happy maritaI Iife.
Our rooms were in the inner
apartments of the paIace.
A passage with stained-gIass windows
Ied to the outer apartments.
The door of this passage
aIways remained cIosed to us.
I didn't mind the confinement,
because I was raised
to foIIow traditionaI vaIues.
But my husband had modern views.
He was the first in his famiIy
to receive a Western education.
He appointed Miss GiIby
to make a memsahib out of me.
Why did you have to come here?
Soon even the cIothes I wore
began to refIect Miss GiIby's infIuence.
English clothes, English songs.
Soon we won't even seem related.
-- You still haven't told me how l look.
-- Very nice.
Pretty as a picture.
You're a lucky one.
You should grab
your good fortune with both hands.
Few brides have known
happiness in this family.
Some barely knew their husbands' faces,
let alone the face of happiness.
l used to wait up for him all night,
hoping he'd come to me.
For two whole days before he died,
l stayed by his bedside.
He was almost unconscious,
dazed with fever.
He was burning hot.
Suddenly, he opened his eyes and said,
''Who are you?''
He didn't even recognize his own wife.
l wonder if you realize
how lucky you are.
Why wouldn't l?
Don't l know my own --
Look who's here.
We were just talking about you.
Really?
l thought only little girls
played with dolls.
Now l see even grown men do.
-- What do you mean?
-- She's dolling herself up for you.
Can't you see?
-- l see.
She's going to make
your dreams come true.
Well, men must have
their little fantasies.
lsn't that true, sister--in--law?
Enjoy them.
l'll look on from the wings.
From the wings? Why?
What's the harm in staying here?
lt's better that way.
ln my day, we used attar.
These foreign perfumes
make me feel sick.
l'll be going now.
Are these clothes all new?
The tailor brought them today.
They're all my own design.
l can see that.
You dress up so beautifully for me.
ls it right that l should be
the only man to admire you?
You think l would dress up
for any other man?
Why any other man?
l'm just thinking of the ones
l've sung your praises to.
You think they're dying
to catch a glimpse of me?
-- You know something?
-- What?
ln the past, confining women
to the house wasn't a Hindu custom.
Sita, Sabitri, Draupadi...
None of them were confined.
So what?
Your Bimala is happy here.
Did you know that women used
to choose their own husbands?
Have you heard of that?
Why are you laughing?
lf l'd had a choice,
l might not have chosen you.
l know.
But you didn't have a choice.
How sad.
l'm envious...
of Draupadi...
and her five husbands.
All your life, you've only
set eyes on one man.
How can you know
what kind of man he is
if you can't compare him with others?
You aren't trying to bring back
the classical age, are you?
What for?
Still, l see no logic in confining women.
l think the Muslims introduced the custom.
Hindus never cared about it.
Do you think people will reject
this custom just because you say so?
lt's not the people
l'm thinking of, Bimala.
You know l'm not like other people.
l don't think tradition
should be followed blindly.
l would be really proud
if l could persuade you
to meet my friends.
You mean him?
Sandip is a genius.
l have no intention of meeting someone
who's constantly asking you for money
on one pretext or another.
Sandip is working
for the good of our nation.
He's gifted, but has no money.
lf my money contributes to his good deeds,
that's to my advantage.
For the good of our nation?
What does he do?
The Swadeshi movement.
Do you know about it?
-- Of course.
They often talk about it these days.
Boycott foreign goods.
Buy only lndian goods.
Don't buy foreign salt or sugar.
Buy our own.
You know so much.
l read the newspaper.
-- Do you know why?
-- l do.
Tell me.
Come. Sit down here and tell me.
Yes, master.
Tell me what's behind
the Swadeshi movement.
The governor--general
has split Bengal in two.
Hindus and Muslims
used to live together in peace,
but he's driven a wedge between them.
You seem to forget
that your wife is educated.
l speak English.
Why wouldn't l know all this?
Sandip is a leader
of the Swadeshi movement.
lsn't their mantra, ''Hail Motherland''?
Yes.
This mantra has set
the whole nation on fire.
Except for one person.
lt hasn't set him on fire.
lt takes a lot to set me on fire, Bimala.
Although...
l certainly don't approve
of Lord Curzon's decision.
Turning Hindus and Muslims
against each other...
l think it's criminal.
Don't the Swadeshi burn foreign clothes?
Yes, they do.
lf they got hold of your sari,
they'd burn it.
-- Really?
-- Yes.
Do you know where
this thread comes from?
Where?
-- Really?
-- Yes.
Most of the articles
on your dressing table are imported.
This brush is an import,
the mirror, the comb.
Your hairpins are imported.
These perfumes are French.
Even these bottles
are imported cut glass.
The table's foreign too.
Most of the furniture in here
comes from Lazarus.
lt's a foreign company.
Really?
We never even gave it a thought.
What do you think we should do?
Why not ask Sandip?
He's coming here.
-- Really?
-- Yes.
-- When?
-- Shortly.
He'll be my guest.
He's holding a meeting
in our courtyard.
l think you'll enjoy meeting him.
Why?
Something about him appeals to women.
He's had quite a few affairs.
And not all the women
believed in Swadeshi.
But he's not married, is he?
He says he has no time for it.
Married life doesn't suit him.
He has a restless nature,
unlike me.
Why would l enjoy
meeting your opposite?
You may not enjoy it...
but you may find it instructive.
l'm happy in my confinement.
l have no wish to be like Sita or Sabitri.
I was unprepared for what
foIIowed in the next few days.
I was shocked by Miss GiIby's story.
It was a Sunday,
so she had gone to church.
On her way back,
a IocaI schooIboy hit her
on the head with a stone.
It seemed to be
the infIuence of the Swadeshi.
The peopIe began to feeI
so much hatred towards the British
that Iife became dangerous even
for innocent peopIe Iike Miss GiIby.
I was toId I couId no Ionger
become a memsahib.
Miss GiIby Ieft.
A few days Iater,
the Swadeshi arrived.
Hail Motherland!
Over there.
Do you see him?
-- Where?
Those boys are carrying him
on their shoulders.
Hail Motherland!
Friends...
you all know why
we're assembled here tonight.
For the past few days,
Bengal has been facing
a serious crisis.
Lord Curzon, the governor of lndia,
with one strike of his diplomatic sword,
has severed our golden Bengal in two.
ln East and West Bengal,
our two religious groups
have been united by a spirit
of solidarity, friendship and fraternity,
and this solidarity has become a source
of grave concern for our rulers.
The partition has cut
at the very roots of this solidarity.
Now we all understand
what the policy of our rulers is:
''Divide and rule.''
They wish to create a rift between
our two religious communities
and thereby strengthen
their own position.
The power of our English rulers
is matched only by their arrogance.
The political leaders of Bengal
have risen as one against the partition,
but our rulers have paid no heed to them.
We lacked the means to prevent
our rulers from fulfilling their plans,
but they failed to realize that
we can fight politics with politics.
The strategy we have adopted
will not only confound our rulers,
but it will also ultimately
benefit our nation
and bring prosperity
and independence to our people.
This is how Swadeshi works.
l call upon all of you,
men and women,
rich and poor,
rulers and subjects,
to take a solemn vow
to reject and boycott all foreign goods
from this moment on
and accept only lndian goods.
Until now our rulers
have blocked all our attempts
to develop our own resources.
We have been forced
to buy their foreign cloth,
their foreign salt
and their foreign sugar.
Have you ever considered
how many everyday items
are being made here?
l don't know if you've seen
the big foreign stores in Calcutta.
l have.
They enjoy staggering prosperity
and a profusion of goods.
Don't we have the right to ask
why our wealth should fill
the coffers of our foreign rulers?
Who gave them the right
to exploit us like this?
ls this not at the root
of our nation's poverty?
ls it not our duty to put
an end to this extortion?
Has not the time come
to abolish this shame?
lf we remain indifferent to these crimes,
if we do nothing,
if these foreigners continue
to steal away all our nation's wealth,
what kind of future
can we expect for our country?
So l say to you, my brothers,
the time has come to rise up against
the arrogance of the English government.
We must not hesitate any longer.
Let us all take the Swadeshi oath.
And the great cry from the heart
that will launch us on this task,
the sacred mantra that
will rock the throne of our rulers,
let us all chant that mantra,
and, braving all peril,
dedicate ourselves
to the service of the Motherland.
Hail Motherland!
-- Hail Motherland!
Still singing English songs after
that impassioned nationalistic speech?
What should l sing, then?
Kirtan, Shyama Sangeet,
Nidhu Babu's tappa.
GentIy she waIks,
the beauteous one
Radiant as the moon,
l must say, he is a good speaker.
He knows how to turn a phrase.
He was good at debate in college.
Her smiIe sends rippIes of deIight
All those boys wearing saffron
were a pretty sight.
That make the Iove god swoon
How long is he staying?
He's going to Rangpur tomorrow.
He has some business there.
Do you want to meet him?
l have nothing to say.
What's the point?
You don't have to say anything.
He'll do all the talking.
What if he asks me about Swadeshi?
Then answer him.
He certainly made sense.
Tell him so.
l'm sure he'll be shocked
if l wear one of my fancy dresses.
What do you think l should wear?
On November 1 5, 1 907,
the young mistress of the Choudhury house
defied aII convention
and stepped into the passage
Ieading to the outer apartments.
Greetings.
Your speech has inspired my wife
to take up the Swadeshi cause.
-- You must be joking, Nikhil.
-- No, it's true.
Come.
Have a seat.
Have a seat, Sandip.
What's the matter with you?
Have a seat.
At first, l couldn't believe my eyes.
Now, l can't believe my ears.
My husband is exaggerating a bit.
Even if only a fraction of what he said
is true, l'll be more than happy.
No matter what l may
accomplish as a politician,
you have already achieved
a social revolution.
l know how important that is.
l also realize that,
although Nikhil's your husband,
you're not his mere shadow.
You have a mind of your own.
Nikhil doesn't take my words
to heart, but you did.
lf you keep on like that,
she'll be walking on air.
lt's no use telling me that.
As a politician, l'm utterly shameless
about seeking support for my cause.
l have never succeeded
in persuading a woman,
but should that ever happen,
l'd be delighted.
lt would be an honor
to have a woman in our ranks.
Women have a rare quality
which we call intuition.
l admire it greatly.
Man's ability to reason
pales beside it.
What do you say, Nikhil?
Why don't you tell him
what you thought of his speech?
Oh, yes.
That's what l was going to ask you.
Tell me...
did it sound like total drivel to you?
Come on. Don't hesitate.
l haven't had much time to think about it.
That's precisely why l'm asking you.
Why do you have to think?
Thinking is his task.
Just tell me what comes from your heart.
Forget about rationality.
l didn't understand much, but...
l feel that if the English
have done wrong by splitting up Bengal,
we should not let it pass.
lf Swadeshi can shake them up
a bit, then we should do it.
Of course, if only a few people take up
the cause, it won't have any impact.
But if the whole country joins in,
then we may succeed.
Exactly!
Exactly.
That's exactly what we're trying to do.
We want to awaken the nation
with our mantra, ''Hail Motherland!''
Don't you think there's magic
in those two words?
Have you ever said them?
You should.
You don't need to shout it.
Just whisper it.
As a matter of fact,
when you all shouted that mantra,
l felt a --
A thrill?
A shiver down my spine.
That's how it should be.
Did you know that your husband
doesn't believe in our mantra?
lsn't that right, Nikhil?
-- l don't believe in propaganda.
Propaganda?
What do you mean by that?
lf you're recruiting people who have never
cared about their country's problems before,
how can you do it
without using propaganda?
But the cause must come first, Nikhil.
That's all that matters.
Commitment to the cause
will come through inspiration,
and the inspiration
will come from our mantra.
Don't you remember the significance of
''La MarseiIIaise" in the French Revolution?
What we need most today
is to rouse the people to action.
Our poets are writing Swadeshi songs.
Their sole purpose is to inspire the people.
Have you ever heard any?
Do you think you are strong enough
to break destiny's bonds?
Are you that strong?
Do you think you are strong enough
to break destiny's bonds?
Are you that strong?
Just because you
hoId the power over us
You take so much pride
Why do you take so much pride?
Do you think you are strong enough
to break destiny's bonds?
Are you that strong?
Just because you
hoId the power over us
You take so much pride
Why do you take so much pride?
Do you think you are strong enough
To keep us back forever?
To hoId us down forever?
You don't have that much strength
Your strength wiII not withstand us
Do you think you are strong enough
to break destiny's bonds?
Are you that strong?
You may try to govern us
But even the weak can summon strength
You may pride
yourseIf on your might
But God is stiII mightier
Rob us of our strength
and you dig your own grave
Your boat wiII sureIy sink
Under the weight of your own guiIt
Do you think you are strong enough
to break destiny's bonds?
Are you that strong?
Just because you
hoId the power over us
You take so much pride
Why do you take so much pride?
Do you think you are strong enough
to break destiny's bonds?
Are you that strong?
l admit it's a beautiful song.
Oh, my. What's all this?
Swadeshi tea. Darjeeling.
But there's a lot more here than just tea.
You should have
some sweets too, not just tea.
They're not only Swadeshi,
Bimala made them herself.
-- Really?
-- Yes.
Then l have to try one.
l haven't gotten over
my weakness for sweets yet.
Nor your weakness
for foreign cigarettes, l see.
Out of the question.
Are you familiar
with the Swadeshi brands?
Unthinkable!
-- Can't you give it up?
-- Smoking?
Don't you have the willpower?
Okay. Join our party,
and l'll stop smoking.
Any sugar?
One teaspoon if it's foreign,
two if it's lndian.
So tell me...
what are your plans?
They're not settled yet.
Your neighbor, the land owner
Harish Kundu, has sent for me.
They're having a bonfire
of foreign clothes at his place.
He wants me to help run the event,
so l must go there at once.
Madam Bimala,
did you know that the only stumbling
block left is your husband?
He refuses to help the cause.
You'll find many landed gentry
around here who support Swadeshi.
What's the harm
in leaving my estate out of it?
You see?
Did you see that?
Not even a shred of patriotism in him.
Ah, well.
So...
will you join our cause?
Don't worry.
You don't have to sign
a pledge or anything.
You'll stay exactly as you are.
l'll come to you if need be.
Well?
Yes or no?
All right.
l should be going now.
-- Do you have to?
-- Yes, l have work to do.
My boys are waiting downstairs.
Madam Bimala, this is truly
a memorable day for me.
l only have one request.
Always trust your intuition.
Don't let this gentleman influence you.
Rest assured, Sandip.
From now on,
my wife is a free agent.
Wonderful!
Good. l'll be going then.
l'll see you out.
HaiI MotherIand!
Hail Motherland.
-- You haven't told me yet.
-- What?
What you thought of my friend.
But l only met him once.
l think the less one knows Sandip,
the better one likes him.
You seem to have so little in common.
l wonder how you managed
to become friends.
That's not unusual, Bimala.
Friendships aren't
worked out mathematically.
We've been friends since college.
lt's not like we have nothing in common.
We both decided to reject
the irrational conventions of our society.
He's always been more radical than l.
When his parents arranged a bride for him,
he was so annoyed
he severed all ties with them.
Shortly after we got married,
he asked me to introduce him to you.
He would remind me from time to time.
Finally, he said,
''l don't believe a word
you've said about your wife.''
And do you know what he said today?
-- What?
-- l'm not telling you.
-- Why not?
What can he say about you
after such a brief meeting?
l could say a lot more.
But you never do.
Do l have to?
Don't you have your intuition?
-- Madam.
-- What is it?
A Ietter from Mr. Mukherjee.
l hope the rule wasn't intended
to be broken for one day alone.
Can l see you for a moment?
-- Tell him l'm coming.
-- As you wish.
''When Krishna's flute beckons so,
how can l not go?''
Hail Motherland.
My husband's not here.
l didn't ask for him.
l asked for you.
Won't you sit down?
You've eluded me for years.
You mustn't keep your distance now.
Come and sit here,
right beside me.
What's the matter?
l can't believe it.
Ever since you married, Nikhil promised
he would introduce me to you.
l never believed him.
Even now, l find it hard to believe.
Until now, l've only heard about
your many accomplishments.
You learned English from a memsahib.
You love reading books, knitting, cooking.
l even know what you like to cook,
to eat, your favorite flowers.
l know everything.
l also know something else.
You resent the fact
that Nikhil lends me money.
So you really aren't a stranger to me.
But l never imagined...
l'd one day find myself
sitting by your side.
-- Did you go to Rangpur?
-- Yes, l did.
-- How was the trip?
-- Great.
That's why the first thing l wanted
to see this morning was you.
Don't you have to leave again?
-- Where to?
-- To Rangpur.
lsn't that your base?
That was the idea, but not anymore.
lt's not?
Let me be frank with you.
l want to be near you when l work.
Just like a bee working for the queen.
You'll be the queen bee.
Do you have any objection?
But won't you find it inconvenient
working from here?
That's true.
l don't think Nikhil will approve of this.
But the thing is...
l am essentially...
a stubborn man.
l just can't accept Nikhil's attitude.
l want to promote
the Swadeshi cause right here...
and l need your help.
But l really know nothing about your work.
l know that you
give speeches. ls that all?
That's one of the most important things.
Persuasion can work wonders.
Wait.
lf you really want to know about our work,
then read this.
OUR STRUGGLE
lt contains everything you need to know.
l will definitely read it.
May l tell you something now?
One of the biggest markets
in this area is here, in Sukhsayar.
Did you know that?
-- So l've heard.
lt's the only market in the area
where foreign goods are still being sold.
Elsewhere, the landowners
have prohibited their sale,
but Nikhil hasn't.
l'm going to do my best to change that,
but, with your help,
my task will be much easier.
l'm afraid you're overestimating
my capabilities.
Not at all.
Nikhil may be my friend,
but he's your husband.
You have much more influence
over him than l do.
My husband isn't easily swayed.
l know...
but l think he'll listen to you.
l know how much you mean to Nikhil.
Will you try just once to persuade him?
Nikhil's tenants wouldn't dare
to go against his will.
He only has to tell them not to bring
any more foreign goods to the market.
And if l fail to persuade him?
l'll be happy if you just try.
lf you fail, l'll find another way.
Not without the queen bee's
knowledge, of course.
Can l depend on you?
l'll try my best.
The more l see you,
the more l admire you.
l think l'll --
Okay, you may go now.
Oh, and one more thing.
This item of yours.
This is the only foreign item
l will keep with me.
Did you see Sandip today?
Yes.
How is he doing?
He's worried.
Why?
You won't let him promote
the Swadeshi cause here.
Nonsense.
You heard me yourself.
He's free to fight for his cause
as long as he leaves my estate alone.
He says he's staying here.
Staying here?
That's what he says.
He's going to stay and work here.
That wouldn't be right.
But all of Bengal has taken up
the Swadeshi cause.
Why don't you?
That would mean banning
all foreign goods from the market.
Harish Kundu can do that, but not me.
Surely the market belongs to you.
Why can't you?
lt's not my market, Bimala.
The market belongs to the traders
who sell their goods there.
They're poor.
Foreign goods are cheaper
and of better quality than lndian goods.
The poor villagers can afford them.
How can l force them not to buy them?
Swadeshi is for those who can afford it,
not for the poor.
What are you thinking?
Can we follow Swadeshi...
without making the poor suffer?
ls it possible?
lf it were possible,
l'd definitely support Swadeshi.
You believe the very idea
of Swadeshi is wrong.
Even if l do,
who would listen to me?
The entire country supports Swadeshi.
You yourself believe Sandip is right.
Many others must feel the same way.
But l believe that coercing the poor
can only harm our country.
l can see you're not convinced.
l was looking at it differently.
l was thinking that
something has to be done.
Even if it means
hardship for the poor now,
it will help them in the long run.
The Swadeshi care about this country.
l believe what they care about
is an abstract idea of this country,
this country as the Mother Goddess.
The nation is our mother.
Worship our mother,
work for our mother, pray to our mother.
Everything you do is for our mother.
Heal our mother's pain.
l can understand that.
And l can understand why
that idea appeals to women.
l know how you feel, Bimala,
but l don't feel the same way.
Those things you said tonight...
Were those your own thoughts?
Why are you asking me this?
l felt as if you were speaking for Sandip.
Sandip is your friend, not mine.
l thought you two had teamed up
''in right earnest'' to fight for a higher cause.
He's working on the public front,
and you on the domestic.
What an idea!
Will you have daily meetings?
You insisted that l meet your friend,
so you can spare me the insinuations.
l just asked a simple question.
l wasn't insinuating anything.
-- Very well.
lf it upsets you so much,
l won't go outside anymore.
You're mistaken, Bimala.
l'm not upset at all.
After all, l know you both so well.
Why shouldn't you go outside?
-- Because l don't want to.
You're being unreasonable.
l've been out twice already.
l don't have to go out every day.
Very well.
l won't restrict you
from going where you please.
As l told you,
you are completely free.
But l must tell you one thing.
lf you tell me you want to give up
wearing foreign clothes,
or do without your foreign
perfumes, shoes and soap,
l won't mind at all.
But clamping down on poor traders
by banning foreign goods in the market
means going against
my own beliefs and principles.
l could never do that, Bimala.
Swadeshi is something l can't take lightly.
The weak say, ''Whatever fate
has given to me is mine. "
And the impotent agree with them.
''OnIy what I can snatch away
by force is mine. "
That is what experience has taught us.
My country is not mine
simpIy because I was born here.
It becomes mine
onIy when I am abIe to win it by force.
OnIy then can the nation be mine.
This funeral pyre celebrates the cremation
of foreign trade in your village.
These ashes are sacred.
Hail Motherland!
AN URGENT MATTER
REGARDlNG OUR CAUSE
-- Please give this to Mrs. Choudhury.
-- Very well.
Madam isn't feeling well, sir.
l see.
-- You know the headmaster, don't you?
-- Yes, of course.
Good morning.
l hope you are doing well.
Not as long as you're around.
How come?
His students have all disappeared
since you arrived.
But you must admit that working
for one's country helps build character.
One of my students was influenced
by the Swadeshi movement.
He threw a stone at Mrs. Choudhury's
governess, Miss Gilby.
Would you consider that
an example of character building?
But that happened before l came.
You can't blame me for that.
After all, you must admit
that a few such incidents
are inevitable in times
of great social upheaval.
You even roped in my best student.
Who? Amulya?
He'd have won a scholarship
if he'd taken his exam.
You stole that opportunity from him.
Amulya? l didn't rope him in.
He joined of his own accord.
What about the other rowdy dissolutes
who have joined your team?
They're the worst troublemakers in the village.
They're not troublemakers anymore, sir.
They're fighting for the cause.
They're working hard.
With two exceptions,
everyone here is working for the cause.
One of them is you.
The other one is your former
student Nikhilesh Choudhury.
l regret that
l couldn't persuade him to join.
Like you, he turns a deaf ear
to the Swadeshi cause.
No, he isn't against Swadeshi ideals.
He's against your
destructive brand of Swadeshi.
He practiced Swadeshi long before you,
and he never relied
on any battle cries or mantras.
-- l know that.
-- You know nothing!
Do you know about his Swadeshi bank?
Or his Swadeshi sugar factory,
his soap factory?
Do you know he set up his own looms
for weaving Swadeshi cloth?
Where were you
and your ''Hail Motherland'' then?
Do you know how much
he spent for Swadeshi?
-- Please, headmaster --
-- You stay out of this!
These things must be said.
-- But that's what l keep telling him.
lf both of us have the same goals,
then why doesn't he join us?
You don't have the same goals.
There are many differences.
Your goal is power and leadership.
You don't care about the people!
Nikhil never thought about himself.
People are applauding you
and singing your praises.
Nikhil was ridiculed.
He had no head for business,
so his brand of Swadeshi didn't last.
But his way was the right way.
Yours is wrong.
lt's more than wrong.
lt's dangerous.
Give those to me.
l'll drop by this evening.
My goodness.
Please, Nikhil, l implore you.
Keep that headmaster away from me.
l came here to give speeches,
not listen to them.
Are you planning to stay here and work?
l'm going to speak
at your market this afternoon.
That's where our greatest
challenge lies, Nikhil.
Not where the landowner
is already in favor of Swadeshi,
but where he isn't.
But remember, Sandip,
most of my tenants are poor Muslims.
l don't want them harassed.
lf l see that happening,
l will be forced to intervene.
lf they prove to be obstacles
to our revolution,
l'll have to take the necessary measures.
Many Muslims have accepted Swadeshi.
They were forced to do so.
lt will happen here too.
l've said what l had to say.
What you do now is up to you.
As you all know,
our English rulers
have divided Bengal in two.
This amounts to erecting a wall
between Hindus and Muslims.
They have not given us
the right to break this wall,
but, to foil the government,
we have chosen a different path.
One important way to fight the partition
is to stop selling foreign goods
in our markets.
Salt, sugar, cloth and soap
are all everyday items
which are only available
as foreign products at your market.
By selling their foreign goods here,
the British are making
a lot of money in our country,
while we keep growing poorer.
This is wrong.
This must stop.
We've tolerated this up to now,
but no more.
l know that lndian substitutes
for foreign goods are not always available,
so you've had to trade with foreign goods
because that's all you had.
But if we can all make sacrifices
and produce our own goods,
then we will overcome these difficulties.
Brothers, we are depending on you.
lf you come forward and join us,
together we will stop
the partitioning of Bengal
and regain our pride.
And now, do you see
this circle here before me?
Throw all your foreign goods
into the circle of flags.
lndian substitutes will be made.
Many manufacturers
have come forward to help us.
Have no fear of losing your livelihood.
Today's loss will not be lost forever.
Now l ask you to throw all
of your foreign goods into the circle.
The land that gave birth to you,
the land that you love...
Now is the time to help her.
Foreign cloth, foreign thread,
foreign sugar, foreign salt,
foreign scissors and knives,
foreign matches,
and everything else foreign...
Throw them in that circle.
We beseech you.
Don't just sit there.
Help the Swadeshi cause.
We want to hear it from the maharaja!
Let him come here.
We won't listen to you!
Your maharaja is my friend.
l'm his guest.
lsn't that proof enough
that l have his support?
We're traders.
lf we have nothing to sell, we'll starve!
We've tried selling lndian goods.
Nobody buys them.
You're a gentleman.
You have money.
lt's easy for you to say,
''Don't sell foreign goods.''
We're poor!
How will we survive?
It's cIear that persuasion
won't work on NikhiI's estate.
We'II have to use other means.
Any compromise on foreign goods
wouId crippIe our movement.
HaiI MotherIand!
This is Mr. Kulada.
Greetings.
Please follow me.
Were those stolen from the villagers?
Have a seat.
You may enjoy your bonfire, but the villagers
will file a complaint against you.
We'll set fire to their crops if they do.
Can't we try picketing?
We can make them understand.
lt's worked in other places.
l know what works and what doesn't.
Picketing won't work in Sukhsayar.
Please sit, Mr. Kulada.
A foreign brand, l see.
Yes, it's the only exception
l make to Swadeshi.
-- May l have one?
-- Be my guest.
These people can't be persuaded, Amulya.
They've been pampered too much.
Listen, l've been the manager of this estate
since the maharaja's father was alive.
The father was a tough one.
The trouble is the son.
lf only he'd been firm with them,
he could have brought
these villagers to their knees.
lt would have been smooth sailing for you.
Anyway, tell me how you can help us.
lf you can't stop the influx
of foreign goods,
you can't stop the trade of foreign goods.
Those boats bring the goods in.
-- You'll have to deal with the boatmen first.
-- Can you do that for me?
The problem is that the boatmen's
leader is very stubborn.
Who is he?
What's his name?
Mirjan.
He's a hard nut to crack.
-- Can he be persuaded?
-- Where there's a will, there's a way.
A boat which sails
is also a boat which sinks.
But it's going to take
more than words to do this job.
lt will take...
-- Money?
We have to stop tongues from wagging,
pay compensation,
bribe the police.
That all takes money.
lt's not like we don't have any money,
and more can be raised if necessary.
Then you can rely on me.
l'll do the dirty work,
but if something goes wrong,
you're on your own.
You don't need to worry about that.
Even so, if l get into any sort of trouble,
l have no intention of taking all the blame.
l'm keeping this letter you wrote me.
I didn't go.
He asked for me.
I gave an excuse and stayed inside,
but what good did it do?
I was thinking of him aII day yesterday.
Why shouId this happen to a woman
who has never thought about any man
other than her own husband?
Madam, how do you want
the fish prepared?
You never told me.
Make a curry with ground mustard seed.
Madam?
Yes, Nanku?
There's a Ietter for you.
OUR STRUGGLE
Are you feeling any better?
Yes.
This boy from our group
was very eager to meet you.
You met me once before when l was little.
l came with my mother.
-- What's your mother's name?
-- Soudamini Devi.
-- Are you Nibaron Ghosal's son?
-- Yes. My name is Amulya.
-- How old are you?
-- Seventeen.
l was about to take
my final exam, but l didn't.
Because of Swadeshi?
Amulya is very hardworking.
He remembers the entire Bhagavadgita.
Really?
Here it is.
-- Do you always carry it with you?
-- Always.
The Bhagavadgita gives one courage
to overcome one's fears.
Even to die for one's country.
Aren't you afraid to die?
''For the soul, there is neither birth
nor death at any time.
He has not come into being, does not come
into being, and will not come into being.
He is unborn, eternal,
ever--existing and primeval.
He is not slain when the body is slain.''
Even when a man dies,
his soul lives on.
Okay, Amulya.
You may go now.
Mr. Sandip said you believe in Swadeshi.
l wanted to pay my respects.
l'll take my leave, sister.
l'll come again.
-- Please do.
Hail Motherland.
-- Hail Motherland.
-- Good--bye.
What are you thinking?
ls there any danger to your life
in the work you do?
Well...
Since we're fighting against
the powerful British government,
of course there is.
But my boys are brave.
My courage doesn't begin to match theirs.
That's a strange confession from a leader.
Sometimes the truth comes out.
Now will you tell me the truth?
What truth?
After so many years,
why did you suddenly decide
to come out of your confinement?
Don't you know why?
How would l know?
You should know.
You should, but you're a man.
You don't have a woman's intuition.
Will you tell me?
Why?
l'd never been face--to--face
with a leader before.
l fear the leader may have let you down.
Not so far.
You play the piano too?
l was taking lessons.
Piano...
singing.
English songs?
You didn't come yesterday.
l had a feeling you weren't really ill.
l racked my brain all day trying to guess...
what l had done or said to annoy you.
You still haven't told me
why you called.
l just wanted to see you.
ls that the only reason?
l didn't see you yesterday,
and it turned out
to be a dismal day for me.
My pride as a leader...
was badly shaken.
The people won't listen to you?
Sometimes words are not enough.
-- What do you do then?
-- l try other ways.
May l know what ways?
Because my husband's
not going to help you.
Nikhil said so?
Do you know what l feel
like doing sometimes?
To hell with Swadeshi.
l'll spend my life
chatting with the queen bee.
With me?
Chatting?
Would that bother you?
Why are you laughing?
That's so absurd.
You're not the type to spend
even an hour chatting.
You're right.
The truth is...
l need Swadeshi...
just as much as l need you.
l don't want you to stop
fighting for the country.
My husband and l don't see
eye to eye on that matter.
He has many virtues,
and l admire him for that.
But, for a man, he is much too placid.
A person can't afford to be so placid
at a time like this.
l agree with you entirely.
My husband says
you don't care about the poor,
so you can't really do
any good for our country.
l don't believe you would hurt the poor.
You'll try to persuade them.
That's all.
But the problem is...
persuasion doesn't always work.
You need something more.
-- What do you need?
-- Let's not talk about that.
-- l want to know.
l don't want to talk
about mundane things with you.
Why?
l want no note of discord
in our relationship.
But l'd be really happy to help.
This is beyond you, queen bee.
Haven't you seen me going beyond?
l know how far you can go.
Even so, l'd rather not talk about it.
lt's a personal request.
Then there's no reason for me to stay.
l'm leaving.
Queen bee, please don't leave angry!
lf l can't help you with Swadeshi,
then l'm just wasting my time here.
l just didn't want you to worry about me.
Must we only talk about politics?
Only about my work?
Promise me you'll tell me
if you need money,
and you'll take it if l give it to you.
l promise, queen bee.
l promise.
Queen bee?
l'll come again this evening.
Please wait for me here.
l hate having to send for you every time.
Let go of me.
Promise me you'll come to me every day.
l must see you at least once a day.
There's nothing wrong with that.
Promise me.
All right.
Please let go of my hand.
l want to go.
Khemi, clean the room later.
GentIy she waIks,
the beauteous one
Back so soon?
What are you staring at?
What is there to stare at but you?
l've never seen anything like it.
Such tender concern for our guest.
He'll never want to leave.
ln my day, we had to look
after our husbands too.
lf only my brother--in--law
were a guest in his own house,
he'd be warmly welcomed.
l don't want any advice from you.
l was just a small girl
when l came here as a bride.
Your husband was
my playmate in those days.
Where were you then?
There's no need to repeat
what l already know.
He was the only one
who understood my pain.
He used to say,
''We're still living in the Dark Ages.
That's why you're suffering like this.
For you, having a husband
is just as painful as losing one.''
''My wife will be a free woman,'' he'd say.
Well, now l see that free woman
before my very eyes.
But don't forget,
there's a God above us, dear sister.
He can see you too.
I beIieved I had the strength to bear
whatever misfortune
fate had in store for me.
I wouId caII up visions of suffering
and steeI myseIf against them.
Visions of poverty,
dishonor or death.
I even imagined BimaIa's death.
But there was one thing
I couId never imagine happening.
Now I keep asking myseIf
again and again.
Do I have the strength to bear this?
-- Hail Motherland!
-- What do you want?
-- We have some questions.
What are they?
Why don't you ban
foreign goods in our market?
-- l have my reasons.
-- ls it because you would lose money?
l wouldn't, but the poor would.
But our nation will profit.
We buy domestic salt, sugar and clothing.
How can you say that?
How can you compare
yourselves with the poor?
You have money.
You can afford
to spend more on lndian goods.
The poor aren't standing in your way.
Why are you standing in theirs?
You want to oppose an entire nation
that's taken the Swadeshi oath?
Never.
That's beyond my power.
But how can you say
the entire nation has taken your oath?
Look at the evidence.
Aren't the traders part of this nation?
So you won't ban foreign goods?
No,
because those goods don't belong to me.
Hail Motherland!
What are you looking for?
PassifIora.
Didn't you have a vial?
Are you having trouble sleeping?
One sleeps less as one grows older,
but these last three nights --
Here it is.
l found it.
Please, keep the vial.
l don't like this, Nikhil.
l have grave misgivings
about the way things are shaping up.
Sandip is your friend and your guest.
Everybody knows that.
Soon they'll believe whatever he does
is done with your sanction.
Don't you realize how terrible
the consequences could be for you?
l'm already feeling those consequences, sir.
They think l'm a British lackey,
that l don't force Swadeshi on my tenants
for fear they would stop paying rent.
That's the propaganda.
-- Don't let it worry you.
Nothing can touch you as long as
you have a clear conscience.
But the situation is deteriorating.
Muslim preachers from Dhaka are
going around stirring up the peasants.
Have you heard about it?
l've read about it in the papers.
What's to stop them from coming here?
-- Nothing.
-- And then?
But if anything does happen,
can we place all the blame
on the preachers?
We are also responsible.
How can we just ignore that?
Think about how we ourselves
have treated the poor Muslims.
Have we even respected
their rights as human beings?
That's true, but what
can be done about it now?
l'll go there.
l want to see for myself.
Rumors can be misleading.
Nikhil, can't you inform the magistrate?
l don't think he'd mind a riot.
lt's an easy way for him
to see the Swadeshi punished.
There is one thing you can do.
You can at least eradicate
the source of the trouble.
Why let Sandip stay?
l thought he'd leave of his own accord.
But now --
Leave? Why would he?
With all the comfort
and protection he enjoys here?
Besides, you've done him a special favor
by introducing him to your wife.
He's taking full advantage of that!
l had no idea he had changed so much.
All this adulation has gone to his head.
l think it comes from
a deep sense of frustration.
Despite all his gifts,
he hasn't really accomplished anything.
Sometimes, l feel pity for him.
This is no time for pity, Nikhil.
You can't bring yourself to be firm
with him because he's close to you.
You're hesitating.
But l fail to see why you're
vacillating at a time like this.
You would if l told you.
But l can't.
Remember this?
lt's from my soap factory.
You saved it?
-- Not just the soap.
Towels, pens, matches.
l kept everything.
Have you ever used it?
lt's no good for anything,
not even for washing clothes.
What foolish notions l had back then.
You still do.
You freed her from her moorings.
Now look where she's drifted.
-- That was no foolish notion.
-- You still think so?
lf she likes what she's doing,
then that's the kind of person she is.
l could prevent her from going out,
but that wouldn't change who she is.
She's not a child.
lsn't the husband the master?
Bending her to my will wouldn't be difficult,
but it wouldn't help.
At least get rid of him.
He's not much of a friend, is he?
lt would certainly be better for my estate
if he were to leave.
But l'm a selfish person.
l can't stop thinking about myself.
l just can't help it.
lf he leaves, you'll soon find her
back by your side.
l know.
But l would find her regretting it,
because it wouldn't be her decision.
That would be unbearable,
both for her...
and for me.
l can't do it.
Hail Motherland!
HaiI MotherIand.
What happened?
Why are you so late?
-- lt was a lot of work.
There's a play in Chandrapur tonight.
l had to wait for the boatmen to go there.
This kind of work can't be done
if there are people around.
Mirjan's boat?
But when he comes back
and finds his boat missing,
it won't take him long
to put two and two together,
and then he'll come groveling to you.
You'll have to give him some compensation.
Keep around 5,000 rupees handy.
-- Let me see.
-- A word of advice.
Can l be frank with you?
Out with it. lt's late.
l think you should finish things up
quickly here and leave.
-- Why?
-- Things aren't looking good.
There could be a riot.
You may be a leader,
but you're not exactly
a popular one, you know.
They're certainly not going
to put you on a pedestal.
l'll decide what to do.
You don't need to worry about it.
Onward, sons of India
The MotherIand caIIs
The strong, the brave, the proud
To serve the nation's cause
Onward, sons of India
The MotherIand caIIs
You should give up Swadeshi
and take up singing.
l once considered becoming an actor.
lt's wonderful to be able to hold
a large audience in your grip.
l was thinking that when l heard
you speak the other evening.
Of course...
it's nothing like winning
the heart of a woman.
l gather you've won
the hearts of many women,
both Swadeshi...
and foreign.
Good God!
Has Nikhil told you all this?
You know so much about me.
Why shouldn't l know something about you?
You know what they were?
Youthful indiscretions.
lt's ancient history.
l wonder what happened to those women.
You shouldn't, queen bee.
l'm no longer the same person.
You know that.
Still, it's helpful in understanding
a person's character.
lt's not difficult to understand men.
lt's women who are unfathomable.
One despairs of knowing their minds.
You know that song, don't you?
-- What song?
Who can ever fathom a woman's ways?
Her siIence means more
than what she says
She Iooks at you,
then drops her eyes
Her siIence means more
than what she says
She Iooks at you,
then drops her eyes
She Iaughs one moment
The next she cries
She Iingers cIose,
then Ieaves you in a daze
Who can ever fathom a woman's ways?
ls that why you never married?
How can l marry if l can't find a woman
after my own heart, queen bee?
l waited a long time for you last night.
You never came.
Forgive me, my queen bee.
l was very busy.
l got back late.
-- Busy with what?
-- The Swadeshi cause, of course.
-- Giving speeches?
-- No.
What, then?
Winding things up.
l can't stay here forever, you know.
We have to be constantly
on the move, campaigning.
You're leaving?
l have to go sooner or later.
What if your queen bee doesn't let you?
No one would be happier than me.
But l'm not planning on leaving just yet.
There are still problems to be resolved.
-- Will you tell me?
-- What?
How much money do you need?
What is it?
How much?
About five thousand.
We spent more
than we were planning to.
lf l get you the money,
you'll have to take it without question.
lf you say so, but you mustn't
part with your jewelry.
When l said money,
l meant money.
What if l can't repay you?
l don't expect you to.
Can't l at least do this much for Swadeshi?
-- l'm worried, queen bee.
-- Why?
l seem to have become a burden to you.
But there's no other way. l can explain.
-- You don't have to.
Just tell me one thing.
-- What?
-- lf l give you the money, will you stay?
-- Do you think l want to leave you?
Then why did you say
you were going to leave?
After all the torment l've been through.
l did it all for you,
and you --
Queen bee.
Brothers!
The Hindus ask you to join hands
with them for the Swadeshi cause.
They wheedIe you.
They coax you.
They even threaten you.
They want you to join them at aII costs,
but don't Iisten to them, brothers.
Remember they don't want our betterment.
The Hindus don't care about your weII-being.
Whatever they say is not
for the benefit of our community.
The Hindus have never
cared about our weII-being.
The Hindus want to keep us MusIims
under their heeIs forever.
That is their onIy objective.
But remember one thing.
By the grace of AIIah,
MusIims are the majority in BengaI.
You are the farmers.
The weaIth of this country
comes from its Iand.
Enough is enough.
No part of this weaIth
is produced by the Hindus.
It's your hard work that made them weaIthy.
They have no right
to the fruits of your Iabors.
This is your hard--earned money.
The Hindus have no right to it.
Listen to me, brother Muslims.
Don't listen to the Hindus.
Don't get mixed up in their politics.
Swadeshi is not for you.
You are the leaders
of the Hindu community in Sukhsayar.
l've called you here to tell you one thing.
You are men of wisdom
and good judgment.
l think you will appreciate
what l am going to say to you.
l have faith in you.
l just wanted to say...
that we can stay true
to our own religious beliefs,
but we shouldn't interfere
with the beliefs of others.
Even as a follower of Vaishnavism,
l can't prevent a follower of Shaktism
from spilling the blood of animals.
And so, similarly...
we should let the Muslims
follow their own religious convictions.
Maharaja, the Muslims in this village
never used to slaughter cows,
but l've heard they do now.
Yes.
l've heard that too.
But l strongly believe that
they've been manipulated into doing so.
They've been convinced to do it,
in order to stir up trouble
between our two religions.
Please don't add fuel to the fire.
They won't stop unless
you put them back in their place.
The good old days are gone.
Listen.
Muslims are a part of lndia.
This is a historical fact.
You must accept this fact.
We can't imagine an lndia without Muslims.
lf we try to put them in their place,
it won't stop them from slaughtering cows.
lt may even lead to them slaughtering men.
That's never been truer than now,
in the present state of unrest and turmoil.
You now have a grave responsibility.
l beg you, l beseech you,
do not encourage hatred.
lf you do so now,
you are courting disaster.
Hail Motherland.
Nikhil.
Did you hear a shot?
-- Yes, l did.
-- What now?
-- l know.
l know what must be done.
But first of all,
take my carriage, go home
and come back with all your belongings.
The roads aren't safe anymore.
l don't want anything to happen to you.
That sounds fine, but --
l'll tell Sandip right away.
Time's running out, queen bee.
l need the money now.
What's that?
Can't you guess?
Money?
So little? There can't be
more than 500 in those bags.
You must have forgotten.
l asked for 5,000 rupees.
What's this?
Gold coins?
Gold.
You should have told me.
How else would l know?
Please don't be angry, my queen bee.
-- l need to talk to you.
-- About what?
l don't want you to stay here any longer.
Things have taken a serious turn.
Your presence may make matters worse.
l want you to leave Sukhsayar
by tomorrow morning.
Am l supposed to take orders from you?
lt's not that.
lf you leave for Calcutta,
it will be good for you,
and for Sukhsayar as well.
-- l have no work to do in Calcutta.
-- All the more reason to go.
You've done too much work here.
Don't think l haven't been
informed of your activities.
From setting fire to the peasants' barns
to sinking Mirjan's boat,
l've been informed of everything.
You speak of unity
between Hindus and Muslims,
but, in fact, you oppress Muslims.
l won't tolerate it anymore.
l may not believe in Swadeshi,
but l truly admire
some Swadeshi leaders.
But l don't admire those
whose actions belie their words.
You're not saving the country.
You're ruining it.
l won't allow this to go on in my estate.
There's only one person here
l'm prepared to obey.
Queen bee...
Do you want me to stay or not?
Queen bee.
l'm waiting for your answer.
Do you want me to leave?
Please tell me, queen bee.
l've said what l came to say.
l hope l won't have to repeat it.
Queen bee.
What's the matter with you?
You suddenly --
-- ls Amulya in your room?
-- Amulya?
-- Yes.
Why?
Send him to me. lt's urgent.
Can't you tell me why?
No, l'll tell Amulya.
Please send him to me.
lt's my request.
Very well.
Amulya?
Can you do me a favor?
-- Of course. What is it?
Go to Calcutta.
You can take the morning train
and return in the evening.
The money for the journey is in this box.
-- What's this box?
-- lt's my jewelry box.
l need 5,000 rupees. Sell some
of my jewelry and bring me the money.
l don't need any jewelry.
l can get you the money.
How?
This is not a small amount
we're talking about.
l'll get it.
No, do as l tell you.
But why did you give
Mr. Sandip 5,000 rupees?
He said he needed that much.
No, according to our calculations,
we only needed 3,500.
lf you give him more,
he spends it on himself.
He's quite a spender.
He always travels first--class.
-- Sandip?
-- Yes, sister.
He says hardship saps a leader's strength.
Well, l can't take back
what l've already given.
He might need it in the future.
You get me the 5,000.
Put the box away.
l'll get you the money tonight.
-- How?
-- From the treasury.
Are you insane?
What about the guards?
We carry weapons, sister.
Good heavens!
Why are you upset, sister?
We need funding
to carry out our work for the nation.
Doesn't it bother you that you're stealing?
Why?
Whose money is it?
Mine today,
the moneylender's tomorrow.
Why not use it for the cause?
-- No, Amulya.
lf you go robbing treasuries,
l'll die of fear.
Listen, you may not need
to sell all the jewelry.
Sell as much as you need to
and bring back the rest.
Take the box and carry it safely.
And be careful, for heaven's sake.
Very well, sister.
l'll take my leave.
-- Okay.
Queen bee.
Are you leaving?
ls there any reason for me to stay?
Why do you say that?
Can't you hear the note of discord?
lf l've done anything wrong,
please forgive me.
Don't leave like this.
My husband said, ''The less one
knows you, the better one likes you''.
Perhaps l know you too well.
Don't say that, queen bee.
Has knowing me meant nothing to you?
Has it all been in vain?
l believed you would
succeed in your endeavor.
l wanted you to.
But not anymore?
AIIah is great!
Kasim?
Hands up.
Go inside.
Go inside!
Move.
Turn around.
Turn!
Now open the safe.
Open it!
Take out 3,500 rupees.
What's going on?
What's all the commotion?
ls there a problem?
l don't know.
l hope it's not a riot.
What are you saying?
What will happen to us
if there's a riot here?
We're going to Calcutta tomorrow.
lt's no longer safe here.
Who is ''we''?
Am l not coming with you?
Did l say that?
l'm so relieved.
A treasury was looted nearby.
What's to stop them from looting this place?
lf they kill me, they'll burn my body
by that shriveled banyan tree.
That would be awful.
Go and get ready.
Pack your things.
You're serious about leaving, aren't you?
l'm always serious.
Don't you know me by now?
Bimala?
l have to tell you something.
What is it?
There were 5,000 rupees
in gold coins in two bags in the safe.
l gave them to Sandip.
He needed the money.
Now you know how hard
it is to refuse him.
l'll pay the money back.
l gave Amulya my jewelry box.
He'll sell my jewels and bring the money.
l felt bad speaking to Sandip
like that in front of you.
But l had to, Bimala.
Things have taken a bad turn.
lt's no longer safe for him to work here.
But what about you?
Your safety is what concerns me.
No one else matters to me anymore.
Tomorrow, we're going to Calcutta.
All three of us.
And if something happens before then?
You won't leave the house, will you?
lf something happens,
l'll have to go and intervene, Bimala.
l knew it.
l knew l'd be punished.
l'll be punished.
Punished? Why, Bimala?
You haven't done anything wrong.
l don't even have the right
to ask you for forgiveness.
But you've come back to me,
haven't you?
Haven't you, Bimala?
lt seems like ages since l last
looked at you and spoke to you.
What came over me?
Why did this happen?
You've done nothing wrong, Bimala.
For ten years, you never saw
another man besides me.
Don't forget that.
There's 3,500 rupees here.
Please return the jewelry box
and the gold coins.
Where did you get that money?
Where have you been?
To the treasury.
l hope nobody saw you.
l had my face covered.
Did you see any trouble in the village?
-- There's a riot.
The Muslims have broken
into the temple of Visalakshi.
Are you leaving?
Yes. To Rangpur.
Will you come with me?
l must go now.
Hail Motherland.
What are you thinking?
Nothing.
l don't want to think.
l want to forget.
Everything that's happened
in the last few days.
Forget? But why?
Nikhil!
Come in, Sandip.
This is the age of breaking rules.
Your wife came out of her confinement,
and now l've invaded
the privacy of your bedroom.
l hope you'll forgive me.
These are your property,
which l duly return.
One jewelry box
and two bags of gold coins.
The jewelry box?
Your devotee didn't take it with him,
but he brought me the money.
Since you have your valuables, l hope
you won't mind me keeping the money.
-- Are you leaving?
-- Yes, Nikhil.
The train to Rangpur leaves in an hour.
Do you hear that?
The riots have started.
Amulya saw them.
And now l must make
my proverbial escape.
l must live.
l have a lot of work left to do.
Don't make the same mistake again.
Can't you see the results of your actions?
l follow the Bhagavadgita, Nikhil.
l am concerned only
with the action, not the result.
And l consider Ravana to be
the hero of Ramayana, not Rama.
So l can't accept advice
from the followers of Rama.
The easy road isn't for me, Nikhil.
l'll take my leave.
This will stay with me.
l'm keeping this as a memento.
Who knows if we'll ever meet again?
Good--bye, Nikhil.
Queen bee.
Hail Motherland.
Courage, Bimala.
l must go out to them now.
-- No! l won't let you!
l must.
Please don't stop me.
My dear.
-- You let him go?
-- We tried to stop him.
He wouldn't listen to us!
You witch!
You sent him to his death!
Have you no pity
in your heart of stone?
Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm