Invest in www.caseway.ai
to change the legal industry!
Hi, everybody!
We are robbers!
Come on! Put your arms up!
You've seen us in the newspapers!
Don't do anything stupid!
This is our way to help the economy.
This is an expropriation
proceeding.
Pack everything up!
Possession is a crime!
Take what you need.
After that, put your hands up!
We are bringing down capitalism!
Pack it in!
Faster!
Come on, Granny!
There's a robbery in progress.
Ah?
Spare a buck, young lady?
You should live forever!
Good luck!
Those were the happy years.
We thought we were
the best, Tatjana.
Somehow,
we tried to abolish injustice,
and then the government.
or the other way round.
Both were connected.
Politics were at war,
all around the world.
She has a .765 Walther.
How do you know that?
It's hidden.
Please open the bag.
I'm travelling in transit.
Please, open the bag.
Take a seat, please.
Your name is Marianna Berg.
Yes.
But you are Rita Vogt.
As you can see, I am Marianna Berg.
As far as I know
you are Rita Vogt.
You are not allowed
to come in with a weapon.
I'm only passing by to West Berlin.
You are not allowed
to pass by with a weapon either.
My friends in Beirut
recommended Schönefeld.
Sometimes you have friends in common.
In case you ever come back here,
take this phone number.
I can pass through then?
When I am informed.
Can I take my friends?
I just need to be informed in advance.
My name is Erwin.
THE LEGEND OF RITA
It's so generous
that you want to help us.
I would love to ride horses,
play tennis or guzzle down salmon.
Here is your passport.
One has to hate
the world's crudeness
in order to appreciate it.
It was different for me,
cause I was in love.
With Andy?
Do you know how to use it?
She can hit trees,
but only wide ones.
Gruber defends him.
Isn't it the best solution?
No way.
He'd be in prison for 10 more years.
Gruber won't be
involved in anything.
Someone is here to see Mr. Klein.
This is my trainee,
Mrs. Adebach.
A police officer shoots
someone who's fleeing.
Does he want to kill him,
or just thwart the getaway?
A guy who flees shoots...
the police officer who follows him...
Does he want to kill him
or just continue his getaway?
That could be possible.
What do you think?
It's also a question of effort.
I'm glad that you are willing to try.
- Hello.
I'd like to ask something.
Please, go ahead.
Last Christmas,
an amnesty was granted.
My brother got out then.
Now he's in again.
Will there be another
amnesty this Christmas?
I don't want to be rude,
but I don't think so.
Yes, but it's Christmas.
Andreas Klein.
My name is Gruber.
This is Ms. Adebach.
We've got one hour.
Are you insane?
Open the door, please.
Venceremos!
Where is she?
Where's Fredericke?
She didn't make it.
Move!
This coat is so freaking
light-coloured!
Why did you shoot?
You didn't have to!
What happened?
Give me your jacket,
this won't work!
Why did you shoot?
Stop yelling!
Nothing went wrong!
Where are we going?
Across the border.
Are you crazy?
Berlin, capital of the GDR.
Train station Friedrichstraße.
Passengers from West Germany
Go to counters 1 - 5.
Passengers from GDR, go to counter 7.
Red cops are cops, too.
It's not possible that
only Erwin is travelling.
That's probably not
even his real name.
In Germany,
aggression has always come
from the right wing.
But we are also against
terrorism from the left.
It doesn't lead anywhere.
It scares the public,
and causes problems
in the administration.
Even Lenin,
his brother was a terrorist.
He was executed.
Sit down!
Thank you.
On the other hand, I sympathise
with young, romantic people.
We are also romantics.
I'm 70.
And I'm still dreaming.
Nothing's ever completed.
How, in plain daylight,
can they break a guy out of prison?
Up to now,
we've never known their plans.
But we're supposed
to know everything!
Wherever possible.
You have to look at it that way.
It's exactly my point
of view, General.
What are you up to?
Trust has to be established through
common experiences.
Correct.
I thought we would
barbecue sausages.
I believe the plane is gone.
Maybe it's a trap?
He gave a good impression.
EXIT
Here I am.
So, we meet again so soon.
I didn't see that coming, either.
Your weapon, please.
But we're just passing through!
That's what I thought, too.
You still have to see a doctor.
I don't have a weapon.
He looked at me.
He understood what was going on.
Maybe he isn't injured so badly.
- Can I help you?
- You are our guests.
- Does anyone want something to eat?
- I do.
This sausage tastes good.
Cause it's Thüringer sausage.
- The beer is Radeberger.
- It's tasty as well.
A toast to my release from
the capitalist prison.
As a free man in a free country.
Cheers!
Okay. This place is cosy.
But what are we doing here?
Exchange of thoughts.
Which thoughts would
you like to exchange?
For example, that the revolution
moves in different directions.
Mainly in the office?
From 8:00 to 17:00?
You guys have such
a sense for violence.
At our place, the government
is the organized form of violence.
You can only break law,
but we create it!
From the outside,
you only see the wall.
Sandwich or bread?
You see the wall from the inside, too.
Does the GDR have to
extradite criminals
who are wanted in West Germany?
I'm not responsible for this.
But both parts are not really friends.
We just want nothing
bad to happen here.
No actions on GDR territory!
Nobody wants that.
Therefore, you could pass through.
We fight independently
against imperialism.
But we have a common enemy,
as you pointed out.
Sometimes it's difficult to define.
We frighten the right people.
The counsellor died on the scene.
Lawyer Dr. Gruber haven't worked on
cases concerning terrorism before.
He leaves a wife
and two little kids.
His employee, Fredericke Adebach
helped Andreas Klein to
get a weapon through.
A large-scale manhunt
has been initiated.
Apart from Andreas Klein,
the following people are wanted:
Detlev Bergmann, Joachim Klatte,
Hans Jürgen Dost,
Martina Lubitz,
Rita Vogt.
Rita Vogt has a visible
scar on her elbow.
Caution:
These people are armed.
The police is sure that they
are still in West Berlin.
However, the search
has been expanded
to cover the entire
federal territory.
Did you really have to shoot?
He was holding me.
Why did he do that?
I can't hit a human being.
Then the cop came and shot.
So did I.
He was in the way.
Should we separate
for a while, Andi?
Will imperialism go down by itself?
And the history develops itself?
The injustice vanishes by itself?
I don't want to argue with you,
I simply want to be with you!
Well...
Excuse me, comrades.
I'm cracking up,
they are having sex.
Here, in the East.
What are we doing?
We are not having sex.
Both are nice girls.
Plus, they have
stable employment.
You won't find anything like them.
I think that they are demotivated.
We tried to
accomplish the impossible,
at least once in our lives.
We felt like we were part
of the international fight.
And then we experienced
how in Beirut,
a right cause led to
a murderous civil war.
We wanted to bring the war
into the capitals of the world.
There was never ending discussion,
successful and failed actions.
Victims on both sides.
A couple of years later,
we were in Paris.
And we were in jail.
I know how it will end in jail.
We just sit in these countries
wasting our lives...
...and for what?
The poor people around the world?
Let's go there!
To those who starve.
Because the culprits live here.
Right, the system is run by people.
We just say everything
within our limits.
Those are Andi's texts,
Andi has started everything.
He has started everything by himself.
You don't want to ride or play tennis
and that can't be.
And so on, and so on...
If they trap me,
I don't know how to deal with that.
Do you see those guys there?
They will kill us.
You are going crazy,
we'll shoot them first.
There are no doubts.
Imperialism is an illegal war
the only way to force that....
Yes, that's the problem,
human or pigs.
We need money for our next steps.
The solution is the guns.
Theoretically, we can put two barrels
of beer in front of the door.
We did it a lot of times,
then we can go out.
He considered it.
I think it's ridiculous
to build a wall.
Can you please explain?
Yes, before we went to people
and said, this is a robbery.
An anticapitalist action.
How do you want to do it?
In which language?
- Frederike speaks French.
- And what should she say?
Hello, French friend,
we want your money,
here starts
the German revolution?
You can't go with a gun
to the people...
Just be practical, show your gun,
hand to the air, no panic.
I want that everyone goes inside,
like we always did.
- I don't want to!
- You have a problem!
But if you go with our money,
and you spend it in a Honda...
and you go around Paris,
then you will give us in.
Then you go to the pigs,
and you'll betray me.
- Is that what you think?
- Yes
You are looking for a fight,
why are you choosing me?
Leave Rita alone.
You live your life
and use expensive brands.
And you are an idiot!
Hey! Calm down!
Don't take it personal.
What's happening to that pig?!
What are you?
Problem or solution?
Person or a pig?
This should be clear.
Fight against the pigs,
so we can free people.
Each shooting breaks
the connections
and brings results.
It's crystal clear, isn't it?
Why are you without helmets, ladies?
We forgot our helmets.
It's required by law.
Please, forgive us, sir.
Oh, you are not from here.
Show me your documents, please.
Early in the morning,
it's cold in the East.
There is everything.
Even Radeberger.
With pleasure. That's what
we used to have back then.
If it's already good,
I don't have to change it.
Some comrades don't
want to carry on.
We haven't finished yet.
Not with the emperor.
As for now, we are in a deep trouble.
Those comrades cost us money
and are unreliable.
Wait a second, I am reliable,
but I don't want
to sit around anymore.
We were to fight around the world.
That's what you said.
And, where is it?
Somewhere in this world,
people like us have to be in demand!
Vase.
Angola would be a destination.
Or Mozambique,
if that's possible.
You have connections there,
don't you?
Now it looks much friendlier.
We have to get out of France, too.
I know.
To whom did that happen,
with the cop?
To me.
It happened to me.
Do you want to quit, too?
No!
There are ten people.
They want to go anywhere.
Preferably Angola
or Mozambique.
So what do they want here?
We are supposed to get them in
and have them accommodated.
People are black there.
They are white.
How do they plan to disappear?
I'll leave that to you.
Let's get back to the topic.
No mistakes are allowed.
That's how I see it, comrade general.
That's how one has to see it.
- Do we talk without any witnesses?
- And off the record.
- Where can we sit down and talk?
- Inside.
Maybe under a tree.
Good idea.
Let's assume that you
are wanted worldwide,
even the ones who want to quit.
We won't send any of you...
to Africa,
nor Angola, nor Mozambique.
The political situation is fragile.
Secret agents are
all over the place.
And the people are black.
You are white.
You can be traced back to us.
We propose a different offer.
Your people can stay here.
In the GDR.
Separated, not as a group.
No contacts are allowed,
neither connections
to your previous life.
Everybody has to agree,
so we can start.
You will have...
new names,
and you would be different people.
For a long time.
Maybe forever.
Given that you lead an utterly
normal, ordinary life.
The life of the working class.
And one more thing:
We should have regular
meetings and talks.
You don't have to inform
us about your plans.
We just want you
to listen to us.
Before you plan anything.
Is it possible to get any
military support?
You can do sports here.
Is shooting considered as a sport?
We can define it like that.
The RPG-7
is an anti-armour weapon.
Who shoots?
I do.
20 meters safety clearance!
They know the drill.
They have already practised.
They couldn't train this dog
to be a fighter.
What's going on here?
It's required by personal security.
We have to obey.
We also have important
people driving in cars.
Is the dog supposed
to be in the car?
Every round has to be accounted for.
The personal security pays for it.
It's a different department.
These songs were ours.
That's how we started
over after the war.
They were always with us.
And rock 'n' roll?
Much less.
Vodka is the soldier's friend.
Hey, Andi...
You used to be my
big love once.
I don't understand this now.
Is this here
the life of the working class?
I'd rather drink my beer
somewhere else.
Good morning!
Four to Beirut.
For you,
and for you,
and for you.
And you.
You don't have to pay!
We insist to.
There is one spare ticket.
Rita!
It's brave of you
to have stayed here.
You are going to see
socialism for what it is.
You are going to see that sometimes
we have to force people to be happy.
Probably you have
understood it already.
We are here for people.
And therefore, we are against them.
And my mother didn't
get along with herself.
She didn't have a lot of money.
At an age of 42, she suddenly died.
I can't wrap my head around it.
- We will start with your story.
- What's my story?
Your made-up life,
which now becomes your real one.
When do you want your birthday to be?
During summertime,
when it's warm.
Which name do you want to have?
For example,
Schmidt?
Schmidt is silly.
Do you have other ideas?
No, Schmidt is okay.
And a name?
You can create it.
We'll make suggestions
for your parents' data.
I don't need parents.
We let them be dead then.
You don't have them anymore anyway.
Otherwise, you'll be asked
about them all the time.
The best lie is the truth.
You know you need to carry
your ID at all times.
I just have another jacket on,
but you know me.
It's not my job
to know everybody.
I'm in fashion
print department.
- Name?
- Susanne Schmidt.
Ouch, damn! Damn! Damn!
Something like this never happened
before you started here.
Everybody makes mistakes.
No wonder that
your hands are shaking!
We'll teach you!
Teach Elfriede,
so she takes a shower.
She even has a theory of why
she doesn't take a shower.
I don't use soap.
Soap destroys the natural
protective layer of the skin.
We can smell that.
I don't care what an alcoholic
has to say about me, anyway.
It's always a fight
with you guys!
Why are you so mean
with Tatjana?
She's the mean one!
And you are cows, stupid cows!
Ready?
I love you all!
Have you never been married?
Unfortunately, no.
There was someone,
when my parents had the accident.
As you know,
they had a fatal accident.
I didn't know that.
Don't you regret coming here?
I've always been left politically.
I didn't have a lot of options.
I used to be a waitress.
Funny.
You come here voluntarily,
the only thing I want is to get away.
That's the way it is.
Here and there.
I'd like to see that myself.
Maybe I would come back.
Then I'd be here on my own will.
Here's the list...
for Nicaragua.
Again already?
Do you have a pen?
Are you messing with us?
Thank you!
What's going on today?
- You don't dance?
- Neither do you.
Red wine, please.
What I don't get is why
you donate 10 Marks?
I didn't think about it that much.
Do you really think
they get the money?
Don't you think so?
Dear colleagues!
Do you still have
access to West Marks?
No.
I spent it on a Trabant.
You can buy everything
with West Marks.
I didn't have much.
Why didn't you rob a bank?
- Oh, I did.
- Cheers to that.
Günnel, Sigrid.
Janzen, Andrea.
And Blechschmidt, Klaus.
''Life is Life... ''
Tatjana!
- Where were you today?
- I overslept.
We were worried.
I doubt that.
- What's the time?
- Half past three.
Damn.
Do you want some coffee?
If you have some, too.
I can do that.
I don't feel well.
Why is it already boiling?
The current goes
directly into the water.
You can't stick a spoon in there.
Or you're dead.
Are you crazy to use
anything like that?
My ex-husband built it for me.
Probably he
wanted to kill you!
Thanks!
Don't use that thing anymore!
I am immortal.
- Hello!
- Hello.
My place?
I live around the corner.
- Bye.
Admit it, you didn't notice!
Did you steal these?
I wanted to get
ourselves a little treat.
What else have you done?
Danced in a bar.
Really?
Yes. First, I did pole dancing.
Then I bent over, and everyone
could see into my butt.
And what do you expect here?
In the past, when a sailing ship
got into a dead calm,
when no one brought up wind,
it was bad times.
Then you spent Easter
off the Christmas islands...
Strange, out of big glasses
one can drink more
without getting drunk.
You can stay here.
I'm falling asleep.
There was still
some left in there.
It's empty.
You poured out the booze!
Don't lie about it!
You have thrown it away!
Let me go!
Give me the key!
You think I can't climb?
Tatjana!
Do you know how much one bottle
costs, stupid western cow?
Step on the gas!
And now, shift into second gear!
Careful! What are you doing?
Stay on the road!
Clutch, take out the gear,
and now, break!
- How am I?
- The best!
Turn around!
Drive down that path in reverse!
How do I do that?
Push down on it, move it downwards.
Accelerate, and steer.
Damn!
This is a new car!
No worries.
It's Sunday.
Lieutenant Knorz.
Who was driving?
I did.
License and registration, please!
What have we done wrong?
We drove against a tree
in reverse.
Exactly.
And that's what you've done wrong.
Have you had any alcohol?
- No.
- Me neither.
Follow me to the garage.
- Please!
- Thanks.
This is a friend from school.
She should've chosen him.
She had bad luck with her marriage.
Do you know that maybe...?
She was too young
and the husband
wasn't mature either.
After the divorce, she dyed her hair.
- Is your name Susanne?
- Susanne Schmidt.
Nice to meet you. Margarethe.
Cheers people,
all the best!
Bloody incident at
the German-French border.
Two men died when they
tried to skip border controls.
One of them is alleged
terrorist Andreas Klein.
His companion is
yet to be identified.
The following people
are wanted:
Fredericke Adebach, Joachim Klatte,
Bernd Ruppel, Rita Vogt.
She has a scar on the left elbow.
Caution: Those people are armed.
Let's go dancing!
Susanne has been to Paris!
She moved back here, nonetheless.
That's a rare case.
The concept is better:
Less poverty, less richness.
Many people died for it,
all around the world.
I've seen the Great Wall.
They drove us there.
But, especially the people!
That's disappointing, all look alike.
My father always
talks about China.
Do you want some wine?
Homemade.
My mother warned me about men.
But never about women.
I gotta leave.
There are tomatoes from Bulgaria!
Look, the colour!
- I'll get some for us.
- I'll then cook Ratatouille.
What?
Ratatouille.
Do you have a scar on your arm?
Why?
Ask her if she has a scar on her arm!
It doesn't bother me.
How is it to live with
such past life?
- Hello!
- A call to Berlin.
Please step into the phone booth!
I'm connecting.
Someone recognized me.
Can I go back to my house?
- She saw you on the news?
- I think so.
- Did you see it, too?
- Yes.
Where?
At a birthday party.
Who's birthday?
My colleague
Tatjana's father's.
So, everybody has seen it?
I was alone in the room.
- I want to be entirely truthful.
- You should be.
Tatjana stood in the door.
But not from the very beginning.
I don't know since when.
But she hasn't
said anything yet.
You stay here for now.
- I'm working early shift tomorrow.
- We'll take care of that.
Someone will miss me too.
You have many friends,
this we already know.
She bought tomatoes
for dinner.
She won't get it.
Rumours are spread.
I don't want to behave this way.
Write a letter.
You'll be back in a couple of days.
We'll deliver it immediately.
- When shall I come back?
- Soon.
Dear Tatjana, I'm in a big hurry,
I need to help a friend.
It won't take long.
Don't overthink it.
It is how it is.
Sad story, the thing with Andi.
Very sad.
He didn't stand a chance.
You can't go back.
What do you mean?
What I said.
Why did you allow me
to write the letter then?
Because we needed time.
But I want to
go back to Tatjana.
- How's that supposed to work?
- That's my condition.
Since when are you giving conditions?
Do you know what would happen
if your cover was blown?
The GDR has signed international
anti-terrorism treaties.
Lives can be easily ruined through
something like that, not only yours.
Are you actually interested in people?
This is our job.
We usually deal with male comrades.
My husband was a lieutenant,
until he retired.
Anyway,
we always lived in the suburb.
20:12
21:12
Hold on. Rematch!
- How did you carry these things?
- I'll show you.
You walk differently.
Your body centre
and movements are altered.
Doesn't the skin get cold?
The gun gets warm.
Are you insane?
Why wasn't the safety engaged?
- It was!
- No!
I'm not stupid!
You've already shot someone before!
I helped him with accounting.
He died at the age of 32.
I didn't want to be a widow.
Please, come in.
You aren't asleep yet.
I'm practising
for my third life.
Sabine Walter.
Too young to live a widow's life.
This time, you're from the East.
There will be less questions.
Maybe you should...
..wear glasses.
You're pretty anyway.
A cat has seven lives.
Are you married?
Yes.
It's important to be married.
You should visit your colleague.
I think it would be possible.
The story needs a closing.
- Who's there?
- Susanne.
You look different.
You too.
I knew you'd get in touch
as soon as you can.
I often checked
if your Trabbi was here.
I didn't want to
abandon you.
I think it's great that I know you.
You are so important, compared to me.
I wanted to
say goodbye.
I'm going back
to West Germany.
Because of my family.
But your parents are dead.
I have siblings.
Don't use that hellish
device anymore!
- What?
- That thing you use to make coffee.
People say you are a wanted
terrorist in West Germany.
If that was true,
I couldn't return there.
When they mentioned
the scar, I knew.
I'm your friend.
Talk to me!
You are mistaken, Tatjana.
I beg you to believe me!
Are you going to write?
Sure!
Yes, sure.
Stop messing with me!
I'll come with you.
I'll be back soon.
I'll be gone then.
- Can I sit in the back?
- Go ahead.
That was quick.
What did she say?
That she's my girlfriend.
Excuse me.
The kitchen.
A couple of lamps will
be delivered soon.
We've unpacked everything.
Except for the books.
Call if there's any problem.
I would like to join the party.
You always need to be
truthful with the party.
Always.
Can you do that?
Good morning!
This is your workplace.
Mrs. Walter is going to prepare
the children's summer vacation.
She used to work
in her husband's shop.
- Yes.
- Tea?
- No, thank you.
Your new colleagues
will show you around.
- Are those the old ones?
- Yes.
I'm Christa.
These are Beate and Monika.
We call each other by names.
My name is Sabine.
Morning!
I've written down
whom we need:
Trade union,
trade union committee,
official youth organization,
the mayor,
the Hygiene, the youth's welfare,
railroad, German Red Cross,
public administration, canteen,
construction management,
and the children's commission.
All at the same table!
Can you swim?
Don't go that far!
Are you keeping an eye
on the children?
Yes.
Then I am going to
keep an eye on you.
My name is Jochen Pettka.
- Good night!
- Good night, Sabine!
What are you reading?
"The Physics
of the Next Millennium".
Here's a nice sentence:
"Innovation is what you cannot see."
Seeing something new from time
to time is what's beautiful in life.
Does that mean things never play
out as you would expect them to?
Yes.
Thanks God, not always.
This is my third summer here,
as a lifeguard.
You've already been
here a couple of times?
Yes, I know a lot of people.
There are beautiful eyes
hidden behind your glasses.
You were killing it!
Do you think so?
Ouch!
- Am I hurting you?
- No, it's just my sunburn.
Noon rest till 3pm!
- What's that ship?
- Ferry to Sweden.
Why do so many people
want to leave?
I've never been on a vacation
at the Baltic Sea!
We are going soon.
- Let me introduce my husband.
- Sabine Walter.
We've met while travelling.
See you in a minute, in the bus!
Excuse me.
Let's just sit down for a second!
It's a pity that we don't have time.
Yes.
This is my son, Eric.
- Glad to hear you're well.
- Why do you think that?
I'm coming.
This is our gratitude for your
commitment to the summer vacation.
As they say: Children are our
most valuable good.
The documents are in the files.
Thank you.
Thank you very much!
Is that really an award
for your sleeping around?
- You shouldn't say things like that!
- I have nothing against it.
But if I do this, I need to have
emotions involved.
Come in!
Hang up your coat!
Are you from Berlin?
Thank you!
Why haven't you got
in touch sooner?
I want to marry you.
I want you to marry me.
It's a big opportunity for me.
Five years,
one in a million gets this.
It's situated in the woods,
But they have everything:
Swimming pool, horse riding,
cinema, theatre.
And Moscow isn't that far away.
And you can come with your wife.
And I thought: maybe I have one.
- And I am going to ask her.
- And what am I going to do there?
You will be my wife.
What will I be doing as your wife?
You will be the mother of my children.
It sounds a little stupid, I know.
I'll be the mother of your children?
You don't take it seriously, do you?
I do.
Put it away!
Why are you wearing glasses?
For fun!
- Why didn't you tell me?
- What for?
I thought, I knew you,
but glasses made of plain glass!
Glasses without a purpose?
Can we just change the topic?
Please, you don't need the be angry!
Maybe somebody once told you were
more beautiful with glasses.
- Are you taking the pill?
- Do I have to?
Hello. Here I am.
I am glad.
We thought about it.
It is out of question.
We can't keep your identity
a secret from the Russians.
We don't want to tell them.
Cause it'd be too messy.
Do you think that you
can control everything?!
No, but that's the way it is.
But I want to go there, with him!
We love each other and we
are going to have a child!
You don't have to have a child.
And if I have one anyway?
Are you watching West German TV?
Why?
They show GDR women
holding up their children,
when they climb into the West German
embassy in Prague.
Do you see something like
that on GDR television?
Do you see?
Some people in this
country are asleep.
Those are my worries
at the moment.
So I am asking for your understanding.
If I don't go to Moscow,
would you stay here?
Why?
If I can't go.
But that's why we are
going to get married!
Even if I won't come with you?
What do you mean?
I don't understand.
I'll tell you who the mother
of your children really is.
I live here under a false name,
with the consent
of the concerned agencies,
because in the West,
I'm wanted as a terrorist.
Are you a terrorist?
Yes.
I used to be.
But terrorists are idiots
who kill innocent people.
Yes, that's what I used to do.
But you can't tell me this!
I am not allowed to know this!
I have to go there now, though.
No. 15, please step forward!
Please, take a seat.
Cigarette?
I came from Berlin.
Whatever.
This concerns
an ex-colleague of yours.
Maybe a girlfriend.
- She's not here anymore.
- We know that.
I'll tell you what I know.
She immigrated into the GDR
a long time ago, from the West.
- I didn't believe it at first.
- Why not?
I had never heard
of anything like that before.
But she was left, politically.
Her parents were killed
in an accident in Amsterdam.
She found out that she has siblings
in the West, so she moved back.
Unfortunately.
She was different
from all the others in the factory.
She was a strong supporter of the GDR,
something not everyone is.
I can't say anything bad
about her in this context.
Have others talked about her?
No, not really.
I don't think so.
But I want to know,
why have I been arrested?
I'm offering you a deal.
You agree, informally,
that we stay in touch.
Then you can go home.
It's a sign that you are
loyal to the republic.
Tatjana...
the wall is gone now,
and the border is open.
It's just like how
you always wanted it to be.
But you are in prison,
because you were in touch
with a terrorist.
And this didn't happen to you
in the West, but in the East.
That's crazy.
It is certain
that nothing in the other
part of Germany,
is ever going to be
the same as it used to be.
I'm writing down what
I'd say if you were here.
I imagined a life without
lies and deception, as you did.
And a different one.
It was clear to me, we are trapped
in an unjust, wrong system.
The guerilla couldn't achieve liberty,
because no one understood us.
When I arrived here,
I didn't want to hide.
I was looking for another world.
I wanted to move forwards,
not backwards.
I hope you'll
manage to get out soon.
You may come in.
The Federal Republic of Germany
demands the extradition
of these people.
How do they know
they are here?
They've always known.
- From whom?
- Maybe from us.
Why did we hide them then?
Twice, even!
We worked our butts off
to hide them.
Excuse me, comrade general.
I've arrested people,
because they might have known.
I can't believe, it was just a game!
Like in a secret agent movie scene!
If you don't explain the world to me,
I won't explain it to you either.
Do you have the address?
This is not an easy task.
You have to manipulate a lot here...
We've done something for them,
not the other way round.
They didn't tell us much
about their secrets.
Maybe they were criminals.
You can look at it like that.
But I'm disappointed
that we abandon them like this.
Why don't you go home and cry?
Your weapons, please!
That's how accidents happen, girl!
I'm sorry!
Look!
Unbelievable!
"Terrorist hidden by StaSi."
What do you think about it?
There you spend your time
with robbers and murders.
Anything for peace!
She was part of a choir.
They had money for things like that!
But we couldn't get decent Jeans.
She didn't do anything
to or against YOU,
I mean, US.
She didn't do anything against us.
One cannot live next to
a murderer, though!
This isn't my government anymore.
Maybe you'll never be
better off than now and here!
Here, you cannot lose your job
or be kicked out of your apartment.
You have no idea,
what's going to happen.
You have no idea what you are losing.
Maybe you'll be able
to afford decent trousers,
but not the butt
in those trousers.
I assume, you lost your mind.
This here was a great attempt,
a revolution.
Despite all the crap,
you were part of it.
It's supposed to be a world
that isn't ruled by money.
Why don't you believe in that anymore?
In yourselves anymore?
We can't do anything for you anymore.
What happened to Friederike?
You don't know?
I do.
But what happened?
They are going to get you, too.
This is still the GDR, though!
And in the GDR, you are going to be
arrested, through the people's police.
What a messed-up ending.
East is over there,
West over there.
You are wanted everywhere.
If they cannot find you today,
they are going to hunt you down.
Avoid airports and big train stations.
If you can, forget
we've ever known each other.
I will also forget it.
I can at least give you a ride.
Why have you arrested Tatjana?
Susanne!
Open up, it's me!
Hands up!
Against the wall!
Are you Rita Vogt?
Go faster!
I need to go to the toilet.
Actually, I cannot take
you with me without a helmet.
You don't know that
as an Eastern broad.
You were pretty much cut off.
But I don't have any prejudices.
Thanks.
It not any individual's fault.
Excuse me, I need to pee.
This is the East.
- She has killed several people.
- Here or in the West?
Doesn't matter,
order and security
are equal everywhere.
I won't shoot.
Documents, please.
THINGS WERE LIKE THIS
BUT NOT EXACTLY.
Invest in www.caseway.ai
to change the legal industry!