WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Previously on Australian Survivor...
- Keep going, keep going, keep going.
- ..Brawn was on a challenge roll...
Go, team!
..firing on all cylinders to bring
home reward and immunity.
Let's go! Let's go!
Sending brains to
their third tribal council.
King George's head has got to go.
With a 6-4 majority, Joey was
hell bent on getting George.
Tonight's the night we can
finally chop King George's head off.
Then Cara found an idol.
- This idol. It's a golden ticket.
- Sit down.
The plan was to play it for George,
but it relied on Baden
and Wai voting with them.
If we stick together,
they have no option.
- But...
- I'm sorry, George.
..Wai had already decided to flip sides.
I'm in a state of shock.
The thing is this.
You don't play your idol, no
matter what, and you survive, Cara.
But at tribal council, empath Cara
did play her idol to save George.
And...
Cara.
You're a hero, Cara.
..she was suddenly out of the game.
Or so they thought.
19 are left. Who will
be going home tonight?
"Your tribe may have spoken,
but your game is not over.
"Another tribe is waiting for
you. Take this torch and join."
Jinkies. Onwards and
upwards. Holy guacamole.
I don't even know what
to say. I can't even deal.
I thought it was all over for
sure. I think it's an amazing twist.
Picking my way over rocks
and water, and I'm just...
my head is already spinning.
I'm thinking, how am I going to
be received into the Brawn tribe?
Who knows what's going to happen next?
Hi!
Oh, sh...
What's going on?
- Oh, my God.
- Wait, what time is it?
I just wanted you to know.
You are?
I'm superstitious.
The moment we've put that snake skin
on that cow head, we started losing.
I'm going to take it
off and see if we win.
Yeah.
We're a resilient bunch
over at Team Brains.
Yeah.
We just keep showing up
with a big smile on our face.
Another crazy tribal council
at the Brains Tribe last night.
Oh, my. It was one for the ages.
There were tears. There was bloodshed.
There was all sorts last night.
We didn't get our man,
Georgie, but we got our girl, Cara.
So I'm sitting here pretty
at the top of my tribe.
It's a good day for man and womankind
out here in the Aussie outback.
Yeah, yeah, 100%. Yeah.
In terms of my alliance,
the pecking order is myself, Laura,
Andrew and Georgia at the top,
Rachel, Hayley and then
last night I've got Wai on board
which is majority.
So I think that I'm the
one calling the shots.
I'm the big lion and I'm the big
bad lion, the head of the pride.
I'm running this game.
I'm feeling sad in the camp
this morning, now that Cara is gone.
Last night's tribal
council was my crucifixion.
If Cara didn't save me by
playing her idol for me, I was out.
I mean, that is one of the
most honourable things
that someone's ever done.
There were three people
that were loyal on this tribe,
myself, Baden and Cara.
I thought Wai was loyal.
So nothing was more
disappointing at that tribal council
than when Wai flipped.
Wai believed the snake
oil salesman in Joey.
But when I write my book
featuring Joey, my main character,
that's going to be a best seller.
And now my kingdom has fallen.
I can't even look her in the eye
because I can't stomach her betrayal.
But I know one thing.
I'm going to confront Wai.
Let's move away.
Why do you have to stab me in the back?
- We were strong, we were loyal.
- I know.
And things just kind
of fell out the other way.
My concern is that you're very volatile.
I know that you've taken
me along this journey,
but it's just been really
frustrating to just feel like
I'm sitting back and being quiet
and just trying to kind
of go with your strategy.
It's still me, Wai.
I will always have a target on my back.
And you'll fight to the death
and continue to bring
chaos to everything.
And I kind of want to
enjoy my time. And I know...
I didn't ask to be frozen out by Joey.
- I didn't ask for that.
- I know you didn't.
But you are causing fallout around you.
I just think that what is going
to make me feel most at peace.
Oh, well.
- I did not expect this from you.
- I know you didn't, George.
I'm going to leave that at that now.
As a result of tribal last night,
emotions are still kind of high.
Things are a little bit awkward,
especially with George and I,
but I finally feel like I made
a move that's right for me.
I took a gamble and a risk
when I made the decision to defect
from the minor alliance
to the majority alliance.
I did feel in the beginning
that I had to align myself
with George just because I owed him,
because of the fact that he
saved me from the first tribal.
But I'm not here to play
anyone else's game but my own
and George, his game has
just become quite volatile
and difficult to work with.
So I'm happy to be
separated from George.
I took some control last night and
I'm stepping up my survival game.
One, under, two, three.
How pretty is the red?
I am delighted to be
rocking the Brawn tribe path.
I'm in the stronger tribe,
which is... very pleasant.
Breakfast.
I'm the luckiest person in the world.
So fancy.
Because it's got that lemongrass in it.
This is delicious.
Did you roast the almonds too?
This is how the other half live.
The luxury in the Brawn tribe is beyond.
They've got forks, for God's sake,
which can also be used as brushes.
I've just found out we've
even got serving plates.
They've got yoga and boxing.
Relax your shoulder, more hip.
And dance class.
To the left, to the back.
I really have gone from
Survivor hell to Survivor heaven,
and I'm so happy.
I feel like I've actually
just landed home.
I played my idol to save George
at last night's tribal council.
And I thought I was
voted out of the game.
I can't wait to see
the look on their faces
when the Brains tribe
realise that I'm still here.
Hi, baby.
Joey and Laura are the ones
who got me voted out last night.
So I'm going to start just
spilling the beans on everything.
Joey and Laura are pretty
much spearheading everything.
Really?
Yeah, and then they keep talking
about how they feel a bit more adult
because, you know,
they're doing all these things
and they're acting like children.
And George, he's really loyal.
Basically, there's a lot of
not... not so niceness over there.
Really?
We're going to have fun
when we see him again.
That we've got to discuss, hey?
It's quite clear that Cara's
allegiance is to the Brawn tribe.
And she's a little bit on the outer.
Although I'm in the minority
with Emmett, Dani and Chelsea
this gives me a lot of confidence.
With Cara joining our tribe it
means there's another number
that's up for grabs, which is huge.
So to get her to join our
alliance is another vote
that we can use moving forward.
I didn't tell George at all that I
was going to use my idol on him.
Oh, OK. So George should have
gone. You played your idol for him.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
We need her because my alliance
of four then becomes a majority.
I would have stayed, but
I'm about building people up.
I'm certainly not about
cutting people down.
Yeah. I've got two
idols in my back pocket.
I just need to make
sure that I've got Cara.
And then we're sweet.
I think Cara is going to be
an easy one to pull across.
One tribe's loss is another one's gain.
And for me, Cara, is a hot commodity
and I'm making a beeline for her.
Oh, I don't know.
Simon and I feel like mum and dad
of two different alliances in this tribe
and Cara is an extra vote for whoever
can pocket her in their alliance.
I'm a big player and I
want her on my side.
If Simon gets her, then I'm in
deep trouble, so I need to make sure
I get there first.
Warm it up, warm it up, warm
it up, warm it up, warm it up.
- I!
- I believe!
- I believe that we will win!
I believe that we will win!
Come on in, guys.
Brains getting your first
look at the new Brawn Tribe.
Cara, joining Brawn
after last night's tribal.
Oh, my God, Cara!
Cara, I'm so happy to see you.
I'm sure I'm the only
one happy to see you.
We're happy here.
Maybe you actually heard
what happens on this tribe.
It sounds horrible.
George, George. Your loss, our gain.
Huge gain for you. You gained a legend.
So, Cara. Have you had time to
process what happened last night?
It took a little while
to process for sure.
I have been accepted and
welcomed with fully open arms.
And I was thinking this is
actually what I signed up for.
Not the Brawn tribe,
but just the heart tribe.
Like, I just actually
feel really at home.
Simon, how does it feel
having a new tribe mate?
You know, it's really cool
just how well that Cara has fit
into this tribe in such
a short amount of time.
It's almost like she
was meant to be here.
So very much so one team, one dream.
Alright. You guys ready to
get to today's reward challenge?
Yes.
In today's challenge, you're
each going to hold a rope
attached to a heavy barrel.
If you tire, you can tap out and
hand your rope to someone else.
But once you do that,
you can't come back in.
If you drop your barrel
and it hits the ground,
the entire tribe is
out of the challenge.
Last tribe with all their
barrels in the air, wins reward.
- Want to know what you're playing for?
- Yes!
Good old fashioned...
Aussie barbecue.
I'm not even going to ask
if this is worth playing for.
Oh, yeah.
Alright. Brawn, today,
you have an extra player.
You're gonna need to sit someone out.
Cannot be the same person
in back to back challenges.
Who's it gonna be?
Well, I'm the weakest I don't mind.
We'll get you fit, don't you worry.
OK, Cara, you're on the bench.
Everyone else, I'll give you a
minute to strategise. Let's get to it.
- Brawn on three!
- One, two three, Brawn!
Alright, for reward,
this challenge is now on.
Everyone's locked and loaded,
holding up a heavy barrel.
To make it fair, each tribe
is holding a percentage
of their collective weight.
If at any point, it
gets too much for you,
you can hand it off to someone else,
but you have to have one hand
on the ring at any given time.
If you do that too soon, you
risk overloading your tribe mate.
If you wait too long, you
risk dropping the barrel
and then your whole tribe misses
out on that Aussie barbecue.
It's hot today.
That's going to make
it a little more difficult.
Flies. They're out in full force.
Brains hasn't won a
reward in over two weeks.
Wai working really hard, trying
to hold in as long as she can.
Andrew, you good?
Drop it like it's hot, Wai.
Brawn targeting Wai.
Brawn feeling very confident today.
Andrew coaching her through.
Andrew takes Wai's barrel.
Thank you, Andrew.
And Wai is out of the challenge.
We're one down. Dun, dun, daaa!
Andrew first with two
barrels on the Brains tribe.
They've gone 19 minutes
further than I thought they would.
True dat.
You're looking strong, George.
That's one of the first nice things
someone said to me for days,
so thank you.
Shannon taps out.
Hands her barrel to Simon.
And just like that, Shannon
is out of the challenge.
You guys have been at it for 30 minutes.
Whoo-hoo!
Emmett takes a barrel from Simon.
Baden handing back to Rachel.
Oh, very close to losing it.
Not even.
Rachel carrying all the
weight now for Brains.
Don't hurt yourself.
Georgia really struggling now.
Georgia could be in trouble.
Brains are feeling the
weight of all those barrels.
You've got this, Georgia.
Brawn, having a party over there.
Oh, hey!
Right, guys, you've
been at it for one hour.
- Nice work, guys.
- Yes, Brawn.
Staying strong.
Baden coming back
in, offering some relief.
Big D's in the house.
Simon handing off to
Chelsea, handing off to Daini.
Hey, Chelsea!
You have to have one hand
on the ring at any given time.
And you had both hands
free during the transfer.
You're out.
- Alright, we're in good shape, guys.
- We're in good shape, come on.
Sorry.
Emmett, inching his
way over, hands it to Dani.
Danny to Gerald.
Daini, back to Simon.
Lots of transfers for Brawn.
Dani really struggling now.
You right?
Two, one.
Dani drops out, hands
her barrel to Emmett.
Oh, yes, yes, we got this, guys.
Brawn have six players now.
- Brains still have eight.
- Whoo!
That is a distinct advantage.
Emmett handing back to Gerald.
Gerald has two, Simon has two.
Daini has two.
I've got to help Daini out.
They're running out of options now.
Come on.
We are 90 minutes into this challenge.
Yeah, all day!
Let's do another 90. Come on!
- 90 more!
- Things are really heating up.
Gerald struggling
with those two barrels.
- Come on, Gezza.
- Trying to keep them up.
We are so close to what we
wanted, an Aussie barbecue.
Let's just keep going.
No one wants to be responsible
for losing all that
protein over at Brawn.
Guys, guys. Focus on ourselves. Focus.
Gerald at full stretch.
Groaning in pain.
All day, guys, all day.
Really trying to find
that strength to hold in.
Gerald buckled over.
Giving it everything.
One hand for Gerald.
Really stretching to
get both hands on it.
Big dig from Gerald.
Oh, that's it!
Let the barrels go.
And Brains win their first reward!
Brains, congratulations.
You finally did it. You won
probably the best reward so far.
Barbie!
Well done. It'll be waiting for you
back at camp, head on out. Enjoy.
Thanks, guys. Thank you.
Brawn, great effort.
But for the first time this
season, got nothing for you.
- Grab your gear, head on out.
- Thanks. See ya.
Finally, we won a reward
and we've won the best reward ever.
A bloody barbecue!
We really put our
bodies on the line today,
which has actually made the
victory taste a little bit sweeter.
There's only so far that rice and
lentils can get a woman, you know.
Oh, my God.
Oh, my gosh.
Welcome to the winner's circle!
This is amazing.
Oh, wow.
Wow.
Let's get into it.
This is the first proper
food we've eaten in 15 days.
- Oh, salt!
- Whoo!
- That could not have been better. - Oh!
There was green salad and potato salad.
We had vegetable skewers and chops.
I'm just going to keep eating.
I feel like this barbecue
could fuel us forever.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, my God.
The lemonade! Give me
more of that lemonade.
That was amazing. Tasted like heaven.
Cheers. Cin-cin.
First bite of that frittata
was like an angel peeing in your mouth.
It was delicious.
It's just the fuel and the energy
we really need to keep on winning.
We can beat the Brawn tribe
and we can outbrawn them
and outbrain them.
I slayed that reward today.
We ate that meat like
a pack of carnivores.
For 15 days, the Brains tribe
has been licking rice and
lentils and beans off a rock.
If this is going to be my last night,
I'm going to eat as much
of the food as possible.
Did you recognise her
when she was walking in?
No, I didn't.
Today at the challenge, the
shock of my life happened.
Cara popped up in the Brawn Tribe.
Cara's my closest ally
and I'm delighted that she's still in.
Oh, my goodness, I
thought I got rid of Cara.
I thought, I've got rid of
George all these times.
Who wants half a sausage?
They just keep coming back
from the dead. This is crazy.
Right now, it's
become very clear to me
that there are big players always
making big moves in this tribe.
A massive part of this game
is that you have to be
able to outwit people.
You have to be strategic.
I'm a pain researcher.
That means you get to manipulate
the way people are thinking.
So I have a really good read on people.
I think that my plan of coming
in here and getting everyone
to trust me has worked.
It's really fun to be out here
and pretend to look easygoing
and not threatening.
Because floating in the
middle is a nice place to be,
but there's no way I came here to
just be a number for someone else.
So I want to find a way to make a
move and take control of this game.
Because I am here to win.
Well done, guys.
Good evening, jocks.
Honestly, every one of us
there went as hard as we could.
The main thing is that we
keep... get up back on our horse
and keep going.
I lost the challenge for the team.
At the end of the day,
it was me that let go of
those handles and I think
I might be on the chopping block.
The Brawns tribe dug so deep today.
We didn't win the reward
and I can just feel there are
a few fractures in the tribe.
My ability to read people
is my secret weapon.
And I'm always looking for opportunity
to use my empath skills.
The other part that's kind of odd,
but interesting, good party trick
- is that I'm an empath.
- So cool.
And right now, I think it's a
really good time to use them
because we need to
galvanise the tribe together.
so I can literally just touch people
and feel pain in their
bodies and stuff like that.
Ooh, that's weird.
I'm just going to check on that,
because that sounds weird, but.
These ones. That. What's that from?
Oh, really?
Yeah, I just get full
activation around here.
You're kind of spot on,
never injured myself.
Really?
Yeah, and the only
thing that's on my mind
and has been for the last two
years is probably having kids.
- And what that means.
- Yeah, that's what I feel.
Now I'm a little teary.
Wow, like I'm in shock.
Cara's ability to pick up on
people's emotions and pain,
it works.
You need that positive
energy in your tribe.
It's cool. It's so cool.
I know Shannon
has taken to pull Cara in close.
It is so crucial that I
get Cara in my side,
especially before we go to
the next immunity challenge.
To get her to join our alliance,
it's really important to ensure
that I have a connection with her,
but I haven't had a really
good chance to chat to her yet.
So first things first.
I need to form a bond with Cara.
She's the kind of person that
has a lot of emotional intelligence.
So I'm going to choose very
carefully and be very strategic
about how I approach this.
And...
How are all the women when
they go through menopause?
Umm...
I went through early.
So I went through, like 43.
Yep.
Um... and that was hard.
Yeah.
And look at you now, hey? Out here.
Simon is a strong player, but
he is no match when it comes
to my social game.
If we lose the next
challenge and we go to tribal.
Simon is the only thing on my radar.
Come on in, guys.
- Joey.
- Yo.
It's been a long time coming. Was
the reward as good as you imagined?
Six in a row. Six losses.
Yeah, we still showed up yesterday.
We still bought it and we got the win
and victory tasted oh, so sweet.
Cara, on the other
hand, you're the only one
who hasn't enjoyed a reward.
- That's got to suck.
- A little bit.
Yeah, I was a little bit disappointed,
but I'm not so food-based.
I'm love and heart-based.
Alright, you guys ready to get
to today's immunity challenge?
Yes.
Hell, yeah, that's what I like to hear.
Thank you, sir.
Once again, immunity
is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're going to race up
a ramp to collect ropes.
Two of you will use those
ropes to build a rope bridge.
Allowing the rest of the tribe
to cross over, climb up a tower
and retrieve an idol.
Once you have your idol, you
make your way under a cargo net
to collect your last pieces
of rope from a high rail.
Finally, four of you will use that
rope to hoist your idol up to a hook.
First tribe to hook their idol
wins immunity, safe from the vote.
Losers, tribal council, where
somebody is going to become
the sixth person voted out.
Brawn, you got an extra player
you're gonna need to sit someone out.
Cannot be the same person
in back to back challenges.
Who is it gonna be?
You're gonna need height, so
I'm gonna be the one jumping up.
Dani, you're on the bench,
everyone else a minute to strategise.
Let's get to it.
Alright, here we go, for immunity.
Oh, actually, hang on,
there's one more thing.
Oh, here we go.
There is a hidden immunity
idol on the course today.
Oh, gosh.
It's hidden at the big Survivor logo.
So if you want it or need
it, go ahead and grab it.
But in doing so, you could
cost your whole tribe immunity.
Survivors, ready.
Go!
The first thing you need
to do is collect all the ropes.
That'll clear a path through the
obstacle so you can all move through.
Brawn have half of theirs.
- Run.
- Go through. Go through, go through.
Brain have half of theirs.
Brains are working quickly today.
Everyone needs to be on your
mat before you can move on.
Run up. You need a run up.
Rachel struggling on
the ramp for Brains.
Right. All on the mat.
Oh, Cara takes a tumble for Brawn.
You good, Brawns? Start
working on your bridge.
George quickly breaking
away from his tribe.
He's going to have
a search for that idol.
Hayley right on his tail.
What the are they doing?
We've got time. We've got time.
And Gerald breaks away from Brawn.
Three of them furiously
looking for that idol.
Ah, Hayley got it.
Hayley, she finds the idol.
That's it.
Comes back to her tribe.
There's a cost to the Brain tribe.
Finally, Brains can
start work on their bridge.
Slow and steady, guys, you got it.
Emmett and Simon, working
well together for Brawn.
Have half of their bridge completed.
Good job, guys.
Hayley, she really wants
to make up for lost time now.
There's a few that aren't
sitting flush on the right.
Alright. I'll fix them.
- Alright, you guys ready?
- Go, Brawn.
Alright, here we go.
Simon's across.
Chelsea on the bridge, now.
Move it. That's it.
Hayley is on a mission
in this challenge.
Got immunity for herself.
She wants to get
immunity for her entire tribe.
Brains have their bridge
completed. Andrew going across.
Good job, guys.
Get ready to climb, get ready to climb.
Shannon last on the bridge for Brawn.
Let's go, go, go, go, go.
Brawn's good. You're
across the bridge. Go!
Watch your back, there.
Up that tower. Simon grabs the idol.
Brawn heading under the net, now.
Simon, Daini, holding
it up for everyone else.
- Hold it up.
- I'm going through.
Quick, quick, quick.
Can you hold it?
Brawn go through the net,
Kez and Shannon going up to
fetch those final pieces of rope.
- Joey is last for Brains. - Nice, Joey.
Get up that tower!
Everyone needs to be at the
top before you can move on.
OK, you're good, Brains.
Andrew has the idol.
Get under that net.
Come on, guys. You got this.
You're doing really well.
Brawn have two of their
ropes, working on the last two.
Good work, guys.
Andrew, pull Rach out.
Come on!
Rachel, last to come through
the net for Brains, really struggling.
They drag her through on her belly.
I've got you, Georgia. I've got you.
Shannon, working on
the last rope for Brawn
She's good! You're good, Brawn.
Move on!
Alright now you need to
throw those ropes over the rail.
Here we go.
Yes!
Nice!
Big D has his rope in
place. Simon has his.
You need to pick it up, Brains.
- Right?
- Hold me, hold me.
Just stay there.
That's it.
Gerald has his. Now you
need to clip them under the disc
to lift up that idol.
Guys, nice job.
We've got to take our time
with this so it doesn't fall off.
Don't panic.
Nice and easy.
All ready? Nice and easy.
All you need to do is
hook that idol at the top.
And you get to relax
tonight back at camp.
Gerald, Gerald... Simmo.
- Me, me.
- You, you, you.
Simmo! Simmo and Gerald.
Oh, boys.
There's definitely a
learning curve involved here.
You have to work together.
Do you want the girls to have a go?
Finally, Andrew has the last rope.
Go, Brains, you can move on.
Baden, Laura, Joey and George
on the final stage of this challenge,
trying to hook that
rope over that high rail.
That's it, guys. Good work,
Laura. Good work, guys.
George, that's enough.
Click it under your disc.
Three, two, one, go.
Just a tiny bit at a time. Tiny.
Despite Brawn's huge lead,
we are neck and neck again.
Yeah, I think we need
a better technique.
Cara and Chelsea are
subbing in for Brawn.
We're going to get slack and
we're all going to go one at a time.
Yeah.
Alright. Three, two, one, up.
Simon and Chelsea, yep, hold it there.
That's it. Hold it here. Nice.
- Hold it here.
- Maybe they're on to something here.
Three, two, one.
And they go again.
Slower than that. Way
slower than that, man.
Yeah, it's got to be super slow.
What are they doing? Tell us.
Bit by bit. With just one person.
Wai, can you please go a tiny bit?
Wait, wait. Everybody wait.
Brains finally have something
that's looking steady.
Brawn get a little higher again.
Hold, hold, hold.
Cara would really like to
prove herself to her new tribe.
Chelsea and Cara release
as we pull. Three, two, one, go.
That's it.
Slowly down, slowly down.
- Slowly down.
- It's on.
Got it!
That's it!
Brawn win immunity!
Oh, my God!
Good job. Good job.
Brawn, congratulations.
Once again, immunity is yours.
She made us work for
it, but she's coming home.
Well done. You guys are safe tonight.
Nobody going home,
grab your gear, head on out.
- Enjoy your night off.
- Thank you, guys.
Alright, Brains. Tribal council
again tonight, where one
of you will become the sixth person
voted out of the Australian Survivor
Brains vs Brawn.
Grab your gear, head on
out. I'll see you guys tonight.
See you tonight.
Kind of sucks that we
lost, but I've got something in store.
I have an idol now and I'm
ready to blow up the game.
Tribal tonight will be fireworks.
- Here, guys.
- I'm stuffed.
Oh, well.
It is what it is.
We'll win the next one.
I've got dirt in places
I've never had dirt before.
So shall we swim, people? Let's swim.
Let's swim.
Wash away our loss.
- Yes.
- We tried that one.
Unfortunately, we came up short
today in the immunity challenge.
So we're off to tribal
tonight to see what happens.
Obviously I want George out
and I think the tribe
will be stronger for it.
He is dangerous in this game.
He is a strategic player
and that is a threat.
So tonight, Georgie is going home.
So we vote George,
we're obviously splitting.
We're 100% splitting. Secondary...
Wai.
I feel a little bit bad because
I did bring Wai into the fold,
you know, for the tribal two nights
ago, and she gave us the numbers
we needed, but I think
it served its purpose.
So tonight, if George plays
an idol, Wai is going home.
OK. So we got it sorted.
I think it's as
straightforward as it gets.
Look, at the end of the
day, everyone's coming to me
to come up with the strategies
because I got the moves.
I'm playing chess. They
playing checkers.
Oh, well, congratulations, Hayley.
That idol's gonna probably propel
you to the top three or four now.
That would be fantastic.
Are you gonna play it for me tonight?
Stranger things have happened.
Well, it was worth asking.
Famous last words, mate.
Oh, it is a breath of fresh air
to know that Hayley got
to that idol before George.
Hayley is definitely
someone I feel like I can trust.
At the end of the day, one of
my alliance members has it.
George doesn't have
it, which is the big thing.
So I feel like it's in my back
pocket whenever I need it.
I am the puppet master.
I'm pulling all the strings.
At the challenge, the idol
was centimetres away from me
and I just didn't see it.
And the next minute, Hayley's
picked it up and she's running away.
It was at that point in time I
knew that my goose was cooked.
The Brains tribe is my political
party, and tonight's tribal council
is Election Day.
The poll's definitely against
me, but the only option is to fight.
So I have to convince Joey's majority
to vote for someone else tonight.
Alright, guys. Am I
able to have a little say?
- Yeah, yeah. Have it.
- Shoot, mate.
Sorry. I'll let you guys
ponder your thoughts,
because clearly I know
my position on this tribe.
You know, I know I'm
public enemy number one.
So I'm the obvious choice for tonight.
But I also I think getting rid
of me right now is emotional.
So the question is, who goes tonight?
The other people that I think
are at least worth thinking about -
you've got Wai. We know what
she can contribute in challenges.
You've got Rachel.
Is she weaker than Wai?
If it's me, it's not
going to be a surprise.
That's just my commentary.
I hear ya.
- So, that's... that's it.
- Right.
Working with these people
is like trying to milk a donkey.
I'm sure it's theoretically possible,
but you're going to get a sour outcome.
And that's what it feels
like for me on this tribe.
I'm milking, I'm milking,
I'm milking away.
But nothing good is coming out of it.
Oh, my God.
My only hope is for Hayley
to play her idol for me.
Otherwise, it's game over.
So George just gave
us his final, you know.
- His sales piece.
- Oh, cool. I want to know what it is.
Oh, well, it's... He, he...
He should be in politics.
We're not taking
another risk with Georgie.
100% he's the primary.
OK.
Like, it is what it is.
There's a clear hierarchy
in this tribe making all the calls
and the rest of us are
just following along.
George is a big target, but
I've got some other ideas.
Finding the idol, it does bring
me power and it makes me feel
like I can make big moves.
So tonight presents an opportunity.
We could get rid of one of
the biggest threats in the game,
and no one will suspect that
I would orchestrate this vote.
It's about time to gather up all
the people at the bottom of this tribe
to take the head off the snake.
I'm going to take control of
the game and I'm going to do it
without using my idol tonight.
Yep.
How are you feeling going forward?
Feeling like...
It's obviously going to
go, George, and then Wai.
Yep. I hear you.
Who have they said for you to vote for?
George.
Orders come down the
line and I'm not enjoying that.
Did you have any interest
in, in... in something tonight?
These guys?
Who would you pick?
Would you have any interest
in, in... in something tonight?
These guys?
Who would you pick?
That's a pretty big move.
But I like your thinking.
Do you know what? I actually
wouldn't have been surprised...
I'm all about stirring stuff up.
Oh, I know that. I know that.
But, um...
I need some carnage
to keep me interested.
Yeah.
I'm in.
Right now, Joey is at
the top of the alliance.
He is like the puppet master
who's running this camp.
So I've decided we
could get Joey out tonight.
It would mean that I knock out a
huge social threat down the line
that's gonna be dangerous for my game.
So all I need is four other
votes to take him down.
I've got Baden.
Now I need Rachel, Wai and
George to make this happen.
But I know no one wants
to work with George,
so I have a huge task on my hands.
Well, then that's when
things start getting serious.
- Yeah.
- What were you thinking?
I think it's too risky.
There is a lot at stake
and I am very stressed
that this plan won't come off.
Wai is going to be a
difficult one to convince.
She voted with Joey
at the last tribal council
and now I need to know that
she's willing to work with George.
It's her name as the split vote tonight.
So she needs to come to
her senses and make a move.
Yeah.
So there's an option we could
do something different tonight.
OK.
But please don't tell everyone
else and then kill my game.
And I don't want you to
go, but what we could do...
Yeah, I know.
Could do it. Could do it.
Is that your gut? That's what you feel.
Because if we burn bridges
now, it could come back to bite us.
You know, that's the hardest
part about this decision.
We are.
Hayley's put Joey's name out there
and I can see the pros and cons.
The advantage of voting up
Joey is Joey is definitely a threat.
So it's important to take him out
now while we still have numbers.
But on the other hand, what I don't
want to do is reverse my situation
and end up back in a place where
I am stuck with George's volatility.
I'm part of the majority alliance now
and I know how
dangerous a position I'm in.
And to kind of turn my back on them,
I don't want to jeopardise
my position further.
I think if I save George, I'm
putting myself at risk here.
I empathise with both sides
and I just need time to process it.
What are you going to do again,
Wai? Are you gonna vote for me again?
- I don't know.
- I mean, we have to vote.
Have you reflected on what
happened two nights ago?
I reflected well.
I guess, like I said,
ownership and I own it.
I trusted you 100%.
People are very surprising and
people can be disappointments.
And that's part of
what we learn about life.
Yeah, I know. And no one is more
disappointed in me, Wai. Trust me.
I know.
I can think about it when
I'm packing my bags tonight.
I don't see a light at
the end of this tunnel.
I know my pitch has failed with Joey.
I know I'm going home
at tonight's tribal council.
My last day here.
If there is a Macedonian
Jesus out there,
I need my bacon saved tonight.
I've put in a lot of
legwork today already.
Everyone else is on board to
vote out Joey, but George is pivotal
for this plan.
Because right now I
need George as a number.
I haven't even been
able to talk to him at all.
I'm sure I could somehow
talk to him at tribal.
But if Joey doesn't go tonight, that
could be really dangerous for me.
Every vote is so important.
I'm feeling very comfortable, I feel
like tonight we have the numbers,
so I don't want any mistakes tonight.
Georgie has to go.
Everyone's falling into line
and I'm calling the shots.
So King George's head will roll.
This should be an easy one tonight.
It's a no-brainer.
So, Hayley, last time
you guys were here,
you chose to go ahead
and get rid of Cara.
Why was that?
We made that choice because
there was a lot of tension
around the camp and some of that
was tied up between relationships
Cara had with people
who are still here now.
And we collectively thought that
it would be better if we let Cara go
so that we could clear
some of that tension.
So, Rachel, did that work?
It definitely worked.
Yesterday, winning,
winning the reward challenge.
I don't think I've had a
better day actually at camp.
We had fun. It felt lighter.
So Georgia, with such
a happy, united tribe,
is it going to be difficult to
vote someone out tonight?
I mean, it's always difficult
to vote someone out.
But, you know, we need
to do what's necessary
to continue moving forward.
Baden. In the dynamic of your
tribe, where do you think you sit?
I'm not overly concerned at the moment.
And by the time it's my numbers
up, according to these guys,
I plan to have something in
place to turn the tables on them.
At the end of the day, you
align yourself with people
to advance your position.
I just so happen to have an alliance
that I've got people that I trust
and they can trust in me.
One team, one dream.
So, Hayley, where do you think
you sit in that pecking order?
Um, it is hard to say. I think
everybody's hierarchy is different.
And that's what makes
this game so complicated.
My priority is to make sure
that I have built really
good relationships.
So when Survivor starts to crumble,
that something is there to be held.
So, Laura, do you agree that
there is an order of who goes next?
Within the alliance
and network that we built
I don't have an order at all.
And like zero.
So you're saying that everyone
in the alliance, in the alliance
- is on equal footing?
- Yeah.
But Wai, isn't that exactly
what people at the top want,
the people at the bottom to believe?
I think the intention is there.
As long as we can stay unified
and stay together, then we don't
have to start thinking
in that kind of way.
And that might keep us OK.
So would you say there's an
alliance controlling tonight's vote?
Yes, I think there is a plan and
that should be how things work out.
Andrew. Sometimes when you
come to tribal, it's just an easy vote.
Is it gonna be an easy one tonight?
I just think there's just so many
unknowns and you just don't know
who's going to pull a
rabbit out of the hat.
Sometimes the, you know, the
hunter can become the hunted.
I guess we're going to
find out tonight, right?
So, Hayley, how do you think
the tribe is going to change
in its dynamics after tonight's vote?
Um, I think that we will
come together more strongly
after this, I think.
George, is it a concern to hear
that the tribe is going to
be more unified after tonight
when you've been an
outsider for so long?
I don't think so.
I mean, being from Bankstown,
I've been an outsider my whole life.
We don't get a fair
share of our resources
and you have to fight for things.
And that's what I am, a fighter.
So if I have to fight for
unity, that's what I'll fight for.
I could be part of a unified team.
I think I showed that
yesterday. I'm the total package.
I'm strong at the puzzles.
I'm athletic.
I have extreme mental endurance
and physically I'm in good shape.
So I bring an asset to this tribe
and you need assets to move forward.
Laura, you have a look on your
face that says you don't agree.
George, I don't completely
agree with you there.
You showed great resilience
yesterday in that challenge.
Absolutely.
But what George contributed
to our society as a tribe
has been lacking compared to others.
So, George, this side of the
tribe is pointing at you saying
that you're part of the problem
when it comes to the
unification of this tribe.
There's no utility in
looking in the past.
I like to look forward to the future.
And the future is going to be bleak
if we just keep getting
picked off one by one.
At the end of the day, the
past is the best predictor
of future behaviour.
I mean, that's basic human psychology.
So I've got a good feeling
where my vote will go.
But as we've seen before, things
can change around here very quickly.
So, Hayley, Georgia makes a good point.
It's not over until it's over.
Yeah.
Is there still time to make
something happen tonight?
I think we've all had
conversations already
about what we want to happen.
I have no intention of changing my
conversations that I've had before.
So.
It's yeah, it's ready to go.
So, George, after
hearing all this discussion,
do you think your poll
numbers have gone up or down?
Jonathan, I've been praying
to the Survivor gods all day.
I'm hoping for a very good outcome.
But as a good politician knows,
the polling numbers
don't look good for me.
I know that.
But the polls are sometimes wrong
and I'm hoping they're wrong tonight.
But you either have the
numbers or you don't.
And I don't think I have
the numbers on this tribe.
Alright, well, I think it's time
to find out where those polls sit.
It is time to vote.
Alright, well, I think
it's time to vote.
Georgia, you're up.
Joey, leader of the cool kids.
I watched you build your alliance
up. Now watch me break it down.
Georgie, this is the only time
you're ever going to get my vote.
I don't trust you and I can't
march forward into this game
with you still in.
Joey, I'm praying to the Macedonian
Jesus and the Survivor gods
that you run out of snake oil tonight.
I will count the votes.
If anyone has an immunity
idol and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
OK, I'll read the votes.
First vote, Wai.
George.
It's one vote Wai, one vote, George.
George. That's two votes,
George, one vote, Wai.
George.
Three votes, George. One vote, Wai.
Joey.
One vote, Wai. Three votes,
George. One vote, Joey.
Joey.
That's three votes, George.
Two votes, Joey. One vote, Wai.
Joey.
We're tied.
Three votes, Joey. Three
votes, George. One vote, Wai.
Joey.
That's four votes, Joey,
three votes, George.
One vote Wai, one vote left.
The sixth person voted out of
Australian Survivor: Brains Vs Brawn,
Joey.
Need to bring me your torch.
- Oh, my God.
- See yas.
See ya.
Joey, the tribe has spoken.
- It was a fun ride.
- It sure was.
- Cheers, mate.
- Time for you to go.
Well, if there's one thing
we've learned tonight,
it's don't ever trust the polls.
Grab your torches,
head on out. Good night.
Oh, you kill me.
Tomorrow night on Australian Survivor -
the tides have finally
turned at the Brains tribe,
I'm feeling absolutely ecstatic.
But in the game of Survivor,
you never know what's round the corner.
It is time to drop your buffs.
My position in the game is back
in the hands of the Survivor gods,
I could be on the bottom again.
I wanted to be the
blindside king, but in the end,
I got hit with the biggest
blindside this season's seen.
I didn't see it coming.
I definitely got outwitted today.
It was a bit of a boss move
and I'm just... I am left in shock.
I don't really know the mechanics
of what happened tonight.
I've got to go process that.
I still can't see George lasting
too much longer in this game,
but I feel like there is potentially
a bit of a power shift underway.