In the year 1701, in a royal
hallway of Edo castle,
Lord Akou assaulted Kira,
a nobleman, with his sword!
Lord Akou was made to commit hara-kiri
as his vassals scattered as ronin,
disguised as merchants and doctors...
Our story begins one year later,
in a poor neighbourhood in Edo
By this winter morning,
sword fighting has blown
out of fashion with the wind
For Rent
Wake up!
Morning time... Wake up!
Quick, wash your face and
get down to the fish market
Let me sleep a little longer, Onobu...
You took the day off yesterday
The sun's already up!
Hurry up!
I'll leave you behind
All this noise
every damned morning
Please let me escape this dump
Is master Soza up and about?
What's your business with him?
I'm sure you're up to no good
Do you have to put it like that?
He needs my advice, that's all
Hurry, Pa, or they'll close
the fish market
I'm taking the day off
You took the day off yesterday
What are you still doing in bed?
Good morning, Osae san
Already off?
The weather's so fine, I'll deliver
the sewing I've finished
Good for you
Off you go
Did you hear that?!
Who cares
Ouch!
What the hell
Can't be helped
in such close quarters...
Watch yourself
How's things?
You know they're never good
Right
At this rate,
I'll never get Onobu to marry me
Fool, you know Onobu's
going to marry me
There you go again
Later
HANA
I envy you
If your revenge plan goes well,
you'll be a rich and respected man
You can leave this seedy life behind
Lucky your father left you
a score to settle
My father died peacefully
that's no use at all
Hirano san, where to, today?
To the castle
Oh, to see your friend, the retainer?
Enough of that ingrate
I've got a relative who's
assigned to the study in Edo castle
I am off to petition him
for an official post
A good position
in contact with the Shogun
I once did this man a favor...
Off already?
I must be on my way
Hey, ronin
If you want the castle, it's this-a-way
Excuse me
You heard? He knows
one of the government retainers
And has a relative in the castle study
Oh, no, the tale keeps
getting taller and taller
I found him, your enemy
Not, again...
This time, I swear it's him
The water's perfect
I know another guy...
"Height 175cm,
fair skin with regular teeth
WANTED
Ah, the marked cheek is on his face,
not his backside...
Yes
Age?
Thirty
Thirty...
Much older looking
since I last saw him...
Don't lose heart, Soza
Finding a man in Edo's sprawl
is like winning the lottery
It could take 10 years, no, 20...
Hey, sis, another sake
Patience...
But he's the right height, right?
I'll go over it once more
so listen well
Our shit fertilizes
the rice paddies and fields
That's why the farmer pays money
to buy it from the rich landlord,
who owns this tenement
And that money pays for New Year's
rice cakes for all of us
You mean, rice cakes
come from shit?
Well, not quite,
but you're not far off, either
Useless, it's damp!
That's a fine sum
Don't be stingy with those rice cakes
Save that line for when
you've paid your rent
And I don't recall letting a room
to that prancing idiot beside you
I'll work hard for lots of
rice cakes next year
Yeah, let's do that
Despite the passage of time you've
yet to avenge your father
Our entire family struggles
to sustain itself
My frugal housekeeping permits me
to forward this sum,
but alas, there is no more...
The samurai goes to the
bath house daily,
thanks to money made off
peasants' backs...
I bet...
You've never killed a soul
Just like you've never used
that sword against anyone
How the hell are you ever
going to avenge your father?
“How the hell..."
I'll strike him with all my might
and if that's not sufficient,
I'll take my life gracefully
just like the cherry blossoms
That's the Warrior's way of death
This, my father taught me
One rainy night last spring,
the man who lived here, was
ruined and decided to end it all
He got as far as slashing
his wife's throat,
but then his only kid
turned on him and stabbed him
Hearing the noise I rushed over,
this place was a sea of blood
Right about where you're sitting now...
The old man was bleeding to death,
guts spurting
I wouldn't call that graceful...
I'd call it a massacre
That's what a man's death means
Don't talk about living and dying,
without being ready for the worst
Good morning, Soza san
Good morning
Are you going out?
Just to the toilet
You, Osae san?
We're going to pray at the shrine
You should come, Soza san
No, Shinnosuke
He's a busy man
Mother
Good day
What did you pray for?
That I may find my enemy soon
Mother?
That you may stay a sweet-natured boy
And you?
That Father will return safely
How can one god answer
so many prayers?
Come here, come here and buy
Take a look at these toys,
very popular!
I've got every kind
We go this-a-way,
we go that-a-way
My husband died of
a lung disease
when our boy was only two
Today is his monthly anniversary
I see...
Time keeps passing by and
I haven't yet told him the truth
What does that say?
No tabs
What's a tab?
A tab? A tab means...
You want to eat now but pay later
Sada san's always asking for that
Actually, he never,
ever pays his tabs, so we call
someone like him "a deadbeat"
How do you write
“run out on debts?"
“Deadbeat?”
The way you write it...
You write "step out"...
with "on your debts"
means “run out"
Let's try that again
Abacus and Writing
Lessons
Clear the abacus
for the next calculation...
Abacus and Writing
Lessons
That's 7 pence
Eight pence
Five pence
Two pence
Three pence
If you're going to teach,
why not teach swordfighting?
What's the point in a world
with no more war? Idiot
But a samurai teaching the abacus?
Got nothing to do with avenging...
As they say,
“Hunger is a terrible master..."
"Hunger's the master"
The point is, a man
doesn't need to read if he's
got the guts to fight
As they say here,
“Only the countrymen keep their money"
We spend our money as soon as
we make it. Who needs calculations?
You're not even from around here
You're in the way, move
What do you want in there?
Soza san to teach me how to write
You, too?
At least I'll learn how
to write my own name
You have no guts
You should learn, too
Damn it
"My own name" my ass!
I'll never write a single word,
until the day I die
Everyone finished?
Can you believe Kenbo's
learning to write?
He's smart
and good looking
Good bye
See you tomorrow
Clinic
Isn't he going to inherit
the martial arts academy?
Yes, his father was a grand
fencing master
A samurai teaching kids to write...
It's not right
You... should investigate
He may be have ties to Kira
I warned you about this
Even scattered, it's risky
with too many of us in town
All right
Not to worry, it's nothing
Though I can't heal
much more than this
Soza san, is this the first time
you've met Kichiemon?
Yes
I'm Kichiemon
I'm Aoki Soza-emon
Soza san has come from up north,
to avenge his father
I see
Revenge, huh...
It's been over two and a half years now,
with no leads...
Two and a half years, I'm sorry
But why here?
Any special reason?
These places often shelter strangers
A good place
to seek my enemy...
Strangers?
Master Aoki,
what do you do for fun?
Fun?
My pleasures are...
Bathing and...
I also keep birds
And I like to play Go
Kichiemon also enjoys Go
Why not challenge each other?
Yes, an excellent plan
Over a game of Go...
Yes
It was at a Go tournament
"You've called halt four times"
“No, it's only three," that's how it began
"You're just an idiot,
how dare you call me a liar! Draw!"
I'm so sorry
He always longed to die at war
Dying over a silly dispute
Must have been a shame
At least...
If he had died in a manner
more worthy of a warrior...
One moment
I've always been...
handy this way
That's all for today, Soza san
So I stand at 7 wins, 3 losses
Do come back
Welcome
Don't stare
Done yet?
Not yet
Tell me when you're done
I hope it's a lot
A lot, a lot
Revenge?
That's right
It's just a play
A play?
This'll be your first
Every spring festival, Shigehachi writes
a script and we stage a revenge play
Despite his looks,
this guy's smart
Despite my looks...
I've got more confidence in
my brains than my guts
Same goes for me
The crowd paid us well
last year
Osae san looked so pretty
in her costume
Osae san, too?
They only love our show so much,
half aware it's a farce,
because real fights are so scarce
We make money...
Thanks to those cowardly
Akou ronin who can't avenge their Lord
Did they beat you up, Shinbo?
No
What then?
They made fun of me
How?
They said I live like a pig
in a rubbish heap
What the hell?
And that everyone
who lives here is trash
Who the hell said that?
Don't get so upset,
they're just kids
Besides, they're right
They said "why bother buying trash,
just sell your own"
That'd be me
Got that right
What's wrong with my work?
Bring the brat here
I'll beat the shit outta him
Hurry up, bring the brat
Soza san
Teach me to use a sword
I really want to beat them
Sounds great
Teach him, Soza
Act like a samurai for once
My father made me promise
no fighting outside the academy
That's pretty useless
I'll teach you
Come here
Hold this
Grab this tight
Hold it in front of your belly
Hold it really straight
Lift it straight up and...
Bring it down
What's going on here?
Shinbo's practicing vengeance
For the play?
No, the genuine article
Swing it down hard
And shout
Oto san
What would you do in his place?
I'd learn how to take a punch
without getting hurt
How's that?
Let 'em hit you where it doesn't hurt
and call it quits
Who taught you that pathetic trick?
My dad, before he died
What a legacy!
Your mom's a real terror...
Yup, it's come in real handy.
Thanks, Dad
Don't force it
Give it here
Hold this, straight, straight
When you're ready to strike...
That's it
Shinbo, come on,
hit me like you mean it
Hey, that's dangerous
Come and get me, crybaby
You want to win, right?
Listen
It's no good swinging
like that useless Lord Akou
Swords are made for thrusting
Got it? Try it
That's right, that's good
Aim at their knees and ankles,
where it's hard and it'll hurt
That's cheating...
Say, noble samurai
Why don't you come after me?
I think not
It's childish to take on an amateur
No need to worry
I want to show Shinbo, fencing
learned in a dojo, is useless in reality
Find any fish?
Watch out!
Mago!
He's useless...
Cheater
Listen up, Shinbo
This way, they'll never bother you again
If that's not your style,
get that guy to show you how
to take a punch without getting hurt
Somebody...
Look after Soza san
Hey, there's a sudden chill in the air
Taking a few days off
Daddy, you're home!
It's spinning
It's caught
You're right
Other way
This time the other way
- Welcome home
- Thanks
What's that?
It was just lying there
Someone was in a hurry
I'm home, baby
Can you hear?
Hirano san...
Are you all right?
Do you have a stomach ache?
Hirano san...
Hey, Sada san!
Look what a mess you made of the floor
The landlord won't like this
Get a doctor, quick!
He'll be fine, it's the third time
And the sword's bamboo
He tries to commit hara-kiri
every spring
- Pathetic
- Ouch
Listen, if you do this on the floor,
it's a pain in the neck to clean up
If you must,
do it on the dirt floor
Answer me
Oh, no!
Soza san, please get Dr. Onodera
Soza san
What a bunch of hopeless losers...
Bamboo...
Osae san...
Thank you
I could've sworn he was taller
Enough of your stories
Give me the money
Money?
Oh, hello
Pick it up
Sada san
I'm grateful
What for?
I was in the mood for something sweet
Actually, Sada san
Why so serious, suddenly?
I've already found him...
Kanazawa Jubei
Changed his name
Heisuke, right?
He's a laborer in Kawaracho
That widow he's living with is a beauty
- You knew!
- Yeah, I knew
- Since when?
- For a while
- But you...
- Listen
Have you told anyone else yet?
Then let's keep it secret
In this day and age, this samurai
revenge thing's out of style
Besides, with your skills,
you're doomed
Think I can have another?
Another, please
So, sell any?
Not this crap
Welcome home, Soza san
Another day
Off to the bath with Sada?
Treat me, sometime
Wish I'd get a good job
Tried buying scraps?
No way!
Why?
Stinks
Figured
What do you see, Mago?
I see night
Say, Soza san
What will happen to your bird?
I wonder...
Is he stuck underground forever?
It's dark and it's cold
and he won't like it
I wonder if my father's
underground somewhere
Shinbo...
Don't tell my mother
She still thinks
he's going to come home
Sure
Let's pray again,
that your father's in some place warm
On his deathbed,
my father held my hand and begged,
“Soza, please avenge me"
But I'm a hopeless swordsman,
and haven't fulfilled this task
His one dying wish
That is my inheritance
Inheritance?
Yes
It's why I have to pay back
his enemy with my own hands
Is that true?
I can understand your feelings,
but this is how I see it
If, after living his whole life,
your father left you nothing
but hate,
it would be unbearably sad
Mother, come
"Owing to my imminent starvation,
"I pray you will send funds
“upon receipt of this letter
"May I inquire, Father,
"whether you are happy and healthy?
"Hope you will take
“the very best care of yourself
"Yours, Sakutaro"
That's what it says
So, how will you reply?
Reply?
I have no reply
What, a samurai?
So spoilt
You have no skills
I wouldn't be so proud if I were you
What's the big deal over
those two swords you have?
The village dumpling-maker
serves them three at a time
Whenever he gets that drunk,
he brings old letters in
for me to read
He never once sent a reply,
so he's bad for business...
Soza san,
why do you think samurai exist?
Why?
Peasants grow rice
Merchants sell things
Just as that drunk said,
samurai alone make nothing,
and sell nothing
The samurai were meant
to live, giving and
taking life at war
Time has passed and war is over
But the samurai remain
I'd say that's the root
of their troubles
Say, that gives me an idea
Will that lazy Oishi
ever come to Edo?
That's why I keep saying
We should've attacked the Kira mansion
when they forced our lord into hara-kiri
But that chief retainer...
He's hopeless
He and his son are both sex maniacs
The father chases female ass,
the son chases male ass
Old man Kira's retired now...
At this rate, he'll die of old age
before we can kill him
Onodera san, it's hardly the time
for poetry
Oh, sorry
But there's nothing gained
by panicking
"A prayer for
a despised enemy's
"longevity"
Revenge, revenge!
"Art thou Akiyama Gengobei?"
They're making a racket
Are they trying to rub it in?
"My son and I...
"rain drenched and windswept...
“The trials and...
“The trials and tribulations
of such times..."
Mocking the Warrior's
sacred vengeance
They won't get away with this
"Now, fight and fight fair"
"I cut my enemy down in warrior's
vengeance, not petty motives
"Now you deserve revenge"
Listen, Soza
This isn't the Kabuki
No need to overdo it
And now, "Not so fast,
just a little wait, please"
That's my cue to step in and mediate
Hey, can I say the
"Not so fast" line?
The part's way too much
for you
Do the best with your "Revenge!" part
For once, I want a big part
You're lucky to even get any lines
"It is a day for admiring blossoms
“Can you face the gods if your swords
draw blood among the temple-goers?
"Out of respect for me,
won't you postpone this fight?"
And if the enemy also does
a little dance, the crowd will applaud
Soza san, excuse me
I'd like to discuss something
What is it?
Not here
May I come to your place?
Oh, don't bother
I won't stay long
Please don't make a fuss
Ouch, ouch...
He's just sipping tea quietly
Hurry up and jump her, man
Despite his looks...
Um...
I don't know if I should be
asking you this...
But it's too late
to ask Shigehachi san...
Um...
What do "Drifting log mokki"' and
"Udonge flower" mean?
Mokki... you mean?
It's one of my lines in the play,
but I've never been able to figure out
what it means
Mokki...
I wonder how you write it...
A mouki is...
The characters are "blind" and "turtle"
A turtle, worn out with swimming,
finally rests refuge on a floating log
The "udonge flower" blooms once
every 3 thousand years
Because the rare “udonge" flower
resemble a spider web,
“udonge" has slowly come to mean
the spider's web as well...
Mokki?
All done
Soza, don't be so nervous
It's just acting
How will you manage
a real revenge?
“Cherry blossoms are blessed
only when they have all fallen"
When it's time for a samurai to die,
one hopes to fall gracefully,
like these cherry blossoms
Make sure you do,
on your fourth try
“Only the countrymen..."
You're not from here, right?
I bet cherry blossoms fall gracefully
'cause they know
they'll bloom next year
Otherwise, they'd never give up
A point for Mago
"Not exactly,
but not far off, neither"
Right, “neither"
“Hunger is a terrible..."
You don't really understand any of it
A revenge! A revenge!
How was I?
Just fine
Shit
- What?
- Some guys I'd rather not see
- What? A big tab?
- Enormous
I know, will you take my
"Not so fast" line, too?
Me?
Don't worry, you can do it
"All to avenge this grudge,
my son and I,
"rain drenched, windswept,
"by the trials and tribulations
of such times..."
"Meeting you like a mokki
reaching driftwood
“the flowering of the udonge..."
“Now fight, and fight fair"
"I cut my enemy down in Warrior's
vengeance, not petty motives
"Now you deserve revenge"
It's your moment!
What's the hold up?
Hurry up
Kill him
Not so fast!
We've heard she avenges
her dead husband
In these peaceful times, a fine
example of a warrior's wife
To ignore her plight
would disgrace any samurai
An excellent chance to showcase
our samurai training
Though we may be inadequate,
we offer our assistance
A gracious offer, but my son and I,
must do this with our own hands...
Listen, I'll strike both his arms
- You, his legs...
- Strike
Once he's disabled,
you deliver the deathblow
"Not so fast!"
So fast
Coward - Lessons Available
How about taking his wife
or child hostage?
I can't do that
Set his house on fire and
get him as he escapes...
Attack him in bed?
Sada san
Retribution must befit a samurai...
But if by some miracle you succeed,
you'll win vast lands
There's got to be a way to avenge him
without risking your life
Are you taking this seriously?
I am
You sure?
I don't think it's just that you're weak,
you've got some other real hesitation
about seeking revenge
Oh, I know
You've fallen in love
with that beautiful widow
Quite the stud, you widow-killer!
"Widow..."
How about a mask?
Hello
Oh, you had your baby!
Uncle?
Soza
His eyes are just like yours
Cut it out, you're wrong
What? He's not your child?
Uncle! Think about it
I only left home 3 years ago
This boy is at least 8 years old
Is that so?
What's your name?
Shinnosuke
Your age?
Eight
Children these days grow up so fast...
I've kept you waiting
Why, thank you
Shinnosuke, come with me
Soza san has important business
It's not so important
I feared his spirits might be low
Thought I'd take him to a brothel
to distract him
But I'm relieved at what I see
There's absolutely no need
for my concerns
I worry because he's
always been a little immature,
but how's "it" going?
Uncle
What "it?"
I mean... with his pen
Oh... he's very skillful
Excellent
Onobu across the street says she's
really improved because of him
That's amazing
My boy's getting better at it every day
What?
Your boy!
Isn't he on the young side?
I was at least 12...
What will you do
for your father's anniversary
next month?
Ah, yes...
When they find out "Shy Soza"
has quite a set-up here in Edo,
it won't just be relatives talking,
it'll be the entire clan
Watch it, Ma!
Shut up!
You useless ass!
This place is full of life
Wouldn't mind moving in myself
I swear I'll go
to the fish market tomorrow
Please open up, Onobu
Onobu?
Where's Onobu?
Uncle, let's go
But what about Onobu...
Take care
What on earth,
have you been up to,
these 3 past years?
I am deeply sorry
You think apologies are enough,
you idiot
I sent you off to avenge your father,
as if you had succeeded,
you might have slightly improved
your pathetic reputation
But not even a single lead...
The monthly allowance
the clan provides you
is not inconsiderable
Monthly?
Brother, there's another reason
why he hasn't located
his enemy...
Uncle
Our Shy little Soza
has made a child
with a beautiful woman
The child is already 8 years old
The sword is not merely intended
to inflict wounds and claim lives
When swords clash,
life encounters life,
death encounters death,
in a tempestuous conflict,
giving birth to a genuine dialogue
That is the samurai's joy and sorrow
That is the only path
of the samurai
In these peaceful times
which know no war,
the samurai must reveal this beauty
to the peasantry...
There are less of them...
than 3 years ago
With war unlikely,
they know that fencing is useless
in advancing their career
Look, here
Our enemy Kanazawa's,
ancestral home
He'd been living alone
with his invalid mother
Soon after he killed Father, his mother,
unable to face the world,
and passed away...
I never knew
How sad for her
How sad?
How can you feel pity, brother?
He got what he deserved
But what did his mother
have to do with it?
How can you be so soft?
Have you forgotten
Father's dying wish?
I'm sorry
You're "sorry..."
You've changed these past 3 years
What sort of life have
you been leading in Edo?
You have no right to pray
at Father's grave
Observe my belated vengeance!
Prepare!
I avenge my father!
Take care of yourself
I've got a lady friend to visit here
Listen...
Your father was a prude, with no
enjoyment of life's subtle pleasures,
but now that he's gone,
he's left a nice setup for you
The gods will punish you
if you waste her
Revenge isn't the only way
to demonstrate your devotion
Bye
Soza
Don't you think,
that's overdoing it?
I'm a living creature, too
I deserve a better life
They say a dog's curse
obstructs the birth of the shogun's heir
Maybe he ate one...
Fans, fans for sale
Sode san
Why would you be picking flowers?
What about you?
They're for my dead mother
I don't have money to buy any
You look after your folks
Say, you're hurt
Another fight with gangsters?
You're hopeless. Why do you
always get yourself beat up?
A mystery
Don't you have anyone special?
If I did, would it fill my stomach?
It wouldn't fill your stomach,
but if you had someone special,
maybe you'd be a little less reckless
You're such a baby, Onobu
You know, having someone special
would only make me more reckless
I'm just worried about you
Well cleaning, well cleaning
All right pull up
Slowly, slowly
All right, release
Release it more
A little more
All right, lift it
Let's go help
Soza!
Making New Year's cakes and cleaning
wells are work for a samurai's servant
Never heard of a samurai pulling a rope
Look, the landlord's new wife
He sure managed to
get himself a beauty
He spent good money buying
her out of a brothel
Not even been 3 years
since the last one died
Money does make the world go round
He knows her?
The man gets around
"Why Sode san,
you're as handsome as ever"
"You're looking pretty yourself"
"You mustn't, I'm a wife, now"
You sure married well
A landlord's wife is a long way up
from a humble village
It wasn't my choice
You didn't choose
the brothels, either?
No woman chooses the brothels
Women have it good
Always got a job waiting
You really want to hear,
all about how I survived,
these last 15 years?
I'll pass
Why won't you build us
a decent outhouse?
Don't be foolish
I'm destroying these tenements
to build new ones
Unfortunately, you'll be ringing in
the new year somewhere else
Interesting...
These days, it seems like
my shit's been runny
I'll be with you soon
Cut it out, Dad
Can't you see, I'm eating
Shut up! It's none of your business
what I say to my wife
Talking about your shit, at this hour!
You're not Mago san
If you're going to fuss,
fuss over the back rent you owe
Listen, Onobu, about Kenbo...
No matter how you look at him,
Kenbo's your child
In 10 years, I won't even be able
to tell you apart
I've got my hands full now
I'm in no mood to discuss your shit
with you, Dad! Just shut up!
Here goes!
Sode san's out
Please, don't come here
Why not?
Because...
whatever happened in the past,
I don't think Sode san
can find happiness with you
You get right to the point,
don't you
And you think he'll find
happiness with you?
I just don't want to spend
my whole life in this dump
Listen
Remember this
When you leave, it'll be because
you're worse off than you are now
They say there's a place over
in Nakano where they feed strays
If we get thrown out of here,
we can go
Fool. They only feed dogs,
not humans
I was born in the Year of the Dog
Still no good?
We're less than dogs
to the Shogun anyway
Pisses me off
With so many of us, how come
we can't figure out how many men
guard their mansion!
There has to be a way to figure it out
Kichiemon
Don't you have an idea?
The volume of crap in the outhouse
should give us a good idea
Crap?
Spoken like a true ex-peasant
Excuse me
Who are you?
What do you mean by that?
I'm here to collect your rent
The question is, who are you?
We're ill... ill...
You're ill...?
No, no,
we have no ill intentions
And nothing to do with Kira...
We're just wounded is all
There are quite a few of you...
Chief retainer arrived from Kyoto!
Oishi-sama's here!
All right, let's go
Finally!
Hey, wait, that's my umbrella!
Let's have a look
Oh, no
Your business is really doing well
No charge
But can you wait for the rent?
No extra charge
I'm begging you
If you take that knife, Dad can't
work at the fish market anymore
You owe 6 months' back rent!
Besides, he never works anyway
Hey there
If all my tenants were prospective
avengers, I'd actually collect rent
You're welcome to move in
to my new tenement
Um...
Can't you hold off...
Let us all live here a while longer
"Let us all live here?"
A fine phrase,
but you're dreaming
No wonder they all
take advantage of you
Don't talk to me like that, when you've
never worked a day in your life
Or are you willing to cover
everyone's back rent?
If you live here, you pay
My, my, the landlord making
the rounds himself in this rain
My tenants are more likely to stay
home in this weather. Easier to collect
Besides, I can't risk sending
my gorgeous wife here
Who knows what might happen
What do you mean, "Risk?"
I heard
You're childhood friends
You were engaged
What's that got to do with you?
Oh, how scary
Time to be going
Too bad, but she's my wife
I won't let you touch her
This fatty meat...
from that other white one was
better than this black one...
Four of you eating from one pot?
You're all wet
Have a bowl and warm up
Don't mind if I do
By the way, that German or
English doctor, Kaempfer,
who visited the Shogun,
sold him an elixir for immortality
for 20,000 ryo
20,000 ryo!
I hear it's made of mermaid flesh
Wonder if it works
20,000 ryo is fantastic...
He's got no children so
he's got to live as long as he can
Sure is greedy
Just like a landlord I know
20,000 ryo, is like...
20,000 ryo is...
Hey... this...
Mind your manners
Sit when you eat
What kind of meat is this?
This? What was it?
This is... you know...
You see it riding on that platform...
It's dog
Tastes pretty good
Today, it's a little
tougher than usual
Than usual?
You know what'll happen
if the Shogun finds out!
He won't,
if you keep your mouth shut
Besides, you ate some, too
Hey, you can't eat and run
Leave the knife in payment
I'll drive you out!
Every last one of you!
Thanks for your patronage
Come back soon!
It's been 5 days now
Can't even go to work
You hardly work
even when the sun's shining
But when it keeps pouring this way,
it even makes you feel poorly
Right?
I haven't been able to shit at all
How long?
It's 4 days now
It's 5 days for me
Look how bloated I am...
See?
You're right
What is it?
I've got no business with you
Move
Are you going to disappear again?
I hate the rain
When it rains,
I always remember that night
I see your face against
that bloody ceiling
I should've died, too, back then
If I had...
Is that how you've always felt?
How sad
Cut it out
You're not the only one
whose folks nearly killed you
What?
What do you want me to do?
Come with me...
Somewhere far away...
Of course not...
It's too late for that
I've got his baby,
inside my belly
Is that so?
You're having a baby
You'll have a new family
That's good
Forget it
You have your baby,
become a mother,
get old,
and go all wrinkly
Can I watch you the whole time?
You live in a filthy dump,
dressed up like a samurai
You'll never amount
to anything, anyway
What's so great about
being a samurai?
We were born better than you
Who says so?
Bring him here
What!
Get 'em!
Wait!
What's with them?
Strange
Let's go
Yoshibo
Before you said, “What's
so great about being a samurai?"
That's what Daddy says,
when he drinks
I see... your father does
Daddy tells me to run from fights
But I hate running,
so I had a different idea
People who are truly strong,
don't fight without a reason
Your father must be
a man of great character
Yeah
Excuse me
Oh, it's Mom
Hello
I live across the way
I'm sorry
they've caused you trouble
Hey, Yoshi!
Were you fighting again?
What did you promise your father?
I wasn't in a fight, right?
Hi, Shinbo
Your mother said
she has a few more customers to visit
Please wait for her a little longer
It's all right
I'll wait until she returns
I'll be going then
Come play with my son again
Tomorrow
I wonder if Daddy will
come home early
I wonder
He said he'd make me a wheel
Won't that be nice
There's a portrait of my father
Would you like to see it?
Of your father?
I know she looks at it
secretly at night
Here it is
WANTED
Doesn't he look strong?
Don't tell Mother
What's wrong, Soza san?
I fell into the crap...
I... may be dressed up
as a simple drug seller,
but in fact I'm a samurai
I say samurai, but I'm just
a foot soldier, a former peasant
I see
So all I think about is wanting
to die a samurai's death
Then I'll finally be a real samurai
That way, my son can truly
live as a samurai's son
I can't leave him any land or money...
So it's the least I can do
Kichiemon san,
who taught you how to play Go?
After I began carrying swords,
however badly
Everyone told me it would
make me more like a samurai
I learned by watching
My father taught me
When I was a child
I'd forgotten that...
I learned more from my father
than fencing...
You're very lucky
I'm grateful
Truly grateful
I'll pass on the basics of Go
to Shinbo, soon
A revenge, a revenge...
After a 3 year search for my enemy,
I, Aoki Sozaemon of the Matsumoto clan,
have finally avenged my father
When cut down, a man...
The single, mortal blow ran
from the right side to his back
What incredible swordplay...
My vengeance was a warrior's revenge
Bear no grudge
Do you hate the man
who killed your father?
I hate...
I hate him
The other day, your son
stopped a fight...
He saved Shinbo,
who lives in our neighbourhood
Our Yoshi...
Is that so?
How old is he?
Seven
He's not mine by birth...
Why don't you
start sending him to my private
school next year
It would make Shinbo happy
A repeat performance of
our spring revenge play
Very cool
It's so like Soza san
But, isn't it risky?
We screw up, we'll be in big trouble
But if we pull it off,
we'll get at least 100 ryo
100 ryo!
With 100 ryo we can pay off all
our back rent
and have some left
That's 14 ryo each
I'm in!
I'm in, too!
Me, too
I want you all to play
the excited passersby
Tomekichi san,
I need you to find a pig
Can I please say that line
"Now you deserve revenge"?
May I?
A samurai holds Justice
dearer than life itself
Composed of Self and Beauty
He defends Justice
and defending...
Enough of your crap
Eat shit!
No,
even I won't eat shit
until it's become rice cakes
Listen, "Eat shit" doesn't actually mean...
If you really want money,
it has to be real
Turning it into a pantomime...
The whole point is, it's fake
I wouldn't dare kill someone
"Tall tales make flowers bloom
but bear no fruit"
That's what they used to say
Well, I say, let's make
a field of flowers bloom
Down to 9 ryo...
Don't you hate him!
Don't you despise your father's killer!
No,
you're all wrong
Each of us has our own
method of hating
Soza san is...
Making that hatred...
It's larger than...
You see...
That's it!
Soza san has turned shit
into rice cakes
Taken the shit inside him
and made it rice cakes...
Osae san
"Shit this and shit that,"
is Mago's line
Turning shit into rice cakes
inside you...
Amazing!
No, Mago, it's not like that
There's no way you can fake a corpse?
Leave it all to me
I've got enough bones
No, any fool can see
they're dog bones
You can't fool a temple priest
Leave it to me
I'll take it to my family's temple
Your father's a priest?
A priest?
Yeah, didn't I tell you?
The Jodo sect
All right
If you insist,
I will help you with this plan
Should we succeed,
recommend me to your clan
- Your real motive!
- What a nerve...
Can't I at least say "Not so fast!"
I'll get it right
You always mix things up
Shut up
Yeah, we don't need you to mess it up
Mago san, I'd like you to
play the lead in this revenge
A revenge!
Took him 3 years
but he avenged his father
What incredible swordplay!
Incredible
A revenge!
I, Aoki Sozaemon have avenged
my father's murderer,
I, Hirano Jirozaemon,
did duly witness this revenge
Deadly combat
Well done!
It was deadly combat
The notices have been posted
In these peaceful times...
a truly commendable spirit
Now for the autopsy...
The mortal blow ran from his
right side to his back
Felled by a single blow
When cut down,
a man bleeds so tremendously...
I was shocked
Oto! Intestines!
You're right
How awful...
What will you do?
Do you still want to see it?
My beloved!
Daddy!
Darling!
He's got a red mark that
matches this likeness
This avenging was
a warrior's revenge
Bear no grudge
Shinbo, do you hate the man
who killed your father?
I hate him
Do you want revenge?
Yeah
Your mother feels exactly as you do
So I can't tell you not to hate him
But you see...
If all your father left us...
was hatred,
how would he feel?
It might make him feel sad
So, now,
let's take what he left behind
and gradually make it
into something better
I'll help you, Shinbo
Will you help me, too?
Yeah, I'll help you
I'll play Daddy's part, too
That's right,
J-I-R-O-Z-A-E-M-O-N
It worked, it worked
I can't believe we pulled it off
That idiot said,
“Bury him with respect"
Otokichi, why are you crying?
Because Osae san and Shinbo...
Idiot, they were acting
But still...
Hey, Mago, you can stop now
Somebody pull off the matting
He's asleep
Seven ryo and 2 pence...
No guts spurting out
It was a single mortal blow
Too much noise to
get any sleep tonight
Well, all that rain,
I couldn't go out
I was stuck inside for so long...
Right?
That's how it is
What do you mean?
You call that an answer?
Don't ruin the celebrations
If we live together,
we halve the rent
Live together!
Of course, we're getting married
I'm moving in with Oto san, too?
Sure, why not, Onobu
You and Otokichi will be siblings
No, not siblings...
In any event, let's have a toast
Congratulations
Not for me
Suzuta ran off?
What's going on?
That's news to me
"My mother, long bed-ridden
in illness,
"has fallen into a bad condition
and truly needs..."
A sick mother, huh
News to me
"If you commanded me to leave
my mother,
"it would be like abandoning
a part of myself..."
Says his mother's more important
than revenge
On the eve of avenging,
he loses nerve
He disgraces all samurai!
Hey, Terasaka
How many remain?
This month, Yano san,
Seo san, Mori san,
and Suzuta san have left our company
We now number some 50...
This is why I told you...
We must strike now. Who knows
how many will stay into the new year
Now, your dojo back home will flourish
All's well in the neighbourhood and
I can head off to your clan as well
The wedding within
this neighbourhood count to...
One, two, three...
Eight marriages
- How was I as the lead?
- Oh, excellent
Really?
Now with Otokichi and Onobu
under the same roof
You fool, we're only siblings
Which means, if I can stand
having you as my brother,
I can take Onobu as my wife?
What an idea...
As her brother, I can't allow that
You're a mere trash collector
If only it hadn't rained so much...
Mom...
So we end up
attacking them in their sleep
How pathetic
News! News!
A revenge!
This chief Oishi's amazing
Acted the lady's man
to fool the enemy
They say news of Aoki Sozaemon's
revenge made him tougher
Says they figured out the number of
guards by the privy. Sure original
That noodle shop owner
is the chicken samurai who took off,
three months before it happened
No wonder his noodle broth
tasted like chicken stock!
Chicken samurai
Sweet revenge buns here!
Don't miss out!
Listen up!
Here's the place where
Dr. Onodera, the 6th most important
of the 46 avengers,
lived in hiding
Preparing for death, he wrote
many letters to his wife in Kyoto
He sent her this poem
the day before the revenge
Listen up
“Thoughts once conveyed,
"in parting,
seem yet unspoken"
He thought he had told her
everything he had to say,
at this final parting,
he fears much remains unsaid
Enough to make a grown man cry
I always knew there was
something noble about him,
and I always refused his money
Buy some sweet revenge buns
Pay to see his house
Look, there he is
Mentor to the 46 avengers
Welcome home
What a result!
There's no result,
we've done no harm
It's those 46 samurai who did harm
That's what I think, too
What they did was bad?
Of course it was,
a sneak attack in the night
The whole swarm of them killing
a poor old man,
that's cheating
But the landlord's getting rich
Those sweet buns marked "Loyalty"
are selling like hot cakes
Mom's all excited about
opening a street front shop
Where on earth can
that coward be hiding?
Maybe he's hiding in the shit pile
Just a foot soldier after all...
I don't see what's funny
What's a shit pile got to do
with a foot soldier?
I was putting on my attack robes,
when I remembered that Soza san
had learned to play Go from his father
Yeah, both are black and white
Sada san!
I realized I'd never taught
my son to make straw sandals...
And that thought...
See, Soza san saved
Terasaka san
Um...
What! What do you want?
A word with master Terasaka
You ask him
No, you do it
What the hell is it?
You can't keep hiding
like this forever, right?
Why not say that chief Oishi
commanded you
to spread word
of the avengers' exploits?
So, reluctantly,
you had to leave the others
Assuming you'd agree to that,
we came up with these
I think we'll call them,
"Kichi Buns"
We made them black and white,
like those Go pieces you so enjoy
And naturally you can keep
a tenth of the profits
Not bad, for a couple of bums
That's enough!
Revenge... is good for business
That's right Onobu
It's important to cash in,
even on misfortune
That's right!
Me... It was only at
the chief's command
that I report the revenge,
that reluctantly, I...
No, it's true
I hadn't told anyone,
but I did not flee in fear,
but for the good of the clan...
That's right, I've no time to waste
I must go home to give a full account
to the families of the 46 samurai...
The flowers bloomed all right,
but they bore some very strange fruit
Now what about those sweet buns?
What about them!
Hey, hear the latest? All 46 samurai
committed hara-kiri!
Such noble men
But...
maybe now, he'll be able
to teach his son to make sandals
Back at home
Hey, Shinbo. Come ask Hirano san
to teach you fencing
After all this, boys won't
need teaching, they'll need swords
Now, listen up. For samurai,
the moment of death is all
As they say, “Cherry blossoms are blessed
only when they have all fallen"
But...
Just as Mago san said,
cherry blossoms only fall
to return again next spring
In even greater beauty
Say
Is there a private school around here?
OKADA Junichi
MIYAZAWA Rie
FURUTA Arata
KAGAWA Teruyuki
TABATA Tomoko
UESHIMA Ryuhei
KIMURA Yuichi
KASE Ryo
CHIHARA Seiji
HIRAIZUMI Sei
EZAWA Moeko
NATSUKAWA Yui
KUNIMURA Jun
NAKAMURA Katsuo
ISHIBASHI Renji
TERAJIMA Susumu
ENDO Kenichi
TANAKA Tetsushi
NAKAMURA Yuji
KATSUJI Ryo
ISHIDO Natsuo
Tommys' Masa
MINAKATA Eiji
ASANO Tadanobu
HARADA Yoshio
Executive Producer :
HISAMATSU Takeo
Development Producer :
YASUDA Masahiro
Producers :
SATO Shiho, ENOKI Nozomu
Cinematographer :
YAMAZAKI Yutaka
Lighting : ISHIDA Kenji
Production Designer :
ISOMI Toshihiro, BANBA Masao
Costume Designer :
KUROSAWA Kazuko
Music : Tablatura
Presented by
HANA Film Partners
Written, edited and directed by
KORE-EDA Hirokazu