Firetruck behind you.
Please clear the road.
MONSTER
Minato?
A fire, a fire.
Come look.
It's a fire.
Don't fall.
If a human gets a pig's brain
transplanted, is it a human or a pig?
What are you talking about?
There's research.
Who told you that?
My teacher, Mr. Hori.
They teach weird stuff these days
That's not a human being, listen...
It started.
Go for it!
Not so loud.
Wait.
Wait, wait.
Your water bottle!
The bottom kids support gymnastic
formations, so hang in there.
Off you go.
Over the white line,
you go to hell.
That was when I was a kid.
You still are.
Excuse me.
Yes, welcome.
Welcome I'll take care of it.
I just passed it, and
it was completely burned.
Well, you know,
I could hear the fire trucks
until after 1am.
There was a hostess bar on the third floor
Did you know?
I saw a girl in short skirt
handing out tissues to promote it.
And according to what I heard,
Mr. Hori was there.
A teacher in a hostess bar...
Is he lonely?
Word gets around fast
about something like that.
I'm tired.
Minato?
In the bathroom?
Sorry, I'll make dinner right away.
What?
Oh, no, what the...
What are you doing?
- What, what?
- I'm naked.
What, what are you up to?
Against school rules.
About your curly hair?
Was it Kamata?
Did he say something again?
What the hell is this?
- Hello.
- Manager, customer.
I'm home.
Here goes,
Happy birthday to you,
Happy birthday to you.
Happy birthday, dear Father.
Happy birthday, to you.
Enough.
Blow them out.
The cake got smaller again
Dad would have eaten it in two bites.
He won't eat it,
he's already dead.
He can hear you.
Give him an update.
About school and
about your friends.
Out loud.
Did they throw dirt over him
in his grave?
He was cremated first,
so there was no dirt.
Is he already reborn?
Then I wish he'd come see us.
What if he's reborn as a stink bug?
He's reborn into something more noble.
Like a giraffe?
I'd have to look up at him.
Meet him on the veranda.
I prefer a horse.
He liked horses,
and he could give us rides.
Give him an update.
If I talk to him, you can hear me, too.
Got it.
What is it?
Go see the doctor?
Will you be OK?
Time to get up and get ready.
OK?
An experiment.
For Science.
Wait for me, I'm hungry!
What time did Gaku last see him?
He was riding his bike?
Where?
What?
Minato?
I'M HERE.
Who's the monster?
Minato?
- Who's the...
- Minato!
Minato!
Sorry.
Your ear hurt?
I...
be like Dad.
Your father was much worse.
He was a rugby player.
He'd come home with a complex
fracture like it was no big deal.
But I've promised your father.
That I'll hang in there until you're
married and have your own family.
Just an ordinary family
you see anywhere is fine.
Until you have your own family,
the greatest treasure...
Minato?
Minato!
Mugino Minato.
Come to the exam room.
Let's go.
Come in.
Please, come in.
You'll be fine.
Let's just have them take a look.
Please wait outside for your son.
Can't we get the car back?
If we can't, I'll go crazy
at the police station.
Don't worry.
Mom, did you...
see the X-rays?
The CT scan? Sure.
Everything looked normal.
Oops, I'm in hell.
You're really fine.
Nothing's wrong with you.
What is it?
What's up?
Did something happen at school?
That you're a slow eater?
Why did you cut your hair?
Why did you lose your sneaker?
What happened here?
It's a pig's brain
My brain was switched with a pig's.
That's what's strange about me,
I'm a monster...
Who told you that?
Was it Kamata?
It was Kamata, right?
Who told you that!
Minato, who told you that!
Who said that?
Mr. Hori.
- Bye.
Principal...
I had been using this at home.
Bye.
Oh, I'm sorry.
I'm fifth grader Mugino Minato's mother.
His gym bag was thrown down the hall,
or not allowed to eat lunch
because he wasn't prepared for class.
He's told me these things.
Yes.
His ear was pulled so hard it bled.
He said, "Mr. Hori, stop,
it hurts,".
Mr. Hori told him,
"Your brain is a pig's brain,
you won't learn until it really hurts".
Yes.
Sorry we're late.
Ms. Mugino, it's been awhile
I was his second grade...
Mr. Kanzaki, hello.
And now?
I teach first graders...
That must be tough.
A war zone.
Please sit down.
Please.
- Please share your concerns.
- I just explained to the principal...
The principal has pressing business.
But it's about a student
What other business...
The principal recently
lost her grandchild in an accident.
It's an appointment about that,
but if you insist...
No.
I'm sorry, I didn't know...
Ouch!
Ouch! What, what?
And here's how we tricked her.
Maybe it's faked
Would you get tricked that easily?
You know it's a lie because
it's on TV.
My skin's super supple!
Super supple!
ELEMENTARY SCHOOL
ENTRANCE CEREMONY
We've kept you waiting.
Regarding
the concerns that you shared with us,
Mr. Hori would like to
offer you an apology.
Stand up.
In this case,
because my instruction,
toward Mugino, to Mugino,
resulted in a misunderstanding
I feel most regretful.
I do formally apologize.
And, so?
- We are terribly sorry.
- That's not right.
This isn't right at all.
Please, please wait.
You see,
can't we all sit down?
Please sit down.
My son...
was wounded by
his teacher's cruel remark.
It wasn't a misunderstanding.
We believe his instruction
was not accurately conveyed.
What instruction?
Which one?
We believe his instruction
required the utmost attention.
May I confirm, Mr. Hori?
Mr. Hori!
You were violent towards
my son, right?
It seems there was
a misunderstanding.
There was no misunderstanding...
My son was wounded
because this teacher hit him.
Do you understand?
We accept your opinion
with seriousness
and we will provide
appropriate instruction in the future.
So,
did you hit him?
Or didn't you hit him?
Please answer yes or no.
Now.
Now!
We have confirmed
that there was contact
between the teacher's hand
and Mugino Minato's nose.
That means you hit him.
There was contact between
the hand and the nose.
The hand?
And the nose contacting
like this?
Twisting his arm,
and pulling his ear,
is a lot more than contact.
What did you put in your mouth?
Candy?
Why's he eating candy?
Do you,
understand what we're
talking about now?
This is typical of single mothers
like mine, so I know...
Mr. Hori.
What about single mothers?
They tend to worry too much...
You're saying I'm overprotective?
We accept your opinion
with seriousness
and we will provide
appropriate instruction in the future
I hope you can understand.
Mr. Hori.
I am terribly sorry.
You'll get scolded.
What are you doing!
You can't run like that
Be careful.
Hurry, go pick it up.
I'm getting sesame oil
at the convenience store.
Sorry, I'm late
We got a watermelon...
What are you doing?
I dropped my eraser.
Do you have a fever?
Did your teacher say something again?
- Hello.
We will reconfirm the facts...
Now! Confirm them now!
I mean, I'm asking.
- Yes.
- Don't "Yes" me.
Well...
I didn't ask you to change
"Yes" to "Well".
At this rate, I'll have to transfer him
to another school.
You were a good teacher.
On parents' day in second grade,
Minato read his composition.
That his dream was to become
a single mother.
I think he wrote that
because I raise him alone
and he wanted to help me.
Everyone in his class
burst out laughing.
But you didn't laugh.
"Be kind to your mother,"
is what he said while praising Minato.
So I don't think all the teachers
in this school are awful,
but I do know that the person
at the top is the worst.
You don't have a human heart!
I'm sorry...
That's not it.
I'm not asking for an apology.
Please have Mr. Hori come here.
Unfortunately he's out
I just saw him over there.
Principal, you just lied to me.
You just said he's out.
When a teacher is out, it doesn't mean
he's not at school...
Get it together!
You know...
I don't see any life
in any of your eyes.
Am I talking to human beings?
Yes.
Can you please answer my question?
About whether we're human?
No.
Fine, just answer that.
You have to check your notes?
We're human.
In that case,
I'm here because I'm worried
about my child.
Could you please deal with me
as a fellow human being?
Just for this meeting,
please.
We accept your opinion
with seriousness and believe...
I'm sorry.
Thank you.
This is really not a good time.
She's here now...
Please wait.
Let's go over there.
Um, we should go...
- Fine, I'll apologize.
- It's not...
I'm very sorry.
A teacher with a school like...
I can't send my child to a school
with a teacher like this.
Make him quit.
- Did I say something amusing?
- Bye.
- Did I say something funny?
- Don't get so excited
I'm not excited, just asking for...
Your son is a bully.
What are you saying?
Mugino Minato is bullying
Hoshikawa Yori.
- There's no evidence.
- Mr. Hori, take it back.
Does Mugino have a knife or
a weapon at home?
What are you talking about?
You're full of crap
You were at that hostess bar.
Oh, I know.
You set fire to that bar
You're the arson?
You're the one with a pig's brain
in your head.
DO NOT ENTER.
You really did it.
Watermelon.
It happens, it does.
It's a release.
A release.
Yes?
You're Hoshikawa?
Yes.
Hoshikawa Yori?
You're Minato's friend, right?
Yes.
Please.
Please, come in.
This looks like Minato's sneaker.
Yeah, he loaned it to me.
Just the one?
Just the one.
Is your mother not at home?
Won't she get mad,
letting a stranger in your house?
It's fine.
Is Mugino still sick with a cold?
Yeah...
Write a letter?
Like we write to kids out sick.
How is
your cold?
Listen,
We are all worried
about...
Yori, here,
this letter here is flipped.
You wrote this backwards.
Here.
Thank you, say, this...
What happened?
Is it a burn?
Yori,
are you being bullied at school?
According to Mr. Hori,
Mugino often mistreats you...
I've never been bullied by Mugino.
- What are you saying...
- And Mr. Hori...
OK, thanks, let's go back to class.
What about the teacher?
He's always hitting Mugino.
What is that?
The other kids all know, but keep quiet
because they're afraid of him.
- Let's go back to class.
- Back to class.
Hoshikawa?
Don't run away, Principal.
You lost your grandchild,
didn't you?
I heard about it.
Your husband was parking his car
and ran over your grandchild
behind the car.
Did it make you sad?
Did it make you grieve?
That's exactly how I feel now.
Good morning.
Saori, Saori.
You've had it rough.
Unfortunately,
something happened
that should never have happened.
Mr. Hori.
I inflicted violence on fifth grader,
Mugino Minato.
I hit Mugino's face
I twisted his arm
I also used terrible words with him.
TEACHER PHYSICALLY PUNISHES
"PIG BRAIN" STUDENT.
Good bye.
- The stairs, he fell from the stairs?
- We're not sure...
He fell running from Hori...
Let's go
Mr. Hori?
Why's he here?
Didn't he quit?
- Minato fell down the stairs.
- Shut up, go home.
Eel keeper!
- Where is he?
- Go home!
- The Guidance Counseling Room.
- Eel keeper!
Minato?
What?
He was just here.
No, no, no.
It's OK.
Don't worry, it's fine.
Enough...
We're going, Gaku.
He was in the bathroom.
...typhoon, 50 kms south of
Yakushima, heading north,
expected to land on
southern Kagoshima soon.
I saw Dad...
He asked me to tell you.
Did he appear in a dream?
He said, "Thank you for everything,
I love you".
I'm just no good.
I feel like I don't take care of you
and I feel sorry for you.
Do you think Dad's reborn?
Maybe.
I wonder what I'll be reborn as.
But you're still totally alive, Minato.
Yeah...
Don't talk like that.
Mom,
don't feel sorry for me.
Mugino!
MONSTER
What's wrong?
What did you say?
Let's get married.
That's a proposal,
you're supposed to make it
somewhere with a beautiful view
of the night.
Night view?
Everybody says it's beautiful,
but it's just lightbulbs.
It's bad
The whole thing's on fire.
Kamata, Hamaguchi,
what are you doing?
It's Hori.
- Stop filming me!
- Girl from the hostess bar!
Hirohashi, you too, go home.
Burning crazy!
- Taking her home!
- Gross!
It'll burn the whole building down.
I wonder if they all went home...
It's like you, Hori
I feel sorry for it.
Don't feel sorry for me.
It has swim bladder disease.
Don't be rude,
my mind and body are healthy.
Says someone whose hobby is sending
letters about typos to publishers?
Look at this.
I wonder what "fish" fell from my eyes,
a yellowtail or a sardine.
Can't you find a hobby
that's more fun?
It makes me squirm with joy.
When you're having fun,
your face is scary
I bet your students are put off, too.
Try smiling.
Your smile is so stiff,
you'll make children cry.
And make flowers wilt.
Stop trying to act like you're a good
teacher and just be yourself.
You don't have condoms.
It'll be fine.
Don't you teach at school
not to trust a woman's "Next time"
and a man's "It'll be fine?"
It'll be fine.
Next time, then.
Watch your hands, hey.
- Morning.
Did you eat all your breakfast?
What did you eat?
Corn soup and bread.
- Sounds tasty.
- I ate soft noodles.
Soft noodles.
What's up, Hoshikawa?
Good morning, my shoe fell off.
Here.
Thank you.
I'm waiting for the parents
to schedule a meeting.
You'd better be careful.
They're more trouble
than their kids, these days.
Do some parents always complain?
They're monsters
Teachers are being crucified, these days.
Hey, little eel.
Oh, Principal.
I am resuming my duties as of today.
Thank you for all of your
kind notes while I was away.
Today, on April 25th,
physical measurements and
eye exams for sixth graders.
I took time off just when
you started teaching here.
Don't...
Please take good care of your students.
Yes.
"Like player Nomo, who didn't fear
public opposition when
"he joined Major League Baseball,
I also declare.
"Practicing my swing on
a West Coast beach,
"I've been reborn
"I solemnly swear,
I will marry the idol Nishida Hikaru
"Fifth Grader, Hori Michitoshi."
- Hey, Tanaka, class is starting.
- Oh, bathroom.
No need to rush.
I have
attended two weddings
of women I once loved.
Will the kids find it funny?
Sounds like a stalker
when you say it.
Save your obsessions
for the hostess bar.
Mugino, hey!
What are you doing?
Mugino, stop!
I'm sorry, you OK?
You OK?
Why do you do this?
What happened? Why?
Playing around?
Pissed off.
Pissed off?
How do you think they feel having
their things thrown like this.
How do they feel?
Don't like it.
Right?
Let's apologize to them.
I'm sorry.
- Oh, no, nosebleed.
- Nosebleed.
His mom is a single mother
That's why.
My mom was, too.
She becomes overprotective
with a shrewd perspective.
You're using "shrewd perspective"
in the wrong way.
It actually means
perceiving the essence of things...
When things are tough,
don't take yourself so seriously.
Do you even remember your elementary
school teacher's name?
- No.
- See?
They're going to forget you,
so don't take it too seriously.
I get off early tomorrow,
so let's meet up and go shopping.
- Shut up.
- Don't say that
Second tier.
Hang in there, hang in.
Hang in.
OK, third tier!
Oh, hang in there, first tier
Don't sway, second tier.
You call yourself a man?
Again, from the second tier
5pm by the station.
Found him, here he is.
Ouch.
Mugino Minato's guardian
is here to protest.
Protest what?
You're shifty-eyed and creepy,
so stay here
I haven't done anything
I can explain it to her.
We can't let this get out of hand.
We're used to dealing with guardians,
leave it to us.
Leave it.
You may not know,
but Mugino's father died...
I know that, but what does...
In the parents' meeting,
did she say he'll test for middle school?
Yes, she did.
If he has to transfer for bullying,
he can't test for any school.
I didn't hit him
My arm just grazed him.
I can explain that I stopped
Mugino from acting out.
If you blame the child,
the parent will become furious.
If this gets to the Education Board,
the whole school will be punished.
- Maybe all of us...
- But actually...
What actually happened
doesn't matter.
Start over.
Because my instruction...
- Well...
- No "Well" needed.
Sit in the guardian's seat.
Can you see this?
Yes, I can see it perfectly.
Mr. Hori?
In this case, because
my instruction to Mugino...
She placed the photo like this
and said, "can you see it?"
The principal does love this school.
But still...
She lives in my neighborhood.
There's a rumor that it was
actually the principal's fault.
What?
That it wasn't her husband
who ran over their grandchild,
but it was the principal herself.
Hoshikawa.
There they were
Thank you, Mr. Hori.
What is it?
Excuse me, I'm Hori
I'm Yori's homeroom teacher.
His teacher.
I wanted to talk to you about him.
Your college?
Excuse me?
I hear teachers don't get paid much.
Do you know Mega-City Real Estate?
I used to work there
I see, amazing.
It's not amazing, but
maybe for an elementary
school teacher.
Um...
- About Yori.
- I'm sure he's a pain,
you don't have to tell me about him
I'll take responsibility for him.
He's not a pain, he's a great kid.
No good,
he's...
A monster.
What?
His brain isn't a human brain,
it's a pig's brain.
Which is why I plan to
turn him back into a human.
- Hello.
Did you pee?
Who's the monster?
Are you OK?
Are you...
- Hoshikawa?
- Oh, it's you, Mr. Hori.
Thanks.
- Hello.
When I found it,
it was already cold.
The cat?
I saw it.
I saw Mugino toying with the cat.
Hoshikawa?
- Hey, Hoshikawa?
- No!
Kida, come here.
Can you please tell the Principal
what you told me the other day?
That Mugino might have
killed the cat?
What? I never said that.
What...
Why do you tell lies?
- What are you doing!
- Hurts.
Did everyone get a copy?
This questionnaire will be filled out
by all the fifth graders.
- So, all homeroom teachers need to...
- What is this?
Return...
What is this?
What is this!
Ms. Mugino has hired a lawyer.
It arrived by certified delivery.
Bathroom, bathroom.
Really think about it.
And write down
your honest answer.
HAVE YOU EVER FELT AFRAID
OF MR. HORI?
DID HE EVER SCREAM AT YOU OR GRAB...
YES
I really haven't done anything.
I'm sure.
In that case, please stop this.
If you object now,
it will only strengthen their case.
Then why didn't you...
You are going to defend our school.
Let's go, Mr. Hori.
A long day for you.
Who actually drove that car?
You're the principal, so to protect
your position and your name,
you made your husband
take the blame.
The principal and everyone
told me to apologize anyway.
My apology would satisfy everyone.
So I had no choice
and even apologized to Mugino.
But...
Have you been busy, recently?
Well, I still have some work
to do later.
Good evening.
You're Mr. Hori, the teacher
at Johoku Elementary, right?
I see you went shopping.
- I'm sorry.
- Please stop that.
I'd like to interview you.
Please stop that.
I think they left.
They were taking your picture.
Why the pajamas?
Why aren't you staying over?
No reason,
you've got a lot going on
I'm fine
A lot of things happened, but...
I wasn't in the photos they took,
was I?
Even so, I'll be the only one
in the newspaper
I'm sorry.
That hurt.
You know I'm innocent, right?
I know that, hang in there.
See you next time.
"PIG'S BRAIN"
ABUSIVE TEACHER'S TAUNT.
Pig's brain! Pig's brain!
It's Hori.
Mugino.
Mugino!
Why?!
Did I do something to you?
I haven't done anything, right?
Yeah, right.
Oh, I see.
You OK?
I'll call a teacher!
- What happened?
- Hori pushed him.
Hori? Hori?
What?
Watch out, be careful!
- Mr. Hori!
Mr. Hori!
Mr. Hori, calm down!
"Selective Breeding?"
The future...
FIFTH GRADER HOSHIKAWA YORI
MI
NA
TO
Mugino Minato.
Hoshikawa...
Mugino!
I'm sorry!
I was wrong!
You did nothing wrong!
There's nothing wrong with you!
Mugino!
Please, let me see Mugino.
Please.
Please!
MUGINO MINATO.
Since he was little,
he always woke up crying.
He always dreamed that the people
he loved were gone and cried.
He's a sweet child.
Um, wait...
Have you seen a child, a boy!
A boy? No, I haven't.
There's an evacuation order
Mudslide in the mountain.
Mudslide?
The old railroad tracks ahead of here
Go back! Go back!
Stop! Stop!
Wait...
Hey, you can't!
You'll die up in the mountain!
Hey!
Further ahead!?
Minato!
Mugino!
Hoshikawa, you here?
Minato?
Are you OK?
It's caved in! Caved in!
Minato!
The train car!
What did he mean by being reborn?
What?
Reborn? Minato!
Minato!
Window! Window!
Mugino!
Hoshikawa!
Hey!
Can you hear me? Minato!
It's your mom!
Minato!
Hey!
- Minato?!
- Mugino!
Hoshikawa!
When we went to the supermarket,
and I told her to buy
whatever she liked,
she refused, saying,
"if I buy my favorite candy,
the candy robber will come."
Candy robber?
She said it was real.
That if you looked away,
it'd steal the candy and run away.
So, I see.
Whatever I say, you say,
"So, I see".
I just remembered, last night.
I'm going back to school
from tomorrow,
so I thought.
I should tell you while I can.
What about the grave?
They'll get one elsewhere.
I thought that was for the best.
You're right.
A candy robber, huh?
That's a great line.
Right?
Oh, this...
Thanks.
Stop, stop, it's dangerous!
- We're fine.
- Where are you going?
- Stop!
- Please stop!
- It's Hoshikawa Yori.
- It's not Hoshikawa.
Please stop!
You sound just like him.
No, he doesn't.
- What are you doing?
- It's Hori, Hori!
- Stop filming me!
- Girl from the hostess bar!
- Good morning.
- Morning.
What time did you go to bed?
Midnight
2am for me
2am?
2am? What were you doing?
Do you ever think sleeping
is a waste of time? No, right?
Bam!
Why are you talking to an alien?
- It's a prank! Surprised?
- No.
Party pooper, party pooper alien.
- Sounds tasty.
- I ate soft noodles.
Soft noodles.
What's up, Hoshikawa?
Good morning, my shoe fell off.
Out loud.
Our Future
I wrote this composition
when I was in fifth grade.
Never heard of Nishida Hikaru?
- Who?
- Which celebrity?
Oh, tambourines.
Mugino.
Here.
Kida, you're on music duty, right?
Please go with him.
Hoshikawa is, too.
OK, Hoshikawa, take this.
Yes.
Please take this.
- Watch your step.
- Yes I will.
Secret.
I haven't touched them,
so they're not dirty
I don't think they're dirty.
You might catch my disease.
Just surprised you brought snacks.
What disease?
I told you.
Is your
brain really a pig's brain?
I thought I wouldn't make friends
in my new class, either.
We're friends, but...
Don't talk to me in front
of the class.
OK, I won't talk to you.
Well, thanks.
Cleaning, cleaning.
- Is he here yet?
- Stop that, Daito.
Stinks, stinks.
Mugino, hurry, hurry.
It's a prank, a prank.
Do it.
Do it more, more!
Keep doing it, more!
Here he is.
- I'll help you.
- Thank you.
Don't just clean it up, react.
Hey, Hoshikawa.
Kuroda's mole looks like a black bean.
Look at it!
- I'll take this.
- Sure.
Say, "Kuroda's mole is a black bean".
I can't say what I don't think.
Why do you take the girls' side?
You a girl?
A girl alien?
My lips are super supple!
- Kiss! Kiss! Kiss!
- Cut it out.
I mean it, cut it out.
Mugino, what are you doing!
Mugino...
Ouch.
Hurts.
No way, no way
I can't let you out.
Just stay there.
You can't.
What? Do you hear something?
A cat.
It's a prank.
Sorry for today.
Ever buy a Coke from
the vending machine by the liquor store?
Yeah.
One in every three times,
the Coke comes out hot.
- No way.
- Never got a hot one?
I have.
Sorry, kept you waiting.
Let's go.
Primrose.
Blue star creeper.
Why do you know flower names?
Because I like them.
Kerria! Columbine!
White nettle, celandine.
Mom said girls prefer boys
who don't know flower names.
That boys who know
flower names are creepy?
She wouldn't say creepy
She's a mom.
You're right.
Girls don't like boys
who are scared of the dark.
Let's go.
Will you tell?
I won't tell It would spoil it.
All aboard!
Clickety-clack, clickety-clack,
clickety...
Hello.
Is it sunny where you are?
It's sunny here.
All aboard!
You put this here
and then tape it like this.
Like this.
The end of the line.
"The fa-ther said,
'No, but, then,
"af, ter, think, ing it over,
"he, said, OK,
"and la, laugh, laughed."
OK, next.
- Fujimori.
- Yes.
- I made mistakes.
- It's OK.
Look, it's here.
A cat.
Actually, a former cat.
Does it stop being a cat
when it dies?
That's true of everything that dies.
Left like this, it might not be reborn.
Cover its face with dirt, too?
It's already dead.
Is it OK?
Will it burn like in California?
Maybe a fire truck will come.
Did you burn the hostess bar?
Because your dad was there?
Drinking alcohol is bad
for your health.
Stinks.
Please, open the door.
Mugino? It's you, Mugino, right?
Let me out.
Did you pee?
Who's the monster?
Are you OK?
Why not tell Mr. Hori?
He's kind.
He'll just say I'm not
acting like a man.
You don't want to?
Well, I have a pig's brain.
You don't have a pig's brain.
Your dad is wrong.
My dad is kind
He promises to cure my disease.
When I'm cured,
Mom will come back.
I don't think you have a disease.
He is my dad, so there are things
I just can't say to him.
There are things I can't
say to Mom, either, but...
Your dad died, right?
Actually, he died on a trip
with a lady, Noguchi Minako
I see.
Noguchi Minako was wearing
a tacky knit dress
I see, that's super interesting.
Glico.
- Glico.
- Big Crunch?
Yeah, the universe keeps expanding.
Right now,
it's blowing up like a balloon.
In the end, when the universe
can't get any bigger.
It will split, bam!
Glico.
Will the universe break?
Yeah, time will go backwards
It will turn back,
so clocks, people, trains
and cats will all move backwards.
Beef on rice will turn back into cows,
and poop goes back into your butt.
Really?
Humans will turn into monkeys,
the dinosaurs will come back
and we'll go back to before
the universe was born.
So, we're going to be reborn.
That's right.
Shall we get ready?
"I'm here."
Maybe here?
If it isn't a horse,
I would say, "Wrong".
- OK?
- OK
It's tasty.
PIG
You eat concrete.
SNAIL
Am I a woodlouse?
No, you're not.
You can't look up at the sky.
Am I chubby?
Like king of chubbiness.
Am I edible?
You're a gourmet food.
I know.
One, two.
- A pig.
- A snail.
- Correct.
Yeah!
- Who's the monster?
SLOTH
You have an amazing talent.
SUNFISH
Do I kick?
You don't kick.
Do I bite and release a poison?
When you're attacked,
you let go of all your strength
and give up.
That's not a talent.
You stop feeling.
Am I Hoshikawa Yori?
My future.
Bull's eye.
Rugby player.
My future...
"Mu-Gi-No Mi-Na-To.
"Ho-Shi-Ka-Wa Yo-Ri."
Do you think Mr. Hori will notice?
I don't think he will.
Ouch!
Oh, wait!
So many Over here, too.
There.
Thanks.
Where else?
Up there, up!
I found a lot!
- Ouch.
- You OK?
It's not your fault.
I was thinking about something.
It seems like I have to
change schools.
Where?
Grandma's house.
So you won't have to
worry anymore.
Your dad's abandoning you.
What a laugh.
Yeah.
No, I said it on purpose
to make you laugh.
I'm not mad.
I don't want you to go away...
I'm sorry.
Minato...
Wait, wait, get away.
Get away.
It's OK.
It happens...
To me, sometimes.
Hey, you're supposed to laugh!
Pass!
Over here!
Pass it, Minato!
Pass it to me! Pass it!
Minato!
Are you friendly with Hoshikawa?
Do you like Hoshikawa?
Gross.
You two are lovey dovey.
Yeah, lovey dovey!
What?
What are you doing?
Stop it!
- No good!
- Mugino!
Teacher's here!
You're bandaged.
You're OK!
I'm supposed to report you
but let's keep it a secret.
Time to make up.
Shake hands like men.
Time for you both to change
into your gym clothes.
Three, two, one.
Who's the monster?
- Who's the...
- Minato?
Minato?
Your ear hurt?
I'm sorry.
I...
Can't be like Dad.
I've promised your father.
That I'll hang in there until you're
married and have your...
Just an ordinary family
you see anywhere is fine.
YORI
own family, the
greatest treasure...
Minato?
Why was I born?
- Say...
- Tell him.
I'm cured of my sickness now.
I worried you, but I'm all fine now.
Cured of what?
- I'm normal now.
- You were always normal.
There's a girl you like near
grandma's house, right?
She's Shindo Ayaka.
Thank you for playing with him.
Thank you.
I'm sorry, I lied!
Hoshikawa! Hoshikawa!
- Hurts!
- Why can't you do what I tell you!
I'll punish you again.
- Shut up!
- Stop! It hurts.
We'll have...
Confiscated.
We'll have a new teacher
replace Mr. Hori.
If you have any problem at all,
discuss it honestly with a teacher.
Is that Hori?
It's Hori.
Why's Hori here?
Mugino.
Mugino, Mugino!
Why is he back now?
- Is he angry about his punishment?
- It's his own fault.
We've had enough of his problems.
I'm sorry.
Who are you apologizing to?
Mr. Hori did nothing wrong.
I told a lie.
I see.
So did I.
I used to be a music teacher.
My brass band club
used to compete nationally.
Hold it this way.
Your left hand holds this.
Have you ever seen one?
You extend this
to change the pitch.
And then your mouth here
Loosen your lips.
Not bad.
Maybe a lighter instrument is better.
I see,
so you told a lie...
I, um...
I'm not really sure,
but I like someone.
I see.
I can't tell anyone, so I lie.
Cause they'll know
I can never be happy.
In that case,
whatever you can't tell anyone,
blow it away.
Blow it away.
But that's nonsense.
If only some people can have it,
that's not happiness.
That's just nonsense.
Happiness is something
anyone can have.
Hoshikawa?
Hoshikawa!
The Big Crunch is coming.
It's safe!
You're right.
Want to eat?
Will it take off?
Sounds like it's taking off.
Were we reborn?
I don't think that happened.
We weren't?
We weren't, we're the same.
OK, great.