Although this film was inspired by
actual events that took place in Tokyo,
the details and characters portrayed
in this film are entirely fictional.
NOBODY KNOWS
Hello.
We've just moved into #203.
We're the Fukushimas.
I wanted to meet the landlord.
It's just a token gift.
Thank you for taking the trouble.
It's very nice to meet you.
Um, my husband's abroad,
you see,
so really, it's just the two of us.
I hope you'll look out for us.
Oh, I see.
Don't hesitate to ask.
Thank you very much.
Introduce yourself.
I'm Fukushima Akira.
I see. And...
...are you in junior high?
- I'm in sixth grade.
You're so big.
Once you get to this age,
it's fine, but little ones...
Well, other tenants tend
to complain about them.
Oh, he's very mature.
He'll be no trouble.
Fortunately, he takes after his father,
and he's a really good student.
But now that he's in sixth grade,
he's ready to learn English...
Mother.
Hold on.
In the back room, please.
The living room?
Yes.
You just know
that landlord remarried.
His first wife,
I bet you his first wife died,
and he went and married again.
Just hold on, Shigeru.
What is this!
Just hold on.
Here goes.
You okay? Was it hot?
It's hot.
Wow, you did a great job.
It was hot.
This is your new home.
Just hold on, Shigeru.
Shall we let Shigeru out...
I'll let you out.
Here comes the noisy boy.
Was it hot?
Super hot.
You did a great job.
We're here.
Okay!
A huge success.
What floor is this?
Our new home is
on the second floor.
Apartment 203.
Get back inside, Shigeru.
What if they see you?
We'll have to move all over again.
Get inside.
Get in here!
Hey, Akira.
Get back inside.
Shigeru, you've got to
unpack your own toys.
I'll go pick up Kyoko
at the station.
Be careful, off you go.
You know the way?
I know.
I'm off.
Okay, off you go, then.
Did you wait?
You're late.
I'm sorry.
Is the apartment big?
Yeah, it's three rooms.
Pretty big.
The washing machine?
On the veranda.
The veranda, huh?
Kyoko!
We're home.
I think I know how
to make the soup.
I know how to make the soup.
Okay, then you make it.
Such big chopsticks!
Oh, I'll eat with these.
Yeah! My favorite.
Tasty?
May I have everyone's attention?
Now that we've moved
into a new home,
I'm going to explain the rules to you
one more time.
Let's promise to keep them, okay?
How many are there?
Okay, first of all,
no loud voices or screaming.
Can you do that?
I can.
Next, no going outside.
I know.
Can you do that?
Not even out on the veranda.
Okay? Can you keep that promise?
Sure!
Can you do it, little Shige-monster?
You're the one that
has to promise hardest.
Absolutely no going outside.
Can you do that?
Bet you can-can.
He didn't raise his hand.
That's right,
remember our old home...
we had to leave because
you always threw such tantrums?
So, now that we've found
a nice new home,
you've got to promise.
Can you?
How's Kyoko supposed
to do the laundry?
For the laundry,
there's no choice, but for Kyoko
to sneak out quietly for the laundry.
Don't go out with her, Shigeru.
And Akira,
you already know all this,
but Mom's sometimes late,
so you'll be in charge.
That's okay, right?
And study a lot.
You really have to get it, Shigeru.
Do you get it?
If you don't...
it's an enema for you!
Not an enema, green peppers.
Green peppers?
Why!
Make him eat peppers.
Oh, that's it, then.
We'll give Shigeru "The Pepper
Punishment," got that?
Next time you're up for a tantrum,
get in the suitcase.
Shut up!
Like I...
That's the time to climb in.
That's right, that's right.
What a great idea.
Put him there when he's noisy, okay?
We'll all put him in.
Mother.
These tatami mats smell good.
The tatami?
What do they smell like?
Like leaves in nature.
That's a nice smell, isn't it?
The tatami are still new.
They're still green.
Make you sleep well?
Good night.
Will you be late?
Today? Let's see...
What's today?
Oh, I guess I might...
Maybe I'll be late.
You want dinner?
Dinner... dinner...
What's for dinner tonight?
Maybe curry.
Curry? I want curry!
Save me some curry.
Please.
Maybe I'll eat it.
Off you go.
Hey, did Mom leave already?
She just left.
Dangerous.
The piano...
I'm going shopping.
Off you go.
Get me an "Apollo Choco".
Sure.
150 yen.
Shall I buy persimmons...
No "Apollo Choco".
There's a video arcade...
"Inageya Hardware Store".
"Near and far-sighted..."
Found it.
Apollo Choco
No bag, right?
Out of 100 yen, then.
Thank you very much.
Save 'em for later...
You okay?
I'm fine.
The bath's ready, brother.
You can go first.
Okay.
Are there carrots?
There are carrots.
None for me.
No, you have to eat them.
Dinner's ready, Kyoko.
Okay.
Shigeru left the carrots, again.
Elementary Japanese
Look, Mother's home.
Hey there, I'm back.
Welcome home.
It's damned cold out there.
Warm in here.
Weren't you in bed, yet?
I was hanging the laundry.
What a good girl.
Thank you.
And what do we have here?
Can I have some?
Damn. It's cold.
Welcome home.
I'm home.
Oops.
Got it?
I can't.
No way.
It clicked but went out.
All yours.
Did I get this right?
What's this?
"A nation that flourished.
"in about 300 C.C."
What don't you understand?
Just wondered if I got it right.
No, it should be "300 B.C."
When you don't know,
you look it up in here.
That way, you'll learn.
Wow, is this Shigeru's?
Wow, what's this?
This yours? Kyoko's?
I hate math...
Six times six is...
Six-six, six-six...
Hurry, six-six.
I can do it.
Six-six is thirty-six...
Hello, yes.
It's noisy there, awful noisy.
Where are you? Karaoke?
Not now, it's too late.
What? Who's there?
Oh, really, what a shame...
And-a 2.
And-a, and-a 3.
Hey, oh no.
And-a 1, hey.
And-a 3.
And-a, and-a 4.
Wow!
Oh, me? And-a, and-a 2.
Oh, no, I'm the loser who
has to go without dinner!
You won't get sleepy.
If there's no lid on,
what could be inside?
You can't tell.
See, if you close your eyes
and put it in,
if you put it in but you don't know...
Mother...
I want to go to school.
School?
You wouldn't have any fun at school.
Besides, when you don't have a Daddy,
they bully you at school.
You don't need to go to school.
Wow, feels really great.
Great smell, did you smell it?
Stinks of sunlight.
Stinks of sunlight?
What a beautiful day...
Your mother...
is in love with someone now.
Again?
Not again.
This guy's really
sweet and serious.
I think he is really
looking out for me.
So, if he promises to really...
to really marry me,
then we can all live in a big house
and you can all go to school
and Kyoko can play the piano...
So just hang on a little longer.
I really think this time, probably...
I'm home.
Here we are, sushi.
I'm home, meow.
Were you asleep?
C'mon, c'mon guys,
the sushi was a present.
A sushi present, c'mon, c'mon.
You wake up?
You wake up? You mad?
C'mon over, come over,
c'mon over, Yuki.
She stinks of booze.
Aren't you cold?
Were you asleep? I'm sorry.
It's just that your Mommy had
a pretty good time today.
Here you are, Mom.
Oh, thank you.
Akira.
Listen, Akira...
he's starting to look
just like his father.
He's got his father's eyes, exactly.
You brother's father...
used to work at Haneda.
You know what Haneda is?
It's a place with lots of airplanes.
You know... right, Shigeru?
That's where he used to work.
Oh, I know... listen, Akira.
Remember going to see your father?
I don't.
We took the Monorail to
get to Haneda Airport.
You forget?
Yeah.
Kyoko, your father was...
a music producer...
I know! Let's give Kyoko's...
pretty hands a nice manicure.
Your mother... actually...
wanted to be a singer.
And I really made it...
part way.
With your father, Kyoko.
Oops, way too much.
I was going to cut a record...
And we were almost ready...
when the deal fell apart.
Your mother really wanted to, but...
Dear Akira,
Your mother's
going away for a little while.
Please look after Kyoko,
Shigeru and Yuki.
I'm going shopping.
Sure, off you go, then.
And also, Mother won't be
coming back for a while.
Why not?
Something to do with work, I think.
I'm off.
Off you go.
Please indicate the account number
for your transfer...
The rent... electricity bill,
phone and gas...
And also...
tissues...
Let's go to my office.
Do you always do this?
No, I don't.
Your first time?
I didn't take anything.
Then what's all this doing here?
Your name?
Fukushima Akira.
Fukushima... Akira...
School?
Your father's name?
I don't have a father.
No father?
Your mother. Then?
She's gone away to work
for a while.
Where did she go?
If you won't tell me,
I'll have to call the police.
Sir,
I don't think this boy stole that.
I think the boys reading comics
over there put them in his bag.
It wasn't him?
No, I don't think so.
Why didn't you speak up?
I'm sorry.
Don't "I'm sorry" me.
This is just between us, okay?
The meat buns are a little bonus.
Hurry, give it to him.
Thank you very much.
Is that a plus sign?
That's right.
9,824 yen.
9,824 yen?
I forgot to add this...
Hello.
Isn't this your day off?
I'm driving again tonight.
No use going home.
How's your mom?
She hasn't been home in a month.
For real?
How old are you, Akira?
I'm 12.
And Yuki?
Yuki's fine.
She takes after me?
Yes, she does.
For real...
Akira!
Shit, I'm 10 yen short.
Lend me 10 yen.
What, 10 yen?
Why make a big deal over 10 yen?
What's with that damned big wallet?
It's a hand-me-down
from my mother.
From who?
From my mother...
You moved, right?
The new place big?
Any pubic hair, yet?
No...
Liar, got mine in 5th grade.
No way.
That's the truth.
It's just...
What are you smirking about?
It's just that since Mother's gone,
It's just, there's no money.
For real? I don't have any money.
What've you got left?
About 10,000 yen.
10,000 yen is enough.
I'm in a hell of a jam, myself.
My girlfriend, you know,
she totally maxed out my credit cards.
I'm in credit card hell, man.
So I'm working my ass off,
slowly paying it off, man.
This is all I've got on me.
This is it, the last time.
Thank you.
All right, I'm off.
By the way, Yuki's not my kid.
Every time I did it with your mom,
I used a condom. Bye, then.
Bye, then.
Thanks for this.
Bye.
Oh no, I'm hopeless.
Gotta get it in.
So cold...
I spent 674 yen
at the supermarket.
I have 650 yen left in my wallet.
How many yen were in my wallet
to begin with?
Soon, I came across Bubu the Pig,
planting turnip seeds in a field.
What a nice bag you have there.
My mother made it for me.
Where, where, where is it?
You can't go out, Shigeru.
I'm not out.
I'm home!
Welcome home.
How've you guys been?
Hey, how've you guys been?
See, I'm home.
Look, presents.
This one's for Yuki.
Thank you.
For you, Shigeru.
I'm home.
Akira, Akira.
Wow, it's been a while.
Shall I open it for you?
You can carry it on your back.
Wow!
It's cute.
Carry it? Carry it?
Like a backpack.
You can put your things inside,
and do that...
The sides? Your ears? Out?
Ears out?
You look so neat.
He looks better with short hair.
Which is more becoming, Yuki?
Long or...
Long.
You like him better with long hair?
Oh, no, but I'll cut it anyway.
A little bit shorter's okay, right?
What's that face for?
Don't tell me
I cut your bangs too short.
You're fine, right?
Too short?
I don't believe it.
Anyway, it'll grow right back out.
Don't act so cool.
You look cute.
I mean it.
Here goes!
Maribo!
A chop! The pits!
Chop Maribo!
Maribo!
Hey, what are you doing?
Kyoko.
What are you doing?
Don't touch my things.
It's your fault.
It won't come out...
Where were you, really, Mother?
I told you I was working.
A whole month?
I was in Osaka.
It was just too far.
I told you not to touch my things.
What are you doing?
What? You see, today,
your mother has to step out,
so I'm getting ready.
You're going already?
Your mother's... busy today.
But listen,
I'll be back for Christmas.
Only 5,000 yen?
He could've lent you a little more.
I mean, you're little kids in a jam.
But hey, pachinko parlors and taxis,
I don't draw customers
in such hard times.
But you go back to him
if you need to.
It's cold.
And the wind's blowing so hard.
It's so cold...
Did you tell the man you're seeing
about us?
I told you, I'll tell him eventually...
Sugar.
You've got sugar there.
God, you're irritating.
Listen, I keep asking you,
when will you let us go to school?
What's this "school this, school that"?
Who needs to go to school anyway?
Plenty of famous people never
even went to school in the first place.
Like who?
How should I know?
But plenty of them...
You're so selfish, Mother.
How can you say that?
Selfish? You want to know
who's really selfish?
Your father's the one who's selfish,
up and disappearing like that.
What is this?
I'm not allowed to be happy?
Oh, I know someone famous.
Prime Minister Tanaka.
Ever heard of him?
Never.
You're too young.
How about...
the wrestler Antonio Inoki?
I bet he never went to school.
I'm not sure, but...
Sure, he did.
Man, you're a drag.
Hurry up and finish eating.
I'll send you money soon.
You'll come home for Christmas?
Sure, I'll come home.
I'll be right home.
You take care of them, too.
Is Totoro really real?
Don't you know how big Totoro is?
I know.
I know, he's really big.
It'd be a real mess if
he was walking around.
The police would've caught him.
Think there are UFOs?
Nope.
If Martians exist, so do UFOs.
Martians are...
What about real zombies?
Scary zombies.
You think Santa Claus is real?
He is, he is.
You think?
There's only one Santa, right?
He can't cover Japan
all by himself, can he?
But he can.
Santa Claus can manage it.
That's right, there are all kinds...
Mother didn't come back, did she?
Her work kept her away longer.
Because I was so mean to Mom?
No, that's not true.
Hello, this is the
Sanwa Department Store.
May I speak to Fukushima Keiko
in menswear?
Excuse me...
This is her son.
Please hold a moment.
I'm terribly sorry, but Ms. Fukushima
resigned last month.
How may I help you?
How many minutes, Shigeru?
Not yet.
Not yet... how many more minutes?
One more minute, maybe.
Maybe?
Not ready yet?
It's about ready, I think.
You think?
Let's eat. Then.
Thanks for the food.
Off you go, then.
I have to lick the lid.
Taste good?
Tastes good.
The super-duper best.
Excuse me, I'm looking
for a phone number.
Kanagawa Prefecture,
Kawasaki City, Nakahara-Ku...
Hello, this is the Yamamotos.
Hello... Hello?
Wonder who this is.
They aren't talking...
Good evening.
Have a happy new year.
Kyoko's next.
With the "kyo" like in Tokyo.
Akira.
That's right...
Mom sent us all
New Year's presents.
Look.
For you, Yuki.
Thank you.
Shigeru.
Kyoko.
That's for you.
Thanks.
4,000 yen!
4,000 yen! No way.
It's 2,000 yen.
1,000 yen.
4,000 yen.
What do you want, Yuki?
A doll.
Shigeru?
Rollerblades.
Rollerblades?
You, Kyoko?
I'm saving mine up for a piano.
You, brother?
A baseball glove.
No, I'm gonna meet
Mommy at the station.
She's not coming home today.
I'm sure she's coming home.
She'll be back next week.
She's really coming next week?
She really will.
How do you know?
I just do.
She's coming home next week.
It's Yuki's birthday today.
These?
Yeah.
Just hang on.
Okay, let's go.
Good evening.
Stepping out?
Where to?
To the station to meet my mommy.
I see, what's your name?
Yuki.
Yuki, I see.
How old are you, Yuki?
I'm 5.
5 years old? I see.
She's our cousin,
just staying overnight.
Oh, I see...
Off you go, then.
Off we go, then.
Adorable little girl.
Tomato, daikon, broccoli,
squash, carrot...
There's so many.
Plates...
Cups...
The butcher's...
Oh, only one left?
The last one.
There's the monorail.
It goes to Haneda Airport.
Someday let's get on
and go see the airplanes.
Yeah, let's do that.
Dear Kyoko
To Kyoko
No, no, it turns on
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, idiot.
No, no, it's 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6.
No. I swear it's on 5.
No, I swear it's 6.
Listen, listen, man.
You couldn't even do it on
that Kamehameha thing.
Yes I could.
Go! No, that's too far-ish.
Oh damn, you did it.
You're a genius, man.
Using the brake?
No brake.
Hey, wow, cool.
You gotta crash it.
That one already burned...
Welcome.
Your friends?
Yeah, friends.
That's 197 yen.
Get off, get off.
Thanks.
Let's go.
Bye, then.
Thank you.
See you tomorrow.
Bye, then.
Please indicate the desired amount.
- Excuse us.
This one, huh?
Let's do it, let's do it.
Are you ready?
Start!
All right, perfect, max.
What!
Take that!
What a weird haircut.
Coke and what?
Coke and orange and...
CC Lemon.
I'm home.
We bought stuff.
You're late.
How far'd you go?
Coke for me.
Me too.
Hey, somebody attacked.
Hey, you jerk, you let 'em in.
But this person attacked.
Your Gas Bill is Overdue
Get away, you jerk.
Okay, nice.
Go away.
Told you so, dammit.
You'll never get it that way.
Butt out.
Let's go to the store, Akira.
I'm hungry, treat us.
Sure.
Hey, I wanna go, too.
No, you stay home.
Don't touch the game.
Don't touch it.
What are you doing?
Hey, hey hey, isn't this great?
Her tits are huge.
Great, huh?
Isn't it great?
You swipe it?
Your turn, Akira.
We're friends, right? Go.
Let's go.
Hey, wait.
He's not your type?
No way! He's way too passionate.
I like a cool guy.
But that's what's so cool.
Been a while.
How you been?
Yeah, fine.
They're too big for me.
They don't fit.
Mom says I'll grow anyway,
so take the big ones.
I hate 'em.
Hey.
Been a while.
How you been? What's up?
Bought a new game,
why don't you come over?
I'll come over
when I have time.
See you 'round.
I've got cram school, sorry.
See ya.
See ya, then.
Who was that?
Take me along to play.
Yeah, but his house stinks.
No way, stinks of what?
Stinks of garbage.
The place is a real mess.
Like rotting?
Here she comes.
To Mizuguchi Saki in Heaven
Got it.
Hello there, Fukushima-san.
Don't worry, he's gone.
How old are you?
I'm 12.
You can't start working part-time
until you're 16.
Shouldn't you contact the police
or child welfare, or something?
If I do, the four of us won't
be able to stay together.
That happened before
and it was an awful mess.
I see...
You need it for your piano.
It's okay.
Let's race.
Don't beat me, Akira.
Welcome.
Did your mother come back?
Who's taller?
We're the same.
There are seeds here, too.
Take them.
I'll take these, too.
Okay, I'll take these.
Look, Akira, seeds.
Somebody just left them behind.
Poor things.
2, 3, 4, 5...
Amazing, for real.
Paper, scissors, rock.
First is rock.
I can't stop.
Akira, got dirt?
Got it.
Shige!
Shigeru!
Shigeru.
Hey, Shigeru.
The bag.
It came out funny.
Yu...
ki...
I'll go get some water.
Brother, the lights don't work.
Not in the bathroom, either.
Mr. String, Mr. String,
where are you?
What are you doing?
Not going to school?
No...
I'm not either.
There's a cicada hole here,
did you know?
No, I didn't.
And again.
Pi-ne-ap-p-l-e.
First is rock.
Paper, scissors, rock.
Ch-o-co-la-t-e.
First is rock.
Paper, scissors, rock.
And again!
We have suspended
your water service
I got so many.
Wow, amazing.
What are you doing?
Nothing special.
Did you catch cold?
Your voice sounds weird.
Shut up.
Are you washing your hair?
Yesterday, at the park.
Nice and cool?
When's your mother coming back?
She's never coming back.
Probably.
I'm not hot.
I'm hot.
I said, I'm not hot, I'm not.
Thank you.
Eat the inari sushi first.
Shigeru.
No salmon?
No, just what's there.
This was Shigeru's.
It died.
She fell asleep.
Excuse me. The door was unlocked...
I'm the landlord from the 3rd floor,
here about the rent.
Where's your mother?
She's working in Osaka.
Are you cousins?
I'll go make some money.
What? How?
Here!
No.
Why not?
Just sang karaoke with him.
No!
What are you eating?
Spit it out.
What is that?
Paper.
That's 287 yen.
Exactly, thank you.
How'd the semester go?
His report card, you mean?
A total disaster.
He got a terrible grade in Japanese.
My child did badly, too.
Wish I could find something.
Hey, where's Shigeru?
Dunno.
What are you doing?
Where's Shigeru?
Dunno.
Shige!
You said you wanted noodles
so I got some!
What do you want!
You watch it, buster.
Don't bother coming home.
Don't take it out on things.
Did it break?
Amazing power.
He's just an idiot.
Cut it out, Yuki.
I have to pee.
Why didn't you pee
in the park, before?
Go pee by the bath.
Don't want to.
Is Saki coming back?
Shigeru! You can't just
use up all the water!
There's none left to drink.
Is Saki coming to play again?
Never.
What are you doing?
I'm selling these.
Don't need 'em anymore.
Stop it.
Cut it out.
Let go!
Shut up!
Move.
Don't touch it!
She's never coming back.
Who cares! Stay in there!
Idiot!
Miyauchi!
Don't move your legs too much!
Kato! Where's Yano today?
Cram school.
Cram school?
Oh, man, we're short.
What year are you?
Akira, #9, right field.
Line up!
We're starting a game between the
White Bears and the Kenzan Fighters.
Let's go!
Bow.
Akira, hold your hands closer,
like this...
When the ball comes,
take a real hard slice at it, wham.
Just, wham, swing at it.
That's fine, nice swing...
"A big, big,
homerun, homerun."
"In heaven...
Grandpa and grandma..."
Yuki.
Yuki won't get up.
Yuki!
She fell off the chair.
Yes, hello?
Is Fukushima Keiko there?
Just a minute.
I'll go get her.
Mommy
A big, big...
homerun...
In heaven...
Grandpa and grandma.
So surprised...
A big... homerun...
In heaven...
Akira.
What happened?
That money...
Can I borrow it?
I want to show Yuki...
the airplanes.
You all off for a picnic?
Looks like fun.
That'll be 1,895 yen.
Okay, thanks.
Kyoko, what's this?
It just arrived.
To Akira: give them my best.
I'm counting on you. --Mother
She doesn't fit.
Guess Yuki... grew.
Is it good bye?
When I touched Yuki
this morning...
she was so cold, it was awful.
It just felt so...
It was just so...
When I ask the midnight sky
the stars just shine
Into the black lake of my
molten heart
I can only flow
Will the angel even give me
a backward glance?
Want to splash around in my heart?
The winds of the coming winter
lap at the waves
calling me into the dark
With eyes as wilted as ice
I'm growing up
A jewel pungent with a stench
that brooks no one's approach.
Thanks.
Found one!
YAGIRA Yuuya
KITAURA Ayu
KIMURA Hiei
SHIMIZU Momoko
KAN Hanae
YOU
KUSHIDA Kazumi
OKAMOTO Yukiko
TATE Takako
KASE Ryo
KIMURA Yuichi
ENDO Ken'ichi
TERAJIMA Susumu
HIRAIZUMI Sei
Executive Producers:
SHIGENOBU Yutaka
KAWASHIRO Kazumi
Development Producer:
YASUDA Masahiro
Associate Development Producers:
KOBAYASHI Eitaro
Lee Bong-Ou
Associate Producers:
URATANI Toshiro
KOHNO Satoshi
Producer KORE-EDA Hirokazu
Line Producer: TAGUCHI Hijiri
Cinematography:
YAMAZAKI Yutaka
Sound:
TSURUMAKI Yutaka
Art Direction:
ISOMI Toshihiro
MITSUMATSU Keiko
Casting:
ARAE Yoshiko
Chief Assistant Director:
KUMAGAI Kiichi
Production Manager:
SHIRAISHI Osamu
Stylist:
KOBAYASHI Miwako
Hair and Make-Up:
SAKAI Mutsuki
Still Photography:
KAWAUCHI Rinko
Publicity Design:
KASAI Kaoru
Music: GONTITI
Theme Song "A Jewel":
TATE Takako
Production Assistance:
TV MAN UNION, INC.
Produced by
BANDAI VISUAL CO., LTD.
ENGINE FILM, NC.
C-style
Cine Qua Non
Directed, Written and Edited by
KORE-EDA Hirokazu
English subtitles: Linda Hoaglund
©NOBODY KNOWS Project Team