[video camera beeps, whirs]
[beeping]
[video camera whirring]
[whirring continues]
[video camera beeping, whirring]
-[video camera whirring]
-[Sophie] Oh. Oh.
-[Sophie sighs] What's that?
-[Calum chuckles]
-[Sophie] Oh, my God, what even is that?
-These are my moves.
[Sophie chuckles]
Dad, that's so embarrassing.
[Calum] That's not embarrassing.
[Sophie] Wait.
-What?
-I was gonna interview you.
Oh, you were, were you?
What were you gonna interview me about?
[Sophie] I don't know.
-Well…
-Well, I just turned 11,
and you are 130,
turning 131 in 2 days.
[chuckles] So…
When you were 11,
what did you think you would be doing now?
[video camera whirs]
[moody music playing]
-[baby crying]
-[music continues]
[video camera whirring]
-[Calum] I love you.
-Love you.
[indistinct announcement over PA system]
[Calum] Bye.
-[video camera whirs]
-[music continues]
[music fades]
-[engine starting]
-Hiya, everyone. My name's Belinda,
and I'll be your tour rep
for the next week or two.
Now, I've only just transferred in
from Torremolinos.
-[microphone feedback ringing]
-[speaks indistinctly]
-[loudly] From Torremolinos!
-[feedback ringing]
[crowd laughing]
[Belinda] Right. Well, I hope I'll be
a good help to you here in Turkey
-all the same.
-[Calum whispers] "Hiya."
-[Belinda] We've got seven stops tonight.
-"My name's Belinda."
So, just bear with us. All right?
"And I've just come in from…
[loud whisper] …Torremolinos!"
[Sophie chuckling]
[enunciating] Torremolinos.
[softly] Torremolinos. Torremolinos…
[calling bell dinging]
[dog barking in distance]
-Hang tight, poppet, okay?
-Okay.
I'm fine.
[door opening]
[Calum] Someone's coming.
Time for bed?
No.
[lifts telephone receiver, dials]
[line ringing]
Hello?
Hi. It's, um, 501.
Yeah, that's us.
Yeah, um, I booked a room with two beds,
but we've only got the one here.
Yeah, okay, well, I paid for it, and, um,
it was confirmed by the travel agency.
Okay, that's all you can do?
[softly] Okay. Scooch under. There we go.
Oh, it'll have to be then.
Okay. Thanks.
Mmm, good night.
[softly] Good night. [kisses]
[objects clatter softly]
[bag zipping up]
[Sophie snoring softly]
[snoring continues]
[Calum snoring softly]
[metal clanging outside]
-[people speaking indistinctly]
-[clanging continues]
-"Digital video entertainment."
-[Calum] Don't get that wet, Soph.
-It was expensive.
-[Sophie mouthing]
[clanging continues loudly]
Sorry about the hotel.
Clive was just here,
said he had a great time.
[hammering, clanging]
Everything okay at home?
What do you mean?
I mean,
how are you and your mum getting along?
Yeah, okay, I guess.
Good.
I'm glad.
Why? What did she tell you?
She didn't say anything.
You just told me you weren't getting along
that well last time I saw you. Remember?
Can't exactly ask you
when I phone you at home.
Oh, yeah. Right.
Things have been better.
Why don't you go over
and introduce yourself?
-Dad, no. They're, like, kids.
-Mmm-hmm.
Why don't you go over
and introduce yourself?
Mmm. Sophie, they're, like, old.
[Calum chuckles]
[Calum] Hmm. See, if you let it rest
on an object for a wee while,
it gets the lighting right.
That's quite clever.
[somber music playing]
[Sophie and Calum laugh]
-You want a massive ice cream?
-Yeah, that's bigger than my head.
[Calum] That's impossible.
You have a massive head. [chuckles]
-[Sophie] Are you done?
-[chuckling] What?
-That's a bit rude.
-No, it's not. It's just a fact.
[Sophie] Your head's bigger than mine.
[Calum] I…
I would disagree with that fact.
Look at the size of it. [laughing]
Your head's bigger. See?
[Sophie squeals, speaks indistinctly]
-[indistinct conversation]
-[somber music continues]
[Calum on video] Say hello to your mum.
That's all you're gonna give her?
-[Sophie] Love you.
-[Calum] Say you miss her.
[Sophie] I miss you.
-[Calum] And what?
-[Sophie] And bye-bye.
[Calum whispers]
And your dad's being amazing.
-[normal voice] And what?
-[Sophie] And my dad's being amazing.
-[Calum] Why is your dad being amazing?
-Because he's taking so much…
[video stops]
[video camera turning off]
[dog barking in distance]
[sighs softly]
Uh-huh. Well, what did she say?
Oh. I'll do it when I'm home.
School doesn't start
until Thursday, right?
Okay.
Yeah, it's good.
We're not actually at our hotel.
But ours doesn't have a phone, so…
Dad?
He's good.
Oh, my God, he's doing some weird
slow-motion ninja moves.
Why is he so weird sometimes?
But, yeah, he's good.
All right. Love you. Bye.
[knocks on door]
-Mum wants to talk to you.
-What?
-Right.
[Calum] Thanks, poppet.
Hey.
Checking up on me?
[girl 1] So, are you gonna do anything?
-[girl 2] What do you mean?
-[toilet flushing]
[girl 1] With George.
He told Seb he wanted to.
With you, I mean.
Not Seb, obviously.
Last night, on the way home, I gave Kenny…
Literally in the bushes
behind the other pool.
[girl 2] Well, like, what happened?
-[girl 1] What do you mean?
-[girl 2] Did he come?
[girl 1] Yeah. I mean, obviously.
[toilet flushing]
You should wear your hair back sometimes.
You look really pretty
with your hair back.
[water running]
[girl 2] Oh, my God,
do you think she heard us?
[girl 1] Who cares?
She's literally, like, nine.
[girls giggle]
[tap closes]
[Calum chuckles]
That's wonderful.
[chuckles]
Yeah, I'm so happy for you.
All right. Love you.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Yeah, will do.
Okay. Bye.
[hangs up phone]
Hey. [chuckles]
-[rock song playing on speakers]
-[indistinct chatter]
Do you know how to play?
It's that one to start.
I know.
[video game beeps]
[automated male voice]
Come on, start your engines.
[engines starting in video game]
[engine revving]
[engines revving loudly]
[countdown timer beeping]
-[horn blaring]
-[engines revving]
[tires screeching]
-[automated voice] Game over. Round one.
-[video game trilling]
-You wanna play again?
-Right, Soph, we're up.
-[Sophie] Bye.
-Bye.
Here you go.
Right, you ready?
[indie rock song playing on speakers]
Right. There you go.
-You don't mind, do you?
-No bother.
Right. Last one for now, then, okay?
Do you want a game of doubles?
Yeah, sure.
-[boy] You've got a built-in rest there.
-[chuckles] No danger.
I'm right-handed,
and I'm playing with a kid, right?
Go easy.
-You wanna break, or…
-Yeah.
[Calum] Good.
-[pool ball strikes]
-Well done.
[balls rolling]
So, what's your sister's name?
-Uh, Sophie.
-Oh, nice.
I'm her dad, though, actually.
-[boy] Oh. Sorry, mate, I just thought--
-[Calum] That's okay.
-[Calum] It's a nice hotel, eh?
-[boy] Yeah, it's all right.
We're staying in that one over the road.
-Basically a building site, so…
-[chuckles]
[ball strikes]
Olly.
Fucking hell, Sophie. Impressive.
Hey, don't say… [whispers] …"fuck."
-Oh, sorry, mate--
-That's okay.
Well done.
[balls rolling]
Right, I'm up. You watching?
[kids screaming excitedly]
[pool water splashing]
-[boy] No!
-That's it. Move it.
-[boy screams] No!
-No.
You want to ruin it again for everybody,
as usual.
[boy shouts] No!
[Calum] Twist.
-[Sophie grunts]
-Nope. Keep your…
-I'm not letting you off. Go again.
-[grunts]
No, you're just pushing.
Look, you have to twist.
Like, here.
Okay? Again.
No. Okay, grab my wrists.
Okay, okay, I get it.
So, the thin part lines up
to where the fingers connect, okay?
-Are you looking?
-Okay. Mmm-hmm.
And then you pull as hard as you can,
like that.
-Ow!
-No, this is serious, Sophie.
Look at me. It's important you get this.
Go.
No. You're not twisting,
you're just pulling.
-Okay, again. Look, grab my wrists.
-I can't twist.
Thin part lines up
to where the fingers connect.
Okay? And you pull as hard as you can.
-[softly] Okay.
-This is serious, Sophie.
It's important you get this.
So that you can defend yourself.
So that if anyone
ever tries to attack you,
you can break free and get away.
What if someone tries to attack me
some other way?
Without grabbing my wrists?
[somber music playing]
[Sophie] I think it's nice
that we share the same sky.
What you mean?
Well, like, sometimes at playtime,
I look up to the sky,
and if I can see the sun,
then I think about the fact that
we can both see the sun.
So, even though we're not
actually in the same place,
and we're not actually together,
we kind of are in a way, you know?
Like, we're both underneath
the same sky, so…
we're kind of together.
One. Head under.
-[speaks indistinctly]
-Two.
Three.
Four.
Four and a half…
-Stop, stop.
-What?
-[kids shouting indistinctly, playing]
-[somber music continues]
[Sophie] Can we do that?
[Calum] Hmm?
You're too young, poppet.
[music fades]
-[shower running]
-[Sophie] Ladies and gentlemen,
the marvelous, wonderful, amazing,
one-armed Calum Aaron Patterson.
Getting ready to see
the evening entertainment.
And…
We'll see…
[squealing] Torremolinos!
[Calum] You okay, Soph?
-[pop song playing on speakers]
-[indistinct chatter]
[Sophie] You've not mentioned Claire.
Hmm? Um…
Remember she had a boyfriend
when we first met?
Yup.
I was like, "Who's that on the phone?"
You were like, "Oh, just this girl I like,
but she's already going out with someone."
Yeah, well, they got back together.
Aw. I liked her.
Mmm-hmm. Me, too.
So, does that mean
you're not gonna open the café?
Café?
Uh, no. Not anymore.
But… I've got this new thing going
with Keith.
What is it?
Well, we're still figuring it out exactly,
but we're thinking of renting a house
a wee bit outside London to work from.
You'd have your own room
for when you come down.
-Yes. Can I paint it yellow?
-Yellow?
Why yellow?
I like the idea of a yellow room,
but Mum doesn't let me
paint my room yellow.
[chuckles]
[sing-song]
You're trying to get me into trouble.
Well, can I, though?
Aye, we'll see.
["Macarena, Bayside Boys Remix"
playing over speakers]
-Right, let's watch this.
-[people cheering, applauding]
-[song continues]
-[people clapping rhythmically]
[people whooping]
♪ When I dance they call me Macarena ♪
♪ And the boys they say
"Que estoy buena" ♪
♪ They all want me, they can't have me ♪
♪ So they all come and dance beside me ♪
♪ Move with me, chant with me ♪
♪ And if you're good
I'll take you home with me ♪
-[song continues playing]
-[indistinct conversation]
[Calum] Soph, did you bring your wallet?
No? No?
Okay. Grab this.
Do not look at him.
When I count to three, we'll throw it
at the stage and leave. Understand?
[Calum shouts indistinctly]
♪ Now don't you worry about my boyfriend
The boy whose name is Vitorino ♪
[Sophie] Did it hurt?
When you fell.
-[Calum] When I broke my wrist?
-Uh-huh.
I don't know.
I don't really remember.
Um, I didn't think it was broken then.
I'd never broken anything before.
[grunts softly]
[Sophie] I've never broken
anything before.
[Calum] Mmm.
-How come you and Mum say, "Love you"?
-What?
Like, on the phone.
You're not together,
so why would you say it?
Well…
Think of all the people you say it to.
Like, your nana, granddad,
uncle, aunties, right?
Yeah, but they're, like, family.
Well, your mother is family.
[Sophie] I remember one time
I asked Mum if she'd phoned you.
-[Calum groans softly]
-And she said that you were engaged.
Like, I didn't know why,
but I thought that meant
that you were getting married,
like, both of youse.
Like, I didn't know if I thought that
about just you or both of you, but…
[Calum grunts, winces]
Isn't that funny?
Well, I didn't know
what it meant at the time.
I didn't know that it meant that you were
just on the phone to somebody else.
I was kind of excited.
About us getting married?
Yeah. I was really young, though.
Like…
I don't know, like, seven.
How are you getting on with the book?
You enjoying it?
Yeah, it's a bit hard
to understand, though.
[Calum] Stick with it.
I think you'll really like it.
[water dripping]
What does "municipal" mean?
[water lapping softly]
[somber music playing]
[Calum] A proper dive, Soph.
[Sophie] I told you, I can't.
-[Calum] You were diving last year.
-No, I wasn't.
[Calum] Here.
-[Sophie] Pass me my mask.
-I did.
[Sophie] What?
[Calum] Come on, Soph,
stop messing around.
[Sophie] I'm not messing around.
[somber music continues]
[music fades]
[man speaking in Spanish]
I don't deserve this.
Shut up, don't be silly.
[man and woman laugh]
No, to the right.
You've already applied it there.
You know I didn't see you throw it.
[Calum] Throw what?
The mask. I know it was expensive.
That's okay, darling.
It's fine.
I'm just a little tired today, that's all.
Can you run up and grab the camera?
It's in the bag.
[sighs]
[straining]
[man] Here.
Put that on your foot, then try again.
[Calum] On my foot?
Yeah, put it on.
It's gonna be much easier.
[chuckles]
-You need help?
-Yeah, please. Thanks.
There we go.
-Thank you.
-That's a trick of the trade.
It's not a bad trade.
Nope, not at all.
Is this what you do all year round, then?
You sound like my anneanne,
my mother's mum.
-Your grandma?
-Yeah.
She would prefer that I had a proper job.
-What is your shoe size?
-Uh, ten.
-Ten.
-Forty-four?
-[man] Forty-four.
-Yeah.
-I think these should fit.
You know, I used to travel a lot.
One season somewhere,
next season somewhere else,
but now I'm here, back home.
And do you miss it?
-Travelling?
-Aye.
Not as much as I was missing home,
to be honest.
And I'm going to have a baby soon.
-[chuckles] Congratulations.
-Yeah.
A few years ago, I thought I would be
at least 40 before all that, but…
[Calum] I can't see myself at 40,
to be honest.
Surprised I made it to 30.
[sighs]
My name is Sophie Lesley Patterson
reporting live from…
I don't know the name of this boat.
Um, but, basically,
I have just went and done
the most amazing thing
in my whole entire life.
So, we went, like, scuba diving thing.
And there was actually, like, a sea horse,
and it wrapped round
my, like, whole finger.
Then when I got out,
there was an… octopus,
and the instructor person…
I don't know.
Like, yeah, instructor put it on…
put an octopus on my head.
A real-life octopus on my head.
Yeah, but right now, Dad…
I mean, Calum Aaron Patterson…
is away on some
scuba diving thing, I think.
I can't remember, but…
Yeah, he doesn't actually have
a diving licence,
'cause he told a porky pie.
[chuckles]
But, yeah.
He'll be fine.
Yeah.
He'll be fine, I'm sure. [chuckles]
But, yeah! Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
[moody music playing]
[music fades]
[people speaking indistinctly]
[paragliding woman screams excitedly]
[paragliding man whooping]
What's that?
What?
Uh, that's just another kind of smoking,
and smoking--
Smoking causes cancer,
and puts tar in your lungs,
and makes your teeth all yellow,
and causes your eyeballs to fall out.
[Calum chuckles softly]
We'll go somewhere else next time.
It's not that bad. When was the last time
you want to see Nana?
Hmm.
Right.
Trouble.
So, watch again, okay?
-Okay. Let's see.
-Okay?
Right, that was a bad start.
When are you back at school?
-Thursday.
-Next week?
-Crazy.
-God, I thought it was a bit later.
-Who's your new teacher?
-Miss Mackel.
Aye, the one from Glasgow?
How'd you know that?
What?
She's pretty.
[laughs]
She's the pretty one from Glasgow.
She's stuck in my head.
Oh, my God, Dad, stop!
-[Calum chuckles] Okay.
-Stop.
Is she supposed to be good?
We done a crossover at the end of term.
Seems all right.
[Calum chuckles]
[indistinct chatter]
[bus honking]
[on speakers] ♪ If all you've got to
Prove today is your innocence… ♪
[automated voice] Insert coin.
[video game trills]
-Insert coin.
-You playing?
[Sophie] Dad's gone to get money.
Here, watch this.
-[automated voice] Insert coin.
-10p.
[coin clatters]
-[Sophie] Got another?
-[chuckles softly]
I'm Michael, by the way.
[Sophie] Well, you better
have been practicing, Michael.
-[Michael] Harsh.
-[video game trilling]
-[Michael] What's your name, then?
-Sophie.
[engines revving in video game]
[tires screeching]
-[automated voice] Game over.
-[Sophie] Are you joking?
-[video game trilling]
-That's 1-1.
I didn't know we were keeping count.
Yes, you did.
♪ You ♪
♪ You've been racing
Through the best days ♪
♪ Space age, road rage, fast lane ♪
♪ And if all you've got to do today ♪
♪ Is find peace of mind ♪
♪ Come here
You can take a piece of mine ♪
[song fades into
somber instrumental music]
-[water lapping softly]
-[insects trilling]
[music fades]
[Calum brushing teeth]
[water running]
[Calum] You okay through there?
-[brushing continues]
-I don't know. I guess.
I just feel a bit down or something.
[Calum] What do you mean?
[Sophie] I don't know.
Don't you ever feel like…
you've just… done a whole amazing day,
and then you come home
and feel tired and down,
and it feels like your bones don't work?
They're just tired,
and everything is tired.
Like you're sinking.
I don't know. It's weird.
[hesitates]
Well, we're here to have a good time, eh?
[spits]
Ready?
[Sophie] Yup.
[Calum] We'll get a nice dinner,
and we'll get an early night, yeah?
-[Sophie] Yes.
-Let's go.
Come on.
[door opens]
[door closes]
[bird chirping]
[water dripping]
[Calum breathing deeply]
-[dripping continues]
-[dog barking in distance]
[Calum breathes deeply]
[hawkers shouting in Turkish]
[Calum] Don't you think this one's lovely?
Yeah. It is, actually.
Yeah, the man was telling me that
each of these carpets
tells a different story.
Like, the symbols and motifs,
they represent different things.
[Sophie] Oh.
[mispronouncing] Teşekkür ederim.
-"Tea-sugar ederim."
-[in English] What?
-Tea-sugar ederim.
-[chuckles]
Tea-sugar ederim.
Teşekkür ederim.
-Oh!
-[in English] You see?
Uh, how much is this one?
This one is 45 million Turkish lira.
-Yeah, and what's that in pounds? Sorry.
-£850.
-Okay. Thanks.
-You're welcome.
-[somber music playing]
-[imperceptible]
[indistinct chatter]
You gonna play pool?
No, come on. Why don't you go
introduce yourself to those girls there?
She can come and play pool with us
if she wants.
There's only three of us, so…
-Play a couple of games of doubles?
-[Laura] She's a bit young, isn't she?
Yeah, but she's good at it.
She's better than him.
-Dad?
-Yeah, okay. Go on, then.
An hour,
and then you come right back, okay?
Okay.
[moody music playing]
-[Olly] Take your time, girls.
-[Laura chuckles]
-[Sophie] What's that?
-[Laura] Uh, it's an all-inclusive thing,
so you can get as much as you want
of anything.
-[moody music continues]
-[Calum breathing deeply]
-That's it?
-It's the same thing.
Well, well, well, look who it is.
[boy] No, this side, innit, mate. Oi, oi.
[Olly] Whoa, whoa,
you don't wanna see that.
Oi, corrupting the youth!
-[laughter]
-You don't wanna see that.
-[moody music continues]
-[hawkers shouting indistinctly]
There you go, your receipt.
-Thank you very much.
-You're welcome.
Thank you.
[music ends]
[Laura] Gross.
They've been snaking for a fucking age.
[Olly] What? What the fuck is "snaking"?
"Snaking." Why, what do you call it?
That? That's tonguing.
[Sophie] No, that's nipping.
-[laughs] Nipping.
-Oi!
[indie pop song playing on speakers]
[whispers] What we'll do, yeah,
is go over there and push them in.
You get him, I'll get her. Yeah?
Push them in.
You get him, I'll get her over there.
-Yeah.
-Let's go.
Come on.
You get him, I'll get her.
Push him. Yeah?
[Jane screams]
Wait, I want a go.
[Laura chuckles] Oh, my God.
[indistinct conversation, laughter]
[Sophie] Okey-dokey.
-This is our room.
-[Calum] Mmm-hmm.
[Sophie chuckles]
And this is dad's teeny-weeny-weeny bed.
This is my giant bed.
Um… [chuckles]
Wait, wait, wait. How do I zoom?
[Calum] Let's see. Pass it here.
Mmm…
It's this button here, see?
-Oh, my God, I'm on TV. How do I look?
-[both chuckle]
[Sophie] Okey-dokey, give that back.
[Calum grunts]
[Sophie] Oh. Oh, oh, oh.
-[sighs] What's that?
-[Calum chuckles]
-[Sophie] Oh, my God, what even is that?
-These are my moves.
[Sophie chuckles]
Dad, that's so embarrassing.
[Calum] That's not embarrassing.
[Sophie] Wait.
-What?
-I was gonna interview you.
Oh, you were, were you?
What were you gonna interview me about?
[Sophie] I don't know.
-Well…
-Well, I just turned 11,
and you are 130,
turning 131 in 2 days.
So…
When you were 11,
what did you think you would be doing now?
Hello?
What did you think you would be doing now?
Come on, Soph. Turn that off now, okay?
[Sophie] Okay, it's off.
Well, I can see a red light.
[Sophie] That…
That's just because it's still on.
[Calum] Mmm-mmm.
Look, it's not even on you anymore.
It's on me.
[Calum sighs]
[Sophie] Dad!
[Sophie sighs, groans]
Okay, it's not recording.
I'll just record it
in my little… mind camera.
-[Calum chuckles]
-[imitates camera lens whirring]
[Sophie] Right. Ready?
What did you do for your 11th birthday?
[Calum] When I was 11,
nobody remembered it was my birthday.
And when I told my mum,
she was so angry,
she grabbed me by the ear,
and made my dad drive me to the toy shop,
and made me pick something to buy.
[Sophie] That's a bit, um, deep.
[Calum] It was okay.
-[Sophie] What did you pick?
-[chuckles softly]
I chose a toy phone.
It was red.
-[Sophie] Good choice.
-Thank you.
-["Tender" playing]
-[indistinct chatter]
[Calum] Want a sip?
-[chuckles]
-Nice?
-Yeah, it tasted amazing.
-[both laughing]
♪ Tender is the night ♪
♪ Lying by your side ♪
♪ Tender is the touch
Of someone that you love too much ♪
♪ Tender is the day
The demons go away… ♪
[Sophie] Think you'll ever move back
to Scotland?
[Calum] No.
[Sophie] Why?
[Calum] There's not enough sun.
-[Sophie] Very funny.
-[chuckles]
[Calum] Hmm.
It's all in the past for me, that's all.
And there's this feeling,
once you leave where you're from,
like, where you grew up, that, um,
you don't… totally belong there again.
Not really.
But Edinburgh was never…
I never felt like
I really did belong there.
I do. It's home.
That's good.
I'm glad you feel that way.
But you never know
where you'll end up, though, eh?
You can live wherever you want to live.
And… be whoever you want to be.
You have time.
♪ Tender is my heart ♪
♪ I'm screwing up my life ♪
♪ Lord, I need to find
Someone who can heal my mind ♪
♪ Come on, come on, come on
Get through it ♪
♪ Come on, come on, come on ♪
Okay.
♪ Love's the greatest thing ♪
♪ Come on, come on, come on
Get through it ♪
[distorted]
♪ Come on, come on, come on ♪
♪ Love's the greatest thing that we have ♪
♪ I'm waiting for that feeling ♪
♪ Waiting for that feeling ♪
♪ Waiting for that feeling to come ♪
-♪ Oh, my baby ♪
-♪ Oh, why? ♪
-♪ Heal me ♪
-♪ Oh, my ♪
-♪ Oh, my baby ♪
-♪ Baby ♪
-♪ Oh, why? ♪
-♪ Heal me ♪
-♪ Oh, my ♪
-♪ Oh, my baby ♪
-♪ Oh, why? ♪
-♪ Heal me ♪
-♪ Oh, my ♪
-♪ Oh, my baby ♪
-[motorcycle revving]
-[indistinct chatter]
[cutlery clatters]
[pop song playing indistinctly
over earphones]
[rock song playing indistinctly
[song stops]
Right, top-up time.
No, no, I'll do it.
How's that working?
Let me help, come on.
No, Soph. Scooch back.
Lift your hair a sec.
There you go.
Let's do something, eh?
Get this day going.
Like what?
Water polo?
No, I'm not a good enough swimmer
for that.
[Calum] You're a great swimmer, Soph.
You know it.
Go on.
It's our last few days,
and it'll be fun, okay?
Up.
Up, up, up, up!
[grunts] We're going swimming.
[players shouting indistinctly]
-[man 1] Time's up.
-[man 2] Quick, quick, quick!
No, no, no. Yes, yes, yes.
Here, here!
Up!
[indistinct shouting]
[Calum] The cross.
Soph, Soph, Soph. Soph! Go!
[indistinct shouting continues]
[man]
♪ Whoa, my love ♪
♪ My darling ♪
♪ I've hungered for your touch ♪
♪ A long, lonely time ♪
♪ And time… ♪
Could I get another one of those, please?
Thank you.
♪ So slowly ♪
♪ And time… ♪
What are you wearing your bikini for?
I don't know.
♪ Are you still mine? ♪
♪ I need your love… ♪
Are you excited for tomorrow?
[chuckles softly]
Yeah.
♪ Godspeed your love to me ♪
-[song ends]
-[people cheer, applaud]
Good, weren't they?
[man on mic] Ladies.
Are we all having fun, guys?
-[Calum] Whoo!
-[Sophie] Yeah.
-[Calum] Soph's having fun.
-Yes, I am.
Can we have a big round of applause
for Calum and Sophie?
-[people cheering, applauding]
-[Calum] Oh, you didn't sign us up?
Of course I did. We've done it
every holiday since I was, like, five.
Maybe you're a little old
for it now, Soph.
What are you talking about, Dad?
Those girls were, like, 50.
Okay, let it go.
He'll move on in a second.
-I'm not up for it, okay?
-Come on, it's a laugh.
-No.
-They just wanna hear us.
We're on holiday,
supposed to be having fun.
-You said so.
-I'm not doing it, okay?
[instrumental "Losing My Religion"
playing on speakers]
[people clapping rhythmically]
[man] Here we go.
[off-key]
♪ Oh, life is bigger ♪
♪ It's bigger than you
And you are not me ♪
♪ The lengths that I will go to ♪
♪ The distance in your eyes ♪
♪ Oh, no, I've said too much ♪
♪ I set it up ♪
♪ That's me in the corner ♪
♪ That's me in the spotlight ♪
♪ Losing my religion ♪
♪ Trying to keep up with you ♪
♪ And I don't know if I can do it ♪
♪ Oh, no, I've said too much ♪
♪ I haven't said enough ♪
♪ I thought that I heard you laughing ♪
♪ I thought that I heard you sing ♪
♪ I think I thought I saw you try ♪
♪ That was just a dream ♪
♪ Try, cry, fly, try ♪
♪ Just a dream, just a dream ♪
[music continues]
-[song ends]
-[light applause]
Big applause for Sophie.
Down you come, please.
There you are, Lucy. Come on down here.
Take it away.
[instrumental "The Tide Is High"
playing on speakers]
You know, we could get you singing lessons
if you wanted to learn to sing.
Trying to tell me I can't sing?
No, I'm just saying
anyone can learn if they put in the work.
Stop doing that.
Doing what?
Offering to pay for something
when I know you don't have the money.
[woman]
♪ The tide is high but I'm holding on ♪
-♪ I'm gonna be your number one ♪
-[chuckles]
♪ I'm not the kind of girl
Who gives up just like that… ♪
Okay. Come on.
Let's call it an early night.
Fresh for tomorrow, okay?
No, I'm staying down here for a bit.
♪ It's not the things you do
That tease and hurt me bad ♪
[Calum] See you upstairs, then?
Sophie?
Okay, not too long.
♪ I'm not the kind of girl
Who gives up just like that… ♪
[on speakers]
♪ I get knocked down, but I get up again ♪
-[indistinct chatter]
-♪ Never gonna keep me down ♪
♪ I get knocked down, but I get up again ♪
♪ You're never gonna keep me down ♪
♪ Pissin' the night away ♪
Just a little bit.
You want help
finding your dad or anything?
[speaking indistinctly]
♪ Oh, Danny Boy, Danny Boy ♪
♪ Danny Boy ♪
♪ I get knocked down, but I get up again ♪
♪ You're never gonna keep me down ♪
[muffled]
♪ I get knocked down, but I get up again ♪
♪ You're never gonna keep me down ♪
♪ Pissin' the night away ♪
♪ Pissin' the night… ♪
[indistinct chatter]
[on speakers] ♪ Boy, I'm in a daze ♪
♪ I feel isolated ♪
♪ Don't wanna communicate ♪
Can I get some water, please?
♪ I will scour, I will roam ♪
♪ To find peace of mind
The happy mind… ♪
You okay?
[Sophie] Hanging out.
Here.
[boy] The crisps are all wet now.
[boys laughing]
[Olly] Get them in you, baby.
Boys are disgusting.
Got it.
I'm going tomorrow anyway, so…
You are staying
for a couple more days, right?
Yeah.
Now you can get whatever you want.
-Thanks.
-It's okay.
See ya.
[bartender] What do you want?
Can I get a Fanta lemon, please?
And I have this.
♪ Never ever have I had to find ♪
♪ I've had to dig away
To find my own peace of mind ♪
♪ I've never ever… ♪
[Sophie on video] Ladies and gentlemen,
the marvelous, wonderful, amazing,
one-armed Calum Aaron Patterson.
Getting ready to see
the evening's entertainment.
And…
We'll see…
[squealing] Torremolinos!
-[Calum] You okay, Soph?
-[video stops]
[video camera turning off]
[loud music playing outdoors]
[door opens and closes]
[muffled grunt]
-[Michael grunts]
-Fuck! What you do that for?
[Michael] I'm sorry.
-I'm sorry. It was supposed to be a joke.
-Idiot.
Where you going?
Supposed to be going home, but I got lost
'cause everything looks the same at night.
Well, why don't you come hang out with us?
-[Sophie] What are you doing?
-[boy shouts] Michael! Come on!
[dogs barking]
[indistinct chatter]
-[water lapping softly]
-[somber music playing]
Didn't know
there was another pool back here.
Yeah, it's quiet in the day.
And I'm not a great swimmer,
so it suits me.
Same. I still can't dive.
So, uh, I quite like you.
Do you like me?
Yes.
[kissing]
[loud knocking on pane]
[somber music continues]
[waves crashing]
[music fades]
Miss.
-[receptionist] Good night.
-Good night.
[door sliding shut]
[lock clicking]
[dog barking in distance]
-[Calum breathing heavily]
-[water gurgling]
[distorted shouting]
[horn blaring]
-[siren wailing distortedly]
-[heavy breathing continues]
[siren wailing in distance]
[woman] Hey.
Are you okay?
[adult Sophie] Yeah.
Happy birthday, Sophie.
[baby crying]
[softly] I'll get him.
[somber music playing]
[telephone ringing]
-[Calum] Hello?
-[man on phone] Your wake up call, sir.
-[Calum] Okay. Thanks.
-Day trip leaves in 20 minutes.
[Calum] Thank you.
[hangs up phone]
[Calum whispers] Sophie. Sophie.
Sophie, come on, let's get up.
It's time to go.
[somber music continues]
Careful with those.
A man died not paying attention
to how to put those on properly.
The lug went right up his nose
and punctured his brain.
-That's not true.
-It is.
Happy birthday, Dad.
Thanks, darling.
[Calum] Okay.
[laughing] You're copying me?
[Sophie laughs]
All right, smartarse.
Attention!
[Sophie] Oh, what's this we're doing?
[Calum] Yeah, I tricked you.
[Calum chuckles]
[Calum exhaling deeply]
-[Sophie] I'm still copying, you know?
-I know.
[Sophie] Exactly.
[Calum] And now copy this.
[Calum breathing deeply]
Breathe.
-[Sophie chuckles]
-Right, you watching?
-Yeah.
-Feet together. Up.
[Calum breathing deeply]
-Up…
-[Sophie grunts] One.
-…and down.
-Two.
-[Sophie] Up…
-Up.
-[Sophie] …and…
-Down.
Now close your eyes and do it.
And focus on your breathing.
[breathing deeply]
[indistinct chatter]
-[Sophie] What's that smell?
-It's where we go after this.
If it's good enough for Cleopatra…
It's kind of amazing
how Cleopatra was, like, here.
Like, right here.
Yeah.
Before she was…
-By a snake.
-[chuckles]
Well, I mean, it was kind of suicide.
It wasn't for sure there was a snake.
Nobody ever found a snake, so…
-It might've just been a needle.
-How do you know that?
We learnt about Egypt last term.
What happened to your shoulder?
I don't really know.
I'm sorry I passed out on your bed.
It's fine.
I didn't have a key, though.
How'd you get in?
Reception.
[clears throat, hesitates]
I'm so sorry, Soph. Yesterday was…
It's fine. It's no big deal.
No, it is a big deal.
I'm sorry, okay?
-Thank you.
-[chuckles]
-You've got none on your arms.
-Uh… I did.
No, you don't.
Now you do.
Let's see your back.
-My back?
-Yup.
Right, I need to get a big clump
for this big back.
[Calum chuckles]
-[Calum] Oh!
-[both laughing]
[Calum] Careful with my shoulder.
-It's okay.
-[Sophie chuckles] Sorry.
[Calum] Did you have fun last night?
[Sophie] Yeah.
This boy, Michael…
I met him on the motorbike game.
Yeah.
We… We kissed last night.
He kissed me, and then we kissed.
[Calum] He's your age, though?
[Sophie] Yeah.
[Calum] Well, that's okay, right?
Peck on the cheek?
[Sophie] Well…
-[chuckles shyly] Yeah, not exactly.
-[chuckles] Okay.
[Calum] I want you to know
that you can talk to me about anything.
As you get older, you know.
Whatever parties you go to…
boys you meet,
drugs you take.
-[Sophie] Dad!
-No, I'm serious, Soph.
I've done it all. You can, too.
I just want you to promise me
you'll talk to me about it, okay?
[Sophie] Okay.
But I'm never gonna do any of that anyway.
[Calum] That's okay, too.
But if you do, remember, okay?
[insects trilling]
[Sophie] On the count of three
we're going to sing.
On the count of three we're gonna sing.
It's my dad's birthday.
It's my dad's birthday,
so we're gonna sing.
It's my dad's birthday. It's for my dad.
Can you sing for my dad's birthday?
Three, two, one!
[all]
♪ For he's a jolly good fellow ♪
♪ And so say all of us ♪
Hip, hip, hooray!
[sobbing]
[sobbing continues]
[somber music playing]
[somber music continues]
[music fades]
-[indistinct conversations, laughter]
-[Turkish song playing on speakers]
-Should've gotten your own.
-No. I only wanted a taste.
Dad, that was, like,
half of it on your spoon there.
[chuckles]
[man] Photo?
-Uh, how much?
-50,000 lira.
Sure.
[Calum] Ready?
[camera shutter clicks]
-[Calum] Teşekkür ederim.
-[man] Rica ederim.
[chuckles softly]
Did you have a good holiday, then?
The best.
Wish we could've stayed for longer.
Mmm-hmm.
Me, too.
What?
[Sophie] I mean, why can't we?
[Calum] What do you mean?
[Sophie] Why can't we just… stay here?
-[Calum] Um…
-[chuckles]
[Sophie] Can't live in hotels
for the rest of our lives.
[Calum] Yeah.
-[Sophie] You can have the wafer.
-Oh, thank you very much.
[both laugh]
[Calum] Eat it in one. Yes.
[both laughing]
[Calum] Too slow!
["Under Pressure" playing on speakers]
Last night. Time for a dance.
-I don't dance.
-Sophie.
[Sophie] I never, ever dance.
Okay, I'm dancing with or without you.
I told you, I love to dance.
[Sophie] Dad, stop.
You're so embarrassing.
This is embarrassing?
♪ Pray tomorrow gets me higher ♪
♪ Pressure on people
People on streets ♪
[music continues]
♪ Okay ♪
♪ Chipping around
Kick my brains… ♪
[Calum] What? Come on!
-Ready? Let's dance.
-Stop.
Stop!
Hand.
[Calum chuckles]
♪ People on streets ♪
♪ It's the terror of knowing
What this world is about ♪
♪ Watching some good friends screaming
"Let me out!" ♪
♪ Pray tomorrow gets me higher, high ♪
♪ Pressure on people
People on streets ♪
♪ Turned away from it all
Like a blind man ♪
♪ Sat on a fence, but it don't work ♪
♪ Keep coming up with love
But it's so slashed and torn ♪
♪ Why? ♪
♪ Why? Why? ♪
♪ Love, love, love, love, love ♪
♪ Can't we give ourselves
One more chance? ♪
♪ Why can't we give love
That one more chance? ♪
Give love, give love, give love ♪
♪ Give love, give love
Give love, give love, give love? ♪
♪ 'Cause love's
Such an old-fashioned word ♪
♪ And love dares you to care for ♪
♪ The people on the edge of the night ♪
♪ And love dares you
To change our way of ♪
♪ Caring about ourselves ♪
♪ This is our last dance ♪
♪ This is ourselves ♪
[video camera whirring]
-[Sophie] Bye-bye.
-[Calum] I love you.
-[Sophie] Okay, bye-bye.
-Safe travels.
[Calum] Give my love to your mum.
-I don't need a babysitter, you know.
-[chuckles]
[indistinct announcement over PA system]
[Calum chuckles]
-[Calum] I love you.
-Love you.
[Calum] Bye.
[video camera whirs]
[siren wailing in distance]
[baby cooing]
-[somber music playing]
-[cooing continues]
[video camera turns off]
-[baby continues cooing]
-[somber music continues]
[bag zipping up]
[cooing continues]
[somber music continues]