Downloaded from
YTS.MX
[boat engine running]
Official YIFY movies site:
YTS.MX
[birds chirping]
[dramatic music]
[music fades]
[radio blares rock music]
[man humming]
(Russ)
Hurry up.
This is poker not fucking chess.
[other men laughing]
Call.
(Larry)
Ohhhh.
Aha! Boom, mother fuckers!
(Russ)
Hey Phil!
Get another bottle
while you're back there.
Ah, your money's mine.
Larry, you talk too much.
(Larry)
Well, you know,
you gotta fill the time.
[chatter]
(Larry)
Beans in the middle, gentlemen.
Beans in the middle.
You got a tiny bladder
and a tiny dick, Phil?
(Phil)
Is that what your wife
or your sister told me?
(Ricky)
Both of 'em; they report back.
(Larry)
You in the game?
Oh, I'm in the game, Larry.
(Ricky)
Well, that's too much for me.
[chatter]
I'll raise.
(Larry)
Ohhhh.
You got enough on you
to cover that?
I'll pay you later if I have to.
Hold on, me and the boys
don't fuck around
when it comes to money.
I got the money, all right!
Yeah, well, I hope you do have it covered.
[others laughing]
[chatter]
[zipper unzips]
[urine hitting the wall]
[siren wails]
[pants zip]
(Officer)
Hey! Drop the weapon!
[laughing]
You want a ride home?
Ohhh, come on!
You almost made me zip it up.
Asshole.
I got you so good;
the look on your face was—
Oh my God.
The worst.
Did you get picked up
for public urination too, Mee-maw.
Come on, ass.
She doesn't seem to recognize
her favorite son-in-law.
Yeah, it's just one of those nights.
Sorry again about you seeing me.
I should probably join the
local fire department or something.
What's going on?
(Emily)
I just gave him a ride from uptown.
Oh.
Well, do you want to stay
and have a drink?
I can't I have Mom in the car.
She got out again.
- Is she okay?- I fired Adam.
Yes. He fell asleep.
She's fine.
- What an asshole.
- She had this on her.
I think it's yours.
- Ohhh!
Yeah, thank you.
[muffled voices continue talking]
[door creaks shut]
How much was it this time?
Just making sure I have enough
for tomorrow's deliveries.
Okay.
Hey.
What's the matter?
Stop it.
You know, you promised me.
What are you talking about?
When are you going to stop
acting like a fucking child?
Get the fuck off me.
Come on! Nothing happened, okay?
I know what I'm doing
with my money.
Oh, with your money.
Yes.
[mumbling]
Fuckin' pussy.
[door shuts]
(Anne)
Hey, Dad.
Hey, what are you doing up?
Can you just sign this
for school real quick?
Yeah.
How was everything
at the diner tonight?
It was good.
You gonna be in tomorrow?
Mhm.
That's a good girl.
Okay?
Thank you!
[exhales deeply]
[dog barking]
[door slides open]
[birds chirping]
[groans]
[yawns]
[gas burners click]
[door opens]
Good morning to you too,
beautiful.
[slap]
[customers chatter]
All right, here you go fellas.
(Larry)
Hey.
(Customer)
Wow, that looks great.
(Larry)
Hey Robert,
looks like you survived
a rough night last night.
Yeah, you could say that.
All right guys, enjoy.
Thanks, buddy.
Is that for Nancy?
No.
Who's it for then?
It's for you.
Can I come over tonight?
We'll see.
[Robert growls]
You got the money?
Yeah, I'll bring it around tonight.
We can play a couple of hands.
I need it now.
I don't have it now.
I got a business to run.
Well, that's your problem.
I'm not gonna run off
to Mexico or any—
Look here, boy.
I'll be back at 3.
You either got the money,
or I'll take this piece of junk
and strip it for parts.
Don't fuck with me.
Okay.
[Phil blows a kiss]
Loretta?
[phone ringing]
Hey! Have you seen Loretta?
Well, do you have any idea
where she might be?
Okay, well, uh,
could you come over here?
All right, thanks.
What's going on?
I can't find my money.
What money?
Just money that I saved.
You think someone broke in?
No.
[sighs]
Loretta and I got into it last night,
and I keep hoping she hid it
somewhere to fuck with me.
Look, this is between you two.
I gotta go.
Come on.
Did she say anything to you?
You owe someone again,
don't you?
You fucking serious?
Are you gonna help me or not?
It's a small town, Robert;
you'll figure it out.
[door closes]
(Robert)
Sam.
Sam!
What do you want, Robert?
I'm lookin' for Loretta.
So?
Come on, man.
What do you want from me?
Cut the bullshit!
I gotta find her!
What the fuck?
What's going on here?
You trying to embarrass me
in front of the guys?
Where is she?
Don't bring your family problems
into my gym!
Dude, you brought my
family problems into this gym!
Don't blame me for your fuck-ups.
Man, you have no idea
what's going on.
And if I find out you had anything
to do with this,
I'm gonna burn this place
to the fucking ground.
Oh please.
Go ahead, pussy.
What the fuck?
You let them take the truck?
What are you talking about? Who?
What the fuck, Melissa?
I'm sorry I wasn't guarding the truck
while you left me here
alone during lunch!
Where are you going now?
I got to get it back!
Robert, I need to talk to you.
Yeah, not now.
I got stuff going on.
It's about Loretta.
Oh, yeah, where the fuck is she?
Umm,
there was a situation
at the lake.
Okay.
She rented a boat.
[dramatic music]
And it was empty.
What are you talking about?
Umm,
What?
There was a suicide note.
Hey, what's up?
It's Loretta.
Robert, what's going on?
Robert?
[music fades]
Does this still look pink
to you?
Elvis.
Yeah, I guess.
[groans]
What, come on it's not like
they're not going to take you
because of your hair color.
Hey, hey, hey no.
What, are you nuts?
Anne.
Can I use some paint thinner
or something instead—
No! That shit'll ruin your head.
Well, what am I supposed to do?
I look like an idiot.
[sighs]
Does this actually work?
[chuckling]
It's worth a shot.
[laughing]
Bon appétit.
[bottle squirts]
[laughing]
Oh my God.
O-oh.
Here, let me try.
Okay. I'll just—
[Elvis groans]
This is disgusting!
I don't think I've ever had ketchup
in my hand before.
[Anne shrieks]
[laughing]
[voices on TV talking]
Hey, do you mind if I
borrow this?
Yup, sure.
[unzips backpack]
Hey, Porcupine.
When do you think
you'll ship out?
[teasing]
Are you gonna miss me?
No.
No, no.
Nope.
You're gonna miss me.
Are you positive?
Oh, oh God, that smells
like vinegar.
[laughing]
Hey, when you get back,
we have to catch up, okay?
[laughing]
Okay.
Don't get that on me, ugh.
[instrumental folk music]
[food sizzling]
What's going on?
I made dinner.
Don't look so surprised.
What did you do to your hair?
It looks nice.
Where'd you get it done?
Just at a friend's.
You're not hanging out with that
Elvis "Pervesly" again, are you?
No, I was at Grace's house,
[unzips backpack]
and I got dye on my shirt.
So I'm using her dad's.
Okay, yeah, it's fine.
Coach'll be impressed;
you'll look good for your
meeting tomorrow.
Can you sign this?
What is it?
I don't know; it's just
something for graduation.
[pen scribbles]
Where you goin'?
I just have a lot of work to do, so—
Come on, sit down.
No thanks.
(Loretta)
You know, you promised me.
(Robert)
What are you talking about?
- When are you gonna stop acting
like a fucking child?
Get the fuck off me.
- Come on, nothing happened, okay?
I know what I'm doing with my money.
- Oh, with your money?
- Yes.
[thud]
Hey, Dad.
Hey, what are you doing up?
Can you just sign this
for school real quick?
Yeah.
[pen scribbles]
[muffled song in headphones]
[phone buzzes]
[phone buzzes again]
Hey, where are you going?
I gotta take Grandma
to the doctor's.
Wait, I'm driving the car to school
this morning so I can
leave for my meeting after.
Oh, and what meeting is that?
What do you mean?
I'm meeting my coach at O.U.
Don't lie to me, Annie.
I know about the Navy.
Honestly, what's wrong with you?
You're gonna turn down
a full scholarship?
Look, you really don't understand.
What is it that I don't understand?
You're wasting a huge opportunity!
Okay, I don't need your help, okay?
Just stay out of my life!
[door shuts]
[zips backpack]
[printer chimes]
[door slams]
Woah, what the fuck?
My mom found out,
and she took the car.
Oh.
So what are you gonna do?
Well, ummm,
can you maybe drive me up there?
No, I gotta finish the job
at the gym.
Wha-what?
If I drive there,
it'll take up my whole day.
Well, tell Sam you'll
do it tomorrow.
He'll get someone else
if I don't do it today.
Okay, let me borrow your truck then.
Nope, I gotta use it for the job.
Look hey, I'll take you tomorrow.
Hmmm? How 'bout that?
No, I gotta go now
before my mom finds out
I lied about the scholarship.
[crunches cereal]
Hey, where you goin'?
[door slams]
Hey, wait.
I have an idea.
Get in.
[engine starts]
[impact drill revving]
Oh, look who it is.
How you been, man?
Where the hell you been?
We've been waiting
for...like 10 hours.
- Russ is out,
so I'm handling everything.
What do you need?
She just needs a car
for just like a day or two.
(Ricky)
These have been here the longest.
Nobody's gonna care if one disappears
for a couple of days.
How much?
Three hundred a day.
Oh, come on you're shitting me, right?
It'd be one thing if you were driving,
but I don't think Robert's gonna be
too happy when he finds—
I can get the money.
Okay, then.
Uh, you can just drop me off here.
We have to hurry, okay?
Shit.
Let's go.
Did you get it?
Uh, maybe we can convince him
some other way,
like give him collateral
or something like that?
What? No, he's not the kind of guy
that makes deals or anything like that.
We have to do something, okay?
Look. I'll take you tomorrow.
I promise.
Okay?
You know what?
Pull over.
Pull over!
What are you do—
what are you doing?
Come on.
Hey.
Don't be such a child.
[engine revs]
(Melissa)
Oh, good. You're here to help.
Uh, where's my dad?
I need to talk to him.
I don't know.
He left me here alone
right before the lunch rush.
[customers chatting]
Well, do you know
when he's coming back?
[dishes clang in sink]
I have no idea.
Hey. Are you gonna help me or not?
[keys jingle]
[engine starts]
[police siren wails]
Shit!
[siren stops]
[engine shuts off]
Hey!
[Emily knocks]
What are you doing?
Uhh, I had to—
Come on. Out.
Where are you going?
This wouldn't have anything to
do with what your mother
just told me about you
wanting to enlist, would it?
No, no, no, no, no.
Hang—
You know what?
I'm just going to call your dad.
No, please, please.
Look, you don't understand. I—
I didn't get the track scholarship.
I couldn't tell Mom.
Look, I can't stay here forever.
Okay?
I'll get your mom on board.
Seriously?
[Anne laughs]
["On the Road Again, Again"
by Killbuck]
Company driver,
I'm a long-haul rider,
burning through fumes,
living under the wire
Listening to
"On the Road Again," again
[music continues]
Radio wilco,
can't move too slow,
Smokey and the Bear
in the rear-view window
Living the good life
in the hammer lane
(on the radio)
This old road has been my home
and will be—
[radio and engine shut off]
[sniffs]
(Recruiter)
What about your medical history?
Is there anything we need
to know about?
Diseases, surgeries?
[to Anne]
Go ahead and have a seat.
I'll be with you in a second.
What we're basically going to
do today—
[Recruiter's conversation continues]
All right, so what can I do for you?
Uh, I'm here to enlist.
[phone buzzes]
Great. Do you have your
[buzzing continues]
social security card and birth certificate?
[buzzing stops]
Okay, fill this out for me,
and I'm going to finish up
with these folks,
and I'll be right with you, okay?
Okay, thanks.
[Recruiter talking with the other family]
[phone buzzes]
[buzzing continues]
Hello?
Yeah, I just got here, what?
[dramatic music]
What?
Yeah, no—
why would she do that?
All right. Miss Foreman.
I have to go.
Let's see.
Anne K. Foreman.
Five-foot-three,
from Glouster, Ohio?
[sniffling]
Mmhmm.
That's down in Athens County, right?
All right.
And you're only 17?
Yes, sir.
[sniffling]
Did your parents bring you today?
Um, no, I have their consent form.
[papers rustling]
Is everything all right, Miss Foreman?
Miss Foreman.
[sniffling]
[crying]
[music fades]
[door swings open]
[keys jingling]
Come here.
[voice on TV talking]
(Melissa)
Here you go.
Uh, no, thank you.
I'm okay, actually, today.
Oh, okay.
Can you pack up mom's lunch for me though?
Sure.
The kid's mom is gonna press charges.
I mean, really, Emily,
what were you thinkin'?
He fell on his face when
he was running away from me,
I told you.
That is such bullshit.
You're gonna be lucky if
you don't get probation.
Are you serious?
You just can't go beat
the shit out of some kid
because he's smoking pot
and calling you names.
He spit in my face.
I should be the one pressing charges
and apologized to.
That fucking kid—
- That's enough. That's enough.
Just do your job,
and I'll see what I can do.
But this is the last time
I'm backin' you up.
You have got to get your shit together.
[car beeps]
What did he say?
I might get probation.
That's bullshit.
Did you tell him
the kid called you a "dyke?"
Yeah.
Honestly, it's fine.
It really could be worse.
Let's go somewhere.
We can go up to that bar in Nelsonville.
I can't—I told you,
I have my mom.
Just tell Adam you'll be a little late.
Can we maybe do it tomorrow?
I could ask my sister to watch her.
Sure.
Can we not do that here?
I'll take you home.
No, thanks. I'll walk.
[car beeps]
[door thuds]
[engine roars]
[voice on TV talking]
[snoring]
Ow.
Hi.
Hey.
I was out just for just a second.
Where's my mom?
She's in her room watching TV.
I'll go bring her dinner.
All right.
Mom?
I'm not sure—
Hey, wait!
Hey, look, I'm really sorry.
- Mom?
Mom?
Get out.
I'm really, really sorry.
The fuck am I paying you for?
[brakes squeak]
[car beeps]
Mom?
Hey, are you okay?
Where are you going?
What is this?
Is this Loretta's?
[Margaret chuckles]
Let's take you home.
You wanna go home?
You gotta be kidding me.
[siren blares]
Hey! Drop the weapon!
[laughing]
Sorry, again, about you seeing me.
I should probably
join the local fire department
or somethin'.
(Loretta)
What's going on?
Uh, nothing.
I was just giving him a ride from uptown.
Do you wanna stay and have a drink?
I can't. I have mom in the car.
She got out again.
- Is she okay?- I fired Adam.
Yes, he fell asleep.
She's fine.
- What an asshole.
She had this one her.
I think it's yours.
Ohhh!
Yeah, thank you.
You think maybe you can
take care of her tomorrow,
after the hospital?
I already promised that
I would help out at the pound.
Well, I don't have any options.
You think you can help me out this once?
- You can't call in sick or something?
- No, I cannot call in sick,
I'm a cop.
Okay, okay, okay.
'Night.
Mom, are you almost ready?
Mom?
Did you take your underwear off?
Okay. Okay, hold it.
Come on up. Come on up.
Let me get it.
[Emily gasps]
Okay, sit, sit, sit.
Sorry. Sit.
[urine trickles]
[Margaret exhales]
- I'm sorry.
- It's okay.
It's okay.
[Margaret cries]
Mom, here, it's okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
[Margaret sobbing]
Shh.
It's okay.
Hang on.
(Margaret)
One,
two.
- There we go.
(Emily)
I don't understand,
she remembers me.
She remembers Loretta.
She remembers my dad sometimes.
(Doctor)
I know.
It's a really hard decision,
difficult position.
But you need to think about
what's best for her right now,
and keeping her safe.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Let me know what I can do.
I am not putting her in a home.
Em, we gotta do what's best for her.
I'm taking care of her myself.
Did you hear what the doctor said?
She needs her daughters,
not some stranger
that doesn't give a shit.
That's not what's happening here.
Why do you care anyway?
She's living with me.
She's staying with you
because you insisted on it.
It doesn't mean that I don't care.
You care now because you've
taken us to the doctor once?
And paying a kid to
fall asleep on the job,
that's doing it?
- At least I give a shit.
What do you do besides fuck around?
(Emily)
Mom, let's go.
[car door slams]
[Margaret groans]
[door thuds]
[spatula scraping]
Hey, sleeping beauty.
Hungry?
Here, come here.
Let's sit you up.
Good scrambled eggs.
Mmm.
- Good?
- Mm.
[pictures rustling]
No.
[orchestral TV score]
Dad's favorite show.
[Margaret laughs]
[both laughing]
Do you remember dad?
Dad used to work all day in the mines.
[laughs]
- No, not your dad.
- No?
My dad.
Your husband.
[orchestral music continues]
[voice on TV talking]
[knocking]
Hey.
[utensils clank]
I just wanted to see Mom.
[envelope crinkles]
What is this?
It's...it's for Mom.
It's enough money to get her
started in a nursing home.
[Emily sighs]
Emily.
Do you even care?
Of course I care, I—
You know she needs constant care,
Em, we—
[bills crash]
I don't need your fucking money.
Okay.
[faucet runs]
[voices on TV talking]
Hey.
Do you think you could
come over for a few hours
and watch my mom?
[voices on TV continue]
[knocking]
Coming.
Hi. Thank you so much.
No problem.
These are her pills.
Her next dose is at noon.
She gets only one.
Okay.
She's just in her room sleeping.
Hey.
Thank you.
- Yeah, of course.
Let me know if you need anything
or if something happens.
Okay. Bye.
[phone buzzes]
[buzzing continues]
Hey.
[door creaks]
What's going on?
I can't find my money.
What money?
Just money that I saved.
You think someone broke in?
No.
[sighs]
Loretta and I got into it last night.
And I keep hoping she hid it
somewhere to fuck with me.
What the hell, Loretta?
You can't just take Robert's fucking money
and then disappear.
If you don't fucking
tell me what's going on,
I'm gonna just give the money back.
[police radio chatters]
[seat belt clicks]
[siren blaring]
(Emily)
Talk to your parents.
Go. Good luck.
[food truck door shuts]
[food truck engine revs]
Hey, it's Emily.
I was wondering if you could
pack up Mom's lunch for me.
Hello.
What the hell happened?
Why wouldn't you call me?
It's just a scratch.
[Emily groans]
Mom.
(Margaret)
I'm bad.
She's fine.
It isn't a deep cut.
It's fine.
I was in the bathroom,
and I heard a noise.
[dish shards clatter]
Look, I'm sorry.
I was away for less than a minute.
I guess she was trying to get
something from the kitchen.
So you're not gonna talk to me?
[door creaks]
Whoa, Mom!
Mom, mom, mom.
Hey, hey, hey.
Come here.
What?
Come here. Let's have a seat.
I know, I know, I know.
Yeah, it's fine.
All right, let's have a seat.
You got blood on your sweater.
(Margaret)
Uh-oh.
(Emily)
We'll just get you a new sweater, okay?
Stop avoiding me.
I'm just trying to help.
What?
(Margaret)
Who is that girl?
Emily?
- She's my friend, Mom.
Get out.
You are so pathetic.
[door slams]
(Police Dispatcher)
Hey, Emily,
we got a call from the
boathouse up at Burr Oak.
Potential theft.
Can you take a look?
Over.
Copy that. I'll be over in ten.
I'll be right back, okay?
Hello, officer.
Hey, Jimmy, what's going on?
Well, Tim rented a boat earlier today
to a young lady for an hour.
It's been four hours now,
and she hasn't come back.
I don't know where she is.
[boat motor roars]
[dramatic music]
[boat engine shuts off]
(Captain)
Maybe we'll find something.
Maybe not. Who knows?
Okay?
We don't know anything yet,
so don't assume too much.
I need to check the lake house
and see if anyone saw anything.
Brian's already taking care of that.
Why don't you take a few hours?
[train horn blaring]
[train wheels clanking]
Mom.
[sobbing]
[train rumbles]
All right.
Here, take it.
Take it.
Mom! Mom!
- No.
- Please take this pill.
Mom, we're taking a pill tonight.
Open up. Open up.
- No.
- Mom!
Just do it.
[Margaret spits]
[slap]
[Margaret whimpers]
Mom, are you okay?
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Come here.
Will you take this?
Please?
[dramatic music]
[truck roars]
(Diver)
There's nothing more we can do tonight.
We'll start again in the morning.
[music fades]
[breathing]
[lighter clicks]
[exhales]
My turn.
Here, guess this one.
Flower.
No!
[both laugh]
That was close though it was a cloud with rain.
- Nice.
- That was pretty good.
I told you, man. I'm getting better.
That was good.
You know, I never smoked
until I was 40 years old?
Not even one time.
- Really?- Yeah.
- You missed out.
- I know.
Now that I know what it tastes like.
But...the very first night that I ever smoked
was actually the last night that I ever fought.
We were in New York City, Madison Square Garden,
And I got my ass kicked, bad.
[Loretta laughs]
But, Joe Frazier was in the crowd,
and he felt so bad for me
that he sent his boys up
with a box of Cubans.
Like a fancy box, fancy lighter,
the whole works.
So the first time I ever smoked?
[mouth clicks]Box of Cubans.
You smoked a box of Cubans?
Dude, I smoked a whole box of Cubans.
[laughing]
Didn't you get sick?
I threw up everywhere.
[both laughing]
I didn't know, man, I didn't know
you weren't supposed to inhale.
I never even had a cigarette before,
nobody told me anything.
But hey, I was hooked.
I'm sorry, where'd you get that ugly thing?
Oh, see this?
Go for it quick, before it fades away.
[laughing]
Stop.
Oh no. No I'm lying.
I got it at a garage sale in Texas.
What were you doing in Tex—[knock at the door]
(girl's voice)
Dad?
- Hey! Sarah, what's up?
- We were gonna get dinner, remember?
Yeah, just hang on a sec.
I'll be right out.
All right. I'll be waiting down
in the car with mom.
[pants rustling]
[inaudible]
[whispering]
What am I supposed to do?
Look, I'm sorry.
[Sam kisses Loretta]
[whispering]
I'll make it up to you, all right?
Come on.
[door shuts]
[keypad beeping]
[stove lighter clicking]
[water trickling]
[car approaching]
[car door shuts]
(Emily)
She had this on her. I think it's yours.
Oh, yeah, thank you.
You think maybe you can take care
of her tomorrow?
After the hospital?
I already promised that
I would help out at the pound.
Well, I don't have any options.
Think you can help me out this once?
- I gave them my word.- I don't have anything right now,
- I know.- It's just volunteer work.
You can't just like call in or something?
- No I can't just call in, I'm a cop.
I have a real job.
- Okay, okay. Okay, okay, okay.
[door opening]
'Night.
[money rustling]
[Sam breathing heavily]
Hey!
Woo! What are you doing here?
[keys jingling]
I just wanted to give you these.
What's going on?
I can't do this anymore.
Why not?
[keys hit the table]
Come on, Sam.
I don't get this.
What did you expect me to do last night?
You know, I'm not stupid.
I mean, I know what this is.
I know what we are.
Look, this is how it ended up.
This is what we've got.
All right? We have us,
and we have our families.
You know, I don't?
I have you for two hours a week.
And what do you want me to do?
Leave my family?
Why don't you grow up?
This isn't high school.
[engine starting]
[water trickling]
[glove compartment opens]
What is this?
You know she needs
constant care, Em, we—
[bills crash]
I don't need your fucking money.
[voices on TV talking]
Do you remember this?
That fair they have by the lake every year?
Well, they used to.
I don't think they have it anymore.
But do you, do remember this?
[TV character shouts]
You and me and Emily and Daddy used to go.
[dramatic music]
God, I'm so lonely, Mama.
You know that? I'm so fucking lonley.
[music continues]
[keys jingling]
[boat engine whirring]
[music fades]
[engine shuts off]
[cigarette box falls to the deck]
[pills rattling]
[Loretta humming]
[Loretta gasps]
[coughing]
[vomiting]
[insects chirping]
[Loretta breathing heavily]
[cars whirring in the distance]
[vehicle approaching]
[truck honks]
[engine shuts off]
(Driver)
Are you okay, young lady?
Are you lost?
No...Can I get a ride?
Where're you going?
Wherever you're headed is fine.
Hop in.
[engine starting]
(Driver)
All right sweetie, this is far as I'm goin'.
[southern rock music]
(Bartender)
Need another?
Mmhmm.
Enjoy.
Thanks.
[pool balls clicking]
[belt unbuckling]
[moaning and panting]
I gotta pee.
Really?
[laughing]
[southern rock music fades out]
[car whirring]
[engine revving]
[whimsical music]