Jimmy? Come on.
You're serving today.
Christine?
Where's my pants?
On the bed. If they had teeth
they would've bit you.
Jimmy! Go to the store, buy me
the newspaper and cigarettes.
Can't. Serving mass.
I'm an altar boy.
Hey, Kevin!
Hey, Jimmy!
There you are.
Overslept.
Well, you made it. I'll do the
cruets if you light the charcoal.
You think I'm fat?
You're all right. What?
Clothes don't fit?
No, they fit.
You're gonna be going to
the bakery after mass.
I am?
Why don't you go?
I'm gonna be making breakfast.
I can make breakfast.
When have you ever?
Funny man.
Good morning, Connie.
Good morning.
♪ Holy God,
we praise thy name
Good morning, Father.
♪ Lord of all,
we bow before thee
♪ All on Earth
thy scepter claim
♪ All in heaven above
adore thee
♪ Infinite thy vast domain
♪ Everlasting is thy reign
Be seated.
What do you do when
you're not sure?
That's the topic of
my sermon today.
Last year when President
Kennedy was assassinated,
who among us did not experience
the most profound disorientation?
Despair?
Which way?
What now?
What do I say to my kids?
What do I tell myself?
It was a time of people
sitting together,
bound together by a common
feeling of hopelessness.
But think of that.
Your bond with your fellow
being was your despair.
It was a public experience.
It was awful,
but we were in it together.
How much worse is it then for
the lone man, the lone woman,
stricken by a private calamity?
"No one knows I'm sick." "No one knows
I've lost my last real friend."
"No one knows I've
done something wrong."
Imagine the isolation.
Now you see the world
as through a window.
On one side of the glass,
happy untroubled people,
and on the other side, you.
God bless you, Sister.
Thank you.
I wanna tell you a story.
A cargo ship sank one night.
It caught fire and went down,
and only this one
sailor survived.
He found a lifeboat,
rigged a sail,
and being of a
nautical discipline
turned his eyes to the
heavens and read the stars.
He set a course for his home,
and, exhausted, fell asleep.
Just keeps going on.
Clouds rolled in,
and for the next 20 nights, he
could no longer see the stars.
He thought he was on course, but
there was no way to be certain.
And as the days rolled on,
and the sailor wasted away,
he began to have doubts.
He just keeps on going.
Had he set his course right?
Was he still going
on towards his home?
Or was he horribly lost and
doomed to a terrible death?
No way to know.
The message of the
constellations,
had he imagined it because of
his desperate circumstance?
Or had he seen truth once...
Straighten up!
and now had to hold on to it
without further reassurance?
There are those of
you in church today
who know exactly the crisis
of faith I describe,
and I wanna say to you,
doubt can be a bond as powerful
and sustaining as certainty.
When you are lost,
you are not alone.
In the name of the Father, the
Son and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Please rise.
♪ Praise God,
from whom all blessings flow
♪ Praise him
all creatures here... ♪
Hey, Father.
Hey, champ.
That was some sermon.
Did it mean something to you?
I wanna do that.
I wanna be a priest.
You'd be a good one,
I'm sure. Here.
Take a look.
See?
She's dancing.
Kind of neat?
Yeah.
Here. You try.
That's for you.
Take it.
Thank you, Father.
Welcome.
Like Noah's Ark,
girls. Two by two.
- Maryanne said it.
- Let's do it together.
- Okay.
- Yeah. It's true.
And did I tell you that Jessica's
having a sleepover on Saturday?
Morning,
Sister James.
Good morning, Father Flynn.
Beautiful day.
Not too bad.
How're the criminals doing today?
Not bad, Father.
Good, Father.
Morning, champ.
Morning, Father Flynn.
You wash those hands
today, Mr. London?
I washed them, Father.
I don't know. They're a
different color than your neck.
Morning.
Morning, Father Flynn.
Sister, are we having
the test today?
Get in line.
Tomorrow, William.
Is it long division?
Among other things.
Sister.
Good morning, Sister.
How much of it
will be long division?
Boy!
William London.
Come up here.
Come smartly, now.
Don't make me wait.
What did he do?
He touched
Sister James.
The dragon is hungry.
You don't
touch a nun.
Take out your history books,
please. Turn to page 683.
Yes, Ralph.
I forgot my history book.
You can look on with Raymond.
Mr. London?
Do you have your history book?
No, Sister.
Share with
Mr. Malloy, please.
Do I have to?
His breath stinks!
I'm sure Mr. Malloy's
breath is just fine.
Be seated.
Franklin Delano Roosevelt was the
32nd president of the United States.
That barrette out of
your hair, Miss Horan.
Yes, Sister.
Morning, Sister James.
Continue.
Franklin D. Roosevelt,
together with
Abraham Lincoln and
John Fitzgerald Kennedy,
was perhaps our greatest president.
When he assumed office,
13 million people in this
country were unemployed.
They'd lost hope,
and President Roosevelt
said to these people,
"The only thing we have
to fear is fear itself."
What did he mean
by that? James?
I think he was trying to say
there's nothing really wrong.
You know?
So don't get so emotional.
Maybe.
Maybe he was saying that
the world is good
and we need only work together
to overcome our problems.
What's this,
Mr. Conroy?
I don't know, Sister.
You don't know you have a
wire coming out of your ear?
No.
Huh?
No, Sister.
I didn't.
You come with me, boy.
Go.
Who knows
what the New Deal was?
♪ The first noel
♪ The angels did say
♪ Was to certain poor shepherds
in fields as they lay
I love this song.
♪ In fields where they lay
keeping their sheep
♪ On a cold winter's night
that was so deep ♪
This past Sunday, what do you think
that sermon was about? Sister James?
Huh?
What was Father Flynn's
sermon about?
Well, doubt.
He was talking about doubt.
Why?
Excuse me, Sister?
Well, sermons come from
somewhere, don't they?
Is Father Flynn in doubt?
Is he concerned that
someone else is in doubt?
I suppose you'd
have to ask him.
No, that would not
be appropriate.
He is my superior,
and if he were troubled he should
confess it to a fellow priest
or to the monsignor.
We do not share intimate
information with priests.
No.
That's true.
What are we saying?
I want you all to be alert.
I am concerned, perhaps needlessly,
about matters in St. Nicholas School.
Academically?
I was not inviting a guessing
game, Sister Raymond.
Missy! Get away from her,
and sit down.
May I join you,
Sister Aloysius?
Yes.
Chicken chow mein.
Sister Veronica's favorite.
It's very good.
I like the noodles.
I like the crunch.
What happened to
William London?
I sent him home.
Oh, dear.
So he's still bleeding?
Yes.
His nose just let loose
and started gushing during
the Pledge of Allegiance.
Was it spontaneous?
What?
His nosebleed.
What else would it be?
Self-induced.
Mmm-hmm.
You mean you think
he might have intentionally
given himself a nosebleed?
Exactly.
No.
You are a very innocent
person, Sister James.
William London
is a fidgety boy.
If you do not keep right on him, he
will do anything to escape his chair.
He would set his foot on fire
for half a day out of school.
Here. Sister, allow me
to help you. Your sleeve.
Uh-oh.
Let's see.
Oh, thank you, Sister.
Sister Veronica is going blind.
Oh, how horrible.
If they find out in the
rectory, she'll be gone.
So if she looks unsteady,
take her hand.
Ordinarily I assign my most
experienced teachers to eighth grade,
but I am working
within constraints.
Are you in control
of your class?
I think so.
Usually more students
are sent down to me.
I try to take care
of things myself.
That can be an error.
You are answerable to me,
I to the monsignor,
he to the bishop, and so
on up to the Holy Father.
There is a chain.
Make use of it.
Candy?
Cough drops.
Candy by another name.
How is Donald Miller doing?
Steady.
Good.
That girl, Noreen Horan.
I've seated her as far away
from the boys as possible.
Doesn't do much good.
Mmm.
Just get her through intact.
What's this?
The wind is so peripatetic
this year.
Is that
the word I want?
Is something
the matter?
What?
Is something
the matter?
No.
Why? Is something
the matter?
I don't think so.
Well, then, nothing's
the matter then.
Yes.
What's this?
A pen.
A ballpoint pen.
The students are not using
them for assignments, I hope.
No, of course not.
I am sorry I allowed even
cartridge pens into this school.
Always easy way out,
these days.
Every easy choice today will
have its consequence tomorrow.
Mark my words.
Yes, Sister.
Ballpoints make them
press down.
When they press down,
they write like monkeys.
I don't allow them
ballpoint pens.
And yet here one is.
Penmanship is dying all
across this country.
I hope not.
You should frame something.
Put it up on the blackboard.
Put the pope up.
That's the wrong pope.
He's deceased.
I don't care what pope it is.
Use the glass to see behind you.
Children should think you have
eyes in the back of your head.
Wouldn't that be
a little frightening?
Only to the ones
who are up to no good.
Relax.
Put it up there.
All right, now.
The thing about shooting from the
foul line is it's psychological.
All right, come up
with a routine.
You shift your weight,
move your hips...
Yeah, you think
that's funny, Ralph?
You know what's funny is you
never getting a foul shot.
All right, concentrate on the routine,
and you'll forget to get tensed up.
All right, go ahead, Jimmy.
Good man. You listen. That's good.
All right, now sit down, everyone.
Good.
On another matter, I've noticed
several of you guys got dirty nails.
All right, I don't
want to see that.
I'm not talking about
the length of your nails.
I'm talking about cleanliness.
See, look at my nails.
All right, they're long.
Whoa!
Yeah, I like them a little long,
but look at how clean they are.
That makes it okay.
The climpity-clomp.
Clomp-clomp-clomp.
Harder than
a herd of elephants.
You are wicked!
No, I told her,
"You're her mother.
"You raised her. You fed her.
You tell her she's fat."
But wait, how fat is she?
What, the mother
or the daughter?
The daughter.
I never met the daughter.
What about the mother?
Fat.
Father, we having
practice after school?
If you guys want it,
we can have it. Let me know.
The Fascist governments
of Germany and Italy
were already working together.
They formed the Pact of Steel.
The Pact of Steel was...
Hi.
a military alliance between
Benito Mussolini and Adolf Hitler.
Mr. London, get back in your seat and
stop bothering Miss Horan, please.
Now, who can tell me...
Yes?
Yes. Of course, Father.
Donald? You should
go to the rectory.
Two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven.
Go one, two, three, touch.
One, two, three, kick.
And back, side, front, kick.
Back, side, front. Again.
♪ We began to dance
♪ Swaying to and fro
♪ And soon I knew
I'd never let him go
Raymond, what are you doing?
The mashed potato.
You're supposed to be
doing the bossa nova.
But I know the mashed potato.
Oh...
All right, now follow.
Back, side, front, kick.
Back, side...
One, two, three, kick.
Back, side, front, kick.
Back, side, front...
Let me get in front of you so
that you can see what I'm doing.
And one, two, three, touch.
One, two, three, kick.
Back, side, front, kick.
Back, side, front...
Okay. This is really good.
Very good there.
♪ Now I'm glad to say
♪ I'm his bride to be
♪ And we're gonna
raise a family ♪
Donald,
are you feeling ill?
No.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Are you all right?
I just want to go home.
Good afternoon, Sister.
Good afternoon, Sister James.
Sister, can I speak with
you about Donald Miller?
Is he
being accepted?
He has no friends.
That would be a lot to
expect after only two months.
Has anyone hit him?
No.
Someone will.
And when that happens, send
them right down to me.
I'm not so sure anyone will.
This parish serves Irish
and Italian families.
Someone will hit Donald Miller.
He has a protector.
Who?
Father Flynn.
What?
He's taken an interest.
I told you to come to me, but
I hoped you never would.
Maybe I shouldn't have.
So, it's happened.
What? Oh, no.
I'm not telling you that.
I'm not even certain
what you mean.
Oh, excuse me there, Sisters.
No bother. We're done here.
Come, Sister.
What have you seen?
It is unsettling to look
at people with suspicion.
I feel less close to God.
When you take a step
to address wrongdoing,
you are taking a step away
from God, but in his service.
What have you seen?
Good afternoon, Sisters.
Good afternoon, Mrs. Carson.
Why the cat?
'Cause there's a mouse.
Want some tea?
If you don't want to dance with
her, don't dance with her.
Well, is it wrong?
No.
But what if the girl
turns you down?
All right, you have the right
to ask a girl to dance.
All right, she has the
right to turn you down.
The trick is,
don't take it to heart.
What if they all turn you down?
Well, then you become a priest.
All right, next question.
What have you seen?
He called Donald Miller
to the rectory.
What for?
A talk.
Alone?
Yes.
When?
A week ago during class.
Why didn't you tell me?
I didn't think there was
anything wrong with it.
Of all the children,
Donald Miller.
I suppose it makes sense.
How does it make sense?
He's isolated.
I don't know
that anything is wrong.
Our first Negro student.
I thought there would be
fighting. Thought we...
A parent or two to deal with.
I should have foreseen
this possibility.
How could you imagine it?
Well, it's my job to outshine
the fox in cleverness.
That is my job.
But maybe it's nothing.
Then why do you look like
you've seen the devil?
It's just the way the boy acted
when he came back to class.
He said something?
No, it was his expression.
He looked frightened.
And he put his head on the desk
in the most peculiar way, and...
And one other thing, I think
there was alcohol on his breath.
There was alcohol
on his breath.
Years ago at Saint Boniface
there was a priest.
But I had Father Scully then.
Here, there's no man I can go to.
Men run everything.
We are going to have
to stop him ourselves.
There we go. She got him.
Takes a cat.
Yes, it does.
This towel will never
be dead white again.
Yes, it will.
Mrs. Carson.
I'm fine.
What happened?
There's a branch down.
- Are you all right, Sister?
- She didn't see it.
Fine. Just bushwhacked.
No need for a fuss.
You just go lie down.
I'll bring you some tea.
- Come with me.
- I just...
I'll get you
a compress.
I did not fail to see it.
MR. McGUINN: Hello?
Yes, Sister.
Mr. McGuinn.
Could you look in on the courtyard?
I've got branches falling.
What has?
A branch has!
Watch your step here,
Sister. I'll cut it up.
The world is crashing, Michael.
I haven't heard a wind like
that since I left Mullingar.
I've never known a wind like it.
The wind has changed.
What are you doing
out here, Conroy?
I talked in class, Father.
Waiting for Sister Aloysius.
She know you're here?
She knows.
Good morning, Father Flynn.
Good of you to come by.
Morning, Sister Aloysius.
How are you today?
I'm very well, thank you.
Mr. Conroy.
Yes, Sister.
Mr. Transistor Radio.
Multiplication table,
10 times, in its totality,
delivered to me
tomorrow morning.
Legible, boy.
Return to class.
Go. Go, go.
I'd invite you in, but we're
just short Sister James.
Hear that wind last night?
I certainly did.
Oh.
Did I hear Sister
Veronica had an accident?
Yeah. Sister Veronica fell,
practically killed herself.
Is she all right?
Oh, she's fine.
Her sight isn't good, is it?
Her sight is fine.
Nuns fall, you know.
Nah, I didn't know that.
It's the habit. It catches
us up more often than not.
Hmm.
We go down like dominoes.
Am I past the time?
Not at all.
Good morning, Father.
Good morning, Sister.
I'm sorry I was delayed.
I ran into Sister Veronica.
How is she?
I'm afraid she has a
bit of a bloody nose.
I'm beginning to think
you're punching people.
Sister?
First, William London
and now...
Never mind.
Well, come in, please.
Sister.
Please. Sit.
Have a seat.
I actually have
a hot pot of tea.
And close this, but not
quite for form's sake.
Father, would you care for a...
Would you have
a cup of tea, Father?
I'd love a cup of tea.
Sister, perhaps
you could serve him.
I'd be glad.
And yourself, of course.
Would you like a cup of
tea, Sister Aloysius?
No, I've already had my cup.
Is there sugar?
Sugar?
Yes, yes. Somewhere here.
I put it in the drawer
for Lent last year.
Never remembered
to take it out.
It mustn't have been
much to give up, then.
I'm sure you're right.
Here it is.
I'll serve you, although for want
of practice I'm a little clumsy.
I see your fingernails.
Wear them a little long.
The sugar?
Yes. One?
Three.
Three?
Sweet tooth.
Two. Three.
Sister, you care for sugar?
Never.
Not that there's anything
wrong with sugar.
Well, thank you, Father,
for making time for us.
We are at our wit's end.
I think it's an excellent idea to
rethink the Christmas pageant,
'cause last year's effort
was a little woebegone.
Oh, I loved it, but I love all pageants.
The hymns.
O Little Town of Bethlehem, O Come,
O Come, Emmanuel, O Come...
All right.
Thank you, Sister James.
So what do you think, Father?
Is there
something new we could do?
Well, we all love
the Christmas hymns,
but it might be jolly
to include a secular song.
Secular?
Yes.
It's Beginning To Look A Lot Like
Christmas. Something like that.
What would be the point
of a secular song?
Just fun.
Or Frosty the Snowman.
That's a good one.
We could have one of the boys dress
up as a snowman, dance around.
Which boy?
We'd do tryouts.
Frosty the Snowman espouses
a pagan belief in magic.
The snowman comes to life when an
enchanted hat is put on his head.
If the music were more somber,
people would realize the images are
disturbing and the song heretical.
I never thought about Frosty
the Snowman like that.
It should be banned
from the airwaves.
So, not Frosty the Snowman.
Oh, It's Beginning To Look A Lot Like
Christmas would be fine, I suppose.
Parents would like it.
May I ask what you're writing
down with that ballpoint pen?
Oh, nothing.
It's an idea for a sermon.
Oh. You had one
right now?
I get them all the time.
How fortunate.
I forget them, so I have
to write them down.
Oh.
What is the idea?
Intolerance.
Would you like
a little more tea, Father?
Not yet.
It's a new time, Sister.
What's new about it?
Something inside
of people is new.
There is nothing new
under the sun.
The Church needs to change.
We should sing a song
from the radio now and then,
take the kids out
for ice cream.
Sweet tooth.
And maybe take the boys
on a camping trip.
The point being?
We should be friendlier.
You know, the children
and the parents
should see us
as members of their family.
But we are not members of their family.
We're different.
Why?
Because of our vows?
Precisely.
I don't think
we're so different.
You know, Sister,
I would take some more tea.
And they think
we're different, yeah?
The working...
The working class people of this
parish trust us to be different.
I think we're getting
off the subject.
Yes, you're right. You're right.
You're right. Back to it.
Yes?
Sister Raymond? Mmm.
Well, you tell her to wash her face and
her neck and report to me at 3:00.
Yeah.
Excuse me.
The Christmas pageant.
We must be careful
how Donald Miller is used
in the pageant.
Easy there, Sister.
Father.
All right, what about
Donald Miller?
We must be careful,
in the pageant,
that we neither hide Donald
Miller nor put him forward.
Because of the color
of his skin?
That's right, yeah.
Why?
Oh, come, Father.
I think he should be treated
like every other boy.
Well, you yourself singled the
boy out for special attention.
You held a private meeting with
him at the rectory. A week ago?
Yes.
What are we talking about?
Donald Miller.
The boy acted strangely
when he returned to class.
He did?
When he returned from the
rectory, a little odd, yes.
Can you tell us why?
How did he act strangely?
He...
I'm not sure how to explain it.
He laid his head
on the desk and...
Do you mean
you had some impression?
Yes.
And he'd come from the
rectory, so you're asking me?
Mmm. That's it.
Hmm.
Mmm.
Did you want to discuss the pageant?
Is that why I'm here?
Or is this what
you wanted to discuss?
This.
Well, I'm a little
uncomfortable.
Why?
Why do you think?
The boy's well-being
is my responsibility.
His well-being
is not at issue.
I'm not satisfied
that that is true.
He was upset
when he returned to class.
Did he say something?
No.
What happened in the rectory?
Happened?
Mmm.
Nothing happened.
I had a talk with the boy.
What about?
Private matter.
He's 12 years old.
What could be private?
- Should I get...
- No.
I object to your tone.
This is not about my tone
or your tone, Father Flynn.
It's about
arriving at the truth.
Of what?
You know what I'm talking
about, don't you?
And you're controlling the expression
on your face right now, aren't you?
My face?
What exactly
are you accusing me of?
I'm not accusing you
of anything, Father Flynn.
I am asking you to tell me
what happened in the rectory.
I don't wish to continue this.
And if you're
dissatisfied with that,
I suggest you speak
to Monsignor Benedict.
I can only imagine this unfortunate
behavior is the result of overwork.
Have a good morning,
Sister. Sister.
There was alcohol on his breath
when he returned
from his meeting with you.
Alcohol?
I did smell it on his breath.
Well?
Let this alone.
No.
Take your time, Father.
Would you like some more tea?
You should've let it alone.
Not possible.
Mr. McGuinn caught Donald
drinking altar wine.
When I found out, I sent for him.
There were tears,
and he begged not to be removed from
the altar boys. I took pity on him.
I told him if no one else found
out, I'd let him stay on.
What a relief. That explains
everything. Thanks be to God.
Look, Sister,
it was all a mistake.
And if I talk to
Mr. McGuinn?
Talk to him, by all means.
But now that
the boy's secret's out,
I'm gonna have to remove
him from the altar boys.
That's what
I was trying to avoid.
You were trying
to protect the boy.
That's right.
I might have done
the same thing.
Is there a way Donald could
stay on the altar boys?
If the boy drank altar wine, he
can't continue as an altar boy.
Of course.
Are you satisfied?
Yes.
Hmm.
Well, I'll be going.
I have some writing to do.
Intolerance.
That's right.
I'm not pleased
with how you handled this.
Sister. Sister.
Well...
What a relief.
He cleared it all up.
You believe him?
Of course.
Isn't it that it's easier
to believe him?
But we can corroborate his
story with Mr. McGuinn.
Mmm-hmm.
Yes.
These types of people
are clever.
Well, I'm convinced.
You're not.
You just want things to be resolved
so you can have simplicity back.
I want no further part of this.
I'll bring him down.
How can you be so sure
that he is lying?
Experience.
You just don't like him.
You don't like it that
he uses a ballpoint pen.
You don't like it that he takes
three lumps of sugar in his tea.
You don't like it that he
likes Frosty the Snowman,
and you are letting that convince you
of something terrible, just terrible.
Well, I like
Frosty the Snowman!
And I think it would be nice if this
school weren't run like a jail,
and I think it's a good thing
that I love to teach history
and that I might inspire
my students to love it, too.
And if you judge that to mean that
I am not fit to be a teacher,
then so be it!
Sit down.
Look at that.
You blew out my light.
In ancient Sparta,
important matters were decided
by who shouted loudest.
Fortunately, we are not
in ancient Sparta.
You honestly find
the students in this school
to be treated like
inmates in a prison?
No.
Actually, they all seem fairly happy, but
they're all uniformly terrified of you.
Yes.
That's how it works.
Sit there.
Hello, this is
Sister Aloysius Beauvier,
principal at St. Nicholas School.
Is this Mrs. Miller?
I'm calling about
your son, Donald.
A woman was gossiping with a
friend about a man she hardly knew.
I know none of you
have ever done this.
That night she had a dream.
A great hand appeared over
her and pointed down at her.
She was immediately seized with
an overwhelming sense of guilt.
The next day she
went to confession.
She got the old parish
priest, Father O'Rourke.
She told him the whole thing.
"Is gossiping a sin?"
she asked the old man.
"Was that the hand of God
Almighty pointing a finger at me?
"Should I be asking your
absolution, Father?
"Tell me, have I done
something wrong?"
"Yes."
Father O'Rourke answered her.
"Yes, you ignorant,
badly brought up female.
"You have borne false witness
against your neighbor.
"You have played fast and
loose with his reputation,
"and you should be
heartily ashamed!"
So the woman said she was sorry
and asked for forgiveness.
"Not so fast," says O'Rourke.
"I want you to go home.
Take a pillow up on your roof,
"cut it open with a knife,
and return here to me."
So the woman went home,
took a pillow off her bed,
a knife from the drawer,
went up the fire escape to her
roof and stabbed the pillow.
Then she went back to the old
parish priest as instructed.
"Did you gut the pillow
with a knife?" he says.
"Yes, Father."
"And what was the result?"
"Feathers," she said.
"Feathers," he repeated.
"Feathers everywhere, Father."
"Now, I want you to go back
"and gather up every last feather
that flew out on the wind."
"Well," she said,
"it can't be done.
"I don't know where they went.
The wind took them all over."
"And that," said Father
O'Rourke, "is gossip!"
In the name of the Father, the
Son and the Holy Ghost. Amen.
Please rise.
What's that bird
complaining about?
What kind of bird is that?
That a starling?
A grackle?
A crow.
Course it is.
Are you praying?
I didn't mean to interrupt.
I'm not praying.
No.
You seem subdued.
Oh, I can't sleep.
Why not?
Bad dreams.
Yeah, I can't sleep
on occasion.
Why? Do you see that big hand
pointing a finger at you?
Yes. Sometimes.
Was your sermon directed
at anyone in particular?
What do you think?
I received a letter from
my brother in Maryland.
He's very sick.
Then maybe you should
go and see him.
I can't leave my class.
Is it true?
What?
You know what I'm asking.
No.
I saw you put an undershirt
in Donald Miller's locker.
He left it in the sacristy.
Why didn't you hand it to him?
I'm trying to spare him
further embarrassment.
It's me that cares about
that child, not her.
Has she ever
reached out a hand?
That black boy needs help
or he's not gonna make it.
If she has her way, he'll
be left to his own undoing.
Why do you think he drank the wine?
He's in trouble.
And she sees me talk in a
human way to these kids
and she immediately assumes that there
must be something wrong with it.
Well, I'm not gonna let her keep
this parish in the Dark Ages,
and I'm not gonna let her destroy
my spirit of compassion.
I'm sure that's not her intent.
That I care about
this congregation.
I know you do.
Like you care about your class.
You love them, don't you?
Yes.
And that's natural.
How else would
you relate to children?
Now, I can look at your face
and know your philosophy.
It's kindness.
I don't know.
I mean, of course.
There are people who go after
your humanity, Sister,
that tell you that the light
in your heart is a weakness.
Don't believe it.
It's an old tactic of cruel people to
kill kindness in the name of virtue.
There's nothing wrong
with love.
Love?
Have you forgotten the
message of our Savior?
It's love of people.
I just feel as if
everything is upside down.
There are just times in life
when we feel lost. It happens.
And it's a bond.
Flowers.
Yeah.
To remind me of spring.
I should be going.
I'm sorry your brother's ill.
Thank you, Father.
I don't believe it.
You don't?
No.
Thank you, Sister.
Thank you very much.
- Hey, Anthony!
- That's not funny.
That's also the day
that I tripped. I broke my ankle.
I barely...
Father. I think I've just
gotta tell somebody.
Hello, Noreen.
I'm in love.
That's wonderful.
Who's the lucky boy?
Jimmy Hurley.
Have you told him?
For life and death,
I'd go for waffles.
Maybe you should.
Maybe I will, Father.
Jimmy!
Jimmy Hurley?
Come over here!
Hurry up, already!
Father Sherman.
Jimmy, I just
gotta tell you something.
You dropped
something.
It's not funny.
Get out of the way.
It's all right.
He doesn't like me.
That is so easy!
My parents are
gonna be so angry at me.
Okay. Be quiet.
I said be quiet!
The next one of you that speaks out of
turn gets sent right to the principal.
Now the question was,
what was Patrick
Henry's famous remark?
Donald.
Sister?
What was the question?
Nobody help him.
Jimmy, put your hand down.
Donald Miller, stand up.
What was the question, Donald?
I don't know, Sister.
It means you weren't listening.
Yes, Sister.
The question was, what was
Patrick Henry's famous remark?
I don't know.
"Give me liberty
or give me death!"
James Hurley, down to
the principal's office.
Now!
Mrs. Miller?
Yes.
Come in.
Please, have a seat.
I was changing a bulb.
Thought I mighta had the wrong day.
You didn't answer.
Huh?
Oh, well, just between us,
I was listening to a transistor
radio with an earpiece.
Look how tiny
they're making them.
I confiscated it from
one of the students,
now I can't stop
listening to it.
You like music?
No. News reports.
Years ago I used to listen
to all the news reports,
because my husband was
in Italy, in the war.
You were a married woman?
Yes.
But then he was killed.
Is your husband coming?
Couldn't get off work.
I only have half an hour myself.
I see. Of course.
It was a lot to ask.
How's Donald doing?
He's passing his subjects.
He has average grades.
Oh. Good.
He was upset about getting
taken off the altar boys.
Mmm. Did he explain why?
He said he was caught
drinking altar wine.
That is the reason.
Well, that seems fair.
But he's a good boy, Sister.
He fell down there,
but he's a good boy
pretty much down the line.
How is he at home?
His father beat the hell
out of him over that wine.
Oh, he shouldn't do that.
You don't tell my husband what to do.
You just stand back.
My husband didn't want
Donald to come here.
Why?
He thought he'd have trouble
with the other boys, but
that hasn't really happened.
Good.
That priest, Father Flynn,
been watching out for him.
Yes.
Excuse me.
James Hurley, what are
you doing out of class?
Sister James sent me down.
What for?
Talking.
Well, go back up and shut up!
Go! Go!
What's going on?
None of your business.
Now go on. Go back to class.
Bullshit.
What'd you say?
Nothing!
You have 20 minutes, you say?
It's just that I have
to walk to work.
Where is work?
Parkchester.
If I don't start cleaning by noon,
I'm not home to let Donald in.
May I walk with you?
I don't mind.
Eight sixty-fourths.
Who can tell me what the
common denominator is?
Nobody?
Back already,
Mr. Hurley?
I said, back already,
Leave me alone!
Who do you think
you're talking to?
This is my classroom, boy!
Don't you forget that.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, Jimmy.
Have you met
Father Flynn?
Just seen him on the altar.
Haven't met him face to face.
No, just, you know,
heard from Donald.
And what does he say?
You know, "Father
Flynn, Father Flynn."
He looks up to him. Man gives him his
time, which is what the boy needs.
He needs that.
Mrs. Miller, we may
have a problem.
I thought there must a been a
reason you wanting to see me.
Principal's a big job.
I just want to say though,
it's just till June.
Excuse me?
Whatever the problem is, Donald
just has to make it till June.
Then he's off into high school.
Right.
If Donald can graduate
from St. Nicholas,
he has a better chance of getting
into a good high school,
and that would mean an
opportunity at college.
I don't see anything
at this time
standing in the way of his
graduating with his class.
Well, that's all I care about.
I doubt that.
Try me.
I am concerned about the relationship
between Father Flynn and your son.
You don't say. Concerned.
What do you mean, concerned?
That it may not be right.
Well, there's something
wrong with everybody,
and their soul gotta be forgiven.
I work right there.
I am concerned, to be frank,
that Father Flynn may have
made advances on your son.
May have made?
I can't be certain.
No evidence?
No.
Then maybe
there's nothing to it.
I think there is
something to it.
I think Father Flynn gave
Donald that altar wine.
Why would he do that?
Has Donald been
acting strangely?
No.
Nothing out of the ordinary?
He's been himself.
All right.
Look, Sister, I don't
want any trouble.
I don't... I'm not sure
you completely understand.
I think I understand the kind
of thing you're talking about,
but I don't want
to get into it.
What's that?
Look, I only have a few minutes.
Not to be disagreeing,
but if we're talking about
something floating around
between this priest and my
son, it ain't my son's fault.
I'm not suggesting that...
He's just a boy.
I know.
Twelve years old.
If someone should be taking
blame, it should be the man...
I know. I agree
with you completely.
not the boy.
You're agreeing with me,
but I got called
to the principal, if you
know what I'm saying.
I am concerned about
Donald's welfare.
You honestly think that priest
gave Donald that wine to drink?
Yes, I do.
Then how come my son got
kicked off the altar boys
if it was a man
that gave it to him?
I know.
The boy got caught,
the man didn't.
So you're giving my son the blame.
No.
No problem my son
getting blamed,
and you know why that is.
Perhaps you should let me talk.
I think you're getting upset.
Sister, you ain't going against
no man in a robe and win.
He's got the position.
And he's got your son.
Let him have him then.
What?
It's just till June.
Do you know what you're saying?
Know more about it than you.
I believe this man is creating,
or may have already
brought about,
an improper relationship
with your son.
I don't know.
I know I am right.
Why you gotta know something like
that for sure when you don't?
What kind of mother are you?
Excuse me, but you don't know enough about
life to say a thing like that, Sister.
I know enough.
You know the rules maybe,
but that don't cover it.
I know what I won't accept.
You accept what you gotta
accept, and you work with it.
This man is in my school.
Well, he's gotta be
somewhere and
maybe he's doing some good, too.
He is after the boys!
Well, maybe some of them
boys want to get caught!
That's why his father beat him.
Not the wine.
What are you telling me?
I'm talking about
the boy's nature now,
not anything he's done.
You can't hold a child responsible
for what God gave him to be.
I'm only interested
in actions, Mrs. Miller.
But then there's
the boy's nature.
Leave that out of it.
Well, forget it then.
You're the one forcing
people to say things.
My boy came to your school
'cause they were gonna kill
him in the public school.
His father don't like him.
He come to your school,
kids don't like him.
One man is good to him,
this priest.
Then does a man
have his reasons, yes.
Everybody does.
You have your reasons,
but do I ask the man
why he's good to my son?
No.
I don't care why.
My son needs some man
to care about him
and to see him through
to where he wants to go.
And thank God this educated man
with some kindness in him
wants to do just that.
This will not do.
It's just till June.
I'll throw your son
out of this school.
And why would you do that
if it didn't start with him?
Because I will stop this.
You'd hurt my son
to get your way?
It won't end with your son.
Throw the priest out then.
I am trying to do just that.
Then what do you want from me?
Nothing.
As it turns out.
Please leave my son out of this.
My husband will kill that
child over a thing like this.
I will try.
I'm late.
Sister,
I don't know if you and me
on the same side.
I'll be standing with my son and
those who are good with my son.
It'd be nice to see you there.
Good morning.
May I come in?
A third party
would be required.
Yeah. What was Donald's
mother doing here?
We were having a chat.
About what?
A third party would truly
be required, Father.
No, Sister.
No third party!
Me and you are due for a talk!
You have to stop
this campaign against me.
You can stop it at any time.
How?
Confess and resign.
You are attempting
to destroy my reputation!
Who keeps opening my window?
What are you doing
in this school?
I'm trying to do good.
Even more to the point,
what are you doing
in the priesthood?
You are single-handedly holding
this school and this parish back.
From what?
Progressive education
and a welcoming church.
You can't distract me, Father.
This is not about my
behavior, it's about yours.
No, this is about
your unfounded suspicions.
That's right.
I have suspicions.
Just leave that.
It's not important.
I will decide
what's important.
Why do you suspect me?
What have I done?
You gave that boy wine, and
you let him take the blame.
That's completely untrue.
Did you talk to Mr. McGuinn?
All McGuinn knows
is that the boy drank wine.
He doesn't know
how he came to drink it.
Did his mother have
something to add to that?
No.
So that's it.
I am not satisfied.
Ask the boy then.
He'd protect you.
Why would he do that?
Because you have seduced him.
You're insane.
You've got it in your head
that I corrupted this child
after giving him wine, and
nothing I say will change that.
That's right.
But this has nothing
to do with the wine.
Not really. You've had a fundamental
mistrust of me before this incident.
It was you that warned Sister James
to be on the lookout, wasn't it?
That's true.
So you admit it!
Certainly.
Why?
I know people.
That's not good enough.
It won't have to be.
How's that?
You will tell me
what you have done.
Oh, I will.
Out again.
Sister James is convinced
I'm innocent.
So you talked to Sister James.
Well, of course
you talked to Sister James.
Did you know Donald's
father beats him?
Yes.
And might that not account
for the odd behavior
Sister James noticed
in the boy?
It might.
Then what is it? What?
What did you hear?
What did you see that
convinced you so thoroughly?
What does it matter?
It matters! What does it matter?
I want to know!
Out this window,
I saw you grab
William London's wrist,
and I saw him pull away.
Are you serious?
I am.
That's all?
Yeah. That was all.
That's nothing.
What are you doing now?
I'm writing down what you say.
It might be important when I have to
explain why you have to be removed.
This morning before I
spoke with Mrs. Miller,
I took the precaution of
calling your last parish.
What did he say?
Who?
The pastor.
I did not speak to the pastor.
I spoke to a nun.
You should have
spoken to the pastor.
I spoke to a nun.
You know that's not the proper route
for you to have taken, Sister.
The church is very clear.
You're supposed to go through the pastor.
Why? You have an
understanding, you and he?
No, you have no right to go
rummaging through my past!
You have a history.
This is your third parish
in five years.
Why?
Call the pastor.
Ask him why I left.
It's perfectly innocent.
I'm not calling the pastor.
I'm a good priest.
Go after another child and another
child, until you are stopped.
What nun did you speak to?
I won't say.
Yeah, I've not touched a child.
You have!
You haven't the slightest
proof of anything.
But I have my certainty.
And armed with that,
I'll go to your last parish
and the one before that.
If necessary, I'll find a parent.
Trust me, Father Flynn, I will.
You have no right
to act on your own!
You have taken vows,
obedience being one!
You answer to us!
You have no right to
step outside the church!
I will step outside the church
if that's what needs to be done,
though the door
should shut behind me!
I will do what needs to be done,
though I'm damned to hell!
You should understand that,
or you will mistake me.
Now, did you give Donald
Miller wine to drink?
Have you never done
anything wrong?
I have.
No mortal sin?
Yes.
And?
I confessed it, Father.
Then whatever I have done,
I have left in the healing
hands of my confessor.
As have you.
We are the same.
Mmm-mmm.
No, we are not.
We are not the same.
A dog that bites
is a dog that bites.
Did you give Donald
Miller wine to drink?
No.
Mental reservations?
You lie.
Very well then.
If you will not
leave my office, I will.
And once I go, I will not stop.
Wait.
I can't say everything,
you understand?
There's things I can't say,
even if you can't imagine
the explanation, Sister.
Remember, there are things
beyond your knowledge.
Even if you feel certainty,
it is an emotion, not a fact.
You will request a transfer
and take a leave of absence
until it's granted.
You'd leave me nothing.
It's Donald Miller
who has nothing,
and you took
full advantage of that.
I've done nothing wrong.
I care about that boy.
Why?
'Cause you smile at him?
And you sympathize with him?
And you talk to him
as if you were the same?
You are a cheat.
And that warm feeling
you experienced
when that boy looked at you with trust
was not the sensation of virtue.
That could be got by any
drunkard with his tot of rum.
I can fight you.
You will lose.
Where's your compassion?
Nowhere you can get at it.
Stay here.
Compose yourself.
You can use the phone
if you'd like.
Good day, Father.
I have no sympathy for you.
I know you are invulnerable
to true regret.
And cut your nails.
♪ Praise God,
from whom all blessings flow
♪ Praise him all
creatures here below
♪ Praise him above,
ye heavenly host
♪ Praise Father,
Son and Holy Ghost
♪ Amen
I never like to say goodbye,
but there is a wind behind every one
of us that takes us through our lives.
We never see it.
We can't command it.
We don't even know its purpose.
'Cause I would have
stayed among you longer,
but that wind is taking me away.
I will miss it here,
and I will miss you.
But I'm content that the
power that propels me
does so with superior knowledge
as to what is for the best,
and that is my faith.
I would like to come
down now among you
and say goodbye
and wish you peaceful hearts
and loving hearts.
Goodbye, Senator.
Father.
Carol.
Thank you so much. Thank you.
Bless you, Father.
Happy holidays.
Susan. Bless you.
Thank you, Father.
Father.
Thank you.
Be good. Thank you.
Thank you, Father.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Paul.
Thank you so much.
God bless you.
Goodbye.
♪ ...a midnight clear
♪ A glorious song of old
♪ From angels bending
near the Earth ♪
Sister James.
Welcome back.
Thank you, Sister.
You were missed.
How is your brother?
Better. Much better.
I'm very glad.
I prayed for him.
It was good to get away.
I needed to see my family.
Mmm. Then I'm glad
you did it.
And Father Flynn is gone?
Yes.
So you did it.
You got him out.
Yes.
Donald Miller is heartbroken.
Can't be helped.
It's just till June.
I don't think Father Flynn
did anything wrong.
No? He convinced you?
Yes, he did.
Mmm.
Did you ever prove it?
To whom?
Anyone but yourself?
Nope.
But you were sure?
Yes.
I wish I could be like you.
Why?
Because I can't sleep anymore.
Maybe we're not supposed
to sleep so well.
They made Father Flynn
pastor of Saint Jerome.
Who?
The bishop.
Appointed Father Flynn pastor of
Saint Jerome Church and School.
It's a promotion.
You didn't tell them?
Oh, I told our good monsignor.
I crossed the garden, and I told him.
He did not believe it
to be true.
Then why did Father Flynn go?
What did you say
to make him leave?
That I had called a nun
in his previous parish,
that I had found out his prior
history of infringements.
So you did prove it?
I made no such call.
You lied?
Yes.
But if he'd had no such history,
the lie wouldn't have worked.
His resignation
was his confession.
He was what I thought he was.
And he's gone.
I can't believe you lied.
In the pursuit of wrongdoing,
one steps away from God.
Of course, there is a price.
I see.
Oh.
Sister James.
What is it, Sister?
I have doubts.
I have such doubts.
♪ Come, thou,
redeemer of the Earth
♪ And manifest thy virgin birth
♪ Let every age adoring fall
♪ Such birth befits
the God of all
♪ Begotten of no human will
♪ But of the Spirit,
thou art still
♪ The word of God
in flesh arrayed
♪ The promised fruit
to man displayed
♪ The virgin womb
that burden gained
♪ With virgin honor
all unstained
♪ The banners there
of virtue glow
♪ God in his temple dwells below
♪ Forth from his
chamber goeth he
♪ That royal home of purity
♪ A giant in twofold
substance one
♪ Rejoicing now
his course to run
♪ From God the
Father he proceeds
♪ To God the Father
back he speeds
♪ His course he runs
to death and hell
♪ Returning on God's
throne to dwell
♪ O equal to thy Father, thou
♪ Gird on thy fleshly mantle now
♪ The weakness of
our mortal state
♪ With deathless
might invigorate
♪ Thy cradle here
shall glitter bright
♪ And darkness breathe
a newer light
♪ Where endless faith
shall shine serene
♪ And twilight never intervene
♪ All praise, eternal
Son, to thee
♪ Whose advent sets
thy people free
♪ Whom, with the
Father, we adore
♪ And Holy Ghost for evermore
♪ Amen