Black thorns and roses.
Smiles and tears.
They're sown together
and grow so near.
Dima, wait!
- I win.
- All right.
- Come. Let's go back.
- Oh, relax.
Sergey?
Enjoy yourself for once.
One more time. Please.
Race you to the rocks.
OK, but you're
going to lose again. Ready?
Luisa, quick.
Halt. Identify yourself.
- Stop or I'll shoot.
- Popov? It's Sidorov.
Sidorov?
You again.
Kurilka, 0900 hours.
Next time, I'll shoot you.
Oh! Volodja.
Sergeant Popov's easy.
Two packs of cigarettes.
Life's about who you know.
We can't all have your connections.
You could have my connections,
Luisa. You could have them all.
Oh, bloody rocks!
Get up!
Fucking lazy rats.
Slow. Stupid.
Useless little rats.
Faster.
- Attention.
- At ease.
Comrade Colonel, second
squadron ready to manoeuvre.
You know, one day the colonel
is going to open his flight reports
and find your human-anatomy diagrams.
It's the hardest exam.
Then one more to go -
scientific communism.
I'm not going to have a life.
It'll be worth it in the end.
Let's do the morning report.
Selenoy, 1:34.
Tokarev, 1:12.
You won't reconsider the colonel's offer?
Give me one good reason.
Two good reasons.
You could make
a career for yourself here,
rather than stack hay
in the middle of nowhere.
What else is there?
Sergey. Luisa. Wait.
Sergey, take our photograph,
for posterity.
Not again.
- I'm going to the canteen.
- Please.
Smile in this one.
Comrade Lieutenant.
We were ordered to take
this photograph for the weekly journal.
At ease.
Let me take one of all of you.
Move to your right.
Which way to the commander's office?
Comrade Lieutenant, I'll show you.
Since the NATO forces increased
surveillance of our border,
I've got four Migs up in
the air around the clock.
We now assume each B-52 is carrying
several thermonuclear devices.
Should just one slip through,
they will be on the direct
air corridor to Leningrad.
It will be your duty to prevent
this from happening.
- Understood?
- Yes, Comrade Colonel.
Welcome, Lieutenant Matvejev.
Dismissed.
Send him in.
So, young man, I hear you have declined
my offer to stay on.
What are your plans?
I will return home to find
work, Comrade Colonel.
Very well.
Take the Uazik and drive
the lieutenant to the officers' block.
You'll be receiving some
additional duties n your final weeks.
Yes, Comrade Colonel.
Orderly.
Yes, Comrade Major.
No, he has not returned.
I will report immediately,
Comrade Major.
Here.
I'm afraid there are no facilities
to develop photographs here,
Comrade Lieutenant.
Now there are.
- You develop photographs too?
- Yes, I do.
- I'll finish it myself.
- Yes, Comrade Lieutenant.
- Permission to leave?
- Granted.
Private.
Thank you, Comrade Lieutenant.
Matvejev.
Graduating with first-class hon ours, eh?
Don't they say those who
do well at flight school
have problems handling their
equipment in the sky?
I was told that one particular pilot
here has problems in that department.
Time will tell.
Shit! Volkov is on duty tonight.
He woke up the second unit at 0300 hours
because he found a cigarette
butt outside their barracks.
He made them run 10km
into the forest, dig it a grave
and give it a full burial with hon ours.
What a dick.
What?
At least someone's getting it tonight.
Hey, Matvejev.
Kissed my chances goodbye.
Now I see why she didn't
come swimming with us.
What's the matter with you?
I told you. "Like a sister"?
You are in love.
Sergey, do something about it.
Before it's too late.
The safety of the squadron
is paramount.
There will come a day when you
have to choose between
missing your target or
saving your wing man's life.
There's a fine line between
bravery and recklessness.
Tomorrow, we will proceed
with the high-altitude attack scenario.
That is all.
- Private Serebrennikov?
- Comrade Lieutenant.
At ease. Is Luisa here?
No, she went to human
resources, Comrade Lieutenant.
That's fine. I'll come by later.
Comrade Lieutenant.
Permission to ask you a question.
Would you have time to develop
some photographs later?
You're too soft.
Harder. Not one spot left.
A love letter from another
admirer of yours.
- It's been opened again.
- Must be such a fun job,
reading all the thrilling
letters from your mother.
Come on. We're playing
durak in the Lenin room.
Sergey.
Get out of your fantasy world.
Maybe later.
Take it by the corner,
and gently
place it in the water tray.
- Like this, Comrade Lieutenant?
- That's better.
And call me Roman.
You really see other people, Sergey.
You capture their essence, their soul.
I search for something deeper,
but I can't quite grasp it.
How do you mean?
When you take a photo
there's something in that very moment
which is gone forever.
A moment that will never be there again.
Like a ghost escaping this world.
I didn't know you were a philosopher.
I think we need a drink.
So I gave him a lower score.
The radio was practically
melting with his anger.
He was yelling and threatening
like I'd slept with his wife.
You know it?
Tchaikovsky.
When I first heard it, I was 14.
My best friend Misha was in it.
I've never seen a real ballet.
How could you be
so uncultured coming from Orel?
I've seen a lot of theatre
before being locked up here.
Now there's no chance.
Let's check the photos.
Steady there, Private.
I should be getting back.
I shouldn't even be here.
- You'd better sleep it off here.
- No, I can't
I'll tell the duty officer that
I needed you at the hangar.
No, no, no. I have to go.
I can't stay.
Listen. If you turn up at
the barracks like this,
you'll be cleaning the toilets
for a week.
Oh, shit.
Put your fucking coat on!
Why can't you dress yourself
like any other pig here?
Lebedev.
Did I give you permission to
leave the barracks last night?
No, Comrade Sergeant.
Then why the fuck were
you smoking outside?
What's your problem?
Why the fuck are you staring at
me with those dewy wept eyes?
- Are you a pervert?
- No, Comrade Sergeant.
Then why the fuck do
you look like one?
What the fuck are you smiling at?
Go fuck up the pervert.
Are you fucking deaf?
Go fuck up the pederast now!
- To the stations.
This is a combative exercise.
After I'm done at the regional HQ,
I want to show you something.
- What is it?
- You'll see.
You haven't said a word since we left.
I hope it wasn't that bad.
No. I loved it. I'm sorry.
Whenever I used to watch a play
with my best friend Dima.
I'd never want it to end.
Dima grew up without a mother
and me without a father.
It sort of created this
invisible bond between us.
We'd write secret letters to
each other and sign them Valentin.
- Valentin?
- Zubkov.
The fighter pilot who became an actor.
We wanted to be just like him.
We even promised we'd go to the same
drama school in Moscow together.
What happened?
It was just a silly dream.
What will you do
after you leave the base?
Go back to the farm,
support my mother, find work.
Couldn't you support her even
better if you studied in Moscow
and got a job at Mosfilm?
- I'd never get in.
- How do you know?
Because they only take 20
people from across the country.
There are hundreds of conscripts here
but the colonel chose you.
"It is not in the stars to hold
our destiny, but in ourselves."
Shakespeare.
Pull over.
This could take a while.
Look.
They're dancing with each other.
Oh. Shit.
That definitely wasn't a blueberry.
Do you have a girl back home?
No.
Do you?
Shit! Border guards.
What happened to you last night?
I thought you were going to go
after her, not ignore her even more.
I had to drive the lieutenant.
That late? We waited for you.
Luisa kept going on and on
about him, so I told her to stop
and then she got mad at me
and went home.
Where did you drive him?
He went to the theatre.
And then?
Then we were delayed coming back.
- What?
- Sergey, you've got that look.
No, really. I was on duty.
You've found another girl, haven't you?
- Tell me, who is she?
- Swap, anyone?
Kolja, I'll swap with you.
Yes, Sergey.
Come on, Sergey.
- So, how is he?
- Who?
Lieutenant Matvejev.
Not like the other officers.
That's what I thought.
I have to drive him
to Tallinn this weekend.
What do you think?
Where should I take him?
I could come and show him around,
if Lieutenant Matvejev doesn't mind.
Yeah?
- Yeah.
- Of course.
Stalin is standing in this
field, a green field,
and there's this farmer nearby,
and Stalin...
No, the farmer...
If you insist on telling it,
at least do it properly.
Dick.
A farm worker greets Josef
Stalin at his potato farm.
"Comrade Stalin,
we have so many potatoes that,
"piled one on top of the other
"they would reach all the way to God,"
the farmer excitedly tells...
Go on, Private Serebrennikov.
Go on. I love a good joke.
Go on.
"But God does not exist," replies Stalin.
"Exactly," says the farmer.
"Neither do the potatoes."
That's a good one.
Follow me.
Telling jokes of that nature could
interfere greatly
with your future prospects.
We have immense responsibility
for how we affect society.
So I'd choose more carefully
which stories you tell.
This will never happen again,
Comrade Major.
I do hope so.
For your own sake.
One more thing.
According to
the orderly's logbook,
on your trip to Tallinn, you
returned the Uazik at 22:34.
What was the cause of such a delay?
The lieutenant was attending
the theatre, Comrade Major.
We were delayed at the crossing at Risti.
The gates were broken again.
I did everything I could to
return as quickly as possible.
Whom did he attend the theatre with?
The lieutenant was alone, Comrade Major.
I see.
You will report to me
if you notice anything
outside the ordinary.
- Understood?
- Yes, Comrade Major.
Dismissed.
And the Oleviste church was the tallest
building in medieval Europe.
That there is treasure buried
under Mary's chapel.
Sorry.
Thank you.
How do I look?
You are right.
Oh, thank you.
Would you like one?
Thank you, Comrade Lieutenant.
And this, of course, is the
famous cobbled street
where Lenin had his first
pair of boots made.
Luisa?
- Olga.
- Luisa.
It's been years.
- You look so good.
- You too.
Hello.
Which one of these handsome
men are you married to?
- Olga!
- Don't tell me.
This one's your husband?
And this must be your brother.
Olga, these are my colleagues
from the base.
- Oh.
- Yeah.
Colleagues.
- Nice to meet you.
- He's so sweet. It's your baby?
- Yes.
Comrade.
Luisa.
"To be or not to be.
That is the question."
To be,
or not to be...
That is the question.
To be,
or not
to be.
That is the question.
Shit!
Who's that?
You scared the hell out of me.
Where's Luisa?
Let's go.
Will you help me with my lines?
- What lines?
- For my audition.
Another one of your dreams.
You know you'll end up going
back to the farm.
No, Luisa, I'm serious.
I sent my application.
I'm going to be an actor.
I can't wait to see you on stage, then.
Let's do the reports, then your lines.
Petrov 1:05.
Tokarev 0:52.
Matvejev...
- Comrade Lieutenant.
- At ease.
A little something.
Sergey here told me
how well your exam went.
You shouldn't have,
Lieutenant Matvejev.
I'll be right back.
Where were we?
Er... Selenov 1:25.
Yes, Comrade Colonel?
He's ready for you.
He is different.
Platonov.
You exceeded all your targets
last week.
Excellent.
- That is all.
- Not quite.
One more thing.
Lieutenant Matvejev,
are you familiar with Article
154A of the Criminal Code?
No, Comrade Major. I'm not.
Sexual relations of a man
with another man,
which is punishable by five years'
imprisonment in a hard-lab our camp.
I'm not following,
Comrade Major.
A report has been received
implying you have engaged in
immoral conduct with a private.
- This is malicious gossip.
- Lieutenant Matvejev.
I wouldn't recommend
you interrupt me again.
There was no name of
the private in question.
Give me his name.
There is no name to give.
It is a lie.
I assure you, comrades.
Consider your words,
Lieutenant Matvejev.
Comrade Major
who wrote this?
It was delivered anonymously,
unsigned.
Without hon our.
I trust the lieutenant's word.
Dismissed.
Yes, Comrade Colonel.
Lieutenant.
It would be a pity.
So, when you buy a brand-new Soviet car,
what do you get for free?
- I have no idea.
- Train and bus timetable.
- I have a good one, too.
- I have to go.
So, where's my gift?
Sergey.
Listen to me and don't react.
Someone filed a report.
- About us.
- What?
They didn't mention your name
but...
But the KGB know something.
You better go, Sergey.
Oh, no. False alarm.
All personnel to stations.
This is a red alert.
I repeat, this is a red alert.
This is not a training exercise.
- Attention.
- At ease.
Comrade Colonel, we have four
B-52 strategic nuclear bombers
in neutral air space,
on a direct flight path to Leningrad.
011 and 023 are escorting.
Rock. 011.30 seconds to the border.
Permission to engage?
011. Negative. Do not engage.
I repeat, do not engage.
Ten seconds to the border.
Rock. 011. Awaiting orders.
Wait. Targets diverting
90 degrees north.
011 and 023, continue escorting.
Rock. 011. Engine malfunction.
011. Status report?
Power at 30, declining.
Cooling negative.
I've lost the engine.
Permission to abort.
All stations, we have an emergency.
011, drop your weapons and fuel tanks.
023, mark the coordinates.
Mark. 85km.
10,200.
That gives him a range of 73km.
He'll crash at least 10km short.
011, negative.
Proceed to eject over the sea at 3,000.
I can save the plane.
I can fly it at stall speed.
Damn it, he's trying to land.
Matvejey, it's too risky.
I need you to return alive.
Eject. That's an order.
I do not copy.
Parachute negative.
Mark. Parachute negative.
Activate the stop net.
Duty mechanic to control.
- Karamazin, Serebrennikov, to the net. Go.
- Yes, Comrade Colonel.
Come on.
- Come on!
- What is it?
Shit. The fuse is blown.
The crank!
Damn it!
It won't move!
Rock. 011. Airfield in sight.
- Permission to land?
- 011, permission granted.
Try now!
Come on. Come on.
Faster.
It's going. Run!
Faster. Faster. Get back to
your station, Private.
Serebrennikoy, let's go.
You! You! You!
Get him out of there!
All clear, Lieutenant Matvejev.
You were very lucky today.
Get some rest.
Comrade Lieutenant?
Up here.
For you.
So you won't forget me.
We could get the training plane
and fly to Sweden.
Sweden?
Why Sweden?
I don't know.
I don't care
as long as we're together.
Sergey, I'm an officer.
I can't leave my motherland.
If you get into drama school.
.I'll find something to do
in Moscow, too.
And then we could go to the
cinema whenever we wanted.
And take a cruise on the river
and watch all the shows at the Bolshoi.
And have an ice cream on Arbat,
and then throw up on
the American Mountains.
That's decided, then.
All right, then.
Comrade Major.
At ease.
Sounds like you're having fun in here.
Just analysing my flight report,
Comrade Major.
- Alone?
- Yes, Comrade Major.
I see.
Where did you develop these?
Just personal photos, Comrade Major.
Personal.
Matvejev
if there is the slightest
truth in that report
believe me, I will find out.
And nobody can protect you
then, not even Kuznetsov.
And I'll personally make sure
that you'll never fly again.
Goodnight.
You better return to the barracks now.
Make sure nobody sees you.
Faster! Move it!
Fucking rats.
Move it!
Won't have to listen to him
ever again. One more day.
Good luck.
Comrade Lieutenant.
Vasja, wait here.
Colonel's orders.
Comrade Lieutenant?
- Comrade Lieutenant?
- What is it, Private?
I made a plan.
- What plan?
- For Moscow.
Get back to your station, Private.
What?
- Last night...
- Listen...
Comrade Serebrennikov.
There was no last night.
Nothing ever happened
between us. Nothing.
Understand?
Moscow? Moscow is where I'll be.
I'll hold you to that.
Vasja.
Sergey
don't forget - write to me
after your auditions.
Of course.
Take care.
O, happy dagger.
This is thy sheath.
There rust, and let me die.
Let's try again.
If Juliet had just married Paris,
who's smart and wealthy, the man of wax,
then this terrible tragedy
would never have happened.
That's love for convenience.
That's not true love.
Oh, really?
And how does true love behave?
You can't stop thinking about
the other person.
You have to be with them
no matter what.
But she could save both their lives,
and they could still meet up in secret.
And only live half a life?
Romeo doesn't just go "I defy you stars"
to see her in secret.
Not when he's madly in love.
I've got to get to my class.
Wait. I'll walk with you.
Have you got time to go over
our scenes later?
We could practise at my place.
I can't tonight. I have to
practise my monologue.
Sergey, there you are.
Your friend is here.
I'll see you later.
Luisa.
Look at you.
You've become so handsome.
All that time in the library.
- Oh.
- Oh, and edible food.
Your mother still looks so young.
How is she?
Oh, she's... She's fine.
Anyway, you've heard all my news.
How is medical school?
I deferred. I'll go next autumn.
Why?
I'm still working for the colonel.
The days are flying by.
Sergey, so much changed
after you left the base.
I needed to come and see you.
I don't want
anything to change between us.
Of course.
- Thanks.
- What is it?
I am to be married
to Roman.
Roman?
Well, that's...
You're sure?
Of course.
Of course I'm sure.
That's wonderful.
I'm truly happy for you.
For both of you.
I missed you so much.
You will come to our wedding,
won't you?
- Sugar?
- Yes.
A toast to Sergey.
We are all here today thanks to you.
Na zdarovje.
- Na zdarovije.
One more?
Hey-hey! Gorko!
Gorko! Gorko!
Two, three, four,
five, six, seven!
Difficult thing to watch the one you love
swept off their feet.
I see what goes on
under my nose.
It's no consolation now but
if he'd never walked onto my base,
I do believe
she would have married you.
Thank you, Comrade Colonel.
Excuse me.
How have you been?
Fine.
How is drama school?
It's a lot better than the base.
It's like another world.
Have you got a girl?
Do you love her?
Of course.
She's given up everything
for you.
- I had to protect you.
- From what?
You know what happens to men like you.
Men... like me?
What are you, then?
I just married the woman I love.
You really believe that
if you live a lie long enough
- it'll suddenly become true?
- Sergey
you don't know anything about me.
Wait. Sergey.
Gorko!
I tried.
Sso hard
to forget you.
But I can't.
- All these months, I...
- Sergey.
- Waited.
I thought you'd come.
I couldn't.
What are you doing?
Comrade Major.
Your wife is looking for you.
Thank you, Comrade Major.
I'll be right there.
I must go, Sergey.
We could still go to Moscow together.
Nobody would have to know.
- Have that ice cream on Arbat.
- Sergey.
Luisa is
pregnant.
"You have sense enough",
said Father Zossima.
"Don't give way to drunkenness
"and incontinence of speech.
"Don't give way to sensual lust
"and to the love of money.
"And above all"
"don't lie."
"You mean about Diderot?"
"No, not about Diderot."
"Above all, don't lie to yourself."
"The man who lies to himself,"
"and listens to his own lie
comes to the point"
"that he cannot distinguish
the truth within him"
- "Daddy!
- " or around him.
"And so loses all respect for
himself and for others."
"And having no respect"
"he ceases to love."
Dinner is ready.
It won't be a holiday.
I'll be doing long hours.
You'd be alone in the city all day.
I think it would be
better for you to stay here.
But I don't want to be stuck here.
And he'll miss his daddy.
You have your family here
to help you.
Just for a few months.
- Did you think about us?
- Yes.
And?
When I finish in Moscow,
they'll promote me.
And we can finally get
a bigger apartment.
- Do I have a say in this?
- It's for the best.
Have you seen my jumper?
- Which one?
- The grey winter one.
Why do you have to go?
Serjozha, I'll see you soon.
- You are both mean.
- Serjozha...
- This one?
- Yes.
And that's why I love you.
I should just make it to the train.
See you soon.
Prison, my lord?
Denmark's a prison.
Then is the world one?
A goodly one, in which there are many
confines, wards, dungeons.
Denmark being one of the worst.
We think not so, my lord.
Why, then, 'tis none to you,
for there is nothing either good or bad
but thinking makes it so.
To me
it is a prison.
I'm going to read all his
books during the break.
That better not be all you'll be doing.
I'll make sure it won't be.
Or I'll throw his books
into the river again.
Sergey? You have a visitor.
What are you doing here?
I... came to see your play.
Did you like it?
The prince
was very good.
Thank you.
Sergey
I've been sorting out my apartment,
so I have a week off
before I start at the academy.
Why are you telling me this?
Didn't you get my letter?
How's your wife,
and your child?
Come to Sochi with me.
I have two tickets.
For the 1800 train.
You think you can just turn up
here and I'll drop my life?
What was it,
could she not join you?
Sergey.
I'll be right there, llya.
I've got to get back to my friends.
Why do you think we use
the classics to teach you?
Because the characters
of these stories
are not intellectuals.
They are living, breathing
feeling beings
whom are tender,
with tremble
in their hearts.
And I want you to catch this tremble
to your own heart and soul.
Tea?
Train 505 for Sochi is departing
now from platform two.
- He's still with that model?
- Yeah.
And she came with him to visit Luisa.
How is she?
Later, Sergey. Later.
Come on!
Roman?
I'm afraid of this dream.
Of waking up.
Of losing you.
I'm here now.
What is it?
You remember my best friend, Dima?
On his 13th birthday
my mother made him an apple pie.
He lived by the school.
I wanted him to have it
while it was still warm.
So I ran all the way.
When I arrived.
I heard shouting from inside,
and so I went around
to the window.
My letters were scattered
all over the floor.
His father had him pinned to the table.
Beating him across the back
yelling, "No son of mine
will be a fucking faggot."
I'll never forget his look
of disgust.
And then Dima looked up,
and saw me.
And I ran away.
I ran away.
He didn't come to school the next day.
There's a lake
in the forest near the village.
They found his body there
three days later.
I've never told this to anyone.
I have three rules here.
No vodka, no parties with loud music,
and no girls.
After 11.
This place is incredible.
Welcome home.
As you requested.
The sickle and the hammer.
First, it cuts off your legs
and then it smacks you in the head.
- A drink?
- Need you ask?
Look at this place.
Fighter pilots certainly
make lots of money.
Na zdarovje.
Sergey is always so serious
about it all.
He'll play Hamlet or Uncle
Vanya the rest of his life.
- Yeah, you are right.
- Nothing wrong with that.
- Matvejev. Fuel is running out.
- Coming right up.
Sergey.
Sorry.
Who'd have thought it?
Actors and pilots getting along so well.
I can't imagine it any other way.
- I knew it.
- No.
Volodja.
- Volodja.
- Get the fuck away from me.
- I knew it.
Zverev should have
investigated my report.
You?
You could have got us sent to prison.
How was I supposed to know
it was you?
Why would you do this to her?
You've ruined her life.
Volodja...
- We love each other.
- Stop. Stop it.
- We love...
- Stop it. It is not love.
It's disgusting.
You make me sick.
Fuck this.
You won't tell anyone.
Not Luisa. Not anyone.
No. That is your job.
You really think he's going to
leave her and the air force,
for you?
More Soviet volunteers arrived
in Kabul this week
to liberate the people of
Afghanistan.
The Afghani children welcomed the Soviet
soldiers with love and national dances.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
- He won't tell her.
- That's good.
Are you expecting someone?
Matvejev?
- Roman Alekseyevich?
- Yes.
Sign here.
What are you waiting for?
Sergey, please. Go and get
the rest of your stuff.
Roman, she can't come here.
- I can't tell her to go back.
- Then take her to a hotel.
She's my wife.
You're an actor. Act
like you're just visiting.
I have to pretend every fucking second
\of the day I walk out the door.
I will not do it in our home.
Just tell her it's not working.
And then what?
What then?
You'll move in with me at the base?
Hey, get to the back.
Sergey!
- It's so good to see you.
- Yes.
This is Serjozha.
- Hello.
- Hi, Serjozha.
Hi.
He's definitely got Roman's eyes.
- Hasn't he?
- Yes.
How have you been?
I was supposed to go to my
mother's for the holidays
but when Roman said that
you were coming,
I just had to stay and see you.
You are always welcome in
our home and you know it.
It's about time that you met
Serjozha too.
Let's see.
Such a big flat. Come on.
When Roma has his night flights,
Serjozha sits by the window
and stares into the night,
waiting for him to come home.
Yeah.
When Roma finishes here,
I'll start my medical school.
And he'll get a transfer.
- Yes.
Of course.
You have to be with the ones you love.
Yes.
Sergey
is there anybody special
in your life?
Him.
And you.
And dear Serjozha.
May you have all the blessings of love.
Nothing and...
And no-one
will ever replace you.
To your love.
To being with those who you truly love.
To your beautiful family.
- Thank you, Sergey.
- Thank you.
- Happy New Year.
May it be the happiest year yet.
Roman.
You belong with your family.
You always did.
I won't be the one to take you
away from your son, and from Luisa.
- Don't you dare touch me.
- Luisa, let me explain.
- Leave me alone.
- Calm down.
- Get away from me.
- Luisa!
I know now that our love
can only exist
where there is no thought
and no time.
Please
don't come looking for me.
- Did you order a long-distance call?
- Yes, I did.
- Kuznetsov.
- Captain Matvejev reporting.
Sergey.
Where did you disappear to?
Oh, I
went home to see my mother.
- Roman came looking for you.
- When?
Last month,
just before he left Moscow.
Oh, he gave me a letter for you.
I put it with your mail.
- Kuznetsov.
- Comrade Colonel.
Private Serebrennikov calling.
Serebrennikov.
It's been a long time.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
Do you know how
I might reach Captain Matvejev?
I must speak with him urgently.
Matvejev?
Didn't Luisa call you?
He left for Afghanistan
shortly after the New Year.
He was assigned to escort convoys
from the border to the compound.
Last Monday...
Sergey, we lost him.
No.
That can't be.
Sergey...
To speak and to do,
to think and to live...
They are not the same thing, Sergey.
By the time you receive this letter,
I will have left for Afghanistan.
The three days that Kuznetsov gave me
to consider are coming to an end.
But what is there to consider?
I can't choose for fear of
hurting those I love.
I can't divide myself any longer
and belong to everyone at the same time.
Come in.
Nadja, will you have lunch with us?
Why have you come here?
- Luisa, I wanted to...
- To what?
To tell me that our friendship
meant nothing to you?
To tell me that you were
sleeping with my husband?
I'm so sorry.
Tell his son that you are sorry.
I don't want to hear it.
Since you wanted
to sleep with him so badly
why don't you go and lie
next to him in his grave?
Oh, of course you don't even know
where your true love is buried.
Why would they have told you?
You're not his widow.
What were you to him?
You were nothing.
Then why did he move
to Moscow to be with me?
Stop it. Stop it, Sergey.
No.
What you felt,
and what I felt was the same thing.
My love
was no lesser than your love.
You made my life a disgrace.
- I trusted you my whole life.
- How could I have told you?
- I married him.
Don't you understand that?
Here.
Take these before you go.
I have no use for them.
Not in front of him.
- Oh.
- Oh, Luisa.
I'm so sorry,
I didn't know you had company.
I'll come by later.
Hi, Serjozha.
Did Daddy come back with you?
- No.
- But why?
We already talked about this.
Daddy's gone to live in heaven.
But why?
Because...
Because he had to.
- But when is Daddy coming back?
- Serjozha.
Get me the shoes, please.
Show me. What is this?
Sergey
I have to choose the only place
where I still feel free.
The sky.
Please
don't wait for me.
Forget me.
I shall always think of you, Sergey.
No matter what life may bring,
I will always be there with you.