- Can't you be quiet?
- We're having fun.
lf you don't like it, go back to sleep.
Mama.
Looks nice. Try the other one too.
This one.
Put it on.
Turn to me.
That looks good.
Moussa.
Moussa, hurry up. lt's time to go.
Move it, now！
You look beautiful.
Gorgeous.
Give it back!
Seydoul Seydou!
Hey, Seydou!
- What is it, mum?
- Where are you going?
- Going to play football.
- What about the Sabar?
- I told you I had a match.
- I'll come after.
Don't be late.
Okay.
Better not be late!
Don't worry.
Stop counting!
You've seen how much we have?
You count it every time!
We're almost there!
Come, they're waiting for us
at the Sabar.
Come on!
Mum.
Seydou.
You were great.
Serious?
You danced so well.
I mean it.
Really.
Mum, l have to tell you something.
Go ahead, l'm listening.
I want to leave and go work abroad.
I didn't hear you well.
What did you say?
I want to leave.
I want to work in Europe
so l can help you out.
So many made it.
They're helping their families.
I want to become someone.
I want to help
I love music.
I can realize my dream there.
I can help my sisters.
- Look where they sleep.
- The house is falling apart.
I want to help you
Enough!
Who told you this?
Who's put this idea in your head?
I don't need you to leave.
You have to stay here
and breathe the same air as me.
Leave, go become someone.
Want to you help me? Stay.
Those who made it
are not any better than me.
Don't make up crap!
Those who left
are dead in the desert
or in the middle of the sea.
Dead bodies everywhere!
Do you have any idea
of how many people died at sea?
Do you have any idea?
I was just kidding.
I'Il never go and leave you.
Seydou, you don't think.
You're so gullible.
You come and tell me
you want to leave.
Mum, it was just a joke.
Don't get all worked up, I was kidding.
Come on, mum, don't be angry.
You're my mum.
Don't be like that.
I love you.
I don't want to upset you.
Come on, give me a smile.
I don't recognize you when you pout.
You'll always be my mum.
Come on.
I love you.
Stop it.
Moussa, wait!
You're the one who put
this idea of a trip in his head?
What?
lt must be you.
Don't play dumb,
you know very well.
Yesterday, he told me he wants to leave.
Leave? No way.
I really don't think so.
Leave? Not possible.
Mum, ltold you it was a joke.
I pulled your leg and you believed me.
I know what l'm talking about.
Don't get on my nerves.
And you, stop messing with his head.
I have food, l have water, all is good.
I'm not moving from Senegal.
Leave? Never.
I told you he had nothing to do with it.
lt was a joke!
I gave birth to you, I know you.
Now go to school.
What got into you?
You know your mum.
lf she finds out, we're dead.
I said nothing,
I was just testing her.
Six months of secretly working!
What were you thinking? Six months!
I worry about her being alone.
Shut up!
You feel guilty. I do too.
But we have no choice.
I know we have no choice.
I said nothing...
Shut it!
Don't do this, I said nothing.
Let's not argue.
We're cool.
Give me a break.
OK.
Cultural heritage encompasses
all the beautiful things in the world.
Things that were created
thanks to the brilliance of human beings.
Seydou, where were you?
l've been looking for you!
You didn't see my calls?
No.
l've been waiting for hours!
You have to take my place.
I didn't look at my phone.
Hi, Mama.
Wait, we'll do something.
Did you hear what my mum said?
Did you?
"l've been looking for you.
You didn't see my calls? "
We can write a song.
Sure.
There's some wind.
l've been looking for you
You didn't see my calls
You never answer
l've been looking for you
You didn't see my calls
You never answer
Write it down.
You don't care about me
You don't give a damn
l'm nothing to you
Why do you treat me like this, baby?
I've followed you everywhere
I see you everywhere
You don't care about me
Why do you reject this love
That I feel for you?
I called you
You read my message
And you ignored me
l've been looking for you
You didn't see my calls
You never answer
You don't care about me
You don't give a damn
l'm nothing to you
You don't care about me
You don't give a damn
l'm nothing to you
Where's this Sisko?
Sure it's here?
Hello.
Are you Sisko?
What do you want?
We want information about the trip.
Who's sending you?
Some friends.
lfIwere you, I wouldn't go.
You think Europe is better than Africa.
Europe is nothing like you imagine.
What you see on TV is not real.
ln Europe, it's really cold.
There are so many people
sleeping on the streets.
ddld
What?
ln Europe, people on the streets?
- You think I'm Iying?
－ No.
He thought so.
No, we only came to get information.
We need some advice.
You'll see
mothers and children dead,
thugs, criminals, thieves.
Dead bodies on the streets.
Siblings, couples, all dead.
lf you want to die, go!
But how.
You want to die, just go!
Enough questions!
Stop asking!
But
Get out!
So when you said you wanted to leave,
it was a load of crap?
You weren't serious? djdo
Look at me.
- You're scared?
lt's not that.
Admit it.
Not at all.
Come on, say it.
So what's the point?
Yes, l'm scared.
You see?
OK.
Seydou,
you don't want to do this anymore?
Six months we've been preparing.
We did so much work
to be able to go.
And our dreams?
l'm not going without you.
Me neither.
So now what? Europe is waiting for us.
Think about your becoming a big star.
White people will be asking you
for autographs.
You'll go on stage like a real star!
What do you think? Give me a smile.
Smile.
You know I'm scared,
but I won't stay here without you.
Did you believe that nutcase?
You saw his goatee?
Yes, but
You saw what he did.
Okay.
Smile!
Come on.
You saw how he banged on the table?
He's crazy.
You heard what he said.
He was shouting …
You shit yourself?
Whatever.
Listen,
before leaving, we have to do something.
What?
Something.
Whatever you want.
Just the two of us.
You two have to go to the cemetery
and visit the ancestors.
You'll ask for permission to leave.
Then, after three days,
come back here.
But we're ready to leave now.
We're in a rush.
Three days is long.
Come back in three days.
I'll have talked with them
0e
I'll give you their answer.
Greetings, dear ancestors,
with our deepest respect.
We put ourselves entirely in your hands
for a journey we're about to make.
We want to go to Europe.
We ask for your blessing.
lt's a difficult journey.
Many people die there.
We ask you to pray for us.
Please, watch over our families.
We're leaving without telling our mums.
We know we shouldn't
keep this from them.
We ask our mums
to please forgive us
for what we're about to do.
We know it's not right.
You can leave.
Go.
lt has four legs but can't walk.
A table!
lt's high and has a lot of lines.
A power linel
Where are you going?
Listen, l'm going to take a trip. OK?
l'm not going to stay long,
I'll be back soon.
Can I come too?
lf I take you with me,
who'll stay with mum?
lf she can't find you,
she'll blame who?
You.
You see? lt'll be all my fault.
You're not leaving anymore?
Later.
Sleep.
There's a guy who makes passports.
So?
He does it for 100 dollars.
That's too much!
We have no choice.
Remove your hat.
Malick Mara.
Salif Bamba.
You are Malian from today.
But we are Senegalese.
Border patrol.
Everyone passports in hand.
Raise you head.
Hurry, ma'am.
Faster.
Passport, sir.
What's your name?
Salif Bamba.
- And you?
－ Malick Mara.
And you?
口 Malick Mara.
Where are you going?
Agadez.
Agadez?
When was the passport issued?
Two years ago.
口 Really?
You're wearing
the same clothes for two years?
You think I'm stupid?
You should go straight to prison.
50 dollars or prison? lt's your choice.
50 dollars?
Or prison, understood?
Next.
Ma'am, you're next.
Libya?
What do you mean?
I'lI take you to Libya directly
How much?
400 each. 800 total.
What do you say?
800 is too much.
Our cars are brand new, look.
Guaranteed to arrive in Tripoli.
Tripoli?
Yes.
Once there,
we'll find a way to make money.
lf we go on like this,
we won't have enough for the trip.
Do we have a choice?
Fine.
lt's illegal, we have to move quickly.
Just to Tripoli?
Even to Italy.
ltaly?
200 more. That makes 600 each.
Because you're my brothers.
What a boat!
Let's go.
Where is it?
I don't do it for everyone,
just for you.
The car over there.
The grey one?
Wait there. Got it?
Libya?
Hurry, guys!
Guys, wait here.
Take a good rest
Take a good rest.
As soon as the cars are full,
I'II come and pick you up.
Come on, guys.
Make space.
I'm warning you,
the desert is really dangerous.
Believe me, it's really bad.
We will run into rebel groups.
lf they see your money, it's gone.
The most important thing
is to hide your money.
Understood?
Some of you have hidden it
in your shoes, your clothes,
all stitched in.
That's all good
but these guys are professional.
They'll find it.
As you are my Senegalese friends,
I'm giving you some advice.
The only spot where your money
will be safe
and no one can find it,
is to put it up your ass.
I'm telling you.
lf you don't want to, good luck.
Just have to stick it up?
No, you take the money
and you roll it tightly.
You roll it in plastic wrap,
so it slides in.
Listen, l'm giving you advice.
Those who want, take it.
I have one thing to say:
it's the safest bank.
Good night, guys.
lt's me.
We're leaving tonight.
- Really?
- l swear.
- Are you sure?
Yep.
What time?
Tonight, don't know the time.
Moussa, is this nice?
Take it.
Let me see.
Looks good?
How much?
Twenty.
Your turn next.
Me? ldon't think so.
Got in?
Easy, easy.
Let me help.
Someone felllStop!
Stop!
I told you to hold on tight.
Shut up!
Shut it!
Shut itl
Get down.
AII of you.
Follow him.
Follow him!
You take all our money and you leave us
in the middle of the desert.
Why are you doing this?
口 Thug!
We're not even in Libya
and you're abandoning us.
I have a child with me,
what am I supposed to do?
Help mel Help mel
Help, l can't anymore!
Help!
lcan't.
Let's go!
Ma'am, get up, let's go.
Ma'am, stand up.
Have you lost your mind?
The guide is leaving.
lf we lose him,
we'll die in the desert for sure!
We're losing him!
Get up.
Slowly.
My son, you've come back.
Moussa, wait, we're coming!
Coming.
What is it?
Let's go
Drink.
Stop!
Police!
On the ground!
Hey, you!
Get up!
Where's your money?
We're in Libyal
Give us your money or it's jail!
Get up!
On your feet!
Where did you hide your money?
I have no money.
No money?
Where's the money?
We'll see if it's in your ass.
Drink this!
Drink!
Drink up!
Come on, drink!
There's nothing here.
Go.
Here neither.
- Nothing.
Go!
Nothing here.
Look at this.
You tried to cheat us.
You cheated us!
You're coming with me! To prison!
Get in!
Please, take me too.
I don't want to stay alone.
Nationality?
Group 2, quick!
Where are you from?
Congo.
Group 3, quickl
Where are you from?
－ Senegal.
Group 3.
Move quickly!
Where are you from?
Cameroon? Group 2.
I'm your middleman.
I speak your language.
l'm here to help you.
Do you know where you are?
You're in prison.
The people you see here
are not police nor military.
They're really dangerous.
They're the Libyan mafia.
Everything they ask you to do, do it.
lf you don't, they'll harm you.
Even worse, they could kill you.
What you have to do
is to call your parents back home
and ask them to send you money.
800 dollars, not much
to save your life.
Call them.
We can fix this and you'll be free.
l'm telling you this
and I'll give you time
to think about it.
I'll give you some time.
You'll think about it
and find a solution.
Hurry!
Come on!
You know where you are?
ln a torture room.
Because they refused to give a number.
One thing is sure,
if you don't give a number,
the same will happen to you.
lf they don't give me a number,
I'II kill them.
Got it? With no number, you're dead.
Look at those bodies,
your brothers are dead
because of a number.
Give a number
and walk away from torture.
Either way, you'll end up giving it.
You have a number, you give it.
You have a number?
See? Do like him.
Who else?
Bravo!
That's good.
Come on.
Nabil!
They have numbers.
These three.
Go ahead.
Who else has a number?
Who?
Do like your brothers.
Guys, avoid all this.
Give the number and call home.
I'lI call for you.
You don't have a number?
No one?
l'm really sorry.
Nabil.
They don't have a number.
Come on!
You, come here.
What is it?
l'm scared I won't see my mum again.
I want to see her
to ask her to forgive me
for secretly leaving.
I want her to know that I'm alive,
I'm not dead.
Tell her that I miss her.
I miss her.
So much.
I want her to forgive me.
Malaika!
Come here.
I'II give you a message
to take to Seydou's mum.
Go to her,
tell her that Seydou is alive and well,
and asks for forgiveness.
Tell her that he misses her a lot.
Remember.
He'll tell her.
Can I go with him?
No.
Please, l want to see my mum.
OK, you can go with him.
But only you will see her,
she won't see you.
Mum.
Give me some water.
Hey...
You'll be fine.
Make some space for him to stretch.
Wake up!
l need people.
I need a carpenter.
Who's a carpenter?
Are you sure?
lf not, you'll die.
Go!
Quick, get up!
Hurry!
We have no time to waste!
I need a builder.
Builder!
Are you sure?
Sure?
Move it!
No one else?
How much for this one?
600 dinars, he's strong.
Ok, l'll take him.
Come on.
We work together.
I'lI cut you a deal if you take both.
500 each.
That works.
Here's the house.
You're going to build a solid wall
all around the house, OK?
You'll sleep here.
There's food.
And after, work.
Here's my family.
ls that you?
Yes.
That's my daughter.
the eldest, she's 19.
That's the second, she's 18.
That's my son, he's 16.
And their mum's here.
－ She's beautiful.
Thanks.
How old are you?
16.
Like my boy.
Did your dad know you were leaving?
My dad died.
May he rest in peace.
And your mum?
No, I left with my cousin
without telling her.
Where's your cousin?
They caught him
when we were in the desert.
I'm sure we'll find him.
Of course.
You've done a good job.
The boss is happy with you.
There's something else.
The boss wants a fountain Iike this one.
Can you build it?
Yes, lcan do it.
Like this one?
Even better.
Are you sure?
Yes.
lf you make it as good as this one
and the boss likes it,
he'll free you
and pay for your trip to Tripoli.
OK?
Back to work.
You can see how it works.
See, we've built it
in the shape of an octagon.
We used these splendid tiles.
The foundation comes from abroad.
Shall we see how it works?
Hi, have you seen
a Senegalese named Moussa?
Thanks.
Have you seen a Senegalese named Moussa?
No, l don't know him.
A Senegalese?
Yes, his name is Moussa.
You should ask there.
Seydou!
Comel
He speaks Wolof.
How are you?
Have you seen
a Senegalese kid called Moussa?
No, Idon't know.
Go ask there.
There's a Senegalese community.
Where?
See the house behind the tree?
Ask them, Moussa could be there.
He says there's
a Senegalese community over there.
Let's go. Thanks.
No, wait.
I have to leave.
I can't stay with you.
Leave already?
Yes, lhave to.
Sure you don't want to come with me?
l can't.
I can't leave my cousin here.
We left together,
we have to finish the trip together.
OK, if you succeed in doing it,
you know where to find me.
I'II be in Caserta, near Naples.
You saved my life.
Thank you.
You're really strong.
Keep your courage.
Don't ever lose it.
When we meet again,
we'll make plenty of great fountains!
God willing.
Thanks.
Go find him.
Do you know a guy named Moussa?
Moussa? Don't know him.
Sorry.
Boy.
Boy!
Yes?
Maybe he got here,
didn't find you and then left?
lt's not possible.
We left together.
I know he'd never go without me.
Then go check
the other Senegalese shelters
There are more?
Yes.
There's even one close by.
You may find him there.
lt's not far.
口 Right behind?
Yes.
Thank you so much.
Boy, come here.
lf you don't find him, come back here,
I'lI give you a place to stay.
But I have no money.
No problem. You'll pay me when you can.
Thank you.
Moussa?
Try over by the ironworkers.
There are many Senegalese there.
lronworkers? Where's that?
口 Straight ahead.
口 This way?
Do you know a Moussa?
More or less my height.
l don't.
There's a Senegalese over there.
lbrahim?
Yes.
Do you know a Senegalese guy
named Moussa?
No, l'm sorry.
How can I find him?
Search everywhere.
Be careful on the streets.
I hope you find him.
The Nigerians who work with me
say a Senegalese has just arrived.
Maybe it's your cousin.
口 Really?
Yes!
Where?
lt's me, Seydou.
lt's me.
I was sure I would find you.
So sure.
lt's me, Seydou.
You don't recognize me? lt's me.
I knew I'd find you again.
Here I am.
Let's go.
What is it?
What's wrong?
I was shot.
They shot you?
I escaped from prison and they shot me.
My leg.
How did they shoot you?
Let's go to the hospital.
Get up, let's go.
Let's return to Senegal.
You know they won't let me in
at the hospital.
Then what?
I want to go back home.
Why go back?
They'll cut my leg.
No!
l'd prefer to die in Senegal.
You won't die.
l'm here.
Europe is so close, we're almost there.
We're so close to Europe.
You were right
when you said we shouldn't go.
Don't say that.
We shouldn't have left.
You're a man.
Be strong and get over this.
Remember you said
we'd sign autographs for the whites?
Come on, let's go.
Go?
You really want to go back to Senegal?
Sure you want to go home?
After all we went through in the desert?
We went through hell!
How would you cross the desert
with this leg? lmpossible.
You convinced me to leave.
Remember?
Stop this. Let's go.
Europe is waiting for us.
You and me.
Let's realize our dream.
What do you think?
Come on, get up.
Let's go.
lt's hurting me.
We'll go slowly.
You're strong.
We'll get through it.
When did it happen?
Three days ago
Three days?
You re lucky the bullet passed through.
lt didn't touch the bone.
lt could have been much worse.
I know it's painful.
Can you sleep?
No, l can't.
Will they amputate?
No, don't worry.
You have to get him
medication right away.
Disinfectant,
antibiotics and painkillers.
I'll give him an injection
to stop the infection.
I'II get all this at a pharmacy?
A pharmacy? No.
Go to the market
and ask for the barber, Samir.
Tell him I sent you.
Samir?
Don't touch, your hands are dirty.
I wasn't touching.
lt's perfect.
You OK?
Seydou, can I speak to you a moment?
- Take care, Moussa.
Thank you.
I got the leg under control.
I did my best,
but you have to take him to hospital
as soon as possible.
They need to do an X- ray
and then operate.
I don't have the instruments.
There's nothing else I can do.
His only hope is to get to hospital.
But how? They don't admit blacks.
I know, but there's no other option.
lt's the only solution.
You have to take him.
How much time do we have?
No time left, ten days at most.
Otherwise, he's risking losing his leg.
Believe me, it's a huge risk.
He may even die.
－ Seriously?
Of course.
lt's him.
Sit down.
What's your name?
Seydou.
lt's not even enough for one person.
That's all I have.
That's it?
Here. Come back when you have enough.
Please, help me.
That's all I have
and my cousin is injured.
We really have to leave.
How old are you?
16.
·16?
Yes.
Do you think it can work?
Listen, l have a solution.
lf you pilot the boat
you can both leave
for the price of one.
- The boat?
- Yes.
- l've never done that.
- I don't even know how to swim.
No problem. I'll show you.
- Very easy.
- ln one day, you'll be in ltaly.
- ln one day, we'll be in ltaly?
- Just one day.
You just go straight ahead.
And as you're a minor,
if the police catch you, you don't risk much.
But it's not sure they'll catch me?
No. When you see the police,
stay away from the cabin.
There won't be a problem.
- lt's easy?
- Very easy.
I don't have time.
lf you two want to leave.
it's the only way.
Or I'll find someone else.
OK.
Great.
Hey!
We're going!
Where?
Europe is waiting for us.
How?
We're leaving for ltaly.
There I can take you to hospital
and fix your leg.
Then we'll call our mums
to tell them we're fine.
Everything will be fine.
口 Where did you get the money?
That's not a problem.
We didn't have enough.
So, they're having me drive the boat.
Can you imagine?
Excuse me, but you can't even swim.
Who cares?
Just got to hold the wheel straight
and we'll be in ltaly!
I can even speak ltalian!
I can also say that!
Hurry up!
ZUARA, LIBYA
Come in quicklyl
I have to take them all?
Maybe there are other boats.
Get over here!
Come.
I'll show you.
That's the gear.
Faster up, slower down.
That's for moving forward and backwards.
You go forward, you go back.
Got it?
Yes.
That's the compass.
ln the middle of the sea,
sometimes the current
will make the boat turn.
So you have to stay on course,
always going north. Stay on zero.
Zero is north. Straight ahead.
Got it?
Sometimes, waves get really big...
You understand?
When they're big, you have to face them.
Not on the side.
When the waves are big,
you take them on directly.
Don't move to the side. Understood?
So we go with the waves?
No, in general the sea is calm.
But you never know.
Normally, there's no problem. OK?
Here's the GPS.
lf you're in trouble, call this number.
Just call.
The boat is not good?
Yes, it's good.
But you never know. lf ever there's
an issue with the engine, whatever.
You call this number
and we can help.
lt's good? Got it?
Yes.
Now, the most important thing:
the engine.
What's up?
You have to find someone
to take my place.
I can't drive that big boat.
What do you mean?
I showed you. lt's really easy.
Just straight ahead.
I taught you how to drive it.
What's the problem?
I can't be responsible
for so many people.
l'm scared.
Why are you scared?
There are so many people,
so many lives.
There are children.
There are women.
I showed you how to drive it,
you agreed.
Now do it and shut up.
I'm scared to kill people.
Find someone with experience.
I have no experience.
I don't care. You're doing it.
Stop wasting my time.
You're driving the boat!
Take him away!
I'm scared I'll kill.
Doesn't it feel like the sea is rising?
What?
You don't see the waves?
They're higher.
lf water hits the engine, we're dead.
I don't think they've changed.
They weren't like this. They're bigger.
I don't see it.
No.
See the lights?
Where?
Here.
Look, we're here.
We did it.
We're in Italy?
Definitely.
Can you believe it? We made it.
We did it!
ln just five hours.
But I can't see the shore.
What do you mean?
Look, there's no land.
That must be the port.
The city must be behind.
Land is surely behind.
That's just the port.
I don't see a city, there's no land.
What makes you say
there's something behind?
What's that?
I've no idea.
For sure it's not Italy.
Move over.
Ma'am, drink.
Ma'am, be strong.
We'll get there.
Be strong.
You'll have your baby, safe and sound.
You won't die.
Okay? You won't die.
I'II call for help.
Okay?
On the boat,
there are people who are really sick.
And there are kids and women.
Okay, there are women on board?
Yes, there are women
and I can't keep going
because there's a pregnant woman.
lf I keep going,
she'll get banged about,
she's bleeding.
She'll lose the baby.
There's a pregnant woman who's bleeding?
Yes, she's bleeding.
l understand.
You gave me your coordinates
and your GPS position.
I'lI call for help now,
I'II call the coastguard.
Thank you.
Listen to me, this is important.
lt will take time.
What? !
lt'll take time,
I'II call them immediately.
Please, help us.
I have your position,
I'lI forward it to them right now.
I'II call them immediately.
Hurry or that woman will die!
But I'm telling you, I need help.
OK, understood.
l'm calling the Maltese coastguards.
No answer.
I also tried the ltalian coastguards.
But they said you were not
in their territorial waters.
They said I should keep calling
the Maltese guards.
l've been waiting for hours.
You don't want to come?
l've been calling for hours too,
but there's no answer.
I'm really sorry.
Please, l'm scared
someone's going to die.
OK, I'II try again.
l know you don't want to come.
You want to let us die here,
in the middle of the sea.
OK, I'II take responsibility.
I'll get them to ltaly
and no one will die.
They'll all arrive safe and sound.
Does it hurt?
People are sick in the engine room.
ln the engine room?
Yes, there are people there.
How's that possible?
Take over.
There's no one left.
Give me waterl
More water!
Sit down!
Calm downl
Don't you see
what you're doing could kill her?
Calm downl You're men!
You're men, dammitl
We'll get there.
No one will die, no onel
No one will die!
We are with Allah, no one will die.
Allah is greatl
Allah is great!
God is with us.
Look, land!
We're there!
I'm the captain!
I did it!
l did it!
I saved everyone!
No one died, no one!
MOROCCO