LOVELESS
Guys, wait for me!
Okay, see you.
People are here
to look at the apartment. Tidy up.
Good evening. Come in.
- I'll get out the shoe covers.
- Don't worry about it.
It's a nice neighborhood, with clean air.
We'll soon have a subway station,
and there's a shopping center nearby.
- They just built a church over there.
- That's nice.
- How are the neighbors?
- Quiet.
- Why sell?
- We're divorcing.
- Sorry to hear that.
- No worries.
- What's down here?
- The bathroom.
And toilet.
- And this?
- The bedroom.
- How many square meters?
- Eighteen.
- And this?
- The living room.
- How many square meters?
- Twenty-five.
- Twenty-five?
- That's right.
What's next?
Here's the kid's room.
- Say "hello!"
- Hello.
Twelve years old, and still no manners.
- Relax. The man's growing.
- Yeah, some man.
Constantly crying.
- Mom!
- Don't start whining.
Remind me
how many square meters total.
- Eighty-five-point-four square meters.
- I see.
Hi.
Relaxing?
What do you care?
I don't.
So did they come today?
They said they'd think about it.
I see.
And have you thought about it?
About what?
You know what?
You're the mother.
I'm so sick of you.
He needs his mother more.
At his age, he needs his father more.
Although maybe not one like you.
He likes summer camp.
He'll like boarding school too.
And after that, the army.
Let him get used to it.
What did you expect? Same as always?
You fuck everything up,
and I clean up the mess?
No, it won't be like that.
I'm moving on too.
- Heard of equal rights?
- They'll pester us.
Who will? You're one to talk.
Social workers, I don't know.
Child psychologists...
Fucking ombudsmen.
So you take him, and don't sweat it.
You'll have it worse. You're the mother.
Oh, so you're concerned about me?
Thanks a bunch.
Social workers...
...they'll be overjoyed.
Rescuing a babe from a house fire.
No matter,
the house and family burned to ash.
A triumph for the ombudsman.
Should we talk to your mother again?
Go talk to your own, at a séance.
I'm done talking to mine, thanks.
Not to mention, Beardy will find out.
So that's what this is about.
And like an idiot, I thought
you were worried about the kid.
Hey, wouldn't it be fun
if you got booted from your precious job?
For sending your kid to an orphanage.
Not so Christian, huh?
Beardy won't approve.
Then what? That would be a laugh.
- Enough.
- Oh, gosh.
Aren't you tough?
What?
What are you looking at?
Yeah, grit those teeth.
- I've fucking had it with you.
- Scumbag.
- When will we tell him?
- We? Who's this "we"?
You'll tell him!
Anytime you want.
Why not wake him up now?
Go on. Off you go.
Scumbag!
Not another word about this.
Not another word, period.
Just seeing you makes me sick.
Move out already! I can't stand this.
If you're being cheap,
I can pay for your shit to be removed.
Fuck off already!
- You're a waste of space!
- This is my home too!
It's half your home. You'll get your share!
Damnit.
Fuck's sake.
Piece of shit.
I don't want any more.
Finish it. Am I supposed to throw it away?
Drink your hot chocolate.
What's up with you? Are you sick?
I'm fine.
Okay, leave it. I'll clean up.
- How about a "thank you"?
- Thank you.
The governor and press committee
are under pressure:
"To take steps to counteract the media's
incitement of public hysteria."
And here comes the best part:
"To consider legislation to restrict
the spread of apocalyptic propaganda."
According to the 9th-century
Mayan calendar...
...the end of the world,
Leningrad Region included...
...is scheduled for December 21st...
...the day after the widely observed
Security Agency Workers' Day.
Deputy Gorchishnikov believes that
apocalyptic sentiments are on the rise...
...while reporters in pursuit
of high ratings are responsible for:
"Misinformation
to whip up public hysteria."
Now that it's fall,
and depression in the city is rife...
...the end of days may propel some
of Pushkin's and Putin's countrymen...
...to seek solace in drugs and alcohol...
...and others towards more radical acts,
such as crime and suicide.
Excuse me.
Fifth floor, please.
Thanks.
Hi.
Hey.
- Here's your borscht.
- Thanks.
I'll have the same.
Thanks.
Bon appétit.
- Hello.
Two hundred and fifteen rubles, please.
Hey, if an employee's
marital status changes...
...do they find out at the top?
Sooner or later.
It would come up at some
team-building exercise or office party.
Everyone's expected
to have family and kids.
- Why do you ask?
- Just curious.
In all the time I've been here,
I don't remember a single divorce.
Well, that's our corporate policy.
As you well know.
People only part due to natural causes,
like death and stuff like that.
And what, nobody has ever divorced?
At the company's last New Year party...
...one of the programmers brought
a bogus wife with two daughters.
No way.
He had divorced his actual wife.
So that's how he saved his hide.
No idea where he found them, though.
Maybe he hired them.
Seems like he got away with it.
He's still here.
- Or maybe he remarried.
- I see.
So if you divorce and remarry quick,
maybe nobody would notice.
- If you have no close friends here.
- I don't.
- Then it's nobody's business.
- Right.
How do you know this programmer?
First of all...
...he's not a programmer.
I said that to protect him.
He's from a different department.
Don't ask me which one.
Secondly...
...I heard it from him directly.
You understand.
Actually, we haven't talked for a while.
Too busy.
Just greet each other from afar.
But this stays between us, okay?
But of course. Like confession.
Do you think the world is about to end?
Definitely.
Can you help out with work?
Got any leads?
The Lord taught us to share.
I may have some by the end of the day.
You know I'll make it worth your while.
- He's a nervous wreck.
- Good.
- He's suffering, poor thing.
- They mess up, but don't clean up.
And is he worried about his son?
Yeah, right.
He has loans.
Now he's scared of being sacked.
His boss is a hardcore Christian,
you see.
A fundamentalist?
With a big bushy beard and Brioni suit.
- A glamorous type.
- I'll say.
It's Russian Orthodox Sharia Law there.
They only hire family people
who have been baptized.
We went on a pilgrimage
for our vacation.
Yeah, I remember.
Sounds kind of fun. Exotic.
I was bored to death.
- Straighten your leg.
- It pays well, though.
Now I see he's properly scared.
- They'd seriously fire him?
- Hell if I know. I hope so.
What about child support?
What the hell?
Almost done. Relax.
A friend of mine told me
that her boss is into extreme sports.
- For real?
- Yes.
So he makes his staff go skydiving,
rafting, skiing...
- Skiing is fun.
- I don't know about that.
My friend broke her kneecap
and spent half a year in a cast.
- Goodbye, tendons.
- Damn.
Some of them bought fake doctor's notes
online to get out of it.
And?
He fired them, saying,
"If you're ill, go to hospital."
Crazy.
So prayers and pilgrimages
aren't so bad. Turn over.
Well, I don't know.
A vacation should be sun and sea...
...at an all-inclusive hotel.
- And what does your new guy think?
- He's fine with it all.
He's pretty forward-thinking.
Well, he's got money and his health.
- Why not move forward?
- Knock on wood.
Don't worry, I won't jinx you.
No, I'm not superstitious.
Is he divorced? Any kids?
Divorced three years ago.
Has a grown-up daughter.
She's studying in Portugal.
Works there too.
- How old is he?
- Forty-seven.
He looks great.
He does tai chi, doesn't smoke
and barely drinks.
I'm jealous.
- You want it trimmed a bit?
- Yes, a little bit.
- How does he get on with your boy?
- He doesn't.
I think that boy hates me.
Just like his father.
He's even beginning to smell like him.
Sure, he's hitting puberty.
Want him to stay your little angel?
He only looks like an angel.
He's prickly as hell.
Almost tore me apart at birth.
He wouldn't come out.
Took almost 24 hours.
Yeah, such is our lot.
My little cow.
I look at her, and sad to say,
she's just like her dad.
I hope he's drunk himself to death.
Look.
She doesn't drink, fortunately.
I told her I'd kill her if she did.
It's her temperament.
It's not even his,
but his bitch of a mother's.
- How old is your daughter again?
- Nineteen. And a total idiot.
I mean, she's smart-assed
her school exams.
And that's it. She's done with learning.
Just off cavorting somewhere.
I tell her, "If you get pregnant,
your life's over. I won't help."
- She says she's careful.
- Well, that's something.
She just has no plan at all.
No vocation, no ambition.
She says she wants to be a politician.
I tell her, "Then study while you can."
She says you don't need to study for that.
- She's smart, your girl.
- She gets that from me.
- Yes?
- Zhenya, can you come down?
Why won't you tell me anything?
Meaning?
Did the buyers like the apartment?
They said they'd think about it.
Masha, if there were any news,
I'd tell you right away.
Why is it taking so long to sell?
You work in sales after all.
You understand, it's not the same thing.
No, I don't understand.
Leave the dumplings.
Mom said no dumplings.
Is she home today?
No, she went to see my aunt.
I'm a little tired of her too.
- We have the place to ourselves.
- Thank God.
Don't say that. She's my mom.
Grab some broccoli.
Boris.
Wait.
We'll be fine, won't we?
You won't leave us?
What?
Masha.
Are you crazy?
Where's this coming from?
I just get so scared sometimes.
Hey, I'm here.
I bet that's what you told your ex-wife.
With you, it's totally different.
I've never felt this good with anyone.
How many others have there been?
More than 10?
I'm hungry. You?
Now I'm hungry all the time.
- I'm a little mad at you.
- I'll make something to eat.
Bring me an apple.
Catch.
Steamed chicken with broccoli?
I don't want that.
- I want a vegetable salad.
- And a vegetable salad too.
Dream of having a tooth pulled out.
What does it mean?
- Hi.
You're early.
I expected you later. I barely got away.
The girls didn't want to let me go.
The salon is packed today.
Where are we going?
Why so quiet? Tell me your plan!
Hey, let's buy a watermelon on the way.
Hey.
I'd love to get your number.
Eight, nine hundred...?
Twenty-five, 160, 78, 88.
- What's your name?
- Sofia.
I can't eat when you look at me that way.
Sorry.
Just kidding.
Did you cut your hair?
- You noticed?
- Of course.
I love studying you.
Still?
After all that we've been through?
Especially after that.
After what happened two days ago?
Or three days ago?
Zhenya...
What?
What is it?
Anything wrong?
Right, girls, let's drink to love!
To love!
Love? Please!
Let's take a selfie.
- Sure!
- Here's to love and selfies.
Hey.
Are you asleep?
Not fair.
I love you.
You hear me?
I've never loved anyone.
Only my mom when I was little.
And she was such an idiot.
Never cuddled me,
never said anything nice.
Nothing but rules, discipline, school...
Just a bitter and lonely old battle-ax.
I hope she's alive and well?
Yes, she's alive...
...and basically well.
We don't talk much.
Every time I call, we fight.
I never even know how it gets started.
It's with you
that I finally realized what love is.
I never loved my husband.
He was my first.
I got pregnant out of stupidity.
He was overjoyed.
Asked me to marry him.
It all seemed fine. We were together.
But I didn't want it.
I was so scared.
Scared of getting an abortion,
and scared of keeping it.
I really didn't want that child.
I thought I'd die giving birth.
They had to resuscitate me.
Later, when they brought him to me...
...I was barely able to look at him.
I was repulsed.
I wasn't even producing milk.
But things gradually settled.
A kind of normal life began.
A kind of...
Lovelessness.
You cannot live in that state.
To this day, when I see him,
or think of how things are...
...I feel like I made some terrible mistake.
I blame him, and I blame myself.
I so want to be happy.
I'm a monster, aren't I?
Certainly.
The most wonderful monster in the world.
Do you really love me?
Come to me.
Just a second.
Hello?
Did you see Alexey last night?
No, I wasn't at the apartment. Why?
The school just called.
He hasn't been there for two days.
What do you mean?
Who called?
His teacher.
His teacher? And what did she say?
That he's not been there in two days.
Are you deaf?
- Did he come home?
- I don't know.
I came back late. I thought he was in bed.
I woke up late,
thinking he had already left, as usual.
He won't answer his phone.
Did he call you?
No.
Oh, Lord...
Don't panic. He'll turn up.
We should call that friend of his.
I already did. He hasn't seen him either.
Okay.
- Where are you now?
- At home.
You can't fucking tell if he's been there?
No, I fucking can't!
Why not? It should be obvious.
Then get over here, and work it out!
I'm at work, in case you forgot.
He's missing for over a day.
Don't you get it?
He may be on his way home
as we speak.
I think you're overreacting.
He probably did something,
and thinks you'll get mad...
...so is staying away.
So it's my fault again, right?
You don't even know
whether he was home recently.
And he probably was.
Hello?
Here's what I'll do.
I'm calling the police.
You can sit at work, speculating
on what may have happened, got it?
Useless idiot!
So, Dasha,
one office worker asks another:
"What kind of car do you drive?"
"A Volkswagen Passat."
"Well, I have a Volkswagen Credit."
Hilarious.
- Hey, so one office worker...
- Yes, Sergey, I heard you.
It's funny.
I'm done.
Okay, thanks.
Take this.
Wait for me in the car.
We'll try one more place.
Okay.
Well, I can say
that there's no hint of foul play.
What do you mean, "foul play"?
You know how it is.
The parents kill the child,
and then report him missing.
You thought that about me?
We always check that angle first.
But this looks like a standard runaway.
He's 12.
A rebellious age, lots of hormones.
He'll run around for a few days
and come back.
Of course, we can go to the station
and spend a few hours questioning you.
But not today, I guess.
Not least because
your husband should be there too.
But I don't think it will come to that.
You say there's no foul play.
But what if he's been kidnapped?
Because I can't imagine
where he might be.
I'm sure he's knocking around nearby.
He won't stay away long.
We all enjoy comfort,
and your home has that.
You should see the dumps kids return to.
Even the shittiest home beats the streets.
As for possible kidnapping,
it goes like this:
First, we examine the situation.
This includes questioning relatives,
friends and possible eyewitnesses.
We have limited resources
and many other matters.
Theft, murder, armed robbery...
So that stage may take a few days.
If the kid hasn't come back by then...
...we start searching for him.
If we obtain evidence indicating
possible murder or kidnapping...
...then we open a criminal case
for the Investigation Committee.
So you see how long
this process may take.
The paperwork alone...
In that time, they can return
and run away again.
So you won't do anything?
Now, look, I'm just telling you how it is.
We'll handle this case.
But here, we lack the means
of chasing each runaway.
I get it.
This will just be filed away.
What am I supposed to do?
Sit around and wait?
- What if he doesn't return?
- The stats are on your side.
In virtually all cases, runaways come
back within seven to 10 days.
What can I recommend?
If you really want someone
to look for him, go online...
...and contact
the Search and Rescue Team.
Call them, and they'll tell you
what info they need.
They're volunteers.
It's not a state service.
They work 24 hours, for free,
with no bureaucracy.
They have well-developed
and highly effective methods.
I know this because I worked with them,
and we got results.
Right, here's my card.
I already have your number.
We'll be in touch.
- That's it?
- For now, yes.
- Unbelievable.
- Now listen here.
Another cop would have been tougher
with you and less informative.
Not because I'm such a good guy.
I'm just saving everyone time.
The sooner you contact the volunteers,
the sooner they'll find that dolt...
...who's loitering in some street
or shopping mall.
He's probably with a friend
whose parents left town for a bit.
So contact them.
Or just wait. It's up to you.
Money paid by candidates
for the opposition council was stolen.
According to the prosecutor's website,
over 600,000 rubles was taken...
...by the creators
of the Electoral Committee's website...
...where candidates and voters register.
Boris Nemtsov called it
a government provocation...
...planned to disrupt voting
for the opposition council.
New York State Police have detained
U.S. presidential candidate Jill Stein...
...and her running mate, Cheri Honkala.
The two were denied access
to the Obama-Romney debate...
...given the Green Party's position
on presidential debates...
When did you two last speak
on the phone?
I took him to school, and that was it.
- Hello.
Sorry, traffic was bad.
Take a seat, I'll fill you in. I'm Ivan.
- I'm a coordinator here.
- Yes, my wife told me on the phone.
Great, then let's get started,
or rather, continue.
I'll tell you our plan,
to give you an overview.
I'll ask you questions about your son...
...while others will interview neighbors
and possible witnesses...
...at any locations
he may have been. Yes, Lena?
- Nothing from the neighbors.
- At all?
No one saw or heard him,
either yesterday or today.
- The rest of the team is here.
- Okay.
- They brought the flyers.
- Great, well-done.
- I'll keep asking around.
- Yes, carry on.
So...
...depending on what info we get,
we'll focus on particular sites.
You and I will go to the police station.
The detective there promised
to get us CCTV footage.
That's vital, and may be a huge help.
Also, it'll be dark soon.
The boy needs a place to sleep.
It's cold out.
We'll search for him
in apartment buildings.
Hopefully, we'll get access codes
from the detective.
Okay, let's start from the beginning.
"Alexey Sleptsov, 12 years old...
...about 150 cm tall...
...healthy, without any
distinguishing features, blond hair.
Was wearing blue jeans, red jacket
with a hood, and blue sneakers.
He had with him a blue school rucksack.
Yesterday, he left for school,
and it seems, hasn't been back since."
His phone is off, or has no signal,
but we keep calling him.
Onwards.
What is the boy interested in?
Any hobbies or favorite sports?
Dreams of building a spaceport
or traveling the world?
No, he has no hobbies
and doesn't play sports.
I think he just sits at home.
You "think"? I see.
So he's on a computer.
- He has a laptop?
- Yes.
- We try to limit his use.
- You, especially.
- Leave the arguing for later, okay?
- Yes, of course.
- Is his laptop accessible?
- Yes.
Access to his e-mail,
social accounts and friends' numbers?
He only has one friend:
Kuznetsov, I think.
Again, you "think"? Okay, fine.
I have all of his passwords.
Kuznetsov really is his only friend.
I mean, in real life.
As for online...
Okay, I understand.
Any close relatives
to whom he may have gone:
Grandparents, uncles, aunts, cousins?
There's only my mother,
who lives near Moscow.
I doubt the squirt would go there.
"The squirt"? I see.
I assume you called her
to confirm he wasn't there?
Can't reach her.
We're not on great terms.
What do you mean by that?
Her phone has been off,
although it could be the signal.
The signal is fine. She's the problem.
So Grandma's a strong type.
- Call her neighbors?
- I don't have their numbers.
It's her home, her neighbors.
Better not to meddle there.
Could she be hiding Alexey?
Say, if he asked her to?
I don't think so.
That Stalin-in-a-skirt could do anything.
Enough!
How would he even get there?
- Maybe they were talking in secret.
- She doesn't like him.
Like that matters.
She uses him against me.
You must pay Grandma
a visit right away.
- Where exactly does she live?
- A small house.
It's off the Kiev highway. Hard to explain.
There's an unmarked turnoff.
- You have a car?
- Yes.
- How long is the journey?
- About three hours.
Okay, give me the contacts
of his friends and acquaintances...
...and his teacher's number.
- I hope you have it.
- We do.
Great. And all his passwords.
I'll take his laptop to be inspected.
Then we'll decide what to do next.
So...
Is this the teacher's number? Okay.
As for you, get in the car...
...and go see lovely Grandma.
Lena will also go.
She's highly experienced.
She'll follow you in her car.
Along the way,
keep trying to call Grandma.
When you're there, look carefully.
Then call me, whether he's there or not.
- Got it?
- Yes.
Sure?
Questions?
Someone will watch the apartment,
in case he comes back.
Well?
Right, on with the song.
For fuck's sake.
- Turn it off. I have a headache.
- We have aspirin.
Just turn it off. Please.
- Do you think he's there?
- Where else would he be?
What a fucking pain.
Great fucking timing.
- What if something happened?
- Let's not even go there.
He's fine.
And he's in for an ass-kicking.
You can't smoke here.
Pardon me. I'll smoke out of the window.
I said, don't.
Or what? You gonna leave me
on the side of the road?
Headache's gone, eh?
Roll up the windows.
Roll up the windows!
Scumbag!
Roll up the fucking windows!
An encroaching Arctic front will lead
to the weather worsening.
Tomorrow we can expect
low temperatures and heavy snow.
Damn, they put up a gate.
Now what do we do? Ram it?
- Probably barricaded herself in.
- Quit it.
- Can we enter some other way?
- Only by climbing the fence.
We don't have keys.
I see.
Where is she going?
Thanks.
Mom!
Mom, open up! It's me!
She's in there.
Mom, open up! Alexey has gone missing!
For God's sake...
Almost had a heart attack.
Calling in the middle of the night,
like there's a fire...
...then they climb the fence!
May God help me.
I'll go insane.
And I can't find my phone.
How am I to call for help?
- You could have warned me!
- I called enough times!
- Don't say you didn't hear.
- I swear!
- You switched it off.
- I told you, I probably lost it!
It's been gone all day,
but to hell with that.
Instead, my dear, tell me:
What made you think your son was here?
- He's not here and never was.
- We'll check everywhere.
Where's that damn prick of yours?
Lord forgive me.
You mentioned a divorce.
You're God and the devil rolled into one.
What?
What's that supposed to mean?
Huh, what are you saying?
Have you totally lost it?
Think you're so clever?
Don't look away from your mother.
Have some respect!
If you don't like it,
get out, and good riddance.
I didn't invite you!
What a mess.
You were a mistake.
Look what you've become.
- What?
- A whore is what!
- Mom...
- Don't "Mom" me!
Want a tit? Here!
Whining for Mom.
You done snooping around?
Didn't find him?
You're losing it.
Looks like the battery's dead.
Of course. Where was it?
It was under your bed.
Must have fallen.
Thank God it's not lost.
How about some tea?
I don't have anything sweet
to go with it, mind you.
- That's okay, Mom. We'll go.
- Well, aren't we polite?
You two sure don't seem too worried.
Alexey is missing, you say.
I bet you made it up
to try to melt my heart.
Dream on.
I can see through your tricks.
You said you were getting divorced.
Plan to stick me with your spawn?
Never going to happen.
I'll say it again: I will not babysit him.
Do you interact with anyone?
When you got pregnant,
I warned you to come to your senses!
Remember you told me
to go to hell? I do.
I told you that you'd crawl back to me
only when it's too late.
You made your bed, you lie in it.
Let that be a lesson to you.
Mom, why make a scene?
Someone else is also here.
Don't you lecture me.
I don't care. I'm at home, you know.
Trying to make a fool out of me.
Breaking in at night,
like a pair of thieves!
Brought along some appraiser.
Don't think I'll leave this house to you.
Not on your life!
I'm bequeathing everything to God!
You'll get nothing.
I only have my pension...
Let's go.
...no help from you.
Well, I don't need it!
Least of all from you.
Won't even bury me.
- Oh, we will.
- Get the fuck out!
Are we nearly there yet?
Another 40 minutes or so.
Her paranoia is getting worse with age.
So much hatred. It's awful.
And you're so full of love?
- Why are you defending her?
- Because she's right.
About what?
That you want her to drop dead?
Watch your mouth.
She warned me to ditch you,
abort the kid and not be an idiot.
And I listened to you instead.
"It's okay. We're together."
Well, explain this:
How did all that talk
of love and happiness...
...lead only to pain and disappointment?
A miserable heap of shit.
I never loved you.
I just couldn't bear living
with her anymore.
And I couldn't find a way out.
You offered me a way out.
I used you...
...or so I thought.
But it was you who used me.
You needed a family, not me.
I would have been fine. Really.
I just needed to move in with someone.
If only I never got pregnant...
That really messed me up.
- I should have just aborted it.
- Yes, you should have.
- Better for everyone.
- Yeah? What's changed?
You've changed?
Getting another dumb girl pregnant
to join in your misery?
In 12 years, if you can still get it up,
you'll play the same trick on her.
That poor girl. Even I feel sorry for her.
You have ruined my life.
Do you understand?
Thank God I met a good man,
who wants nothing but me alone.
- Did we break down?
- Yeah, we broke down. Get out.
- I'm serious.
- So am I. Fuck off.
Get out before I throw you out.
- This is a new trick!
- Go fuck yourself, bitch!
Don't forget
your son is missing, scumbag!
Keep the line.
Stick together.
Fox-1 to call out to the boy.
Alexey!
Fox-1, finished.
Let's go, guys.
That's all of it.
Can I see it again?
No other cameras picked him up.
Nothing by the school
or shopping mall, which they love.
It's fun, and it has food.
Nothing on the way to the bus stop.
If he were taking the subway
to get to the train station...
...there are a few possibilities.
Either he turned into a street
without cameras...
...of which there are many...
...or he picked a route with no cameras,
which is unlikely.
Or someone took him.
What do you mean, "took him"?
Kidnapped him.
Are you serious?
We don't joke about things like that.
That's impossible.
It's possible, sadly.
What do you have?
Nothing from yesterday's interviews.
Of course, it's already been a while.
It's time to file a search case.
Actually, a criminal one.
Excuse me.
We handed out flyers to paramedics,
traffic police, shopkeepers...
- Hello.
- I've missed you, my love.
- You promised to come today.
- I doubt I can. I'm needed here.
What about me? Yourjob?
- You said they were strict.
- I took some time off.
Time off from me too?
Don't be silly.
I'm sure you understand.
I'm just so lonely. We feel so far apart.
- Will it be over soon?
- Of course.
- I really have to go.
- Don't hang up.
Let me listen to what's happening.
Why are you being like that?
It would be awkward.
Why?
Are you hiding something?
Of course not.
Yes, you are.
Is your ex there?
Masha, give it a rest.
I love you.
- Really?
- Of course.
I love you too. We love you.
Okay, kisses. Gotta go.
Kisses. Goodbye, can't wait to see you.
- Well, aren't you a sweet kitten?
- Mom.
Let me handle him.
Good Lord, by all means.
Of course you will.
It's just, my mom taught me,
and now it's my turn.
Men are all like little kids.
Oh, Masha, you're my beautiful girl.
- Hey, look at this one. Like it?
- No.
Hi, Dad.
Hi, honey.
How are you doing there?
We're okay.
It's fall.
Over here it's summer. All the time.
Coming to Moscow soon?
Why would I go there?
To see me.
I can see you just fine!
Okay, Dad...
...I gotta go.
I have a meeting.
Only, don't miss me, okay?
Sending big kisses your way!
Okay. Kisses to you too.
Bye, now.
Zhenya, wake up.
It's time to go.
What time is it?
I'll come with you, if you don't mind.
- Sure. Don't you have work?
- Work can wait.
Okay.
I need to call that coordinator guy.
God, it's so late. I even set the alarm.
I turned it off. You needed rest.
Yes?
- Ivan?
- Yes.
- It's Alexey's mom.
- Any news?
- No. Do you have any?
- Nothing so far. Working on it.
- I see.
- Anything else?
- I got in late last night, and...
- Sorry, I don't have time.
Of course. What can I do?
I can't just wait.
Get on the phone,
call all the hospitals near you.
Follow up on any boy aged 10-13,
no matter who brought him in...
...matching the description or not.
If a hospital says they have one,
let me know.
Preferably by text.
I'll send some people there.
- We could go.
- Great. But let me know anyway.
A search-team member will also go.
Someone who knows what to do.
If there are a few possibilities,
we'll need several groups.
Okay, sorry, I gotta go.
- When did you see him last?
- Three days ago, I think.
On the ninth? Tuesday?
Yes.
Where?
Here, at school.
And what did you do after school?
Nothing. Everyone went home.
Where do you usually hang out?
- In the yard. I don't know.
- Sure, and where else?
Nowhere else.
Come on, now.
At the shopping mall, I bet?
No, our parents don't let us.
What, so you just sit in a sandbox,
like babies?
What? No.
We play soccer at the hockey rink.
Do you have a bike?
Yeah.
And where do you
and Alexey usually ride?
Nowhere. Just in the yard,
around buildings.
Look, kid...
...if you're not telling us where he is
because you made a pact, okay.
I get it. I really do.
As long as you're sure
that your friend is safe.
We adults will do the legwork.
That's okay.
It's a bit of a game, right?
Like hide-and-seek?
Seriously, I don't know where he is.
Okay, I believe you.
Where do you think he could be?
I know you have a base.
I don't know where,
but I've seen your online chat.
If you don't know where he is,
but think he may be there...
...then you must tell us where it is.
Because your friend could be in danger.
You see, kid, we'll find it sooner or later.
But it may be too late,
and that would be bad.
Is this place more important
than your friend?
You'll find plenty of other spots.
If you made a pact,
you won't be breaking it.
You're saving your friend,
who really needs your help.
In the forest.
- The base is there.
- Good.
What is it? A dugout? A tent?
No. An abandoned building.
In the basement.
Is it walkable? Or better to cycle over?
It's a bit far. Better to go by bike.
Will you show us?
You really helped us. Thank you.
Your kid did great.
- Do you have more time?
- Yes.
- Will you come and help us?
- Okay.
- Thank you. Bye.
- All the best.
- Well, shall we go?
- Yes, let's get going.
Just a second.
Over there.
It's his jacket.
Pihto to Ivan: We found his jacket.
The father is sure it's his. Over.
Understood.
Comb the entire complex
and surrounding area.
Remember, it's dangerous
and unknown territory.
Keep us informed,
but don't go in yourselves.
We have specialists for that.
Don't get hurt. It'll make things worse.
Any injuries, stop the search...
...and direct all efforts
to helping your buddy.
First, contact the coordinator. That's me.
Only the doctor provides
medical assistance.
That's him.
Before he arrives...
...do not touch the runaway,
if he's unable to move.
Talk to him, reassure him...
...wait for the doctor.
Right, on with the song.
I mean that figuratively, by the way.
Okay, let's go.
Dawn to Ivan: We've checked
the ground floor and basement.
Waiting for further instructions.
Do you copy?
Copy that, Dawn.
Assist Fox-1 in the next building. Over.
Copy that. Over.
Pihto to Ivan: We've searched the roof
and the entire second floor.
Nothing.
- Do you copy? Over.
- Copy that.
Message to all:
Both buildings are empty.
The boy hasn't been found.
Move on to the forest.
- Hello.
- We need your help.
- Yes?
We're looking for Alexey Sleptsov,
12 years old.
This is his mom.
He may be using an alias.
Yesterday, you admitted
a boy matching the description.
Can we see him?
You two, please take a seat.
And you follow me.
- Is he okay?
- Yes. Just tired and scared.
Scared by what?
Being picked up by the cops.
Kept overnight.
But they know about him.
I filed a statement.
They knew nothing.
It was a different shift.
They had no idea who the kid is.
He said nothing...
...so they brought him here.
Happens a lot.
This way.
Hey, wake up.
Don't run ahead, and don't fall back.
Keep visual contact.
Hold the line.
No, I've not seen him.
You can't enter without a pass
or special permission. It's restricted.
May I leave flyers with you?
Perhaps your colleagues saw him.
- Yeah, sure.
- Thank you.
Thanks!
Fox-1 to call out to the boy.
Pihto to Ivan: We're at the river.
No trace of him here either.
- You copy that?
- Copy that.
Come back.
- What about the river?
We don't look for bodies.
The police or Emergency Department
do that, if needed.
Team, we're wrapping up.
We're going back to base.
Fox-1, we're wrapping up.
Given the lack of progress
in locating the runaway...
...and a sharp change in weather,
we're moving on to the next phase.
We'll inform all the locals
as much as possible.
Post flyers in as many places
as possible.
That includes bus stops, underpasses...
...apartment buildings, street poles,
benches, message boards, fences.
When posting in stores,
make sure you get permission.
You know the drill.
I also need two groups of five
to check apartment stairwells.
Great, we'll manage.
Everyone else, go put up the flyers.
Let's go.
Get the flyers from me.
Wait.
Dawn to Ivan:
The elevator stopped on the third floor.
Got it. I'll be waiting.
It's going down.
Hello.
Dawn to Ivan: It's not him.
Copy that.
- Why, hello there.
- Come on.
Sorry about her.
You nutcase.
You're the nutcase.
I was so close
to getting me a man there.
Look. Little green men!
- Which planet are you boys from?
- Just walk on by, girls.
You're so polite!
Such killer charm!
Wait here.
- Hello.
We're here.
Anton...
This won't be easy.
I'm ready.
My God...
That's not him.
Alexey has a mole on his chest.
A mole on his chest.
That's not him.
You sure?
No, that's not him.
Hands, fingers, hair... no, it's not him.
Please take him away.
We should run a DNA test
to be absolutely sure.
Sure of what? It's not him.
Sometimes,
people just refuse to believe...
- How many times must we tell you?
- Listen to me.
Only you can do this test.
The cops are still stalling.
Didn't you hear? It's not him!
Don't you get it?
- Are we talking different languages?
- Zhenya...
It's not him!
Why aren't you saying anything? Why?
I would have never given him up!
You hear me, scumbag?
I'd never give him to anyone!
Never in a million years!
Help her.
Easy now, easy.
...cities of Donbass remain
under deadly Ukrainian artillery fire.
Mines or shells hit here.
When will this war end?
This week, it became quite clear...
...that eastern Ukraine is at war again...
So your aunt and I talked it over.
Basically, she's agreed.
Want some?
What about you? Are you ready?
Have you talked to him?
I did. He said he'd think about it.
What's there to think about?
It's a perfect solution.
Masha, you know we're living
on top of each other here.
Destroyed armored vehicles
are everywhere.
The city is still under fire. Shots can
be heard just 100 meters away.
Kiev won't reveal the numbers
of casualties in the armed forces.
The DPR reports that over
100 Ukrainian soldiers have been killed.
Mommy!
Thousands dead. Tens of thousands
wounded. Countless refugees.
Living conditions in these cities
and villages are horrific.
Ukraine has fallen apart
and continues to do so.
The Ukrainian army is disorganized,
deceived and demoralized.
The government in Kiev is run
by foreigners...
...or those who put the interests
of the West before those of Ukraine.
I can hear explosions.
Death is very close.
People perish daily.
May Poroshenko,
the government, their families...
...grandchildren,
great-grandchildren, mothers...
...may they live six months in this terror!
What are we dying for?
We're miners, builders, drivers!
We're the working class.
Why are you torturing us?
After each shoot-out,
the streets are full of bodies.
Over 50 people were killed
this past week in Donetsk alone.
Lift him onto the stretcher.
The shells landed next
to a local cultural center.
People came here for bread
and other humanitarian aid.
After a large crowd formed,
they came under fire.
Cars were destroyed.
Five people died, many were wounded.
People came here to get food.
Bread can be seen
amid the mutilated bodies.
Donetsk and Gorlovka
are now partly underground cities.
Artillery fire drives people to shelters.
Some hide in groups.
Others with just their family.
In one cramped basement lives
a woman: Elena Rodina.
One, two, three, four.
Under four blankets.
Surviving this is hard.
- Is it cold at night?
- Yes, it takes two hours to warm up.
After that, it's possible to sleep.
Just a few kilometers away,
shelling is a rare occurrence.
People here get to see daylight.
But it's clearly still Donetsk.
Alexey Sleptsov, born in 2000.
On October 10, 2012, he left home,
walking down Svetlogorsk Street.
He hasn't been seen since.
Subtitles Translated by:
William Hackett-Jones