Working in the store Sunday all day.
Can I help you?
I want to drink
this Mexican boy, Johnny Alonzo,
from LA near Riverside.
He makes my heart throb--
♪ Thumpety bum, bum, bum, bum, bum ♪
when I see him.
He says he's 18,
but he could be 16.
Do you want some chips?
All I want to do is caress him.
I want to hold him.
What's that? He has these hickeys
on his neck.
What have you got there?
He likes men.
What's that?
That looks like a hickey.
Gonna be your friend.
Su amigo.
He's out on the street with friends
staying in a three-dollar-a-night...
cheap hotel room on Sixth
off skid road.
And he speaks
almost no English.
Hey, tell him I'm not
the Immigration.
¿Cómo se llama?
Me llamo Johnny Alonzo.
And you don't have any place
to stay, do you?
Look here, man.
Let me have a pack of Top, will ya?
That's all I wanna hear.
- There you go, huh?
- All right. Thanks a lot.
Thanks.
Hey, Johnny.
Hola.
¿Qué pasa?
Es muy frío.
Come here, you little cutie.
You need a place
to stay tonight?
I mean, there's always
my place.
Okay?
And it's right across
from the YWCA over there.
Hey. Wait a minute.
Come back.
No way.
I'm in love with this boy.
Really.
You are always in love.
No. I mean, Sarah,
he just came into the store.
I mean, I'm sure
he just got into town.
You see people come
into the store all the time.
Let me invite him
to dinner.
Okay.
So where are we gonna
find him?
I don't know.
Hmm.
The street.
How old is he?
He says he's 18, but--Oh.
I don't know.
He's probably--
Vegetables and rice.
Sounds good.
I don't care. Even--
Even if it jeopardizes
working at the store,
I have to show him that--
that I'm gay for him.
I have to show him
how I feel.
What are you doing out here
by yourself, honey?
Oh, I-- I'm waiting for
some friends of mine, actually.
Oh, okay. You're all right?
Yeah, I'm fine. Thanks.
Hello. Hola.
You ran out without paying?
Are they looking
for you now?
Are they after you?
Um, we're gonna be
leaving pretty soon actually.
I'm sorry. I didn't know you're--
Are you married?
Well, no. It's a--
It's some friends of mine.
You know, usually people cook,
you know, they're married.
It's kind of dumb.
No. Um, you're gonna get hit, you know.
Oh, God. I've been hit
before, you know.
Hey. What are you doing
under my car?
Johnny.
No, we'd like to invite you
over-- Excuse me.
We'd like to invite you for dinner.
We're gonna make you some good food.
We're hoping to cook him
for dinner tonight.
You're gonna cook him
for dinner?
Gonna make something
for them to eat actually.
¿Tienes hambre?
Are you hungry?
Come on.
Sure. Sure. Come on.
Take care, okay?
Okay. You too, lady.
Be careful.
Bye-bye.
¡Guau!
Hey. Hey.
What are you doing?
I am gonna be making you some good food.
Where'd you get this stuff at?
No, no. I'm gonna be cooking some vegetables.
Listen to her.
All right. All right.
He is a sugar freak.
¿Permiso?
Sí.
It's okay. Sure. We can go back.
It's all right. Don't freak out.
What's the matter?
He wants to go back to the hotel.
It's okay. Sí. Es posible.
- Okay. I'll take him back. Then we'll--
- Sí. Es posible.
Hey.
Sure. Sure. Tell him to come.
Let him get in the front.
Get in the front.
There's room up here.
Hola.
Un momentito.
Shh.
What'd he say?
Well, he says that when, um,
they first came on the train,
they had another friend
with them, and--
and the police came--
¿Tres policía?
Sí.
There were, like, three police.
Jumped him, and they--
They hurt their friend.
Killed him?
That's horrible.
I think he, like, killed him.
- What's this--
- The biggest pro--
The biggest problem is you get
too far removed from the death aspect.
It's like you walk into McDonald's,
and they just line the cows up...
and they bump 'em all off for you,
and you never have to see it happening.
If you had to go out there
and kill every piece of meat that you ate,
that's a-- that's a little easier
for me to buy, because you experience the death.
You see it happening, and you
realize what you're doing when you eat it.
But when you walk into a McDonald's
and say, "Uh, give me a Big Mac,"
you know, you're just getting
dead cow and you never see the cow die.
That's--
All those poisons release
at the time of death too.
Bad for your karma.
So it's not bad to eat food without
meat in it. You know. You can survive.
Nice meeting you.
- Adiós.
Gracias. Gracias.
De nada. De nada.
We returned downhill
through the tunnel curves fast.
Jesus Christ. The boy's insane, like
all Mexicans, about driving fast and crazy.
In the front seat next to him
I cover my eyes, tell him to slow down.
It's too late to get control
of the wheel.
The look on his face
is pure ecstasy.
The incredible, beautiful, turned-on
face of an ignorant Mexican teenager.
His friends laughing
in the backseat,
driving a maniacal machine
downhill as fast as he can go.
I'll give you $15
if I can sleep with Johnny.
Quince dólares.
¿Sí? Para me and Johnny.
Is okay? ¿Bien?
Quince dólares.
I wish I had more. I wish I had a hundred.
I love you.
Come on.
Ask him.
Mm-mmm.
I'd give you 50 if I had it,
but I only have 15.
Quince dólares para tú.
Fifteen dollars?
Come on. Angel face.
- I want to sleep with him.
- Okay, vamos.
Where the hell do you
think you're goin'?
Upstairs.
No visitors.
No, we're not visitors.
Uh, I'm with him.
We're going upstairs.
Got a key?
The key.
Doesn't have it.
No visitors.
Oh, come on. We're going upstairs.
You're not going anywhere.
He lives here.
Where's his key?
Get out of here.
We're going upstairs.
No, you're not
going anywhere.
Open the door.
No.
Come on. Just open the door.
Get out.
What's it gonna hurt you? Just open the door.
Get out. Get out.
Bitch!
You fat cow!
Shit!
Damn slut!
Fat cow!
What are you gonna do?
You're locked out too.
You want to stay
at my place?
You can stay there.
It's better than out here.
Okay?
Fuckin' bitch!
I have to go
work for about an hour.
I'll be right back.
Make yourself at home.
Más lento. Más lento.
Slow down.
He said he needed to
tomar agua-- get some water.
Is that when he slips the
$10 bill from my pants, or did I lose it?
I think he got it.
They need money-- Johnny and him.
I hope they got it.
Though I was upset that I'd
been fucked, violated and lost the money too,
for a few moments,
thinking about it, in the morning...
of the Mexicans gloating over having
fucked the gringoputo and got his money too,
talking about it and laughing,
my ass sore.
And the more I think about it,
the more I know I asked for a reckless evening.
Johnny'll probably never
look at me or talk to me as a friend.
He probably wouldn't have
in the first place. I had to find out--
to get as close to him
as I could,
even if it turned into
a shit-bad night.
Hey, buddy, how's it going?
All right.
What can I get ya?
Oh, we need a fifth
of Night Train.
Fifth of Night Train.
Yeah.
He said he was gonna
return to LA in 15 days,
as soon as he got
traveling money together.
He lives with nine
or 10 brothers.
Maybe when they're making love
they can think about Roberto
having fucked me.
Roberto's cock fucks Johnny
fucked me.
That's about as close to Johnny
as I'll ever get.
Unless I had the money.
Poor boys never win.
Who fucks whom?
Mala noche.
Every street Mexican on Sixth
will think he can
stick it in me.
Well, they're wrong.
But they never were too smart
to begin with,
or they wouldn't be here.
Chíngalo. My ass is sore.
It's true.
I think he tried to use his cock
like a weapon on me,
macho fucking prick.
Johnny comes
into the store often.
An acquaintance of mine
brought a camera
into the store the other day,
and I gave him $10 for it.
We decided to go out
and see if it worked.
It does!
Hey!
Pepper talks to a dog
we find on the street,
and I say,
"You lead a dog's life."
I don't think he understands.
Johnny doesn't want--
doesn't want to be
in our movie.
And tells me Roberto wants
to learn to drive the car.
Tell me.
Randy. Is that your name?
- No, no. My name's Walt.
- Walt. All right, Walt.
- Okay, Walt. I'm Dieter.
- Yeah.
This is my cousin Franz.
Ah. Good to meet you, Franz.
We went through
the Second World War.
Yeah, can I have
some Night Train?
Right where his daddy was born.
Buck and a half.
Hola.
What happened with the police?
Are they after you, or--
Can I get you something?
¿Tienes hambre?
Cuidado.
Veinticinco.
Para tú, nada.
¿Y eso por qué? Cuidado.
Un momentito.
Hey!
Hasta luego.
Shut up.
Hey. Little brother.
Come here.
Me speak a little English.
"A circuit court jury
in Portland unanimously
convicted...
22-year-old
Armando Zamora Flores,
a transient, of murder
and first-degree robbery...
in the slaying
of William Somerset, 53."
Night--
"1543 Bidwell Street."
Hey, hey, hey.
Look. "Flores, through a
Spanish-speaking interpreter"--
"maintained that they thought
they were going to another
tavern,
but went instead
to Somerset's house."
Hey, hey.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
"He said there a man made
homosexual advances
towards him,
and when he refused,
came at him with a knife.
They struggled, and Flores said
he stabbed Somerset."
Friend of yours?
You see how sad that is?
Nope.
Vámonos.
You know any--
Great. You got a gun, huh?
You can't just
carry it around like that.
What are you trying to prove?
You're gonna shoot
your balls off with it.
What are you gonna do
if somebody pulls a gun on you,
and you have to use it?
Look.
Don't point that thing.
It's not a toy.
Take it out of here.
Man.
Get it out of the store.
You're just gonna
get in trouble.
Take the pie. Vamoose.
Take it and go.
Roberto never acknowledges
the fuck of the night before.
It's as though
it never happened.
Johnny has
two tiny pimples--
zits from bad food on his chin.
And he looks sleepy
all the time.
Look, driving's not a game for kids.
All right? It's serious.
Johnny!
No!
¡Juanito!
¡Muchachos!
The police are gonna pick us up.
¡Muchacho!
Pull over right now.
I'm gonna drive.
You can drive later.
I just don't want you
to kill me.
We can't stay here forever.
Get in the car.
Get back in the car.
We're heading west
towards the Pacific Ocean.
Johnny will never, never
go anywhere with me alone.
I find that sad and absurd.
But it's part of the game
that he and I play
in having a relationship at all.
I don't take it personally.
He feels more comfortable
surrounded by his friends.
I don't want to interfere
with their lives.
If these two friends are happy,
that's the way it should be.
A gringo like me
has an easy life--
a privileged life--
and just because
I see someone attractive
like Johnny...
doesn't mean I should be able
to have him,
to buy him or whatever,
just because he's hungry
and on the street,
desperate, good-looking.
That wasn't my intention
exactly, but it could be
misunderstood that way.
Get back here!
Cough 'em up,
you little niño.
Muchacho.
Give me the keys,
you little shit!
Open the door! Open the--
Open the door.
Open it.
Where you goin'? Sto--
What are you doing?
Oh, great.
Look. Open the door.
Open it up.
Open the fucking--
Stop the car!
Bring it back here!
The drink's--
That's for credit.
No credit. I'm sorry, buddy.
It's 3.69. You got cash,
I'll sell it to you.
No credit.
Credit's like sex.
Some get it, some don't.
Sorry, buddy.
The plan is simple.
I go to his room at midnight.
He opens the door,
sees that I want him
that badly--
I lay down at his feet
like a dog.
Or rather, at the feet
of Roberto and him and--
And after an hour or so,
when none of us knows
what to do any longer,
I get up and I leave.
My point is being made,
that I want to see him badly,
right?
That must mean something.
How many gringos...
have acted that dramatically
toward him ever?
And whether or not he could
respond in any meaningful way
doesn't matter.
He would think of it
as a dramatic macho act.
Oh, shit. Shh.
No. Look, no-- I'm not--
I'm not Immigration.
Yo no migras.
Qué--No. N-No. No-- Shh!
No, wait. Wait.
It's okay.
I'm not the Immigration.
All right?
It's a mistake.
Shh! No! W--
What the hell are you
doin' out there?
Look, I'm just looking for some
--Get off of there!
I was looking for some friends of mine.
Get off of there!
I got the wrong apartment. It's a mista--
Don't you remember me from the store?
Goddamn sleazeball.
Get out of here! Get!
Okay, I'm leaving.
I'm going, all right?
It was a mistake.
I'm sorry.
J-Just--
Damn!
I think there was one kid.
He moved out this morning.
Do they
know that I'm here because
I'm in love with the boy?
Why would a gringo be here?
Who would he be looking for?
A junk dealer?
A whore? A queer?
Well, at least I tried.
Excuse me. Have you
seen a guy come in here,
a Mexican kid?
He's about this tall, he's got
long hair, he's wearing a--
a jean jacket and jeans...
and, like, a plaid shirt,
and he's got boots--
I seen a lot of--
a lot of Mexicans
coming in here.
It's, like, Saturday and Sunday
we were so close,
and then, phfft--
it's all over.
I really thought
he was starting to like me.
But I guess not.
Just another fantasy.
Or maybe we can only communicate
to a certain point.
I've always had
that problem with you.
I go to the Grecian Gardens
raving, "Johnny's gone."
I have a couple of beers
and tell my old buddy George...
about the impossibilities
of love.
So, is he gonna come back
and get you, or what?
No sé.
Where did they go? Thanks.
What do you need? No sé.
Maybe Idaho.
Um, get me a big bottle
of Night Train.
All right. A big one.
And a pack of Pall Malls.
$2.60-- Buck and a quarter.
Well, I can't believe that they
just took off and left you here.
You sure he's coming back?
What do you need?
Hey, you can't bring
that cart in here!
Take that out. Take that out!
- I'll take it out.
- Yeah, right.
Yeah?
Yeah.
It's worth about two bucks.
I don't--
I can't use it, though.
Yeah. Veinticinco.
Veinticinco.
Right. That's the price tag.
That's what people pay
in the store for it.
But it's worthless
unless you want
a pot like this.
Por tú, quince pesos.
But it's not worth anything
unless you happen to want
a pot like this,
and then you go into
the store and get it.
I can't do anything
with it.
Don't you have
a place to stay?
No.
You're welcome
to stay at my place.
No sé eso.
No, no, it, um-- We'll have a beer.
This is my amigo--
my friend Pepper.
¿Habla español?
Okay, Pepper, this is--
this is Esther,
and this is Mike.
Hi. Mucho gusto.
This is Frank
the homophobe here.
That's Henry,
Hannah Duncan, Betty,
Don Chambers--
the incredible
Mr. Don Chambers--
Yeah. This is Sharon,
and this is Marty.
Marty the poet.
Marty the poet
extraordinaire.
Right?
You're never
gonna remember that.
How can you remember
one name to 40 names, huh?
The deal with Marty is--
¿Qué es tu problema?
Tú es muy serio.
¿Preocupado?
¿Qué es tu problema?
No problema.
So-- ¿Qué tal?
No.
I'm off.
Hasta luego.
Fuck it.
Do I need him that badly?
Am I that desperate?
Of course I am.
Okay, you wanna pick up
a couple extra dollars?
You go up
to this club, okay?
It's up on Fifth Street.
You go up there, be nice
to the guys, they'll pay you
a little bit. All right?
Okay? Got that?
If that don't work out for you,
you go up to another club
up on Sixth Street.
Just about a block up.
Go down about a half
a block, okay?
Do some nude dancing, maybe,
pick up a couple extra
dollars, no problem there.
If nothing like that works out
for you, go talk to a guy
named Bill. Okay?
He'll take care of you.
Just be nice to him.
He'll do everything for you.
All right? That's all you
gotta do. You got that?
You understand
what I'm saying?
Okay.
A poor Mexican
has a snowball's chance
in hell, man.
It's because disaster
is right around that corner.
Hope Johnny comes back.
Look, take care
of yourself, man.
Come by the store
and I'll give you some
cough medicine, all right?
Look, I wanna be
your friend,
your amigo.
I'll help you
any way I can.
Wait a minute.
Take care of yourself,
all right?
Gracias. Hasta luego.
What do you want?
What?
Look, Juan,
we can't go driving now.
Later. Después.
Is Johnny back?
Shit.
Hola.
Hi.
♪ Adiós, adiós ♪
Everything comes out beautifully
with Spray 'n' Starch.
Hey.
Pizza, taco, burrito.
Comida-- ¿Cómo se llama--
Mil-- Milk shake.
¡Ándale!
Hello!
Hello?
Howdy.
My friend's looking
for work. Do you know
if there's any work?
I remember your friend
from last year.
He's a good worker.
But you guys came
at the wrong time of the year.
It's the wrong season.
And I'm not really
the guy to talk to.
We don't really have
a lot of work right now.
¿Dónde vas?
What are you doing?
What's that stuff?
What is that? Es por granos.
Granos.
¿Qué es tu problema?
Granos. Granos.
¿Granos? No me molesto.
¿En su boca? ¡Por favor, no me molesto!
Para.
Pobrecito.
¿Me lo hago? ¡Para!
Come on. Oh.
Para, para. No me molesto.
Hey!
¡No más! ¡Para!
Pendejo.
H-Hold--
¡No más! ¡No más! Pendejo.
All right, stop!
Stop! Hey!
Look! Wait!
Look, all r--
Hey! Alto.
Go.
Puto.
Tú eres un pendejo.
He only wants to have sex
at night, not during the day.
And certain aggressive acts--
that's what he wants and needs.
That's not what I want.
I mean, I'm not an invert.
His sexual desires
are very stereotypical,
and mine aren't.
These buggers.
Little varmints.
Shh-shh-shh-shh.
I love the countryside here.
This is great.
You're doing good.
You're doing real good.
This is your first curve
coming up right up here.
It's your first one.
Do you see it?
Now, all you're gonna want
to do is turn to the left.
It's real easy.
All right, get ready.
See it there?
Okay, turn-- Turn-- No, turn--
Turn the car! Turn--
What are you doing?
Turn the car!
Why would-- Look!
What? All you had to do
was turn the car!
What did you do?
Shit! You drive
like you fuck!
Get--
How--
It's a simple little thing.
All you had to do
was turn the car.
Thanks a lot.
For $300, the Ebony store
gift certificate.
Okay, that is-- What?
That is 401.
I can't help feeling
that his well-being...
depends on Johnny coming back.
I know he accepts me
and that we're friends, but...
Johnny may have been arrested.
He says one of their friends
told him that he saw him
in the back of a police car.
So, your grandfather
sent you out for milk?
Es pepino.
That's a cucumber.
Cucumber. Cucumber.
Cu... cum-- cumber?
They make pickles
out of 'em.
Leche.
Mm-hmm.
Huevos.
Right.
We're gonna have some beans.
No sé ése. No sé ése.
Garbanzo beans. Sí.
Shall we put 'em in the--
in the tortilla?
Tortillas aquí. Tortillas aquí. Sí.
Manteca.
Butter. Margarine.
It's not margarine. It's shit.
And Pepper
has girlfriends too.
I don't think
he likes me that much.
I don't blame him.
We're just not compatible.
But why isn't it easy
for them?
I mean,
they don't have
any imagination about sex
or anything else,
like fantasies
or erotic friendship.
Friendship?
I guess
it's not their fault.
Let me in. Let me in.
Who is it?
It's me, Polly. Let me in.
What do you want now?
There's a guy-- There's a weird guy upstairs.
H-He followed me in.
Wh-What guy?
Did you look?
There is a guy
who makes Son of Sam
look like Tweety Bird.
We've gotta call the cops.
He's a derelict, man.
We gotta call the cops.
All right, I'll call the cops.
But, look, you handle it.
Okay. I will. You talk to 'em.
I don't want anything to do with this.
All right, all right.
Hey! Let me in.
Wait a minute.
Oh, I like it!
You must love that flavor. I've never had that.
Officer 2, where is the Code 5?
Barney's, 14th and Davis.
14th and Division? Davis.
Horton, are you there?
We'll be out talking to him.
Freeze, or you're wallpaper!
Second man down.
He'll be
on the northeast corner.
That's a man down.
He's on the northeast corner--
They're people like we are.
I found out they call him Papas,
not Pepper,
because he likes to eat
papas-- or french fries.
El Loco Papas
is smart like a fox,
staying off by himself,
but they got him anyway.
These kids shouldn't be
out on the street, man.
They get into trouble
that way, man.
Dealing marijuana--
The cops are gonna get him,
man. You know that.
Jesus Christ.
It ain't fair, but--
Hello, everybody,
goddamn it.
Señor.
Amigo-- Mexico.
I'm gonna have to boot
your ass out of here pretty soon
if you don't mellow out.
Go ahead. Make me go--
Watch out.
Sorry.
All right.
Love a--Love a duck.
You see?
So, what I told him was
the story about the lady
with one in her bedside stand.
I said, "What the fuck is that?"
And she said,
"That's for burglars."
And I said, "You will not
blow a burglar away with that.
You'll blow him
into little pieces."
And she said,
"That's what it's for, George."
Okay, great.
Everybody knows that?
Looking for Johnny,
I saw no sign.
I think they got you too.
You have no place
to go or to hide.
I don't know
what's gonna happen to you.
Or, Ido know
what's gonna happen to you,
and so do you, probably.
And that's why
I fell in love with Johnny
in the first place.
And that's why Roberto was
silent most of the time
and chased white butt--
if you know what I mean--
hoping some of that sticky
good comfort, luck and security
might rub off on him.
Or at least he could
make it squeal.
Are you all right?
Hey!
Man, don't be afraid.
I'm your friend.
Hey, assholes!
Shut the fuck up down there!
I'm tryin' to get some sleep!
Give me a break!
I gotta work for a living, huh?
- Damn!
- Johnny!
Hey! Johnny!
Hey! What happened to you?
They didn't get you.
Were you in Idaho?
Shit!
So, come on.
Tell me what happened.
All this time we think
Johnny's on vacation in Idaho.
Well, it seems that
the Immigration picked him up,
they captured him, and they
shipped him back to the border,
not to Idaho.
Swimming the Rio Grande
by moonlight, he's back
in less than two weeks.
He rode the rails,
hopped the freights.
¡Toro! ¡Toro, muchacho!
¡Olé! ¡Olé!
¡Toro! ¡Toro!
Whoa!
The police came.
I told you
to get rid of that gun.
How you doing?
Hey, how you doing?
Good to see you.
Hey!
I'm thinking of leaving
for Anchorage tomorrow.
What's in Anchorage?
I can do nude dancing
in just about any bar in town
and make 150 bucks a night.
Why do you wanna do--
Look!
I can't believe he's there.
Hey, hey! What are you doing?
Hey, come down to the store
and see me sometime.
All right?
Come-- Come down to the store
and talk to me. All right?
♪ I'm gonna see your face
appear ♪
♪ Like mirrors
shown to a blind man ♪
♪ Once a black sheep ♪
♪ Of the flock ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ Are you ♪
♪ An answer to
a rich man's prayers ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ Standing there ♪
♪ Waiting on
the corner ♪
♪ Your kiss
gives a ♪
♪ Lift on
the shoulder ♪
♪ How, girl is he ♪
♪ Comin'
and goin' ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ Are you ♪
♪ An answer to
a rich man's
prayers ♪
♪ Will
you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ In and out ♪
♪ To in front of us ♪
♪ Eat me
Not like in the restaurant ♪
♪ Beg her to tell me
I didn't warn you ♪
♪ Will
you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ Are you ♪
♪ An answer
to a rich man's prayers ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they
come for
the rich man ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ Are you ♪
♪ An answer
to a rich man's prayers ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ History
police ♪
♪ Can't keep it
from exposure ♪
♪ Runnin' wild child ♪
♪ Peaceful streets ♪
♪ Can't go along ♪
♪ These thin
enrichment streets ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪
♪ Are you ♪
♪ An answer
to a rich man's prayers ♪
♪ Will you stop ♪
♪ When they come
for the rich man ♪♪