[coins clatter
in vending machine]
["House of the Rising Sun"
by The Animals playing]
♪ There is a house
In New Orleans ♪
♪ They call the Rising Sun ♪
♪ And it's been the ruin
Of many a poor boy ♪
♪ And God I know I'm one ♪
♪ Mother was a tailor ♪
♪ Sewed my Levi jeans ♪
♪ My father was a gamblin' man ♪
♪ Down in New Orleans ♪
Hey.
Sorry. Bad traffic today.
I hate the first morning shift.
Always puke all over the place.
Like the other day
at Nanago Dori Park.
In Hatagaya.
That was a real nightmare.
Some guy took forever
to come out.
Out of ten,
a level eight nightmare!
Are you even listening?
Hirayama, take it easy.
It's getting dirty again anyway.
Oh.
Mom!
Mummy!
What's wrong?
Huh?
You're here with your mom?
It's gonna be fine.
Yosuke?
Yosuke!
I was looking for you!
Where have you been?
Listen,
I was looking all over!
I told you to stay close, right?
I was searching
through the whole park.
Sorry, darling.
Now he's crying, too.
I'm so sorry.
But now we are good.
How the hell does this work?
Thanks a lot.
OK.
["Pale Blue Eyes" by
The Velvet Underground playing]
♪ Sometimes I feel so happy ♪
♪ Sometimes I feel so sad ♪
♪ But mostly,
You just make me mad ♪
♪ Baby you just make me mad ♪
♪ Linger on ♪
♪ Your pale blue eyes ♪
♪ Thought of you
As my mountaintop ♪
♪ Thought of you as my peak ♪
♪ Thought of you as everything ♪
♪ I've had but couldn't keep ♪
- Hello.
- Hello, welcome back.
Get set!
Fight!
Somebody's back!
For a hard day's work!
Yes! He hit it!
It's in right?
It's in! See?
Hey, what are you doing?
Buying scores with money?
What's the fun in that, huh?
Kat-chan! Get back!
Always pay respect
to the sport teams or religions
of others. Give paw.
Now go.
Settled!
They're playing dirty,
stealing good players from other teams.
["Dock of the Bay" by Otis Redding playing]
♪ Sittin' in the mornin' sun ♪
♪ I'll be sittin'
When the evenin' comes ♪
♪ Watching the ships roll in ♪
♪ Then I watch 'em
Roll away again yeah ♪
♪ I'm sittin' on
The dock of the bay ♪
♪ Watchin' the tide ♪
♪ Roll away ooh ♪
♪ I'm just sittin' on
The dock of the bay ♪
♪ Wastin' time ♪
♪ I left my home in Georgia
Headed for the Frisco Bay ♪
♪ 'Cause I've had nothin'
To live for ♪
♪ It look like nothin's
Gonna come my way ♪
♪ So I'm just gon' sittin'
On the dock of the bay ♪
♪ Watchin' the tide roll away ♪
Um...
Oh.
Holy shit!
Aya! You really made it!
What a huge surprise!
Like ten out of ten!
Just a sec!
This is my last spot.
I'm finishing up right now!
You can be fast if you want.
My girlfriend is waiting.
I'm done for the day.
Turn on, turn on! Huh?
Hey. Wait, for real?
Sorry, just another second.
What?
Wait, what is this?
Hold on, hold on.
Goddamnit, seriously?
What's going on?
Come on, come on!
Hirayama, let me use your car.
Can't miss this chance tonight.
Please, Hirayama!
I'm begging you.
Come on, please.
That's Hirayama,
my senior at work.
Great worker,
but not a great speaker.
I don't even know his voice.
Hirayama, this is Aya.
Ten out of ten, for sure.
Stop saying that.
Can I play this?
Uh, uh, uh.
["Redondo Beach"
by Patti Smith playing]
♪ Late afternoon
Dreaming hotel ♪
♪ We just had the quarrel
That sent you away ♪
So, Hirayama ...
Shhhhh.
♪ I was looking for you
Are you gone gone? ♪
♪ Called you on the phone
Another dimension ♪
♪ Well, you never returned... ♪
- I like her voice.
- Do you?
♪ Oh you know what I mean ♪
♪ I went looking for you ♪
- Smith?
Very common name.
♪ Are you gone gone? ♪
♪ Down by the ocean ♪
♪ It was so dismal ♪
- Hirayama,
you really like this job, huh?
- ♪ Women all standing ♪
♪ With shock on their faces ♪
You got your own gadgets
and stuff.
♪ Sad description ♪
♪ Oh I was looking for you ♪
How can you put so much
into a job like this?
♪ Everyone was singing ♪
Not that I'm expecting an
answer.
- ♪ Girl is washed up ♪
- Just wondering.
- ♪ On Redondo Beach ♪
- This guy is weird.
Nine out of ten
on a weirdness scale.
♪ Everyone is so sad ♪
I like the sound
of cassette tapes.
♪ I was looking for you ♪
♪ Are you gone gone? ♪
- Yeah! Cassettes do sound great!
- ♪ Pretty little girl ♪
- It's my first time.
First times are always great!
♪ Everyone cried ♪
♪ Of sweet suicide ♪
♪ I went looking for you ♪
♪ Are you gone gone? ♪
Drop me off down there.
- Aren't we going out?
- Extra shift at the girl's bar.
If you show up,
I'll be with you all night.
Still waiting for my pay day.
Hirayama, this is
really a big deal for me.
Dammit! If I had money,
I could handle all this.
Can't even be in love
without money?
What's up with
this shitty world?
Is this the modern age?
Hey, how much would this make?
Don't you wanna know?
I'm just curious!
Analogue is really making
a comeback. Might be worth lots.
Just out of curiosity! I know
a good place in Shimokita.
That's not in my direction.
Won't even take us 30 minutes.
Ouch!
Should be right here...
Here, this is the place.
Oops.
Hello there.
Excuse me,
how much would these make?
This one's rare, it's Lou Reed.
120 Dollars for this.
- Seriously?
- For this, $80.
- Really?
- Where'd you find these?
- These are all my senior's.
This one's 40 bucks.
For real?
This could go for 60.
You'll make a lot
with all these.
Here's my estimate.
Wow, holy shit!
Unbelievable!
Let's sell them, Hirayama!
We'll take them all.
Cassettes are in fashion.
Especially from the 70s or 80s.
We gotta sell them,
your whole collection.
120 for this single tape!
Now's the time!
OK, just one.
Let's just sell one.
Then I can see Aya at the bar.
Tonight's a big deal for me.
It's a big deal tonight!
If I miss this chance...
No love life if you're broke?
Is that it?
Seriously?
Thank you so much!
You saved me!
I'm off!
Hirayama, you're the best!
Thanks for coming...
♪ Walkin' through
The sleepy city ♪
♪ In the dark
It looks so pretty ♪
♪ Till I got to the one cafe ♪
♪ That stays open night
And day ♪
♪ Just a lookin' at
The sleepy city ♪
♪ In the night
It looks so pretty ♪
♪ No one sees the city lights ♪
♪ They just care about
The warmth inside ♪
♪ No one listens
To what people say ♪
Good night.
["Aoi Sakana" by
Sachiko Kanenobu playing]
♪ Blue oceans and blue fish ♪
♪ I held them all
A long time ago ♪
♪ But now only cold winds
Pass through ♪
♪ These empty hands ♪
♪ There is a crowd
Of grotesque children ♪
♪ There are skid marks
On the sidewalk ♪
♪ Only the blurred moon ♪
♪ Followed yesterday's
Foot prints ♪
Thanks!
Hirayama ...
I don't think I have a chance
with Aya. Like, two out of ten.
Not that I've given up yet.
Say, Hirayama ...
You're not married, right?
Being alone at your age ...
Aren't you ever lonely?
Takashi!
- It's you!
- Takashi!
- It's been a while.
What's up?
I was looking for you.
- You were?
- Yeah.
Oh, Hirayama, this is
Dera-chan, my good old friend.
He likes my ears, you see.
Whenever he finds me,
this is what happens.
Takashi!
He always chases me down.
10 out of 10.
Dera-chan is friends
with my ears.
And I'm just a bonus.
Right?
- Yes.
- Or no?
Yes!
Yesss!
Hey!
Ah.
I wanted to give this back.
Here.
Can I listen to this again?
Hmm.
["Redondo Beach"
by Patti Smith playing] ♪ Everyone was singing ♪
♪ Girl is washed up ♪
♪ On Redondo Beach ♪
♪ And everyone is so sad ♪
♪ But I was looking for you ♪
♪ Are you gone gone? ♪
♪ Pretty little girl ♪
♪ Everyone cried ♪
♪ She was the victim ♪
♪ Of sweet suicide ♪
Thanks.
Uh-huh.
Did Takashi tell you anything?
["Perfect Day"
by Lou Reed playing]
♪ Just a perfect day ♪
♪ Drink sangria in a park ♪
♪ And then later ♪
♪ When it gets dark ♪
♪ We go home ♪
♪ Just a perfect day ♪
♪ Feed animals in the zoo ♪
♪ Then later a movie too ♪
♪ And then home ♪
♪ Oh it's such a perfect day ♪
♪ I'm glad
I spend it with you ♪
♪ Oh such a perfect day
You just keep me hangin' on ♪
Welcome back.
For your hard work!
Hi.
Thanks.
["Sunny Afternoon"
by Ray Davies playing]
♪ The tax man's
Taken all my dough ♪
♪ And left me
In my stately home ♪
♪ Lazin' on a sunny afternoon ♪
♪ And I can't sail my yacht ♪
♪ He's taken everything I got ♪
♪ All I've got's
This sunny afternoon ♪
♪ Save me save me
Save me from this squeeze ♪
♪ I got a big fat mama
Tryna break me ♪
♪ And I love to live
So pleasantly ♪
♪ Live this life of luxury ♪
♪ Lazin' on a sunny afternoon ♪
♪ In the summertime ♪
Aya Koda,
she deserves more recognition.
She uses the same words we do
yet there's something
so special.
Good evening, Hirayama.
Your usual?
What are you reading now?
Aya Koda, "Tree".
Her essays?
You've read them?
You're such an intellectual.
No, I wouldn't say that.
Here.
Your potato salad.
And cheers after a long day.
Hey, Mama.
We didn't get that appetizer.
Oh, I'm sure you did.
And we don't always
see such portions.
That's not true.
We're all equal here, right?
Have to look up “equal” in my dictionary.
Oh, ladies don't like fussy men.
You always had a wrinkle here?
No, other side.
There.
Hey Mama,
do you have fried tofu?
No we're out. Go get it
and I'd cook it for you.
His wife left him, you know.
How can he stay so cheerful?
You're talking about me?
Oh, nothing.
How can you still act like that,
she says, with your wife gone?
That's easy.
I'm back to my carefree single days.
That makes any man happy.
Got rid of that nagging woman.
What a relief.
Acting like a tough guy.
Soon you'll be moaning to Mama
about how lonely you are.
Such boring small talk.
Another drink will get you
through it.
Here.
Why can't things
just stay the same?
Mama.
Sing us that song.
Our favorite one.
Oh yeah!
Ah.
Well, but ...
Hirayama only just got here.
- Don't let us down.
- Please!
Here we go.
Ah.
Come on.
Since you got your guitar out...
Let's go.
It's a good song.
["Asahi No Ataru Ie"
by Maki Asakawa playing]
♪ I ended up in a place ♪
♪ In New Orleans ♪
♪ A brothel called ♪
♪ "The House of the
Rising Sun" ♪
♪ The man I loved ♪
♪ Did not come back ♪
♪ That was when I left ♪
♪ My homeland ♪
♪ I took a train ♪
♪ And then another one... ♪
And two lemon shochu!
Oh, you're here,
give me a sec!
For your hard work!
Uncle.
Where've you been?
You took forever.
Which door is yours?
Up the stairs or below?
Niko?
My, have you grown!
Uncle.
Off to work now?
Can I come along?
You'd better let me.
Dunno what I'll be up to
if you leave me alone.
Get in from the other side.
Wanna coffee?
Yeah!
- Same as mine?
- Sure.
Thanks.
- Wanna play it?
- Yes.
No, no.
This way.
- Like this?
- Yes.
The tape is on this side.
["Brown-eyed Girl" by
Van Morrison playing]
♪ Hey where did we go? ♪
♪ Days when the rains came ♪
♪ Down in the hollow ♪
Is that the Skytree?
♪ Playin' a new game ♪
Yeah, that's right.
♪ Laughin' and a-runnin'
Hey hey ♪
♪ Skippin' and a-jumpin' ♪
♪ In the misty morning
Fog with ♪
♪ Our... our hearts
A-thumping and you ♪
♪ My brown-eyed girl ♪
♪ You my brown-eyed girl ♪
- So this is a cassette tape?
From way back?
Way back.
♪ And whatever happened ♪
Can I put this on my iPhone?
♪ To Tuesday and so slow ♪
What's written on it?
♪ Going down the old mine ♪
♪ With a... ♪
- Van-morri-son.
Is this on Spotify?
♪ Transistor radio ♪
♪ Standin' in the sunlight Laughin' ♪
Not sure.
♪ Hidin' behind
A rainbow's wall ♪
Where is that place?
♪ Slippin' and a-slidin' ♪
- What place?
- ♪ All along the waterfall ♪
♪ With you ♪
- That shop.
It's not a shop.
♪ My brown-eyed girl ♪
♪ You my brown-eyed girl ♪
♪ Do you remember when ♪
♪ We used to sing? ♪
♪ Sha-la-la la-la la-la la-la
La-la tee-da ♪
Oh, that one!
You mean this?
My camera. It's quite old.
Look!
How come?
You don't remember?
Uncle, you gave this to me.
Ahh.
Sure I did.
- Liar.
You don't remember, do you?
Is that tree your friend?
My friend?
Isn't it?
Mm.
You're right.
This is my Tree Friend.
Uncle?
Huh?
Can I borrow this book?
What book is that?
“Eleven. Short Stories”.
Huh.
Sure.
This boy, Victor,
from “The Terrapin”.
He's so much like me.
I kinda get
what he's going through.
Can I help?
Really?
Thanks.
Uncle, you and mom
don't get along?
She told you that?
Whenever I talk about you,
she changes the subject.
I see.
You had a fight with your mom?
Sort of.
Do you always
run away from home?
This is my first time.
Staying at your place
was always part of my plan.
What's that supposed to mean?
Hi.
Here.
Thanks. I go this way?
- See you in ten minutes.
- That's too short.
Then, in twenty minutes.
OK.
Yes. Got it.
Yeah, OK.
Hungry?
- Uh-huh.
Time to eat, then.
- Yay!
- Towel goes here.
- Thanks.
You and mom have nothing in common.
You think so?
She said like, you and
we live in a different world.
Might be true.
Is it?
The world is made up
of many worlds.
Some are connected
and some are not.
My world ...
and your mom's
are very different.
What about my world?
Which world am I in?
Does this flow
into the ocean?
Yeah.
To the ocean.
Wanna go?
Next time.
When's that?
Next time is
next time.
And when's that exactly?
Next time is next time.
Now is now.
Now is now!
Next time is next time.
Now is now.
Now is now!
Next time is next time.
Now is now.
Hi, brother.
Long time no see.
So, this is where you live?
I didn't mean it in a bad way.
Niko, get your things.
- No!
That's not an option.
Uncle!
Hurry now.
Come back here anytime.
Haven't finished your book yet.
Take it with you.
I'm gonna become like Victor.
No, no.
- You shouldn't say that.
- Niko!
For all the trouble.
Your favorite chocolate.
She's a good girl.
Not so sure about that.
As for father...
he no longer recognizes
anything.
Won't you go and visit him
in his nursing home?
He won't act like he used to.
Are you really cleaning toilets?
Uncle.
Thank you.
Hey, it's Takashi.
Takashi speaking. Hello?
I hear you.
Hirayama,
you've been good to me.
I really appreciate it.
Like, nine out of ten.
So, it's hard to tell ya,
but I'm quitting.
What?
I'll pay you back
the money soon.
Wait. What about your shift?
Yes.
On such a short notice,
we can't find a replacement.
No replacement?
What's gonna happen then?
You'll have to cover
for the day.
Heh?
Can I? Sorry, just quick.
Sorry.
Excuse me!
- Are you new?
- I'll be done soon.
What is it?
Where's Takashi?
Three times, I've called.
Why'd no one answer?
Listen,
I'm only doing this today.
Just find anyone, got it?
I'm Sato. I was suddenly
asked to come here
and take over
the former staff's shift.
Should I start over there?
Ah, yes.
- Hi.
Remember what used to be here?
Huh?
That's what growing old means.
Patricia Highsmith knows
everything about anxiety.
She made me realize
that fear and anxiety
are different things.
What brings you here?
Oh, you know ...
May I?
Come in.
A pack of 'Peace'.
And a bag.
May I have one?
Been a while
since I last smoked.
Did you see us at the bar
earlier?
You always go there, I guess?
Yes.
Since it opened,
so, for five or six years.
I see.
It is a nice place.
I'm her ex-husband.
Oh.
I see ...
It's been about seven
years since we got divorced.
I'm married again.
Seven years
since I last saw her.
Ah.
I've got cancer.
It metastasized.
My body's
all inflamed from chemo.
Then I...
suddenly felt
I owed her an apology.
Not that anything had happened.
Maybe it wasn't an apology.
I wanted to thank her.
No, that's not it either.
I just wanted to see her,
that's all.
Wanna drink?
- Oh no.
- Still got one more.
Well, in that case ...
I'll take one.
Please take care of her.
Oh no, we're not like that.
I'm counting on you.
We're not like that.
Shadows ...
Do they get darker
when they overlap?
Not sure.
So many things
I still don't know ...
That's how life ends ...
I guess.
Hmm.
Let's find out now.
What?
Try standing here.
Huh?
What do you see?
Looks the same to me.
Not getting darker?
Probably not.
Looks darker to me.
Don't see any difference.
But there is!
It has to get darker
to make sense!
You're really into this.
Nothing is changing after all?
That's just nonsense.
I agree with that.
Let's play shadow tag.
Huh?
I'll be “It”.
Ready?
Here I come.
Run!
- You alright?
- This is tough.
I'll be “It” now.
- Sure? Ready?
Here I come.
Tag!
So tough.
This is exhausting.
Tag!
That was close.
I stepped on you!
- You did?
- I did.
["Feeling Good" by Leslie
Bricusse / Anthony Newley]
♪ Birds flying high
You know how I feel ♪
♪ Sun in the sky
♪ Breeze driftin' on by
You know how I feel ♪
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life
For me ♪
♪ Yeah it's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life
For me ♪
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ And I'm feeling good ♪
♪ Fish in the sea
You know how I feel ♪
♪ River running free
♪ Blossom on a tree
You know how I feel ♪
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life
For me ♪
♪ And I'm feeling good ♪
♪ Dragonfly out in the sun
You know what I mean ♪
♪ Don't you know ♪
♪ Butterflies all havin' fun
You know what I mean ♪
♪ Sleep in peace
When day is done ♪
♪ That's what I mean ♪
♪ And this old world
Is a new world ♪
♪ And a bold world
For me ♪
♪ Stars when you shine
You know how I feel ♪
♪ Scent of the pine
♪ Oh freedom is mine ♪
♪ And I know how I feel ♪
♪ It's a new dawn
It's a new day ♪
♪ It's a new life for me ♪
♪ I'm feeling good ♪
["Perfect Day" by Patrick Watson
instrumental version playing]