1944: Summer war
... and our Fuhrer Adolf Hitler
will be grateful for what you've done.
I speak here in his name.
"Operation harvest" is a great service
to the people and to the soldiers.
Your sense of duty is
the very cornerstone of our society.
Furthermore, it sets a great example
for generations to come.
Girls,
daughters of the city of Hamburg,
stricken with grief and yet so proud,
on behalf of our leader
and of the country's peasantry,
I hereby thank you for volunteering.
As I'm in charge of "Operation Harvest"
among the NSDAP's youth movement
in Hamburg
and Schleswig-Holstein,
It's my duty to urge you...
to urge you: keep it up!
To our great Fuhrer Adolf Hitler.
Sieg Heil!
That's for the official part.
And now I have a little surprise.
How many are they? 32?
31. One of them got sick.
It's only a matter of good will
and dedication.
Since you helped with the harvest,
your comrades
have expressed
their gratitude by donating
a pound of hard wheat
and a pound of rye wheat.
Silence!
And now, let me hand you
a small token of my appreciation.
Here.
A cornflower
to each and every one of you.
Germany's harvest flower.
The flower
of our great queen Louise.
The flower of loyalty.
- What's your name?
- Henny Jansen.
- Do you have a boyfriend?
- No.
- I've seen you working without letup!
- Sure.
She also ate her heart out!
And she was right to do so.
Who works well
has the right to eat well.
I knew a carver who liked to work
with models built like you.
Anyways...
- Hertha Von Pfeil.
- Is your father a general?
No, insurance sales agent.
Well...
- How old are you?
- I'm almost 16.
Golly! That's impressive!
What about your father?
Johannes Kopp, born Tressler.
It's my mother, errr, my father...
Don't be overawed.
I don't bite.
Quite the contrary.
Let's cut to the heart and get to
your comrades' offering.
A pound of hard wheat,
and a pound of rye wheat.
Come and get it.
I have a few pennants spare
to brighten your farewell party.
They're in my car.
Don't push around.
Madam.
Same thing here.
Cold potatoes and sauerkraut.
What? Potatoes
and sauerkraut again?
You sure got some nerve!
A portion of potatoes
and sauerkraut!
My comrade got his call-up.
Let me buy you a drink.
That's on me.
What's your name?
Back off, ship boy!
- Where's Lucy?
- Upstairs.
Ouch! Are you mad?
Willi! Serves you right!
I don't like to be groped like that.
Where were you?
Look, it bleeds!
Such a crybaby!
It's just a little scratch.
I feared it might be the old man.
With his crone being on a trip and all.
- Are you finished?
- Not here. If the boss...
- Trude will soon be on duty.
- I have a nice present for you.
All right! I'll come Afterwards.
But don't make any noise.
- Check.
- That's 2, 80 marks.
90, three, four...
- Where could I make a phone call?
- Across the street, at the baker's.
And five. How was the food?
You call that a tip?
Are you outta your mind?
You want to pay for this bottle?
We're in short supply these days.
24, 25,
26, 27...
31.
Alarm.
There should be 32 in all.
Why all the bits and pieces?
Why didn't they give you just a slice?
Bacon's bacon, no matter what.
Here's looking to you:
32 proofs of gratitude.
Willi Keun,
he's not just anyone.
All for one...
Lucy...
If I still had
my left thumb,
I'd go on the front as soon as tomorrow.
You? Thanks for the good laugh!
Do you remember Klaus, the guy
who worked at the counter?
Yes, that's my friend, Klaus Schmides.
I envy him.
That's what I call a real soldier.
He was. He's dead now.
He's fallen on the battlefield.
What do you say about that, huh!?
Fallen? Maybe...
But for the Fuhrer
and the people's sake.
"Our grief shall be pride, Emmi. "
You gotta be out of your mind, Willi.
How are we supposed to go on like this
without supplies, without income?
I didn't get any tips today.
Tips!
North to south and east to west
soldiers fight for the Reich's survival
and...
And you're right in the middle of it,
including 32 slices of bacon!
Don't tell me fibs.
You shouldn't show off like that.
What? Why me?
You're not complying with the Nazis.
A family, for instance?
"The family is the nation's rampart",
so said Adolf Hitler.
All right...
I'm married, but...
We already discussed this, Lucy...
My wife,
she can't bear children of her own.
That's crazy! You want me to bear
your children instead of her?
Great sense of humor!
That's not what I meant. After all,
we've been only together for a day.
- My sweet little whale.
- My goodness!
All that fancy talking of yours,
makes me feel sick.
- Take a schnaps.
- No!
I'm dying for something sweet.
Fruit cans.
Excuse-me for a moment.
There are some spare mason jars
with cherries hidden in the stroller.
In the stroller?
I had to! The city block's captain
is nothing but a low-down thief.
I hid all my sweets in my old stroller,
right under the stairs to the cellar.
No one will take 'em away from me.
We fight for the Reich's survival
and this girl stuffs
herself with morello cherries!
Alarm!
Lucy, what the hell are you up to?
Are you done with your cherries now?
- We're not taking this porcelain tiger!
- Yes, we are!
Get a grip!
It's just like every other night.
- They're just above our heads.
- Speed up! Alarm!
Quick! Hurry up!
Run to the cellar! Alarm!
Mrs. Hansen!
Quick, to the cellar, there's...
They're coming down on us,
captain.
A Gestapo hot shot is there.
Sparks will fly.
Come in.
Am I interrupting anything?
Far from that. I was just expecting
someone from the Gestapo.
Come!
I'm delighted.
Take a seat, Kersten.
Let's hope it won't cave in.
Let's hope so.
How's your leg?
I can't complain.
I still need to get treatment.
It's quite convenient to have
a shrapnel in the knee!
You seem to have fulfilled
your hunger for heroic deeds.
Most of all, I'm not too keen on seeing
our Russian "brothers" again.
The Russians,
they're tough as nails.
Obviously!
I agreed on your transfer
to my department.
I'm very grateful for that.
You're quite happy
to be back in Berlin, huh?
I've seen way too many horrible things
on the eastern front.
Besides, the Homicide Department
seems to be a peaceful place.
My motto now
is duck and kowtow.
I can't blame you for that.
Kersten, you have no idea.
This world's a pitiful and absurd one.
Every day, thousands of soldiers
die on the front and I'm heading
a huge bureaucratic hellhole,
investigating only a few criminal cases.
For instance, a certain Willi Keun
has strangled a waitress in Hamburg.
It's all over the papers.
But when thousands of soldiers
get killed on the front,
the headlines say:
"Our losses are insignificant. "
This guy must have an iron fist.
There was a similar case 2 or 3 years ago.
Unsolved if memory serves me right.
That could be a case for you!
For me?
Certainly not! Our colleagues
in Hamburg should deal with it.
Inspector, you seem to have
overlooked a few details.
Let's fix it fast and let's avoid
the Gruppenfuhrer's wrath.
You're quite a joker.
How dare you drag a SS
in front of your shitty civil court!
This man committed a crime...
A crime? Give me a break!
Besides we're the only ones
to have the power to judge this case.
The guy got drunk
and didn't behave himself, I agree.
But he was on the front.
And he came back with all honors.
The court will take that into account.
And he almost killed a man.
The wounded survived...
So what! A foreigner anyhow!
They think they can
get away with everything.
You don't understand our times.
But I'm a member of the party.
He improved himself a lot.
Who are you?
Don't mind me by the way!
I wasn't going to stand up.
This is inspector Kersten. He's been
discharged from the military hospital.
He served as a Battalion Commander.
No, I only served
as a Company Commander.
Why the "only"?
I knew a few officers that were
somehow smarter than generals.
Mr Kersten's under my command now.
Very well.
I'm looking forward to working with you.
My name's Mollwitz.
Central security service.
We insist upon a faultless exchange
with the Homicide Department.
We're all in the same boat, aren't we?
Comrade Bohm, I trust you to find
an acceptable solution
in this matter.
It won't be easy.
Put more effort to it then.
Have a nice lunch!
Maybe I should follow your motto.
Duck and kowtow.
But I'm wondering
If we'll get used to it, in the end.
I certainly will.
It was kind of tense back there.
Be careful!
Give back to Caesar what is Caesar's.
Heil Hitler!
Mrs Paschke,
a pack of cigarettes, please.
Without coupons?
Sweet Jesus, Miss Hornung!
You know I'm accountable for that.
I sure don't want any trouble here!
- Let me help you with that.
- Don't bother.
Hold on!
Is that trick fully tried and tested?
I planned to open an umbrella shop.
Oddly enough, this summer's quite dry.
All right. All right.
Do you mind if I keep you company?
Miss, is this a large German beef-steak?
As big and large
as the Great Germany?
You bet!
That's Ukrainian horse-meat.
Silence! Wehrmacht bulletin!
Here, the general staff of the Wehrmacht:
American bombers
have crossed the Reich's borders
and attacked West and South Germany.
In the residential districts of
Munich, Mannheim
and Karlsruhe,
we suffered important damages.
What about here in Berlin?
Here. Won't use it. I'm a nonsmoker.
That's what I call
a perfectly good timing.
- What about your wife? Your friends?
- Friends?
Who's got any friends these days?
Help yourself.
- Too proud?
- No, just suspicious.
Mrs Pashke, cigarettes!
Don't mind if I'm curious. I work
at the Criminal Investigation Department.
I thought you were
an apprentice in upholstery.
Is that some sort of disguise?
How cunning!
My name's Kersten.
I work with Bohm.
You don't say!
You're an inspector?
Yes. Who did you think I was?
A civilian general, maybe.
You do have a low opinion of me!
Thanks.
What are you going to do
with this stuff?
You're gonna laugh:
I'm going to wallpaper.
I'll be on my own though. Berlin's
finest upholsterers are on the front.
In case you're running out of glue...
Spoiled child, eh?
You don't even have an idea.
By the way, I do know a upholsterer.
A great craftsman.
But he only works on Sundays.
Undeclared work, you understand?
Give me the address.
I'll send him over to you.
That'd be lovely.
Let me write it down.
Helga Hornung,
Weberstrasse 14.
- Is he reliable?
- Quite.
He's difficult to live with, a loner.
I won't marry him. All he has to do
is to wallpaper and bring a stool.
Cigarettes.
A friend of yours?
Not yet.
But he might be someday.
We still have common interests with
the Central security service, don't we?
Possible.
Hey, Anna.
- Anna...
- Hi, Bruno.
Is that how you walk around?
Where were you all the time?
I was at the Obligatory Work Service.
- I gained some weight, eh?
- I don't think so.
Are you going to stay here now?
Are you going to the dance with me?
We'll see about that. I just arrived!
- Those suitcases nearly finished me off.
- Those little things?
- I'll take care of it.
- That's sweet, Bruno.
How are you Bruno?
Are you making a living now?
I'm doing fine. I know how to earn
potatoes and schnaps.
But your father is such a cheapskate...
- And I often go abroad.
- abroad?
- To Bamberg.
- What are you doing there?
Sometimes I'm going to Hamburg, Kassel.
Truck drivers give me a lift.
And with the money I make, I buy
potatoes, schnaps, cigarettes.
Thanks a lot, Bruno.
When are you going to the dance
with me?
I don't know yet.
I have a lot of work on my plate.
I'm completing a nursing apprenticeship
at the Red Cross hospital.
Where's the
Red Cross hospital?
It's in the Wedding quarter.
I know Wedding inside out.
Excuse-me,
WeberstrassYe 14?
It's just next door.
The number plate fell.
- Darn those bombs!
- Bombs in Berlin? No way!
The latest news
made the plate grow wary.
Thanks.
I'm bitterly disappointed.
I come all the way here to flirt nicely
and now you got an upholsterer already.
I don't flirt
with my next of kin.
Tell me at least what you're up to
with your bottle?
That's the upholsterer's wage.
Stop it. You've had enough already.
I barely started.
Our Fuhrer needs heroes, you know.
A true hero is either a total drunk,
or stupid as cabbage.
And I certainly don't want to
let our beloved Fuhrer down...
Thomas, get a grip on yourself.
I don't know that man.
You don't know him, and yet you're ready
to offer him some schnaps?
Heil Hitler!
I didn't know
you were expecting someone.
I hope you don't mind if I mess up
your place more than it is already?
No, no.
Thomas, this is the man
who claims to be an upholsterer.
This is commanding officer Wollenberg.
Welcome to you!
I hope my mere presence won't
be detrimental to your art, master.
I don't think so. It's the first time
that I lay out paper on a wall.
Thumbs up!
Germany's in dire need of brave men.
M. Kersten is an inspector
at the Homicide Department.
On Sundays,
he's working under the table.
You could have told me that you were
the loner.
I would have spared the bottle.
How come you didn't guess it?
I thought you were working
at the Criminal Affairs department!
I'm not very gifted.
I work at the Central Records Division.
Which means this bottle is of no use,
so to speak.
I suggest to raise our glasses
to our beloved Fuhrer
and to his inevitable final victory.
Honey, did you wash
the glasses we used this evening?
Don't get too cheeky.
They're right over there.
Did you invite him
to protect yourself or did you mean
to provoke me?
Mr Wollenberg is my cousin.
Fourth cousin!
His grandmother was the cousin
of my mother's aunt.
Good luck!
I wasn't referring
to the tapestry.
What were your referring to then?
My angel, did you invite this gentleman
to protect yourself from me
or did you just mean to provoke me?
All right, all ready. Let's get it on.
Since my wound requires that I glue
the bottom part of the wall, I suggest
you take the upper part, officer.
Which leaves the middle to Miss Hornung.
Why me?
I'm a cousin and a pilot, so be it.
By no means, I'll be an upholsterer.
But I'll take care of the schnaps.
I thought so.
Schnaps is any cousins, aviators
or upholsterers' favorite beverage.
In these heroic times,
it should be everybody's beverage.
It gives you wings.
A Missing persons notice
under the wallpaper?
I guess my job sticks to me.
Did I say something funny?
Yes, a murder.
Are you interested?
Why not?
Entertain us a bit.
"On the night of September 23, 1937
"Vera Fenner, 38 years old,
was slayed by an unknown man"
"in a woodland near Hagenow. "
Thank God,
I've a rock-solid alibi for that day.
"The victim died as a result of
the hyoid bone's fracture. "
Heavens! This sounds like an athlete
with giant hands.
That's weird!
Somehow it rings a bell...
There's been a similar a case
in Hamburg not so long ago.
No matter.
That's none of my business.
Any other subject we might talk about?
Yes, yes.
What do you think about love?
Potatoes for Lehmann!
Second floor,
but there's nobody home.
- Well, I leave 'em here then.
- No, you certainly won't.
Or they'll stay here
till the next harvest.
Look, Mr Lehmann is too weak a man
and the lady has tuberculosis.
Well, I was paid to make the delivery
and I'm a man of my word.
Heil Hitler!
Go upstairs and ring the bell.
Three long and two short ringtones.
Maybe they'll open up.
Wait!
You certainly didn't hear it from me...
Three long, two short.
I'm delivering the potatoes.
The potatoes... Very well.
Thanks a lot.
Should I leave them here?
Excuse me...
Would you be so kind to carry
the potato sack to the kitchen?
Right over there.
It's hot, isn't it?
I'm hungry. Those ration coupons
are barely enough.
Can I fix you a sandwich?
I reckon I wouldn't say no,
Mrs. Lehmann.
You're welcome.
I've had enough of it.
Too much work and nothing to eat.
I prefer to roam the roads.
I like the countryside.
I'm leaving next week.
You're going on a trip?
Yes, I'm leaving with the truck drivers.
As a back-seat driver?
And where do you go?
- All kinds of places.
- Everywhere?
You think
they could take me along?
I'd do anything to get out of here.
Yes, there's enough room
in those big trucks.
Is that true?
There's something I gotta tell you.
I'm not the real Mrs Lehmann.
I'm just a guest.
But please sit down, mister...
Bruno.
I'm not bothering you?
No, I'm all on my own.
I'm happy
when I have some company.
Always alone.
Yes, ever since my husband passed away.
Damn the war...
My husband died in Auschwitz.
Never heard of it.
He was a doctor.
Professor Weinberger.
Does the name ring a bell?
No.
I never get sick.
So you're always alone?
Let me fix you
something to eat, all right?
I didn't know where to go.
I'm Jewish...
But the Lehmanns
were very kind with me.
And not just because they needed
the money to pay their debts.
They're really good people.
But because of me, they have taken
too many risks. I have to leave.
Where are the Lehmanns now?
He's working at Siemens
and she's on duty at the Post office.
They're coming in late then?
Rarely before 10 pm.
Of course, they're beat.
I'm so happy
to talk to someone.
I can't go out
for a walk.
Always alone...
Aren't you afraid?
Yes, I'm always afraid.
Less so by death
than by the abasement.
I heard terrible rumors.
Why are people
so cruel?
Beats me.
I have a few worries of my own.
Maybe I'm afraid to die after all.
I don't know.
I'm not that old.
How old do you think I am?
I don't have a clue.
Around forty, fifty.
Do I look that old?
The last few years were...
I was such a beautiful woman...
My husband loved my hair.
Look what they became?
No hairdresser, no soap.
My God!
It's me. Mrs. Lehmann!
Mrs. Lehmann!
I didn't lock the door.
Or maybe I did?
Did you lock the door?
Me? Why are you asking?
I guess I'm the one to blame.
I leave in constant fear.
I guess it just comes to me naturally.
I beg your pardon.
I'm coming, Mrs. Lehmann!
This is Mr Bruno.
He brought the potatoes.
How come you're home so early?
A shell fell on the central office.
They're repairing the roof.
I'm gonna sleep in late
tomorrow.
- Thanks for the sandwiches.
- You're welcome.
If you're in the neighborhood,
don't forget:
three long ringtones,
two short.
I'm pleased to have visitors.
And think about the truck.
If there's any opportunity...
Please...
But why?
Why would I kill her?
She was my girlfriend.
I couldn't say no to her.
I had a few drinks all right
but I know where to draw the line.
I'm not a violent man, counsellor.
I've never beaten my wife.
As to the missing bacon,
I'll make up to it.
Even we may give in to temptation.
Always on duty!
You must mention that,
consellor.
I've been decorated
with the Cross of War.
- When do I get out?
- Get out?
You don't get it, do you?
Your life's at stake here.
I suggest to plea for "crime of passion
committed in a state of inebriation".
You don't remember
anything that happened.
I remember every single thing!
I walked out into the hallway...
Lucy went to the stroller
to take her morello cherries.
Morello cherries? Stroller?
Do you mean to plea insanity
in your defense?
Don't think you can fool those judges
that easily!
But the story with the cherries,
that's in the file.
Didn't you read it?
Briefly.
But you should
know my file inside out!
You're my counsel!
Court-appointed counsel.
But you need to know everything!
It all started with the celebration.
A harvest celebration.
I'm always doing one when the girls
have accomplished their service.
By chance, I met Lucy again.
- By chance?
- Not really. I came to pick her up.
I went at her place and we had a drink.
- And you argued?
- Not at all, counsellor. Not at all.
We talked about the country's situation
and we disagreed, that's all.
What about those scratches on her hand?
These are struggle marks.
Come on!
The court won't buy your story!
I don't believe it either! There's enough
evidence to send you to the gallows.
Well, we're not quite there yet.
Tell me.
What happened to your thumb?
Can I take a look?
I sawed it off when
I was a child.
The very reason of my misfortune
I volunteered 4 times!
Can I take a look at your other hand?
That's a flaccid hand you got there.
Don't you play any sports?
I suffered from cardiac insufficiency.
After that, I never got around to it.
I think the public prosecutor
didn't kill himself over this case.
He doesn't believe me!
My own lawyer doesn't believe me!
How can you defend me
if you don't believe me?
That's up to me!
With any luck, you might benefit from
mitigating circumstances.
I dismiss you.
My lawyer has to believe
in my innocence.
That's insane!
I'm a member of the party.
I sacrificed myself for the Fuhrer.
Get off your high horses.
Above all, don't mention the party
during the trial.
They'll most likely take you
down a peg.
Well, Keun, think it over.
I'll be back tomorrow.
That's still mister Keun to you.
Mark my words!
Mister Keun...
I don't think you're guilty.
- Good evening.
- Good evening, Miss Helga.
- Come in, please.
- Thank you.
Gee, it's so dark in here!
Anything wrong with those light bulbs?
No.
It's just that I like candlelight.
And it's the perfect thing
to mark special occasions.
Don't tell me you're celebrating
your birthday!
No, but I'm expecting a
very friendly guest.
That blond provocateur with the
Knight's cross? What's his name again?
Thomas Wollenberg. He's my cousin.
How many times do I have to tell you!
I actually meant to say
that you're the friendly guest.
How nice of you.
I guess I don't really deserve this.
Can I switch on the light for a second?
Just a minute.
I'm gonna turn it off right away.
Don't you want to eat?
It's getting cold.
Sure, right away.
What are you doing over there?
It peels off easily.
What peels off?
The wallpaper.
Tell me, Miss Helga...
Do you have a spare fragment of paper,
about this size?
- No. What for?
- Just in case you need to paper the wall.
If memory serves me right,
there's a piece of evidence,
right there.
- Now turned into under-layer.
- Good appetite.
Good appetite.
Don't you remember?
The old missing person notice.
The country girl from Hagenow.
No.
I do.
Right here.
What are you doing?
Here goes your wallpaper
and my good resolutions.
The wolf has killed
and will kill again.
I'm hunting down a serial killer,
still at large.
You're really obsessed!
If you ask me,
he's this century's greatest monster.
And you're the hunter?
Before, you satisfied yourself
- with dusty files.
- That's true.
But there's a suspect in Hamburg,
whose neck is already in the noose.
Now, maybe he's guilty
and maybe he isn't.
But he has only one life to live.
I do care about that.
"September 1937. "
Let's see.
- Should I heat the tea pot?
- No need for that. I'm almost through.
Vera Wenner or Fenner, whatever.
There it is.
"Died as a result of
the fracture of the hyoid bone,
"suffocating"
I have a memory like an elephant!
That's the 5th case so far.
What do you say now?
Nothing. The wallpaper is bust
and I don't like the turn of events.
I don't know why exactly.
I sort of hoped you'd let it go.
And I don't talk about the wallpaper.
I'll buy you a nice painting.
A funny little whatsit with the Fuhrer.
Don't bother.
Look, I'm sorry,
but it was important to me.
Sure enough.
How lovely.
And all those delicacies!
Just like the in the good old days.
I think I'm going to turn the lights out
now.
Leave it be,
we'll see better like this anyway.
Probably but candlelight is far lovelier
and fits special occasions better.
Are you angry with me?
I guess I lost my manners.
You should invite me more often.
Somehow, I have the impression,
you feel already at home.
Wouldn't you like that?
Only if you don't ruin
my furniture and my wallpaper.
Sit down at last!
At your command!
Leave me alone!
Bruno's a tard, Bruno's a tard...
- How nice of you to come by.
- What was all that racket about?
Children stuff.
Sit down.
Bruno, I'm in a rush.
I have to go upstairs.
Why? Your father's not there.
I've got some work to do.
Besides, I've got nothing to do here.
What's that vest?
Well, a vest, that's what it is.
It's a gift.
Don't tell me fibs.
That's a woman's vest.
Bruno, Bruno!
Are you're seeing a lady?
Don't let my father know about it!
- Here, take it.
- No, thanks, Bruno.
We can go on a date now, look!
- Where did you get that?
- I found it on the streets.
You have to give it back!
I found it, it's mine.
It's not yours.
You have to give it to the police.
You know what? Damn the police.
I'll go with you just to make sure
you're really giving it back.
Somebody has lost it and
must be desperate now!
I don't think so.
It doesn't matter what you think.
You've always been an honest guy.
Sure, but there's almost 300 marks,
a pretty nice sum to get out on a date.
We can go out for less than 300 marks.
Let's go to the police station.
And that's final.
Stay here.
Wouldn't you like that.
Want to get cozy, eh?
Come on, take the purse
and let's go.
Come on!
Thank you, sergeant.
- Hello.
- Heil Hitler!
Miss Hohmann,
did Bruno give you hard time?
No, Mr. Ludke has found a purse.
Since when do you call me like that?
I'm only Bruno the retard.
I found it.
It should be mine now.
Look at that!
Where did you find it?
On a bench
next to the town hall garden.
Come on Bruno!
There are no benches
at the town hall anymore.
Must've been some place else then.
What's the difference anyway.
Sounds strange to me.
Let's file a report.
Don't you think it's a good thing
he came in willingly.
Willingly?
He's known to one and all!
His file speaks miles about him:
cruelty towards animals,
wood theft and whatnot.
Yeah but you can't prosecute me.
I'm protected by article 51!
I'm a mental case.
Fuck all of you!
Inspector Kersten?
Follow me, please.
On Central security service's orders.
- I don't understand. What does it mean?
- I'm sorry, that's an order.
What about tomorrow? It's the end
of our service and I've an appointment.
I see.
Nevertheless!
What's going on?
I've absolutely no clue.
I just got an invitation
from the Central security service.
Miss Hornung, would you be so kind
to call captain Bohm?
Yes, of course.
And tell him...
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
- Can I make a call?
- I'm afraid not.
What if
it takes longer than expected?
What makes you think that?
Your strange behavior,
to start with.
You're free to complain
to the Gruppenfuhrer.
Inspector Kersten, Gruppenfuhrer.
Excuse-me for this somewhat
informal invitation...
But between former soldiers...
Please, take a seat.
You may leave.
Sit down already.
You're a hard-working man.
I received a detailed report on you.
I'm just doing what I can, sir.
Come on,
no need for false modesty here.
You're on the verge
to crack a very sensitive case.
You're always on the road,
Hamburg, Kassel,
Lubeck, Schwerin, etc.
That's very interesting.
Very interesting.
Cigarette?
I don't smoke.
Congratulations.
Now, excuse me!
If I may inquire.
Who gave you that file?
A liaison officer
from your department.
Someone who's eagerly
following your progress.
Yes, sometimes, one has friends
where one least expects it.
His name's... hold on...
His name's Bruehl.
Our assistant Bruehl?
Your record's outstanding,
my dear friend
You're a decorated war veteran
You're extremely successful
in your career and...
Good grief!
You're not a member of the party?
That's none of my business anyway.
You have your reasons, I understand that.
Tell me everything
about that killer of yours.
Since you've already read the file,
I won't elaborate.
In my book,
all those murders have been committed
by the same killer.
And he's still at large.
Which implies to call for
numerous judgments revision.
And so?
These are miscarriages of justice!
Those are not supposed to happen
in our german rule of law.
Go on.
The death was caused
by the fracture of the hyoid bone.
Which is extremely rare.
The killer has
incredible strength.
His motive for killing always seems
to be the same.
One moment.
Fracture of the hyoid bone?
What does it mean?
I'm not familiar with the human anatomy.
Maybe you could show me?
Yes.
That's how he kept his grip...
He put his hands just like that.
So?
If you squeeze hard enough,
the hyoid bone breaks
and the victim dies,
choking on his own tongue.
That's weird.
Anyway,
I still can't picture it.
I can't demonstrate it.
I haven't enough strength, unfortunately.
"Unfortunately"?
Kersten!
"Unfortunately"!
Is this remark of yours directed at me
or at the SS in general?
Gruppenfuhrer!
The murderer
must be strong like a bull.
A circus performer maybe. In any case,
a man with abnormal behavior.
Stop it.
Sit down.
That's exactly
what I wanted to hear from you.
A man suffering severe psychic disorders,
afflicted with a genetic retardation
and an alcoholic father. Who knows?
A neighbor in the streetcar,
or a waiter maybe,
a circus performer.
Bring me his personal file.
He kills women in the dead of night.
One at first, then a dozen,
even more maybe...
A bona fide citizen of
this quiet and peaceful city.
No record,
no criminal history whatsoever.
But as soon as you check
his family history,
you stumble upon an uncle
who ended up in an asylum
or a grandfather who died
of alcohol poisoning.
In any case,
we're looking for a village idiot,
someone who's mentally
and physically impaired.
Did you study
the racial theories?
- Superficially.
- Read them line by line.
Our supreme duty is to
uphold the strength of our race.
You wouldn't object to
the superiority of our race, would you?
No, of course not. Very wise.
We need to develop our skills
to an elite level.
And that's only possible through
a stringent if somewhat cruel selection.
We should abide by the laws of nature
and dispose
of the weaker, impaired species.
Where are you, my little devil?
Another air-raid warning. We'd like
to resume the party in the basement.
Sweetie, don't you
see I have a guest here.
Bring him over, then.
You should see my little devil's
wine cellar. It's quite an eyesight.
I'm giving a little party.
Just what one needs from time to time.
Where were I?
You got me all confused now.
Yes, that's right: the elimination
of the pathological elements.
This is almost a textbook case.
Bring me that abnormal murderer
and I'll scare the good people witless.
I need to set the proper context
to pass a lex... what-you-call-it,
a bill applying to certain persons.
Do you need any assistants?
A power of attorney letter? Cars? Gas?
Nobody's going to interfere. You'll
have access to all the files you need.
I'm not sure
I'm really the fit you're looking for.
It seems my wound
got the better of me,
but I can recommend you
several names.
My god, you were stationed
in Podwoliszicka?
In that godforsaken hole.
There's a slaughterhouse,
close to the station.
How long did you stay there?
Two months.
I stayed for two hours.
You wouldn't go back, would you?
Just the thought alone,
makes me want to itch.
We're going to clean up every inch,
from Beuthen to Moscow.
Where were I? Right!
You'll be in charge. And that's that.
I knew I could be straight with you.
On the front, during the air raids,
we used to say: "Come in!"
- Nervous?
- No.
A genuine Wouwerman.
Someone acquired this
in the Netherlands for me.
They're making a fortune
on our backs.
Go ahead, I'll be right there.
All right, all right!
Come on, Kersten.
Another beer, captain?
I'd prefer a cognac.
A good brand preferably.
I wouldn't say no to a glass of Hennessy
A barrel or a crate, general?
Don't be silly,
a bottle will do.
Or do you mean to keep
your special stash a secret?
Precisely.
I'll bring you a plain beer then.
Coming up.
You're worrying way too much,
my sweet little cousin.
Tell me, is there anything going on
between you and the upholsterer?
Don't be daft.
What do you mean anyway?
Courtly love's what I had I mind.
He's a swell guy, isn't he?
Yes, it's true.
I do appreciate him a lot.
Did you ever "appreciate"
someone like that?
If you really want to know: no.
All right, I'll put him
on my long list of "proteges".
While I still can.
Your cousin will soon
leave this district.
Have you been transferred?
- To the front?
- That's all I can say.
Secret order.
Nobody knows about it, except for me
and my radio-operator.
Tell me, have you ever been to Sweden?
No, what would I do in Sweden?
We have some relatives there.
The Suderstrom, for instance.
Anyway, you know how to reach me.
If your upholsterer
doesn't manage to stay out of trouble,
call me.
I think we can arrange something.
I talked to the boss. He's open-handed
and likes soldiers a lot.
Hello and Heil Hitler!
Any news about my purse.
Why are you asking?
Anna said the purse would be mine
if nobody asked for it.
And, well, I found it.
In two years, brother.
These things take time.
That long?
Where's my purse now?
Beats me. It was passed on.
Another department claimed it.
Bad luck!
Maybe the owner
has finally showed up.
What do you mean?
Gruppenfuhrer Scharf.
At your service.
Thank you.
What are these goods for?
- That's your ration.
- What ration?
You'll be supplied with these
every 10 days.
- Canned foods will arrive shortly.
- Canned foods?
Put it all in the safe,
this is a state secret after all.
French cognac.
Russian tea... grown in China.
Soap, that's nice.
Cigarettes. So what?
Heavens!
Help yourself, Bruehl.
Do you drink, do you smoke?
I sure wouldn't mind
a nice cup of coffee.
I'm afraid it won't happen so soon.
The canned foods are on their way.
I'll just set myself some soap aside.
In these nasty times,
it's better to keep one's hands clean.
So far so good.
Miss Hornung, what happened to
the found object, the purse?
It was delivered this morning.
There you go.
Thanks.
Here's the file:
"Delivered
at precinct 185
"by Bruno Ludke,
living at Jaegerstrasse 14,
"in tow with Anna Hohmann,
living at the same address... "
Hi, Bruno. How are you doing?
What do you want?
I'm looking for a strong man.
I don't work for money
anymore.
What's the point?
Money's become useless.
I need to eat. I want
cigarettes and Schnaps.
I'm sure we'll agree on something.
- What's that?
- That's Aquavit. Comes from Denmark.
What are you waiting for?
Pop the cork.
So be it.
And let's talk business.
- You wouldn't have a corkscrew, would you?
- Yes.
Can't find it.
Forget about it.
Let me try it my way.
Jesus!
What's wrong with that bottle?
A firm hold, that's all you need.
Too bad, I spilled some.
- What's your name?
- Axel.
You're a nice fellow.
Have a drink.
That's quite an act you showed me there,
popping the cork without a sweat.
It seems like you impressed a few people
in Hamburg as well.
Lucy Hansen, for instance.
Whaddaya mean?
You know who I mean.
The pudgy waitress you wasted.
She must have been...
Man! How did you do it?
Nobody ever managed
to knock me down.
Strength alone is worth nothing.
I know a few tricks myself.
I gotta learn those tricks.
Who showed them to you?
I learned those on the police force.
So you're a copper.
What about
that job offer of yours?
And don't say
I wasted somebody ever again.
I don't like the sound of it.
Are these your men?
Screw you!
I'm protected by article 51!
I'm crazy!
Come, Bruno. Here you go.
All righty, Axel. Let's go.
According your own confession,
you committed several murders.
How many?
I didn't keep the score.
Around fifty, one hundred or so.
So you know how to count?
Well, do the math then!
One, two, three, four...
Axel, he's making a fool out of me.
I'm not going to count for everyone.
Bruno, stop the act.
You promised you'd behave yourself.
I'm starving.
Name all 5 continents!
East, west, south, north.
How big's your little finger?
About three feet.
Don't let yourself get distracted.
Do you go to church sometimes?
I used to go before.
Not anymore.
- Why is that?
- 'Cause I'm in jail.
Are you still praying in your cell?
"Help me God each day,
To follow You along the way. "
I want to be good.
I won't do it again.
Tell me.
Don't you think
he's getting a rise out of us?
He's fooling us.
He's stringing us along.
But his confessions match with
the facts of the case.
We could link him to all 55 killings.
Well, listen carefully!
Who was Bismarck?
It was Hindenburg!
That does it! This isn't the proper way
to lead an investigation.
He's making everything up!
You should catch him in his own trap.
He's quite stubborn in public.
I'll talk to him alone, later.
When we'll make a plaster cast
of his head at the museum.
The perfect occasion to grill him again.
He's all yours.
Unless this case is rock solid,
it won't be of no use to me.
There's so much at stake here,
my head's almost on a plate.
That goes for you as well, by the way.
Your memory's excellent, Bruno.
I'm counting on you.
Tomorrow we'll drive you to a place
you're familiar with.
You'll guide us and you'll tell us
exactly where and how it all happened.
You won't leave out any details.
You know,
my boss is very thorough.
He wants to know every detail.
Axel, you're still there?
I think this guy wants to snuff me out!
It's so dark in here!
I'm all ears, Bruno.
Over there, to the left.
There's a hill.
Nothing beats the whiff of fresh air
in the early morning, Axel.
Come on, Gee up!
Let's get this horse moving!
Are you out of your mind?
What's wrong with you?
Come on!
That was just for kicks.
We need to lighten up.
We're working too much.
Boy, did she get sacred!
Let go of him.
It reeks of mushrooms here.
Jail sucks.
There's a lake nearby. Let's take a dive.
The others can wait here.
Work comes first.
Where did it happen?
Not here. Come.
So?
- And my smoke?
- Do your part first. Tell me.
I'm fed up wit it!
Don't make things harder than
they already are. Let's hear it.
All right, just to make you happy then!
I walked a lot that day,
my legs were aching.
That's the place where I took a rest.
I still had a potato in my
pocket, I ate it up.
She arrived.
She was pretty.
She wore a blue what-you-call-it.
A blouse.
She had a bunch of flowers.
And she was singing.
Those were buttercups.
I said to myself:
let her sing just a little bit more.
I stood up
and I followed her.
She didn't notice me.
Suddenly,
she dropped something.
She bent over
and picked it up.
I hid myself
behind a tree.
She must have seen me by then
'cause she got all scared.
She ran off.
I ran after her.
I was faster.
"Stay!
I won't hurt you. "
Just wait till I get you,
little pest.
That's when I did her.
She didn't budge.
I had to bury her.
What if someone came by?
And so I dug
and looked all around.
I was on all fours
and while I was digging,
I took a look.
Up. And down again.
There was nobody around.
Is that her?
That's right.
What about my cigarette?
You really have an excellent memory.
You deserve your cigarette.
Hold on a sec!
I concealed it.
What do you say about that!
You didn't find it!
Are you convinced now?
And how!
It seems you hit the jackpot!
- Care for a gulp?
- Thank you.
My name's Wolf-Dieter.
I'm Axel.
Listen Axel,
there's a rumor going around.
I have a good sense of hearing.
Seems like our case
will land on the highest desks.
- You mean the SS-Reichsfuhrer?
- Higher.
The Fuhr...
That's fine.
Let's go.
Are we stuck?
It looks a lot like sabotage.
Gruppenfuhrer, may I inquire
if your hearing with the Fuhrer
went well?
Your curiosity is totally understandable
and yet unseemly.
Anyway, this is what I can tell you:
bureau M1/7 is dismantled
with immediate effect.
There were certain factors
that bothered the powers to be.
I'm expecting Kersten tonight
for a full report.
The Fuhrer expects us to proceed
with the execution tomorrow.
I'll make the necessary arrangements
as soon as we arrive in Berlin.
Arrangements?
That's an order.
You ought to read
between the lines by now.
Our Fuhrer
is the greatest mind of our time.
It's such an honor to work under
his orders for the sake of our country.
The idea that the Lubke case
could support
a bill to eliminate degenerate beings,
was quite appealing at first,
but to what results?
Not to mention the people's reaction?
A feeling of insecurity maybe.
I mean he killed 80 people.
Fear? You're talking about fear?
A true german doesn't live in fear.
It's much more dangerous than that.
That monster has been on the loose
ever since we seized power.
Imagine the mess if people
lost their confidence in the police.
If only he were a
jew or a foreigner...
Why are we still stuck?
Chase those sheep away!
Pull away!
- Cheers!
- Thank you.
Three weeks from now,
and everything will be over.
There'll always be a case to deal with.
Huh! Huh! Not for me. My purpose is...
to keep a low profile.
Everything has been settled!
From today on,
we'll have a private life.
I imagined my private life
a bit differently.
A wedding with Wollenberg?
Thomas is my cousin.
You still don't get it, do you?
Besides, I'm worried about him. I think
he's about to make a big mistake.
What do you mean?
He talked about going on a trip.
Are you saying he wants to run away?
- Is it worth it?
- Now, look who's talking.
You're the Gestapo's darling.
Come on!
All men above the age of 18
as well as all women
between age 25 and 55
are concerned.
How many years before you turn 55?
Hamburg's criminal court
has pronounced today
his final verdict
in the Willi Keun case, 44 years old.
Based upon clear evidence,
the accused has been sentenced to death.
The bastards! They promised to
adjourn the proceedings.
Helga, we have to act!
Call Mollwitz in Berlin.
At this hour,
he must be boozing in some bar.
And there's plenty of them!
- And Rossdorf?
- This is saturday!
All offices are closed.
Those gentlemen like to play peace.
Let's leave right away.
He could be hanged tomorrow.
Excuse the rubble.
Courtesy of the everlasting bombings.
Please, sit down.
That's quite an unusual hour, Kersten.
And so is the situation,
your honor.
Yes, you've alluded to that.
However the verdict
has already been pronounced.
Your honor, Keun is innocent.
I have the murder's written confession.
That's interesting!
Proof again that evidence
can be misleading.
Can I take a look at the file?
Well.
There's a small problem though.
I'm not really authorized
to let you go through the file.
We need to obtain a reprieve
from the court in Hamburg.
You're speaking to the wrong man.
I barely presided over the court.
I know.
The DA's office has been bombed.
We don't have his personal address.
The court must have it.
It's closed now.
And tomorrow's sunday.
I'm afraid we won't be able
to avoid the irreparable.
- You understand...
- I...
You seem to be so positive
about this Keun case.
Absolutely.
We have way more evidence
than a mere confession.
Still! You need the proper documents.
The DA is extremely meticulous.
Can I make a phone call to Berlin?
Of course.
I'd like to have an urgent talk
with Gruppenfuhrer Rossdorf.
What's the phone number?
007003.
Rossdorf.
What are you doing in Hamburg?
Indulging in some beer and skittles, eh?
I've been expecting you, Kersten.
Who? Keun?
Haven't heard about him.
None of my concern either.
Listen to me Kersten.
You should mind your own business.
I would appreciate
if you'd cease your investigation.
You do remember that this matter
is still a state secret.
Come immediately to Berlin.
I'll wait for you right here tomorrow.
Heil Hitler mister Kersten! Over and out.
All right, I'll hand the file
to Dr Schleffien.
Heil Hitler! Over and out.
I wonder if Rossdorf
really heard your last words?
Your honor,
we're talking about a man's life here
and about the law in general.
The Law?
"The law benefits to the german people.
The absence of the law harms him. "
I'm merely quoting
a renowned speech.
Kersten, you should rely
on your lucky star now.
Our dearly beloved rule of law
has been scraped a long time ago.
Let me remove that cover.
It's all worn out anyway.
Rossdorf!
I don't like being
disturbed at night.
Dear Kersten,
thank you for this surprise visit.
Keep me fully informed and...
Be careful,
as far as that goes.
Good night.
Thanks.
Come on, Keun.
Time to grab your stuff.
- No, I'm innocent.
- You have some awesome connections.
No one has ever left
this cell alive before.
Come on.
They didn't have the decency to leave
a piece of soap, those bastards!
"And keep me
fully informed. "
Helga...
Get a hold of yourself.
"Be careful,
as far as that goes. "
I knew it!
Axel!
The car is waiting for you.
I'm coming.
I'll call you later.
Here's inspector Kersten.
Thank you. You're dismissed.
So?
Go on,
tell me everything commissioner.
I'm all ears.
Given the hard work I've done so far,
I think you owe me
an explanation
for this rather unusual method.
You think so?
How dare you hold the
Central security service
accountable for it's decisions?
- That's not what I meant.
- Be more accurate then!
- I went to Hamburg.
- I'm aware of that.
Besides,
you called me.
Keun had been sentenced to death.
So I was told.
In the meantime you did a
very foolish thing.
How dare you lecture me?
Anyhow, go on...
Keun is innocent.
We have the proof
that Ludke killed the waitress.
Mr Kersten, you need to erase
Bruno Ludke from your memory
once and for all.
As you still don't seem to understand,
let me break it down for you:
the hunt is over,
we have to bury the file.
Fuhrer's order.
Do you get the full picture at last?
No, I guess my
intellectual capacities are limited.
I should have known
you wouldn't be cooperative. All right.
Let me explain what's at stake here,
in plain and simple words.
It would be highly prejudicial to us
to acknowledge the existence
of a serial killer.
That Keun!
He's merely a grain of sand
in the wheels of our machine!
A grain of sand? One that can easily
be discarded I guess.
Watch it, Kersten.
I don't like your tone.
And I certainly don't approve of
your personal initiative in this matter!
Which forced us
to take decisive measures.
I guess I owe you this summons then.
We work fast and efficiently, don't we?
And yes, that's my doing.
Incidentally, "owe" is the right term.
You owe this loyal measure to my patience.
And to your efforts in a matter
I barely remember anything about.
You stood up against us!
Your irresponsible attitude forced me
to take matters into my own hands!
Executing Keun
amounts to a judicial murder.
- Keun is insignificant!
- He's a member of the party.
So what!
The party's full of black sheep.
You were close to
join the party yourself.
And you're everything but a nazi,
aren't you?
For once, I'll agree with you.
You may put a brave face now
but we both know you're desperate,
and I'm not impressed.
I've seen so much people turning
their backs against God and the Fuhrer.
I'm used to it.
Get off your high horse, inspector!
You're the only one to blame
for Keun's death.
This is going
to be very difficult to prove.
Difficult?
He could have been sent home tomorrow
if only you had kept quiet.
You were the one who started
yacking about Ludke.
Shut up already!
Divulging state secrets!
If your so hell-bent on wasting
your life, do it on your own!
Are you fitting me up
for a judicial murder?
You brought this upon yourself.
Examine your own conscience.
You're nothing but a big mouth!
That's the foulest trick
I've ever lived to see.
I only did my duty, that's all.
You're not even flinching
at the thought of a man's death.
True enough.
Nor am I worried about yours,
for that matter.
I realize that.
I believe...
"I believe"!
That word's got whiskers on it!
Do you believe in God?
Yes.
Don't trust him too much.
You can't count on his help these days.
One day, the law
will be the law again.
We'll probably be dead by then but...
You will, that's for sure. Which brings
me right to the matter at hand.
You will not be prosecuted
before a secret military court
as I first had in mind.
However, I have to forgo my plans
as our country's military situation
is at stake here.
You see, that's the Curonian peninsula.
A heavily crowded place.
I arranged for a sector
where you can prove your mettle.
That's what I call "front" probation.
You won't serve
as a commanding officer though.
I'm afraid you'll have to learn
to be obedient again. Heinrich!
Mr Kersten will remain in custody
before his departure for the front.
At your command.
Mr Kersten, you'd do yourself a favor
if you erased Bruno Ludke's name
from your memory.
The man never existed!
Bring me Helga Hornung's
personal file now.
Criminal Investigation Department,
bureau M1/7.
Kersten, are you expecting someone?
I'm not quite sure.
Sergeant major!
- Lieutenant?
- Time to get on and go.
At your command.
First train!
You got my message!
I was expecting the worst.
Rossdorf asked for your file.
Don't worry.
What's that uniform you're wearing!
It could have been worse.
"Front probation".
Nothing to write home about.
Axel, you can't fool me.
I know exactly what it means.
Did you hear about Keun?
He's been shot dead
while he was on the run.
They're all in a hurry.
It's not going to last. Anytime soon,
we'll go to the front by subway.
Be careful.
Don't forget to go to the shelter.
Get some warm clothes
and don't smoke too much.
Ah yes, the cigarette coupons.
My god, the cigarette coupons!
It all started like this.
The umbrella, the tapestry.
Have a drink with your old company.
Surgical Schnaps. 60% of alcohol.
Just what one needs to die a heroic death.
Sorry, it's a soldiers' joke.
- Thanks.
- What happened?
You're sent to the front
as a skirmisher!
I assume you got into a fight
with the brass then?
- I guess you could put it that way.
- Don't worry.
Rumor has it that the battlefront
we're sent to as reinforcement
is in shambles.
We're not going to make it.
What are you babbling about?
He's shedding tears of joy while
drinking down the cup to the last drop.
- Third company, get on the train!
- Come on.
What was I about to say...
There's something I wanted to say too.
Good luck, Axel!
Come back to me in one piece!
The sooner the better.
Of course. Don't cry.
I won't shed any tears, I promise.
Heil Hitler, little cousin!
Thomas!
Things look dodgy, my girl.
Now listen to me very carefully.
I'm not drunk!
Get in the car and please
don't make any fuss.
Leave all your stuff.
No need to worry about that.
We're going to Stockholm. Silk stockings
are prettier there and less expensive.
- I don't understand.
- That's not necessary. Trust me!
Be kind and tactful!
I have to go home,
the rent is due...
I'll pay the rent
through the Fuhrer's chancellery.
You don't want to go home.
The Gestapo is waiting for you.
Thank you, Thomas! Thank you
Excuse me.
- I know you.
- Yes?
You're the inspector
who arrested Bruno Ludke.
I just wanted to know
what happened to him.
He never came home.
Who are you talking about?
I know you.
You're the one who arrested him.
Bruno Ludke?
You're mistaken sister.
Bruno Ludke never existed!
Wheels shall roll for victory
We hereby inform you
that Mr Ludke has been executed
yesterday in the afternoon
in compliance with your orders.
He died at 3. 31pm
Case closed