[ Man narrating ]
And perhaps I wouldn't
be writing it if some devil...
Hadn't made me stop him
that night... in the rain.
You want to drown, Henry?
Oh. I wanted a bit of air.
How nice to see you, Bendrix.
How long has it been? A year?
June, 1944.
As long as that.
How's Sarah?
Oh, she's out and about
somewhere.
She at the cinema?
No, she never goes.
Hmm. Good night, Henry.
You should go home
before you catch your death.
Is something wrong?
Let me take you home, Henry.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
or perhaps I wouldn't
be writing this...
If I had known then who I hated.
Was it Henry?
Was it his wife, Sarah?
Or was it some other who was
yet to be revealed to me?
Sarah?
See, she's out still.
Come upstairs.
Come in.
Let me get you a drink.
Whiskey, thank you.
Whiskey.
So what's troubling you, Henry?
Sarah.
She's out for a walk now,
Bendrix.
A walk.
Well, she always was
a great Walker.
Jealousy's a terrible thing.
Well, you know
you can trust me, Henry.
You know, I went so far
as to get the name
of a private detective.
You think she's...
Seeing someone?
[ Chuckles ]
of course you think me a fool.
No, Henry.
I don't think you're a fool.
You mean you think
it's possible?
of course.
Sarah's human.
Can't sleep.
Keep... picking up
this wretched card.
Burn it.
I wish I could.
Well, then go and see--
what's his name? Savage?
And sit where all the other
jealous husbands sit?
Do you think they have
a waiting room, Bendrix?
Where we see
each other's faces
as we pass through?
Why not let me go, Henry?
You?
Yes.
I could pretend to be
a jealous lover.
Jealous lovers
are less ridiculous
than jealous husbands.
They're supported by
the weight of literature.
Tragic, never comic.
Think of Troilus.
I shan't lose my amour propre
when I interview Mr. Savage.
This is ridiculous.
One can't spy on one's wife
through a friend...
And have the friend
pretend to be her lover.
What else
are friends for?
you're a good chap, Bendrix.
All I needed was to talk,
clear my head.
The name was savage,
and the address
was 3 vigo passage.
Forget what I've told you.
Doesn't make sense.
I'll see a doctor.
[ Door opens,
footsteps approaching ]
that was the door.
Sarah's come in.
It's the maid.
She's been to the pictures.
No, it was Sarah's step.
[ Henry ]
Sarah, darling.
[ Sarah ] Henry.
You. Is that you?
Been out for a walk?
Yes.
It's a filthy night.
You're wet through, Sarah.
One day you'll catch
your death of cold.
[ Kisses ]
good night.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
their marriage
was conventional,
like their
well-appointed house.
And I liked them both
the first night we met,
drinking bad
south African Sherry
because of the war in Spain.
Good evening, sir.
May I take your hat?
Thank you.
Mr. Miles is upstairs.
♪ [ Chattering ] [ Big band ] ♪
Sherry, sir?
Thank you.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
she seemed... restless.
In the summer of 1939,
the whole of London
was restless in the face
of the coming storm.
♪ [ Continues ]
[ Chattering continues ] ♪
How nice of you to come.
Sarah,
this is our neighbor,
the novelist chap.
- What on earth is a novelist
doing here?
- research.
On what?
On your husband.
I'm trying to write
a character who works for
the ministry of pensions.
I need to find out his habits,
what he drinks before bedtime.
Cocoa, and when.
11:00, isn't it, Sarah?
Unless we're entertaining.
Would you be so kind
as to excuse your character?
The ministry needs him.
Unfortunately, it does.
So, tell me.
What?
His secrets.
Henry's a good man,
Mr. Bendrix.
Good men have no secrets.
I was afraid you'd say that.
You see, goodness has
so little fictional value.
- What does have
fictional value?
- a minister of home security.
Are you saying my husband
is fictional?
no, I'm saying he could be.
In the right hands.
Oh, dear. This is alarming.
Can we get away from
the service for a moment?
You mean change the subject?
I meant fresh air,
actually.
Of course.
So how long
have you been married?
Is your character married?
Yes, he's been married
happily for ten years.
Henry's a perfect model then.
We've been married ten years.
You know that happiness
is even harder to write
than goodness.
Henry prefers habit
to happiness.
- I'll give them to you
to sign tomorrow.
- We were discussing the house
let me take that for you.
[ Henry ]
it's a lovely house.
My wife found it.
Your wife is charming.
She's a great help to me.
Yes, I'm sure.
They've made a picture
of one of your books,
haven't they?
Yes, it's playing at the Rialto.
- I'll take you both.
- I'm far too
busy for pictures,
should I make a note of that?
yes, make sure your character
never gets home before 10:00.
Oh, come out, Henry.
For once?
you know I can't, darling.
But you go.
[ Sarah ]
No, I--
take her, Bendrix.
With Sarah, one has to insist.
Henry--
[ man on film ]
where are you going?
[ Man #2 ] To see wonder.
But you promised!
My dearest promises keep.
[ Woman on film,
indistinct ]
it's not what I wrote.
You can't
keep saying that.
It's true.
♪ I know.
[ "The blue Danube" ] ♪
[ People chattering ]
There was one scene
you did write.
Describe it.
Where he offered her
onions with her meal.
She refused
because her husband
didn't like the smell,
and why did he get angry?
He didn't want to think of her
going home to him.
Does Henry like onions?
No.
I'm in love, you know.
Me too.
Susan?
Come upstairs.
[ Moans ]
[ Moaning ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Cries out ]
[ Panting ]
[ Henry ]
Sarah?
[ Sighs ]
one minute, dear.
What if he heard?
He wouldn't recognize the sound.
♪ [ Woman singing
on phonograph ] ♪
[ Door closes ]
Sarah,
been eating onions?
sorry, darling.
So, Bendrix,
how was the picture?
Up to scratch?
Yeah.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
and, of course,
as she began to love me.
She learned to deceive Henry.
So why was I upset
to find that
two years later...
She was deceiving him again?
Mr. Bendrix, I assume
we are discussing
Mrs. Bendrix?
Not exactly.
She's the wife
of a friend of mine.
Perhaps you and the lady
are intimate?
No. I've only
seen her once since 1944.
I don't understand.
You said this was
a watching case.
Can't one love or hate
as long as that?
There's nothing discreditable
about jealousy, Mr. Bendrix.
I always salute it
as a Mark of true love.
Well, I've come
on behalf of the husband.
He thinks she's deceiving him.
She has secrets.
Ah, secrets.
Yes.
well, there may be
nothing in it, of course.
In my experience, Mr. Bendrix,
there almost invariably is.
Shall my man report to you
or the husband?
uh, to me.
He must know nothing about it.
Ah. A most
interesting case.
Well, all my men
use great discretion.
I will put one on it
immediately,
and he will do his damnedest
to put your mind at rest.
Or should I say, the husband's?
[ Phone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
Hello?
Sarah. Good.
Yes, it was good to see you.
Yes, how long has it been?
Two years.
As long as that.
Well, you were always better
at anniversaries than me.
You want to meet?
Well, whatever for?
Uh, not tomorrow, no.
I've got this article.
Wednesday?
Let me check.
Um, would Thursday do?
Good. The park Lane hotel
at 1:00?
♪ In the night
♪ though we're apart
[ Bendrix narrating ]
it was odd to think that
during the war...
We could be so totally at peace.
[ Air raid siren wailing ]
there were
nights when I wished
♪ ghost of you
♪ my lost romance
♪ lips that laugh
♪ eyes that dance
♪ haunted heart
♪ won't let me be
tell me again.
I love you.
And I always will.
♪ Dreams of dust it's you
♪ who must belong to me
♪ and thrill
♪ my haunted heart
I'm sorry I'm late.
I came by tube,
but it was crowded.
Well, taxi's quicker.
I know.
I didn't want
to be quick.
[ Coughing ]
I've booked a table at Palmer's.
Can't we sit here?
Well, it's where
we always used to go.
But you see,
I've never been back there.
Well, it was never
your restaurant, was it?
so you still go there?
Yeah, two or three
times a week.
It's convenient.
Let's go.
[ Man ]
thank you.
[ Man #2 ] Thanks. Uh-oh.
Sorry about that, mate.
That's quite all right,
sir.
Got my hand caught in the way.
Ah. Such a pleasure
to see you, sir.
It's been so long
I-i thought
you'd forgotten us.
I was afraid
you'd say that.
And you, madam.
It's been
a long time too.
Two years, Alfred.
There.
Thank you.
Why did you lie?
About my coming here?
Yes.
Why did you want to meet?
I wanted to ask you about Henry.
[ Chuckles ]
Henry.
I'm worried about him.
How did you find him
the other night?
was he strange at all?
No, I didn't notice
anything wrong.
I wanted to ask you,
but I know you're very busy,
whether you could
look him up occasionally.
I think he's lonely.
With you?
You know he's never
really noticed me.
Not for years.
Well, maybe you've
given him reason.
What reason could I give?
What reason did you give me?
None.
Are you on a new book?
Of course.
It's not about us,
is it? The one you
threatened to write?
A book takes a year
to write. It's too
hard work for revenge.
If you knew how little
you had to revenge.
I'm joking. Yeah,
we had a good time together.
We're adults, and we knew
it had to end sometime.
Now we can lunch
and talk about Henry.
[ Chuckles ]
[ Coughing ]
[ Coughing continues ]
I'm sorry.
This was stupid.
And I really
shouldn't have called.
That cough needs attending to.
It's only a cough.
Good-bye, Maurice.
Good-bye.
[ Alfred ]
your menu, sir.
Thank you.
I'm sorry. But you
have to realize...
I'm jealous
of everything that moves.
I'm jealous of the rain.
How can you be jealous
of the rain?
Where did you get it?
Spain. That was my war,
I'm afraid.
Finished me off for this one.
You were shot.
How romantic.
Not really.
They put a pin inside me.
[ Chuckles ]
I wondered about the limp.
Could I grow to love it?
And have you?
I have never, ever loved
anyone as much as you.
Thank you.
[ Knocking on door ]
yes?
A Mr. Parkis
to see you, sir.
Show him in.
This way, please.
Thank you.
I'll be with you
in a minute, Mr., um--
the name's Parkis.
Mmm.
Mr. Savage's man.
Sit down, take a cigarette.
Oh, no, sir.
Not on duty, sir.
Unless, of course,
for purposes of concealment.
But you're not on duty now.
Well, in a manner
of speaking, yes, sir.
I've just been relieved
for half an hour
while I make my report.
So there's something to report?
It's not quite a blank sheet.
Have we met
somewhere before, sir?
I don't think so.
Well, like I say, sir.
It's not quite a blank sheet.
But then it never is.
Me and my boy,
we followed the, uh--
your boy?
My son, sir.
Yeah, I'm...
Teaching him the business.
I mean, a boy can be
useful in all sorts of ways.
On the day in question,
the party in question went
by tube to Piccadilly...
And proceeded
to the park Lane hotel.
She seemed quite...
Agitated.
And there met a gentleman
with whom she was
obviously quite close,
since they greeted each other
with an affectionate lack
of ceremony.
And at one point,
although I cannot
be certain of this,
held hands along the bar.
They held hands?
Yes, sir.
The gentleman pushed
the lady's glass
towards her,
and the hand
sort of stayed there
for some time, sir,
which would certainly indicate
a squeeze of that nature.
After a short conversation,
they proceeded to
a restaurant called, uh,
Palmers, which was difficult
to gain access to, me bein'
with the boy and all.
But I observed them
through the window.
And after a while,
the lady left,
laborin', well,
it seemed to me,
under great emotion.
[ Bendrix ]
great emotion.
You're sure of that?
Oh, without doubt, sir.
You see, I then followed
her down charing cross road
to maiden Lane,
where she turned into a church
for what I can only presume
w-w-was a good cry.
She's not a Roman, is she, sir?
No.
[ chuckles ]
Thought not.
She didn't kneel, sir, but sat.
And from
the angle of her face,
I could tell...
Forgive the personal touch.
Of course.
You see, I liked the lady,
the party in question.
- As did I, but you were wrong
about the hands, Mr. Parkis.
- The hands, sir?
We never so much
as touched hands.
Oh, dear.
I have made a fool
of myself.
Sarah has that effect.
Mr. Savage should have
introduced us.
Oh, no, sir.
It was up to me.
Well, it's not serious.
If you look at it
from the outside,
it's quite funny.
But I'm on the inside, sir.
It's not Mr. Savage
I mind about so much.
It's my boy, sir.
And when I tell him
that you're the husband--
yeah, but you're wrong.
I'm acting on
the husband's behalf.
So you've requested
an investigation of yourself?
It's an interesting paradox.
But who's the wrong party
then, sir, if you'll forgive--
pardon me, sir.
I am slow in such matters.
Both you and the husband
have been supplanted
in that lady's affections by--
another?
Try to think of it
the way I do, Mr. Parkis.
Jealousy can only exist
with desire.
You are on a hunt for desire.
Just regard yourself
as its servant.
Of course, sir.
That's my job.
Thank you.
The vicarious lover, Parkis.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
I wondered how much of her
he could reclaim for me.
And for a moment,
I wished I was him,
shining his searchlight
around her world.
[ Narrating continues ]
♪ [ Instrumental
on phonograph ] ♪
I'm jealous
of this stocking.
Why?
Because it does what I can't.
It kisses your whole leg.
And I'm jealous...
Of this button.
Poor, innocent button.
No, it's not innocent
at all.
It's with you all day.
I'm not.
♪ [ Woman singing
on phonograph ] ♪
I suppose you're jealous
of my shoes.
Yes.
Why?
Because they'll take you
away from me.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
I measured love
by the extent of my jealousy.
- And, as my jealousy
was infinite,
- anyone who loves is jealous.
My love should have
been infinite too.
[ Air raid siren wailing ]
I hate you being unhappy.
I don't mind anything you do
that makes you happy.
And if I slept
with someone else?
that's neither here nor there.
I want you to be happy,
that's all.
Maybe you'd want an excuse
to do the same.
I never would.
But you do.
Do what?
Sleep with
someone else.
You mean Henry?
- How can anyone be jealous
of Henry?
- he has you.
[ Distant explosions ]
I don't.
We inhabit the same house,
that's all. You know that.
I'm the shadow
he walks around.
And I love you.
I would rather be dead
or see you dead
than with another man.
[ Explosions continue,
louder ]
I will never, ever be
you may see me dead,
but I will never be
with another man.
We should go down
to the shelter.
Stay here, Sarah.
If a bomb hit us now,
think of what wouldn't happen.
What wouldn't happen?
You wouldn't leave at 9:00
or walk back across
the square to Henry.
I would never imagine
another lover.
My jealousy would end.
Would that make you happy?
[ Rumbling ]
[ Explosion ]
[ Explosions continue ]
[ Breathing heavily ]
[ Gasping, yells ]
Do you believe me now?
[ Bendrix narrating ]
but, sadly,
I didn't believe her.
There was a devil in my mind
that would never let me.
And now I had Parkis' boy
playing the devil's game.
[ Clock ticking ]
[ Door opens ]
[ Door closes ]
[ Parkis ]
my boy managed
to gain access, sir.
Remarkably useful, he can be.
I call that exhibit "a."
[ Sarah's voice ]
They say a promise is forever,
but I don't know
if I can keep this one.
He killed me with jealousy.
You're killing me with love.
So, he's got the scent too,
Parkis.
What scent?
The scent of love.
Stalking it like a retriever.
Well, he's remarkably
persistent, sir.
He observed
the party in question,
then in a state
of partial undress,
with an unidentified male.
Where?
In the bedroom, sir.
The male party
then closed the door,
and my boy made his exit.
The implication,
and I think you would agree,
is that... intimacy
was, uh,
imminent.
Indeed. Who is he?
Well, now, here, sir,
is where our progress
was definitely made.
As my boy left, he glanced
at the appointment book
in the front hallway.
Now, the party in question
had a dental appointment
at 3:30 the following day.
And, in fact,
she visited at 3:30 a premises
on 65 cedar road...
Where no dentist's sign
was in evidence.
[ Doorbell ringing ]
A Mr. Smythe
owns the premises, sir.
[ Chuckles ]
"Smythe." with a "Y"?
Yes, sir.
S-m-y-t-h-e.
And, uh, no--
[ clears throat ]
though we had no, uh,
evidence... of intimacy,
the implication
is clearly there.
How is it there?
Why, the fictitious
dental appointment, sir.
Exhibit "B."
My boy took that.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
And the party in question
emerged two hours later.
Passage of time being
amply sufficient for, um,
intimacy to have taken place.
The courts generally demand
at least an hour, sir.
Now, my boy would have
provided us with photos
of her reemergence,
but for the, uh,
unfortunate occurrence
of him fallin' asleep.
Luckily, sir, the, uh,
party in question...
Mistook him
for an abandoned urchin,
are you lost?
Woke him up and led him
to the nearest tube station.
So the time of reemergence
is definitely established,
as was an acquaintance,
which may have its uses
in the future,
for all we know, sir.
So, should I walk in
and confront him
like the injured husband?
I'm against it, sir.
It complicates things
in the courts.
This will never reach court.
An amicable settlement then.
There's lack of interest.
One can hardly make a fuss
about a man called Smythe.
I'd just like to see him,
that's all.
Well,
perhaps Lance can oblige
us next time with a frontal.
My boy.
Called after Lancelot.
The round table.
He found the holy grail.
That was Galahad.
Lancelot was found in bed
with Guinevere.
I hadn't heard.
I have to say, sir,
I would advise against it.
Oh, I'd just like to see
what a man called Smythe
looks like.
Will you lend me your boy?
Well, if you assure me
there'll be
nothing unpleasant.
Well, Sarah isn't there.
This scene will have
a universal certificate.
Come with me, young Lancelot.
Now, go on, Lance.
No need to worry.
Now, you're feeling ill,
remember?
How ill, sir?
I'll enough to faint.
Can you act that?
Well, if I hold my breath
I can go all pale, sir.
Good.
[ Doorbell ringing ]
Excuse me, but doesn't
Dr. Wilson live here?
No, I'm afraid he doesn't.
Oh, dear.
See, I was given this address,
and my boy is quite ill,
and we've traveled all this way.
Are you all right?
would you mind?
you'd better come in.
I'm sorry. Thank you.
I think he needs to sit down.
Yes. Oh.
Thank you.
Can I fetch him
a glass of water?
That's very kind.
Or some orange squash?
Water will be fine.
Orange squash, please.
Say thank you, Arthur.
Is his name Arthur?
Yes. Arthur James.
His mother was fond
of Tennyson.
Is she--
yes. Yes, four years now.
- He must be a great comfort
to you.
- And anxiety.
I ought to introduce myself.
Bridges.
Oh, my name is Smythe.
With a "Y"?
Yes. Oh, this is
my brother, Richard.
This is Mr. Bridges.
His boy isn't feeling well.
Huh.
I was given this address
for a Dr. Wilson.
Hmm. There's no such
doctor here.
I've seen your boy before.
Uh, maybe on the common.
What was the real purpose
of your visit?
I told you, a doctor.
No, you're not ill,
are you, boy? Hmm?
People sometimes come to me...
And can't explain why.
But if there is a reason--
[ miss Smythe ]
my brother often deals--
hush, Susan.
They must ask themselves.
I recognize your boy.
But you--
who recommended you?
we have a friend
in common.
Sarah miles.
And your name is?
Bendrix.
I know all about you.
I'm sure you do.
But you must enlighten me.
- Aren't you bound
by vows of chastity?
- oh, my dear!
Go, please.
Would you just go?
Come along, Lancelot.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
poor Sarah.
She had committed
nothing but love...
And here were Parkis
and his boy watching
her every move.
I would've
called the spies off
had the devil not tugged
Henry.
Still in the rain?
Walking, Bendrix.
Doctor recommends it.
Well, walk with me.
I recommend a drink.
[ Cash register dinging ]
[ Sighs ]
How's Sarah?
Pretty well.
Did you ever consult
that private detective?
I'd hoped you'd forgotten that.
I was overworked, and I had
royal commission brewing.
Well, don't worry, Henry.
I did it for you.
You had absolutely no right.
- No, I'm paying
all the charges.
- It's infernal cheek.
Here's the report, Henry.
His name is Smythe,
with a "Y."
You've been promptly led up
the garden path, Henry.
Will you let me pass?
You don't want them?
photographs, names,
love letters?
[ Jabbing papers ]
And now will you let me go?
I can always get you
a carbon copy.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
strange how much dignity
there can be in a hat.
Without it,
he seemed one
of the anonymous,
the dispossessed.
I had pitied myself
for so long,
it was odd to pity him.
I'm sorry, Henry.
Sit down.
Were you two lovers, Bendrix?
It's the only explanation.
The only excuse too.
Can't you see that
what you've done...
Is monstrous?
You must think me a fool
not to have guessed.
Why didn't she leave me?
Because you're a habit
she's formed.
You're her security.
Why did she leave you?
I became a bore, like you.
But I wasn't born one.
You created me.
She wouldn't leave you
so I bored her
with my jealousy.
You can't be jealous of me.
Well, you won, in a way.
We had come to the end of love.
She'd only make love with me,
but she could shop and cook
and fall asleep with you.
She's still very fond of you.
One isn't satisfied
with fondness.
I was.
Yes, and that made you
her pimp.
The bore of a husband
who knows where
his slippers are...
But never notices his wife.
But you weren't
the only pimp, Henry.
The war was the greatest
pimp of all.
And the V-1s
never affected us until...
The act of love was over.
♪ [ Airplanes
roaring overhead ]
[ Woman singing
[ explosion ]
[ Shouting ]
[ Explosions continue ]
♪ [ Continues ]
So what will you do
when it ends?
It won't end, I told you.
I meant the war.
It's the only certain thing.
What do you mean?
It allows me to see you.
[ Airplane roaring overhead ]
You think love ends
when you don't see me?
To be is to be perceived.
[ Chuckles ]
do I exist for you
when you're with him?
Yes.
[ roaring continues ]
Isn't that why you stay
with Henry?
Because you know this will end?
No.
[ loud explosion ]
We should go to the basement.
My landlady
might be there.
Does that matter?
Maybe to her.
It's close, Maurice.
Let me go with you.
I'll go and check.
I'll be one second.
Hello?
There's nobody there.
It's clear.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
I never heard the bang.
I awoke after five minutes
or five seconds...
To a changed world.
For a moment,
I was free of feeling...
Love, hate, jealousy.
And it all felt like happiness.
Sarah.
Oh, my god.
You're alive?
You sound disappointed.
You're hurt.
I'm all right.
I just cut myself, that's all.
What were you doing
on the floor?
Praying.
To what?
To anything that might exist.
Well,
it'd have been more practical
to have come downstairs.
I did.
Then why didn't you wake me?
I tried.
You didn't move.
I don't understand.
I knew for certain
you were dead.
There wasn't much to pray for,
then, was there?
A miracle.
And we don't believe
in those.
No.
[ Air raid siren wailing ]
And that siren means you go.
[ Whispers ]
yes.
Please don't.
I have to.
Henry'll be--
well, forget Henry.
- I don't understand.
You were gone.
- Now I'm back.
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
Sarah.
Love doesn't end...
Just because
we don't see each other.
Doesn't it?
People go on loving god,
don't they,
all their lives...
Without seeing him?
That's not my kind of love.
Maybe there's no other kind.
So I was a disappointment
in the end.
I lived.
And that was the end
of the affair...
Until I met you
with that detective's card
in your hand.
I wondered why
we hadn't seen you.
You should go home, Henry.
You'll catch your death.
I'm sorry.
Hello.
♪ [ Orchestral ]
[ Parkis ]
it was quite easy, sir.
There was such a crush.
And Mrs. Miles thought
I was one of his friends
from the ministry.
And Mr. Miles thought
I was one of her friends.
Well, I knew the way
to her room from my boy.
Anybody would have stopped me,
I would've been looking
for the toilet.
Of course, nobody did.
[ Bendrix ]
did you think it was
a good cocktail party?
[ Parkis ]
highly successful,
I would say, sir.
But Mrs. Miles looked
a bit out of sorts.
I refer to this
as exhibit "B."
Did you look at it?
I ascertained its nature, sir.
And, from one entry, judged
she wasn't the cautious type.
[ Sarah's voice ]
so happy.
"M" returns today.
My experience of diaries
is that they always give
things away, sir.
People invent their
little codes. You soon
see through them, sir.
[ Sarah's voice ]
I woke up,
and the sun was shining.
This covers several years.
[ Parkis ]
I hope you're
satisfied, sir.
[ Sarah's voice ] life was
going to be happy again,
but last night I dreamt--
I think this may well
close our account, Parkis.
Yeah, I had a feeling
it might, sir.
I have enjoyed
our association, sir,
if one can talk of enjoying
under the sad circumstances.
As have I.
So I hope you wouldn't
resent a memento, sir.
There's quite a history
with that. You remember
the Bolton case?
Uh, I can't say I do.
Caused quite a stir
at the time, sir.
Lady Bolton, her maid
and the man,
all discovered together.
That ashtray stood
beside the bed, sir.
On the lady's side.
I shall treasure it, Parkis.
If ashtrays could speak, sir.
Indeed.
Perhaps I should call later,
just to make sure
there were no loose ends.
Thank you, Parkis.
Good night, sir.
Good night.
[ Sarah's voice ] sometimes
I get tired of trying to
convince him that I love him..
And shall love him forever.
He pounces on my words
like a barrister
and twists them.
[ Bendrix ]
so what will you do
when it ends?
You think love ends
when you don't see me?
To be is to be perceived.
Do I exist for you
when you're with Henry?
Yes.
Isn't that why
you stay with Henry?
Because you know this will end?
No.
[ loud explosion ]
We should go to the basement.
My landlady
might be there.
Does that matter?
Maybe to her.
It's close, Maurice.
I'll go and check.
Let me go with you.
I'll be one second.
Hello?
There's nobody there.
It's clear.
Maurice!
[ Coughing ]
Oh, god!
Oh, god.
Oh, god, don't take him.
[ Sarah's voice ]
but you had.
Maurice.
Whatever was him was gone.
You'd taken it.
Maurice.
I've never believed
in prayer.
God, please bring him back.
Let him live.
I don't believe
in you, but please,
let him live.
Dear god, please...
Let him--
Maurice.
Maurice!
[ Sobbing ]
dear god, please let him live.
Please bring him back.
Please don't take him.
I'll give him up forever.
Only please, let him be alive.
Let him live, and I promise...
I'll never see him again.
Sarah?
Oh, my god.
You're alive?
[ Bendrix ]
you sound disappointed.
[ Sarah's voice ]
but if he was alive,
now I was dead.
Sarah.
What were you doing
on the floor?
Praying.
To what?
to anything
that might exist.
[ Sarah narrating ]
how could I explain to him...
What made no sense to me?
You didn't move.
I knew for certain
you were dead.
There wasn't much
to pray for then, was there?
a miracle.
And we don't believe in that.
[ Air raid siren wailing ]
And that siren means you go.
Yes.
[ Sarah's voice ]
and I knew that nothing
in this world...
Would make sense to me again.
Sorry to disappoint you.
Sarah.
Love doesn't end...
Just because we don't
see each other.
Doesn't it?
people go on
loving god, don't they,
all their lives...
Without seeing him?
That's not my kind of love.
Maybe there's no other kind.
[ Men chattering ]
[ Sarah narrating ]
I can't be held
to that promise.
But something told me
I would be.
I had tempted fate,
and fate had accepted.
So I was in the desert now,
a desert without him.
I started a tour with Henry--
civil defense
in Southern England--
Henry and I
sleeping side by side
like figures on tombs.
In the new reinforced shelter
at Bigwell-on-Sea,
the chief warden kissed me.
I allowed him to,
but felt nothing.
I'm beginning
to believe in you, god.
And maybe that's how you work.
You empty me of love,
then fill that emptiness.
[ Henry ]
they're recommending me
for an O.B.E.
[ Sarah ]
what's that?
Step below a C.B.E.
When I retire,
I'll probably be a K.B.E.
It's confusing.
Couldn't they stick
to the same letters?
Would you like to be lady miles?
[ Man narrating newsreel ]
this was the British people's
finest day--
V.E. day--
the end of the German war.
A man we seem to have seen
before somewhere...
Looks down from a balcony
in Whitehall.
[ Cheering ]
[ Sarah narrating ]
the whole of London seemed
happy because there was peace.
And there were no more bombs.
But I'm not sure
I like the peace.
I walked his walks,
tried to think where he'd be.
Then I gave up.
I thought that now
the world is at peace,
maybe I should have some.
I told him it all.
And whoever heard my promise
must have heard it too...
And must have known it already,
since god knows everything.
How cruel that knowledge seemed.
It knew what I would say
before I made that promise.
Knew it would keep me to it.
Knew me the way
his hands knew me.
[ Henry ]
Sarah, darling.
Henry.
You.
knew I would meet him
on the stairs.
Been out for a walk?
Yes.
It's a filthy night.
You're wet through,
Sarah.
One day you'll catch
your death of cold.
Good night.
Knew he would hate me.
Wednesday.
[ Bendrix ] Wednesday?
let me check.
Uh, would Thursday do?
Thursday, then.
The park Lane hotel
at 1:00?
I took my time.
I didn't want to be early.
Why did you want to meet?
[ Sarah narrating ]
I wanted to tell you I've been
dead for the past two years.
I can't be without you
any longer.
I think he's lonely.
But of course, I didn't.
He's never really noticed me.
Not for years.
Maybe you've given him reason.
What reason could I give?
What reason did you give me?
None.
Are you on a new book?
Of course.
It's not about us, is it?
the one you threatened
to write?
A book takes a year to write.
It's too hard
work for revenge.
If you knew how little
you have to revenge--
I'm joking.
We had a good time together.
I mean, we're adults...
And we knew it had
to end sometime.
And now we can lunch
and talk about Henry.
[ Sarah narrating ]
in the old days,
he would have followed.
We would've made up.
Or made love.
I said to god,
as I might've
said to my father,
"dear god, I'm tired.
"I'm tired of being without him.
And it's all because of you."
Dr. Gilbert's appointment.
I'd almost forgotten.
He asked me how I felt.
I said I felt nothing.
There was a stone
where my heart should be.
I need help, father.
Sarah, god granted us free will.
Good. So it's settled.
I'm leaving my husband.
You can't.
Why can't I?
I'm a whore and a liar.
I'm asking Henry for a divorce.
You can't...
Because you're good.
Better than any person I know.
You're wrong, father.
And you don't know me.
[ Sarah narrating ]
I found a small boy
sleeping on the steps...
With a birthmark
covering his face...
And wondered what kind of god
would give a child that.
Are you lost?
It's all right.
Where do you live, then?
You'll be
all right, now?
yes, ma'am.
I kissed his cheek and wished
I could wash it away.
And suddenly I felt happy again.
I could free myself of this.
I...
Am leaving you.
For the last...
Five years,
I have been...
In love...
With Maurice.
[ Henry ]
I love you.
Do you know that?
Why now, Henry?
Why do you say that now?
I had a drink with Bendrix.
A horrible drink.
[ Whispering ]
I can't do without you.
Oh, yes, you can, I thought.
You changed
your newspaper once,
and you soon got used to it.
What's wrong, Henry?
Did Bendrix upset you
in some way?
I know I haven't been
much of a husband
to you, my dear.
We are good friends.
You can do without a friend.
Don't leave me, Sarah.
Stick it out a few more years.
I'll try.
I promise.
Is this coincidence, I wondered,
or the way life happens?
And if this is life,
am I stuck with it?
But whatever it is,
I can't fight it anymore.
It has won...
And we have lost.
[ Phone ringing ]
[ Ringing continues ]
Hello?
[ Bendrix ]
Sarah.
She's not here.
I know your voice, Sarah.
Talk to me.
Sarah!
Sarah.
[ Sobbing ]
Stop here.
- Thank you.
- [ Man ]
Thank you very much, gov.
One, please.
Ticket, sir.
Sarah.
How did you get it?
[ Sighs ]
you had a drinks
party last week.
Yes.
That small man.
He is my snoop.
Oh, Maurice.
How ridiculous.
It's no more
ridiculous than you.
Why didn't you tell me?
I tried.
Each time I tried,
something would happen.
That's mumbo-jumbo,
Sarah.
No, it doesn't work like that.
Accidents.
Little things.
God is in
the details, Maurice.
You can't believe that.
Do you believe
in things you can't see?
You mean him?
I mean you.
You see,
I never stopped loving you,
even though I couldn't see you.
My mother baptized me
a catholic.
My father was Jewish,
so we never practiced.
But she always said
she hoped it would "take."
Like a vaccination.
I've only made
two promises in my life.
One was to marry Henry,
the other to stop seeing you.
And I'm too weak to keep either.
I know you don't believe in him,
but try to.
Talk to him.
I can't.
Tell him I'm sorry.
I'm too human,
too weak.
Tell him
I can't keep my promises.
I'm tired of being without you.
Let's get you home.
[ Sobbing ]
I don't want to go home.
I know.
So have we broken the spell?
The world didn't end, did it?
It did, in a way.
But then it always did.
Can I sleep now, Maurice?
Please let me sleep.
[ Doorbell ringing ]
It's Henry.
Don't answer it.
Why not? We'll have
to tell him sometime.
Come away with me.
Where?
Anywhere.
Brighton.
I want a few days' peace
before the arguments begin.
Henry never argues.
I wasn't talking about Henry.
[ Man chattering ]
[ Bendrix narrating ]
pain is easy to write.
In pain, we're all
drably individual.
But what can one write
about happiness?
[ Screaming ]
whoo!
[ Both laughing, shouting ]
It doesn't suit you,
and it's mine!
you want it?
There's a price.
How much?
Can I pay again?
I want children,
you know.
How many?
We'll start
with one.
Only one?
You want to start with two?
Is that a promise?
Yes.
[ Coughing ]
Let's get you back to the hotel.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
[ Chattering ]
Still on the job, Parkis?
don't worry. Don't worry.
[ Gasps ] Oh, dear.
Come with me.
Come.
So where's your boy this time?
I left him
at home, sir.
Hardly a wise move.
He'd have had the sense
not to get noticed.
You think so, sir?
perhaps I wasn't cut out
for this job.
Tell your employer
the circumstances are unique.
That-- what was your phrase?
the party in question
is a writer.
They notice everything.
They certainly
seem to, sir.
So who's hired you this time?
I'm not at Liberty to say.
Let me guess:
The jealous husband.
I never expected to be
recalled to this case, sir.
Yours is a secure
profession, Parkis.
As long as fools
like us love, your
employment never ends.
You could put it like that.
And love never ends, does it?
It seems not, sir.
What do you need,
Parkis?
Photographs of us
in flagrante delicto?
Copies of hotel bills?
evidence of soiled sheets?
we'd be happy to oblige.
No. My brief
is to follow you.
Inform him
as to your whereabouts.
Which, of course,
you'll do.
I'm obliged to, sir,
under the terms
of my employment,
posthaste.
But won't you need
supplementary evidence?
divorce courts will demand it.
They generally do, sir,
if it come to that.
Well, exhibit "a."
Um, receipt for
two sandwiches bought
on the train to Brighton.
Mutual sandwiches are surely
evidence of intimacy,
aren't they?
They could be so construed, sir.
Exhibit "b" --
two tickets for a big Dipper.
[ Sighs ] you seem to be
doing my job for me, sir.
But we haven't got there.
I mean, what would
clinch it for us, Parkis?
What would make
divorce a certainty?
Generally, sir,
some kind of
photographic evidence of, um--
of intimacy.
W-would be
most useful, sir,
if it came to such a pass.
It will, Parkis.
It most certainly will.
Sarah.
[ Coughing ]
I dreamt
we had a child.
We will.
We were on the bed together.
The room filled up with water.
There was a child between us.
Why water?
The sea had come in the window.
[ Camera shutter clicks ]
So, you'll marry me.
That's a promise.
The prince regent began
building it for his mistress,
Mrs. Fitzherbert.
Beautiful but flawed.
How was she flawed?
She was catholic.
Impossible, of course.
So he loved her?
Yes, but he married
Princess Caroline
of Brunswick,
who was protestant.
But huge. And he built
this huge folly
to impossibility.
Not now, Henry.
Forgive me, Sarah.
I had to.
- Oh, god.
Please, Henry. Not now.
- You had to what, Henry?
Talk.
Go back home, Henry.
You can't hold on
to her forever.
I know, but--
it hardly suits you,
Henry--
the role of a jealous husband.
Please, Bendrix.
I don't mean
to make a scene.
Go home.
I'm not jealous, Bendrix.
What was it you said?
Lovers are jealous.
Husbands are ridiculous.
I was never her lover.
Not much
of a husband either,
I'm afraid.
But you hired our detective.
I had to find out where she was.
So you know.
She wants a divorce.
That won't be possible, old man.
You'll contest it?
No.
But it would take
at least three months.
What's three months, Henry,
out of a lifetime?
Half.
Half of what?
Of a lifetime, I'm afraid.
Sarah's dying, Bendrix.
Her doctor called the night
she didn't come back...
With the result of some tests.
I knocked on your door.
I imagined you were both there.
H-how oddly we behave
at such moments.
You shouldn't get wet, darling.
Don't you like the rain, Henry?
Yes, dear, but--
you've had news, Henry.
Is it good?
No, dear.
You see, Maurice?
Never make a promise.
You may have to keep it.
You should never have been
jealous of me, Bendrix.
I did Sarah
a great disservice
when I married her.
I realize that now.
I'm not the sort
that makes a lover.
She wanted someone like you.
I'm not sure
it's as simple as that.
If you don't mind me asking,
I'd like you there
when the time comes.
It may not come, Henry.
You of all
people don't believe
in miracles, Bendrix.
No, but Sarah does.
See, I always believed
that I'd be the one
to die first,
and that Sarah would
know what to do.
Are you at a loss, Henry?
I am, quite.
And it would save you a bit...
If you moved in with us.
Sarah always said your books
weren't as successful
as they should have been.
You could be there,
working in the daytime
while I'm at the ministry.
And at night,
we could both--
[ Bendrix narrating ]
and so I moved to the north
side of the common.
[ Doorbell rings ]
and oddly enough,
I felt instantly at home.
[ Ring ]
Oh.
Can I help you, father?
I've come about Mrs. Miles.
She's indisposed.
You mean she's ill, don't you?
Yes, I suppose I do.
Yes.
She's been to see me
several times.
And I know she would
like to see me before--
she left word with me
she is not to be disturbed.
Is her husband here?
No.
She told me about you.
I know she did.
I'm the lover, father.
Who was that?
The postman.
What did he bring?
He had the wrong address.
How odd for a postman.
You know what happened that day?
You thought I was dead,
and I wasn't.
No, darling.
Something happened in that room.
There were the same
walls around me,
the same sunlight
coming in the window.
But nothing would ever be
the same again.
You can't believe this, Sarah.
[ Whispering ]
but it's true.
I never loved anyone
as I loved you.
Then when you came
through that door
with blood on your face,
another kind of love
came with you.
And I caught belief...
Like a disease.
[ Whispering ]
I fell into belief
like I'd...
Fallen into love.
And I tried to fight it,
but I haven't any fight left.
It wasn't the postman, was it?
No, it wasn't.
Dear Maurice,
you can't go on fighting.
It's only love, after all.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
so, you're taking her.
But you haven't got me yet.
I don't want your peace
and your love.
I wanted Sarah for a lifetime.
And you're taking her from me.
So I hate you, god.
I hate you
as though you existed.
[ Henry ]
Bendrix!
You have to help me,
Bendrix. I can't.
I will.
I can't live in a world
where she's gone.
I'll help you.
I would have taken care
of all the arrangements
if I'd known.
Surely you disapprove
of cremation.
I would've arranged
a catholic burial.
But she wasn't a catholic,
was she, Henry?
We recognize
the baptism of desire.
She said things
that seemed like prayers.
We've made all
the arrangements.
We can't alter things now,
you wouldn't want talk, Henry.
There's
the notice in the times.
No, no.
If you'd come
a little sooner, father.
Please don't think--
I think nothing bad
of you, Mr. Miles.
Perhaps me.
Don't worry,
Mr. Bendrix.
Nothing you can do
will affect her now.
She was a good woman.
She was nothing
of the sort. Bendrix!
She could put the blinkers
on any man. She deceived you,
father, her husband and me.
She was a consummate liar.
[ Henry ]
You've no right.
[ Father ]
let the poor man rave.
Don't give me professional pity!
- Keep it for
your confessional.
- You can find me there
I don't want you, father.
I'm no Sarah.
[ Henry ] Sorry, father.
No need to be. You see,
I know when a man is in pain.
I'm not in pain, father.
I'm in hate.
I hate Sarah
because she was a tart
to your mumbo-jumbo.
I hate Henry
because she stuck to him.
And I hate you and your
imaginary god because you took
her away from all of us.
[ Scoffs ]
you are a good hater.
To hell with all of you!
I'm sorry, Henry.
The thing is, Bendrix,
I always knew.
I knew she was with someone.
But I never thought you.
The odd thing is,
I'm glad it was.
It's a sad pleasure
to see you here, sir,
where bygones
are always bygones.
Do you always follow
your people as far as this?
She was a very fine lady, sir.
At the cocktail party,
she handed me
a glass of Sherry.
Was it south African Sherry?
I wouldn't know, sir.
There weren't many like her.
My boy, now,
he's always speaking of her.
How is your boy, Parkis?
He's exceptionally well, sir,
but he's a bit upset today.
He imagined she'd be buried
in a catholic way.
And why would he think that?
Young boys, sir,
they get these ideas.
Though I have to admit,
even I can't explain it.
Explain what?
On the day of her assignation,
she walked him to a tube.
She thought he was lost,
gave him a coin, and
kissed him on his cheek.
On his affected cheek, sir.
And over the weeks
that followed,
his affliction
gradually went away.
I tried to keep him
rational, but he swears
it was because of her.
Say hello
to Mr. Bendrix, Lance.
Hello, sir.
[ Bendrix narrating ]
I wrote at the start
that this was a diary of hate.
I hated you
as though you existed.
Now I'm tired of hating,
but you're still here.
So your cunning is infinite.
You used my hate to win
my acknowledgement.
Thank you, Henry.
And I've only one prayer left.
Dear god, forget about me.
Look after her and Henry.
♪ In the night
♪ though we're apart
♪ there's a ghost of you
♪ within my haunted heart
♪ ghost of you
♪ my lost romance
♪ lips that laugh
♪ eyes that dance
♪ haunted heart
♪ won't let me be
♪ dreams repeat a sweet
♪ but lonely song to me
♪ dreams of dust
it's you who must
♪ belong to me
♪ and thrill
♪ my haunted heart
♪ be still
♪
♪ Dreams of dust
it's you who must
♪ belong to me
♪ and thrill
♪ my haunted heart
♪ be still
♪ my haunted
♪ heart