The restoration of Roma (1972)
was created from the 35mm version
held by Titanus
at the Cineteca di Bologna.
In 1972, after the first screening
ofthe film in Rome,
Fellini, along with the producer
and screenwriter Bernardino Zapponi,
decided to shorten some sequences
for the international market.
Only traces remain of these shots
in the production documentation
and the Deposito Legale's
positive print version,
stored at the
CSC - National Film Archive.
This copy is the version
for the international market.
The restoration was carried out
at the Immagine Ritrovata lab,
Bologna, in 2010.
- He's written from America.
- What does he say?
They eat everything
out of cans over there.
The first image of Rome
was a centuries-old stone
rising out ofthe field
just outside my hometown.
Later on, at school, we were told
other interesting things about Rome.
This is the Rubicon...
the river Julius Caesar crossed,
sayin'g, ''Alea iacta est!''
- Take offyour shoes, children.
- Take offyour shoes
and we'll cross the river together.
Alea iacta est!
- To Rome.
- To Rome!
The fascist shit, his head is split -
half a head, they say
Crossed the Rubicon one day
and lost his balls along the way
Now we've got another meanie
by the name of Mussolini
Julius Caesar took a chance
and led his army into France
in those days, the French were Gauls
and Caesar a man with balls
Bring me then Metellus Cimbers'
petition and I shall examine it.
And now, hands, speak for me.
You too, Brutus?
My son.
Julius Caesar.
Sir, if I may say so,
last night you had us all in tears.
It was a truly artistic performance.
Eternal gratitude
to our humble web-footed friends.
To our humble web-footed friends
with their excited quacking.
It's always that one, sir.
Always the same one.
Woke the soldiers who picked up
their weapons and saved Rome.
And you can hear their descendants
quacking right outside the window.
Careful, now. Careful.
Return to your seats.
I won't tolerate any disorder.
Stop it.
You are not out in the streets now.
You're in school!
Barbetti! Stacchiotti! Ballazzi!
I'll beat you to death, by God!
...in saecula saeculorum, amen.
On your feet.
Rings.
Napkins.
Dismissed.
Silence. Order.
Order and silence.
The bronze she-wolf
at the Capitol.
Santa Maria Maggiore,
one ofthe four Roman basilicas.
The tomb of Cecilia Metella
on the Appia Antica.
The Arch of Constantine.
The altar ofthe fatherland.
St Peter's,
Holy Mother Church's greatest temple.
Turn it off!
Turn on the lights, somebody!
The lights!
Don't look, children.
Close your eyes. It's the devil.
Whoever looks will go to hell.
Keep your eyes closed.
- It's the devil! The devil!
- Good Lord! On your feet!
But church bells
are the voice of God.
We should turn
on the radio, signora.
- There's a blessing from the Pope.
- Just bring the soup here, you idiot!
- Stay where you are!
- But, Severino, it's a papal blessing.
So put it on the salad!
- Shame on you. You'll go to hell.
- Stay where you are.
On your knees. Don't pay attention
to your good-for-nothing father.
Drop dead, you old bat!
For heaven's sake, folks, there's
no need to push. We've got enough seats.
Three adults, two children
and one maid. What?
Full price for a maid?
Well, I'll be damned.
Shut up!
Adele, keep an eye on that kid.
Carmela, the baby!
Hang on to my coat and follow me.
Excuse me. Pardon me.
Besides, there's three shows today.
Come back later.
May the gods smile upon you,
Pompeo.
I have come
to bid you farewell.
With what adventures,
Priscilla the Christian?
I have a generous nature.
But vengeance is a temptress.
- Be on your guard, both ofyou.
- And yet, i love her.
No, no, have mercy!
I beg you, mercy!
Let me go!
There are some seats. Hurry! Adele!
Leonina! You sit over there.
- My wife's purse was on that seat.
- Purses don't count.
Carmela, the baby!
Sir, you are an ill-mannered boor,
that's what you are.
And you don't seem to realise who I am.
I'm the school principal, that's who.
The principal, understand?
Rome: the parade of October 28
was in an atmosphere of enthusiasm.
The entire city was there to greet
our leader and proclaim its faith
in the glorious and indomitable
destiny ofthe imperial fatherland.
His Excellency S. De Carolis
took part in the jump through the hoop.
What a man.
Sons ofthe she-wolf
flocked to the beaches of Rome
where Italians and their automobiles
paraded to the songs ofthe revolution
followed by a box lunch which included
bread, famous national cheeses
and piping red tea.
Florence.
The magnificent stone walls
ofthe Pitti Palace
seem to smile
beneath the warm spring sunshine.
This lady was the wife
ofthe local chemist.
Everyone said
she was worse than Messalina.
And no need to play with yourself.
That's what's nice about Rome.
It's big and nobody knows you.
You are free to come and go.
What about the Roman women?
What are they like?
The Roman women?
They've got an ass as wide as that.
Quit fucking around
and get out of my way.
Don't worry. I'm going.
Get your lottery tickets here.
- Hey there, need a lighter?
- No, thanks. I've already got one.
I'll give you, as a present,
a bolt offirst-class English wool.
- Got a place to sleep tonight?
- In via Albalonga.
I have a room with your own entrance
and a cute little French girl.
No.
Hotel Dragoni.
Hotel Dragoni!
veal at eight lire a kilo.
What's this world coming to?
There's only two things
you can be sure of.
That's right.
Death and taxes.
- I'm looking for the Palletta family.
- Fourth floor.
The elevator's broken.
David, I'm going to beat
the hell out ofyou.
There, stupid!
You always do it wrong.
Where can I find
the Palletta family?
Thank you.
He says to me, ''Are you kidding me,
or are you really stupid?''
''What do you mean?''
And he says, ''Come on. You must
be kidding.'' I say, ''What do you mean?''
- So?
- What do you mean, so?
The solemn military and religious rites
at the tomb ofthe unknown...
I'm gonna throw the cat
out the window!
His Excellency
Count Racobelli attended
and Mons. Troisi Ragusa was there
to represent the Holy Sea.
Hey! Listen.
Ciao. Is your mother home?
Hello?
Anybody home?
Signora?
Antonietta! I did it!
Stay there a minute.
I'm coming.
- There's someone at the door.
- I did it! I did it!
Signora,
that young man is here,
the one whose mother wrote you
from up north.
Shall I let him in?
- How do you do?
- I was making pasta. Let me help you.
- Come in. Come in, please.
- Thanks.
Make yourself at home.
The signora's not feeling very well.
Come on. This way.
One of her ovaries is inflamed.
We'll just set it down here, all right?
Come on. I'll show you the house.
Come in, come in.
I hope you don't mind children,
because there's a lot ofthem living here.
This is the dining room.
Florentine furniture. Nice, eh?
- That's the signora's eldest son.
- Who is it?
He's going to work as a clerk.
- Why did you have to go to the beach?
- How do you do?
- Why shouldn't I have gone?
- Did you have to go at noon?
When, then?
My poor baby.
A bad sunburn, eh?
Do you have a fever?
I think so, yeah.
- Nice shirt you've got there.
- Thank you.
Are you afraid of Chinamen? He is one
and he's even got kitchen privileges.
My God, it stinks in here. Why don't
you open the window when you cook?
Bucatini matriciana sauce.
Have some?
- No, thank you.
- very good. Delicious.
Let me out of here
before I throw up.
Bucatini matriciana.
Yeah, for pigs.
Signora,
shall I show him the kitchen?
Yes, honey,
show him the kitchen.
Oh, my God! What have I done
to deserve such suffering?
The kitchen's this way.
- After you.
- No, please, after you.
Antonietta, I did it!
I did it! I did it!
All right, so you did it.
You don't have to broadcast it.
Just a moment.
- Ciao.
- Good afternoon.
- What did you bring me?
- Nothing, yet. What do you want?
How about you?
Do you think there'll be a war?
- Want to see the little granny?
- Sure. That's why I came.
Follow me.
She's littler than us kids.
Little granny!
Look who's here!
- Bless you.
- Thank you, and same to you.
Bet your granny's not that little.
- What's this?
- This is my room.
I haven't tidied up yet.
- It's nice and sunny.
- Will you put down those scissors!
Good afternoon.
Landi is the name. Marco Landi.
- Remember me?
- I think so.
I made my debut with Camerini
and I worked a lot with Gennaro Righelli.
I play the part ofthe bon vivant.
- I was the butler in Heartthrob.
- Yes, of course.
- But you're much too young to remember.
- No, I do. I really do.
By the way, you're a reporter,
aren't you?
- I could give you an interview.
- Sure, except I'm not working yet.
My friends, we have a newspaper
reporter among us.
- Hello.
- I presume you will be staying here.
- Enjoy your meal.
I refuse to believe that the people
of Great Britain, always friends,
feel it their duty to lead Europe
into a catastrophe
by defending an African nation.
The resemblance is frightening.
Universally branded and without
the shadow of any kind of civilization
against this nation of heroes,
artists, poets, saints, navigators...
- Lucrezia!
- What do you want, Ma?
Send the young man in here.
I want to have a look.
- Antonietta, she wants to see him.
- All right, miss.
Shall I take him?
Ifthe Mediterranean
is a shortcut for England
and a permanent zone for Russia,
for us Italians it is like itself.
Keep still for a minute
or you'll knock me over.
May I come in?
- May I come in?
- Yes, and bring him with you.
You're so young
and distinguished-looking too.
You'll like it here.
I'm sure your mother wrote me,
you know. Poor woman.
- Did you show him the house?
- Of course, and he liked it too.
Good. You look like a nice boy.
That's all. You can go now.
One more thing before I forget.
Look me in the eyes, boy. There's
to be no fooling around in this house.
We're church-going people. We respect
others and want respect in return.
I wouldn't come to your house
and do anything dirty.
So let's live in peace
and not bust each other's balls.
Ma, I don't want to eat today.
Poor baby. Not even a teeny bite?
What has the sun done to you?
I want to lie next to you, Mama.
My God,
why couldn't you stay home?
We brought two chickens with us.
Hey, do you want me
to throw you in the oven?
And then we want
to eat at Ostia.
Hey! Sit down with us.
Marcello, give him a chair.
You're family now.
- I'll put him with these friends, OK?
- Was it good?
That's short pasta.
No, you don't.
I'll put the baby here.
Go on. Sit down.
You know the saying:
''The devil takes whoever eats alone.''
...cannolicchi, cheese and pepper,
penne in hot sauce.
Let me make up my own mind.
- What do you think?
- Take my advice. Cheese and pepper.
Cheese and pepper sauce. I had
that for lunch. What else is there?
How about rigatoni
in anchovy sauce?
All right, spit out that gum.
You're going to eat now.
And you keep still.
Fettuccine with chicken giblets...
Bucatini in carbonara sauce...
And then there's our specialities,
kidneys, tripe...
- Maybe the schiaffoni?
- I'll just try a small portion
because I've been having trouble
with my stomach all night long.
- Take my advice. Have the pajata.
- What's that, pajata?
It's calfgut filled with milk.
Remo, don't forget
this young gentleman.
Here, eat some ofthese.
They're not snails. They're pigeons.
- Giggetto, where are the bananas?
- Sorry, we're all out. Just one left.
- Then give me that one.
- Do you think I'm crazy?
- Who's that, Lallo's daughter?
- Whose do you think, the priest's?
Is she that big already? Isn't she cute?
Can't tell her face from her behind.
I dreamt about poor Aunt Judy last night
and asked her a winning number.
Then she fried this broccoli with
a mint leaf. You should have tasted it.
You know what they say:
''The more you eat, the more you shit.''
I told you not to let him eat any tripe.
He's had a fever since then.
All right, then give him
a couple of snails.
- But it almost killed him.
- Then I guess it'll kill me too.
Give her something to drink
so she'll shut her trap.
- Cheers!
- Go on. Drink up.
I want some ice cream!
Where's my ice cream?
You got to me once already.
Hey, verna!
Come on down!
Come on down! What's
the matter with you, anyway?
Come here before I beat
the hell out ofyou. Come on.
verna! Come on down!
Tell your sister to get down here
before I throw her offthat balcony.
And hurry up.
I asked for a half-portion,
but this plate is practically empty.
You can always order more.
- Enjoy your meal everyone.
- Thanks.
- Bon appetite.
- Thank you. Say thank you.
Slowly. Don't eat so fast
or you'll choke to death.
Nobody's going
to steal your plate.
I'm not feeling well. I've had heartburn
since yesterday morning.
You have a big heart.
Silvano! Silvano! Here she is!
I brought her down.
Finally.
Here she is, everybody.
''verna the Sulker'' has arrived.
What...?
Now what's the matter?
- Come on. Let's make up. Come on.
- Just leave me in peace.
Open that sweet little mouth ofyours.
Come on. Open it.
- You silly, stupid shit.
- You're the stupid shit.
- Not me. You. That's who.
- You are both stupid shits.
These snails are too full of mint.
I can't taste anything else.
- Is that so?
- And not enough peppers.
Taste these, one of
our most popular specialities.
I'll show you how to eat them.
Watch carefully.
Here, take a pin and dig in.
You can learn a lot
from snails, young man.
Your girlfriend will explain that
to you one day.
I never eat snails in restaurants.
Only when I cook them myself
because I soak them for four days first.
Then you can... suck them clean.
But I wouldn't touch these ones!
Don't listen to what she says.
In Rome we say, ''No matter what
you eat, it all turns to shit.''
And what you eat tastes like shit.
Excuse me.
Mary had a little sheep
With the sheep she went to sleep
The sheep turned out to be a ram
Mary had a little lamb
Where'd she learn those?
Will you listen to that!
Some mother you are,
teaching her that stuff!
You taught her, not me.
What do you mean me?
I didn't teach her anything.
Pinocchio's nose was long
As long as Pinocchio's dong
Maestro, give me a ''la.''
All together now...
All right, all right, I'm coming.
Torquato, bring this guy a drink.
- Cough up some money for the orphans.
- We gave last year.
Give me that. I'll serve them.
How about this, eh?
And you'd better eat it all.
We don't believe in leftovers.
Will you keep still!
What about the Rome oftoday?
What impression does it make on
the visitor arriving for the first time?
Inevitably, coming offthe motorway
one finds oneself
on the Grande Raccordo Anulare
which circles the city
like one of Saturn's rings.
Scaratti at midfield?
Christ! We'll never win.
Five-nil.
You bet on the wrong team.
Oh, get lost.
- How much longer? It's about to rain.
- Almost ready.
Tough life, eh, boys?
Hold on tight.
Hey, you bloody gypsies, we're going to
stomp the shit out ofyou today.
Go get your sister
and we'll bust her cherry for her.
Can you hear me?
Raise the boom as high as you can.
Move! Move! Move!
Let's kick the ruling class
back out on its ass!
- Tell me what you see.
- I'm framing Piazza di Siena.
There's a tourist bus coming into the shot.
Shall I follow it?
Yeah, stay with it.
- Do you want a picture? I'll take it for you.
- Oh, thanks.
You'll shine in a photo.
There. Don't move. Smile.
What are you framing now?
- Domes and bell towers.
- It's beautiful. I can see the whole city.
The piazzas, the streets,
people on their way to work.
Ifyou're seeing people on their way
to work, it ain't Rome.
Get lost.
You're up so high
you must be seeing another city.
That's what they say about Romans,
and here we are sweating blood all day.
This isn't Rome anymore. Everyone's
gone crazy. Too much of a hurry.
They've become mean.
The true Romans have disappeared.
You don't think so?
Just take a look around.
All you see are filthy hippies,
students who don't want to study,
transvestites, drug addicts,
trash of every kind.
You're forgetting that this film
will be seen abroad.
Ifyou show the perverts,
the street whores, negative aspects,
what are they going to think
of our lovely Rome?
What is it?
He wanted to ask you ifyour film
would give a Roman perspective
on the important and eternal problems
faced by modern-day society.
And we're not only referring to
the problems in the educational system.
And the working world, with problems
in the factories, in housing.
We wouldn't want to see the same old
colourful Rome, easygoing, messy.
- The usual bland and commercial image.
- That's not the only Rome.
But I think a person
should be true to his own nature.
Lunch time!
- Pino, what do you see now?
- The station and a small dome.
Yeah, it must be the dome
ofthe old Barafonda Theatre.
That's what I'd like to film,
for example,
a variety show
at the Barafonda Theatre,
thirty years ago,
at the beginning ofthe war.
Hey, shit-face!
So you're here too, eh?
Will you move your big feet?
What do you say, Spino?
How's it going?
Give me a light, will you?
Sit down! Just cos you ate some glass
don't mean you're a window.
He can't help it.
He's never seen one before.
Don't look too hard,
you might hurt yourself.
Take 'em away.
- Hey, Ciriola, how do you like that?
- She's really good looking, isn't she?
Hey, Pericles! Pericles!
- Ding-Dong. What do you want?
- Shove that spotlight up your ass.
Here I am, ladies and gentlemen.
Good evening.
Most comedians start things off
with a joke or two before their routine.
Hey, get offthe stage.
Well, I don't tell jokes
because I'm not very good at it.
So ifyou don't mind I'd like
to present a few of my imitations.
After my successful tour of Roccasecca,
Frascati, Marino and Zagarolo,
I was greatly honoured
to perform for the royal police force.
All right, shall we begin?
Just a moment.
The first imitation is that
of a man who has eaten too much.
I said get offthe stage.
And now, my second imitation.
What's the matter, are you deaf?
The man said get off.
- Sit down, you big loudmouth.
- Second imitation.
A young lady having a shower.
Maestro!
Hey, do us all a favour
and go away!
Yeah, go away!
Why? I've as much right to make
a living as anyone else, haven't I?
- Just disappear.
- All right, ifyou don't go, we will.
We'll pretend we enjoyed the act
and you pretend it's over. OK?
- I'm what's known as ''stile.''
- Stile, achmile, you stink too.
Here you have the modern-day saturnalia,
the variety show.
As you can see, it is a combination
of circus maximus and brothel.
Listen, ifyou're going to start
talking dirty, I'm leaving.
What did I say?
I mentioned a brothel.
Even Proust,
in Remembrance of Things Past,
gives us a lengthy description
of a house of ill repute.
Oh, you and your damned Proust.
But I've got to work
like everyone else.
Yes. So go out and find a job.
Hey, Maestro,
strike up the band.
That's so funny.
Will you shut your trap?
You guys are really making me laugh.
I'm laughing so much it hurts.
Goddamn bastards. Won't let decent
people enjoy an evening oftheatre.
- That man's a real artist, lady.
- Get lost.
I heard a little noise
Coming from the audience
Get lost!
Listen, lady,
what do you want from me?
Certain people
shouldn't be allowed in here.
I bought a ticket to enjoy the show.
So just shut up and leave me alone.
What are you trying to do?
Ruin everybody's evening?
Ifyou're not having fun,
go home and play with yourself.
Kiss my ass.
- There.
- Madam, really!
- You ought to be ashamed ofyourself.
- He's only human.
We're all humans,
but we don't go around doing that.
He's going to get my purse
right in his face.
What a bastard!
Right, you little shit,
I'm going to smash your head in.
Have you lost your mind?
I didn't do it. It wasn't me.
- I saw you throwing those beans at me.
- I keep telling you, it wasn't me.
I'm gonna rip your arms off.
Gonna rip 'em both off.
Pipe down, baldy.
Hey, Maestro,
see ifyou can play this.
- Stick it up your ass.
- How about this one?
Up your mother's too.
And now we come to the main attraction
ofthe evening...
the Amateur Hour.
Where did that big bloke go?
The tall one with all those muscles?
He was right here a minute ago.
- Did somebody shrink you?
- No.
- Born premature?
- Yes.
I bet he was born even before
Dad got through with Mother.
- What's your name?
- Alvaro.
- And what do you do?
- Tap dance.
- Yeah, but what do you do besides that?
- I'm an electrician.
An electrician. And you learned
how to dance from all those shocks.
OK, ladies and gentlemen,
Alvaro!
An imitation of Fred Astaire.
Help!
I feel sick!
I feel sick! Help!
Hey, Chiodo, it's here.
Here it is. Here it is.
Give me it. Give it here.
Let me have it. Go on.
Make yourself a fur coat,
Fred Astaire.
That's what you had for dinner, eh?
Double-time, Maestro.
Ifyou'd thrown it at me,
you would have eaten it for sure.
- Your father's moustache!
- At least he wasn't queer like yours.
Same to you.
I'll take care ofyou later.
Come here, darlin'.
Come over here.
- What's your name?
- Loredana Fiorini.
- And what are you going to sing?
- ''You Stole My Heart.''
''You Stole My Heart.''
Dickhead.
Get back in the toilet,
you bag of shit.
Have you got a match, young man?
I really don't know why they let her sing.
Wouldn't you be better off at home,
doing the dishes, girlie?
Thank you.
Whatever happened to talent?
I feel sorry for the poor girl.
Hope I didn't disturb you.
- Come with me for a minute.
- What do you wanna talk to me for?
Just for two minutes.
You must have me mixed up
with someone else.
I've not done anything,
you're making a big mistake.
Go on. Move.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the three Kants.
I said Kant and not what your
dirty minds are probably thinking.
''Trotta Cavallino''!
Shut up!
You'd like to hear
''Trotta Cavallino''?
I like it.
It's a nice song, isn't it?
Hey, Orestes, give me a hand.
Your attention, please, everybody.
Attention! We interrupt the show
to give you some good news.
After all, our country comes first!
The radio just broadcast
the following war bulletin
which I'm proud to read to you.
''The attack on Sicily by the enemy
began last night
''backed by heavy naval and air support,
including paratroopers,
''has received a setback
from our allied forces
''fighting in south-eastern Italy.
''German artillery have downed seven
aircraft and damaged three steamships.
''This treacherous attack against our
country's sacred soil will be crushed
''and the enemy thrown into the sea.
''For the greater glory
of our fatherland and its Duce.''
Long live Italy!
Oh, baby! Baby!
Where have you been all my life?
All right, that's enough from you.
Now sit down!
Can I help it if I like women?
Watch out how you talk
to my father!
- I'd sit down if I were you!
- There it is!
I'm in love with you, angel eyes,
you and your nice little bum!
Hey, isn't that the siren?
It's an air raid!
The audience is requested
to go to the air raid shelter
at number  104,  104.
Whose kid is this?
Who gave me this little boy?
Please keep calm.
Hey, Romolo! The chorus girls!
Over here! Over here!
Put that light out!
What time is it?
There I was, sound asleep,
if it wasn't for that idiot.
Excuse me. What did you say?
''If it wasn't for that idiot''?
What did I say? I don't know.
Speak up.
What did you mean by that?
- He didn't mean anything by it.
- I didn't mean anything.
It's unforgivable!
Certain people ought
to be ashamed ofthemselves.
Especially now, with our country
united as never before
on the verge ofvictory,
and you still hear defeatist remarks!
Shame on you!
Fascist Italy. The Duce.
They're your only hope.
- And we must win.
- Yes.
- And we will win.
- Right.
Do you want a cigarette?
Smoke ruin my voice.
No very good.
- Oh, you sing?
- Yes.
I learn in my city, Dusseldorf.
Have you been in Italy long?
I been to Roma,
Milano, Bergamo, Como.
This Hans, oldest son.
What do you want?
This is my husband in Russia,
Wehrmacht.
You come rest a little with me?
My boarding-house is very near.
They won't bomb us
as long as the Pope's in Rome.
Good night, Anita.
Might as well say good morning.
- What's that booming?
- My God, do you hear that?
Mother of God! They're bombs!
Help! Help!
We're being bombed!
Help!
Alberto's house has gone!
The babies! The babies!
Help! Help!
Can I shoot a bit of it?
Go ahead, ifyou like.
A perfectly preserved mammoth's tusk.
We discovered it during construction
ofthe Piazza Re di Roma station.
The Capitoline Museum
has already asked for it.
Shall we go down?
This way, please.
I could've used the subway
trying to cross town this afternoon.
I wish they'd finish it.
What was that?
The ground beneath Rome
is unpredictable.
Every hundred metres,
we come across some important find.
Naturally, this slows up the work.
This is a very difficult contract.
We merely wanted to resolve
the traffic problem
with a subway
like Munich's or Dublin's
but here the ground has eight strata
and we're forced
to become archaeologists.
The first time the necessity
of a subway for Rome
was discussed was in 1871.
- You mean 1971.
- No, exactly a hundred years ago.
Roman bureaucracy is even more
unpredictable than Roman soil.
The paperwork which has passed
between ourselves
and the community of Rome is enough
to fill the entire length of subway.
Right now we're passing
beneath the Appio Quarter.
Agenore!
Agenore, what's that?
My God, it's an earthquake!
Agenore!
Oh, my God! My God!
The buildings overhead
began to crack.
- Are we coming to the end?
- I don't think so.
Hey, look at this, will you?
Looks like a big cork
stuck in the end ofthe tunnel.
Where are we now?
Beneath the Appia Antica,
near San Sebastiano Gate.
To your left you can hear the roar
of a genuine underground river.
It emerges about
ten kilometres from here
at a place called ''Cessati Spiriti.''
- What did he say?
- He said the noise comes from a river.
When will the whole thing
be completed?
I don't know.
Michael, look!
How many hours
do they work down here?
Ten hours straight, I think.
At this point,
we had to change course again.
On the left you can see
a necropolis with 400 skeletons.
Third strata.
Track 22!
Rinaldo, the current
in the right channel has gone down!
Stop!
Sir, I think we've run
into another hollow spot.
It's been showing on the gauge
for two days.
- Do they sleep down here?
- I think they do.
We've got to suspend
the work again, sir.
- What's happened?
- Come have a look at the gauge.
Take the flame cutter
to number three.
We've got a hollow spot
as big as the Alban Hills!
What is it, Amirildo?
Don't you feel well?
I don't know what it is.
Ragu, the right wheel!
The right wheel, Ragu!
Hey! Stop the drill!
It goes like this. Now we know
there is an open space on the other side.
The archaeologists will make us
suspend work for a couple of months.
It could be a cavern
or some catacombs.
We could try testing the wall
very carefully in different spots.
Start up the cutter.
- Stop the cutter.
- Stop the cutter!
Michael, look! There are Roman paintings!
Frescoes! They're fantastic!
Down this way, sir.
A Roman house
from 2,000 years ago.
Michael, look at their faces.
Keep your mask on.
It's as ifthey were staring at us.
Look! Aim the light down there!
There!
Hey! Look at this!
What's happening?
The frescoes are fading.
It's the air from outside.
The fresh air
is destroying the frescoes.
Oh, no! How awful!
Michael! What can we do?
We've got to do something.
Do something!
For these disenchanted youngsters,
huddled together like puppies,
making love is not a problem.
They might do it,
or they might not.
But it certainly isn't as complicated
as it once was for us
when our amorous yearning
led us to the nearest brothel.
Remember?
Come on, move!
All right, stop messing around like yobs
just out of prison.
Go and screw your grandma!
Where are you going? How old are you?
Show me your ID.
Let's go! Move it! Upstairs!
Come on, who's going to be first?
Come on! Come on! Can't you see
the tongue she's got on her?
Come on, boys, make up your minds!
You too, Gramps.
What's the matter?
Are you all asleep on your feet?
All right! Enough ofthis shit!
Pretty soon I'm going to turn off
the lights and kick everyone out!
Have you got blood in your veins
or water?
Every one ofthese girls is an artist.
Are you guys blind?
- Now get your asses upstairs.
- All right, let me by. Let me by.
Let's go upstairs, girls.
Come on.
Come on, boys.
The young ladies are all here.
Teresa!
Where the hell's my coffee?
It's coming.
I already ordered it.
You wanna come with me, yes or no?
Come on, come on, soldier boy.
I don't want to sleep by myself.
Hey, Rita, turn around.
I wouldn't take you
even ifyou gave me food for a month.
Why don't you
go take the next train
back to Naples, fuckface?
Come on, honey!
Ifyou wanna stand there and jerk off,
then go home and do it.
What kind of men are you?
Ifyou keep waiting,
it's going to drop offfrom old age
and not even the cat
will eat it then.
It's closing time.
They're all pretty
and they're real artists!
- Is Dolores back?
- She went to have a bite to eat.
Who's going to come upstairs
with the pride of Florence?
That's a good boy.
Look! Those tits
must weigh 40 pounds each.
Shut your fucking trap!
What's an ugly, skinny bitch like you
doing in a nice place like this?
So why'd you go upstairs, then?
Just to make fun of a working girl?
- Two.
- I've got a good mind to call the cops.
I'll throw you down the stairs
three at a time, you bastards.
Come on!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
There she goes again. Every time
it rains, she gets hysterical.
- Marcella. Watch out for her nails.
- All right. Who's my next victim?
You thieving bitch.
Nives, calm down.
Wanna come upstairs, handsome?
Let's go. Let's go.
Shut up. Tonight you can
pack up and get out.
Two monkeys!
- Let the lady by!
- What is this shit?
Think you're a bloody cop, do you?
Don't shove me around.
Ladies, up to your rooms, please.
All right, gentlemen.
Everybody out, please. Out.
The ladies are going to eat.
We're closing.
Turn offthe lights.
We're closed.
Go get some fresh air.
We're closed. Everybody out.
All right! Time to go home.
Everybody out.
Time to go home!
All right, buster! Cut it out.
I'm not your sister.
Who knows why, why we live
And why the fuck we die
But there were also
some very sophisticated houses
which would make your heart beat
in fear and excitement.
Sit down, sit down.
What's the matter? What's everybody
so quiet about? This won't do at all.
Come on, who wants to come up
to my room for a game of chess?
How are you, darlin'?
Don't you love me today?
This morning I woke up feeling aroused.
OK, gents, who's going to be first?
Here I am.
I can't wait to get back to my room.
Let's not waste any time.
Come on!
- Babies, are you afraid of mama?
- Last chance, gents.
I'm off. I'm going up to bed.
Last chance, gentlemen.
I'm all on fire!
Where the hell do you think you are?
It's not your home.
All I want is one good man.
Come on! I'm Spanish and hot.
Come on, men, move it!
Come on!
Oh, my babies, shame on you!
Who nailed your feet to the floor?
Dad! See if I've got something in my eye.
Where's my nice little sailor?
Who's going to ride my ship?
I'm so excited,
I can't even think straight!
Take anyone you want.
Come on and quit pretending.
I've seen you here before, stupid.
Gentlemen, shame on you for keeping
all these beautiful ladies waiting.
All clear! All clear!
But I have to leave.
No, you don't, not yet.
I'm not losing myjob on account ofyou.
Damn it! Some bigwig, I bet.
Gentlemen,
please remain where you are
and don't leave the room
for the next five minutes.
Thank you.
I see.
Ladies, upstairs to your rooms,
please.
Hurry up, please. Thank you.
- Who's arrived, the mayor?
- Who knows? Maybe it is.
Maybe so, l don't know
i don't know, maybe so
Experience, my dear.
That's what counts in life.
Ifyour son's experienced,
he'll never have any problems.
I think that dark guy wants you.
But if he's not experienced
all he'll get is a royal screwing, right?
It's so true.
Dolores is always right.
Not always, no.
You are very beautiful, you know.
Where are you from?
Santa Maria la Bruna.
- Where's that?
- Near Pompeii.
- Is that your son?
- Yes, that's my son.
But you...
How long have you...?
Two years.
Listen, I mean,
how did you happen to...
What the hell. I found myself alone,
and Assuntina said, ''Come with us.
You'll like it, you'll see.
I'll introduce you.''
Lace me up?
To tell the truth,
I can't complain.
The signora likes me
and I've got everything I need.
Does that mean you wouldn't
want to leave this place?
To do what?
Haven't you ever fallen in love?
Haven't you ever met someone...
Sure I have.
And this is the result.
Listen. Couldn't we
see each other sometime?
Do you ever go out?
Some morning, whenever you want,
we could go to the beach for lunch.
Really, I'd like to take you out.
Let's make a date.
Tomorrow, OK?
The day after tomorrow?
Perhaps you have heard
of Princess Domitilla.
Her mother Fabiola,
her grandfather Eugenio
and her ancestors further back
were all born in this palazzo
where today Domitilla lives alone.
Salvatore! Domenico!
Can't you hear the carriage?
He's arrived.
Go.
At last.
Your Eminence! Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Princess Domitilla!
There. There.
How nice it is
to see you all again.
Good evening.
I hope you are all well,
with the grace of God.
You must be Francesca, is that right?
Yes, I'm Francesca,
Your Eminence.
Ah, my eyes
aren't what they used to be.
And is this little rascal
still causing his mother trouble?
It's not true.
How can you say that?
But of course, I was onlyjoking.
Well, isn't it little Filippo!
Remember when you used to drink
the wine out ofthe ampullae?
And who are these little devils?
Augustarello's children, eh?
How do you do? We've already met.
I gave you your first Communion.
This little blond boy
I've never seen.
- What's your name?
- Giulio.
Are you good?
I bet only when you're asleep.
And now offto bed, eh?
Good night, children,
and God bless you.
Good night, Your Eminence.
IfYour Eminence
will come this way.
My friends! Please sit down.
Ah, yes, why, even today
there was an audience with people
who want to tell the Pope
how to run the church.
What can you do?
Be patient, I suppose.
''Fire's for burning
and patience for learning''
as we say in Rome.
I remember your grandfather.
He was a good man, Don Eugenio.
My compliments.
Please! Please!
My friends.
- Please sit down.
- Thank you.
Peppino, Gervasio,
you may begin serving.
Ah, you've finally arrived!
What would you like,
Your Eminence?
- A mint to freshen my mouth, thank you.
- Ah, a mint. I knew it.
Here we are.
- Your Excellency.
- Why not?
Thank you. I'd love one.
- What would you like, Monsignor?
- Monsignor.
I must tell you that when I was little,
I was quite a mischief maker.
What did he say?
He said when he was young,
he was a rascal.
Mama used to make a liqueur
just like this for the guests
and she would have
to hide it from me.
The minute she wasn't there, I'd climb
up and drink it out ofthe bottle.
Your Eminence, I can't believe it.
I'm sure that even as a baby,
you were a saint.
A long life to His Eminence.
How much time has passed.
Everything seems so far away,
so different.
i'm sorry to leave this life
in a city which is no longer home.
The Rome l knew was different.
People were nicer, more respectful.
Everyone knew everyone else.
Monsignors, cardinals, the Pope.
They were all either friends
or relatives.
Friendship with the church
has been lost.
The marvellous balls
in villas and palazzos
with all those cardinals dressed in red
wandering about the house.
It was like living in a painting
and at Christmas.
Now, why should I suddenly
remember that?
The little presents
Monsignor Altieri would give me.
Wax statuettes,
crosses out ofwoven straw
and a lot ofvelvet for the toy manger.
And all of it gone,
lost over the years.
Who knows where all those
little wax statues have gone?
For the following presentation
of ecclesiastical fashions,
we welcome His Eminence
and our other illustrious guests.
Model No. 1:
habit in black satin,
along traditional lines, for novices.
The same model may be done
in another type offabric
such as silk or wool,
according to the season.
The boots are in leather and suede
in two colours.
Navy blue and black
for harsher climates.
Model No. 2:
tourterelle immaculee.
Starched cap with flexible wings.
Useful also for interiors
with poor air circulation.
Model No. 3: little sisters
ofthe purgatory's temptation.
The world must follow the church
and not vice versa.
And now for the more casual modes:
quicker to paradise!
Here you have Model No. 6
for country priests.
Sacristan variations
for first-class ceremonies.
The sacerdotal vestments
have passed through evolution:
Anitto, viviale
cotta, vianita and casula.
All types ofvestments are made today
ofvery light fabrics
in the most brilliant colours,
which don't fade.
One, two,
three, go!
Balloons! Balloons!
All colours and shapes.
First he has a drink
before he eats an egg,
then he has a drink
while he's eating the egg,
and now he wants a drink
because he's eaten an egg!
Jesus!
Won't he get sick
from all those eggs?
Balloons for you.
For children and for grown-ups too.
- What the hell do you want?
- Go on, it's red!
They're making their movie
all over the place
but not paying anybody.
This pork's from genuine Ariccia pig!
How about a slice?
''Rooky'' here! ''Rooky'' here!
''Leal'' silk! ''Pletty sirk scalf!''
''Pletty sirk scalf.''
Hey, Brit, do they sell
pork sandwiches in Germany?
Leave Grandpa alone!
Let him sleep. Why bring him along?
Hey, Torquato! Some petrol!
Petrol.
Antique paintings.
Fancy frames!
very cheap!
I'm going back to the cemetery tomorrow.
Fancy coming?
They gave him a nice spot.
Really sunny!
Hey, you bystanders,
where are you going?
Why don't you eat here?
Hey, young man,
where are you going to feed her?
Your wife! Well, come on over then
and buy her a decent meal for a change.
Checco! It stinks
like hell over here!
Did you have to give us a table
next to the manhole?
It's not true! That's the smell
of history, honey, centuries.
You shit! You shit!
I'll slit your belly open.
You always believe everything
that dumb bitch tells you?
There! It's Gore vidal,
the American writer. Let's ask him.
Good evening, Mr vidal.
Do you mind ifwe disturb you
forjust two minutes?
Well, you ask me why an American writer
would want to live in Rome.
First of all,
because I like the Romans.
They don't give a damn
whether you're dead or alive.
They're neutral, like the cats!
Rome is the city of illusions.
Not only by chance, you have here
the church, the government, the cinema.
They each produce illusions
like you do and like I do.
As the world dies
from overpopulation...
Yes, by Americans.
...too many cars, poisons.
And what better city than Rome,
which has been reborn so often?
What place could be more peaceful
to wait for the end
from pollution and overpopulation?
It's the ideal city for waiting to see
if it will really come to an end or not.
To the end!
Get out! Clear the piazza!
Why?
We weren't bothering anybody!
Hurry up! Move! Move! Move!
Ifyou don't mind,
I would like to say this -
despite the recent
and incredibly permissive laws
which protect the guilty man
more than the innocent,
the restraining measures of
our police force are successful
in keeping at an acceptable minimum
the outbreak of delinquency
in a city, or in a society,
where protest movements, drugs
and a desire for wealth
are actually regarded
as legitimate goals.
They were minding their own business.
You have no right to beat them!
I'm a witness! Have you gone mad?
I'm a teacher, I'll have you know.
They've turned our piazzas
and monuments into a rubbish dump.
Right!
All they think about is sex.
Don't worry, madam. They're not
really hurting them, believe me.
He's beating the hell out of him!
He's killing him.
- Belt him one!
- You clowns!
Are you fighting or dancing?
I think they're engaged.
You're nobody! You're nobody!
You're just a lucky bastard,
that's all!
He's a champion!
He could kill all ofyou.
He's a real champ!
The camera.
Somebody swiped the camera!
Somebody stole the camera!
This lady you see walking home along
the wall of an old patrician palazzo
is an actress from Rome,
Anna Magnani.
in a way, she's a symbol
ofthe city itself.
What am I?
Rome: she-wolf and vestal virgin,
noblewoman and fishwife,
sombre and festive.
I could go on
until tomorrow morning.
You'd better go home
and get some sleep, Federico!
- Can I ask you a question?
- No, I don't trust you. Ciao!
Good night.
phim.fun