AND THE SHIP SAILS ON
They tell me: "Do the news,
tell what happens!"
And who the hell knows
what happens?
Whoever might have accidentally
wandered onto Pier Number 10
one July morning of 1914 would
have seen that...
I must hand over the ashes
of Edmea Tetua
Mr. Partexano!
Permission to bring the ashes
of Edmea Tetua aboard
- Permission granted.
- On the broadside!
- What are you doing, Monica?
- It's very hot, Mommy!
Wait for it to cool!
Even if my husband agreed,
it doesn't mean anything
My husband is a great artist.
But don't get mad, darling...
he's simply a child
in business matters
I wouldn't say so. However, I'm
here to defend your interests
That's not true! You didn't act
on his behalf in that contract!
And I'll tell you why.
First:
advertising. It's not
to his advantage
Change the soprano, she's more
prominent than my husband
Charity or not, I won't appear
before a stupid bunch of kids
I'm Ricotin, a sophisticated
comic!
Children are not my audience!
- Intellectuals appreciate me!
- That's what you think, darling!
Your last reviews
were disastrous
- Gilbert the French critic...
- Comply with your contract!
You're here to advertise my
film, nothing else!
Well, the Hindus around
Bombay say,
even though I don't know
if it's true or not,
that if you look a tiger
straight in the eye
- She won't attack you.
- Is that possible, Sir Reginald?
- What?
- I asked if it's easy to do
No, quite the contrary.
It's the hardest thing on earth
especially if the tiger
looks at you
straight in the eye
Where are all these beautiful
people going?
How is it that we see them all
together aboard this
- Fabulous...
- Excuse me for cutting in,
but here you're in
the waiters' way
Could you please go into that
corner, for example?
- I see.
- Thanks, that's kind of you
I'm grateful. Excuse me
As I was saying, where are all
these characters going?
They represent, as it were,
the highest
values in the fascinating world
of show business, of the arts
Now I'll tell you who they are
The talented superintendent
of La Scala in Milan
his illustrious colleague
of the Rome opera
the one involved in the scandal
of cats, of rats
And that one is
his second wife,
the former singer Rumena.
The one with her back turned
is his first wife's daughter
His secretary, a medium with
amazing visions
and by the window, the legendary
conductor Von Rupert
the child prodigy, slightly more
child than prodigy,
holding on as always to his
terrible mother's skirts
Out there is a seagull, it beats
its wings like a conductor
- In the style of...
- My work as a chronicler is hard
due to the amount and accuracy of
the information I must provide
Now let's see... oh yes
The famous tenor Aureliano
Fuciletto
That would be the bearded one
feeding the seagull
- Do you want it? I'll eat it!
- How witty
The two superintendents of the
Vienna opera, born in Warsaw
Ah, a toast, thank you!
The feared columnist,
Brenda Hilton
How are you, Ziloev?
He is the deepest bass
in the world
The mezzo Valegnani and the
ever so nice Ines Ruffo Salitin
The singing masters Rubetti.
And finally, she
who after the death of Tetua
became a well-loved queen
among today's voices:
Ildebranda Cuffari
- What's your name, sir?
- David Fizmaier.
- What do you do?
- I'm a conductor
- Ah, an orchestra conductor?
- Precisely
Thank you. And the lady?
- She's a famous dancer!
- I see
- And what's her name?
- What do you mean? Svetlana!
- Everyone knows her!
- Thanks
Oh, it came in!
I didn't know it could fly
inside!
It's obvious that it's
a domestic seagull!
Go to the tool room,
have them bring a ladder!
- Partexano! The net!
- What?
The net, in my cabin!
It never happened! Excuse me!
It was a stupid incident
I'm really...
- I'm scared.
- Don't be afraid, they'll catch it
Without a doubt, they will!
Take it there and be on guard
By the way,
who's going upstairs?
- Be quick!
- Captain, let us try
They will only frighten
it more.
That's right, the net!
Watch the chandeliers!
And the bird was free
to look for its birdcage
- Do I know you, sir?
- I wanted to interview you
- Then talk to my secretary.
- O.K., later then
- Come on, go out. Through here.
- Have they caught it?
Go out. Fly away.
Bye, beautiful!
Close the window! Tomorrow I'll
change my table
Captain, the seagull has left,
sending regards
- It didn't like the menu.
- He should change his table
- The feather fell on your neck!
- Get it off!
- Please, get it off!
- Don't get excited, my dear
- But lldebranda, it brings luck.
- I don't see anything
The bird wanted to pay its
respects to you. Here we are!
I don't want to see it!
- Maestro!
- One, two...
A 5-meter-high equestrian
monument!
It was his dream! And now that
he's got it
he cannot see it, poor Papa!
Long live our prince!
I'm a journalist, I must
interview the Grand Duke, please
The noble person we've awaited is
the Grand Duke of Herzog
How old is he?
Judging by his political ability,
I think about eight
He is followed by his sister Herimia,
the blind princess
who lost her sight while still
a child. Have you noticed?
She walks at the side of
the Premier so confidently!
She doesn't want compassion
and she doesn't want help,
as if she could see!
Consomme Vichyssoise, turtle
soup.
Yesterday's excellent cream soup,
can we have it today too?
That was vegetable soup
Yes, it was vegetable soup
Do you want to know why they're
making this trip?
It's a funeral. You'll ask,
"What do you mean, a funeral?"
Yes, ladies and gentlemen,
a funeral
All these famous characters are
here to follow a funeral
It was her expressed wish,
in her last will and testament
"Cremation and dispersion of my
ashes when the sun rises
"around the island where
I was born."
That's the island of Erimo,
where Edmea Tetua was born
and where her soul wishes
to return
Edmea Tetua, the greatest singer
of all time!
A vocal miracle! The voice
of a goddess!
Light blue
Light blue and white.
Ultramarine blue
Light blue, ultramarine blue
Emerald green. Green.
Light blue
Music makes her see
a rainbow
White, white, white
My sister says that each note
has its own color
The scientists of Sotierre say
some people have this power
by which they have a chromatic
view of sounds
Excuse me for interfering,
but I don't think that anyone
can prove such a thing
Anybody can say he sees colors
Mr. Kuntz, it's obvious that not
everyone can have
such a sensitive soul!
I wouldn't dare to doubt it!
I'm just saying that it's almost
impossible to prove
Once when I was ill,
all faces were green to me
But we can all perceive
the colors of music
And not only music. Voices are
colored too
You say my voice is grey! But
is it always grey?
Not always. When you are worried
your voice becomes rusty
Brownish red. But the police
chief's voice
is always the same color.
Yellowish, matte, not clear!
And what color is the voice of
our general?
I'd like to hear it, General
This is my voice. I'm unable
to sing with it
Strange!
I see no color.
A voice without color,
like a void, an absence
A void as head of the
Armed Forces is troubling!
Here, her ashes are all here
For this small casket,
so small, and yet so large,
friends and fans from around
the whole world
chartered the most luxurious liner,
commanded by the fearless
captain
born in indomitable Genoa
Spezia! Spezia!
Spezia! Born in indomitable
Spezia,
Captain Leonardo De Robertis
It's the other way round,
Roberto De Leonardis
- What did I say?
- Roberto De Leonardis!
Right. And he shall lead us
to the island of Erimo
so that all of us can solemnly
perform
the funeral rites,
spreading the...
Sir Reginald!
Excuse me
Sir Reginald! Sir Reginald!
Excuse me, just a couple
of questions
Is it true that you were the one
who asked our divine singer
to make her debut in London?
- Of course. Please excuse me.
- Thanks
Look Rudi, he's looking
for her
This is the second wheel, should
the one in the main deck fail
This is the mechanism used to
maneuver, without the other one
- And when do you use this one?
- For emergency cases, as I said
- And what is down there?
- Please follow me
He's an Egyptian. They say he was
our great artist's lover
He owns all the railways
in his country
It seems his penis is enormous,
violet colored
That's something I heard,
of course
Ah, here he is!
He hasn't found her
There are strange rumors about
our baron and his gentle wife
Did you see it too?
Really upset
Upset and longing, what?
That F wasn't right, didn't
you hear it was off-key?
What do you mean, off-key? It was
perfect, didn't you hear?
That way it doesn't fall. If you
remove a single drop of water
- It becomes a different note!
- This way it doesn't fall
but you, being tone deaf, go on
with your pa, pa pa
You rise instead
of going down.
How marvelous! It looks as if it
were painted!
Oh, look, Lisa! Look! The moon!
The sun, and the moon, together!
The overture of Barber of Seville
gives me goose pimples!
And that's Andromeda, and that
small star on the right
near Orion was discovered
only 50 years ago
Correct, Sir Reginald. You're
giving a lesson in astronomy!
That star is known
as Cauda Pavonis
Its blue silver, see? But now
it's emerald
and now bright orange
And do you know who discovered
it? A well-known surgeon
who was an amateur astronomer
Guess what his name was?
Reginald!
Besides the myth of a great
singer, she was a sensitive girl,
very Ionely. One felt one had
to help her,
but maybe you're interested in
a few events in Edmea's life?
The lady is her cousin, why
don't you ask her?
Yes, I could have sung
- Captain!
- Mr. Orlando
- How are you, Reverend?
- What a view!
- On one side the cold moon.
- Good evening
- Divine!
- On the other the sun's heat
Absolutely beautiful. Between
light and darkness, and
fire and ice, there you are,
lldebranda
- How poetic.
- Can I accompany you?
- It's too humid here!
- Thirty years have gone by
I haven't seen her since then
I don't remember anything. Sorry,
we were children
Thank you, madame. Anyhow,
you've told me something
When there is a moon, he says that
nightwatch makes him nervous
Hi! Who knows you, dear friend?
But I have to write
about you
and that one there, for example,
that fatso waving at me
Who knows him? My job is a bit
ludicrous, isn't it?
- She never read the contracts.
- Is there a place for me?
Nor signed them.
Whatever was practical
offended her deeply
But we're creatures of habit,
we are on it, all of us
And yet she knew her
contractual rights
better than any attorneys
Before going into the theatre,
he once told me:
"Couldn't you remove my name
from the billboard?"
No, I think she was conscious of
her personal charm
Whoever came near her was
conquered!
It might seem that way. But she
was terribly insecure
She was terrified of strangers
But you should stop
telling stories about this girl
At least as a sign of respect.
Excuse me, which girl?
She may have been intimidating,
but she didn't scare me!
- You say she was aggressive?
- She threw things at people
- Didn't she throw things?
- Aureliano!
Actually, I never had problems
- I'd like a glass of red wine.
- Of course, sir
- But Lambrusco, mind you!
- Lambrusco
She was the perfect partner,
she liked me a lot
and this made our collaboration
ideal
She always said I was the best,
the best Italian tenor
True! Tetua always said so:
to sing with Sabatino Lepori is
glorious!
At my house, she wept before a
small painting
"It makes me cry, madame" she said
with her eyes full of tears
And you, haven't you anything
to tell?
The most extraordinary fact
of those we have heard
was that in the last act of
La Traviata she was feverish
She fully identified with
Violetta's character
Mommy, did you love Tetua?
Not one of your best
evenings, was it?
I caught him leaving the cabin
I thought he had an air of
satisfaction. Was it worth it?
Answer me, Violet
I'll go to sleep right
away tonight. I'm so tired
Well? I want to know everything,
every detail
Did you spot him on the dock?
- Be nice, Reginald I'm sleepy!
- Oh, did you go too far?
He came to repair the light,
it did not work properly
You can do better than that, Violet!
You know I'm afraid of the dark!
You whore! You're amazing. Say it
with your little voice
"Yes, Reginald, I'm a great
whore!"
I won't stand for it!
- I can't bear it!
- Yes!
- Give me that stupid bear!
- No! Anything but him!
- Crazy bitch!
- Give it to me!
Why? Why do you treat me like
that?
Yes, I've earned it. Do it,
do anything you like!
You have needs...
you're a queen,
my child, my boss
Please, Violet, do it
always, do it like this, more
more
"A vocal phenomenon"
"A divine voice." "A hundred
singers in one"
So many definitions,
so many words
They've written so many stories
about you
But no one said who you really
were
Your favorite flower.
You'll never be without it
No one ever discovered your
secret, my love
I'm the only one who knows
who you really are.
You're a child who came from
the sea
Remember the poem I wrote
for you?
"Born from the sea,
like a goddess"
Who is it?
Your Highness,
I'm a journalist
- Excuse me!
- Good night
- Thank you.
- Oh, of course
Count Bassano. A romantic guy
Very romantic
For years now, he always
brought her a very rare flower:
"Rubens Pistila." You've seen it
in his cabin, haven't you?
But I deny
that he was ever in love
with her
Perhaps he's in love with her,
since her death
An ambiguous guy! Really
ambiguous!
Under the pretense of setting up
a museum
he managed to have them
keep him for years!
Excuse me,
These are notes
that I have been jotting down
for one of my newspapers: "I
write, I tell...
"Well, what do I want to tell
about?
"A sea voyage?
"A voyage through life, but it
is not told
"It is made"
Trivial, isn't it? Has this been
said already?
And better?
But everything has already been
said and done!
We're in the famous and smoky
boiler room
What is it?
This is the large boiler,
it never goes out
How many hours do they work
in here?
They are used to it
Captain, sir, we all have a
small favor to ask
- What did you say?
- Ask Madam Cuffari to sing!
Scream louder!
- We want to hear Cuffari sing!
- Are you crazy?
This is a crazy request!
- Friends, don't, on your life!
- Sing something, beautiful lady!
Bravo, bravo!
The keeper is a Turk.
He loves the big beast
- What did he say? Who
understood? -What a stink...
He says since he came
aboard he has had nothing to eat!
He needs to get some fresh air!
- How can you heal it?
- Who will stroll it on deck?
The other day you said the
beast was lovesick
- What name have you given it?
- See how humiliated it is!
Don't you ever wash, boy?
- You're having a bad time, eh?
- We made it go down
All animals on board suffer due
to the pitch and roll
Even when they're not with
their cage mates
- Pardon me.
- What?
- You have to take her out.
- Just a moment! I'll take her!
I was saying that this little
man was taken aboard in Genoa
We're taking him to Amsterdam
These pachyderms are always
a handful on board
Remember, Mr. Partexano, when
we took an elephant in?
No
- Do you?
- I wouldn't know.
Yes! No! The "City of Brescia".
A small rodent had the bad idea
of visiting the elephant
The beast, terrified, broke
his chains
and threw two sailors
into the sea
Even here we have rats?
Rats, dear madam,
are inevitable guests
They love sailing on the sea
Yes? He's in love. And that's the
effect it has on it?
- Love is debilitating.
- What are you saying?
When I'm in love I feel stronger,
get fatter, become twice as big
Love is healthy!
Who's this girl?
He's in love
On the guard
And now...
Daydreaming during the watch!
You're nuts!
Who is it? Help!
Let me go, you're hurting me!
I'll explain, I'm a journalist
I've used this disguise to meet
the Grand Duke
I must interview him.
Can't you help me?
He says he's a journalist, wants
to interview the Grand Duke
Listen! I'm a respectable
passenger aboard this ship
A famous journalist, performing
his professional duties,
informing his readers of world
events!
I'll complain to the captain.
A journalist in here! Awful!
He's a journalist, wishes to
interview the Grand Duke
He's an Italian journalist who
succeeded in getting in
He wants to ask you a few
questions
Your Highness!
- O.K., but with a translator.
- Let go of him!
Let go of him!
- I'm sorry.
- Never mind
The Grand Duke grants you an
interview with a translator
You'll ask your questions and
I'll translate them
- Thank you!
- You may start!
An interview! He doesn't know
I'm less than anyone else
We know you were a great fan of
this sublime artist,
and the fact that you wanted to
pay your respects in this trip
with your august presence has
touched everyone
In the name of your extraordinary
humanity I would like to ask
for a few words of comfort, of
hope for those who
live without knowing what fate
has in store for us
and feel threatened by the
international situation
Thanks
The Italian journalist says that
most men are unhappy
and it seems he wants a word of
comfort
What exactly is he asking for?
He asked, "What's your question?"
How does the Grand Duke see
the international situation
Thank you.
He wants your comments on
the international situation
We're all sitting on the edge
of a mountain
H.H. says, "We're all sitting on
the edge of a mountain"
Excuse me for interfering,
but the Grand Duke
said "the mouth..."
and then the rest.
Count Kunz corrects me. He says
Y.H. said "mouth of a mountain"
I though he said "edge"
What mouth?
He asks Your Highness "what
mouth?"
Excuse me.
The Grand Duke used a metaphor
He said we're all sitting
on the edge of a mountain
Count Huppenback says the Grand
Duke used a metaphor
and that the problem does not
lie in "edge" or "mouth"
However, I understood "edge"
- No, you see...
- No, no, edge
- However, you know...
- Edge
- He meant mouth!
- German is my 2nd language... edge!
Oh, my God!
- What does he want to say?
- I think H.H. wants to say...
Does he want to renege his duty?
Do you wish to leave Italy to its
tragic fate?
Your Highness, the journalist...
Pum! Pum! Pum! Translate
The Grand Duke says: "Pum! Pum!"
The mouth of a mountain?
That's the crater of a volcano!
We're sitting
on the mouth of a volcano!
Perfect!
Now I got it! It's a tragedy.
Thank you
The mouth of a mountain!
Undoubtedly, a catastrophe
The interview is over
"The interview is over"
Of course, I thank His Highness.
Gentlemen!
Look at Mommy!
Look!
Maestro, let us rehearse!
- Mr. Orlando.
- Thank you, my love
It's the second day, and all
is well
and in order to remember
this day,
photographs are taken
Two, no three! Four!
They're there, there
Our tenor, Fuciletto, would like
to be a dolphin
and the two song masters,
whale hunters
This is the funny thing about
sea voyages
After a few days, you feel as
if you'd been sailing forever
You feel you've always known
your fellow voyagers
Captain!
Stay put, like that!
Just one minute, please,
get ready
My grandfather always wanted
to have his portrait painted
He spent half his life sitting
for painters!
They had to sit longer
than we do!
Am I all right here?
How much happier our people
would be
if they were ruled by these
delicate hands
We're all waiting for that day
- Smile, Daddy!
- I am smiling!
Have you noticed that whenever
he deals we lose?
Mr. Orlando, we need
the press here!
Come with us. Our Russian says
his voice is so deep
that it causes catatonia
Good morning to you all!
A hen!
- Please.
- What?
A live hen!
- He wants a live hen!
- Yes, dear friends,
we're sorry to interrupt your
gastronomic activities,
but we really need a hen
- We have to perform an experiment.
- I need to put it here
Quite unusual but very
important
You all will attend. We've
got the captain's permission
I won't tell you what it's all
about because if it succeeds
it will be an extraordinary
surprise!
Does the chef agree?
Thank you all
- Thanks!
- You're welcome!
Come, we must document
this event for posterity
- What are you doing?
- Put it on top
No, turn it like this,
turn its head this way
Now please be silent
Maybe it'll lay an egg!
Look, it's sleeping now!
- Right, it closed its eyes!
- Incredible, poor chicken!
What's happened
to him?
- My God, he's sick! A doctor!
- Take him away from the fire!
- Hold his feet above his head!
- There, near the air!
A bit of water!
I noticed he was pale,
take him outside!
Take a glass of water and pour
it on his face
Breathe deeply, sir
You have to be acclimated
to be down here
He's better. It's over,
everything's over
The hen's sleeping! Look,
it sleeps! He succeeded!
True, it sleeps
He made it sleep!
you sleep too
I doubt that you're satisfied
with the rehearsal for
the Oratorio in Memoria
Singing in remembrance of Edmea
requires your talent & technique,
but also your gratitude
to the great artist whom we
all loved
Undoubtedly she was the
greatest Soprano of all time.
Are you ready, lldebranda?
What is that funny smell?
- How old am I?
- What?
- I didn't understand
- Well, how old?
I couldn't say, I can't even
guess your age
Don't be afraid, try!
Come on, tell me at least how
old I look
I don't know
The same as my father
And how old is your father?
To me, my father is forever
young
Excuse me, Mother
Go get your cape, darling,
you can't stay like that
- I'm not cold
- It gets damp when the sun sets
Look at these colors, darling
Every sunset bearing the stamp
of divinity!
You know, Mr. Orlando, I spent
all Saturday painting
I don't know what I'd give
to paint such a picture
But how can we compete with
the Creator?
Now I'd like to rehearse
the Domine Deus
They're rehearsing.
Excuse me a moment
Sit next to Fuciletto.
It's the Oratorio!
Captain, I want to ask you
one thing. Last night
I was awakened by a
patter on my porthole
- Is that possible?
- It's our seagull, Icarus
We gave him that name because
he broke a wing
Don't you smell that horrible
odor? Why does it stink?
Don't you smell it?
- Mother, where is it coming from?
- Yes, it's the fish
I can't breathe!
- What's this stench?
- Are you looking at me?
I'm not looking at you,
there's quite a stench!
You talk of a stench
and look at me!
I don't stink!
- Idiot!
- You're the idiot!
I'll tear off your moustache
and make you eat it!
What are you doing? This smell
is in the air, outside
Yes, gentlemen, the air is quite fetid
but Dr. Lamela guarantees that
you cannot get infected
- Absolutely! Stay calm!
- The discharge is lessening
and before night it shall
cease completely
Following our physician's
suggestion,
we're trying to get the
pachyderm out of the hold
- We'll hoist him on deck.
- It's being done, captain
Some ship-boys will sling
the rhino on the scales
and a winch will hoist him
on deck
We can assure you everything'll
end very shortly
Prepare the pumps!
Keep the ropes taut!
Increase pressure!
- You'll throw him into the sea?
- No, on that lifeboat!
The doctor said he needs
fresh air!
Here!
The stink!
He's getting better, however
- Like a flying dragon!
- You could use a bath!
Everyone is looking at you,
get up!
And she went from natural F
down to
E flat to natural E
to upper F. A miracle
The orchestra was almost
silent,
the audience stopped breathing,
and I was paralyzed hearing her
I'll remember it all my life!
Excuse me, Maestro, but how
could she?
Almost three octaves without
making an effort...
- That's not human!
- Why not, Edmea was just a woman
So many racked their brains
trying to understand her!
She must have had a secret
and that's what I wanted to ask
you, Maestro
...as I would ask a father... what...
- What can I do?
- Listen
One evening, Edmea told me
something, she said
that when she sang,
she saw a snail
- A snail?
- Yes, she said so
"I see a snail
"and with my eyes I follow the
spiral, curling up
"and my voice comes out without
making an effort."
Do you understand? My dear,
it wasn't only lungs,
diaphragm and vocal chords
It was an energy-catalyzing
phenomenon
I only know that Edmea was
different from anyone else
She was unique. There'll never
be another like her!
Why are you so quiet?
You look like a marvelous
Egyptian sphinx
You're superb!
The third night of our voyage,
things started going wrong
Everything became
more and more strange
You interrupted me
It's her fault,
she didn't want to come
Be quiet. He's already
in a trance
- Is he all right?
- Sit here, close by
Hold hands, everyone. Maestro,
give your hand to madame
- Me too?
- Yes. Sit with us
Thanks, I'd rather stay out
If Sister Angela knows I'm here
she'll feed me only bread
and water for a week!
Come on! Ask something!
Edmea, excuse me, but I always
wanted to ask you
Which opera made you
suffer most?
What a stupid question!
No, once you told me that
- What fell?
- I don't know
Don't break the chain!
It's dangerous
- For God's sake!
- A book has opened!
The icy hand
Look! It's La Gioconda!
It opened in La Gioconda!
- Right! Incredible coincidence!
- How come?
I can't stay. This is awful.
I can't stay. Excuse me!
Could I also ask a question?
He says no because he's afraid.
He understood that
since I knew her well, I'd ask
a more intimate question
Look, she always used
that gesture to thank
Oh, Edmea, Edmea!
Who is it? Who are you? Switch
the light on! You idiots!
Who was it? Tell me who it was.
Who was it?
- Who was it?
- Someone played a joke!
What's the matter with you?
Come to, you idiot!
Ines, come on, get your
bearings back!
Is it you? Look at him, come
here, show yourself you clown
Look who our ghost was!
Leave her alone!
We must applaud him, bravo!
For a moment, there,
even I believed it!
You had us all fooled
- Damn you!
- Even you are inspired
Excuse me, I thought you still
had the shivers
And Ines, where's Ines?
Is she still unconscious?
If you talk, you can't breathe
to the beat of your feet
- Where did she come from?
- I've never seen her!
What are you doing here so late?
Who are you?
- She's a darling!
- Yes
You're very pretty,
look at your pretty braids
- You're a real darling.
- Wolfgang, let her be
What's your name?
- Do you want to cause a disaster?
- Exactly
I don't understand you
You can't light fires on deck
It's the grandmother,
how are you?
Scram!
Harder!
Come on!
Good day!
Where were you?
- Krassavitza!
- Ilia, who are these people?
- I don't know them!
- Ildebranda!
- They're Serbians!
- Come up!
Serbians! Let's go listen!
We're getting things ready
in the hold
so as not to interfere with
activities on board
or the privacy
of the passengers!
But captain, how did it happen?
How did they come on board?
When the Austrian Archduke was
murdered in Sarajevo,
Austria declared war
against Serbia
and the people fearing the
arrival of the enraged troops
tried to escape by sea, and get
on a ship sailing Italy's coast
- I don't understand.
- Call a doctor!
They're Serbs, how did they get
on board?
We rescued them
from the sea tonight
We believe they are Serbs
Do you want water?
Good morning, young lady.
Still sleepy?
Our physician is checking them,
one by one
And my officers and myself,
by means of an interpreter,
have talked to most of the men
They are shepherds, peasants,
gypsies
We rescued them at sea tonight
There are also students,
maybe unjustly chased
by the police
Captain, no one can force us to
travel with these people
who come God knows from where
He's right
Their rafts were sinking due
to the great weight
To rescue these women, children,
these families in despair,
was a duty I could not forego
Yesterday's Pommard was not one
of the best
I'd like to suggest a white wine
for my wife and friends
A Chablis, let's say.
Let's give it a try
But I'll still have a Rayon
de Soleil champagne
You! Scram, scram!
- Look there!
- You're not worthy of the spaghetti
Sit down, Monica
Turn around and look.
What does that pretty
one want?
She's beautiful! Krassivaya.
She has savage eyes!
I'm frankly embarrassed, eating
while they look at us like that!
Divine providence will
look after them!
- Right! If you're thinking...
- Finally they've decided...
Why?
I'll drink to you! No!
What're you doing?
I want to see my fiancee
Violet, please
Andrew, what do you think
she'll do?
I think she wants to bring food
to the horrible people on deck!
Violet, this philanthropic
gesture of yours
is admirable, but
a bit too much
Sir, I'll try, Sir
Please, Andrew, make her come
back to the table!
- Sir Reginald wishes...
- I don't need any help
Waiters, please follow me with
the trolley
Mrs. Dongby, wait Mrs. Dongby.
A table is being set outside
Good, so they'll have something
more today. Come on
- I insist!
- Please open the door!
- Excuse me.
- Thank you
- My lady, please
- Can I bring them my soup, Mommy?
- Do you think I should do it too?
- No, lldebranda, not at all
- Mommy, please, let me take it!
- Not another word!
Give me the tray, madame,
I'll carry it
Now I've got to go with you.
Please
Stay back. Sailor, tell them
to stay back.
Let's come here, let's see if
you're a singer too
Say "Aaah". Come on, open
your mouth!
Stay back! Stay back!
- Excuse me?
- I'll do it!
Go back to the salon, madame!
I'll take over here
How much do you want?
Cut the cake and distribute it
to the children, to all of them!
Yes
Why are you laughing?
What is it?
What?
What did you see?
Why're you laughing?
It's inadmissible for a ship to
be boarded by Serb anarchists
without the captain doing
anything to prevent it!
Please. The captain must rescue
shipwrecks
following a basic principle
in the Naval Code:
- The duty of assistance.
- You probably know, Captain
that among those you kindly
define as refugees
there are professional
assassins
That's right!
This is very serious. The Grand
Duke's life is in jeopardy
We'll protest before
the Italian government!
We'll protest before your
government!
I'll be responsible for
His Highness' safety
aboard this ship around the clock
As soon as they came on board,
I've ordered my officers
to control them,
to isolate any potentially
dangerous persons
Control is not enough
if those so-called refugees
can move freely
throughout the ship, on deck,
in the bar, in the halls,
in the salon
Cuoco! You speak their language,
they cannot stay here
They have to go!
Captain's orders
Leave, all of you, scram
Hello! I'd like a box
of cookies. Good ones.
Right! These are chocolate
- Are they good?
- Yes, thank you
How much? How much?
Here you are!
Don't make us evict you
by force!
You must go back on deck, come
on! Sailors, take them on deck
Whoever knows the language, tell
them we're getting them a place
You may not cross these ropes
without asking permission from
the sailor on duty. Translate!
Stay behind the ropes,
do you understand?
Did they understand? They
may not leave this place
Olga, little one, come here,
come here, beautiful!
Do you like cookies?
Take them, darling.
They are all yours.
Taste them, put them
in your mouth
What a lovely dress
you're wearing!
Is this your daughter?
She's lovely, Klassivaia!
I was giving her cookies.
Take them, little Olga
This is further proof that one
cannot trust the Italians
Your Highness, I was right
predicting trouble in this voyage
- Aren't you going to make a move?
- Let me think, if I make a move...
Your Highness
Excuse me, for safety reasons
I must ask Your Highness
not to leave this cabin till
this situation on deck
is under control
Isn't that a bit too much?
But thank you anyhow
Excuse me
I don't feel in danger.
Ah, right
Checkmate!
I can't play with you!
You always win
You move the pieces saying you
want to "look" at them
What is it?
- I'm afraid!
- What of?
- I don't know, it's too complex.
- It is not
Listen, do you remember?
In the 5th century the Serbs
descended on the Balkans
and then invaded Epirus
and Thessaly
Can you imagine if they're
confined to the stern area?
I see the thermometer, I've got
a fever of 103! What shall I do?
Spoil the show? The audience
had come to see me
- Change the topic.
- No, I sang and gave 7 encores!
You build a mystic gulf where
there are hardly 50 players...
The strength of character and
the grace of warm feminity
make English women...
Let's not waste time beating around
the bush, O.K.?
She's so expressive, she almost
seems to understand what's said
My brother is asleep,
fast asleep
Your Highness, can't we change
our decision?
The voyage is getting to its
end
and Count von Stauffen is
getting more & more suspicious
No, everything'll turn out all right
without us doing a thing
How can you be sure,
Your Highness?
I've had this dream: I was
in a garden with my brother
and an eagle swept down
from Heaven
It flies towards us, catches
my brother and flies away
But he, poor thing, is heavy,
so heavy
So the eagle lets him fall
and he is swallowed up
by a hole in the ground
You can always set my mind
at ease
make me believe every word
you say
Bravo! Hasn't she lovely color
in her voice?
Who was singing?
Like acrobats and monkeys!
- Even the old people dance!
- They don't know anything
This is a very ancient dance,
a pagan one! I've studied it!
They dance it mixed up
with Hungarian Czardas
This is a ritual dance, a rite,
and it goes like this
Bravo!
You're good!
Go down, I want to see
you dance!
Attention! I'd like to present
two great dance masters!
They'll show you how you ought
to dance
This dance is meant to bring
rain on the country
The women lift their arms
so as to pick up the water
The men beat the soil
with their feet
because the seeds must know
that the dance has started
and they open their mouths and
drink the rain from heaven
Like this, like this
I don't have anything
to teach them,
but I think I can learn
something from that one!
Excuse me, excuse me!
Music always seems to be about
to tell you a secret, but then...
Eugenio, Eugenio,
what are you doing?
Don't make me afraid!
Answer me! Eugenio
Is it over?
The object of this dance
is to befriend the elemental spirits
who control the growth
of the seeds
Please, don't lie to me.
Don't act like a child.
- But I didn't sign up, I swear!
- Don't swear at your mother!
She's not my protegee. I don't
care about Righini Biagetti
But you do. I don't question
your taste! Everyone wonders
how a handsome man like you can
lose his head for Righini B.!
- What about us?
- No
Mrs. Dongby, may I have
this dance?
Listen, I think I've got the
right to do what I want and
to give all the lighters in
the world to whoever I wish
That sailor reminds me of
a cousin of mine
Can't I give him a present? I
won't have my feelings checked
or be controlled day and night
as if I were a child
I'm forty years old,
leave me alone!
- Dorotea!
- Good evening
Sir, miss
- May I have the honor of...
- No!
Please! Thank you
Stop it now, Mother.
Sit down, please
Piltro, Piltro, a battleship!
Open, Open!
What are they signaling?
It's the flagship of the
Austro-Hungarian fleet
they want us to surrender the
Serbians we picked up
We'll send them
a telegraph
The refugees will be taken by
the officers of the battleship
Why are you so worried? It's an
Austro-Hungarian battleship, so?
What does the youngster say?
He says we'll all be
made prisoners
that you'll have to deliver
all of us
Excuse me, now let's see
Captain
There is an exchange with the
Austro-Hungarian battleship
- What do they say?
- I haven't intercepted them
Why are these people so afraid?
They tell me to bide my time.
To keep them in the forecastle
- Yes sir!
- Captain
The situation is as follows:
we're signaling
but I don't know the contents
of the messages
We should calm
the gentlemen down
The captain seems calm to me,
doesn't he?
You, Mr. Orlando, how do you
interpret the events?
- Are you also being mysterious?
- Look, right there!
On the forecastle
of the battleship
You can see the signaler's
flags moving
I cannot accept their demand
to hand over the refugees
Transmit that
"Hand them over immediately!"
- Ah, the Grand Duke.
- Good day
The captain is waiting
for you on the forecastle
Y.H., the Austrian ship demands
immediate delivery of the Serbs
Indicate that I'm on board
and the object of this trip
His Highness wishes to let them
know the object of this trip
Signal to the battleship that we
must get to the island of Erimo
- Yes, sir!
- Please, Your Highness
Please, I want to see
They allow us to get to the
island and send the Duke greetings
"They allow us to get to the island
and send the Duke greetings"
We go back on the course towards
the island, Your Highness!
That battleship, too,
knew and loved our Edmea?
The Grand Duke obtained from
the Austrian admiralty
a truce to let us perform
our funeral rite
In a short time we'll see
the island of Erimo
- And remove that daisy!
- You're in a mood
One day she told me this:
"You always talk of my voice,
"but sometimes I'm almost sure
it's not really mine
"I'm a voice,
"a diaphragm, breathing
"I don't know where the voice
comes from
"I'm just an instrument,
a simple girl
"who's even been afraid of this
voice that all my life and
"forced me to do what it wanted
- Squad, halt!
- Excuse me, Mr. Dongby,
- The ceremony's begun!
- To your left!
Mr. Partexano, proceed
Attention!
Hats off!
Psalm of David:
"The Lord is my Shepherd
"I shall not want
"He makes me lie down
in green pastures
"He leads me beside quiet water
"He restores my soul
"He guides me in the paths
of righteousness
"for His name's sake. Lord,
"listen to my prayer
"You know Man is only dust
and ashes
"Dust to dust, ashes to ashes
"The Lord will protect my exit
and my entrance
"From now on, and for all
eternity"
- Proceed.
- On the broadside!
Sailor!
Come, madame
Proceed, madame. Spread the
ashes on the cushion
Hats on!
To your right!
On the left row, go on, march!
Count von Huppenback
please go into your cabin
and stay there until
further orders
- What do you mean, sir?
- By Order of the Princess,
you're under arrest!
It would be lovely
if at this point the
commotion would've also touched
the hearts of the Austrians
and their battleship
would sail away
sending a touching salute
But it didn't happen like that
They wanted the Serbs back,
and how!
And it would have been
even more beautiful
if we, faced with such arrogance
would have said: "No, we won't
give them up!"
No, we won't give them up!
On the other hand, the battleship
had to arrest the Serbs
It was an order from the
Austro-Hungarian police
and the Grand Duke of Herzog
was aboard, representing
the Austro-Hungarian empire!
Mirko!
As I was telling you
It's almost impossible to recall
the sequence of events
It seems that everything was
caused by the rashness
of the young Serb terrorist who
hurled the bomb against the ship
Can such a primitive and rough
hand bomb
hurled by a youngster cause a
historical catastrophe?
Are we certain that it was
the boy who threw the bomb?
If he was living a love story,
why did he run towards
his own destruction?
Apparently he did. The bomb seems
to have been thrown into the ship
and it exploded under the barrel
of a gun,
automatically causing a fire
Others say that they're
sure that automatically
the first gunshot triggered
off the fire
in the whole battery of the
enormous battleship
Others say that it wasn't the
Serb terrorist, nor the bomb,
but the battleship did it
on purpose
to bring about
an international incident
There's a fourth version, which
I haven't got the guts to tell
Apparently
Gentlemen, listen: you can save
yourselves, follow our orders!
Just a few remarks
before I finish:
I want to tell you that many of
the people you met were saved
A ship rescued the survivors
in the lifeboat
The lifeboat was
the "North Star"
and appeared miraculously
Unfortunately, I've heard
nothing more of the others
As for myself
I've got great news
Did you know that rhino milk
is first-class?