2
00:02:33,528 --> 00:02:35,320
It's beautiful here.

3
00:02:36,406 --> 00:02:38,031
It was our aunt's.

4
00:02:38,408 --> 00:02:40,409
We used to come here as kids.

5
00:02:41,202 --> 00:02:43,620
The Order uses it now as a safe house.

6
00:02:45,206 --> 00:02:47,040
What's left of us, at least.

7
00:02:49,335 --> 00:02:53,422
Muggles think these keep evil away,
but they're wrong.

8
00:02:55,967 --> 00:02:57,843
I need to talk to the goblin.

9
00:03:09,731 --> 00:03:10,981
How are you?

10
00:03:13,067 --> 00:03:14,484
Alive.

11
00:03:19,616 --> 00:03:20,949
You probably don't remember--

12
00:03:21,117 --> 00:03:24,286
That I showed you to your vault
the first time you came to Gringotts?

13
00:03:24,871 --> 00:03:27,998
Even amongst goblins you're famous,
Harry Potter.

14
00:03:31,753 --> 00:03:33,462
You buried the elf.

15
00:03:33,880 --> 00:03:35,005
Yes.

16
00:03:35,173 --> 00:03:36,882
And brought me here.

17
00:03:39,302 --> 00:03:40,594
You are...

18
00:03:42,513 --> 00:03:44,806
...a very unusual wizard.

19
00:03:52,315 --> 00:03:54,608
How did you come by this sword?

20
00:03:59,113 --> 00:04:00,489
It's complicated.

21
00:04:02,575 --> 00:04:06,245
Why did Bellatrix Lestrange think it
should be in her vault at Gringotts?

22
00:04:07,622 --> 00:04:09,498
It's complicated.

23
00:04:12,794 --> 00:04:16,380
The sword presented itself to us
in a moment of need.

24
00:04:16,714 --> 00:04:18,298
We didn't steal it.

25
00:04:21,302 --> 00:04:24,721
There is a sword in Madam Lestrange's
vault identical to this one...

26
00:04:24,889 --> 00:04:26,515
...but it is a fake.

27
00:04:26,683 --> 00:04:28,350
It was placed there this summer.

28
00:04:28,518 --> 00:04:31,853
- And she never suspected it was a fake?
- The replica is very convincing.

29
00:04:32,021 --> 00:04:35,899
Only a goblin would recognize
that this is the true sword of Gryffindor.

30
00:04:36,067 --> 00:04:37,776
Who is the acquaintance?

31
00:04:37,944 --> 00:04:42,406
A Hogwarts professor.
As I understand it, he's now headmaster.

32
00:04:43,199 --> 00:04:44,241
Snape?

33
00:04:45,535 --> 00:04:47,953
He put a fake sword in Bellatrix's vault?

34
00:04:48,663 --> 00:04:49,705
Why?

35
00:04:49,872 --> 00:04:54,459
There are more than a few curious things
in the vaults at Gringotts.

36
00:04:55,253 --> 00:04:58,380
And in Madam Lestrange's vault as well?

37
00:05:01,092 --> 00:05:02,259
Perhaps.

38
00:05:04,637 --> 00:05:08,056
I need to get into Gringotts.
Into one of the vaults.

39
00:05:08,725 --> 00:05:09,891
This is impossible.

40
00:05:10,059 --> 00:05:13,979
Alone, yes. But with you, no.

41
00:05:19,068 --> 00:05:20,569
Why should I help you?

42
00:05:20,737 --> 00:05:23,488
I have gold. Lots of it.

43
00:05:23,656 --> 00:05:26,700
- I have no interest in gold.
- Then what?

44
00:05:31,914 --> 00:05:33,415
That.

45
00:05:34,042 --> 00:05:35,083
That is my price.

46
00:05:49,140 --> 00:05:51,808
Are you thinking
there's a Horcrux in Bellatrix's vault?

47
00:05:51,976 --> 00:05:54,478
She was terrified when she
thought we'd been in there.

48
00:05:54,645 --> 00:05:56,521
She kept asking you
what else we'd taken.

49
00:05:56,689 --> 00:05:59,608
I bet you there's a Horcrux in there,
another piece of his soul.

50
00:05:59,776 --> 00:06:02,736
Let's find it and kill it,
we're one step closer to killing him.

51
00:06:02,904 --> 00:06:04,696
And what happens when we find it?

52
00:06:04,864 --> 00:06:08,283
How are we supposed to destroy it
now you've given the sword to Griphook?

53
00:06:08,451 --> 00:06:10,494
I'm still working on that part.

54
00:06:12,830 --> 00:06:14,122
He's weak.

55
00:06:23,424 --> 00:06:25,133
Yes?

56
00:06:26,844 --> 00:06:30,972
Mr. Ollivander, I need to ask you
a few questions.

57
00:06:31,140 --> 00:06:33,934
Anything, my boy, anything.

58
00:06:34,894 --> 00:06:37,479
Would you mind identifying this wand?

59
00:06:37,647 --> 00:06:40,273
We need to know if it's safe to use.

60
00:06:46,197 --> 00:06:47,989
Walnut.

61
00:06:48,866 --> 00:06:51,451
Dragon heartstring.

62
00:06:52,078 --> 00:06:54,871
Twelve and three-quarter inches.

63
00:06:55,832 --> 00:06:57,666
Unyie--

64
00:06:59,752 --> 00:07:01,420
Unyielding.

65
00:07:02,505 --> 00:07:06,758
This belonged to Bellatrix Lestrange.

66
00:07:06,926 --> 00:07:09,719
Treat it carefully.

67
00:07:10,471 --> 00:07:11,721
And this?

68
00:07:15,101 --> 00:07:17,018
Hawthorn.

69
00:07:18,312 --> 00:07:20,939
And unicorn hair.

70
00:07:21,107 --> 00:07:25,777
Ten inches. Reasonably pliant.

71
00:07:29,323 --> 00:07:33,869
This was the wand of Draco Malfoy.

72
00:07:34,579 --> 00:07:37,080
Was? Is it not still?

73
00:07:37,248 --> 00:07:41,376
Well, perhaps not, if you won it from him.

74
00:07:43,754 --> 00:07:47,382
I sense its allegiance has changed.

75
00:07:52,054 --> 00:07:56,975
You talk about wands
as if they have feelings...

76
00:07:58,895 --> 00:08:00,187
...can think.

77
00:08:03,566 --> 00:08:08,028
The wand chooses the wizard, Mr. Potter.

78
00:08:08,571 --> 00:08:13,533
That much has always been clear
to those of us who have studied wandlore.

79
00:08:15,244 --> 00:08:18,079
And what do you know
about the Deathly Hallows?

80
00:08:23,085 --> 00:08:26,254
It is rumored there are three:

81
00:08:28,007 --> 00:08:30,091
The Elder Wand...

82
00:08:30,843 --> 00:08:36,097
...the Cloak of invisibility
to hide you from your enemies...

83
00:08:36,265 --> 00:08:42,103
...and the Resurrection Stone
to bring back loved ones from the dead.

84
00:08:42,271 --> 00:08:47,275
Together, they make one
the master of death.

85
00:08:47,443 --> 00:08:53,532
But few truly believe
that such objects exist.

86
00:08:53,699 --> 00:08:55,367
Do you?

87
00:08:55,952 --> 00:08:58,119
Do you believe they exist, sir?

88
00:09:01,457 --> 00:09:08,255
I see no reason to put stock
into an old wives' tale.

89
00:09:08,714 --> 00:09:09,923
You're lying.

90
00:09:11,175 --> 00:09:13,385
You know one exists.

91
00:09:13,553 --> 00:09:15,387
You told him about it.

92
00:09:15,555 --> 00:09:21,101
You told him about the Elder Wand
and where he could go looking for it.

93
00:09:24,564 --> 00:09:26,690
He tortured me.

94
00:09:29,318 --> 00:09:31,194
Besides...

95
00:09:32,154 --> 00:09:34,906
...I only conveyed rumors.

96
00:09:36,659 --> 00:09:38,201
There's...

97
00:09:39,412 --> 00:09:42,581
There's no telling whether he will find it.

98
00:09:45,626 --> 00:09:47,502
He has found it, sir.

99
00:09:53,384 --> 00:09:55,176
We'll let you rest.

100
00:09:57,722 --> 00:10:00,098
He's after you, Mr. Potter.

101
00:10:00,600 --> 00:10:06,521
If it's true, what you say,
and he has the Elder Wand...

102
00:10:08,357 --> 00:10:10,025
...I'm afraid...

103
00:10:10,610 --> 00:10:13,528
...you really don't stand a chance.

104
00:10:14,739 --> 00:10:18,325
Well, I suppose I'll have to kill him
before he finds me, then.

105
00:10:23,539 --> 00:10:25,749
Are you sure that's hers?

106
00:10:27,501 --> 00:10:29,044
Positive.

107
00:10:35,092 --> 00:10:36,718
Well?

108
00:10:37,803 --> 00:10:39,638
How do I look?

109
00:10:40,014 --> 00:10:41,723
Hideous.

110
00:10:42,391 --> 00:10:45,644
You can give that to Hermione to hold,
all right, Griphook?

111
00:11:05,498 --> 00:11:06,665
We're relying on you.

112
00:11:06,832 --> 00:11:10,877
If you get us past the guards
and into the vault, the sword's yours.

113
00:11:23,432 --> 00:11:24,599
Madam Lestrange.

114
00:11:24,767 --> 00:11:26,559
Good morning.

115
00:11:27,853 --> 00:11:31,439
"Good morning"? "Good morning"?

116
00:11:31,607 --> 00:11:34,734
You're Bellatrix Lestrange,
not some dewy-eyed school girl.

117
00:11:34,902 --> 00:11:36,611
Hey. Easy.

118
00:11:36,779 --> 00:11:41,324
She gives us away, we might as well
use that sword to slit our own throats.

119
00:11:41,492 --> 00:11:43,368
Understand?

120
00:11:43,536 --> 00:11:47,038
No, he's right. I was being stupid.

121
00:11:47,289 --> 00:11:48,790
Okay.

122
00:11:49,041 --> 00:11:50,709
Let's do it.

123
00:12:55,274 --> 00:12:58,234
I wish to enter my vault.

124
00:13:01,447 --> 00:13:03,698
Identification?

125
00:13:06,827 --> 00:13:09,370
I hardly think that'll be necessary.

126
00:13:11,874 --> 00:13:13,708
Madam Lestrange.

127
00:13:19,882 --> 00:13:21,716
I don't like to be kept waiting.

128
00:13:21,884 --> 00:13:23,301
They know.

129
00:13:23,469 --> 00:13:25,637
They know she's an imposter.

130
00:13:28,474 --> 00:13:30,266
They've been warned.

131
00:13:38,317 --> 00:13:39,901
Harry?

132
00:13:40,569 --> 00:13:42,612
What do we do, Harry?

133
00:13:48,077 --> 00:13:52,038
Madam Lestrange,
would you mind presenting your wand?

134
00:13:52,915 --> 00:13:54,207
And why should I do that?

135
00:13:54,375 --> 00:13:59,921
It's the bank's policy. I'm sure you
understand given the current climate.

136
00:14:00,089 --> 00:14:03,258
No. I most certainly do not understand.

137
00:14:03,425 --> 00:14:07,262
I'm afraid I must insist.

138
00:14:12,476 --> 00:14:14,435
Imperio.

139
00:14:19,942 --> 00:14:24,112
Very well, Madam Lestrange.
If you will follow me.

140
00:15:00,316 --> 00:15:01,441
What is that, Griphook?

141
00:15:06,906 --> 00:15:08,239
Griphook.

142
00:15:28,218 --> 00:15:29,719
Arresto momentum.

143
00:15:33,349 --> 00:15:34,724
Well done, Hermione.

144
00:15:43,025 --> 00:15:44,901
Oh, no, you look like you again.

145
00:15:45,527 --> 00:15:49,364
The Thief's Downfall.
Washes away all enchantments.

146
00:15:49,531 --> 00:15:50,657
Can be deadly.

147
00:15:50,824 --> 00:15:52,450
You don't say.

148
00:15:52,618 --> 00:15:55,620
Just out of interest,
is there any other way out of here?

149
00:15:55,788 --> 00:15:57,455
No.

150
00:15:58,374 --> 00:16:02,335
What the devil are all you
doing down here?

151
00:16:02,503 --> 00:16:03,711
Thieves!

152
00:16:03,879 --> 00:16:06,172
- When you gave up the keys, you--
- Imperio.

153
00:16:17,226 --> 00:16:19,435
That doesn't sound good.

154
00:16:29,780 --> 00:16:31,197
Bloody hell.

155
00:16:31,365 --> 00:16:32,699
That's a Ukrainian Ironbelly.

156
00:16:32,866 --> 00:16:34,409
Here.

157
00:16:44,962 --> 00:16:48,381
It's been trained to expect pain
when it hears the noise.

158
00:16:48,549 --> 00:16:50,091
That's barbaric.

159
00:17:19,788 --> 00:17:21,706
Lumos.

160
00:17:25,836 --> 00:17:27,378
Blimey.

161
00:17:34,470 --> 00:17:36,637
Accio Horcrux.

162
00:17:38,182 --> 00:17:40,183
You're not trying that one again,
are you?

163
00:17:40,350 --> 00:17:43,144
That kind of magic won't work in here.

164
00:17:47,357 --> 00:17:49,358
Is it in here, Harry?

165
00:17:50,194 --> 00:17:51,652
Can you feel anything?

166
00:18:13,342 --> 00:18:15,968
That's it. Up there.

167
00:18:19,473 --> 00:18:22,767
They've added the Gemino curse.
Everything you touch will multiply.

168
00:18:22,935 --> 00:18:24,393
Give me the sword.

169
00:18:42,412 --> 00:18:44,080
Stop moving.

170
00:19:06,478 --> 00:19:07,937
Got it.

171
00:19:10,566 --> 00:19:12,191
We had a deal, Griphook.

172
00:19:12,359 --> 00:19:13,734
The cup for the sword.

173
00:19:19,408 --> 00:19:24,412
I said I'd get you in.
I didn't say anything about getting you out.

174
00:19:46,018 --> 00:19:47,101
Griphook!

175
00:19:47,269 --> 00:19:48,936
- Thieves! Help!
- Griphook!

176
00:19:49,104 --> 00:19:50,938
Thieves!

177
00:19:53,609 --> 00:19:56,569
Foul little git.
Least we've still got Bogrod.

178
00:20:03,785 --> 00:20:04,452
That's unfortunate.

179
00:20:09,458 --> 00:20:11,626
- We can't just stand here.
- Who's got an idea?

180
00:20:11,793 --> 00:20:13,336
You're the brilliant one.

181
00:20:13,503 --> 00:20:15,796
I've got something, but it's mad.

182
00:20:15,964 --> 00:20:17,298
Reducto.

183
00:20:30,187 --> 00:20:31,312
Well, come on, then.

184
00:20:33,982 --> 00:20:36,025
Relashio.

185
00:21:22,698 --> 00:21:24,615
He's moving! Aah!

186
00:21:51,226 --> 00:21:52,393
Now what?

187
00:21:52,561 --> 00:21:53,894
Reducto.

188
00:21:55,105 --> 00:21:56,522
Hold on.

189
00:22:06,074 --> 00:22:09,952
That was brilliant. Absolutely brilliant.

190
00:22:37,272 --> 00:22:37,938
We're dropping.

191
00:22:42,027 --> 00:22:44,278
- I say we jump.
- When?

192
00:22:44,446 --> 00:22:45,821
Now.

193
00:23:40,252 --> 00:23:43,212
He knows. You-Know-Who.

194
00:23:43,380 --> 00:23:45,005
He knows we broke into Gringotts.

195
00:23:45,173 --> 00:23:48,342
He knows what we took
and he knows we're hunting Horcruxes.

196
00:23:48,510 --> 00:23:50,344
- How is it you know?
- I saw him.

197
00:23:50,512 --> 00:23:52,972
You let him in? Harry, you can't do that.

198
00:23:53,140 --> 00:23:56,684
Hermione, I can't always help it.
Well, maybe I can. I don't know.

199
00:23:56,852 --> 00:23:58,561
Never mind. What happened?

200
00:23:58,728 --> 00:24:00,521
Well, he's angry.

201
00:24:00,689 --> 00:24:02,273
And scared too.

202
00:24:02,441 --> 00:24:05,943
He knows if we find and destroy all
the Horcruxes we'll be able to kill him.

203
00:24:06,111 --> 00:24:09,780
I reckon he'll stop at nothing
to make sure we don't find the rest.

204
00:24:10,991 --> 00:24:13,242
There's more. One of them's at Hogwarts.

205
00:24:13,410 --> 00:24:15,119
What?

206
00:24:15,287 --> 00:24:17,955
- You saw it?
- I saw the castle and Rowena Ravenclaw.

207
00:24:18,123 --> 00:24:20,708
It must have to do with her.
We have to go there now.

208
00:24:20,876 --> 00:24:24,170
We can't do that. We've got to plan.
We've got to figure it out.

209
00:24:24,337 --> 00:24:27,465
Hermione, when have any of our plans
ever actually worked?

210
00:24:27,632 --> 00:24:30,050
We plan, we get there,
all hell breaks loose.

211
00:24:31,178 --> 00:24:32,428
He's right.

212
00:24:32,596 --> 00:24:36,849
- Snape's headmaster now.
- We can't just walk through the front door.

213
00:24:37,017 --> 00:24:41,770
Um, well, we'll go to Hogsmeade,
to Honeydukes.

214
00:24:41,938 --> 00:24:44,273
Take the secret passage in the cellar.

215
00:24:44,441 --> 00:24:47,818
It's-- There's something wrong with him.

216
00:24:47,986 --> 00:24:52,323
It's like, you know, in the past, I've always
been able to follow his thoughts.

217
00:24:52,491 --> 00:24:55,367
And now everything
just feels disconnected.

218
00:24:55,535 --> 00:24:56,827
Maybe it's the Horcruxes.

219
00:24:56,995 --> 00:24:58,996
Maybe he's growing weaker.
Maybe he's dying.

220
00:24:59,164 --> 00:25:02,291
No. No, it's more like he's wounded.

221
00:25:02,459 --> 00:25:05,252
If anything, he feels more dangerous.

222
00:25:54,678 --> 00:25:56,637
- They're here!
- Search everywhere!

223
00:25:56,805 --> 00:25:58,055
- Look down by the stables!
- You two, come with me!

224
00:26:00,141 --> 00:26:01,642
Any sign?

225
00:26:17,158 --> 00:26:18,200
Potter!

226
00:26:31,464 --> 00:26:32,923
In here, Potter.

227
00:26:46,438 --> 00:26:48,397
Did you get a look at him?

228
00:26:48,565 --> 00:26:51,358
- For a second, I thought it was...
- I know. Dumbledore.

229
00:27:07,959 --> 00:27:09,335
Harry?

230
00:27:11,338 --> 00:27:13,547
I can see you in this.

231
00:27:26,728 --> 00:27:29,271
You bloody fools.
What were you thinking coming here?

232
00:27:29,439 --> 00:27:31,732
Have you any idea how dangerous it is?

233
00:27:31,900 --> 00:27:35,569
You're Aberforth, Dumbledore's brother.

234
00:27:36,112 --> 00:27:37,905
It's you who I've been seeing in here.

235
00:27:38,740 --> 00:27:40,366
You're the one who sent Dobby.

236
00:27:40,533 --> 00:27:41,825
Where have you left him?

237
00:27:42,243 --> 00:27:43,577
He's dead.

238
00:27:44,162 --> 00:27:46,163
Sorry to hear it. I liked that elf.

239
00:27:46,331 --> 00:27:49,249
Who gave that to you? The mirror?

240
00:27:49,709 --> 00:27:52,086
Mundungus Fletcher, about a year ago.

241
00:27:52,253 --> 00:27:55,506
- Dung had no right. It belonged to--
Sirius.

242
00:27:56,007 --> 00:27:57,883
Albus told me.

243
00:27:58,468 --> 00:28:02,680
He also told me you'd likely be hacked off
if you ever found out I had it...

244
00:28:02,847 --> 00:28:07,768
...but ask yourself,
where would you be if I didn't?

245
00:28:10,730 --> 00:28:13,440
Do you hear from the others much?
From the Order?

246
00:28:13,608 --> 00:28:15,567
The Order's finished.

247
00:28:15,735 --> 00:28:17,111
You-Know-Who's won.

248
00:28:17,278 --> 00:28:20,656
Anyone who says otherwise
is kidding themselves.

249
00:28:20,824 --> 00:28:23,367
We need to get into Hogwarts, tonight.

250
00:28:23,785 --> 00:28:25,494
Dumbledore gave us a job to do.

251
00:28:25,662 --> 00:28:27,329
Did he now?

252
00:28:27,497 --> 00:28:28,956
Nice job? Easy?

253
00:28:31,000 --> 00:28:33,043
We've been hunting Horcruxes.

254
00:28:33,211 --> 00:28:36,630
We think the last one's inside the castle,
but we'll need help getting in.

255
00:28:36,798 --> 00:28:40,509
That's not a job my brother's given you.
It's a suicide mission.

256
00:28:40,677 --> 00:28:44,054
Do yourself a favor, boy, go home.
Live a little longer.

257
00:28:44,222 --> 00:28:48,892
- Dumbledore trusted me to see this through.
- What makes you think you can trust him?

258
00:28:49,310 --> 00:28:51,854
You think you can believe
anything my brother told you?

259
00:28:52,021 --> 00:28:55,816
In all the time you knew him,
did he ever mention my name?

260
00:28:56,776 --> 00:28:58,902
Did he ever mention hers?

261
00:28:59,070 --> 00:29:02,781
- Why should he--?
- Keep secrets? You tell me.

262
00:29:03,783 --> 00:29:07,286
- I trusted him.
- That's a boy's answer.

263
00:29:07,454 --> 00:29:10,539
A boy who goes chasing Horcruxes
on the word of a man...

264
00:29:10,707 --> 00:29:13,459
...who wouldn't even tell him where to start.
You're lying!

265
00:29:14,127 --> 00:29:17,921
Not just to me, that doesn't matter.
To yourself as well.

266
00:29:18,089 --> 00:29:20,132
That's what a fool does.

267
00:29:20,300 --> 00:29:24,178
You don't strike me as a fool,
Harry Potter.

268
00:29:24,345 --> 00:29:29,016
So I'll ask you again.
There must be a reason.

269
00:29:31,060 --> 00:29:34,354
I'm not interested in what happened
between you and your brother.

270
00:29:35,064 --> 00:29:37,357
I don't care that you've given up.

271
00:29:39,778 --> 00:29:42,404
I trusted the man I knew.

272
00:29:45,533 --> 00:29:48,619
And we need to get into
the castle tonight.

273
00:29:53,875 --> 00:29:56,293
You know what to do.

274
00:30:02,884 --> 00:30:04,843
Where have you sent her?

275
00:30:05,303 --> 00:30:08,889
You'll see soon enough.

276
00:30:15,063 --> 00:30:17,856
That's your sister, Ariana, isn't it?

277
00:30:18,691 --> 00:30:21,568
She died very young, didn't she?

278
00:30:22,487 --> 00:30:26,240
My brother sacrificed many things,
Mr. Potter...

279
00:30:26,407 --> 00:30:28,909
...on his journey to find power...

280
00:30:29,077 --> 00:30:31,328
...including Ariana.

281
00:30:31,746 --> 00:30:34,623
And she was devoted to him.

282
00:30:35,250 --> 00:30:37,668
He gave her everything...

283
00:30:38,628 --> 00:30:40,379
...but time.

284
00:30:41,756 --> 00:30:44,132
Thank you, Mr. Dumbledore.

285
00:30:50,974 --> 00:30:53,517
He did save our lives twice.

286
00:30:54,143 --> 00:30:56,311
Kept an eye on us in that mirror.

287
00:30:57,564 --> 00:31:00,607
That doesn't seem
like someone who's given up.

288
00:31:05,780 --> 00:31:07,906
She's coming back.

289
00:31:08,658 --> 00:31:09,825
Who's that with her?

290
00:31:18,042 --> 00:31:19,126
Neville.

291
00:31:19,294 --> 00:31:21,795
- Oh, you look--
- Like hell, I reckon.

292
00:31:21,963 --> 00:31:24,590
This is nothing. Seamus is worse.

293
00:31:25,174 --> 00:31:28,802
Hey, Ab, we've got a couple more
coming through.

294
00:31:29,971 --> 00:31:31,847
Don't remember this
on the Marauder's Map.

295
00:31:32,015 --> 00:31:33,932
That's because it never existed till now.

296
00:31:34,100 --> 00:31:37,352
The seven secret passages were sealed off
before the start of the year.

297
00:31:37,520 --> 00:31:39,313
This is the only way in or out now.

298
00:31:39,480 --> 00:31:42,107
The grounds are crawling with
Death Eaters and Dementors.

299
00:31:42,275 --> 00:31:43,984
How bad is Snape as headmaster?

300
00:31:44,152 --> 00:31:47,112
Hardly ever see him.
It's the Carrows you need to watch out for.

301
00:31:47,280 --> 00:31:48,322
Carrows?

302
00:31:48,489 --> 00:31:50,949
Yeah. Brother and sister.
In charge of discipline.

303
00:31:51,117 --> 00:31:52,826
They like punishment, the Carrows.

304
00:31:52,994 --> 00:31:54,995
They did that to you? Why?

305
00:31:55,163 --> 00:31:58,832
Today's Dark Arts lessons
had us practicing the Cruciatus Curse.

306
00:31:59,000 --> 00:32:00,918
On first-years.

307
00:32:01,085 --> 00:32:02,920
I refused.

308
00:32:03,713 --> 00:32:05,839
Hogwarts has changed.

309
00:32:18,728 --> 00:32:21,188
Let's have a bit of fun, shall we?

310
00:32:26,319 --> 00:32:29,237
Hey, listen up, you lot.
Brought you a surprise.

311
00:32:29,405 --> 00:32:33,533
Not more of Aberforth's cooking, I hope.
Be a surprise if we can digest it.

312
00:32:36,371 --> 00:32:37,454
Blimey.

313
00:32:37,622 --> 00:32:39,957
- Harry!
- Yeah!

314
00:32:52,637 --> 00:32:55,472
Get the word out to Remus and the others
that Harry's back.

315
00:32:55,640 --> 00:32:57,808
Okay, let's not kill him before
You-Know-Who--

316
00:32:57,976 --> 00:32:59,518
River, D.A. calling. Do you read?

317
00:32:59,686 --> 00:33:01,603
Lightning has struck.

318
00:33:03,690 --> 00:33:04,564
What's the plan, Harry?

319
00:33:09,404 --> 00:33:10,445
Okay.

320
00:33:11,406 --> 00:33:13,532
There's something we need to find.

321
00:33:13,700 --> 00:33:18,662
Something hidden here in the castle.
And it may help us defeat You-Know-Who.

322
00:33:18,830 --> 00:33:20,622
Right. What is it?

323
00:33:20,790 --> 00:33:21,957
We don't know.

324
00:33:23,918 --> 00:33:26,837
- Where is it?
- We don't know that either.

325
00:33:28,214 --> 00:33:31,425
- I realize it's not much to go on.
- That's nothing to go on.

326
00:33:31,592 --> 00:33:34,094
I think it has something to do
with Ravenclaw.

327
00:33:34,262 --> 00:33:38,932
Um, it'll be small, easily concealed.

328
00:33:39,767 --> 00:33:41,935
Anyone, any ideas?

329
00:33:43,271 --> 00:33:45,772
Well, there's Rowena Ravenclaw's
lost diadem.

330
00:33:45,940 --> 00:33:49,484
- Oh, bloody hell. Here we go.
- Lost diadem of Ravenclaw?

331
00:33:51,571 --> 00:33:54,990
Hasn't anyone heard of it?
It's quite famous.

332
00:33:55,158 --> 00:33:58,535
Yes, but, Luna, it's lost,
for centuries now.

333
00:33:58,703 --> 00:34:01,496
There isn't a person alive today
who's seen it.

334
00:34:01,664 --> 00:34:03,874
Excuse me. Can someone tell me
what a bloody diadem is?

335
00:34:04,042 --> 00:34:06,793
It's a sort of crown.
You know, like a tiara.

336
00:34:10,048 --> 00:34:11,298
Harry.

337
00:34:12,592 --> 00:34:13,884
Hi there.

338
00:34:17,055 --> 00:34:20,140
Six months she hasn't seen me
and it's like I'm Frankie First-Year.

339
00:34:20,308 --> 00:34:22,059
- I'm her brother.
- Got lots of those.

340
00:34:22,226 --> 00:34:24,519
- There's only one Harry.
- Shut up, Seamus.

341
00:34:24,687 --> 00:34:26,188
What is it, Ginny?

342
00:34:26,355 --> 00:34:30,567
Snape knows. He knows that Harry
was spotted in Hogsmeade.

343
00:35:09,816 --> 00:35:15,195
Many of you are surely wondering
why I have summoned you at this hour.

344
00:35:17,657 --> 00:35:21,409
It's come to my attention
that earlier this evening...

345
00:35:22,870 --> 00:35:25,122
...Harry Potter was sighted
in Hogsmeade.

346
00:35:27,625 --> 00:35:29,209
Now...

347
00:35:29,377 --> 00:35:31,002
...should anyone...

348
00:35:32,672 --> 00:35:37,884
...student or staff,
attempt to aid Mr. Potter...

349
00:35:39,053 --> 00:35:41,179
...they will be punished...

350
00:35:41,347 --> 00:35:45,809
...in a manner consistent with
the severity of their transgression.

351
00:35:45,977 --> 00:35:48,228
Furthermore...

352
00:35:48,563 --> 00:35:53,233
...any person found to have knowledge
of these events...

353
00:35:54,569 --> 00:35:58,530
...who fails to come forward...

354
00:35:59,448 --> 00:36:04,035
...will be treated as...

355
00:36:04,704 --> 00:36:07,914
...equally guilty.

356
00:36:10,209 --> 00:36:12,043
Now then...

357
00:36:15,506 --> 00:36:17,591
...if anyone here...

358
00:36:18,092 --> 00:36:24,264
...has any knowledge of Mr. Potter's
movements this evening...

359
00:36:26,475 --> 00:36:30,353
...I invite them to step forward...

360
00:36:33,900 --> 00:36:35,609
...now.

361
00:36:50,249 --> 00:36:54,127
It seems, despite your exhaustive
defensive strategies...

362
00:36:54,295 --> 00:36:56,963
...you still have a bit of a security problem,
headmaster.

363
00:37:00,468 --> 00:37:03,470
And I'm afraid it's quite extensive.

364
00:37:04,222 --> 00:37:06,306
How dare you stand where he stood?

365
00:37:07,934 --> 00:37:10,060
Tell them how it happened that night.

366
00:37:10,228 --> 00:37:14,773
Tell them how you looked him in the eye,
a man who trusted you, and killed him.

367
00:37:15,149 --> 00:37:16,816
Tell them.

368
00:37:41,676 --> 00:37:42,676
Coward!

369
00:37:51,769 --> 00:37:54,229
Harry.

370
00:37:55,356 --> 00:37:56,523
Potter?

371
00:38:31,183 --> 00:38:36,730
I know that many of you will want to fight.

372
00:38:36,897 --> 00:38:41,943
Some of you may even think
that to fight is wise.

373
00:38:42,361 --> 00:38:45,405
But this is folly.

374
00:38:45,906 --> 00:38:48,742
Give me Harry Potter.

375
00:38:49,702 --> 00:38:53,872
Do this and none shall be harmed.

376
00:38:54,040 --> 00:39:00,086
Give me Harry Potter
and I shall leave Hogwarts untouched.

377
00:39:00,254 --> 00:39:03,173
Give me Harry Potter...

378
00:39:03,341 --> 00:39:07,260
...and you will be rewarded.

379
00:39:07,428 --> 00:39:11,056
You have one hour.

380
00:39:20,775 --> 00:39:22,776
What are you waiting for?

381
00:39:22,943 --> 00:39:24,277
Someone grab him.

382
00:39:33,204 --> 00:39:35,121
Students out of bed.

383
00:39:35,915 --> 00:39:38,166
Students out of bed!

384
00:39:38,334 --> 00:39:39,918
Students in the corridor!

385
00:39:40,086 --> 00:39:43,463
They are supposed to be out of bed,
you blithering idiot.

386
00:39:44,840 --> 00:39:46,299
Oh.

387
00:39:46,884 --> 00:39:47,926
Sorry, ma'am.

388
00:39:48,094 --> 00:39:51,971
As it happens, Mr. Filch,
your arrival is most opportune.

389
00:39:52,139 --> 00:39:54,474
If you would, I would like you, please...

390
00:39:54,642 --> 00:39:59,145
...to lead Miss Parkinson and the rest
of Slytherin House from the hall.

391
00:39:59,313 --> 00:40:01,689
Exactly where is it
I'll be leading them to, ma'am?

392
00:40:01,857 --> 00:40:04,651
The dungeons would do.

393
00:40:06,737 --> 00:40:09,447
Right. Come on. Come on.

394
00:40:09,615 --> 00:40:12,909
I presume you have a reason for returning,
Potter. What is it you need?

395
00:40:13,077 --> 00:40:15,662
Time, professor.
As much as you can get me.

396
00:40:16,247 --> 00:40:19,833
Do what you have to do.
I'll secure the castle.

397
00:40:20,668 --> 00:40:22,293
Potter.

398
00:40:24,171 --> 00:40:26,005
It's good to see you.

399
00:40:26,924 --> 00:40:29,259
It's good to see you too, professor.

400
00:40:29,844 --> 00:40:31,970
Hold the fort, Neville.

401
00:40:35,391 --> 00:40:37,392
Hurry up, come on!

402
00:40:45,025 --> 00:40:46,151
Harry. Hermione and I
have been thinking.

403
00:40:46,318 --> 00:40:48,236
It doesn't matter if we find a Horcrux.

404
00:40:48,404 --> 00:40:50,530
- What do you mean?
- Unless we can destroy it.

405
00:40:50,698 --> 00:40:52,073
So we were thinking...

406
00:40:52,241 --> 00:40:54,742
Ron was thinking.
It was Ron's idea. It's brilliant.

407
00:40:54,910 --> 00:40:58,037
You destroyed Tom Riddle's diary
with a basilisk fang, right?

408
00:40:58,205 --> 00:41:00,373
Me and Hermione
know where we might find one.

409
00:41:00,541 --> 00:41:02,375
Okay.

410
00:41:02,543 --> 00:41:06,296
Okay, but take this. That way you can
find me when you get back.

411
00:41:06,464 --> 00:41:08,548
- Where are you going?
- Ravenclaw common room.

412
00:41:08,716 --> 00:41:10,216
Gotta start somewhere.

413
00:41:16,307 --> 00:41:18,725
Harry. Harry!

414
00:41:20,811 --> 00:41:23,521
Let me get this straight.
You're giving us permission to do this?

415
00:41:23,689 --> 00:41:25,565
That is correct, Longbottom.

416
00:41:25,733 --> 00:41:27,150
To blow it up? Boom?

417
00:41:27,318 --> 00:41:28,818
Boom!

418
00:41:28,986 --> 00:41:32,405
Wicked. But how on earth
are we gonna do that?

419
00:41:32,573 --> 00:41:34,908
Why don't you confer with Mr. Finnigan?

420
00:41:35,075 --> 00:41:38,620
As I recall, he has a particular proclivity
for pyrotechnics.

421
00:41:38,787 --> 00:41:39,829
I can bring it down.

422
00:41:39,997 --> 00:41:42,373
That's the spirit. Now away you go.

423
00:41:43,250 --> 00:41:46,586
You do realize, of course, we can't keep out
You-Know-Who indefinitely.

424
00:41:46,754 --> 00:41:49,923
Well, that doesn't mean
we can't delay him.

425
00:41:50,591 --> 00:41:55,094
And his name is Voldemort, Filius.
You might as well use it.

426
00:41:55,262 --> 00:41:58,181
He's going to try to kill you either way.

427
00:42:00,434 --> 00:42:03,770
Piertotum Locomotor.

428
00:42:19,286 --> 00:42:21,120
Hogwarts is threatened.

429
00:42:21,288 --> 00:42:27,460
Man the boundaries. Protect us.
Do your duty to our school.

430
00:42:30,464 --> 00:42:34,217
I've always wanted to use that spell.

431
00:42:43,060 --> 00:42:47,060
Protege Maxima. Fianto Duri.
Repello Inimicum.

432
00:42:55,948 --> 00:42:56,656
Protege Maxima.

433
00:43:25,811 --> 00:43:30,189
- Harry, wait. I need to talk to you.
- I'm a bit preoccupied at the moment, Luna.

434
00:43:30,357 --> 00:43:33,026
You won't find anything
where you're going. You're wasting time.

435
00:43:33,193 --> 00:43:35,194
- Look, we'll talk later, okay, Luna?
- Harry.

436
00:43:35,362 --> 00:43:36,738
- Later.
- Harry Potter!

437
00:43:36,905 --> 00:43:38,865
You listen to me right now!

438
00:43:40,367 --> 00:43:43,411
Don't you remember what Cho said
about Rowena Ravenclaw's diadem?

439
00:43:43,871 --> 00:43:46,831
"There's not a person alive
who's seen it."

440
00:43:46,999 --> 00:43:51,711
It's obvious, isn't it?
We have to talk to someone who's dead.

441
00:44:02,056 --> 00:44:04,891
It's very impressive, isn't it?

442
00:44:20,240 --> 00:44:22,867
If you're to find her,
you'll find her down there.

443
00:44:23,035 --> 00:44:24,452
- Aren't you coming?
- No.

444
00:44:24,620 --> 00:44:27,121
I think it's best if you two talk alone.

445
00:44:27,289 --> 00:44:29,499
She's very shy.

446
00:44:56,026 --> 00:44:57,568
You're the Grey Lady...

447
00:44:58,320 --> 00:45:00,113
...the Ghost of Ravenclaw Tower.

448
00:45:00,280 --> 00:45:01,989
I do not answer to that name.

449
00:45:02,157 --> 00:45:06,744
No, I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
It's Helena, isn't it? Helena Ravenclaw.

450
00:45:06,912 --> 00:45:09,038
Rowena's daughter.

451
00:45:09,206 --> 00:45:11,249
Are you a friend of Luna's?

452
00:45:11,417 --> 00:45:13,334
Yes.

453
00:45:13,502 --> 00:45:15,962
And she thought you might be able
to help me.

454
00:45:17,881 --> 00:45:20,466
You seek my mother's diadem.

455
00:45:21,969 --> 00:45:23,678
Yes.

456
00:45:24,596 --> 00:45:25,638
That's right.

457
00:45:27,391 --> 00:45:32,061
Luna is kind,
unlike so many of the others.

458
00:45:32,229 --> 00:45:35,314
But she was wrong. I cannot help you.

459
00:45:39,945 --> 00:45:42,363
Wait. Please.

460
00:45:44,992 --> 00:45:46,117
I want to destroy it.

461
00:46:24,114 --> 00:46:26,616
They never learn.

462
00:46:27,701 --> 00:46:29,786
Such a pity.

463
00:46:30,037 --> 00:46:33,372
But, my Lord...

464
00:46:33,540 --> 00:46:35,833
...shouldn't we wait for...?

465
00:46:36,001 --> 00:46:37,710
My Lord.

466
00:46:42,883 --> 00:46:44,383
Begin.

467
00:47:04,988 --> 00:47:07,323
That's what you want too,
isn't it, Helena?

468
00:47:12,913 --> 00:47:14,163
You want it destroyed.

469
00:47:14,331 --> 00:47:17,375
Another swore to destroy it
many years ago...

470
00:47:17,543 --> 00:47:20,419
...a strange boy with a strange name.

471
00:47:20,587 --> 00:47:23,422
- Tom Riddle.
- But he lied.

472
00:47:23,590 --> 00:47:24,757
He's lied to many people.

473
00:47:24,925 --> 00:47:28,052
I know what he's done! I know who he is!

474
00:47:28,220 --> 00:47:31,097
He defiled it with dark magic!

475
00:47:46,113 --> 00:47:49,782
I can destroy it once and for all.

476
00:47:51,785 --> 00:47:54,745
But only if you tell me where he hid it.

477
00:47:56,707 --> 00:48:02,461
You do know where he hid it,
don't you, Helena?

478
00:48:04,006 --> 00:48:06,465
You just have to tell me.

479
00:48:07,968 --> 00:48:09,760
Please.

480
00:48:21,481 --> 00:48:23,816
Strange.

481
00:48:26,653 --> 00:48:29,780
You remind me of him a bit.

482
00:48:30,991 --> 00:48:32,241
It's here...

483
00:48:32,910 --> 00:48:37,163
...in the castle, in the place where
everything is hidden.

484
00:48:39,374 --> 00:48:40,791
If you have to ask...

485
00:48:40,959 --> 00:48:43,252
...you will never know.

486
00:48:44,254 --> 00:48:47,173
If you know, you need only ask.

487
00:48:49,343 --> 00:48:51,052
Thank you.

488
00:49:03,815 --> 00:49:08,110
Tell Professor McGonagall Remus and I
will handle this side of the castle.

489
00:49:08,946 --> 00:49:10,696
Yes, sir.

490
00:49:14,076 --> 00:49:17,203
Hey, Dean, on second
thoughts, tell Professor McGonagall...

491
00:49:17,371 --> 00:49:20,206
...we might need one or two more wands
this side.

492
00:49:22,709 --> 00:49:25,711
It is the quality of one's
convictions that determines success...

493
00:49:25,879 --> 00:49:27,630
...not the number of followers.

494
00:49:27,798 --> 00:49:29,799
Who said that?

495
00:49:30,217 --> 00:49:31,801
Me.

496
00:49:36,556 --> 00:49:38,474
You okay, Freddie?

497
00:49:38,850 --> 00:49:40,267
Yeah.

498
00:49:41,728 --> 00:49:43,437
Me too.

499
00:50:00,539 --> 00:50:04,166
Harry talks in his sleep.
Have you noticed?

500
00:50:05,043 --> 00:50:07,086
No, of course not.

501
00:50:54,634 --> 00:50:56,302
Yeah?

502
00:50:56,470 --> 00:50:57,970
You and whose army?

503
00:51:18,158 --> 00:51:19,825
- You do it.
- I can't.

504
00:51:19,993 --> 00:51:22,078
Yes, you can.

505
00:54:20,173 --> 00:54:21,799
Neville!

506
00:54:38,984 --> 00:54:40,734
That went well.

507
00:55:27,032 --> 00:55:31,076
- Get inside!
- This way, everyone. Take cover!

508
00:55:48,762 --> 00:55:50,596
Stupefy!

509
00:55:51,931 --> 00:55:53,432
Get your coat on!

510
00:55:53,600 --> 00:55:56,727
Ginny. Neville. Are you all right?

511
00:55:56,895 --> 00:56:01,440
Never better. I feel like I could spit fire.
You haven't seen Luna, have you?

512
00:56:01,608 --> 00:56:03,442
- Luna?
- I'm mad for her!

513
00:56:03,610 --> 00:56:07,905
I think it's about time I told her
since we'll probably both be dead by dawn.

514
00:56:11,868 --> 00:56:13,619
I know.

515
00:56:41,439 --> 00:56:44,024
Bloody hell. We'll never find it on this.

516
00:56:44,192 --> 00:56:46,860
- There he is, just there.
- Brilliant.

517
00:56:47,028 --> 00:56:50,322
He just vanished. Just now. I saw it.

518
00:56:53,493 --> 00:56:55,452
Maybe he's gone to
the Room of Requirement.

519
00:56:55,620 --> 00:56:59,081
It doesn't show up on the map, does it?
You said that last year.

520
00:56:59,249 --> 00:57:01,583
That's right. I-- I did.

521
00:57:01,751 --> 00:57:03,460
Let's go.

522
00:57:04,170 --> 00:57:05,879
Brilliant.

523
00:57:11,511 --> 00:57:13,178
Come on!

524
00:59:05,083 --> 00:59:06,416
Well, well.

525
00:59:07,377 --> 00:59:09,461
What brings you here, Potter?

526
00:59:10,296 --> 00:59:12,130
I could ask you the same.

527
00:59:12,757 --> 00:59:14,800
You have something of mine.

528
00:59:15,677 --> 00:59:17,219
I'd like it back.

529
00:59:17,387 --> 00:59:19,763
- What's wrong with the one you have?
It's my mother's.

530
00:59:19,931 --> 00:59:23,809
It's powerful, but it's not the same.

531
00:59:23,977 --> 00:59:27,604
Doesn't quite understand me.

532
00:59:28,106 --> 00:59:29,565
Know what I mean?

533
00:59:30,149 --> 00:59:32,109
Why didn't you tell her?

534
00:59:33,778 --> 00:59:34,987
Bellatrix.

535
00:59:38,366 --> 00:59:41,618
You knew it was me.
You didn't say anything.

536
00:59:43,663 --> 00:59:47,958
Come on, Draco.
Don't be a prat. Do him.

537
00:59:48,751 --> 00:59:50,085
Easy.

538
00:59:51,504 --> 00:59:52,796
Expelliarmus.

539
00:59:52,964 --> 00:59:54,006
Avada Kedavra!

540
00:59:54,173 --> 00:59:55,173
Stupefy!

541
00:59:59,679 --> 01:00:02,681
That's my girlfriend, you numpties!

542
01:00:24,287 --> 01:00:25,912
Got it.

543
01:00:32,712 --> 01:00:34,046
Run!

544
01:00:35,298 --> 01:00:36,506
Run!

545
01:00:40,553 --> 01:00:43,388
Goyle's setting the bloody place on fire!

546
01:01:50,415 --> 01:01:52,290
Come on! This way!

547
01:01:59,632 --> 01:02:01,633
We can't leave them.

548
01:02:01,801 --> 01:02:03,969
He's joking, right?

549
01:02:12,645 --> 01:02:15,480
If we die for them, Harry,
I'm gonna kill you.

550
01:02:38,171 --> 01:02:39,838
Harry!

551
01:03:26,260 --> 01:03:27,552
My Lord?

552
01:03:27,720 --> 01:03:30,263
Avada Kedavra!

553
01:03:36,604 --> 01:03:40,899
Come, Nagini. I need to keep you safe.

554
01:03:53,246 --> 01:03:55,080
It's the snake.

555
01:03:55,248 --> 01:03:58,875
She's the last one. It's the last Horcrux.

556
01:04:05,550 --> 01:04:07,926
Look inside him, Harry.

557
01:04:08,094 --> 01:04:11,888
Find out where he is.
If we find him, we can find the snake.

558
01:04:12,056 --> 01:04:14,182
Then we can end this.

559
01:04:41,878 --> 01:04:43,628
My Lord?

560
01:04:43,796 --> 01:04:47,632
Might it be less, uh...

561
01:04:48,426 --> 01:04:52,721
Might it not be more prudent
to call off this attack...

562
01:04:53,472 --> 01:04:55,807
...and simply seek the boy yourself?

563
01:04:55,975 --> 01:04:59,311
I do not need to seek the boy.

564
01:04:59,478 --> 01:05:03,857
Before the night is out, he will come to me.
Do you understand?

565
01:05:05,818 --> 01:05:07,819
Look at me.

566
01:05:07,987 --> 01:05:11,948
How can you live with yourself, Lucius?

567
01:05:12,116 --> 01:05:13,867
I don't know.

568
01:05:15,995 --> 01:05:18,496
Go and find Severus.

569
01:05:19,123 --> 01:05:21,166
Bring him to me.

570
01:05:29,175 --> 01:05:31,217
I know where he is.

571
01:05:40,895 --> 01:05:43,021
Come on!

572
01:06:23,062 --> 01:06:25,188
Crucio!

573
01:06:30,903 --> 01:06:32,362
No!

574
01:07:18,492 --> 01:07:21,745
You have performed extraordinary
magic with this wand, my Lord...

575
01:07:21,912 --> 01:07:23,955
...in the last few hours alone.

576
01:07:24,123 --> 01:07:25,874
No.

577
01:07:26,333 --> 01:07:29,627
No, I am extraordinary...

578
01:07:29,795 --> 01:07:33,423
...but the wand resists me.

579
01:07:33,591 --> 01:07:36,634
There is no wand more powerful.

580
01:07:36,802 --> 01:07:39,637
Ollivander himself has said it.

581
01:07:39,805 --> 01:07:45,435
Tonight, when the boy comes,
it will not fail you. I am sure of it.

582
01:07:47,480 --> 01:07:50,315
It answers to you...

583
01:07:51,150 --> 01:07:53,485
...and you only.

584
01:07:54,236 --> 01:07:55,737
Does it?

585
01:07:58,741 --> 01:08:00,283
My Lord?

586
01:08:02,578 --> 01:08:06,915
The wand, does it truly answer to me?

587
01:08:08,667 --> 01:08:10,794
You're a clever man, Severus.

588
01:08:10,961 --> 01:08:12,837
Surely you must know.

589
01:08:14,548 --> 01:08:18,259
Where does its true loyalty lie?

590
01:08:18,761 --> 01:08:20,512
With you...

591
01:08:21,013 --> 01:08:23,139
...of course, my Lord.

592
01:08:23,307 --> 01:08:24,516
The Elder Wand...

593
01:08:25,309 --> 01:08:31,106
...cannot serve me properly
because I am not its true master.

594
01:08:32,191 --> 01:08:37,695
The Elder Wand belongs to the wizard
who killed its last owner.

595
01:08:43,619 --> 01:08:47,288
You killed Dumbledore, Severus.

596
01:08:48,165 --> 01:08:53,419
While you live,
the Elder Wand cannot truly be mine.

597
01:08:54,880 --> 01:08:58,633
You've been a good and faithful servant,
Severus...

598
01:08:59,135 --> 01:09:04,222
...but only I can live forever.

599
01:09:07,518 --> 01:09:08,560
My Lord--

600
01:09:14,567 --> 01:09:16,359
Nagini, kill.

601
01:10:17,463 --> 01:10:19,422
Take them.

602
01:10:20,591 --> 01:10:22,508
Take them.

603
01:10:23,344 --> 01:10:24,802
Please.

604
01:10:24,970 --> 01:10:28,681
Give me something. Quickly.
A flask, anything.

605
01:10:46,992 --> 01:10:48,493
Take them to the Pensieve.

606
01:10:52,039 --> 01:10:53,998
Look at me.

607
01:10:59,755 --> 01:11:02,507
You have your mother's eyes.

608
01:11:36,166 --> 01:11:39,711
You have fought valiantly...

609
01:11:41,130 --> 01:11:43,881
...but in vain.

610
01:11:47,177 --> 01:11:49,429
I do not wish this.

611
01:11:49,596 --> 01:11:55,143
Every drop of magical blood spilled
is a terrible waste.

612
01:11:55,311 --> 01:12:00,064
I therefore command my forces to retreat.

613
01:12:00,232 --> 01:12:05,778
In their absence,
dispose of your dead with dignity.

614
01:12:06,280 --> 01:12:12,327
Harry Potter, I now speak directly to you.

615
01:12:12,494 --> 01:12:17,874
On this night, you have allowed
your friends to die for you...

616
01:12:18,042 --> 01:12:20,543
...rather than face me yourself.

617
01:12:20,711 --> 01:12:24,255
There is no greater dishonor.

618
01:12:24,423 --> 01:12:29,427
Join me in the Forbidden Forest
and confront your fate.

619
01:12:30,637 --> 01:12:33,264
If you do not do this...

620
01:12:33,432 --> 01:12:40,104
...I shall kill every last man,
woman and child...

621
01:12:40,272 --> 01:12:44,859
...who tries to conceal you from me.

622
01:13:04,421 --> 01:13:06,339
Where is everybody?

623
01:13:31,156 --> 01:13:32,156
Harry.

624
01:13:37,830 --> 01:13:40,623
- Oh, come on.
- What's the matter with you?

625
01:13:40,791 --> 01:13:42,417
Oh, she's passed.

626
01:13:44,211 --> 01:13:46,712
There, she's gone.

627
01:15:55,467 --> 01:15:56,467
Freak!

628
01:15:56,635 --> 01:15:58,135
Come here.

629
01:15:58,303 --> 01:16:00,388
I'm gonna tell Mummy. You're a freak.

630
01:16:00,556 --> 01:16:02,974
You're a freak, Lily!

631
01:16:03,141 --> 01:16:04,767
Come here.

632
01:16:25,747 --> 01:16:29,041
She's jealous because
she's ordinary and you're special.

633
01:16:29,209 --> 01:16:31,752
That's mean, Severus.

634
01:16:54,568 --> 01:16:56,652
Gryffindor!

635
01:17:04,202 --> 01:17:07,121
- Hi. I'm James.
- Hi. I'm Lily.

636
01:17:11,710 --> 01:17:15,838
Just like your father. Lazy. Arrogant.

637
01:17:16,006 --> 01:17:17,840
Don't say a word against my father.

638
01:17:24,139 --> 01:17:25,723
Blood shall be spilt...

639
01:17:25,891 --> 01:17:30,895
...and servant and master
shall be reunited once more.

640
01:17:31,063 --> 01:17:32,980
Severus.

641
01:17:34,066 --> 01:17:36,067
No. Don't kill me.

642
01:17:36,234 --> 01:17:40,071
The prophecy did not refer to a woman.

643
01:17:40,238 --> 01:17:42,490
It spoke of a boy born at the end of July.

644
01:17:42,658 --> 01:17:44,909
Yes, but he thinks it's her son.

645
01:17:45,494 --> 01:17:48,663
He intends to hunt them down now,
to kill them.

646
01:17:48,830 --> 01:17:53,334
Hide her. Hide them all. I beg you.

647
01:17:53,502 --> 01:17:56,587
What will you give me
in exchange, Severus?

648
01:17:58,340 --> 01:17:59,382
Anything.

649
01:17:59,549 --> 01:18:04,261
Harry. Harry, you are so loved. So loved.

650
01:18:05,263 --> 01:18:07,932
Harry, Mama loves you.

651
01:18:08,100 --> 01:18:09,975
Dada loves you.

652
01:18:12,062 --> 01:18:14,063
Harry, be safe.

653
01:18:14,231 --> 01:18:15,272
Be strong.

654
01:18:15,440 --> 01:18:16,941
Avada Kedavra!

655
01:18:21,446 --> 01:18:25,908
You said you would keep her safe.

656
01:18:26,076 --> 01:18:30,121
Lily and James put
their faith in the wrong person, Severus.

657
01:18:31,081 --> 01:18:33,124
Rather like you.

658
01:18:35,293 --> 01:18:36,752
The boy survives.

659
01:18:36,920 --> 01:18:39,171
He doesn't need protection.
The Dark Lord is gone.

660
01:18:39,339 --> 01:18:41,590
The Dark Lord will return.

661
01:18:41,758 --> 01:18:45,302
And when he does,
the boy will be in terrible danger.

662
01:18:46,513 --> 01:18:48,848
He has her eyes.

663
01:18:52,310 --> 01:18:55,479
If you truly loved her...

664
01:18:58,191 --> 01:19:02,027
No one can know.

665
01:19:02,195 --> 01:19:04,697
That I should never reveal
the best of you, Severus?

666
01:19:04,865 --> 01:19:05,906
Your word.

667
01:19:06,074 --> 01:19:08,993
When you risk your life
every day to protect the boy?

668
01:19:09,161 --> 01:19:12,705
He possesses no measurable talent,
his arrogance rivals that of his father...

669
01:19:12,873 --> 01:19:14,749
...and he seems to relish his fame.

670
01:19:14,916 --> 01:19:17,793
Don't say a word against my father.

671
01:19:17,961 --> 01:19:20,171
James Potter?

672
01:19:20,338 --> 01:19:21,839
Lazy, arrogant.

673
01:19:22,007 --> 01:19:23,340
My father was a great man.

674
01:19:23,508 --> 01:19:25,384
Your father was a swine!

675
01:19:27,220 --> 01:19:28,888
Drink the rest.

676
01:19:29,055 --> 01:19:33,100
It will contain the curse to your hand
for the time being.

677
01:19:33,268 --> 01:19:35,186
It will spread, Albus.

678
01:19:35,353 --> 01:19:37,062
How long?

679
01:19:38,023 --> 01:19:40,524
Maybe a year.

680
01:19:42,694 --> 01:19:43,861
Don't ignore me, Severus.

681
01:19:44,029 --> 01:19:45,529
Harmonia Nectere Passus.

682
01:19:45,697 --> 01:19:49,700
We both know Lord Voldemort
has ordered the Malfoy boy to murder me.

683
01:19:51,745 --> 01:19:55,998
But should he fail,
one should presume the Dark Lord...

684
01:19:56,166 --> 01:19:58,292
...will turn to you.

685
01:20:01,046 --> 01:20:04,965
You must be the one to kill me, Severus.

686
01:20:05,133 --> 01:20:07,301
It is the only way.

687
01:20:08,261 --> 01:20:12,640
Only then will the Dark Lord
trust you completely.

688
01:20:12,808 --> 01:20:15,476
Avada Kedavra.

689
01:20:18,730 --> 01:20:23,651
There will come a time
when Harry Potter must be told something.

690
01:20:25,237 --> 01:20:30,407
But you must wait until Voldemort
is at his most vulnerable.

691
01:20:30,575 --> 01:20:33,494
Must be told what?

692
01:20:33,662 --> 01:20:35,704
On the night Lord Voldemort...

693
01:20:35,872 --> 01:20:39,083
...went to Godric's Hollow to kill Harry...

694
01:20:40,085 --> 01:20:42,795
...and Lily Potter cast herself
between them...

695
01:20:43,588 --> 01:20:45,506
...the curse rebounded.

696
01:20:47,300 --> 01:20:50,928
When that happened,
a part of Voldemort's soul...

697
01:20:51,096 --> 01:20:55,933
...latched itself onto the only living thing
it could find:

698
01:20:56,101 --> 01:20:58,269
Harry himself.

699
01:20:59,604 --> 01:21:03,023
There's a reason Harry can speak
with snakes.

700
01:21:03,608 --> 01:21:06,443
There's a reason he can look into
Lord Voldemort's mind.

701
01:21:08,780 --> 01:21:14,869
A part of Voldemort lives inside him.

702
01:21:21,293 --> 01:21:24,253
So when the time comes...

703
01:21:25,130 --> 01:21:27,298
...the boy must die?

704
01:21:29,217 --> 01:21:31,260
Yes. Yes.

705
01:21:31,428 --> 01:21:33,679
He must die.

706
01:21:51,990 --> 01:21:56,827
You've kept him alive
so that he can die at the proper moment.

707
01:22:00,498 --> 01:22:03,083
You've been raising him
like a pig for slaughter.

708
01:22:05,170 --> 01:22:08,672
Don't tell me now that you've grown
to care for the boy?

709
01:22:13,178 --> 01:22:16,430
Expecto Patronum.

710
01:22:27,359 --> 01:22:28,859
Lily.

711
01:22:32,113 --> 01:22:34,114
After all this time?

712
01:22:37,869 --> 01:22:39,036
Always.

713
01:22:45,168 --> 01:22:48,170
So when the time comes...

714
01:22:48,338 --> 01:22:51,340
...the boy must die?

715
01:22:51,508 --> 01:22:54,885
Yes. He must die.

716
01:22:55,053 --> 01:22:58,055
And Voldemort himself must do it.

717
01:22:58,473 --> 01:23:00,683
That is essential.

718
01:24:05,707 --> 01:24:06,790
Where've you been?

719
01:24:06,958 --> 01:24:10,127
- We thought you went to the forest.
- I'm going there now.

720
01:24:10,295 --> 01:24:13,255
Are you mad? No.

721
01:24:13,965 --> 01:24:16,467
You can't give yourself up to him.

722
01:24:19,804 --> 01:24:21,722
What is it, Harry?

723
01:24:23,266 --> 01:24:25,184
What is it you know?

724
01:24:27,979 --> 01:24:30,564
There's a reason I can hear them...

725
01:24:31,149 --> 01:24:32,399
...the Horcruxes.

726
01:24:34,903 --> 01:24:37,279
I think I've known for a while.

727
01:24:38,698 --> 01:24:40,991
And I think you have too.

728
01:24:43,953 --> 01:24:47,122
- I'll go with you.
- No, kill the snake.

729
01:24:47,832 --> 01:24:50,000
Kill the snake and then it's just him.

730
01:26:10,206 --> 01:26:12,249
I'm ready to die.

731
01:26:53,541 --> 01:26:55,959
The Resurrection Stone.

732
01:27:25,657 --> 01:27:29,034
You've been so brave, sweetheart.

733
01:27:33,122 --> 01:27:34,998
Why are you here?

734
01:27:35,792 --> 01:27:37,584
All of you?

735
01:27:39,963 --> 01:27:42,130
We never left.

736
01:27:51,015 --> 01:27:52,599
Does it--?

737
01:27:53,351 --> 01:27:54,518
Does it hurt?

738
01:27:55,561 --> 01:27:57,271
Dying?

739
01:27:58,189 --> 01:28:00,732
Quicker than falling asleep.

740
01:28:04,654 --> 01:28:06,947
You're nearly there, son.

741
01:28:07,115 --> 01:28:08,323
I'm sorry.

742
01:28:08,491 --> 01:28:11,994
I never wanted any of you to die for me.

743
01:28:13,579 --> 01:28:15,205
And, Remus, your son...

744
01:28:15,373 --> 01:28:19,626
Others will tell him
what his mother and father died for.

745
01:28:19,794 --> 01:28:23,255
One day, he'll understand.

746
01:28:35,018 --> 01:28:36,560
You'll stay with me?

747
01:28:38,104 --> 01:28:40,397
Until the end.

748
01:28:41,065 --> 01:28:43,066
And he won't be able to see you?

749
01:28:43,234 --> 01:28:44,901
No.

750
01:28:46,195 --> 01:28:48,780
We're here, you see.

751
01:29:03,338 --> 01:29:05,380
Stay close to me.

752
01:29:07,091 --> 01:29:09,259
Always.

753
01:29:24,025 --> 01:29:27,778
No sign of him, my Lord.

754
01:29:43,211 --> 01:29:45,962
I thought he would come.

755
01:30:26,838 --> 01:30:30,507
Harry? No! What are you doing here?

756
01:30:30,675 --> 01:30:31,967
Quiet!

757
01:30:42,979 --> 01:30:45,230
Harry Potter.

758
01:30:48,359 --> 01:30:51,027
The Boy Who Lived.

759
01:30:55,283 --> 01:30:57,701
Come to die.

760
01:31:15,928 --> 01:31:17,637
Avada Kedavra!

761
01:32:14,320 --> 01:32:16,696
You can't help. Harry...

762
01:32:18,783 --> 01:32:20,575
...you wonderful boy.

763
01:32:21,077 --> 01:32:24,955
You brave, brave man.

764
01:32:26,958 --> 01:32:28,917
Let us walk.

765
01:32:36,384 --> 01:32:38,635
Professor, what is that?

766
01:32:41,305 --> 01:32:44,349
Something beyond either of our help.

767
01:32:47,228 --> 01:32:50,480
A part of Voldemort sent here to die.

768
01:32:50,856 --> 01:32:52,065
And exactly where are we?

769
01:32:53,317 --> 01:32:57,320
I was going to ask you that.
Where would you say that we are?

770
01:32:57,488 --> 01:32:59,197
Well...

771
01:32:59,365 --> 01:33:01,992
...it looks like King's Cross station.

772
01:33:02,326 --> 01:33:04,661
Only cleaner.

773
01:33:04,829 --> 01:33:07,038
And without all the trains.

774
01:33:07,582 --> 01:33:10,333
King's Cross, is that right?

775
01:33:10,668 --> 01:33:14,254
This is, as they say, your party.

776
01:33:15,423 --> 01:33:18,425
I expect you now realize
that you and Voldemort...

777
01:33:18,593 --> 01:33:21,428
...have been connected by something
other than fate...

778
01:33:21,596 --> 01:33:24,639
...since that night in Godric's Hollow
all those years ago.

779
01:33:24,807 --> 01:33:26,516
So it's true then, sir?

780
01:33:26,684 --> 01:33:29,686
A part of him lives within me, doesn't it?

781
01:33:30,021 --> 01:33:31,021
Did.

782
01:33:31,188 --> 01:33:36,026
It was just destroyed many moments ago
by none other than Voldemort himself.

783
01:33:37,069 --> 01:33:41,781
You were the Horcrux
he never meant to make, Harry.

784
01:33:54,337 --> 01:33:55,879
I have to go back, haven't I?

785
01:33:56,047 --> 01:33:57,922
Oh. That's up to you.

786
01:33:58,090 --> 01:33:59,883
I have a choice?

787
01:34:00,051 --> 01:34:01,843
Oh, yes.

788
01:34:02,011 --> 01:34:04,846
We're in King's Cross, you say?

789
01:34:05,931 --> 01:34:10,727
I think, if you so desired,
you'd be able to board a train.

790
01:34:12,146 --> 01:34:13,480
And where would it take me?

791
01:34:15,066 --> 01:34:16,900
On.

792
01:34:34,877 --> 01:34:36,961
Voldemort has the Elder Wand.

793
01:34:39,590 --> 01:34:40,632
True.

794
01:34:40,800 --> 01:34:43,593
- And the snake's still alive.
- Yes.

795
01:34:43,761 --> 01:34:46,346
And I've nothing to kill it with.

796
01:34:46,889 --> 01:34:51,601
Help will always be given at Hogwarts,
Harry, to those who ask for it.

797
01:34:52,812 --> 01:34:56,523
I've always prized myself
on my ability to turn a phrase.

798
01:34:57,441 --> 01:35:00,610
Words are,
in my not so humble opinion...

799
01:35:00,778 --> 01:35:04,364
...our most inexhaustible
source of magic...

800
01:35:04,532 --> 01:35:08,868
...capable of both inflicting injury
and remedying it.

801
01:35:09,495 --> 01:35:15,417
But I would, in this case,
amend my original statement to this:

802
01:35:18,212 --> 01:35:24,384
Help will always be given at Hogwarts
to those who deserve it.

803
01:35:30,224 --> 01:35:32,976
Do not pity the dead, Harry.

804
01:35:33,436 --> 01:35:35,478
Pity the living.

805
01:35:36,021 --> 01:35:40,900
And, above all,
all those who live without love.

806
01:35:41,861 --> 01:35:47,282
Professor, my mother's Patronus
was a doe, wasn't it?

807
01:35:48,325 --> 01:35:50,952
That's the same as Professor Snape's.

808
01:35:51,829 --> 01:35:53,913
It's curious, don't you think?

809
01:35:54,081 --> 01:35:59,043
Actually, if I think about it,
it doesn't seem curious at all.

810
01:36:00,755 --> 01:36:02,922
I'll be going now, Harry.

811
01:36:03,466 --> 01:36:04,799
Professor?

812
01:36:09,305 --> 01:36:11,473
Is this all real?

813
01:36:12,141 --> 01:36:13,975
Or is it just happening inside my head?

814
01:36:14,143 --> 01:36:17,687
Of course it's happening inside
your head, Harry.

815
01:36:17,855 --> 01:36:21,608
Why should that mean that it's not real?

816
01:36:27,198 --> 01:36:29,824
Professor? What should I do?

817
01:36:34,538 --> 01:36:36,331
Professor?

818
01:36:39,710 --> 01:36:41,002
My Lord?

819
01:36:41,170 --> 01:36:43,296
My Lord, are you hurt? My Lord?

820
01:36:43,464 --> 01:36:45,089
I don't need your help.

821
01:36:45,257 --> 01:36:47,967
No. Come.

822
01:36:56,685 --> 01:36:58,520
The boy.

823
01:36:58,687 --> 01:37:00,605
Is he dead?

824
01:37:14,703 --> 01:37:16,913
Is he alive?

825
01:37:17,081 --> 01:37:19,249
Draco, is he alive?

826
01:37:45,943 --> 01:37:47,443
Dead.

827
01:39:14,615 --> 01:39:17,241
Who is that Hagrid's carrying?

828
01:39:17,910 --> 01:39:19,744
Neville, who is it?

829
01:39:20,412 --> 01:39:22,914
Harry Potter...

830
01:39:24,041 --> 01:39:25,541
...is dead.

831
01:39:25,709 --> 01:39:27,293
No! No!

832
01:39:27,461 --> 01:39:28,836
Silence.

833
01:39:32,508 --> 01:39:33,549
Stupid girl.

834
01:39:35,761 --> 01:39:39,222
Harry Potter is dead.

835
01:39:39,390 --> 01:39:44,519
From this day forth, you put your faith...

836
01:39:44,687 --> 01:39:45,728
...in me.

837
01:39:56,240 --> 01:39:58,574
Harry Potter is dead!

838
01:40:03,414 --> 01:40:06,874
And now is the time to declare yourself.

839
01:40:08,419 --> 01:40:11,170
Come forward and join us.

840
01:40:13,090 --> 01:40:14,799
Or die.

841
01:40:20,347 --> 01:40:21,389
Draco.

842
01:40:27,062 --> 01:40:28,938
Draco.

843
01:40:31,817 --> 01:40:33,735
Draco...

844
01:40:36,572 --> 01:40:38,448
...come.

845
01:40:49,460 --> 01:40:52,879
Ah. Well done, Draco.

846
01:40:53,672 --> 01:40:55,548
Well done.

847
01:41:18,113 --> 01:41:20,865
Well, I must say I'd hoped for better.

848
01:41:25,287 --> 01:41:28,164
And who might you be, young man?

849
01:41:29,458 --> 01:41:31,375
Neville Longbottom.

850
01:41:36,673 --> 01:41:40,384
Well, Neville, I'm sure we can
find a place for you in our ranks.

851
01:41:40,552 --> 01:41:42,804
I'd like to say something.

852
01:41:48,936 --> 01:41:54,690
Well, Neville, I'm sure we'd all be fascinated
to hear what you have to say.

853
01:41:57,694 --> 01:42:00,196
- It doesn't matter Harry's gone.
- Stand down, Neville.

854
01:42:00,364 --> 01:42:02,990
People die every day.

855
01:42:04,660 --> 01:42:08,704
Friends, family.

856
01:42:10,749 --> 01:42:12,333
Yeah.

857
01:42:13,752 --> 01:42:15,920
We lost Harry tonight.

858
01:42:17,464 --> 01:42:21,968
But he's still with us, in here.

859
01:42:22,970 --> 01:42:24,887
So's Fred...

860
01:42:25,889 --> 01:42:27,682
...and Remus.

861
01:42:28,767 --> 01:42:30,101
Tonks.

862
01:42:31,436 --> 01:42:33,354
All of them.

863
01:42:34,523 --> 01:42:36,774
They didn't die in vain.

864
01:42:41,905 --> 01:42:42,989
But you will.

865
01:42:43,157 --> 01:42:45,533
- Because you're wrong.
- Ha-ha-ha.

866
01:42:45,701 --> 01:42:48,494
Harry's heart did beat for us.
For all of us. This is not over!

867
01:42:54,585 --> 01:42:56,419
Confringo!

868
01:43:04,720 --> 01:43:06,262
No! No, come back!

869
01:43:06,430 --> 01:43:10,391
Lucius! Come back! Come back and fight!

870
01:43:10,559 --> 01:43:12,602
Come back!

871
01:43:17,649 --> 01:43:20,818
I'll lure him into the castle.
We have to kill the snake.

872
01:43:20,986 --> 01:43:22,904
- You'll need this.
- Neville!

873
01:46:16,453 --> 01:46:18,954
Not my daughter, you bitch.

874
01:46:52,447 --> 01:46:53,781
You were right...

875
01:46:55,534 --> 01:46:57,868
...when you told Snape
that wand was failing you.

876
01:46:58,036 --> 01:46:59,703
It will always fail you.

877
01:47:00,997 --> 01:47:02,581
I killed Snape.

878
01:47:02,749 --> 01:47:04,875
But what if the wand
never belonged to Snape?

879
01:47:05,043 --> 01:47:07,920
What if its allegiance was always
to someone else?

880
01:47:08,088 --> 01:47:11,298
Come on, Tom.
Let's finish this the way we started it.

881
01:47:11,758 --> 01:47:12,800
Together.

882
01:50:47,265 --> 01:50:49,266
- Ha, ha.
- I always figured he would be a big fellow.

883
01:50:49,434 --> 01:50:53,771
I couldn't find my wand.
I haven't lost my wand in my entire life.

884
01:50:53,938 --> 01:50:55,939
It was lost in the folds of my gowns.

885
01:50:56,107 --> 01:50:58,901
I managed to find it
and I dispatched a few of them...

886
01:50:59,069 --> 01:51:00,319
Harry.

887
01:52:00,797 --> 01:52:04,466
Why didn't it work for him,
the Elder Wand?

888
01:52:05,468 --> 01:52:07,386
It answered to somebody else.

889
01:52:08,346 --> 01:52:11,140
When he killed Snape,
he thought the wand would become his.

890
01:52:11,307 --> 01:52:15,477
But the thing is,
the wand never belonged to Snape.

891
01:52:15,645 --> 01:52:20,149
It was Draco who disarmed Dumbledore
that night in the astronomy tower.

892
01:52:20,316 --> 01:52:24,319
From that moment on,
the wand answered to him.

893
01:52:25,196 --> 01:52:27,030
Until...

894
01:52:27,198 --> 01:52:31,785
...the other night
when I disarmed Draco at Malfoy Manor.

895
01:52:31,953 --> 01:52:34,079
So that means...

896
01:52:35,623 --> 01:52:37,374
It's mine.

897
01:52:39,335 --> 01:52:40,835
What should we do with it?

898
01:52:41,880 --> 01:52:43,005
We?

899
01:52:43,381 --> 01:52:47,634
I'm just saying, that's the Elder Wand,
the most powerful wand in the world.

900
01:52:47,802 --> 01:52:51,722
With that, we'd be invincible.

901
01:55:14,866 --> 01:55:16,533
Together.

902
01:55:33,843 --> 01:55:36,011
Look after each other.

903
01:55:55,198 --> 01:55:56,990
- Bag?
- Yeah.

904
01:55:57,158 --> 01:55:58,200
Jumper?

905
01:55:59,869 --> 01:56:01,870
I'll miss you.

906
01:56:02,997 --> 01:56:04,706
Here they come.

907
01:56:19,889 --> 01:56:24,101
Dad, what if I am put in Slytherin?

908
01:56:26,396 --> 01:56:28,939
Albus Severus Potter...

909
01:56:30,233 --> 01:56:33,944
...you were named after two headmasters
of Hogwarts.

910
01:56:34,112 --> 01:56:35,737
One of them was a Slytherin...

911
01:56:35,905 --> 01:56:39,116
...and he was the bravest man
I've ever known.

912
01:56:40,994 --> 01:56:42,244
But just say that I am.

913
01:56:42,412 --> 01:56:48,041
Then Slytherin House will have gained
a wonderful young wizard.

914
01:56:48,209 --> 01:56:53,922
But, listen, if it really means that much
to you, you can choose Gryffindor.

915
01:56:54,090 --> 01:56:57,009
The Sorting Hat
takes your choice into account.

916
01:56:57,593 --> 01:56:59,636
- Really?
- Really.

917
01:57:01,014 --> 01:57:03,682
- Bye, Mum.
- All aboard.

918
01:57:03,850 --> 01:57:04,891
Ready?

919
01:57:05,059 --> 01:57:06,601
Ready.

920
01:57:18,865 --> 01:57:20,490
Come on, Jay, get a move on.

921
01:57:20,658 --> 01:57:22,117
Come on.