WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Should we give them some more space
between the beds?
Well, we could give them...
Not much.
I'm determined to defend the library
as a recreation room.
Where are we to sit?
We can screen off the small library.
Is that all? I suppose...
Or we could leave you the boudoir.
I wanted to put the intermediaries
in there, but we don't have to.
How kind.
Why will we only have officers?
Surely all wounded men need
to convalesce.
The hospital is for officers.
The whole idea is to have
a complimentary convalescent home.
Of course. But I don't know if we
can make that an absolute rule.
If the world were logical, I would
rather agree with you.
Which comes as no surprise.
You would not, I imagine.
You imagine right.
What these men will need is rest
and relaxation.
Will that be achieved by mixing ranks
and putting everyone on edge?
Granny!
Different ranks can relax together.
It has been known.
Well, don't look at me.
I'm very good at mixing.
We always danced the first waltz
at the Servants' Ball, didn't we,
Carson?
It was an honour, my lady.
It's a lot to ask when people
aren't at their best.
I'm searching for Lady Mary, Carson.
Will you tell her I'm in the library?
Don't loiter, Edith.
There's plenty to be done.
Of course, but I'm not quite sure...
Sybil I wanted to have a quick word.
I'm going down to the village this
afternoon if anyone wants anything.
Some stamps would be kind.
I'll get you the money.
I'd like to thank you all
for your work this morning.
It's so strange to see the rooms
converted into dormitories. But good.
It was wrong for our life to chug
along as if the war were only
happening to other people.
How will it be, though? Are we all
working for Mrs Crawley, now?
We are not.
I'm sure the chain of command will
be sorted out soon.
Or there'll be blood on the stairs.
Thank you, Miss O'Brien.
But what do you think it meant?
Really, Granny. Lavinia Swire knows
Richard Carlisle. So what?
One knows lots of people in London.
I don't know many people who'd
threaten me behind the laurels.
Aunt Rosamund said herself
she didn't know what to make of it.
I still think it's a peculiar way
for a gentleman to speak to a lady.
I'm not sure it matters much to me.
Well I'm going up to London to stay
with Rosamund for a day or two.
I think we'll have Lavinia for tea.
You sound as if
you're going to gobble her up.
If only we could.
But where are they going to eat?
I understand from Mrs Crawley that
they'll share the dining room with
the officers who are almost well.
So, am I running a canteen now?
William says he's got time
off between the end of his training
and going overseas.
He'll be with his father, surely?
He's going home first, but wants
to come here for his last night.
You wouldn't mind that,
would you, Mr Carson? Certainly not.
I'd be glad to wish him well
on his way.
Oh, for you, Mr Branson.
Why do you think he's coming here?
To see us all and say goodbye.
What's wrong with that?
But suppose it's something more.
Suppose he's got plans.
Well, you have to deal with that
when it happens
and mind you deal fair.
Now go and grate that suet
before I grow old and die.
Who will be in charge?
Cousin Isobel thinks it'll be her.
All I know is that she'll drive us
mad before the end.
I'm going up to change.
I just want to finish this.
Aren't you going to the hospital?
Not yet.
I'm on a night shift.
I'll walk down after dinner.
And please don't start lecturing me.
I won't.
The truth is I envy you.
Do you ever miss helping out
on the Drakes' farm?
That's a funny question.
Why?
No reason.
It's just you seemed to have
such a purpose there.
It suited you.
It did suit me.
I enjoyed it,
but now I feel like a spare part.
Trust me.
You have a talent
that none of the rest of us have.
Just find out what it is and use it.
It's doing nothing that's the enemy.
The truth is, my lady, Mrs Crawley
has forgotten this is your house
and we need a friend in charge of
the day-to-day management,
because if Mrs Crawley gets one of
her toadies in to run things,
she'll have her nose in every pie
before you can say Jack Robinson.
But who?
What about Thomas, my lady?
He's hospital trained and he's always
had a soft spot for Downton.
Thomas, the footman?
Managing Downton Abbey?
But he's not a footman, now, is he?
He's a corporal, with real battle
experience as a medic.
Could Dr Clarkson spare him?
Well...
I suppose he'll have to spare
somebody.
Are you all right?
You seem a bit preoccupied.
I had a...
No, never mind.
What?
It was this afternoon,
in the village.
I thought I saw Mr Bates.
Bates?
Isn't he in London?
I might have been wrong.
I walked over to where he was
standing. There was no sign of him.
Do you know his address in London?
As long as he's still there. Why?
I'll telephone Sir Richard
and ask him to look into it.
But what would he know?
He works in newspapers.
A world of spies, tip-offs
and private investigators.
I promise you, he can find out
whatever he likes.
All right, then.
If you think he can help.
Good.
I'll ring him tonight.
Not bad.
Try to fit in a bit of practice.
We've plenty of time
to get it right, before there's
anyone to see me who matters.
I only know Sir Richard
because he is or was
a friend of my father's
and of my uncle, Jonathan Swire.
The Liberal minister?
That's it.
But I'm afraid they've fallen out.
Oh.
This room is so pretty.
Has the house always been
the Painswicks' London home?
There's no 'always'
about the Painswicks, my dear.
They were invented from scratch
by my son-in-law's grandfather.
We bought the house
when we were married.
You make Mr Painswick sound rather
a rough diamond, Lady Grantham.
Marmaduke wasn't a rough diamond,
was he, Mama?
No. He was just cut and polished
comparatively recently.
Carson's told Papa
you've been called up.
There's no need to look so serious.
You'd think me rather heartless
if I didn't.
I'm not going to fight.
You'll have to.
I will not.
I'm going to be a conscientious
objector. They'll put you in prison.
I'd rather prison
than the Dardanelles.
When will you tell them?
In my own good time.
I don't understand.
I'll go to the medical.
I'll report for duty.
When I'm on parade, I'll march out
front and I'll shout it,
loud and clear.
If that doesn't make the newspapers,
then I'm a monkey's uncle.
But you'll have a record
for the rest of your life.
At least I'll have a life.
I know the popular fantasy is
that we can feed six strong men...
from a single seed cake,
but you and I know better.
Have we got the flour for any more?
Go and check now.
Cheer up.
It's not as bad as that.
What's the matter, Mr Lang?
Tell me. I won't bite.
I sometimes feel I'm the only one
who knows what's going on over there.
You all wander round ironing clothes
and cleaning boots and choosing
what's for dinner,
while over the Channel,
men are killed
and maimed
and blown to pieces.
We know more than you think.
The war hasn't left us alone.
It hasn't left me alone,
however it may look.
Have you any idea...
how scared they are?
How scared they all are?
I lost my nephew.
My sister's boy.
He was shot.
For cowardice.
That's what they said.
But I knew him and he'd never
have done such a thing...
if he hadn't have been
half out of his mind with fear.
Don't blame him.
It was him,
but it could have been me.
It could have been any of us.
Suppose I don't want to come back?
To be in charge?
Telling Mr Carson what to do?
Why? What's in it for you?
All right. It's to stop Mrs Crawley
bossing her ladyship about.
She behaves as if she owns the place.
You've changed your tune.
When I were last here,
you'd have given money to see
her ladyship eat dirt.
Well, like you say,
I've changed my tune. People do.
Not without a reason.
I've got my reasons.
You've also got her ladyship
wrapped round your little finger.
Maybe. That's my business.
But I'll not hurt her and I'll not
let anyone else hurt her, neither.
That's all I've got to say.
You're a queer one and no mistake.
So will you come if I can fix it?
Why not?
I like the idea of giving orders
to old Carson.
I go away for five minutes
and everything's settled.
Nothing's settled.
For a start,
which rooms will we live in?
The small library and the boudoir.
If Cousin Isobel can find somewhere
else for the intermediaries.
There's always the boot room.
I'm sure you'll have use of that.
And where are we supposed to eat?
You can share the dining room
with those officers...
No.
We all have to make sacrifices.
No!
Then we'll have tables set up
in the great hall for the mobile
officers and the nurses.
And, Lady Grantham, I know you'll be
happy about one decision.
Lady Grantham asked that the house
management might be put into
the hands of Corporal Barrow.
Your former footman, Thomas.
Thomas? In charge of Downton?
No, that's what I thought at first,
but he isn't a footman now,
he's a soldier.
He's worked in medicine.
Someone has to run the place who's
had medical training. But I feel...
The men won't accept the authority
of a corporal. I've thought of that.
I told my Commanding Officer that
Lady Grantham had asked for
Corporal Barrow.
He's prepared to have him raised
to the rank of Acting Sergeant.
But can you spare him?
We can.
I've gone to some trouble to do so.
Sergeant Barrow will manage
the daily running of Downton
and I shall be in overall charge.
Aren't we missing a tier? There
should be someone here, permanently,
under you but over Thomas.
That's correct and I will make
a decision before long.
Until then,
I do assure you,
Corporal Barrow is very efficient.
I say good.
If someone is to manage things,
let it be our creature.
Why? Are you planning to divide
his loyalties?
I wouldn't say I was planning it.
William has asked to stay here,
my lord. Just for a night.
On his way to active duty in France.
Good. I should like to see him.
I don't suppose there's any way
we can keep him from harm?
Him being an only child and all.
We'd hate for anything to happen.
Thank you, Lang. I can do the rest.
Very sorry, my lord.
To get back to the notion of Thomas
as the manager of Downton.
He won't be a manager in that sense.
But her ladyship fixed it all with
Clarkson and she was so pleased
I didn't know what to say.
'I cannot have him working here
because he is a thief'?
You know she's ignorant of
Thomas's crimes.
We agreed at the time
that would be best.
And anyway...
is it honourable in us to hold
Thomas's sins against him
when he has been wounded
in the service of the King?
And who is to be in charge
over Thomas?
You mean under Dr Clarkson?
Well, we asked today,
but he hasn't decided.
So we just make it up
as we go along?
Unless you've got a better idea.
Are you still here, Mr Branson?
Stay and have something to eat.
Mr Branson's been telling us the
news from Russia. What news is that?
Kerensky's been made Prime Minister,
but he won't go far enough for me.
Lenin denounces the bourgeoisie
along with the Tsar.
He wants a people's revolution and
that's what I'm waiting for.
It won't be long, now.
And what's happened to the Tsar?
Imprisoned. In the Alexander Palace.
With all his family.
What a dreadful thing.
They won't hurt them. Why would they?
To make an example?
Give them some credit.
This is a new dawn,
a new age of government.
No-one wants to start it with the
murder of a bunch of young girls.
You don't know that.
Nobody knows who'll get killed
when these things start.
Look at her nephew.
Shot for cowardice.
Who'd have guessed that when he was
saying hello to the neighbours
or kissing his mother good night?
Can you look at the crumble?
I think it should come out, but it's
five minutes earlier than you said.
I'm sorry. I never thought.
Then you should think, Mr Lang.
You're not the only member of
the walking wounded in this house.
Why are you coming in this way?
I'm the manager here now, Mr Carson.
Or had you forgotten?
No. I had not forgotten.
And will you be moving into
your old room?
Or should we prepare
a guest bedroom?
I'll sleep in my old room, thanks.
So...
Are we ready for the big invasion?
Cos they'll be here at teatime.
We'll have to be ready,
won't we, Thomas?
We will, Mr Carson.
And it's Sergeant Barrow, now.
'Acting Sergeant', I believe.
How many are there altogether?
36.
36. Right.
Quick as you can, gentlemen.
Driver, when you've finished
unloading here, go straight back.
This way please, gentlemen.
Mustard gas...
Don't worry.
We'll get you seen to quickly.
Major Bryant, you're in the Armada
bedroom. Do you mind the stairs?
It depends what I find at the top.
He's handsome.
Handsome and off-limits.
It'll be nice to have the house
full of men. Full of officers.
Officers aren't men.
Not where we're concerned.
Oh, speak for yourself.
I speak for you, too, if you know
what's good for you.
I'm very sorry, but I...
Matthew! What in the world
are you doing here?
We start our tour of Yorkshire and
Lancashire tomorrow.
General Strutt knew you lived up
here, so he's given me
a few hours off.
What a lovely... lovely surprise.
Mrs Crawley, how can we separate
the hospital's linen from our own?
You go. We'll talk later.
As soon as I've done this,
I'll take your orders for books.
I hadn't cast you
as Florence Nightingale.
We can't leave all the moral
high ground to Sybil.
She might get lonely there.
How are you? I know I mustn't ask
you what you're doing.
You can ask what I'm doing in
Downton.
We've finished in the Midlands.
Tomorrow, we start on the camps
in the northern counties.
Will we see something of you?
My general ought to come here.
It's exactly the sort of thing people
like to read about. Sybil, come.
Edith can do that.
Dear Mother.
She does love a bit of authority.
I suppose she's driving
Cousin Cora mad.
No names. No pack drill.
Breathe in... and out.
I'm surprised they didn't get
to you before now.
Some people have all the luck, sir.
You can get dressed.
Shall I report for duty in Richmond?
You'll be told what to do.
But I must supervise
the medical staff. Overseen by me.
Carson, I'm relying on you to make
sure that that is so.
What is going on?
I was arranging the household
duties,
where they overlap with the duties
of the nursing staff.
Shall we continue this upstairs?
Well, I've made up some charts...
Of course.
Did you say you were the manager
or the referee?
You see what we're up against.
Don't worry. We'll find a solution.
You take over every room, you bark
at me like a sergeant major and you
give orders to my servants.
Cora, I'm sure - I'm sorry.
Are you in the middle of something?
We're discussing the arrangements.
Oh, good.
We've had a letter from
Evelyn Napier. He's in a hospital
in Middlesbrough.
He's heard that we're
a convalescent home now
and wonders if he can come here
once he's released.
Of course he can come here.
Just a minute.
The Middlesbrough General will have
their own arrangements for where
their patients convalesce.
I'm afraid Mrs Crawley is right.
Downton must function as part of
the official system or it cannot
function at all.
Now I think perhaps I should make
one thing clear.
Downton is our house and our home
and we will welcome in it any
friends or relations we choose.
If you do not care
to accept that condition,
then I suggest you give orders for
the nurses and patients and beds
to be packed up
and shipped out, at once.
Thank you, Lord Grantham,
for making your position so clear.
Oh, just one more thing. The dog.
What should we do to stop Isis
getting into the patients' rooms?
I can answer that.
Absolutely nothing.
Ah.
Anna, there you are. Ethel, could
you leave us for a moment?
That was Sir Richard
on the telephone.
It might have been Bates
you saw in the village.
Really?
He's working up here at a pub.
The Red Lion in Kirby Moorside.
That's odd.
Mr Bates in a pub?
The question is what'll you do with
the information now you've got it?
Could you just take this into
the hall for me? Yes, of course.
Are you waiting for Papa?
Do you want me to go and find him?
They turned me down.
The army.
Why?
Apparently, I have a heart murmur.
Or... to be more precise...
'A mitral valve prolapse is causing
a pansystolic murmur.'
I don't know what to say.
Is it dangerous?
Only if you're planning to humiliate
the British Army.
I suppose you're glad.
You're not going to be killed
or go to prison. Of course I'm glad.
Don't count your chickens.
If I don't get them one way,
I'll get them another.
Why do you have to be so angry
all the time?
I know we weren't exactly
at our best in Ireland.
Not at your best?
I lost a cousin,
in the Easter Rising, last year.
You never said.
Well, I'm saying it now.
He was walking down
North King Street, one day,
and an English soldier saw him
and shot him dead.
When they asked why he was killed,
the officer said because he was
'probably' a rebel.
So don't say you were
not at your best.
Sorry to keep you waiting, but we're
going to have to step on it.
I'm not sure about Marryat.
Not to worry. I know we've got
lots of GA Henty.
And I haven't forgotten about
your tobacco - just as soon as
I can get into the village.
I think a bit of it
might have come loose.
Is that better?
Much.
But I may need some more tucking
very soon.
Well, no-one tucks better than I do.
Ethel.
Go back inside, please.
There are still more bedrooms
to be done.
'Rosamund's going to find out.'
She knows some of those feeble-minded
idiots on the Liberal front bench.
Poor Lavinia. I feel sorry for her.
She's an obstacle to your happiness,
dear, and must be removed.
When it's done,
you can feel as sorry as you wish.
But even if Matthew does break it
off with her,
why should he propose to me again?
With your permission, dear, I will
take my fences one at a time.
Any plans for your afternoon off?
Major Bryant wants me to go to
the pictures in York with him,
when he's allowed out.
But you'll say that's stupid.
Not stupid. Insane.
Oh, he really likes me, though.
He says he wants
to get to know me better.
Has he told you how he's planning
to achieve it?
Spoilsport.
What are you up to?
Just practising with these for
Lady Mary. I promised her I would.
That's one and eight, altogether.
Might I have a glass of cider?
Thank you.
I don't know if I've dreaded
this moment or longed for it.
Well, either way, it's happened.
I'm glad I'm in time
for tomorrow's state visit.
I gather Lavinia will be there.
We must seize the opportunity
to challenge her.
I don't really see on what basis.
She stole secrets from her uncle,
Jonathan Swire, and gave them to
Carlisle to publish. Swire told me.
The papers showed that half
the Cabinet were trying to get rich
by buying shares before a government
contract was announced.
Would you rather we were kept
in ignorance? It wasn't Lavinia's
business to make it public.
Without her, the Marconi scandal
would never have happened.
The politicians broke the law.
Lavinia did nothing wrong.
She drags the Chancellor of
the Exchequer's honour through
the mud and you say it's nothing?
It was only Lloyd George.
But why did she betray her uncle
to Sir Richard in the first place?
Because... they were lovers.
Exactly.
And now it is down to you to save
Matthew from the clutches of
a scheming harlot.
Really, Rosamund.
There's no need to be so gleeful.
You sound like Robespierre, lopping
off the head of Marie Antoinette.
It was me.
I knew you used to go into
the village on a Wednesday.
I so longed for a glimpse of you.
But why are you up here, at all?
And why didn't you tell me? Because
I want to get things settled first.
You see, I've discovered that Vera
has been unfaithful to me.
I've got proof.
We can't criticise her for that.
No, but it means I can divorce her.
I've had to leave the house to prove
that it has broken the marriage.
So I came up here to be nearer you.
But what if she fights it?
She can't.
For her to divorce me, she needs
something beyond adultery.
Cruelty or suchlike.
For a husband, adultery is enough.
That's not very fair to women.
I don't care about fairness,
I care about you.
The point is, I can get rid of her.
If she goes quietly, I will give her
money and plenty of it.
If not, she leaves empty-handed.
And when will this be? I need to get
her to accept it, first.
She's made threats
about selling stuff to the papers.
What stuff?
Don't worry.
They won't offer what I will.
You've changed your hair.
I was trying out Lady Mary's
new curling iron.
What do you think?
I think I would love you, however,
whatever, whenever.
We don't have to wait, you know.
If you want me to throw up
everything and come with you,
I will.
Gladly.
I can't marry you yet, not legally,
and I won't break the law.
It's not against the law
to take a mistress, Mr Bates.
I know you, Anna Smith,
and I love you and that is not
the right path for you.
It won't be long, now.
So, you're not going to war, then?
Apparently not.
Is it true about Mr Crawley bringing
a famous general here?
Captain Crawley.
But yes, why?
No reason.
If they arrive at five, we'll walk
him round the wards, then show him
the recovering men at play.
After that, a fairly grand dinner.
I'll tell them to bring mess kit.
That is my challenge, my lord.
How to make the dinner sufficiently
grand with no footmen in the house.
Plenty of people give dinners
without footmen.
Not people who entertain Sir Herbert
Strutt, hero of the Somme.
I'm sure he'll have seen worse
things at the front than a dinner
with no footmen.
Carson only wants to show the general
proper respect.
We will not criticise him for that.
Indeed we will not.
I think Lord Grantham's plan is a
good one, with or without a footman.
Matthew writes Miss Swire is coming
down from London for it.
Really?
He never said so to me.
Does he need your permission?
I think I should go round with him.
You and Lady Grantham will both
come with us.
But won't he want to talk about
the treatments?
The treatments... and the house.
Miss?
It's Captain Smiley, isn't it?
We haven't met yet,
but I'm Edith Crawley
and tomorrow I can show you
where everything is.
It's just that I'd like to write
a letter to my parents.
Of course. There's paper and
envelopes in the library.
No. You see, I've not written before.
I didn't want to worry my mother
with the different handwriting.
I'm left-handed. How's that for luck?
I'm surprised your school didn't
force you to use the right.
My mother wouldn't let them,
but now I wish they had.
I've asked the others and they say
you're the one to help me.
Of course I will.
I'd be happy to.
That's what they said.
If you can just...
find a way to tell her.
We'll both find a way.
Together. I promise.
Mr Carson, might I have a word?
I'm busy with this dinner for
tomorrow night.
Well, that's just it. I don't expect
you'll be using Mr Lang,
not after last time.
I will not.
So I wondered if I might be any help.
I've waited at table before.
Do you mean it?
I know I've no right
to ask it of a chauffeur.
We have to keep up the honour of
Downton, don't we?
I'm very grateful, Mr Branson. I'll
not hide it. Very grateful, indeed.
You know where to find a livery?
I do.
And I gather you won't be
leaving us, after all.
Who knows what the future will bring?
Aaa-aaargh!
Aaaargh!
Mrs Hughes? What is it?
Who is that shouting?
What's going on?
It's Mr Lang.
What in heaven's name is happening?
No! No, I can't do it!
Mr Lang?
I can't do it!
Wake up. You're having a bad dream.
You're having a dream.
It's the soldiers, Mr Carson,
soldiers, but I can't.
I can't go back,
no matter what they...
No-one is asking you to go back,
Mr Lang.
Just to put a sock in it.
Don't worry. You've had a bad dream.
That's all.
Is it a dream?
Thank God.
Oh, thank God.
Thank God. You're all right.
Let's get you back into bed.
You're all right.
I'm sorry.
It's all right, Mr Lang.
You're all right.
Is it any wonder,
when he's been to hell and back?
Up.
My cousin, Lord Grantham.
Very kind of you, Lord Grantham.
Welcome.
Lady Grantham.
And this is Major Clarkson
who runs our hospital here.
And I am Captain Crawley's mother
and will accompany you on your tour
and explain the different levels of
care we practise here.
Lady Grantham and Mrs Crawley will
both accompany us,
as we go round, sir.
Makes a nice change
from the craggy-faced warriors
I'm usually surrounded by.
I'd like to think that were true.
Please, come this way.
There's a large recreational room.
I don't believe...
Poor Mother. How she longs to hold
all the reins.
Crawley!
I should go, if only to keep
our respective mothers apart.
I'm afraid Mrs Crawley is none too
pleased to play second fiddle, sir.
Well, I hope she doesn't spoil
things.
Well, that's just what I've been
meaning to talk to you about, sir.
I'm trying to run a tight ship...
What's the matter with your aunt?
We should follow them in or Mama
will say we're unsupportive.
Tell me what it is, please.
All right.
I know he's going to propose.
Well, then you're going to accept.
Did you get that picture taken?
I did, yeah - Then fetch it.
If you think I'm going to stand by
and watch that boy's dreams
stamped in the dust, you've got
another think coming.
You can take back your promise
when the war's over and not before.
But it's a lie.
Don't make him give up
when he's off to face the guns.
You'd never forgive yourself
if owt happened.
Do you remember when Aunt Rosamund
found you and Richard Carlisle
together in the garden?
I knew I'd hear more about that.
She thought he was threatening you
and now she's decided
that you were behind
the Marconi share scandal in 1912.
The Chancellor and other ministers
were involved, including your uncle.
I remember the Marconi Scandal.
No. Let's forget it. It's absurd.
But Lady Rosamund is right.
I did steal the evidence
for Sir Richard to print.
I did start the scandal.
The trouble is Aunt Rosamund can't
understand
why you would do such a thing,
unless you and Sir Richard were...
- Were lovers.
- Mary, you must come.
The ground floor rooms are for those
men who need the most care, sir.
Yes, of course.
General Strutt, sir.
Oh, right, yes.
Tell me about this officer.
Who is that man?
I hope he's not complaining.
Oh, no. That's Captain Smiley.
He hasn't an unkind bone
in his body.
How do you know?
Matthew, listen to this.
Everything all right, sir?
What on earth is that about?
Oh, don't worry.
Major Holmes can be a little
waspish, but he wouldn't want
to get us into trouble.
How do you know so much
about a pack of strangers?
They're not strangers to me.
This is all very impressive,
Lady Grantham.
The nurses and your own staff are
to be congratulated.
I believe they are.
I wouldn't say I was scared.
I'm nervous, of course I am.
But not scared.
I think I'm ready.
Don't mind me.
Only I'm thinking of what
your dear mother would say.
Well, I wish she was here
to see me off.
Oh, she'd be so proud.
Why, when we waved off our Archie,
I remember...
What do you remember, Mrs Patmore?
I'll tell you.
You remember a fine young man,
who enlisted before he had to,
and who gave his life
for his country,
because he'd be alive and well today,
if he hadn't chosen to go to war.
She's right.
Happen she is.
Come on, Daisy.
Back to the grindstone.
What is it?
I just want a word with Daisy.
I'm needed in the kitchen.
There's plenty of time later on.
Let's see what my aim is
like.
And again.
You must be enjoying your respite
from the front.
Actually, I'm struggling a bit.
I've just lost my soldier servant and
I haven't managed to replace him yet.
So, when will you tell Matthew?
Dinner is served, my lady.
Don't waste the opportunity.
Why must she be so savage?
It's my broken heart.
It was her advice that wrecked it in
the first place. Classic Rosamund.
She's never more righteous than
when she's in the wrong. Come on.
Everything all right, Mr Branson?
I think so, Mrs Hughes.
Where's Mr Branson?
He's just taken up the soup. Why?
Read that.
'They'll have arrested me by now,
but I'm not sorry.'
'The bastard had it coming to him.'
Oh!
What in God's name?
Read this.
Where is he now?
Oh, my God.
Thinking of renovating
the entire stable...
I'm sorry to hear about
your servant.
Pneumonia not a bullet.
No!
Yes.
I don't envy you.
A decent servant can change
your war.
Get downstairs now!
All right, all right!
There's no need to be so rough.
There's every need to stop a murder!
Murder? What do you mean, 'murder'?
You were going to assassinate
the general! Kill the general?
I was not.
Eurgh! I was going to throw that lot
all over him.
What is it? Oil and ink and a bit of
a cowpat, all mixed with sour milk.
He'd have needed a bath right enough,
but not a coffin.
I thought you'd taken the soup up,
but you left it in the pantry.
We'll use this. It's not been heated,
but the hell with that!
We'll decide what happens to you
later!
Never mind later, what about now?
How do we keep this dinner going?
I'll serve, Mr Carson. I don't mind.
And who knows when I'll have
the chance again.
What was going on with the soup?
It came. It went.
Nothing to worry about, my lord.
Branson was taken ill, so William
volunteered to be footman,
one last time.
You don't mind, do you? Oh, not
a bit. It's very kind of him.
Our footman, William, is leaving us
tomorrow to join his regiment.
That's why he's not in livery.
You're are a credit to this house
and this country.
There is no livery so becoming
as a uniform.
Sir.
Lady Rosamund, Mary, all of you,
have been so kind to Lavinia.
Well, naturally we're all curious
to know more of Miss Swire,
if she is to reign over Downton
as queen.
Dear me. I hope you haven't
unearthed anything too fearful.
You must ask Mary.
One thing I am still not
quite clear about.
Who precisely is in charge of
Downton when you're not here?
I've given it some thought, sir,
and it seems to be only fair
that Mrs Crawley
and Lady Grantham should share
that responsibility.
Capital. Well said.
The fact is I have been more than
gratified by my visit here today
and I thank Captain Crawley
for arranging it.
Hear, hear.
You are all to be praised for your
response to our national crisis,
but I've been talking
and I've been listening.
I feel there is one among you
whose generosity is in danger of
going unremarked.
It seems the daily cares and needs
of the patients are being dealt
with, quietly and efficiently,
by Lady Edith.
Or that's what the officers tell me.
So, let us raise our glasses
and drink her health.
- Edith. Darling.
- Lady Edith.
Edith, dear.
We were never lovers, not ever.
You don't have to explain anything.
Not to me.
But I want to.
You see...
My father owed Sir Richard Carlisle
a lot of money.
Enough to bankrupt him.
And Sir Richard offered
to waive the debt,
if you gave him the evidence
of the ministers' guilt?
Papa was terrified
and I knew I could get into my
uncle's office and find the proof.
What is it?
He threatened to tell you all about
it and now I've told you anyway.
My uncle was guilty.
They all were.
Sir Richard didn't make it up.
I believe you.
But that's not why I did it.
It was entirely to save Papa
from ruin.
I'll just go in and check
that everything is ready.
Have you got that picture for me?
I might have.
Because...
You know what I'm going to ask you,
so... will you?
William, you're not sure.
You can't be sure.
I am sure.
And so is she, aren't you, Daisy?
Isn't this just what you told me
you hoped would happen?
It's like a fairy story.
Is she right, Daisy? Are...
Are we engaged?
Because if we are,
I know I can tackle
whatever may come.
Go on, then.
William?
Do you want to go up top?
The general is leaving and Mr Carson
likes a full complement.
No, Daisy. Not you.
The war has not changed everything.
The general is just about to leave.
I'm afraid he doesn't have time
to come in here.
I hope it's all been a success.
Cousin Violet said you had something
to say to me about Lavinia.
What is it?
I haven't the slightest idea.
Oh.
What a relief. She was hinting you
had uncovered some horrid stain.
The only evidence I've uncovered is
that she's a charming person.
What a testimonial.
The truth is we're very much alike,
so naturally I think she's perfect.
We all do.
Don't we, Aunt Rosamund?
Quite perfect.
Is there any chance you might take
our footman William,
for your servant?
I can pull some strings, get him
transferred to your lot.
If you'd like me to, of course, but
I can't promise to keep him safe.
I know, but he'd have someone
looking out for him.
Oh, my God.
Lang, are you all right, old chap?
Come, come, man.
Things can't be as bad as all that.
Carson?
Mr Lang, what's happened?
Sir...
The general and all these
officers...
I don't have to go back with them,
do I? Because... I can't, sir. No.
The general is looking for you,
my lord. Excuse me.
It's been a great pleasure.
If I don't see you again
before I have to go back, be safe.
You, too.
Come inside.
Up!
Here. We've earned it.
Ah...
So, what will you do with him?
Branson or Lang?
Not Mr Lang.
He isn't well,
but he's not a bad man.
No, not at all, but he doesn't
belong at Downton.
I meant, Mr Branson.
Hm, it's a delicate business,
Mrs Hughes.
Would we really be right to tell
the police and cause a furore
and bring a riot down on our heads?
And all because he wanted to pour
a pot of slop over a man's head.
From your phrasing, I gather
the answer you want from me is no.
Would it help, Mrs Hughes?
That's all I'm asking.
Would it help?
Where's Mr Branson? Mr Carson sent
him back to his cottage to stew in
his own juice.
Will we see you in the morning,
William, to wish you luck?
Oh, yes.
But I've got something I'd like
to say now, if you don't mind.
Don't. Not yet.
They must know sooner or later.
Daisy and I...
are going to be married.
You never are! When?
After the war.
I'm not sure I can wait that long.
I see what I had planned to say is
already superfluous, Mr Lang.
You got there before me.
I've let you down, Mr Carson,
for that, I'm sorry.
We let you down.
You weren't suited for work
and I should have spotted that.
You'll have two months' wages and
please tell us how you get on.
And, when you're ready for work
again,
you may rely on
a good report from me.
That's kind.
Thank you.
It was nice of William to serve
tonight. He didn't have to.
I'm going to arrange for him
to be Matthew's servant.
With any luck,
it'll keep him out of trouble.
Matthew and Mary looked so natural
together. Did you notice?
Talking and laughing.
But I suppose Lavinia is a nice girl.
We've dreamed a dream, my dear,
but now it's over.
The world was in a dream
before the war,
but now it's woken up
and said goodbye to it.
And so must we.
I'll stay until you want
to run away with me.
Am I to see if Sir Richard Carlisle
has a brother?
One who's even richer than he is?
What's the matter with you?
I'm on your side.
Then be on my side.
If I am not appreciated here,
I will seek some other place
where I will make a difference.
Good.
I am a woman, Mary,
I can be as contrary as I choose.
Watch yourself, Mr Bates.
Thomas is in charge now.
We don't need anyone with us.
Matthew's missing.
Subtitles by ITFC, MemoryOnSmells
www.MY-SUBS.com