WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
We can put the presents
in the drawing room
against the window.
Very good, m'lady.
I suppose we do have to
display all the presents.
It can look rather greedy.
I can't bear the disruption we've
brought on your heads. Don't be silly.
How are you feeling? I just wish I could
get rid of this damn stick. Sorry.
Don't be. If anyone has a
right to swear, it's you.
Don't bully yourself.
Think of where we were a few months
ago and smile. I quite agree.
I want to make it up and down that
aisle without assistance. Up, yes.
You'll have me to lean on coming
down.
You still have three full days
of practise so never say die.
My goodness, is that the time?
I must be getting back.
I'll go with you.
She's just sucking up, Mother.
Any bride who doesn't suck up
to her husband's mother is a fool.
(SNIGGERS)
Can I bother you?
Mrs Bryant has written a letter
I did not expect.
She says her husband wants to see
the baby. They both do.
Isn't that what you hoped?
Yes and no.
Remember what he was like last time?
I don't want to
build up Ethel's hopes again.
Ethel's not important.
It's the boy's chances you have to
look to. I believe you're right,
though we come at it by different
routes.
Why announce it tonight,
all of a sudden?
He's got a job at a newspaper.
He heard today, it's a real chance.
Let him go to Dublin then you can
use the calm to consider. (SIGHS)
Mary doesn't want you
to be trapped before
you're completely sure.
But I am sure!
How many times do I have to say it?!
Anna, tell them!
Lady Mary's right.
It's a big thing, to give up
your whole world. Thank you.
Listen to her if you won't listen
to me. I'm not giving up my world!
If they give me up,
that's their affair!
I'm perfectly happy to carry on
being friends with everyone.
Married to the chauffer?
Yes.
Anyway, he's a journalist now,
which sounds better for granny.
We're going to tell papa tonight.
We? You mean, you and Branson?
Downton is not a hostel.
No, Mr Carson.
You made such a point
of not being a servant
any more, our ears
are ringing with it.
Trouble is, I'm a little out
of pocket at the moment.
I cannot say that
I'm sympathetic
when you dabble in the black market.
I just need some more time,
Mr Carson.
How long is it since the last
patient left, Sergeant?
You're trespassing on our generosity.
I'll try to make myself useful.
Just find somewhere to go.
Yes?
I'm here.
So I can see.
It's not such a good idea.
We mustn't worry granny.
You asked me to
come and I've come.
Would someone please tell
me what is going on or
have we all stepped through
the looking glass?
Your grandmother has as much right
to know as anybody else.
Why don't I find that reassuring?
Oh, how much longer is Mr Carson
going to be? It's never worth
trying to make food interesting
in the servants hall.
You're very quiet this evening.
I've had a letter off Mr
Mason, William's dad.
Oh, yes. What does he want?
To see me. You're his daughter-in-law,
why shouldn't he see you?
I wish it were as simple. I think
it is but I'll not reopen the wound.
'What do you mean, you knew?'
I hoped it would blow over.
I didn't want to split
the family when Sybil
might still wake up.
You've driven me about,
bowing and scraping and seducing
my daughter behind my back?!
I don't bow and scrape and
I've not seduced her.
Give your daughter some credit
for knowing her own mind.
How dare you use that tone!
You will leave at once!
Oh, Papa! This is a folly!
A ridiculous, juvenile madness!
Sybil, what do you have in mind?
Mama, this is hardly ... No,
she must have something in mind.
Otherwise she wouldn't have summoned
him here tonight.
Thank you, Granny.
Yes, we do have a plan.
Tom's got a job on a paper.
Oh!
I'll stay for the wedding.
I don't want to steal their thunder.
But after that, I'll go to Dublin.
To live with him? Unmarried?
I'll live with his mother
while the banns are read.
And then we'll be married.
And I'll get a job as a nurse.
What does your mother make of this?
If you must know, she
thinks we're very foolish.
So, at least we have
something in common.
I won't allow it! I will not allow
my daughter to throw away her life!
You can posture all you
like, Papa, it won't
make any difference.
Yes, it will! How?
I don't want any money! You can
hardly lock me up until I die!
I'll say goodnight.
But I can promise you one thing.
Tomorrow morning, nothing will have
changed.
Tom.
He's not coming here!
I don't want him to see this place.
I won't have him pity me.
The question is are
you prepared to let them
in to Charlie's life?
I suppose so, yes.
Good.
I'll ask them to Downton
for Monday at four
and this time, it'll
be all above board.
Can't expect to live here free forever.
I didn't expect to get booted out.
You'll have to find some work.
It's not that easy. Every Tom, Dick and
Harry's looking for work these days.
And they all don't have a hand
like a Jules Verne experiment.
Mr Branson. I know it wasn't easy
last night.
You should have spoken out long ago.
Spoken out about what?
Oh, why not?
Lady Sybil and I are getting
married.
Have you no shame?!
I'm sorry you feel like that,
Mr Carson. You're a good man.
But, no, I have no shame.
In fact, I have great
pride in the love of that
young woman and I will
strive to be worthy of it.
I will not disgrace myself by
discussing it, nor will anyone else.
Now, if you will go, Mr Branson,
we will continue with our day.
Leave an address where we will forward
what is owing to you. No problem.
I'll be at the Grantham Arms until Lady
Sybil is ready to make her departure.
I bid you all a good day.
Is it really true?
Please! I have asked for silence.
And silence I will have.
What on Earth is it? A gramophone.
Some cousins of mine have given it.
(MUSIC PLAYS) You
should stand well clear
when you light the
blue touch paper.
All on your own?
I've left space at
the front for Jules.
I know Lavinia's getting
something from papa.
And from me. As she's so slight,
a real necklace would flatten her.
What news of Sybil?
Papa is with her now.
I'm afraid it'll end in tears.
Maybe, but they won't be Sybil's.
I used to think that Mary's beau
was a Leonce but compared to this,
he's practically a Hapsburg.
Don't worry. Your turn will come.
Will it? Or am I just to be
the maiden aunt?
Isn't this what they do? Arrange
presents for their pretty relations?
Don't be defeatist, dear,
it's very middle class.
I'd better go up and support your
father.
Your threats are
hollow, don't you see?
I won't be received in London?
I won't be welcome at court?
How do I make you understand,
I couldn't care less?
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
I do hope I'm interrupting
something.
I only wish you were. I seem to be
getting nowhere. Have you seen Cora?
She's lying down.
And can we blame her?
Now, Sybil, dear, this sort of thing is
all very well in novels, but in reality,
it can prove very uncomfortable
and while I am sure Branson
has many virtues...
No, no, he's a good driver.
I will not give him up!
Don't be rude to your grandmother.
No, she's not being rude. Just wrong.
This is my offer.
I will stay one week to avoid
the impression I've run away
and because I don't want to
spoil Matthew's wedding.
Then we will marry in Dublin
and whoever wishes to visit
is welcome. Out of the question!
Will you forbid Mary and Edith?
No, no.
Don't say anything you
may have to retract.
Know this. There will be no more
money.
From here on in, your life
will be very different. Well...
Bully for that.
I thought this might tide
you over... (GROANS)
Whatever's the matter?
I'm sure I'll be all
right if I can just stay
still for a moment.
You will not stay still.
Not down here.
Get to bed this minute.
I'll send for the doctor.
I can't. We've got the Crawleys
tonight and Miss Swire.
What with this business of Lady
Sybil. I'll deal with it.
Look, get Mr Mosley to help.
There's no need. I mean it!
The war is no longer an excuse for
sloppy presentation. Oh, very well,
I'll ask him, but only on condition
you go to bed. (GROANS AND COUGHS)
Are you too hot in that, m'lady?
You still have time to change.
No. Thank you.
So, what do we do next?
God knows!
This is what comes of spoiling her.
The mad clothes, the nursing.
What were we thinking of?
That's not fair.
She's a wonderful nurse
who's worked very hard.
And she's forgotten who she is!
Has she, Robert? Or have we
overlooked who she really is?
If you're turning American on me,
I'll go downstairs.
Mr Carson likes to serve
two white wines which
you should open and decant
just before they eat.
A light one for the hors d'oeuvres,
a heavy one with the soup.
Keep that going for the fish then change
to claret which you need to decant now.
There's a pudding wine and,
after that, whatever they want in
the drawing room with their coffee.
It's a wonder they make it upstairs.
They don't drink
much of any of it.
Let me show you the decanters.
These four...
So, I don't have to receive
that terrible man again.
It won't be necessary.
They'll meet her in here but...
Should you be downstairs, m'lady?
Oh, I'm perfectly all right,
thank you.
Why Mosley? I could have done it.
But you always make a mountain
out of not being a servant.
I'm just trying to be helpful.
I'm afraid, "being helpful", is not
something we associate you with.
Ooh, it's wonderful what fear
can do to the human spirit.
You quite right, Mr Mosley?
Yes, I just want to be absolutely
sure
that this is the lighter wine.
What does it matter as
long as it's white? No.
I believe in starting the way
you mean to go on.
Don't want to get off on the wrong
foot.
I'm glad you're here, Sybil.
I was afraid you'd have
a tray in your room.
Maybe you should have done.
Why?
I'm not eloping like a
thief in the night.
I might have once but Mary and
Edith talked me out of it. Oh!
The plot thickens.
After all, Sybil's had time
to think about it. Mother!
It is not for us to have an opinion.
(CLATTERS GLASS)
Mr Mosley, are you quite well?
(PANTS)
I'm all right, thank you, sir.
I don't believe you are.
The awful truth is, I'm not quite
all right. I'm afraid I'm going
to ask you to excuse me.
I'm so sorry.
Would you like us to call
Dr Clarkson? No, it's too late.
He's coming for Mr
Carson, Your Lordship.
I'll bring him up
when he arrives.
I can sleep in my dressing room.
Oh, I'm glad I've got you.
What you serving?
They're on the main course
so I can spare a moment?
I've been thinking and, erm, ...
I have to say something
that you won't agree with.
We're going to get married.
We can't. Not now.
You're not listening.
Go to Ripon tomorrow and take out
a special license,
I don't care how much it costs,
and fix the day.
We'll tell no-one, but this,
you will do. I can't.
Aren't I as strong as Lady Sybil?
I don't doubt that.
Well, then, if she can do it,
so can we.
That's what I've been thinking.
I have stuck by you, through thick
and thin.
Thin and thin, more like.
Mr Bates, if we have to face this,
then we will face it
as husband and wife and will not be
moved to the sidelines
to watch from a distance, with no
right even to be kept informed.
I will be your next of kin.
And you can't deny me that.
Anna!
You better come, quick.
(GROANS)
Mr Mosley? What's happened?
Haven't you taken it in yet?
Oh, I'm not well. I'm not well, at all.
First, Mr Carson then her ladyship
and now him.
Help him down to
the servants hall.
The doctor can look at him,
too, when he gets here.
Spanish flu has found it's way
to Yorkshire. And to Downton.
Dr Clarkson says
he's got ten cases.
Ah, I thought Mosley had
joined the Temperance League.
I'm afraid he's been taken ill, My Lord.
I'm sorry. Mosley, too? Good heavens.
Everyone's falling like ninepins.
Lavinia?
Do you know, I'm not at all well,
either.
I wonder if I could lie down for a
minute? Of course. Come to my room.
They'll have lit the fire by now.
Excuse me.
Do you think we should take her
home? No, let her rest for a moment.
Well, I think I should go and help.
Wasn't there a masked ball in Paris
when cholera broke out?
Half the guests were dead before they
left the ballroom. Thank you, Mama.
That's cheered us up no end.
I'll take you to Mr Carson now and then
to see Mr Mosley in the servant's hall.
Dr Clarkson, you're kind to come.
How is she?
Not too bad but she'll need some
nursing for a day or two.
Don't worry about that, all our
daughters are professionals.
Let's leave her
to get some rest.
Miss Swire may be
another victim.
She's sleeping now, I don't
want to disturb her.
When she wakes give her
some aspirin, cinnamon and
milk and keep her here.
I'll look at her tomorrow.
We better go to Carson.
I'll come, too.
(MUSIC PLAYS)
(SINGING)
Where is everyone?
I'm not sure.
Cousin Violet's gone home.
What about you?
I'm waiting for Lavinia and mother.
Dr Clarkson wants Lavinia to stay
here. He'll see her tomorrow.
I don't know this one.
Actually, I rather like it.
I think it was in a show
that flopped.
Zip Goes A Million, or something.
Can you manage without your stick?
You are my stick.
We were a show that flopped.
God, Mary.
I'm so, so sorry.
You know how sorry I am.
Don't be.
It wasn't anyone's fault.
If it was, it was mine.
You know cousin Violet came to me,
told me to marry you.
When was this?
A while ago.
When we knew I would walk again.
Classic granny.
What did you say?
I couldn't accept Lavinia's
sacrifice of her life.
Her children, her future and then give
her the brush off when I was well again,
well, I couldn't, could I?
Of course not.
However much I might want to.
Absolutely not.
Hello?
What are you doing up?
Shouldn't we be getting back.
It's decided.
You're staying here.
Dr Clarkson's coming in the morning
so he can treat you all together.
You can borrow some things until
Matthew brings you what you need.
I'll go and organise a room.
How do you feel?
Like a nuisance.
You could never be that.
I mean it, Matthew.
Don't ever let me be a nuisance.
Don't ever let me get in the way,
please. (RECORD ENDS)
I'll sleep on a chair in her room.
There's no need for that. I don't mind.
I'd like to be on hand.
So, we're quite the hospital again.
You'll probably gain more patients
over the next few da...
(SNIFFS)
You don't need to worry about
Mosley. He'll be fine in the morning.
Oh?
Ah-hah.
The others have Spanish flu.
He's just drunk.
Oh, did you want Mr Bates, My Lord?
Oh, I forgot to say I want to be
woken early. I can tell him that.
Freddie got into Ripon Grammar,
so whatever you said, it worked.
Marvellous, some good news at last.
I hate to hear you talk like that.
I'm sorry, that was selfish of me,
to spoil your happy moment.
You need never say sorry to me.
How are you?
Really?
Since you ask, I'm wretched.
I lost my youngest child today,
I suspect forever, and I can't
see any way round it. I wish
you knew how much I want to help.
Do you?
I think you know I do.
I'll see if I can get up tomorrow.
Oh, don't be foolish.
You're ill and in all probability,
you'll be a lot iller in the morning.
How will you manage?
What about the wedding?
I'm not sure there'll be a wedding,
but I won't burden you with it.
Perhaps Mr Mosley could come on a
permanent basis, until I'm better.
I doubt that's a
solution, Mr Carson.
Neither my patience or his
liver could stand it.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Who is it?
I'm sorry, My Lord, we
never settled a time
you wanted to be woken.
Early, I think,
with everyone ill, seven.
I'll breakfast at half past.
Very good, My Lord. Good night.
This isn't fair.
I'm placing you in an impossible
situation.
I want to be with you.
Let me.
I see.
You don't want me now. I want you
with every fiber of my being
but it isn't fair to you,
it isn't fair to anyone.
I wish I were different.
I wish everything was.
(GASPS)
I don't want you different.
I like you the way you are.
Thank you for that.
I will cherish it.
Truly.
What can I bring to help?
Ice, to bring her temperature down.
Mrs Hughes.
Sir Richard telephoned this morning.
He's coming down to help.
Can you have some rooms made ready
for him and his valet?
And tell Mrs Patmore.
Very good, m'lady.
'I don't accept I'm ruining her
life!'
Nor cutting her off from her family.
You cut her off, that's your decision!
How will you look after her?! How
can you hope to provide for her?
You seem to think she can only be happy
in some version of Downton Abbey.
If she wanted that life,
she would not be marrying me.
Very well.
I'd hoped to avoid this, but I see
that I can't!
How much will you take to leave us
in peace?
What?
You must have doubts.
You said your own mother thinks
you're foolish. Yes, she does.
Yield to those doubts and take enough
to make a new life back in Ireland.
I'll be generous if we can bring
this nonsense to an end. I see.
You know your trouble, My Lord?
You're like all of your kind, you think
you have the monopoly of honour!
Doesn't it occur to you
that I believe the best
guarantee of Sybil's
happiness lies with me?
Well, if you're not prepared
to listen to reason!
I'm not prepared to listen to insults.
Then, I'll bid you good day.
And I want you to leave the village.
Even though she'll come to me
the moment I call?
Do you really want me to leave now, when
I will take her with me that same hour?
Ah, there you are.
Dr Clarkson's here.
Cora's not at all well.
Sybil and Edith are with her.
Mary's gone to meet Sir Richard
from the train. Why's he coming?
He wants to be useful.
I don't see how. My Lord.
We're two more maids down.
I hope you forgive
some catch as catch can
in the days ahead.
Which maids? Not Jane?
No, My Lord. Not Jane.
Thank you.
What are they doing?
Decorations for the wedding.
It still hasn't been cancelled.
They have to prepare for it.
If Anna or Jane appear,
tell them to come
and help me do the
room for Sir Richard.
I can help with the bedroom then
I'll sort out a room for his man
and serve at dinner.
I can't pay you. Call it rent.
The awful truth is the wedding
simply cannot go ahead.
Don't say that.
I must.
Dr Clarkson says you'll be groggy
for at least a week, maybe longer.
We have to face the facts.
What about my father?
Matthew can telephone him.
He can't come here while everyone's ill.
He has a weak chest, we mustn't
take the risk. All right.
I suppose we've made a decision,
then, to delay?
I don't think we've got any choice.
No. I'm afraid we don't.
At least she doesn't seem
too serious. No, no.
I'd say she's been lucky. I am
terribly sorry about the wedding.
These things are sent to try us.
Why didn't anyone tell
me she was like this?
She took a turn for the
worse half an hour ago.
Where were you?
Out, I went for a walk.
There we are, m'lady, that's better,
isn't it?
She's been with her all night.
O'Brien, you must have a rest.
Not just now, My Lord.
I want to see her through
the worst, if I can.
I'll just make this
cooler for you.
How is she, really?
Tell me the truth.
I can't yet. Dr Clarkson says we
will know more in a few hours.
God almighty! How can this be?
My whole life gone over a cliff
in the course of a single day.
(BELL RINGS)
Take care of that, thank you.
How are you doing?
I'm not sure.
Her ladyship's worse.
I'm sorry.
Jane said you wanted to see me.
I've done it. I've booked the registrar.
(SNIGGERS) When for?
He's had a cancellation
so it's Friday afternoon.
This Friday? (BABY GURGLES)
Ethel, what are you doing here?
The Bryants have turned up aga...
That's what.
I'll find Mrs Hughes and come back
for you.
I hope I haven't kept you waiting.
No, no.
We have illness in the house so I hope
you'll excuse Lord and Lady Grantham.
It's not them we've come to see,
is it? Is she here?
She's just coming now.
May I meet him properly?
Come along, Charlie.
This nice lady is your grandmother.
Perhaps you could call me, "Gran"?
He's a stout little chap, isn't he?
And so like Charles. I thought it
when we were last here.
I know what was said at the time
and Mr Bryant's sorry for it now.
But I could see he was just like
Charles.
Never mind all that, let's get down
to business. Business?
That's what you want
from us, isn't it?
Find out what me mean to do for
little Charlie in the future?
What do you mean, "She might die"?
What do you think
happens with a fatal illness?
The fairies come?
If anything happens to her, it
won't be your fault, Miss O'Brien.
I've never seen such care.
I wish I could talk to her, that's
all. But she doesn't know me.
I'm sure she knows how hard you've
worked for her. It's not that.
There's something I nee...
Never mind.
Either I will or I won't.
You never know people, do you.
You can work with
them for 20 years, you
don't know them at all.
What? You mean give him up?
Never see him again?
Those are my terms.
But would it hurt if Ethel were
to care for him in your own house?
She could be his nurse.
That might be possible.
Of course she can't be his nurse.
We need to bring him up as a gentleman.
Send him to Harrow and
Oxford, and all the
while his mother's in
the servant's hall.
How does that work? I could
- No, we want to raise
his as our grandson,
not as a housemaid's bastard!
Well, he has to know the truth sometime.
Maybe, but not for a long time.
Till then, his father had
a wartime marriage until
he died and his mother
succumbed to Spanish flu.
A lot of people have.
We've quite a few upstairs.
And that, for many years at least,
is all that Charlie will be told.
So, I'm just to be written out?
Painted over? Buried?
What matters is what's
good for Charlie.
And what's good for you!
You've got a heart, I know you have.
You see what he's asking?
Ethel, consider this. In the world
as it is, compare the two futures.
The first, as my heir.
Educated, privileged, rich.
Able to do what he wants,
marry whom he likes.
The second, as the bastard son
- I think we've heard enough of
that word for one day. Very well.
As the nameless offshoot
of a drudge,
you're his mother.
Which would you choose for him?
Suppose I could be his nurse and never
tell him who I am. I promise that.
Surely ... Come on! We all know that's
a promise you could never keep.
(DOOR OPENS) I'm sorry,
Mrs Hughes, we need the
doctor at once.
Her ladyship's much worse.
I'm afraid ... Go where you're needed,
we've had our say.
You know how to reach us
when you've made your decision.
Come along, Daphne.
O'Brien?
Is that you, O'Brien?
Yes, m'lady, it's me, m'lady.
You're so good to me.
You've always been so good.
Not always, m'lady.
So good.
No.
And the fact is, I want to ask
so much for your forgiveness.
Because I did something once
which I bitterly regret. Bitterly.
And if you could only know
how much ... So very good.
(DOOR OPENS)
How is she?
She slept and she seemed better.
Then suddenly the fever came back.
O'Brien, thank you for the way
you've looked after her. I mean it.
I'm very grateful, whatever comes.
What a marathon, but I think I got
them all.
Everyone sends love. I told your
father I'll telegraph him
as soon as it's safe for him
to come. But not before.
Well, I don't think I should
leave you alone. (SIGHS)
But if you don't tell.
I've been thinking about
the date for the rematch and...
What is it?
I wonder if we haven't been rather
lucky.
Why, I think we've both been very
That we've been given a second
chance. A second chance at what?
To be quite, quite sure about
what we're doing.
Darling, what can you mean?
The thing is, ...
I might as well say it.
When I came downstairs and you
and Mary were dancing, ...
I heard what you said.
And I saw what you did. That was ...
No, I'm not in a rage, in a fury,
in fact, I think it's
noble of you to want
to keep your word when
things have changed.
But I'm not sure it would be right
for me to hold you to it.
Lavinia, I can explain.
No, listen.
I've had lots of time to think about
it.
I love you very, very much.
And I've wanted to
marry you from the
first moment I saw you.
All that is true.
But I didn't really know what I was
taking on.
It's not in me to be
queen of the county.
I'm a little person, an ordinary
person
and when I saw you and Mary
together, I thought,
how fine, how right you looked
together.
I don't want to hear this!
You must!
Because it isn't a sudden thing.
I was starting to worry and then,
when you were wounded,
I thought it was my calling
to look after you.
And care for you.
And I don't think
Mary would have done
that quite as well as me, really.
No, no.
Not nearly as well.
I do have some self worth.
Just not enough to make you
marry the wrong person.
This is pointless, Mary is
marrying somebody else.
Is she?
We'll see.
I won't let you do this.
You will.
We won't fight about it now.
In fact, I'm tired.
Can I rest for a bit?
We'll talk later.
Of course.
It's good of you to come but I don't
really see what you can do.
I thought I'd better do my bit.
The chauffer's gone so
I could drive the car.
Preferably over the chauffer.
Father's not having an easy time
of it.
How's Lady Grantham?
Not well.
Clarkson's with her now.
And Miss Swire?
Oh, she's...
Is that why you've come? Because
I said Lavinia had been taken ill?
I was coming up anyway,
in a day or two, for the wedding.
Well, she won't be getting married
on Saturday.
Which I suppose is what you'd like
best?
But she's not seriously ill.
I see what was worrying you.
If Lavinia had been carried
off, you wanted to be
here to stop Matthew from
falling into my arms
on a tidal wave of grief.
It's a tricky disease.
(DOOR OPENS)
His lordship's asking for you,
m'lady.
I think we should aim at a sort
of buffet dinner.
Then they can run in and
out as it suits them.
Sorry to make extra work.
Never mind, it's hours like these
we must all pull together.
This arrived in the post, Daisy.
Tea for Sir Richard in the drawing room.
I'm glad to know he's here to help(!)
I can do it.
You're very obliging, Thomas.
I can take some up to Mr Carson,
if you'd like?
Is that from your Mr Mason?
He's not mine.
What does he say? He just says,
again, we should talk about William.
He wants me to go to his farm.
Oh, poor man.
Will you not visit him?
I'm not going to any farm!
You're all he's got, Daisy.
Well, then, he's got nobody
cos he hasn't got me.
Oh, I'm sorry, m'lady, I didn't
think you'd want to change tonight.
I don't. I just need a handkerchief.
How's her ladyship?
Not good, I'm afraid.
What is it?
I don't mean to bother you, m'lady.
Go on.
Can you keep a secret?
Well, I know you can.
You see, Mr Bates and I had a plan.
To get married this coming Friday.
What?
He's worried the police haven't
finished with him and, if he's right,
then, I'm not going
through it with no
proper place in his life.
A brave decision.
Or a stupid one.
Anyway, with her ladyship ill now
and half the servants on their
backs and everybody working
- Where is the marriage to be?
Just in a register office in Ripon.
It wouldn't take long but... Go.
I'll cover for you. We're all here.
You won't help mama by changing your
plans.
You better come. She's worse.
I've given her the epinephrine.
Doctor! Oh, no!
What does that mean?
It's a hemorrhage of the mucus
membranes.
It's not unusual.
(VOMITS)
It's all right, m'lady, don't worry.
Everything's going to be all right.
Everything is clearly not all right.
How bad is it?
If she lasts through the night,
she'll life.
What about the others?
Come with me.
I'll be back shortly.
(GROANS)
I've given some medicine
to Mrs Hughes.
She'll bring it up later. I gather
her ladyship is not improving.
We'll, er, we'll know more tomorrow.
And Miss Swire?
Not too bad, I think.
I'll go to her when I've
seem the rest of the servants.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Ah.
Thank you, sir. Here we are,
Mr Carson.
Now, have you got everything
you need?
M'lady.
I want to thank you for coming up,
m'lady. Not at all.
I mean it. I know I've been
a disappointment to you.
Maybe.
But I've relied on your support for
too long to do without it entirely.
You'll always have my support,
m'lady. And you, mine.
On which subject...
I should be careful of Thomas.
Oh, I don't know how we're to get
rid of him after all this.
I doubt he'll want to stay a footman
forever, so, watch out.
You look very smart, Thomas.
I still have the shirt, m'lady.
And I found my livery in the
cupboard so I thought, "Why not?"
I have a place for you here.
How's Lavinia?
All right, I think.
The illness has made her rather
confused. What do you mean?
Matthew! Mary!
Is it mama?
That's what's so... It's Lavinia.
Let him go to her. Let him be with
her. Surely you owe her that?
What happened?
This is how I found her.
It's bad, I'm afraid.
Very bad.
The worst. I don't understand.
When I was with her, she was fine.
It's a strange disease with sudden,
savage changes.
I'm terribly sorry. What can I do?
Can I talk to her? Yes. Of course.
My darling. Can you hear me?
It's me. It's Matthew.
Matthew.
I'm so glad you're here.
Of course I'm here.
Darling, where else would I be?
Isn't this better?
Really?
I don't understand you.
You have to make our decision.
Be happy.
For my sake.
Promise me.
It's all I want for you.
Remember that.
That's what I want.
But I can't be happy.
Not without you.
How could I be happy?
What are you doing?
They were put up for the wedding,
Mr Crawley.
My dear chap.
I cannot find the words to say how
sorry I am.
How is cousin Cora?
Much better, thank you.
Glad to hear it.
I came to see if there's
anything I can do.
We've taken care of all that.
We always use Grassby's. Of course.
Travis suggested Monday for the
funeral to give people time to get
here. It will be in tomorrow's paper.
That's very kind of you.
Mary wanted to see you.
No!
I mean, I...
don't really want to see anyone.
Not yet.
Now I know everything's
settled, I'll go back.
When you speak to her father,
do ask him to stay here.
Thank you.
He'll be very grateful.
Just tell me what you want me to do
and I'll do it.
Are you feeling more yourself?
A bit.
I still can't get over it.
I hope you'll not pretend you liked
her now.
I didn't want her here,
Mrs Hughes, I'll admit.
But I had no objection to her being
happy somewhere else.
A sight to gladden my heart.
Is it? I hope it is.
You gave us quite a fright.
They told me about Lavinia.
The funeral is on Monday.
I'd like to go, if I can.
We're all right,
aren't we, Robert?
Of course we are.
I got so caught up in
everything, I think
I neglected you and
if I did, I'm sorry.
Don't apologise to me.
Ethel!
Whatever are you doing here at this
time of night?
I said I'd be back with
my answer and here I am.
You know we're a
house in mourning?
Yes and I'm sorry.
But, if anything, it's made my mind
up for me.
Life is short and what's my life
without Charlie?
They're not having him.
As long as you're sure.
They say they can do
better for him but what's
better than his mother's love?
Answer me that.
I'll write and tell them.
You agree with me, though, don't
you?
My opinion has no place in this.
'I, John Bates.'
'Take thee, Anna May Smith.'
'To be my wedded wife.'
'I, Anna May Smith.'
I, Anna May Smith.
Take thee, John Bates.
To be my wedded husband.
And now the ring.
With this ring I plight thee
my troth.
As a symbol of all we have promised.
And all that we share.
It therefore gives me great pleasure
to say you are now husband and wife
together.
You rang, My Lord?
I keep forgetting Carson's ill.
Mrs Hughes says he's much better.
I really want Bates. He'd gone out.
He's in your dressing room.
He went up with
your evening shirt.
Golly, is that the time?
Actually, can you stay a moment?
I was trying to think how to contrive
a meeting and here you are.
You see ...
I'm glad Lady Grantham's better.
Truly.
And don't worry.
There's no harm done.
No harm done yet.
I'm almost packed.
And I've given in my notice.
This is the name and address
of my man of business.
Why?
You don't owe me anything.
Oh, it's not for you.
It's for Freddie.
Let me give him a start in life.
I'm not sure ...
It would make me very happy.
If I thought that, then I'd take it,
gladly.
Will you be happy?
Really?
I have no right to be unhappy,
which is almost the same.
Almost.
Not quite.
Can I kiss you before I go?
The secret Mrs Bates.
We will tell everyone but I thought
we should leave it a while.
At least till after
the funeral, anyway.
You'll have to control yourselves.
Well, we've had enough practise.
Come with me.
Smuggle Bates in here
when everyone has gone to bed.
And for heaven's sake,
make sure he gets the right room.
I don't know what to say, m'lady.
Who did all this?
Jane.
I told her. She said it would be her
leaving present.
You can stay all night.
She won't tell.
M'lady, thank you.
Very, very much.
Are you sure you should be up,
Mr Carson?
I wanted to check the silver before
tomorrow.
I think I've cleaned all the pieces
we might need.
We'll get everything ready
the moment breakfast is over.
Thank you for the way you've kept it
all going, Thomas.
I wish I knew how to express
my gratitude.
You'll find a way, Mr Carson.
I think that's everything we owe.
Thank you, Mrs Hughes.
I'm sorry you're going, Jane.
You're a good worker.
I wish you well.
I'm sorry, too, Mrs Hughes.
But in the end I think it's for the
best.
For everyone.
When all is said and done, my dear,
you may be right.
Well, ... Mrs Bates?
You've had your way with me.
I just hope you don't live to regret
it.
I couldn't regret it.
No matter what comes.
I know only that I am now
who I was meant to be.
I'm not worthy of you,
that's all I know.
And they'll call me names
for pulling you into my troubles.
Mr Bates.
We've waited long enough to be
together, you and I.
And now that we're man and wife,
can that not be enough,
just for this one night?
Earth to earth,
ashes to ashes,
dust to dust.
In sure and in certain hope of the
resurrection to eternal life
through our lord, Jesus Christ,
we shall change our vile body that it
may be like unto his glorious body,
according to the mighty working
whereby he is able to subdue
all things to himself.
Amen.
(ALL) Amen.
Would you give him a moment?
Of course, ma'am, I understand.
We better get moving if we're
to be back before they arrive.
Mrs Patmore and Thomas will go ahead
in the trap. They'll sort it out.
Hmm, I've no doubt Thomas
will have everything sorted out.
I'm sorry but it's no good thinking
we'll get shot of him now.
Why doesn't that come as a surprise?
I've been hoping I might meet you
here one day.
I expect you'll come as often
as I try to do?
It was a funeral...
of a lady that was going to marry
Mr Crawley.
I heard about that.
There's nothing so wrong as when
young folks die.
Nay, needn't hide your tears from
me, love.
It does me good to see how much you
loved him, it does.
You must tell me if there's anything
I can do.
Anything at all.
Thank you.
But I don't think so.
That night when we were dancing.
Lavinia came downstairs.
She heard, she...
She saw everything.
How terrible for her.
I'm so sorry.
Because of what she saw,
she thought we should cancel
the wedding.
That I belonged with you.
Not with her.
She gave up because of us.
She said tome when she was dying,
"Isn't this better?"
I know it's a cliche but...
I believe she died of a broken
heart because of that kiss.
We were the ones who killed her.
Oh, Matthew. I could never be happy
now. Don't you see?
We're cursed, you and I.
And there's nothing to be done
about it.
Let's be strong, Mary.
Let's accept that this is the end.
Of course it's the end.
How could it not be?
I'm so very sorry about this.
Thank you.
Can I walk you up to the house
or...? Certainly, you can.
I want you to.
So sad.
Why are you here? To pay my respects
to Miss Swire. And to see Sybil.
Lady Sybil! Papa, what's the point
in all that nonsense?
I suppose you'll go to Dublin now,
isn't that your plan? In a day or two.
Mama is well again and I see no
reason to delay.
Although, I do so wish
we could have parted friends.
What about you?
Do you want to part friends?
I do. Although I don't expect to.
All right.
What?
Well, if I can't stop you,
I see no profit in a quarrel.
You'll have a very different life
from the one you might have lived,
but if you're sure it's what you
want?
I am.
Then you may take my blessing
with you, whatever that means.
Oh, Papa! It means more than
anything! More than anything!
If you mistreat her, I will personally
have you torn to pieces by wild dogs.
I'd expect no less.
Will you come over for the wedding?
We'll talk about that later.
And there'll be some money.
But not much.
So, you've given in?
She would have gone anyway.
And perhaps we should let Lavinia's
last gift to us
be a reminder of what really matters.
You'll think that's soft?
Not at all.
The aristocracy has not survived
by its intransigence.
No, we must work with what
we've got to minimise the scandal.
But what have we got to work with?
You'd be surprised.
He's political, isn't he?
And a writer.
I could make something out of that.
And there's a family called Branson
with a place not far from Cork.
I believe they have a
connection with the Howards.
Surely we can hitch
him onto them?
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Mr Bates! You all right,
Mrs Patmore? I'm all right.
There are two men waiting for you
in the servants hall.
Are you looking for me?
John Bates?
Yes. You are under arrest
on the charge of willful murder.
You are not obliged to say anything
unless you desire to do so.
Whatever you say will be
taken down in writing and
may be given in evidence
against you upon trial.
I understand.
No! No!
Please, ... do whatever is required.
I love you.
And I love you.
For richer, for poorer.
For better, for worse. Come along, sir.
Subtitles by APOLLO
www.MY-SUBS.com