WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Sync and corrected by
www.MY-SUBS.com
Downton Abbey
Season 2, Episode 2
Letter for you, William.
Why on earth are you doing that?
Well, someone's got to. Yes, indeed
they do.
And that someone is William or one
of the maids.
You're making work for yourself,
Mr Carson,
and I've no sympathy with that.
I'm not asking for sympathy.
I don't think you should be... What?
For heaven's sake. If something's
wrong put it right.
I'm sorry, Lang. I don't mean to
snap.
Not to worry, my lord. You've been
in the trenches I have not.
I have no right to criticise.
I'm not a soldier now.
You've been invalided out. That is
perfectly honourable.
Is it?
People look at me and wonder why I'm
not in uniform.
Then you refer them to me and I'll
give them a piece of my mind.
Hm?
Penny for your thoughts. They're
worth a great deal more than that.
What is it? My papers. They've come.
I've been called up.
Oh, you never have. What does it
mean?
I report for my medical
on Wednesday and once
I'm through that I go
to Richmond for training.
Then you go to war? With any luck. I'll be
beggared if it's over before I get there.
If they'd listen to me it'd be over
by tea time.
Daisy, I wonder... would you give me
a picture to take with me?
I haven't got one. Then have one
taken, on your afternoon off, please.
That's enough. Let her get on with
her work.
How's Thomas coming along?
I wish he could be treated at our
hospital here.
Well, it's only for officers. Of
course.
Although, ideally he'd love to be
transferred there to work.
He won't be sent back to the front?
Not with his hand the way it is.
It's such a pity he isn't under Dr
Clarkson.
We might have been able to influence
him a bit. I should hope so.
Without this family
and all the money you've
spent his precious hospital
wouldn't exist at all.
Perhaps I'll ask his advice. You
never know.
I was sure you'd have a good idea of
what to do for the best.
Fancy a tour in England, Davis?
I assume you're having me on, sir.
Not at all. General Sir Herbert
Strutt
has asked for my transfer to be his
ADC.
He's touring England to boost recruitment.
I know Manchester and Yorkshire well.
It would mean a few months at home
and a promotion to captain.
I can't object to that.
I've only got a few days before the
medical, my lady.
Then go and tell your father.
You don't mind, do you,
Carson? We must manage
with no footman at all
from next Wednesday.
It'll be no different if we start
now. And you've always got Lang.
We wish you every good fortune.
Don't we, darling?
We certainly do.
Good luck, William. Thank you, my
lord.
So, both my footmen have gone to the
war
while I cut ribbons and make
speeches.
And keep people's spirits up...
which is very important.
By God, I envy them though.
I envy their self respect and I envy
their ability to sleep at night.
Mr Carson doesn't like
the smell of cleaning
materials in here, not
just before luncheon.
Come on, Mrs O'Brien. We don't want
to be unfriendly, do we?
You obviously don't.
Finish it now but don't blame me if
Mr Carson takes a bit out of you.
(CLEARS THROAT)
Hello, Mr Lang. Everything all
right?
Why do you say that?
No reason. I only meant I hope
you're enjoying yourself.
I know I would be in your shoes.
You never tried for the job, did
you? I never got the chance.
I'd no sooner heard that Mr Bates
was gone than he arrived.
What brings you here, Mr Molesley?
I was wondering if Anna was anywhere
around.
I could find her if you like. Oh,
no, no, no.
Just give her this. We were talking
about it the other day
and I came across a copy in...Ripon.
Elizabeth And Her German Garden?
Whatever's that about?
It's about an invitation to talk
some more, that's what.
Goodbye, Dr Clarkson.
Lady Grantham.
I'd love to help but it's not within
my power
to hook men from hither and thither
as I please.
That's not at all what I was asking.
I thought you were saying you wanted
Corporal Barrow
to come and work here when he's fully
recovered.
I think it a credit to him that he
wants to continue to serve in this way...
after he's been wounded. Well,
that's as maybe
but it's not for me to decide what
happens next.
Mr Carson, are you quite well?
Oh, leave me alone.
(GRUNTS WITH EFFORT)
After 24 hours it disappeared. Are
you all right, Carson? Of course.
That is, perfectly all right, Your
Ladyship, thank you.
Er, no.
Cousin Isobel says Matthew's coming
home in a fortnight.
He's touring England with some
general.
We'll have a dinner when he's here.
I was going to ask Richard Carlisle
about then for Saturday to Monday.
Be careful, Mary. Sir Richard
mustn't think you're after him.
Isn't that the truth? The truth is
neither here nor there.
It's the look of the thing that
matters. Ask Rosamund.
It'll take the edge off it. That'll
be nice.
Like before the war.
How can we manage a pre-war house
party without a single footman?
My dear, Rosamund is not a house
party.
She's blood.
I saw Mrs Drake when I went into the
village.
The wife of John Drake who has
Longfield Farm.
Oh. What did she have to say?
Apparently their final able-bodied
farmhand has been called up.
They need a man to drive the
tractor.
Hasn't Drake recovered from his illness?
I thought he was better. He's much better.
But he doesn't drive.
So I told her I could do it.
What? I said I could drive the
tractor.
Edith! You are a lady not Toad of
Toad Hall.
Well, I'm doing it.
Don't look so bewildered. It's
simple.
I will drive the tractor.
Well, can you do that? Absolutely.
Can you hitch up the plough or
whatever it is I'm dragging?
Of course. When would you like me to
start?
I'd better get you something to
wear.
Oh, I like a bit of life
in a house but I just
hope Mr Carson doesn't
spontaneously combust.
I had a letter yesterday.
Yes? It's my sister's boy.
He's with the Lancashire Fusiliers.
Only he's gone missing.
Missing presumed dead they call it.
Oh, no.
How did it happen? They can't find out
- how it happened, why it happened,
whether we can be sure it did happen
or he isn't lying prisoner somewhere.
Ask his lordship. He'll have friends in
the War Office. They can dig something up.
Oh, I don't like to bother him.
Why not? He's got broad shoulders.
That's ever so fine, Mr Lang.
How can you make those big hands do
such delicate work?
I expect there's no end to the
things they could manage.
Giving you a slap for a start.
That is good. Very good.
I like to see a proper skill.
Blokes think they can be a valet if
they can smile and tie a shoelace
but there's an art to it and I can
tell you've got it.
My mother taught me.
She was a lady's maid, like you.
Well, she knew what she was about.
Oh, Mr Lang. As you know, Sir
Richard Carlisle arrives later
and the Crawleys are coming for
dinner tonight.
I really can't have maids in the
dining room for such a party
so I'd be grateful if you'd help me
and play the footman.
Me? Wait at table?
Well, it's not ideal but I'm afraid
I've no choice.
The footman's liveries are in a
cupboard past Mrs Hughes' sitting room.
You should find one to fit you.
I'm not sure what I can do but I'm
happy to try.
What's his name? Archie.
That is Archibald Philpotts.
He was in the Lancashire Fusiliers.
They think he was in northern
France.
You realise the most likely outcome
is that he has indeed been killed.
I understand, my lord. But we'd
rather know the worst than wonder.
Hm.
Ah. Oh, hello, Mr Molesley.
What are you doing here? I asked inside
and they said you were at the laundry.
Lady Mary is wearing this tonight. I
wasn't sure it was done.
I wondered if you'd had a chance to
read that book.
You only gave it to me yesterday. Of
course, of course.
But when you have read it I hope we
can exchange our views.
That'd be nice. Perhaps we might
bring some of the others in.
We could have a sort of reading
club.
We could do that.
(DISTANT BELL RINGS)
Or we could talk about it together
just we two. (FOOTSTEPS)
Heavens. It's later than I thought.
I must get on.
(DOOR OPENS)
I'm off to change but I wanted you to
know I sent a note to Clarkson
which should do the trick. What did
you say?
That you'd asked a favour and, given that
the estate shoulders the hospital costs,
it did seem unfair if we weren't
allowed a few perks.
Quite right. Thank you, darling.
Well done, my lady.
(ENGINE RUMBLES)
Ready?
Ready!
(HEAVY CLUNKING)
Come on, damn you.
(GRINDING)
Whoa-ho-ho! Yes!
To the victor...the spoils.
Did you plant that tree?
Steady on. It must be 40 years old.
It's not a flattering light.
My father planted it. But you have
to be tough with fruit trees,
not let them outstay their welcome.
Farming needs a kind of toughness,
doesn't it?
There's room for sentiment but not
sentimentality.
Beautifully put, if I may say so, my
lady.
You should be a writer. Thank you.
How are you getting on? Very well, I
think.
It's not too hard for you? Not at
all. She's stronger than she looks.
I've brought you something to eat,
my lady.
I'm afraid it's not what you're used
to.
Hey, it's not for you.
So it is you.
Ethel thought I must have a soldier
fancy man.
Is she the new maid? Yes.
She's a soppy sort.
So, tell me, was Dr Clarkson
thrilled to have your services?
It's Major Clarkson now but yes.
I don't know how you did it.
What about your blighty?
My God. It's not so bad.
And it lived up to its name and got
me home.
You'd better come inside.
Where's William? Training for the
army.
I thought he might have died for
love of you.
Don't be nasty as soon as you're
back.
Imagine Carson without a footman.
Like a ringmaster without a pony.
We'll have none of your cheek, thank
you, Thomas.
I'm very sorry, Mrs Hughes, but I'm
not servant any more.
I take my orders from Major
Clarkson.
Who's this? Ethel, the new maid. I
told you.
I didn't realise I was dealing with
an ex-footman.
I'm the one that got away.
Gives hope to us all.
Ethel, help with the luggage.
They're nearly back with Sir Richard.
We've got a visitor, Mr Carson.
I've seen him.
Where's Mr Bates? Gone. Replaced by
Mr Lang.
So not all the changes were bad.
Oh. We're so pleased to have you
here, Sir Richard.
Lady Grantham. Welcome. Thank you.
I hope the train wasn't too tiring.
Hello, Mary.
Not a bit, no. I got a lot done.
Hello, Aunt Rosamund.
Brother, dear. How are you?
Lovely to see you, Rosamund.
He's nice, isn't he? He spent the
entire journey reading his own papers.
But I'm sure I'll love him dearly if
he'll ever look up from the page.
Branson, when you've finished
unloading
go to the hospital and remind Lady
Sybil that we expect her for dinner.
And tell her I mean it.
Really. They're working her like a
packhorse in a mine.
I think she enjoys it though.
Please tell her to come home in time
to change.
I can't possibly come. Really, Mama
is incorrigible.
It's not poor Branson's fault.
What is the point of Mama's soirees?
What are they for?
Well, I'm going up for dinner and
I'm glad. Is that wrong?
Thomas.
You can cover for Nurse Crawley,
can't you?
I can.
So you're back then, safe and sound.
That's not how I'd put it with my
hand the way it is
but, yes, Major Clarkson's found me
a place and I'm grateful.
Can you give Lieutenant Courtenay
his pills?
Of course I can. Be glad to.
(DOOR OPENS)
Is everything under control?
Mr Lang seems a bit nervous.
Stage fright. But what about you?
Oh... I'm a trouper.
And we can't complain, can we? Not when
you think what's going on in France.
Still...a broken heart can be as
painful as a broken limb.
Don't feel sorry for me, Mrs Hughes.
I'm not.
I know what real love is and there
aren't many who can say that.
I'm one of the lucky ones.
If you say so.
So the fashion for cocktails before
dinner hasn't reached Yorkshire?
I could get Carson to make you one
but I won't guarantee the result.
Mrs Crawley, Captain Crawley and
Miss Swire.
Ah. Isobel.
Well now, still in one piece.
Thank God. Touch wood. I never
stopped touching it.
Do you know Sir Richard Carlisle? My
cousin, Captain Crawley.
How do you do? And his fiancee Miss
Swire.
I know Miss Swire. Her uncle and I
are old friends.
Well, old acquaintances anyway.
What do you think Mary sees in him?
Besides the money, you mean?
It must be more than that. For
you...not necessarily for her.
What's General Strutt like? Well,
you know. Rather important.
And brave. He got the DSO in South
Africa.
Is there any chance it might be permanent
that we can count you out of danger?
It would be such a relief. I wouldn't
want that, I'm afraid.
He's promised to get me back to
France.
How's your appointment with the
North Ridings working out?
Oh, that. W...
It seems I won't be going to the
front after all.
I made a mistake.
They only wanted a mascot.
Mary tells me you're in newspapers.
Well, I own a few. Oh.
That must be quite a responsibility
at a time like this, you know, in a
war.
When it's so important to keep
people's spirits up.
Lady Grantham, my responsibility is
to my investors.
I need to keep my readership up. I leave
public spirits to government propaganda.
So now you've met Granny.
I warn you she has very strong
opinions.
Oh, you need have no fear where
that's concerned, my dear.
We're more than evenly matched.
Where are the spoons for this? Just
here.
Oh, my God. I've forgotten the
sauce.
Mr Lang's bringing the sauce and the
Melba toast. Right, good.
Now, Mr Lang, are you ready? I think
so.
It's always the left and not ladies
first.
No, just follow Mr Carson.
Start with old Lady Grantham, then
his lordship, then just go on round.
You must have done this before. Not
since the war started.
I don't think I even knew that. Why
in't it just ladies first?
Wouldn't it be more
polite? That's how it's done
on the continent. We don't
like foreign ways here.
I gather your footman, Thomas, has
returned to the village. No.
Crikey. Where did you see him?
At the hospital. Seems he's working
there.
I wonder how he wangled that.
(No, no, get back behind me.)
What do you make of our plutocrat?
He's an opportunity. Mary's needs a
position
and, preferably a powerful one. He
can provide it.
You don't think she'd be happier
with a more traditional set-up?
Will she have the option?
Thank you but I already have some.
No, no. Give that to me.
Oh! I do apologise, my lady.
Mr Lang, get a cl...
(GROANS IN PAIN)
(MOANS)
Carson. Carson, what's the matter?
Now, Carson, it's all right.
Everything will be fine.
Edith, go with Branson and fetch
Major Clarkson.
I'll telephone and explain. What
about my dress?
Edith will get you a coat. Come.
Sybil will know what to do until the
doctor comes.
There's never a dull moment in this
house.
Lady Sybil and I will take him upstairs.
Mrs Hughes will show us the way.
I can help. No, let me. I know what
I'm doing.
I'm sure that's not necessary, my
lady.
It's not my lady now, Carson.
Mr Lang. It's Nurse Crawley.
Mr Lang. Come on.
Anna and Ethel, I must trust the
dinner to you.
I'd say the first course is a thing
of the past.
Then clear and lay the hot plates.
Daisy, you fetch the beef and the
rest of it. Anna, you serve the wine.
Mr Lang, you can clear up the mess.
I'll do that. There's no need. I
don't mind. I thank you.
Mr Lang, you'd better go downstairs.
Well, Clarkson's seen him.
It's definitely not a heart attack
but he does need rest.
He's working much too hard.
For a start he's just got to let the
maids serve in the dining room.
Quite right. There is a war.
Even Carson has to make sacrifices.
Poor Lang. He looked like a rabbit
in front of a snake.
I don't understand it. He seemed so
solid when I met him,
even taciturn, now he's a bundle of
nerves.
I heard what you said to Matthew
about the regiment.
Everyone else knows what a fool I
made of myself, why shouldn't he?
I don't think you're a fool. Isn't
that enough?
No.
Maybe it should be but it isn't.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
(DISTANT MACHINE-GUN FIRE)
Are you all right, Mr Lang?
You're not, are you?
I've seen shell shock before, you
know.
I had a brother with it.
My favourite brother, as it happens.
And I was his favourite too.
They sent him back and he's dead
now.
They won't send me back.
I'm a goner as far as they're
concerned.
You shouldn't be working yet. I must
work.
I don't know what to do else.
I have to work.
(FOOTSTEPS)
Mr Lang. I thought you'd gone up.
He wanted to hang up the livery
before it got creased.
Well, we can discuss the dinner
another time.
I'll say good night. Good night, Mrs
Hughes. Good night.
May I come in?
That's very kind of you, my lady,
but do you think you should?
Let's hope my reputation will
survive it.
And rest easy, please.
I gather it isn't too serious. Oh,
I've been very stupid, my lady.
I let myself get flustered.
I regard that as highly
unprofessional.
It won't happen again. Don't be too
hard on yourself.
I was particularly sorry to spoil
things for Sir Richard,
knowing he was a guest of yours.
Don't be.
I think he found it all quite
exciting.
Will we be seeing a lot of him?
I don't know. Maybe.
And Captain Crawley...
is he happy with the changes, so to
speak?
May I give you one piece of advice,
my lady?
Tell him what's in your heart.
If you still love him, let him know.
Then even if he's killed, and he may
be, you won't be sorry.
But if you don't tell him you could
regret it all your life long.
And what about Miss Swire?
Well... Miss Swire.
As if any man in his right mind could
prefer Miss Swire to you.
Oh, I'm so sorry, my lady. I didn't
know you were in here.
I was just going. Carson's been
boosting my confidence.
That's something I'd never have
thought she was short of.
What about you, sir?
What did you do before the war
started?
I was up at Oxford.
But I only ever planned to farm.
Farm and shoot.
And hunt and fish.
And everything I'll never do again.
You don't know that. We've had cases
of gas blindness wearing off.
Rare cases.
And much sooner than this.
It doesn't help me to be lied to, you
know.
I'm finished.
And I'd rather face it than dodge it.
I'd better go.
Where's Rosamund? She's with your
mama.
Trying to talk her into the idea of
Sir Richard.
You don't sound very enthusiastic.
Are you?
Can we stop for a minute?
Don't tell me you're tired. I'm not
tired, I'm hot.
This tweed is too thick.
It looks more suited to shooting
than walking.
I had it made for the weekend. I
didn't know there was a difference.
It doesn't matter. That's like the
rich who say money doesn't matter.
It matters enough when you haven't
got it.
I know you don't care about our
silly rules.
You're always very clear on that
score.
You make me sound rude and I hope
I'm not that.
I mean to learn how to do things
properly and you could help me a lot.
But I'm not ashamed of being what
they call a self-made man.
I'm proud of it.
Is the point of all this to test me
in some way?
Maybe.
Are you shocked by my bold and
modern values?
Oh, Sir Richard, you flatter
yourself.
It takes a good deal more than that
to shock me.
But, Mama, who do you imagine is out
there with more to offer?
I'm not a romantic. I should hope
not.
But even I will concede that the
heart does not exist
solely for the purpose of pumping
blood.
That is charming, especially from
you.
But Mary seems to have...blotted her
copybook in some way.
So she needs a suitable marriage
that will mend her fences.
Well, how do we know Carlisle is
suitable?
Who is he? Who'd ever heard of him
before the war?
Sir Richard is powerful and rich and
well on the way to a peerage.
Of course, he may not be all that
one would wish
but Mary can soon smooth off the
rough edges.
Well, you should know. What do you
mean by that?
Marmaduke was a gentleman.
Marmaduke was the grandson of a
manufacturer.
His mother was the daughter of a
baronet. Maybe...
but they were no great threat to the
Plantagenets.
The point is I made up for any
social deficiencies.
And he provided me with a position.
It was a good exchange and it worked
well.
How can Matthew have chosen that
little blonde piece?
You speak so eloquently of the human
heart, Mama.
You must be aware of its...vagaries.
'Things cannot be as they were and
Jack has your best interests at heart.'
Stop.
Who's Jack?
My younger brother.
He means to replace me.
It's what he's always wanted.
Yeah... well...
I'm sorry.
I mustn't bore you.
Don't let them walk all over you.
You've got to fight your corner.
What with? Your brain.
You're not a victim. Don't let them
make you into one.
You know, when you talk like that...
I almost believe you.
You should believe me.
All my life they've...
pushed me around just cos I'm
different.
How? Why are you different?
Never mind.
Look...
Look, I... I don't know if you're
going to see again or not.
But I do know you have to fight
back.
How dare you threaten me? How dare
I?
I assure I dare a great deal more
than that.
But you can't, you wouldn't. I
didn't say I would.
I was merely reminding you it was in
my power.
Lady Painswick. Lady Rosamund.
I'm sorry. I'll get these things
sorted out before long.
It's not important.
Miss Swire and I were just talking
about old times.
Happy old times, I hope.
Will you forgive me? I want to write
some letters before dinner.
Let's have a rest. We've earned it.
I should have got a glass. You can't
drink out of a bottle, my lady.
I wish you'd call me Edith.
And of course I can drink from the
bottle.
Would you like me to teach you to
drive?
Not much...cos then you wouldn't
come here no more.
Although that wouldn't matter to you.
Why do you say that?
You're pretty and clever and fine.
You're from a different world.
Is something wrong? No, just having
a break.
Because you want to get into town to
fetch the bone meal.
And be back in time to feed the cows
before it's dark.
They could always have a midnight
feast.
That's it, sir. If you move the stick fast
enough you don't have to slacken your pace.
Check the width of the space as well
as any obstruction.
Lieutenant Courtenay, well done.
You're making good progress. Thanks
to my saviours, sir.
So you'll be pleased to hear that it's
time to continue your treatment elsewhere.
What? At Farley Hall.
You're not ill any more. All you need
is time to adjust to your condition.
The staff at Farley can help with
that.
But, sir, these two are helping me
here.
Nurse Crawley and Corporal Barrow
are not trained in specialist care.
Please. Don't send me away.
Not yet.
Sir, surely we...
Lieutenant...you must know that
every one of our beds is needed
for the injured and dying from
Arras.
Hm?
Corporal, I'll see you in my office.
Sir, I only meant to say that
Lieutenant Courtenay is depressed.
I will not leave wounded soldiers
freezing or sweating under canvas
because a junior officer is
depressed!
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
Yes? I thought you may want to know what I think.
Why should I?
Nurse Crawley, I may not be your
social superior in a Mayfair ballroom
but in this hospital I have the
deciding voice.
Please help him prepare his
belongings. He leaves in the morning.
Anna and Ethel will wait at the table.
I will supervise. What's wrong with that?
Nothing. Except that it's how a chartered
accountant has his dinner served.
I can think of worse insults. If you
say so.
But I don't want Lang allowed
anywhere near it.
Oh, Mr Bates. Where are you when we
need you?
Can you bring me the wine ledgers and
I'll make a selection?
His lordship's already done that.
Just try to rest.
To rest or to feel redundant?
Both if it'll slow you down for a
minute and a half.
The world does not turn on the style
of a dinner.
My world does.
How does he know Miss Swire?
What? Miss Swire.
They were in the garden when I came
back from Mama's.
I suppose they met in London.
Would you like me to come back
later, my lady? No, come in.
I was just leaving.
How's Carson getting on? Oh, much
better, my lady.
Mrs Hughes is having a job keeping
him in bed.
He gave me some advice last night.
Oh, yes?
Was it good advice?
It was about honesty.
He thinks I should say what I really
feel.
Sounds a bit wild for Mr Carson.
Do you think he's right?
Well, they do say honesty is the
best policy.
And I think you regret being honest
less often than you regret telling
lies.
He must have smuggled a razor into
his bed.
There was nothing to be done.
It's because we ordered him to go.
We don't know that.
This is a tragedy, I don't deny it.
But I cannot see what other course
was open to me.
We have no room for men to
convalesce
and Farley is the nearest house I
can send them to.
There is a solution and it's staring
us in the face.
Downton Abbey. Would they ever allow
it?
Or even consider it? I think they
would.
After this I think they can be made
to.
(TRAIN WHISTLE HOOTS)
But, Sir Richard, you don't have to
Richard, please.
You see, I want you to marry me.
Why?
Because I think very highly of you.
Very highly...goodness.
I mean it. I think we'd do well
together.
We could be a good team.
Now, that sounds better.
But I can't help thinking
that tradition demands a little
mention of love.
Oh, I can talk about love and moon
and June
and all the rest of it if you wish.
But we're more than that.
We're strong and sharp.
And we can build something worth
having, you and I, if you'll let us.
Your proposal is improving by leaps
and bounds.
(HISS OF STEAM)
You must give me some time.
But I promise to think about it
properly.
I'm counting on it.
If you just go to that one over
there.
You're right here. Right to the
other end. Down you go.
Her ladyship had Mrs Patmore make
this up for you
so you could eat something during
the day.
Dr Clarkson. Good morning.
Oh, Matthew.
I'm afraid I'm very busy, as you can
see. Yes, I just want to help.
Right over there.
Is it what you thought it would be?
No. No, it's more savage and more
cruel than I could have imagined but...
I feel useful for the first time in
my life. That must be a good thing.
Matthew, are you busy? No, of course
not.
I'll just get you on to your bed.
You're quite safe.
So you wouldn't go back...
to your life before the war?
No. No, I could never go back to
that again.
(CHURCH CLOCK CHIMES)
(SNIFFS TEARFULLY)
Lavinia.
What's the matter?
Are you looking for Matthew?
I was...but it's not important.
(SNIFFS TEARFULLY)
Tell me what it is...please.
He has to go a day early. Tomorrow
morning, in fact.
Only to meet his general, surely.
Not back to France.
But he must go back one day.
I can't imagine what I'd do if
anything happened to him.
I know he'll be all right.
No, you don't. None of us do.
We say that sort of thing but we
don't know.
If he died I don't think I could go
on living.
What's doing?
Excuse me.
(SNIFFS TEARFULLY)
Lavinia's a bit upset.
She's awfully cut up that I have to
go early.
But it's only to Coventry - which
doesn't sound too dangerous.
If you're looking for mother she's
at the hospital.
Actually it's you I came to see. Oh?
How can I help?
Mary, can you stay for luncheon?
I can't...but thank you.
So what was your mission?
Just to say...
we hope you're still coming for
dinner tonight.
Certainly we are. Why wouldn't we?
Sure? It'll be your last evening.
Why? Don't you want me? Of course I
want you...very much.
I'm sorry you've had a wasted
journey. Not at all.
I needed an excuse for a walk.
I'll see you at eight.
Ethel said you wanted me. No, no, I
just need a word with you.
If it's about the book I'm afraid -
It's not about the book.
What is it then?
I understand that Mr Bates has
gone...for good.
Yes, I believe that's true.
So I was hoping...
we might be able to see a little
more of each other.
Mr Molesley...
I take this as a real
compliment...
But it's not going to happen.
No.
You see...
if you had a child and that child
was taken from you,
if the child was sent to the moon,
there'd never be one day when they
were out of your thoughts,
no moment when you weren't praying
for their welfare,
even if you knew you'd never see
them again.
That's you and Mr Bates.
That's me and Mr Bates.
But thank you.
I've kept you too long. You should
get back or they'll be looking for you.
We've done a lot, haven't we? We
have.
I'll have to invent some tasks or they'll
be no need for you to come much more.
Then start inventing, please.
I will.
Cos I'd hate it if you were to stay
away.
So would I.
I'd absolutely hate it.
I can't believe I've done that. I'm
awfully glad you did.
You'll have me thrown in the tower.
Only if they give me the key.
Fold it in. Don't slap it.
You're making a cake not beating a
carpet.
Oh, sorry, Your Lordship, I didn't
see you there.
It's quite all right, Mrs Patmore.
I wonder, is there somewhere we could
have a word? Er...
Er... Why not go into my sitting
room?
Please sit.
I do have some news of your nephew.
I telephoned the War Office. They've just
come back to me but it's not good news.
I knew he was dead all along.
I said so to my sister. I said, 'Kate,
he's gone and you'll have to fa -
Mrs Patmore, it's worse than that.
What can be worse than being dead?
Private Philpotts was shot for
cowardice on 17 February.
Oh, my God.
This explains why the regiment was
reluctant to supply information.
(SOBS)
Mrs Hughes, could you come in,
please?
Mrs Patmore has had some bad news.
Her nephew has been killed.
Oh, he never has? And that's not
all.
It is all, Mrs Patmore.
Let us make sure it is all.
Your sister needs to know no more
than this.
We cannot know the truth. We should
not judge.
I think it's a ridiculous idea.
Why? Because this is a house not a
hospital.
Granny, a convalescent home is where
people rest and recuperate.
But if there are relapses, what
then?
Amputation in the dining room?
Resuscitation in the pantry?
It would be the most tremendous
disturbance.
If you knew how chaotic things are
as it is.
But when so much good can be done.
I forbid it.
To have strange men prodding and
prying around the house.
To say nothing of pocketing the
spoons.
It's out of the question. I hesitate
to remind you
but this is my house, Robert's and
mine, and we will make the decision.
Oh, I see.
So now I'm an outsider...who need
not be consulted.
Since you put it like that, yes.
What was it like at the hospital
today?
At the front...
the men pray to be spared, of
course.
But if that's not to be...
they pray for a bullet that kills
them cleanly.
For too many of them today that
prayer had not been answered.
We'll eat in about 20 minutes.
Good. And would you have any to
spare for a poor traveller?
William, I don't believe it. Pinch
me. I am your dream come true.
You're like a real soldier. I am a
real soldier, thank you very much.
Now come and give me a kiss. Ooh.
We'll have none of that. Won't you
let a tommy kiss his sweetheart,
when he's off to fight the Hun? Have
you finished your training?
Not yet but it won't be long. On the
eve of departure we'll see
but right now put her down.
I'll show you.
What do you think? There. Smart, in't
it?
William? What a treat to see you.
And how smart you look.
Welcome. Thanks. Supper won't be
long.
I'm just clearing the dining room.
Shall I help?
Course not. You're in the army now.
So, still full of the joys of war
then?
I'm not sorry to be part of it, Mr
Lang, and I can't pretend I am.
Oh, yes, you're part of it.
Like a metal cog is part of a
factory.
Or a grain of sand is part of the
beach.
It's all right, Mr Lang. I
understand.
And I'm not saying I'm important or
owt like that.
But I believe in this war.
I believe in what we're fighting for
and I want to do my bit.
Then God help you.
(LOW CONVERSATION)
Edith seems jolly tonight.
She's found her metier - farm
labouring.
Don't be so tough on her.
That's like asking the fox to spare
the chicken.
What about you? Last time you told
me good news was imminent.
Would you be happy if it were? Of
course.
I've found someone now and I want
you to do the same.
If you'd taken another minute to
make up your mind,
we'd all have marched over the cliff.
I'll tell you something else as
well...
William's got more to say than a
parliamentary candidate.
What's the matter? I know it's my
fault...
but I wish I hadn't let him think
that we're like sweethearts.
Because we're not. Not by my
reckoning, anyway.
Too late for second thoughts now,
missy.
You don't have to marry him when it
comes to it
but you can't let him go to war with
a broken heart
or he won't come back.
What a time we've had.
Poor Sir Richard must have thought
he'd come to a madhouse.
I don't expect it'll put him off.
I'm going to accept him.
Do you think I should?
That's not for me to say.
If you love him more than anyone in
the world then of course you should.
It's not as simple as that. Oh?
It is for me.
But then I'm not your ladyship.
Did you love Bates more than anyone
else in the world?
I did.
I do.
I'll never love again like I love
him.
Ever.
Well, there you are then.
One day you'll meet someone else and
you'll marry.
Perhaps it'll be second best but...
it doesn't mean you can't have a life.
I think it does... for me.
Are you sure you should be doing this?
We've managed well with Mrs Hughes.
Quite sure, my lord.
And breakfast is not a taxing
assignment.
Edith, this is a message for you. Mrs Drake
writes that they've decided to hire a man
so they won't be needing you any
more.
Is that all she says? Oh, well,
she's very grateful.
Here. She says she and Drake send
their thanks to you
for giving up so much of your
valuable time.
I expect it's rather a relief.
Oh, I wouldn't say that...
not entirely. Has Lady Sybil gone
already?
She had a tray at half past six. She
would.
Carson, did you know we're to be
turned into a hospital?
A convalescent home.
I'm afraid we've all bullied you
into the whole thing.
I hope you're not dreading it too
much.
Not exactly but it's a brave new world
we're headed for, no doubt about that.
We just try to meet it with as much
grace as we can muster.
I thought I saw Mr Bates. Isn't he
in London?
Thomas, the footman, managing
Downton Abbey?
Give orders for the beds, the nurses
and the patients
to be packed up and shipped out at
once!
Do you remember when Aunt Rosamund
found you and Richard Carlisle in
the garden?
I hope you didn't unearth anything
too fearful. Ask Mary.
I'll get them one way or another.
There's no need to be so rough.
There's every need... to stop a
murder.
Are we engaged?
It's not against the law
to take a mistress. I know
you and I love you. That is
not the right path for you.
Sync and corrected by
www.MY-SUBS.com