WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Last June...
saw Emily Davison...
crushed to death beneath the hooves
of the king's horse!
Will the summer of 1914
prove as fatal
for the hopes of women?
It cannot!
This historic by-election...
..has been a first step
on the journey to women's equality.
If you're so keen on women's rights,
let a woman speak!
Why stop there? Let's get the dogs
up and listen to them bark
We are winning! Winning!
You all right, My Lady?
Isn't it exciting?
You're an idiot, man!
I think it's time
for Branson to take you home.
Not yet.
I think so.
I applaud your spirit in coming and I
will applaud your discretion when you go.
But you agree with everything
he says. I do, my dear.
But I also know, if anything happens
to you, Branson will lose his place.
Better safe than sorry, My Lady.
..is an act of mercy. I disagree!
The car is just here.
Women must get the vote,
mustn't they, Branson?
Why does the prime minister
resist the inevitable?
Politicians can't often recognise
the changes that are inevitable.
I hope you do go into politics.
It's a fine ambition.
Ambition, or dream?
If I do...
it's not all about women and the vote,
for me. Nor even freedom for Ireland.
It's the gap between
the aristocracy and the poor and...
And what?
I'm sorry.
I don't mean to speak against
His Lordship.
Why not?
You obviously don't approve of him.
Not as a representative
of an oppressive class.
But he's a good man.
And a decent employer.
Spoken like a true politician.
What do I look like?
Could you sneak me round the back?
I should hate for Papa
to see me like this.
Where? I'm not a mind reader!
Mrs Patmore is very cruel
to that poor girl.
Mrs Patmore is frightened.
Is she right to be? Dr Clarkson
has confirmed she has cataracts.
What can be done about it?
There are treatments.
But even the best are uncertain.
She doesn't want to risk
losing what sight she still has.
I don't blame her.
But it can't go on for ever.
No.
Oh, dear.
Have you had bad news?
I shouldn't have bothered you.
No.
You weren't to know.
Oh!
Excuse me, My Lady.
William, will you find Anna
and tell her I've gone upstairs?
Very good, My Lady.
Ooh, sorry.
You clumsy clodhopper!
Sorry.
You will be when I'm done with you.
Leave him alone.
Anna? Lady Sybil's back from Ripon.
She's gone up to her room.
Thank you.
Why does she waste
her precious time on politics?
Hear, hear! Don't you believe in
rights for women, Thomas?
What's it to you? Well, I know you
don't believe in rights of property.
Some people might find that
interesting.
Who's going to tell them? You?
Mr Carson? Are you all right?
Why shouldn't I be?
You never rung the dressing gong.
And Mrs Patmore's
doing a souffle
for the first course.
Oh, my God!
Rather unlike Carson.
We'd better go straight into dinner.
I shall tell Miss O'Brien and Anna.
Any more news of the by-election?
Mr Crawley was here. He said his mother
had gone to the Liberal rally in Ripon.
I heard it was...quite lively.
I daresay the townies will make the usual
stink when the Tory candidate's returned.
I'm not sure. I heard the Liberal
was given a hard time today.
Mr Branson said it was
getting out of hand when they left.
Typical Branson to be there.
I hope he squared it with Carson.
Who went with him?
Er...
Not sure anyone went with him, sir.
You said 'they.' Who was with him?
I'd rather not say.
Bates? Who was with him?
Lady Sybil.
Lady Sybil?! Why?
I should never have mentioned it,
My Lord. I thought you knew.
No. I did not know.
I gather you went to hear
the Liberal candidate today.
There were several speakers,
actually. He was the last.
Did he speak well?
I thought so.
There was quite a brouhaha.
You know what these things
can be like. I do.
Hence my astonishment you should not feel
it necessary to ask my permission to attend!
I assume this was Branson's scheme.
No. I confess,
I was amused to have an Irish
radical as a chauffeur.
But I see now I've been naive!
I told Branson to take Sybil.
What are you saying?!
Sybil needed to go to Ripon.
I asked Branson to drive her.
I thought it would be sensible.
In case there was trouble.
I want to do some canvassing.
The by-election isn't far off.
Canvassing?
Oh, it's quite safe. You're in
a group and you knock on doors.
Yes, I know what canvassing is.
I think that Sybil is -
What? Are you canvassing too?
Or would you rather
take in washing
I was only going to say that Sybil
is entitled to her opinions. No.
She isn't until she is married.
Then her husband will tell her
what her opinions are.
Oh, Granny! I knew you wouldn't
approve. Which, presumably,
is why you all hid your plans
from me.
Her Ladyship'll have a smacked
bottom if she's not careful. Hurry up.
I don't want anything else
to go wrong.
Where's the sauce?
Doesn't this have Hollandaise?
I'll get it. I won't be a jiffy.
Would you do that for me?
I'd do anything for you.
Does this mean you won't be
presented next month?
Certainly not. Why should it?
Well, I doubt I'd expect to
curtsey to their majesties in June
when I'd been arrested
at a riot in May.
But then, I'm old.
Things may be different now.
She hasn't been arrested
and it wasn't a riot.
But it might be next time.
There will not be a next time.
Her Ladyship's not best pleased
at being told off in public.
William said
she was looking daggers.
I'm sorry I started all this.
Oh, it's not your fault.
He ought to be glad
he's got a daughter who cares.
Her Ladyship's ready to leave.
I'll bring the car round.
You pleased with yourself
Silly chump.
He's nervous. He thinks I'm planning
to tell Mr Carson about the wine.
Well, he shouldn't have stolen it,
then.
No.
But I don't want anyone
to lose their job because of me.
Even Thomas?
Even after
what they tried to do to you?
Even then.
Your Ladyship. Do you have a moment?
Of course.
I have received a letter, My Lady.
From a friend of mine. He's valet
to the Marquess of Flintshire.
I don't envy him. Lord Flintshire
is a minister at the Foreign Office.
As you know, Lady Flintshire
is His Lordship's cousin.
Oh, of course, of course.
The point is,
he has dealings with
the Turkish Ambassador.
It seems His Excellency has made him
privy to a scurrilous story
concerning Lady Mary and the late...
Mr Pamuk.
May I read this letter?
Is there anything
you want me to do about it?
No. Thank you.
Sometimes, even to deny these things is
only to throw paraffin onto the flames.
I did try to inform His Lordship.
What?
But I...couldn't seem to find
the right moment.
Quite right.
Please leave His Lordship to me.
I'm sorry. The only sure way
to get rid of a servant
is to have him or her
suspected of stealing.
We've tried that,
and it didn't work.
But last time, we invented a theft.
We need to make him a suspect when
something's really been stolen.
How do we know anything's been
stolen? Because you stole it.
You noodle!
You mean the wine? Yeah. The wine.
But Bates knows I took it. He was
threatening to tell Mr Carson.
Well, he can't, can he?
Not if we get in first.
Are you telling me
you saw him take the cellar key?
Not exactly. But I saw him in here.
And I thought
the key was swinging on its hook.
I just wondered if
any of the wine was missing.
I think I owe you an apology
after the way I spoke at dinner.
Next time you want to treat me
like a naughty schoolgirl,
you might do it in private,
not in front of the servants.
You're right. I'm sorry. Course, it gave
your mother her best evening since Christmas.
Even so, we must try
to keep control of Sybil.
Robert.
Believe me, Sybil...
is not your problem.
We've got to support Mary this year,
when we get to London.
But it's Sybil's first season.
We can't have Mary
stealing her thunder.
Sybil will do well enough.
It's time Mary was settled.
High time.
Poor old Edith.
We never seem to talk about her.
I'm afraid Edith will be the one
to care for us in our old age.
What a ghastly prospect?
Mamma? Anna said you wanted me.
Look who's paid us a visit.
Sir Anthony!
How nice.
We all thought we'd driven you away
with that horrible salty pudding.
No, indeed.
But I have been away.
He's been in Austria and Germany.
How interesting.
Interesting and worrying.
Sir Anthony's here
to show you his new car.
Oh. Yes. I've rather taken to
driving myself.
I have to keep finding destinations
to justify it.
What kind of car is it?
It's an open Rolls Royce.
And I wondered if
you might like a spin in it.
Oh, how kind. But, alas, not today.
I've had Diamond saddled
and he's waiting for me.
You could ride this afternoon.
But it's arranged now.
But thank you, Sir Anthony.
Do ask me again.
I...don't suppose you'd take me.
Of course. I shall be delighted.
What is it that I'm accused of?
Oh...nobody's accusing you
of anything.
But there has been a suggestion
that you were handling
the cellar key.
And, before I take it any further,
I want to find
if there's a simple explanation.
Because some wine is missing.
How do you know that?
Right. Well.
We'll leave it there for now.
The Kaiser
is such a mercurial figure.
One minute the warlord...
the next a lovelorn poet.
But a poet in need of an empire.
That's very good.
Poet in need of an empire. Yes.
My late wife used to say that...
What did Lady Strallan used to say?
Oh, never mind.
But I should like to hear it.
Really?
Would you really?
She used to say that Kaiser Bill
loved uniforms and medals...
..but he never really
connected them with fighting.
What was she like?
Maud?
Oh, she was awfully funny.
Some people couldn't see it,
but she was.
Is Lynch anywhere about?
I haven't seen him, My Lady.
My horse is lame.
Well, I could have a look at him.
Do you know about horses? I looked
after them on my father's farm.
It was the best job in the world.
Then why did you leave it?
My mother wanted me
to better myself.
As a second footman?
It's a good place for me, My Lady.
Of course it is. I'm sorry.
She hopes, one day, that
I might be first footman. Or even
get to be...
Carson had better watch out.
Stranger things happen at sea.
I've seen Mr Bates with a bottle
from time to time.
I must've thought
he was helping you.
Why would I order a valet
to help with the wine?
When you put it like that,
of course you wouldn't.
So. Mr Bates is taking wine.
And why would this be? To drink it?
It's not to clean his boots
Thank you, Thomas.
Daisy? Thomas says you have
something to add to this. Well...
You're not in any trouble,
or any danger of trouble.
You remember what you saw.
I may have seen him...
coming out of the cellar.
May.
Did you or didn't you?
It's very hard for the girl,
Mr Carson. You're frightening her.
I'm sorry.
Thank you. You may go.
Thank you, O'Brien.
How is everything downstairs?
All right, I think, My Lady.
Though Mr Carson's a bit cast down.
Oh? Why? What's the matter with him?
He's found out something about...
Well...a person he admires.
And it isn't very nice.
Has he said who this person is...
..who's proved a disappointment?
I don't like to say, My Lady.
Please do, if you know.
Oh, I know.
It's Mr Bates.
Oh, Bates? Why? What's he done?
You should ask Mr Carson, My Lady.
It's not my place to tell.
Papa.
Can...Branson drive me into Ripon...
on Friday evening?
I don't think so, no.
Not after the last time.
Oh, please. There's a meeting
of my borstal charity.
I've missed two,
and I simply must be there.
You'd have to take
Mary or Edith with you.
Don't make me. Those meetings
are deadly at the best of times.
And you know what they're like
when they're bored.
Why are all your causes
so steeped in gloom?
Because it's the gloomy things
that need our help.
If everything in the garden's
sunny...why meddle?
Well, I agree with that.
Talking of sunny, are you looking
forward to your coming season?
I am rather.
Hello. What are you doing here?
I'm in search of your father.
Carson thought he was outside.
He's in the library.
What is it? Nothing much. I've had
an enquiry about one of the farms.
Ah.
So.
What's new at the big house?
Oh. Sybil, mainly.
She's discovered politics, which,
of course, makes Papa see red.
I admire Sybil's passion, though.
Of course.
But then, I like a good argument.
Papa does not.
If you really like an argument...
Yes?
We should see more of each other.
So, it's all right? I can go?
Will you be late?
I think I'll miss dinner.
Well, remember
to tell Branson to take a sandwich
for himself.
But who's it from?
Susan Flintshire.
What does she say?
Well, prepare yourself for the worst.
Not the first page.
My poor niece never uses one word
when twenty will do.
Start there. 'I am sorry...'
'I am sorry to have to tell you
that Hugh has heard a vile story
about your granddaughter Mary.'
Sorry? She's thrilled
Now. First I must ask...
And I want you to think carefully
before you answer.
Is any of this true?
I see.
Some of it IS true.
How much?
Oh, dear.
She didn't drag him.
I wondered about that. Obviously,
Susan's forgotten...the distance
between the girls' rooms
and the bachelor's corridor.
She couldn't manage it alone.
So, how did she do it?
I helped her. She woke me up.
And I helped her.
Well...
I always thought...this family
might be approaching dissolution...
I didn't know dissolution
was already upon us.
Does Robert know?
No. And he isn't going to.
Oh.
Of course, it was terribly wrong. It was
all terribly wrong. But I didn't see wha-
Please.
I can't listen to your attempts
to try and justify yourself.
I know this is hard for you to hear.
God knows, it was
hard for me to live through.
But if you expect me
to disown my daughter...
..I'm afraid you will be
disappointed.
Good day.
I thought you must be out here.
And you'd be right.
I know you're upset.
Yes, I'm upset.
I've been working here two years.
And yet, Mr Carson has no difficulty
believing the worst of me.
I think he has
a great deal of difficulty.
Which is why he hasn't
told His Lordship yet.
Can't you just explain about Thomas?
No, no.
It would sound like
a false accusation.
You can't take it lying down.
Because you're not guilty
of any wrong.
And, before it's over,
I'm gonna tell the world.
Are you?
I'm not sure the world is listening.
Sorry. I'm a bit late tonight.
Not to worry. How are you?
Bearing up.
This isn't the end.
You mustn't give up.
We'll get there.
Forgive me, My Lady, but...
You don't get it.
You're brought up to think
it's all within your grasp.
That if you want something enough,
it will come to you.
Well, we're not like that.
We don't think our dreams
are bound to come true, because...
Because they almost never do.
Then, that's why we must
stick together.
Your dream is my dream now.
I'll make it come true.
Why hasn't he done anything?
He's had the story and the witnesses.
The witnesses?
What do you think this is?
A murder mystery?
Mr Bates can't accuse me now. It'll sound
as if he's trying to get his own back.
If I lose my job over this,
I swear to God, I'll swing for you.
Is there any stale bread
you're throwing out?
And some salt.
Why?
Well, I thought I'd make
a last hot poultice for Diamond.
It'll give him a better night.
You big softy.
What'll Mr Lynch say?
Oh, he doesn't mind.
He says I've got the touch.
He thinks I should pack this in
and be a groom. Why don't you?
My mum...
She was so excited when I came here.
They're proud of me,
and I'd hate to spoil that.
Do you miss 'em?
I never had that in my childhood.
Someone you could always trust.
Well, I trust them, they trust me.
There are no lies in our house.
Thanks. That's enough.
I'm glad to catch you.
We have a conundrum at the hospital,
and I would value your opinion.
Of course.
We've been treating...
the mother of your footman
William Mason.
What's the matter with her?
Heart, I'm afraid.
She's forbidden us to say anything
to her son. That's ridiculous.
She's gone home now,
but she's still very ill.
Clearly, the boy should
go and see her.
And I assume you would
have no objections? Course not.
So.
Do we break a patient's confidence
and disobey her orders...or not?
We can't...if she's forbidden it.
I must say, I agree with you.
Well, I'll tell him.
No. You will not.
She has rights, too.
And there are rules.
I don't care a fig about rules.
Where to from here, My Lady?
What do you mean? We've arrived?
The meeting's in this place?
This IS the meeting. We're here
for the counting of the votes.
I don't understand. I thought that -
Don't be silly, Branson. You didn't
think I'd miss my very first by-election.
His Lordship won't approve.
Let me worry about him.
I have to park the car. Don't move!
Stay where you are! Really!
I thought I gave the orders.
Sir Anthony Strallan.
Sir Anthony.
Don't worry.
I haven't got the date wrong.
What a relief. I could hear Cora
wondering if dinner would stretch
No, I'm not really here at all.
But I was driving past your gates
and I thought I'd take a chance.
See, the thing is, I've got two tickets
for a concert in York next Friday.
How nice. Although, I can't -
No.
I was hoping that Lady Edith
might like to accompany me.
But I'd love to. Shouldn't you
ask what sort of concert it is?
Oh, just Hungry Hundreds stuff,
mostly. You know.
Bellini, Puccini, Rossini.
I'm not up to anything complicated.
I...I'd like that very much.
Excellent. Well, it's quite a hike,
so I'll pick you up around six?
Lady Jervas has asked us for a bite to eat
after, if that's all right with your mother.
By all means.
Well, I must run.
I hope I haven't spoilt your dinner.
We may have to
hire a nurse after all
Oh, for heaven's sake hold it steady, if you
don't want to start again from the beginning.
Do these biscuits go up? No. I put
them out for the fairies Oh.
Of course they're going up!
What's wrong with you?
You're always dozy, but tonight
you make Sleeping Beauty look alert.
I was just thinking... Ooh, Blimey!
Batten down the hatches
I think I've let myself down.
It can't be a new sensation.
The Honourable Joseph Gerald Ansty...
..for the Conservative
and Unionist Party...
6,363 votes.
Votes for women! Votes for women!
Martin James Dillon,
the Socialist Party...
2,741 votes.
Call it a day, My Lady!
Don't be silly. This is the moment
we've come for.
Trevor Andrew Morgan,
the Liberal Party...
This lot aren't interested in votes.
They're spoiling for a fight!
..5,894 votes.
I hereby declare...
Come on.
Out you get, lads.
We'll soon wipe the smile off
their Tory bloody faces!
..is duly elected...to serve
as member of parliament...
..member of parliament... Sybil!
..for the Ripon constituency.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't miss this.
Couldn't you? I could!
I don't like the look of this,
My Lady!
Look. Look!
I'm on your side. Don't cause any
trouble. Believe me!
What's your problem, Mr Lah-di-dah?
My problem is you.
Oh, aye?
Oh, no. Oh, please, God, no!
This way!
I fetched a coat.
Why? What do I need a coat for?
I've come to fetch you, My Lady.
We've taken Lady Sybil
to Crawley House.
What's happened?
I took her to Ripon for the count.
She got injured in a fight.
Take me there at once.
My God!
Oh, my darling!
I didn't know what to do.
I had Branson bring her here.
Quite right. Mamma would have
fainted if she'd seen her like this.
As for Papa...
This will sting a bit.
But it's stopped bleeding.
Did you know she was planning this?
Of course not.
Well, what were you doing there?
Working late. I'd forgotten it was
election night, or I wouldn't have stayed.
I'm so grateful you did.
Oh, I could wring Branson's neck!
What was he thinking? I'm afraid
it'll cost him his job. No!
I told him he was taking me
to a committee meeting.
When he saw what it was,
he wanted to come straight back.
You'll have to stick up for him.
Because Papa will skin him alive.
Are you feeling strong enough
to go home?
I think so.
If you'll take me.
Here. Wear my coat
to cover the blood.
You'll look more normal.
Lean on me.
Thank you so much for this.
By the way.
How is William's mother?
Not good, I'm afraid. She's home,
but she's still very weak.
Another attack should finish her.
And he still doesn't know?
She's adamant. I've tried to explain
how hard it'll be on him.
But she won't have him disturbed.
To hear her talk, you'd think
he was a cabinet minister.
He's made her proud.
There are plenty of children in grander
circumstances who'd love to say the same.
I wish you'd tell me
what's troubling you.
If it's this business
with Mr Bates...
It's not that.
I'll get to the bottom of that.
Well, I hope you'll do it soon.
If there's one thing I hate,
it's an atmosphere.
And we've got a real atmosphere
going now.
It's an unfair rumour
which needs to be scotched.
It's very hard to hear
the names of people you love
dragged in the mud.
You feel so powerless.
Well. I...
respect Mr Bates, but...
I'm not sure that I love him.
I wasn't thinking of Mr Bates.
Mr Carson, have you got a minute?
What is it, Daisy?
Mr Carson's a very busy man.
I know he is.
But I think he'll want to hear this.
I told you something
that wasn't true.
Why would you do that?
I did it as a favour...
for a friend. But I know
now it was wrong to ask it of me.
She's not badly hurt, is she?
I don't think so, no.
Thank God.
Better be prepared. I'm afraid
Lord Grantham will hit the roof.
I never would've taken her there.
I may be a socialist,
but I'm not a lunatic.
I'm not sure Papa
knows the difference.
You'll let me know how she gets on?
Please.
If you wish.
How dare you? How DARE you
disobey me in this way?!
Robert. I'm sure -
Are you so knowledgeable...
Papa, I'm sorry I disobeyed you.
But I'm interested, I'm political,
I have opinions!
Of course, I blame Branson. I don't
think that's fair. We had none of this.
None of it!
Until he set foot in our house.
I suppose I should give thanks he hasn't
burnt the place down over our heads!
Branson knew nothing
until we arrived there.
He leaves tonight.
If you punish Branson, I'll never
speak to you again. Never!
I don't believe this is Branson's
fault. Truly, Papa. Blame me.
I do blame you!
Robert, can we do this
in the morning? Sybil needs rest.
But if I find tomorrow
that Branson is missing...
I'll run away, I warn you.
Oh! And where would you go?
Well, I can't think now.
But I will go. And you'll be sorry.
I should be sorry. Very sorry indeed.
How is she?
She'll be perfectly fine. I gather
you're the shining knight in all this.
Not really. But I'm glad
I was there. So am I, by heaven.
If it had been left to
that bloody fool Branson...
You should see what he reads.
It's all Marx and Ruskin
and John Stuart Mill. I ask you.
Papa prefers
the servants to read the Bible
and letters from home
There are sandwiches for Mr Crawley
in the dining room, Lady Mary.
Thank you, Mrs Hughes.
We couldn't let you starve.
You really didn't have to.
Mary, you look after Matthew.
I'll go up and revive your mother.
Do you stand by your story?
I don't have a story. You saw Mr Bates
in here alone, hanging up the cellar key.
To me, that is a story. I only said I
might have seen him. I suppose I was wrong.
And Miss O'Brien. Were you then wrong when
you thought you saw Mr Bates carrying a bottle?
You wicked creature!
Anna.
You are here to watch,
not to participate.
I don't think I was wrong, no.
What do you say to that, Mr Bates?
I know this to be untrue
because I have no need of it.
Since I arrived at Downton...
you have never seen me...
drink one drop of alcohol.
Let us say, then,
that Miss O'Brien was...mistaken.
Mistaken, my eye!
And Daisy, we all know the value
of your contribution. Yes, Mr Carson.
But I must ask one thing, Mr Bates.
How did you know
the wine had been taken?
I'm afraid I cannot answer that.
We can drink to Sybil's safe return.
Why not?
I'll ring for a glass.
No, never mind that.
Here.
You're not very fastidious about
doing things properly, are you?
Are you?
Less than you might think.
Are you at all political?
Yes.
But with a hung parliament, it's hard
to get excited about a by-election.
You know, nothing will change...
whoever gets in.
If I might keep you for a minute
more, Mr Carson...
If you'd like me to leave... No. I
would like you to stay, Mrs Hughes.
And you, Anna.
You have decided...
not to take action over the
allegations Thomas has made against me
because you believe them
to be untrue.
That is correct. And you are right.
There is no truth in them.
But, if you were to proceed with the
matter, you would find them to be proven.
Thomas has tried to convince you
that I am a drunkard and a thief.
Which we never believed.
Because you know no different.
Until a couple of years ago,
I was a drunkard.
And I was imprisoned...as a thief.
I have...
repaid your kindness...very poorly.
I masqueraded as a man of...honour.
And integrity.
But, by any moral code...
I am disgraced.
That can't be the whole story.
Perhaps not.
But it's enough of it to demand...
..my resignation.
Do you want to leave, Mr Bates?
No. But I feel I have no choice.
You owe me a say in the matter,
surely?
If you wish.
Then I will consider the case
and give you my decision when I have
discussed it with His Lordship.
Until then, I hope
you will remain in your post.
Thank you for
coming to Sybil's rescue.
You were very brave.
She told me you knocked a man down.
I hope I did my duty.
Are you a creature of duty?
Not entirely.
When you laugh with me or...
flirt with me...
is that a duty?
Are you conforming
to the fitness of things?
Doing what's expected?
Don't play with me.
I don't deserve it. Not from you.
You must be careful
not to break Sybil's heart.
I think she has a crush on you.
Well, that's something
no-one could accuse you of.
Oh, I don't know.
I assume you speak
in a spirit of mockery.
You should have more faith.
Shall I remind you
of some of the choicest remarks
you made about me
when I arrived here?
Because they live in my memory.
As fresh as the day
they were spoken.
Oh, Matthew.
What am I always telling you?
You must pay no attention
to the things I say.
Mr Bates.
Anna.
Will you really leave?
I doubt His Lordship
wants a thief in the house.
Now, go to sleep...
and dream of a better man.
I can't.
Because there isn't one.
Has Matthew gone?
Yes.
Thank the Lord he was there.
I hope you thanked Matthew properly.
I got them to make him
some sandwiches.
That's not quite what I meant.
And he asked me to marry him.
Heavens! What did they
put in them I'm serious.
He proposed to me.
Oh, my dear!
Have you given him an answer?
Only that I'd think about it.
Well...
That's an advance on what
it would've been a year ago.
Do you want to marry him?
I know you want me to marry him.
What we want doesn't matter.
At least, it's not all that matters.
Do you love Matthew?
Yes.
I think perhaps I do.
I think I may have loved him
for much longer than I knew.
Oh, my darling!
Let's not pretend this isn't the
answer to every one of our prayers.
I'd have to tell him.
Oh.
Is it absolutely necessary?
If I didn't, I'd feel as if
I'd caught him with a lie.
I hope you know that really smart
people sleep in separate rooms.
I always keep the bed made up
in the dressing room.
So at least I pretend
we sleep apart. Isn't that enough?
No. Never mind.
Goodnight.
Oh. Haven't you gone up yet?
Blow this out. You're the last.
Goodnight.
I'm gonna bloody get him.
I don't care what you say.
What would I say?
Everything comes to him who waits.
And I've waited long enough.
Does Carson know you're here?
I heard you were going out.
I wanted to see how he was walking.
Lynch is happy for me to ride him.
Oh, yes. He's better. But I'll wait
and see what he's like when you're up.
William, are you planning
to go home soon?
Well, it's a bit far
for my half day.
But I can maybe get the time in
July, when the family's in London.
That's if I don't go with you,
of course.
I think you should take a few
days off and go now. I'll fix it.
I'll speak to Father and to Carson.
No-one will mind.
But why, My Lady?
Your mother's not been well.
How do you know? I heard someone
mention it in the village. I forget who.
I had a letter, and she never said.
Oh, I'm sure it's nothing.
I know it will cheer her to see you.
Well...if it wouldn't be a bother.
It won't. I'll arrange it
as soon as I get back.
Thank you very much, My Lady.
She ought to spend some time
with the people she loves.
The Dowager Countess, My Lady.
Good afternoon, my dear.
Good afternoon.
There's no need to be so prim.
I come in peace.
Shall I sit here?
Now, I've been thinking.
I confess I do not know
if I would have had the strength,
mentally or physically...
..to carry a corpse...
the length of this house.
But I hope I would've done.
You were quite right.
When something bad happens...
there's no point
in wishing it had not happened.
The only option
is to minimise the damage.
Or try to.
But if the Flintshires
have got hold of it -
I've written to Susan.
I said it was a story
made up by Mr Pamuk's enemies
to discredit him.
Even if she doesn't believe me,
she won't tell,
in case it reflects badly on her.
The ambassador...is dangerous.
But then...how many people
really go to the Turkish Embassy?
It only takes one.
Well...
That just can't be helped.
We can't have him assassinated...
I suppose.
Robert still doesn't suspect.
Oh, I should hope not.
No. Our only way forward...
is to get Mary settled
as soon as possible.
I have news on that score.
Matthew has proposed.
My, my!
Has she said yes?
She hasn't said anything yet,
except that she's going to have to
tell him about Pamuk.
For heaven's sake! Why?
She thinks to keep it secret
would be dishonourable.
She reads too many novels.
I mean, one way or another,
everyone goes down the aisle
with half the story hidden.
The question is...
will she accept Matthew?
I'm not sure.
Well, if she doesn't,
we'll just have to take her abroad.
In these moments...
you can normally find an Italian
who isn't too picky.
We'll give her till the start
of the grouse. Very well.
If she turns Matthew down, we'll
take her to Rome in the autumn.
It's official.
Thank you for
not turning against her.
I know that you have rules and, when people
break them, you find it hard to forgive.
I understand that...
and I respect it.
In this case,
Mary has the trump card.
What?
Mary is family.
Unusual, obviously.
Unusual? It's biblical.
Not quite.
If she won't say yes
when he might be poor,
he won't want her
when he will be rich.
Do you love me enough
to spend your life with me?
There's a war coming.
And war means change.
itfc subtitles