WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
That's the last of the equipment
gone.
The maids have put the drawing room
back to normal.
I'm walking down to the village.
I want to have a word with Travis.
Richard will be here any moment.
That's why I'm telling you. Give him
my excuses. I'll see him at dinner.
Is there any news on
the Bates situation?
Not that I'm aware of.
So you still want to keep him on?
Cora, Bates's wife has committed
suicide. It's very sad, of course,
but not, when I last looked,
a reason to sack him.
They've taken the rest of the beds.
So that's the finish of it.
Not quite. We still have Matthew.
And I wanted to ask you,
isn't it time he went home?
I see. You want to throw him out.
Robert. I want him to learn to be
as independent as he can.
And I want Mary to get on with her
life. What's wrong with that?
Is there something you're not
telling me? What do you mean?
About Mary. And Matthew.
Some element you haven't told me?
Of course not. You're being silly.
If thinking that trying
to protect Mary with a
ring of steel is silly,
then yes, I am very silly.
You shouldn't be doing that.
Let us hope the end of the war brings
the return of the footman, Mr Crawley.
Do you think they will return?
I certainly hope so.
I'm sure Sir Richard can buy you
a dozen when you get to Haxby.
Let me.
No, m'lord. I can manage.
The handle broke.
Aren't we feeding you? They're from
my mother's apple store.
She always loads me up.
How's your boy doing? Freddie?
Yes, Freddie. He's doing very well.
I wrote to the headmaster of Ripon
Grammar. I said to look out for him.
That, that's so kind, m'lord.
I hope it works. I don't see why it
should, but you never know.
I suppose you miss your husband very
much?
Of course.
But I have Freddie...
and when you think of what some
families have gone through. I know.
Almost 30 dead on this estate alone.
And the Elcots down at Longway
lost three out of four sons.
Mrs Carter's only boy was killed
a month before the end of the war.
Do you ever wonder
what it was all for?
I'd better go in, m'lord.
The train was late.
Welcome to the new world.
When a war is over,
the first emotion is relief.
The second, disappointment.
How sad.
But how true.
Come in and have some tea.
Will you miss the extra staff,
Mrs Patmore?
Not really. When push comes to shove,
I'd rather do it myself.
Though God knows what I'm to feed
them on.
There's nothing out there to be had.
Well.
The Lord tempers the wind
to the shorn lamb.
What about you, Thomas?
How much longer will you stay?
Well, now the last of the invalids
have gone, I suppose I'm finished.
I'll report to Major Clarkson,
but he won't be taking anyone on.
I suppose the hospital will revert
to the way it was before the war.
Where will you go?
What's it to you?
I'll tell you where I'm going.
Into business. It's all set up.
Do you mean black market business?
Don't look so surprised.
I've found a dealer
and as soon as I make
the payment, I'll
have the supplies.
Where will you keep them?
I've got a shed in the village
and I'll get a banger
to deliver the stuff.
I'll be well fixed as soon as word
gets out. You heard her.
There are shortages all around.
Isn't it dangerous?
I don't think so.
I don't think the police are bothered
about rationing, now the war's over.
It won't last forever
but by the time it's done,
I should have enough
to go into business, properly.
So that's your future settled
as a plutocrat.
In the meantime, have you found
somewhere to live?
Not yet, but there's no hurry.
I'm sure they won't object
if I stop here for a week or two.
I shouldn't bet on it.
I nearly put out
the new dinner jacket, m'lord,
but then Mr Carson said the Dowager
was dining here. Quite right.
Mustn't frighten the horses.
By the way, her ladyship was asking if
there was any more news about Mrs Bates.
I don't think so, m'lord.
They'd like to know why she did it,
but I don't suppose we ever shall.
You'd think she'd leave a note.
Perhaps it was a spur of the moment
decision. It can't have been.
Wouldn't she have to get hold
of the stuff?
Please forgive me. I was thinking
aloud. We'll drop the subject.
Anna.
It is Anna, isn't it?
Yes sir.
I want to ask a favour of you.
Of me, Sir Richard.
You. I've been waiting for you.
I wonder if you could step into
my room for a moment.
You attend Lady Mary
and her sisters... don't you?
In addition to your other duties.
I do, sir, yes.
You must be kept very busy.
I hope it's worth your while.
Because I would be very willing
to increase your stipend.
If this is about coming with
Lady Mary when you marry,
it's very good of you, sir,
but you see,
my fiance, Mr Bates, works here
and I don't think I...
No, it's not that.
Although it's a pity.
Lady Mary's very fond of you.
That's kind.
You see...
I'm anxious to make Lady Mary happy.
Of course you are, sir. And to that
end, I feel I need to know
a great deal more about her
than I do.
Our customs are so strange
in this country.
A couple is hardly
allowed a moment alone
together before they
walk down the aisle.
I'm not sure I understand, sir.
I'd like to know more
about her interests.
Where she goes, whom she sees.
What she says to them.
Excuse me, sir. Do you mean
you want me to give you
a report of Lady Mary's actions?
It will be extra work,
but I'm happy to pay.
I'm sure.
But I'm afraid I wouldn't have
the time. Thank you, sir.
It's your choice, of course.
I'd be grateful if you didn't
mention this to Lady Mary.
I wouldn't want her to think I was
checking up on her.
I nearly came down in a dinner jacket
tonight.
Really? Well, why not a dressing
gown?
Or better still, pyjamas?
That's why I didn't.
I like the new fashions.
Shorter skirts, looser cuts.
The old clothes were all very well
if one spent the day
on a chaise longue, but if one
wants to get anything done,
the new clothes are much better.
I'll stick to the chaise longue.
Granny, you don't want things to go
back to the way they were, surely?
Of course I do,
and as quickly as possible.
What about you, Papa?
Before the war,
I believed my life had value.
I suppose I should like
to feel that again.
Have you seen the boys' haircuts
the women are wearing in Paris?
I hope you won't try that.
I might.
I'm not sure how feminine it is.
I'm not sure how feminine I am.
Very, I'm glad to say.
Carson, I keep forgetting
to tell Mrs Hughes
we've had a letter from
Major Bryant's mother.
She and her husband are in Yorkshire
on Friday
and she wants to pay us a visit.
Why?
The last time they saw him alive,
it was here. I can understand.
Will they be staying, my lady?
No, but we'll give them luncheon.
That way they can talk about the
Major with all of us who knew him.
That lets me out, thank heaven.
You look very fine.
Everything I own is from my season
before the war.
I'm trying to wear them out.
Where have you been all day?
Nowhere. I've just been busy.
I envy you.
I feel so flat after the rush and
bustle of the last two years.
They were sighing for the old days
at dinner,
but all I could think
about was how much
more I want from life
now than I did then.
Does this mean that you've made up
your mind, at last?
No, not quite, but almost.
What do you mean,
'how did she say it?'
Mr and Mrs Bryant are coming
for luncheon on Friday.
How are things over at Haxby?
Pretty good.
Building materials
are in short supply,
but Sir Richard knows
how to get around that.
I bet he does.
Well, you should see some of the
gadgets in the kitchens.
And the bathrooms - oh, goodness me!
They're like something out of a film
with Theda Bara.
I'm surprised you know
who Theda Bara is.
I get about, Mrs Hughes,
I get about.
But will you be happy there?
That's what I want to be sure of.
If you're asking whether
I'll regret leaving Downton...
I will regret it
every minute of every day.
I thought I would die here...
and haunt it ever after.
Well, then!
You see, I think I can help her.
In those early years when it's
important to get it right.
And if I can help her... then I must.
I wish I could understand.
To me, Lady Mary is an uppity minx
who's the author of her own
misfortunes.
You didn't know her
when she was a child, Mrs Hughes.
She was a guinea a minute then.
I remember once she came in here,
she can't have been more than
four or five years old.
She said, 'Mr Carson,
I've decided to run away
and I wonder if I might take
some of the silver to sell.'
'Well, ' I said, 'that could be
awkward for his Lordship.
Suppose I give you sixpence to spend
in the village instead?'
'Very well, ' says she. 'But you must
be sure to charge me interest.'
And did you?
She gave me a kiss in full payment.
Then she had the better bargain.
I wouldn't say that.
There you are, Mrs Hughes.
They said you were in here.
Might I have a word?
Of course. Shall we go to my room?
There's no reason Mr Carson
shouldn't hear it.
In fact, I think he probably should.
You see, I've had a request from Sir
Richard that you ought to know about.
You've done this before.
Bates, can I ask you something?
If I started to feel a tingling
in my legs,
what do you think that might mean?
Have you told Dr Clarkson?
Yes, he says it's an illusion.
Memory of a tingling or something.
But, I mean,
I do know my back is broken.
I understand that I won't recover,
but...
I do keep feeling it.
Or I think I do.
I should wait and see.
If something is changing,
it will make itself known.
Now will that be all?
Yes, thank you.
Bates...
Please don't tell anyone.
I couldn't bear it if Miss Swire
or mother or...
or anyone started to hope.
I won't say a thing.
Good night, sir.
Morning.
I don't know why I'm doing this.
I must be out of my mind.
Because you know it's my last chance.
That's true. They won't be back.
Not after this trip.
So what should I do?
Come to the house. But stay outside
in the game larder.
I'll leave some food there
and a blanket,
and then I'll try and find a moment
alone with Mrs Bryant
and tell her about little Charlie.
And then, if she asks -
only if she asks, mind you...
I'll bring her out to see the child.
What about him?
If either of them are in the least
interested, it'll be the mother.
And do you think she'll help me?
She might.
Suppose she won't see him.
Then you're no worse off than you
are already.
Look, I shouldn't be doing it.
So if you're not keen,
then for heaven's sake
let's forget all about it. No...
I'll be there. I promise.
Doesn't it feel odd
to have the rooms back?
And only us to sit in them.
I suppose we'll get used to it.
I don't want to get used to it.
What do you mean?
I know what it is to work now.
To have a full day.
To be tired in a good way.
I don't want to start dress fittings
or paying calls,
or standing behind the guns.
But how does one escape all that?
I think I've found a way to escape.
Nothing too drastic, I hope.
It is drastic. There's no going back
once I've done it.
But that's what I want.
No going back.
I don't want to go back, either.
Then don't.
You're far nicer than you were before
the war, you know.
Where did you get it all?
I told you. This bloke from Leeds.
Where did he get it?
Some's army surplus,
some's from America.
And Ireland. Everywhere.
He's got contacts all over.
That's what I'm paying him for.
How much have you paid him?
A lot.
But I'm not worried.
I've taken nothing perishable.
This lot will last for months.
I'll be sold out
long before any of it's gone off.
Starting with Mrs Patmore.
But Carson if you're abandoning me,
I think I deserve to know
the reason why.
I do not believe that Sir Richard
and I would work well together.
But there must be more to it
than that.
You knew what Sir Richard was like.
We were to educate him, together,
you and I. Wasn't that the plan?
Sir Richard offered Anna
a sum of money
to report your activities to him.
Whom you saw, what you said.
He wanted her to spy on me?
Naturally he used a different word.
Naturally.
And she refused?
She refused and she reported the
offer to Mrs Hughes and me.
Well, I wish she'd come to me first.
So you mean you'd be uncomfortable?
Working for a spymaster?
How disappointing of you.
And I always thought
you were fond of me.
There you are.
What about a quick walk before
dinner? We ought to change first.
Will that be all, my lady?
Yes, Carson. Thank you.
I think that WILL be all.
Carson has decided not to come with
us to Haxby.
I'm sorry. Is there anything I
can say to change your mind?
I'm afraid not, sir.
What a shame.
Not really.
Butlers will be two a penny
now they're all back from the war.
I gather Carson was looking for me.
Shall I go and find him, m'lord?
It's all right. Tell him I'll be
in the dressing room.
Has he done the red wine, yet?
It's over here, m'lord.
I'm pleased. It's a new one on me.
I had some at a dinner in London
and ordered it.
Carson thought we might try it
tonight.
Well, I'd better go up.
You made me sad yesterday.
Wondering what the war was for.
Don't listen to me.
I'm a foolish man who's lost his way
and don't quite know
how to find it again.
I'm terribly sorry.
Please try to forgive me.
I do forgive you.
Mr Carson.
His lordship said you were looking
for him.
And?
And well, I was to say that you'd
find him in the dressing room.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing.
I wrestled with it, m'lord,
I don't mind admitting.
And I wanted to be there
to help Lady Mary, and...
And protect her from Sir Richard.
Well, I wouldn't quite have put it
like that, but yes, I suppose.
Only... Only you felt
you couldn't work for a man
who would offer a bribe?
That is correct, m'lord.
Are you quite sure you
won't regret it?
I know how fond you are of
Lady Mary.
But I couldn't work for a man
that I don't respect.
And I certainly couldn't have left
Downton for him.
I shall take that as a compliment.
For myself and for my house.
I still don't see
why you didn't tell me first.
I'm sorry, m'lady, but I didn't want
to add to your troubles.
Well, you have done,
whether you wanted to or not.
Nobody's down yet.
They won't be long.
Look. They've cleared the tea
but forgotten to take that tray.
Ring the bell. I'll do it. They'll be
busy getting dinner ready.
It's too heavy for you.
No, it's not. Look out!
Heavens, that was a near thing.
My God...
Mary! Girls!
Cora! Come at once!
Robert wait.
Everyone come at once.
What is it? What's happened?
Come and see this.
Is it true?
Is it true what Lavinia says?
I don't believe it!
It's so wonderful.
It is, but don't tire yourself out.
Sit down now and we'll send for
Dr Clarkson.
She's right. Edith, go with Branson.
Get Clarkson, but fetch Mama
and Cousin Isobel as well.
I don't care what they're doing.
Tell them to come now!
My dear chap.
I cannot begin to tell you what this
means to me.
It's pretty good news for me, too.
There is only one possible
explanation.
It starts with my own mistake.
Every indication told me
that the spine was transected,
which would have been incurable.
But when Sir John Coates came to see
Matthew, he agreed with you.
Well, he didn't. Not entirely.
He thought that it could conceivably
be a case of spinal shock.
That is, um, intense bruising.
Which was sufficiently severe
to impede the leg mechanism.
But which would heal?
Why didn't you tell us?
Because I didn't agree with him...
and I didn't want to raise Captain
Crawley's hopes to no purpose.
I understand and I don't blame you.
You must take it slowly.
Rome wasn't built in a day. I know.
And I'm afraid you will carry a bruise
on your spine for the rest of your life.
But I will have a life?
Yes.
I think we can say that.
You will have a
normal life and it won't
be long in coming.
My darling boy.
Excuse me, m'lord,
but Mrs Hughes is
wondering what she
should do about dinner.
You'll all stay for dinner,
won't you?
I'm afraid I'm not dressed. Never
mind that. Who cares about that?
What about you, Mama?
Certainly.
All this unbridled joy has given me
quite an appetite.
There you are. I wondered what had
happened to you.
It's wonderful news, isn't it?
Wonderful. Are you busy?
I'm just going up to help in the
dining room. Why? It'll keep.
No. Tell me. I've got time.
It's just something his lordship said
recently, I can't get out of my mind.
How Vera must have bought the poison
and taken it home with her.
Yes. I suppose she must.
And it's... a terrible thing
to think of.
But she didn't. I did.
What?
Months ago, before I left.
Vera said we needed rat poison
and I bought it.
It was Arsenic. I've been thinking
that's what she must have taken.
Have you told the police?
No. Tell them.
If you don't and they find out,
it'll look bad.
But wouldn't I be asking for
trouble? You are if you stay silent.
Anna, we're starting.
Sorry, Mr Carson.
Tell me, how are things progressing
at Haxby?
Quite well. I've put in a condition
so the builders are fined for every
day they go over.
Does that make for a happy
atmosphere? I want it done.
They can be happy in their own time.
Why the rush?
I like everything I own to be
finished and ready to sell.
You're not thinking of selling
Haxby, surely?
Depends. We'll have to see if it
suits us, to be so close to Downton.
I... I want to tell you all
something.
As you know, during this... well,
I think I can say horrible time...
Lavinia has proved to be
the most marvellous person.
Hear, hear.
Indeed.
I never thought we would marry,
for all sorts of reasons,
but she wouldn't accept that
and so now I am very pleased to say
that she's been proved right.
Lavinia and I will get married.
My dear fellow.
Isn't it wonderful? As soon as I'm
well enough to walk down the aisle.
Dr Clarkson can help us with when.
Not long now.
And she feels we ought to marry here,
at Downton.
To bury forever the memories of what
I hope has been
the darkest period of my life.
- Of course!
- Are you sure?
I know it should be at my home
in London,
but we've been through so much here.
We'd be delighted.
Bravo! Excellent news.
Mary, isn't that excellent news?
Just excellent.
You're very late. Won't they worry?
They're all so excited,
they won't care where I am.
I'm pleased. I like Mr Matthew.
He announced at dinner that
he wants to get married at Downton.
Somehow, it made me feel
more than ever
that the war is really over...
and it's time to move forward.
Do you mean you've made your
decision?
Yes.
My answer is...
that I'm ready to travel...
and you're my ticket.
To get away from this house,
away from this life.
Me?
No. Uncle Tom Cobley.
I'm sorry.
But I've waited so long
for those words,
I can't believe I'm hearing them.
You won't mind burning your bridges?
Mind?
Fetch me the matches!
Yes, you can kiss me, but that is
all until everything is settled.
For now, God knows it's enough
that I can kiss you.
What a day. I can't stop smiling.
No. But another time, please ask me
before you agree to host a wedding.
What?
I'm fond of Matthew, of course,
but you do realise this means
Mary's marriage will be delayed?
I can't help that.
Mary is our first priority, Robert.
And just because Matthew's been lame.
Matthew's been lame?!
Can you hear the words
coming out of your mouth?
Can you hear how stupid
and selfish they are?
Because I can.
Don't bother me with it now.
I've enough on, trying to make a
luncheon that looks worth eating.
But that's what I'm saying.
Everything's in short supply now.
Short supply? No supply, more like!
Talk about making a silk purse
out of a sow's ear.
I wish we had a sow's ear!
It'd be better than this brisket.
That's just it. Thomas has come by
some groceries and such
and he's prepared to let them go
for the right price.
He's prepared to let them go,
is he?
And how did he come by them?
That's what I'd like to know.
Well, they're not stolen,
in case you're worried.
I'm not worried.
You're the one who should be worried.
Tell you what. I'm making
a wedding cake now, for Mr Crawley.
I'll finish it early
and feed it with brandy.
So if I give you a list of
ingredients, can you get them?
I can.
And then we'll see.
Now will you leave me and let me
get on with this travesty?
Why are you here?
Mr Bryant, Mrs Bryant, welcome.
We're so pleased to be here.
This is so kind of you,
Lady Grantham.
It is, but we ought to make it clear
we can't stay long.
I wasn't sure we had time to come
at all.
Luncheon is quite ready.
We must eat and run, I'm afraid.
We have to be at Maryport by six.
We're all so terribly sorry about
the reason you're here.
If we could see Charles's room.
Shall I take Mrs Bryant up?
No, I'll do it.
We'll all do it.
My cousin, Mrs Crawley,
who looked after Major Bryant,
and my daughters who nursed him,
will join us. How thoughtful.
But we can't be long. I've told our
chauffeur to stay in the car.
Will I take him something to eat?
Leave him be. He's quite happy.
Please, come and see where Major
Bryant lived while he was with us.
I'm afraid it's not going to work.
Why?
They're in the dining
room and getting
straight into the car
when they've finished.
I tried to speak to her on my own but
there was never the right moment.
Your grandaddy is a bit of a bully.
But I must see them.
I've come all this way.
Of course it's a disappointment.
You said yourself there wouldn't be
another chance. We can't know that.
Maybe you should write to them
after all.
You've nothing to lose. No. They have
to see him. They must see Charlie.
Well, maybe they will...
sometime in the future.
I hope so.
You'd better go now.
This wedding cake... Can I make it?
You wouldn't know how to start.
But you can tell me.
And if I make it early, then you can
make another if it's no good.
If I say yes,
will you do as you're told?
Daisy, there's a wretched chauffeur
at the front
who's not allowed
to get out of the car,
so can you make him a sandwich and
take him up a bottle of pop?
We've some ham and...
My God.
Who was that?
Wasn't that Ethel?
Did you see what she was carrying?
No.
Then just... let's leave it at that.
I'm afraid Downton will be
a place of pilgrimage for a while.
We're glad to be. If we can help
to bring some peace of mind.
There's no point in wallowing in it.
What good does it do?
Leave me alone.
Ethel!
I tried to stop her.
What on earth?
Ethel... I know what this is.
Mrs Hughes, I don't think
it's quite the right - I'm stopping.
Until I've had my say.
This is Charlie. Your grandson.
He's almost a year old.
What proof have you?
What?
I say, what proof have you?
If my son was the father of this boy,
where is your proof?
Have you any letters?
Any signed statement?
Why would there be letters?
We were in the same house.
I think she's telling the truth.
I'm not interested in 'think'.
I want proof that my son
acknowledged paternity of this boy.
If what you say is true,
then he would have known
of the boy's existence
for months before he...
before he was killed.
Yes. He knew.
So... What did he do about it?
Nothing.
He did nothing.
Thank you.
That's the proof I was looking for.
If Charles was the
father, he would never
have shirked his responsibilities.
Never.
Well, he did.
I won't listen to any more slander!
Now will you please go, and take
that boy with you, whoever he is.
You are upsetting Mrs Bryant.
I would like...
I say you are upsetting Mrs Bryant.
Lord Grantham, are you going to stand
by while this woman holds us to ransom?
This isn't doing much good.
Ethel, you'd better come with me.
Come on.
She thinks we're a soft touch.
They hear of a dead officer with
money behind them
and suddenly there's a baby
on every corner.
But if she's telling the truth...
If Charles had fathered that boy,
he would have told us.
Now, I'd say she's done her homework
and discovered he was an only child.
She thinks we'd be ripe
for the plucking.
You knew her. Was she one of the
nurses when he was here?
She was a housemaid.
Were you aware?
No.
No-one told me Major Bryant
was your only son.
That's right. Just Charles.
Matthew is my only son,
and he nearly died.
I think I know what you're going
through. He seems such a nice...
I think that's cast rather a
shadow over the proceedings,
so I don't see any point
in prolonging it.
Daphne, come on, we're leaving.
He's afraid of his own grief.
That's why he behaves as he does.
He's terrified of his own grief.
If that's what he's like, I don't
want his help. I don't want it.
I doubt you'll have the option.
You're a dark horse.
How did you keep it a secret
all this time?
Maybe when he's thought about it he'll
feel differently, you never know.
Anna... will you kindly go upstairs
and help in the dining room?
Ethel, please take the child
and leave.
How did you get here? I caught the
bus and walked up from the village.
Then can you reverse the process
as quickly as possible?
She's very badly shaken, Mr Carson.
She's lost everything.
Are you all right for the fare?
Yes, thank you.
He's their only grandchild.
There can never be another.
Even if Ethel is telling the truth.
I believe she is.
Even so, there's no legal reality
to it.
The child is her bastard
and has no claim on them.
Steady on, sir. The ladies have had
enough shocks for one day.
I just don't see the point in pretending
something can be done when it can't.
What about you, Mother? Can't one of
your refugee charities help?
She's not a refugee and we have more
claims on our funding than we can meet.
The truth is, Ethel's made her choice
and now she's stuck with it.
That seems a little hard.
Does it?
Aren't all of us stuck with
the choices we make?
Candied peel? Well, well. I never
thought you'd find that.
I hope you're pleased, Mrs Patmore.
Course she is. Aren't you?
There's stuff
here we haven't seen
since before the war.
I can't wait to get started.
I won't ask where you got it from,
because I don't want to know.
I keep saying. There's nothing
wrong. So what I'd like to know is...
When will he get paid?
When I'm satisfied.
And when will that be, oh mighty one?
When Daisy's baked the cake
and I'm pleased with it.
He understands.
He knows this is just the sprat
to catch the mackerel.
I really ought to walk
to the library.
No need to rush it, sir.
You're getting better every day.
Cousin, Matthew? May I come in?
Please.
No, no, no. No stay where you are.
Thank you.
No doubt you will regard this as
rather unorthodox,
my pushing into a man's bedroom,
uninvited.
Well, erm... It's just I don't
want us to be disturbed.
I'm sure you know how pleased I am
that you will recover, after all.
Thank you.
Just as I am delighted that you can
once more look forward to a...
to a happy married life.
I'm very lucky.
Now this may come as a surprise...
but I feel I must say it
all the same. Please do.
Mary is still in love with you.
What?
I was watching her the other night
when you spoke of your wedding.
She looked like...
Juliet, on awakening in the tomb.
Mary and I have always had -
Of course, I suspected long ago
that the flame hadn't quite gone out,
but then there was no chance
of your recovery.
And it seemed best to let her try
for happiness where she could.
I quite agree, and Sir Richard is...
No, now, let's not muddy the pool
by discussing Sir Richard.
The point is, you loved her once.
Are you sure you can't love her
again?
Cousin Violet...
Please don't think I mind your...
speaking to me in this way.
I quite admire it but...
consider this.
Lavinia came back against
my orders, determined
to look after me for
the rest of my life,
which meant that she would wash me
and feed me and...
do things that only the most
dedicated nurse would undertake.
And all with no hope of children
or any improvement.
Yes, it's all very admirable...
and I give her full credit.
And giving her that credit, do you
think it would be right for me
to throw her over
because I can walk?
To dismiss her, because I no longer
have need of her services?
Spoken like a man of honour.
And we will not fall out over this.
But you don't agree.
I would just say one thing:
Marriage is a long business.
There's no getting out of it
for our kind of people.
Now you may live 40... 50 years
with one of these two women.
Just make sure you have selected
the right one.
Will it be April or May?
I should steer clear of May.
Marry in May, rue the day.
I think it's April. Matthew should
be walking normally by them.
Spring weddings are the prettiest
of all.
All this talk of weddings
is making me impatient.
I don't think we can go into competition
with Matthew and Lavinia, do you?
After then. In the summer. Let's
settle it before I return to London.
You must be looking forward to
travelling again.
I know I am.
Very well. The end of July.
Then we can be out of England
for August.
You don't sound very excited.
To quote you 'that's not who we are.'
There's something I've been meaning
to ask you. Here's the hero.
Here we are.
Why did you try to bribe Anna?
She told you, did she?
She didn't. Not me.
But why did you do it?
Next time, if you want to know
anything, just ask me.
Well done.
Very well done.
All right then I will.
Once and for all, are
you still in love
with Matthew Crawley?
Of course not!
Would I ever admit to loving a man
who preferred someone else over me?
Where's Sybil?
She's not feeling well.
She told Anna she wouldn't be down
for dinner.
What is it?
I heard from my lawyer today.
Apparently, Vera wrote to a friend
just before my last visit.
Why are they telling you now? It was
only delivered a few days ago.
And do you know what the letter
says? They sent me a copy.
'John has written and he's coming
here tonight.
His words sound as angry as
I've ever heard him,
and you know how angry that is.
I never thought I'd say this,
but I'm afraid for my life.'
What did you write to her?
I said I was coming that evening and
I meant to have it out with her.
I may have said she was being
unreasonable, but so she was.
Will it change anything?
Think about it.
Before Vera's death,
she had taken all my money
and she had wrecked the divorce.
Now, as her widower,
I inherit everything and we can marry
whenever we like.
Anna, they're going in.
You look as if you've got the cares
of the world on your shoulders.
Not the whole world, Mrs Hughes,
but quite enough of it.
Sybil?
Sybil I just want to say goodnight.
Mrs Hughes, can I borrow the
duplicate keys for upstairs?
Why? Lady Mary says one of the
bathroom keys isn't working.
She thinks it must have got swapped.
I'll come.
No, no there's no need.
I'll bring them back in a jiffy.
You've done enough for one day.
My God. She's eloped.
She's on her way to Gretna Green.
They must stop at some point.
It won't be open before morning.
They won't expect us to
follow until tomorrow.
They'll stay somewhere on the road.
We hope.
Everyone keep an eye out
for the motor.
Daisy? What in God's name are you
doing down here at this hour?
I just wanted to check
it were all right.
That it hadn't, you know,
caved in or anything. Caved in?
It's a cake, not a souffle.
I know. But I've never made
a wedding cake before.
Is that the one for tasting?
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
Well, bring it out.
We'll give it a try.
What in God's name
do you call this?
I don't know. I did everything
that you said. I promise.
But didn't you taste the mixture?
Well, then I'm afraid it's time
to look at Thomas's ingredients.
Well, it's two thirds plaster dust.
Where's the peel?
Yuk! This were old
when Adam were a boy.
So, Thomas was happy to 'let it go',
was he?
Well, it won't go anywhere near me
in future!
Chuck the whole bally lot out
and we'll have to think again.
Isn't that the car?
How did you find us?
How did you know?
Never mind that. At least nothing's
happened, thank God.
What do you mean nothing's happened?
I've decided to marry Tom and your
coming after me won't change that.
This isn't the way.
She's right.
Of course Mama and Papa will hate it.
Why should they?
Pipe down.
Sybil, can't you let them
get used to the idea?
Take your stand and refuse to budge,
but allow them time.
That way, you won't have to break up
the family.
They would never give permission.
You don't need permission. You're 21.
But you do need their
forgiveness if you're not
to start your new life
under a black shadow.
Don't listen. She's pretending
to be reasonable to get you home.
Even if I am,
even if I think this is mad,
I know it will be better to do it
in broad daylight
than to sneak off
like a thief in the night.
Go back with them, then.
If you think they can make you
happier than I will.
Am I so weak you believe
I can be talked out
of giving my heart in
five minutes flat?
But Mary's right. I don't like deceit
and our parents don't deserve it.
So I'll go back with them.
Believe it or not,
I will stay true to you.
I'll return the car in the morning.
You're confident you can bring her
round, aren't you? Fairly.
I'll certainly try.
Do you want some money? For the room?
No thank you, m'lady.
I can pay my own way.
Where are the girls?
I suppose Sybil's still ill and
the others just haven't appeared.
I hope they're not coming down
with anything.
The stories of this Spanish 'flu
are too awful.
No, it's nothing of the sort.
Why are you up so early?
I'm meeting Isobel. She wants me to
help with her refugees.
I thought the whole
point of Mama arranging
that was to keep her out of your hair.
I know.
But now the soldiers have
gone, I do have a lot
of time on my hands and
maybe I can be useful.
Why is it different from before the
war?
I don't know exactly. It just is.
Maybe the war's changed me.
I guess it's changed everybody.
Not me.
Don't be too sure.
If I'm not back before luncheon,
don't wait.
I'll take this down to keep it hot,
m'lord.
I wanted to catch you alone.
Yes... You see, I think you might be
happier if I tended my resignation.
What? I'd hate you to be
uncomfortable in your own house...
I won't hear of it.
But I know...
You will not be deprived
of your livelihood
because I behaved in an
ungentlemanly manner.
The fault was entirely mine.
You will not pay the price.
Is this yours? Moseley found it
in your dressing room.
It's not one of your old toys, is it?
Because I don't recognise it.
No. It was given to me. As a charm,
I think. To take to the front.
Well, you're home and safe now.
Shall I put it in the barrel
for the village children? No.
You never know.
It might be bad luck not to keep it.
Luncheon will be ready soon.
It's all rubbish.
It's all bloody rubbish!
Can't you ask for your money back?
Yes. Of course I can ask.
And a fat lot of good that'll do!
You must challenge him.
How?
I only ever met him in a pub.
I wouldn't know where to find him.
But surely -
Don't you understand, woman?!
I've been tricked!
I've been had!
I've been taken for the fool
that I am!
How much did he get from you?
Every penny I had.
And then some.
What are you going to do now?
I don't know.
I don't bloody know.
And all the time you've been driving
me about,
bowing and scraping and seducing
my daughter behind my back.
You know Cousin Violet came to me...
and told me to marry you?
Mr Carson, whatever's the matter?
I wish you knew much I want to help.
Do you?
Let's get down to business.
Find out what we mean to do for
Charlie in the future.
I did something once which
I bitterly regret. Bitterly.
Everything's going to be all right.
Everything is clearly not all right.
Subtitles by APOLLO
www.MY-SUBS.com