WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Downton Abbey: the most successful
British drama series for a decade.
Welcome to Downton. You'll find there's
never a dull moment in this house.
HUGH BONNEVILLE: Two unmissable series
rising to 12 million viewers in the UK.
And some of period dramas most
memorable moments.
I can't believe it.
It's so wonderful.
I won't allow it!
He proposed to me.
Good heavens, what am I sitting on?
Now let's get behind the
drama with exclusive
interviews with the cast
of this hugely loved show.
Literally he has to
fall flat on his face.
When are they gonna kiss?
They finally kiss.
An explosion went off right in front
of our faces.
Hear what they really think of their
characters.
She's damaged goods. She's just a
really good egg, I think.
She's not very nice.
Now who's jealous?
And see them in action
behind the scenes.
There will be explosions
on this take.
To uncover the secret
of Downton Abbey's success.
Whoo!
Guys like me don't always get asked
to do heroic action stuff, you know.
Come at once! Come at once!
Come and see this at once!
It's July 2011.
The cast is filming a scene for the
Christmas episode.
And, action.
I don't want to spoil their
fun but I couldn't wear
a paper hat not with poor
Mr Bates locked away.
His Lordship said much thesame.
Everyone is still reeling from the
shock of Mr Bates's arrest.
If things don't go right
for Mr Bates, have
you given any thought
to his replacement?
There'll be plenty of time for that
conversation after the trial.
Cut there, reset, thank you.
Resetting.
So far we've met 33 characters in
the Downton saga.
Whatever their position in society,
they all have a place in the story.
When we were devising Downton,
we knew it was very important that
we would treat everyone equally.
We just wanted a group of people who
were all, for one reason or another,
living in this one house
but with different expectations of
life
and they go through different
traumas but equal traumas.
and in a great house with more than
50 bedrooms, they had plenty to do.
The house is kind of like a swan.
It's beautiful and graceful and
floating above the surface
and underneath the legs are kind of
going wild making it all happen
and the servants are like the legs
of the house.
You get barely time to,
well, I won't say it
but, yes, you know what I mean.
We all know who's boss upstairs.
The Dowager Countess.
I couldn't put it better myself.
But, if anything, the hierarchy's even
stricter in the servants' quarters.
William, are you aware the seam at
your shoulder is coming apart?
Below stairs you
can generally tell
who is important to be seen
in the principal rooms
and in those days, it was
young men, the footmen.
They were the peacocks.
They are designed to reflect
the status the Granthams
are trying to convey.
Obviously, at the head of the chain
is Carson.
Downton Abbey. Carson the butler
speaking.
And Daisy, everybody knows, is at
the bottom.
And that is why she has the rotten,
miserable jobs,
doing all the gritty, earthy work
that has to be done.
We should go out to greet them.
And me, Mr Carson?
No, Daisy, not you.
She's never allowed to
be seen upstairs and
you can tell because
she's dressed that way.
Today, Britain's great
houses have lost
their traditional
kitchens and sculleries.
So, Daisy's world has been recreated
at the famous Ealing studios.
The upstairs cast rarely get to visit
the myriad of sets here
but it's where every downstairs scene
is shot
and the attention to detail is
amazing.
We used to have taps that worked but
they don't seem to be working any more.
The other day I went to turn the tap on
in a scene and I was gonna wash my hands
and they just didn't turn on,
so I was like, 'Oh, hm. '
But, yeah, this all works.
This gets very hot and you can
actually cook things.
I did a scene with Lady Sybil.
Why does everything go so lumpy?
And this comes out and they shoot
through there.
Ooh, there's this bit. I love the
household wants indicator.
It's an old-fashioned shopping list
and it's really cool.
If they ran out of things, they'd
just do that with the little tag.
How clever is that?
Even the food on set is authentic
for the period,
though once it's gone
cold after a few takes,
it doesn't taste
quite so delicious.
Just don't let Mrs Patmore hear you
say that.
Mrs Patmore looks ready to eat her
alive.
I was only trying to help. Oh!
Judas was only trying to
help, I suppose, when
he brought the Roman
soldiers to the garden.
When I first got the job,
people would say to me,
'Are you above stairs
or below stairs?'
And I'd say, 'What do you think?'
Daisy and Mrs Patmore,
I think they have kind of a
mother-daughter relationship.
Although a very,
very bossy mother
who is also your boss.
I said you could go for a drink of
water not a trip up the Nile.
It's very important to get her up to
speed because if she does,
she'll have a chance of probably
going on and being promoted
and one day she might be
a cook herself, so the
reasoning behind it is not
just to be an old cow.
Sometimes my lines are
really easy to learn cos I
just have to say, 'Yes,
Mrs Patmore, ' 15 times.
Yes, Mrs Patmore. And run around
pretending to make cakes.
Have you laid the service for
breakfast? Yes, Mrs Patmore.
And finish blacking that stove.
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
Lesley has really hard lines to learn
cos she always has sayings and phrases.
You know, like... I'm trying to
think of one now.
It's just the sprat to catch the
mackerel. Is that a phrase?
He knows this is justthe sprat to
catch the mackerel.
He understands. He knows this is just
the sprat to catch the mackerel.
She's witty and she knows she's
witty and she enjoys it
and she enjoys put-downs and she's a
bit sarky.
Ooh, talk about making a silk purse
out of a sow's ear.
I wish we had a sow's ear.
It'd be better than this brisket.
The cook had a very tough working
life.
Will you leave me and let me get on
with this travesty?
I always feel with Mrs Patmore that
if she didn't keep up the cracks,
you know, she would just go forward
with her forehead on her elbows
and think,
'God, is this ever going to end?'
Ooh, what a dreadful thing.
In Britain's great
houses, intimate
relationships between
staff were frowned upon
and the relentless hard work left
littletime for romance.
But against the odds,
some servants did find love.
The Anna and Bates
story was the one that
captured everyone's
kind of imagination.
Everyone wanted them
to get together.
When I was watching it, even though
I knew what was happening.
You'd be like,
'Oh, come on. '
I'm John Bates, the new valet.
The new valet?
That's right.
She clearly has empathy for this
character on his arrival.
I'm Anna, the head house maid.
How do you do?
Before Mr Bates comes along, I think
she's just happy with her lot, really.
There's an attraction. It's just
alchemy.
She does fall for this man and she has
this different option now in her life.
This relationship grows but it takes
a long time to develop.
Everything we were talking about
was not what we were saying.
It's sad to think about.
It's always sad when
you love someone who
doesn't love you back,
no matter who you are.
Really we were kind of
saying, 'I really like you.
' 'I really like you. '
So, it's really nice to
play against the words and
play against what you're
actually talking about.
Perhaps Mr Patrick did love her
back, he just couldn't say.
Why ever not? Sometimes we're not at
liberty to speak.
Sometimes it wouldn't be right.
He doesn't wear his heart on his
sleeve.
He keeps it buried where it belongs
to reveal itself only when necessary.
And while Mr Bates plays his cards
close to his chest,
he still has to deal with hostility
and resentment below stairs.
Remember to help me
with the luggage.
Don't go running off.
I'll give you a hand.
I couldn't ask that, Mr Bates, not
in your condition.
How long do we have to put up with
this, Mr Carson, just so I know?
Someone with such an
injury would rarely,
if ever, be employed
in service in a house
so it's of huge import to him that's
he given this chance.
The arrival of a duke is
an honour for the house
and the servants must
make a good impression.
But for Bates, it's a moment of
shame.
I remember that scene vividly
because, initially,
it was going to be staged as the
character falling to his knees,
but I thought, metaphorically
and literally,
he has to fall flat on his face.
It was shot so many times,
I was winded for a few days.
But it was very important that we
saw this man's absolute humiliation.
Bates, are you all right?
Perfectly, my Lord.
But the physical scars are the least
of Bates's worries.
He can't escape his chequered past.
Nothing is harder to live
with than false hope.
I wish you'd just
come out with it.
With what?
Mr Bates has the most amount of
baggage of anybody, in
the world, I think.
Whatever it is you're keeping
secret.
He makes this, to me admirable, but
essentially unmodern decision...
I'm afraid I cannot answer that.
Not to burden everyone else
with his own troubles.
I just want to know the truth.
I cannot speak of it, my Lord.
But, of course, in a way it plays
against him.
I bet Thomas would like it if they
took you for a thief.
It means people can believe anything
of him.
Yes, I expect he would.
She's a real trooper
to stick by him but
that's because they're
so in love, you know.
(WINDOW OPENS)
The servants might have
it tough but being
at the helm of this
ship isn't easy either.
Pregnant?
Especially with daughters like
these.
The Turk is a true story.
I think he's dead.
The sisters are wicked with each
other. She's a bit of a bitch.
So, he slipped the hook.
Downton Abbey's sumptuous setting is
perhaps the biggest star of the show.
The cast and crew have spent more
than 100 days
filming many of the upstairs scenes
at the magnificent Highclere castle.
It's like working in a piece of
living history.
When you walk into the hall it's
wonderful.
There's certainly a really great
feeling when you're in the real thing.
OK, stand by.
The seat of the Earls of Carnarvon
for three centuries,
it's the perfect location for Downton
Abbey.
Here the family faces losing
everything to a perfect stranger.
When he arrives in the village,
no-one is happy.
They'll push one of
the daughters at me.
They'll have fixed on that when
they heard I was a bachelor.
Lady Mary Crawley.
I do hope I'm not interrupting.
They get off to a
really bad start.
It's probably the worst possible
start to any relationship.
Won't you stay and have some tea?
Oh, no. You're far too busy and I
wouldn't want to push in.
She's a cow at the beginning. You
know, she's so rude.
The whole thing is a complete joke.
Matthew Crawley has been thrust into
Lady Mary's life by a maritime disaster.
I thought it was supposed
to be unsinkable.
I can't make myself believe it.
Is it really true?
Afraid so.
But all them people freezing to
death in the midnight icy water.
The heir to Downton Abbey has gone
down with the Titanic.
This alters everything.
And the entail means Lord
Grantham's title, estate
and fortune must go to the
nearest male relation.
An entail, yes. Yeah, we all had to
have a bit of a lesson on that.
The entail must be smashed.
You can't break it. I'll tell you
that.
I've tried. Can't break it.
It's a very strange thing that's
asked of him, I think.
You know, to come into
their midst and be told
that, 'One day, my son,
all this will be yours. '
You know, it's very odd.
Welcome to Downton.
Thank you. You've been so kind.
It is my duty to make sure that he
comes to terms with that, actually.
They're going to have to make the
best of it.
What should we call each other?
Well, we could always start with Mrs
Crawley and Lady Grantham.
Everybody's trying to
throw him curve balls and
Mary, in particular, is
very keen to wrong foot him
and prove that he's
not the right man for
the job and that he
shouldn't be there.
By the way, if ever you
want to ride, just let
Lynch know and he'll
sort it out for you.
Oh, Papa, cousin Matthew doesn't
ride. I ride.
Mary is irritated, frustrated,
angered by her loss of her own,
what she thinks should have been her
inheritance.
The vast majority of
aristocratic families,
the women have no rights at all.
If they could make a good marriage, then
they could become very powerful indeed.
But if they did not make a good
marriage, they had nothing.
To Lady Mary's family, the solution
to her problem is simple.
Marry a man who can
barely hold his knife
like a gentleman?
Oh, you exaggerate.
When marrying well is your sole
ambition, dressing the part is vital.
I'll admit that if I ever
wanted to attract a man,
I'd steer clear of those
clothes and that hat.
Day to day life for the girls really
would have meant a lot of changing.
They would always change for dinner,
even if it's just the five of them,
they'll be wearing
their pearls, their
diamonds and their long,
beautiful dresses.
So, I don't know how they got much
else done.
It takes quite a while to put on
those dresses.
Behind the scenes, a team of six
works full-time
to recreate the elaborate fashions
down to the tiniest period detail.
This dress for Lady Mary Crawley.
It's a piece of vintage
beading but then it was sort
of reimagined with a new
back and new trimmings.
I did this dress for Michelle as well,
which is slightly later period.
It was inspired by a very early
Chanel from 1919.
You look very nice.
Thank you, darling.
While the men are stuck in the same
old white tie night after night,
the ladies' beautiful look
comes at a price.
I sometimes have personal run-ins
with my corset.
I'm not a big fan of them.
And we've all got corsets
on like they have.
The corsets can get a bit
cheeky after 12 hours.
Below stairs they get
all the discomfort of
Edwardian dress with
none of the glamour.
Downstairs girls, we get really bad
costume envy.
If suddenly
an upstairs character is around,
that's when you start to feel like,
'Oh, my God, I'm so depressed. '
When Lady Crawley comes down, I was
so confused.
I called her Your Majesty by mistake
three times in the scene.
Your Ladyship, I
went, 'Your Majesty.
' Cos I felt like I was
talking to the Queen.
There was no sort of real rapport with
her because she was so different.
Upstairs the finest clothes come out
for visiting dignitaries.
But not every guest is an exciting
prospect.
A Mr... Kemal Pamuk.
I can see him now, a funny
little foreigner with
a wide, toothy grin and
hair reeking of pomade.
I wouldn't quite say that. Here he
is now.
Lady Mary Crawley, I presume?
You presume right.
Sorry to be so dishevelled.
We've been on a train
since dawn and we had
to change in a shake.
You don't look dishevelled to me.
She's often very hard with men and
quite cold and steely
and actually with Pamuk she just
melted and was swept away by him.
You know, she sort of embarrasses
herself quite a lot.
What is it? Is this picture really a
della Francesca?
I think so. The second Earl brought
back several paintings from...
Mr Pamuk.
The man from Turkey is not
constrained
by the social mores of the time that
poor old Mary was
and when Mr Pamuk
walks into that room,
he's decided he's going to have her.
She's not as sophisticated as a young
woman of her age would be today.
She probably doesn't know much about
the facts of life.
You and my parents have something in
common. Oh?
You believe I'm much more of a rebel
than I am.
Now please go.
It's in an era when there
are huge ramifications
for such a thing
being discovered.
Unfortunately in a way that only
Julian can dream up, she is caught
and I don't need to tell you how.
I think he's dead.
No, I'm sure he's dead.
The Turk is a true story.
It's always rather interesting
that what seems the
most fictional is in fact
based entirely in truth.
A great friend of ours who
is an owner of a great
house came upon a diary
of one of his great aunts
and this whole incident is recorded.
Now we must decide what to do for
the best.
There's only one thing we can do.
It's just this dark secret between
the two floors, you know,
I think that's what is so brilliant
about Downton.
It's when the characters come together
that makes it so interesting.
We did all the scenes where we were
carrying Mr Pamuk through the house
and it was a mixture of
it being kind of fun
but also really, really
shocking as well.
Something happened to Mary.
She made this
huge mistake and now
she's damaged goods.
I can't make his eyes stay shut.
It certainly made her more human and
much more vulnerable as a person.
Of course it would
happen to a foreigner.
It's typical.
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm not being ridiculous.
No Englishman would
dream of dying in
someone else's house.
Especially someone they didn't even
know.
But Mary's scandalous story doesn't
stay secret for long,
thanks to the unsisterly behaviour of
Lady Edith Crawley.
We have three grown-up, very rich girls
who are bored out of their skull.
All their energy is turned into this
sibling rivalry and fighting
and bitterness and jealousy.
Spare me your boasting, please.
Now who's jealous?
I told my family. I said this part,
this sister, she's not very nice.
She's a bit of a bitch,
Edith, and after the
first three episodes or
so, my mum said to me,
'I don't know what you're talking about,
she's lovely, she's misunderstood. '
And by the end she
was like, 'No, yeah,
you're right, she's
awful, she's a bitch. '
Is it true you wrote to the Turkish
ambassador about Kamal?
Yeah, she behaves quite badly.
And what if I did? He had a right to
know how his countryman died...
in the arms of a slut.
She is not so good-looking.
She is not so charismatic as her
elder sister.
So, all of these men that are thrown
at Mary,
I think Edith is very jealous and
desperate for an offer to come her way.
So, he slipped the hook.
At least I'm not fishing with no
bait.
Yes, the sisters are really wicked
with each other.
So, Matthew goes from being
flavour of the month
to suddenly being another
pawn in a game again
which is incredibly frustrating for
him, I think.
You know, I don't dislike him as
much as you do.
Perhaps you don't dislike him at
all.
She thinks, 'If Mary doesn't want him,
then I'll have a go, ' without any hope.
Lady Edith's plan of
seduction starts by tempting
Matthew with an architectural
tour of local churches.
Edith doesn't really have any
interest in these churches,
she's just interested in spending
time with cousin Matthew.
I wish we could talk a little more
about you.
What was it like growing up in
Manchester?
Does it say anything about the side
aisles?
Just gazing lovingly at
the back of Matthew's
head and Matthew
completely unaware.
I wonder how Mary's getting on.
All right, I should think.
Why? I just wondered.
I remember the first series, there
was sort of a catchphrase on set
of 'poor Edith' after the end of
every scene.
We've time for one more at least
before we lose the light.
I underestimated your enthusiasm.
Lady Mary can't help
but notice that cousin
Matthew's a hit with both
her younger sisters.
You must be careful not
to break Sybil's heart.
I think she has a crush on you.
Well, that's something no-one could
accuse you of. Oh, I don't know.
I assume you speak in the spirit of
mockery? You should have more faith.
It's quite a bold move, in
those times, to be left
alone, having sandwiches
over a dining table.
It's much more racy than it sounds
these days
but it's a nice scene to
play because suddenly
all the electricity that's
been sparking around
and building up over the
course of the series,
you were allowed to
light the light bulb.
He proposed to me.
Oh, my dear.
Have you given him an answer?
Only that I'd think about it.
Always Mary has to think about it.
She's impulsive in some
ways but when it comes to
making a decision, she
finds it really difficult.
Pregnant?
You needn't be quite soshocked.
Cora's happy news does nothing to
help.
If your mother's child is a boy,
then he's the heir
and I go back to living on my wits
and you'd rather not follow me.
Oh, Matthew, you always make
everything so black and white.
I think this is black and white.
Do you love me enough to spend your
life with me?
It's the moment that she realises
that it's not going to happen,
I think that is the point
where Mary realises
that she does in fact
really love him.
So I've ruined everything.
But in 1914, this whole
world of elegance
is turned upside
down for everyone.
Action!
It beats sitting round a dining
table for three days, I tell you.
Even the great class divide is under
threat.
When are they going to kiss?
Come on!
Are they ever going to kiss?
They finally kiss.
The First World War
transformed life in
Britain and Downton
Abbey is no exception.
I like that whole half century
between 1890 and 1940
because it's only 50 years, you
know, within many lifetimes,
and yet it really was the transition
of the old world into the new.
The trades union movement was
beginning,
Karl Marx's writings were having an
influence across the world.
Women's rights and, of course, it
took a war to release all this stuff.
Sergeant Stevens. Sir?
I want every wounded man taken down the
line before it starts to get dark.
We've bloody well lost enough of
them for one day.
Having volunteered to go
to the front, Matthew
is caught up in the
Battle of the Somme,
which claimed the lives of nearly 20,000
men on the first day of fighting alone.
Forward!
The trenches stuff, it was such a
joy because, you know,
guys like me don't
always get asked to do,
sort of, heroic action
stuff, you know.
There will be explosions
on this take.
Let's make our hero heroic,
for goodness' sake.
Well, he's certainly going
to come across as that.
Give him something jolly brave to
do.
And action!
This is my wounded soldier.
Stuntman.
Yeah. I asked for the smallest,
lightest man they could find.
I've had no breakfast!
On location in Suffolk,
50 supporting artists
help bring to life this
bloodiest of all battles.
Whoo!
It's a world away from the splendour
of Downton Abbey.
I still think Maggie Smith should be
in this scene.
Lobbing mint imperials over the top!
And, action!
With the explosions and everything,
it does get your adrenalin going.
Like there. You know,
differently timed explosions
we hadn't rehearsed so
we were just playing it
as and when the crap falls on your
head, which is amazing.
Yeah, it beats sitting around a dining
table for three days, I tell you.
And the war makes its mark on
Downton Abbey.
Many of Britain's great
houses played a vital
role in nursing injured
soldiers back to health.
Highclere which is, you
know, the real Downton, was
not a convalescent home as
we have it but a hospital.
A rather extraordinary character
called Almina, Countess of Caernarfon,
got her father to fund a real
hospital.
Oh, really.
It's like living in a
second-rate hotel where the
guests keep arriving and
no-one seems to leave.
I think the war sort of broke that
vision that Edwardian England had
of itself as this sort of flawless
place
where everyone knew who they were
and what they should be doing.
Come on, damn you.
I think that was over.
While adjusting to the new order is
difficult for some,
for others, it offers a glimpse of
the future.
Interestingly the daughters rise to
the challenge first.
They find some useful purpose.
As soon as I've done this, I'll take
your orders for books.
She grows up and understands the
world in a different way
and I think that she can be helpful
and practical
and carve a role for
herself in the world
that doesn't just include
getting married.
I hadn't cast you as Florence
Nightingale.
We can't leave all the moral
high ground to Sybil.
She might get lonely there.
She's been in this house in this
sort of little Downton bubble
but being the kind of girl that she
is, she needs to do something.
She can no longer just sit there.
By joining the ranks of World War I's
9,000 volunteer nurses,
Lady Sybil sees the world outside the
walls of Downton
and her taste of freedom has
far-reaching consequences.
We are talking about...
Branson, yes.
The chauffeur? Branson? What has he
said to you?
That he loves me and he wants me to
run away with him. Good God in heaven.
He falls head over heels in love and
then spends a long time
trying to convince her that she
should do the same for him!
I'll stay in Downton until you want
to run away with me.
Don't be ridiculous.
She really has to consider losing
her family, her friends,
her security, her life, everything
she's grown up with.
In the close confines of a
house like Downton Abbey,
it's not easy to pursue love
across the class divide.
She's sort of constantly kind of,
you know, popping into garage.
I wish I knew how an engine worked.
I can teach you if you'd like.
You know in that way when
you like someone and
you just want to sort
of, you know, hang out.
Myself and Jess were joking, we're
back here again.
It's three years later and I'm still
tinkering with this car.
And, you know, we spent a long time
in the garage of Downton.
Oh, don't badger me, please.
It is slow burning.
The whole way through
I was constantly
reading scripts going,
'When are they going to kiss? Will
they ever kiss?
I have to say I think Branson's very
patient.
I wonder how many other people would
wait for that long.
You get that sense every time she goes
back to the garage, people are like,
'If you don't kiss, I'll
throw something at the TV.
' It's like, 'Come on!'
Yes, you can kiss me.
They finally kiss.
And at last, Lady Sybil and Branson
escape the garage.
Oh, my God. She's eloped. She's on
her way to Gretna Green.
They keep leaving notes. This is the
problem.
If they didn't leave notes, they would
have been away, married and everything.
You don't expect a car chase in
Downton.
I suppose we do have one.
Everyone keep an eye out for the
motor.
Mary and Edith get in a car together
and run and save their sister.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
How did you find us? How did you
know?
But these two fear no-one...
not even Lord Grantham.
Yes? He bursts straight into them after
dinner, which is completely unheard of.
Number one, he's a chauffeur, he
shouldn't even be in the house.
You've asked me to come
and I've come.
Would someone please tell me what is
going on?
Or have we all stepped through the
looking glass?
In the scene, everyone's
so shocked kind of going,
'When did this happen?
How did this happen?'
I won't allow it. I will not allow
my daughter to throw away her life.
You can posture it all you like,
Papa, it won't make any difference.
Oh, yes it will. How?
I don't want any money. You can
hardly lock me up until I die.
That's brave, I think, for the time.
I think that's a pretty brave thing
to do.
Tom.
Downton's ordered world appears to be
crumbling.
At least there's one couple doing
things properly.
Mr Bates, is this a proposal?
If that's what you want to call it.
And you might start calling me John.
Everything is rosy in the garden
until the arrival of his first wife.
As an actress I was really pleased
that it all went wrong
cos I thought I don't want
it to just be happily
ever after cos otherwise
I'll be bored.
You see, if you don't
come back to me, I'm
going to the newspapers
with a cracking story
and I'd like to bet the Grantham's
won't survive it. Oh?
A diplomat dying in the bed of an
earl's unmarried daughter?
Well, that takes the ticket for the
tale of the year.
It's bad enough that
he won't come back,
that's bad enough but
that's liveable with.
The idea that he won't
come back cos he's going
to be happy with someone
else, is intolerable.
Vera's interference...
You bitch.
Is enough to push Bates to the
limit.
Your Lordship, I need to go to
London tomorrow.
Please say this concerns property
and not the former Mrs Bates.
I only wish she was the former, my
Lord, or, better still, the late.
Yeah, it does get
worse and worse.
You know, it does get worse
and worse for Bates.
It's erm... He has a pretty rum time
of it.
But could Bates have been driven to
murder?
His wife's dead.
In the shadow of Vera's death,
Bates and Anna finally marry.
The scene this afternoon is their
wedding night.
They finally get married.
Which has been a long time coming.
It's the couple's most intimate
scene yet.
It's a costume drama with no
costumes on.
The setting for their
wedding night is a
bedroom built on a
sound stage at Ealing.
Shall I do that?
For Anna and Bates, it's a snatched
moment of happiness.
Action.
Well...
Mrs Bates.
While everyone tries
to carry on as normal,
in Downton Abbey tragedy
is never far away.
My legs, I can't seem to move them.
BUT... miraculously...
Look out!
My God.
For the characters who inhabit
Downton Abbey's upstairs world,
the Great War accelerates the pace of
life and love.
I think it did make you realise how
short life could be.
Action. Lavinia and I will get
married.
Oh, my dear fellow.
And, as a lot of people did,
got engaged just like that.
I think she seems rather sweet.
Meeting us all together must be very
intimidating.
I do hope so.
It was the first scene that
I did with pretty much
the entire upstairs cast
there looking at you.
It was very easy to access
those nerves and jitters
and everything because
they were kind of real.
But the elegant Lady Mary
keeps her composure in any
social situation, whatever
her personal feelings.
Hello, Miss Swire, I'm Mary Crawley.
Of course you are.
She realises very quickly that she
has to move on.
I mean, she's in her late
20s by the second series
and that's considered
kind of on the shelf.
You know, I love that,
that immediately she
invites Richard Carlisle
to meet the family.
We're pleased to have you here, Sir
Richard. Lady Grantham. Welcome.
Sir Richard Carlisle is a newspaper
proprietor,
inordinately wealthy, self-made man.
They're a wee bit suspicious of him
cos he's sort of new money.
And I think they probably think he's
slightly common.
I was asking about Haxby Park. I'm
taking Mary over there tomorrow.
Our Haxby Park? Why? Are the
Russells selling?
I'm not sure how
comfortable it is.
It'll be comfortable when
I'm finished with it.
Central heating, modern
kitchens, bathrooms
with every bedroom,
it's all possible.
Sounds more like an hotel.
You do get these very
rich, very powerful,
in some cases quite tough
individuals arriving
and buying these great estates up and
becoming sort of slightly ersatz toffs.
What'll we do about furniture and
pictures and everything?
What does anyone do?
Buy it, I presume.
Your lot buys it,
my lot inherits is.
In lots of ways he should appear a
good catch.
You see, I want you to marry me.
He's quite famous. Her position in
society would be very high.
She would have quite an interesting
life with him socially.
But he's...
You know, there's a toughness,
there's a ruthlessness about him
that is very much part of the
business that he's in.
I want to be a good husband and for
you to be happy
but don't ever cross me, do you
understand?
Never.
And having a little bit of badness
in you is always quite fun.
She's with this person who she's now
going to spend the rest of her life with
and she doesn't love him.
Lady Mary's true love is
back at the front fighting
for his country alongside
footman William.
Am I ready?
Only you can answer that, sir.
And they are not to be spared.
I had to run out of the
crater and look ahead as if
we were going to charge but
then hear the incoming.
Shout for him, push him out of the
way...
and then an explosion went off right
in front of our faces.
So, I essentiallysaved his life.
One last act of loyalty to
the members of the house.
Unlike William, Matthew
survives but like so many
veterans of the First World
War, he returns a broken man.
I've still got this funny thing with
my legs, I can't seem to move them.
You know, to be told
that you may never
walk again, you know,
it's not good news.
My God.
Is something wrong, sir?
No, nothing.
BUT miraculously...
It's too heavy for you.
No, it's not. Look out!
Heavens, that was a near thing.
My God.
I gather Julian did his medical
research, this has happened
and his ability to walk is recovered
slowly and quite surprisingly.
Mary! Girls! Cora! Come at once!
And then the celebrations
come in and those were lovely
scenes to play when we're
running down the stairs.
Action.
Cora! Everyone! Everyone, come at
once and see this!
And everyone's so excited and joyful
and weeping.
They use a steadicam
shot which is where our
cameraman sort of straps a
giant robot to his person
and charge down the stairs with
Lavinia, through the library,
and come and find me
slightly... surprised, I think.
Is it true? Is it true what Lavinia
says?
It's a miracle!
Is it true? Is it true what Lavinia
says?
I can't believe it.
It's so wonderful.
I cannot begin to tell
you what this means.
Well, it's pretty
good news for me too.
And there's more cause for
celebration upstairs and down.
I am sorry to disturb you but I...
I've just heard news from the War Office
and I thought you'd all like to know...
that the war is over.
But in Downton Abbey, as
in the rest of post-war
Europe, the euphoria
doesn't last long.
They had just got
to the end of this
massive killing fields
of central Europe,
they'd finally got home,
'Phew, I made it, '
and then as the war ends, Spanish
flu arrives and lays waste to them.
Are you too hot
in that, my lady?
We still have time to change.
No, I'm fine.
I thought it was important to fill
Downton with Spanish flu.
Molesley too? Good heavens.
Everyone's falling like ninepins.
Lavinia?
Do you know, I'm not at all well
either.
It was a vicious disease and
effected the young specifically,
which is what makes it all
the more tragic, especially
after World War I when
so many young men died.
And it did hit you hard and fast.
Wasn't there a masked ball in Paris,
when cholera broke out?
Half the guests were dead before
they left the ballroom.
Thank you, Mama. That's cheered us
up no end.
Oh, no.
Spanish flu was the worst
pandemic in history, killing
more than 50 million
people across the globe.
And as it wreaks havoc at Downton, Mary
and Matthew find themselves alone.
As much as he loves
Lavinia, as beautiful as
she is and as wonderful
as she's been to him,
there's a fire that he can't quite
put out and...
God, Mary.
He's a terribly romantically
confused man.
How can you resist, you know, you're
dancing with Lady Mary.
There's music playing,
it's, you know...
Hello?
What are you doing up?
She is head over heels in love with
Matthew
and to see him completely head over
heels in love with somebody else,
is the most devastating thing
imaginable.
But Lavinia has much more than a
broken heart to contend with.
How's Lavinia?
All right, I think.
The nature of Spanish flu was that
just as you appeared to look as
though you were recovering,
you were at your most vulnerable.
Is it Mama?
That's what's so... It's Lavinia.
If you then got the second degree of
Spanish flu and it went into the lungs,
you would die probably quite
quickly.
There was no medicine available, as
there is now, to deal with it.
Can you hear me? It's me.
It's Matthew.
I knew it was going to come to this
dramatic end and I loved that, actually,
I was, sort of, quite excited by
that.
Now, I'm kind of gutted
because I absolutely
loved doing this job,
absolutely loved it.
Be happy...
for my sake.
And then, of course, she takes it
that she has this broken heart,
which then leads to her death which
is so sudden.
We're cursed, you and I, and there's
nothing to be done about it.
He is a man in hell and the only thing
that will answer is to punish himself
because the one thing that mustn't
be rewarded, in his mind, is sin.
This is the end.
Of course it's the end.
After everything that's happened
above and below stairs,
Downton Abbey is in turmoil.
For the family and their staff,
things can't get much worse.
But who knows what might happen in
the future?
The Christmas special might give us
a few more clues.
A happy Christmas to us all.
ALL: Happy Christmas.
Don't forget to make a wish.
So, what are the cast hoping
Christmas will bring?
I would like Daisy to have a new dress
and a promotion and a new love interest.
I mean, I know I'm a dog's body
but...
How can you choose today, of all
days, to complain about your lot?
God, I just... I've no idea. I think
they are truly in love.
You would have to be to make that
kind of leap.
Things are going very, very badly in
terms of the future of the girls.
Cora, if there is something and you
know what it is, tell me, please.
Perhaps it's time.
Let's just say I hope things
improve.
Let's all make a wish.
A wish and a prayer.
Is this about Bates, again?
I think they'll come good in the
end.
I think they... they kind of... Well,
they don't have to, I suppose,
but I think everyone wants them to
do well.
How terrible it is. We mustn't lose
faith. He's been wrongly accused.
I'm sure you hope so. We know so.
Now, Thomas.
It would be nice to see
her having some sort of
personal happiness outside
cooking a souffle.
Be nice if she had a gentleman
friend, wouldn't it?
Happy new year.
ALL: Happy new year.
Well, Mary and Matthew have just got
to get together.
They're meant to be together.
I deserve to be unhappy, so does
Mary.
But maybe they can't be. I mean,
maybe it's too late.
Fingers crossed.
Forgive me if I'm casting a gloom.
Don't be silly.
And Lord Grantham would like...
Well, that would be telling.
Sync and corrected by APOLLO
www.MY-SUBS.com