WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
(MUFFLED AND DISTANT GUNFIRE)
(SHOUTING)
Here we are! You'll be all right!
Sergeant Stephens. Yes, sir.
I want every wounded man
taken down the line
before it starts to get dark.
We've bloody well lost enough of them
for one day.
When did this arrive?
This morning, sir.
Ah, good news.
We're to be relieved today
by the Devons.
The men can finally get some rest
and I've got a few days' leave
coming to me.
What will you do with them, sir?
London first.
To remind myself what real food
tastes like.
Then north for a couple of days,
I suppose.
Naturally, there's a girl I want to
see while I'm there.
So I should hope, sir.
It's strange, isn't it?
To think about our old lives just
going on as before.
While we're here, in this.
It's more than strange.
When I think of my life at Downton,
it seems like another world.
We normally have everything done
before the family wakes up,
but it's all at sixes and sevens
today.
I'll go through it with you
tomorrow, when we're back to normal.
I do know how to run a house.
Come along.
It goes under the epaulette.
I'm sorry, M'Lord.
If I'd known, I'd have asked
Mr Bates about it
before he left for London.
Because I'll be in uniform
a lot of the time, in future.
Does being lord lieutenant mean
you're back in the army?
Not exactly. The lord liet' is
responsible for the army
in the county while the war's on.
But, no, I'm not back in the army.
It appears they don't want me.
(BARKING)
Morning. I don't suppose there's
any news of Bates?
We expect him back any day, My Lord.
He wrote to Anna that they had the
funeral last Monday.
William's a good chap, but he's not
Bates when it comes to uniforms.
I may not be a real soldier,
Isobel said she was coming up
to help
and your mother threatened
to look in.
No doubt they would love it
if they found me still in bed.
I don't believe it.
Please say it's something nice.
General Robertson's invited me
to be Colonel of the North Riding
Volunteers. This is the best bit.
(READS)
'lt may please you to know
that the idea was given to me
by General Haig.'
Well if Haig's involved, it means
I'm back in the army properly.
How can that be? You were told you
weren't wanted for active service.
You can't jump in and out of the
army like a jack-in-the-box.
I don't see why not.
Churchill went back to the front
after the Gallipoli business.
If he can do it, why shouldn't I?
Sybil, are you all right?
Sybil, darling?
Would you excuse me.
I think I'll just...
She's had more bad news.
I do think I'm getting better,
don't you? Up to a point, M'Lady.
(GEARS CRUNCH)
If you could just get the clutch
right down to the floor. But I am.
Not quite, M'Lady.
It doesn't seem to want to go.
I think it wants to,
if you ask it properly.
(GEARS CRUNCH AND RELEASE)
That's better.
You'll be putting me out of a job.
Won't the call up put you all
out of your jobs?
I'll cross that bridge
when I come to it.
(HORN BEEPS)
What are you giving them to eat?
Not much.
They know the money's
for the hospital,
so they can't expect
Belshazzar's Feast.
I'll make some cheese straws.
What's the matter with you?
Nothing much.
My dad still won't let me enlist.
Your father has no-one but you.
Of course he doesn't want you to
enlist. Who can argue with him?
So I stand by while the lads on the
farms and in the gardens go to war.
Even Thomas is at the front in the
Medical Corps.
Ha, that'll come as a nasty shock.
Oh, you can make fun of him,
Mrs Patmore,
but he's fight for his king and
country and I'm not.
Well, I dare say you won't have long
to wait.
Well, I hope you're right.
Do you?
Because I don't.
I hope very much that I am wrong.
It's kind of you to let us have it
here. They'll enjoy it so much more.
And you can charge so much more
for the tickets.
Good morning, Mama. This is very
early for you to be up and about.
War makes early risers of us all.
I thought I would help with
the flowers.
Bassett has plenty...
but thank you.
You don't mind my taking over
the flowers, do you?
Cora's flowers always look more
suited to a first communion...
in southern Italy.
Well, what else have you planned
for tonight's revels?
Anything we can think of that will
raise money.
Hot, buttered toast with a countess
at tuppence a slice?
You drop the cushions on the floor
to plump them up.
I know.
Ethel, are you settling in?
I would be... if Anna'd stop
teaching me how to suck eggs.
I was head housemaid
in my last position.
You were senior housemaid,
out of two, in a much smaller house.
Are they to come in here tonight?
Only at the interval. And keep them
out of the drawing room.
I thought Mr Bates would've been
back by now,
or he could've stood guard.
Who is this Mr Bates?
His Lordship's valet.
He's been in London
because his mother died.
Only everyone talks about him
as if her were king.
Do they? That's nice to hear.
Anna...
help me do battle with
this monstrosity.
Looks like a creature from
The Lost World.
Oh...
You should let William do that.
He's got enough on his hands,
getting the uniforms out of
mothballs.
(STRAINED) I must remember to put
Anna on alert for dinner tonight.
You have to ease up a bit or you'll
give yourself a heart attack.
There's a war on. Things cannot
be the same when there's a war on.
I do not agree. Keeping up standards
is the only way to show the Germans
that they will not beat us
in the end.
Well, give me some warning
the next time
we're expecting Germans at Downton
and I'll see what I can do.
Thank you.
Oh, we thought we'd come in here
for a little talk.
Oh, well I'm sure we won't be
disturbed.
Please.
Well, the thing is...
I've had a letter from Matthew.
Of course, he doesn't tell me
what he's actually doing.
No, he wouldn't.
But I'm glad he's all right.
I miss him.
Well, that's the point.
You must know he's been down here
a few times since the war started.
We had heard.
Downton is hardly a metropolis.
Is he still determined to go back
to Manchester when it's all over?
He doesn't talk much about life
after the war, none of them do.
I suppose they don't want to
tempt fate.
Until now, that is.
He writes that he is engaged to be
married to a Miss Lavinia Swire.
Well... I suppose we all knew
it would happen one day.
Do you know her?
Not yet.
Apparently they met when he was in
England last time.
It all seems rather hurried.
You can't blame them for wanting to
live in the present.
Anyway, he's been in London on leave
and now he's bringing her here to
meet me.
He'll be here tonight and tomorrow,
and then he leaves on Thursday,
while she stays for a bit.
So will you miss the concert?
Well, that's up to you.
We'd all hoped that he and Mary
would sort things out between them.
But if that's not to be, shouldn't
we try to get back to normal?
Even if he's not keen to live
in the village...
he's still the heir.
And you're still his family.
I quite agree.
We can't know if Matthew will come
through it.
Either way, I would like to see him
and I want to wish him luck.
The trouble is, Mary's back from
London today as well.
She gets in at five o'clock.
Matthew's driving down in Lavinia's
car, they won't meet on the train.
Oh, that's a relief.
I hate Greek drama.
You know, when everything happens
off stage.
But should we tell her not to come?
We might still catch her.
Isobel's right.
We must use this engagement
as a new beginning.
You bring our Lieutenant Crawley
to the concert
and stay for dinner afterwards.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Oh, there you are. I'm just going
home, but I'll be back at four.
Sybil, my dear, what's the matter?
Tom Bellasis has been killed.
What a terrible thing.
I remember him at Imogen's ball.
He made me laugh out loud just as
her uncle was giving a speech.
Sometimes...
it feels as if all the men
I ever danced with are dead.
I just feel so useless,
wasting my life while they sacrifice
theirs.
You've been a tremendous help with
the concert. No, I...
I don't mean selling programmes or
finding prizes for the tombola.
I want to do a real job, real work.
Well...
if you're serious, what about
being an auxiliary nurse?
There's a training college in York.
I know I could get you on to
a course.
It may be something of a rough
awakening. Are you ready for that?
I mean, have you ever made
your own bed, for example?
Or scrubbed a floor?
O'Brien, what is it?
Mr Platt is taking Her Ladyship and
Lady Grantham down to the village.
She wondered if you'd like to go
with them.
That's very kind. Thank you.
Go on, what else would I need?
Well, if you're serious,
what about cooking?
Why don't you ask Mrs Patmore
if she could give you one or two
basic tips?
When you get to York,
it might be useful
to know a little more than nothing.
They want to use her as a maid of
all work at the hospital.
I suppose it's cheaper when Lady
Sybil can live here for nothing.
But it doesn't see quite right,
somehow, to take advantage.
No, it does not.
I hear the young men that are being
brought in now are very disfigured.
How terrible.
Limbs missing and faces blown apart.
And Lady Sybil's been nurtured
so very gently.
And what types would she be working
with?
Still, you'll know what's best
to do.
Yes.
I certainly will.
Where's the butter for the pancakes?
It's in the cold larder.
Are we having pancakes tonight?
Are we heck as like.
Upstairs dinner, crepes Suzette.
Oh, I've always wanted to try those.
Could you save me some?
If they don't finish them all.
Save you some crepes Suzette?
If you don't mind.
What are we having?
Lamb stew and semolina.
Do you eat a lot of stews?
Don't you fancy that, dear?
Not all the time.
Oh, I see.
Would you like to sleep
in Her Ladyship's bedroom
while you're at it?
I wouldn't mind.
I hate sharing a room.
I didn't in my last place.
There were only two maids
and a cook. I'm just saying.
And I'll 'just say' if you don't
look out!
You've got a cheek,
on your first day.
I don't see why.
I want the best and I'm not ashamed
to admit it.
And you think we don't?
I think it's hard to change
at your age.
I don't blame you, but I suppose,
in the end, I want to be more than
just a servant.
I'm sorry,
but if Dr Clarkson needs free labour,
I'd prefer him not to find it in
my nursery.
But Sybil isn't in the nursery.
And in case you hadn't noticed,
she hasn't been there for some time.
You know what I mean.
Well, no, not really.
You can't pretend it's not
respectable.
When every day we're treated to
pictures of queens and princesses
in Red Cross uniform, ladling soup
down the throat of some unfortunate.
But Sybil won't be ladling soup.
She'll have to witness unimaginable
horrors.
When she's an innocent.
Her innocence will protect her.
For once, I agree with
Cousin Isobel.
Sybil must be allowed to do her bit,
like everyone else.
What about you, Molesley? Are you
ready for the call, if it comes?
It won't be coming for me, M'Lady.
I had a letter from the War Office
to say I'm not suitable for service.
Why not?
I really couldn't say, M'Lady.
As you can imagine, Molesley's
father is beside himself with joy.
God moves in a mysterious way.
His wonders to perform.
Bates, no-one told me
you were on this train.
They didn't know, M'Lady.
We'll give you a lift to the house.
Why didn't you say you were coming?
I didn't know till today.
Anna, I borrowed a case from
Lady Rosamund.
I bought some things while I was
in London. Very good, M'Lady.
Well, it would be our secret.
A surprise. You don't mind, do you?
Oh, it's not that I mind, M'Lady...
And I only need the basics.
How to boil an egg, how to make tea.
Don't you know how to make tea?
Not really.
You're right, it is a joke.
But when I start my course,
I don't want to be a joke.
Will you help me?
Course we will, won't we?
If you say so.
Let's get started.
Do you know how to fill a kettle?
Everyone knows that.
Not everyone, apparently.
Oh...
When can I talk to you?
After the concert.
Outside, in the courtyard.
There's bound to be a gap
before they start dinner.
Are you going up for the concert?
Maybe. Can I sit with you?
Don't be daft, we've got a dinner
to make.
I've not got time for concerts.
I've had a letter from my dad.
He won't change his mind.
He says he can live with it
if I get called up, as there's
nothing we can do.
But if I enlist and anything
happens, he'll never get over it.
He loves you. He may love me,
but he doesn't own me.
And he's not being fair.
Glad to be back?
I'm never sure.
When I'm in London, I long
for Yorkshire and when I'm here,
I ache to hear my heels clicking on
the pavement.
I'd forgotten about this nightmare
concert.
Why didn't you warn me?
I'd have come back tomorrow.
But you'd have missed Matthew.
I was going to tell you.
Matthew's on leave and he's in the
village,
so Papa and I thought it would be
a good time to mend our fences.
He's coming tonight with Isobel.
And his fiancee.
What?
Edith...
I don't know how helpful
you're being.
Matthew's engaged.
He's brought her to Downton to meet
his mother.
Well, how marvellous.
You don't mind?
Why should I?
We're not going to marry,
but I don't want him to spend the
rest of his life in a cave.
Exactly what Papa and I feel.
Please try to be happy for him.
Of course I'm happy.
Good luck to him.
Anyway, there's someone I want you
all to meet.
Have you ever come across
Richard Carlisle?
Sir Richard Carlisle?
The one with all those horrid
newspapers?
We met at Cliveden.
But how old is he?
Old enough not to ask
stupid questions.
Anyway, I can't wait for you to know
him.
If only Papa hadn't closed down
the shoot.
Most people have stopped shooting
now that the war's on.
But I'm sure Papa would be happy to
have Sir Richard come and stay.
Are you? I shouldn't have thought
he was Papa's type at all.
Are you coming?
I'll be down in a minute.
Are you all right, M'Lady?
Oh, Anna...
It's awfully grand.
You'd better get used to it.
It'll be your home one day.
I'm not sure 'home' would ever be
quite the word to describe it.
My dear fellow, welcome back.
It's so very good to see you.
May I present Miss Lavinia Swire?
How do you do, Lord Grantham.
How do you do, Miss Swire.
So... that's Mary's replacement.
Well, I suppose looks aren't
everything.
I think she seems rather sweet.
I'm afraid meeting us all together
must be very intimidating.
I do hope so.
Now, please come this way.
Thank you.
It's good to see you.
Hello, Miss Swire, I'm Mary Crawley.
Of course you are. I mean,
I've been longing to meet you
because I've heard so much about you
from Matthew.
Oh, that is...
Nice things, I hope.
What else would she hear from me?
Please.
I can't say.
It's been such a long time.
Who knows what you think of me now?
I think...
I'm very glad to see you looking
so well.
All right, you win.
We are at peace again.
(ORCHESTRA STARTS PLAYING)
Have you found something nice?
Why, particularly?
As a welcome home for Mr Matthew.
(GRUNTS)
Oh, what's the matter?
I'm thought you'd come round to him.
Last time he was here, he hadn't
broken Lady Mary's heart.
Lady Mary broke her own heart.
That's if she has a heart to break.
I don't think we're ever going to see
eye to eye on this, Mrs Hughes.
She refused him when she thought
he'd have nothing.
And when he was heir again,
she wanted him back.
I thought caution was a virtue.
Caution may be, self interest is
not.
Perhaps Miss Swire is a gentler
person.
If you ask me, this Miss Swire,
who, it may interest you to know,
is not to be found in Burke's Peerage
or Burke's Landed Gentry, has an eye
to the main chance.
That's not snobbish, I suppose.
I like to see things done properly,
Mrs Hughes,
and I won't apologise for that.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
What is it?
A white feather, of course.
Coward.
Stop this at once!
(ORCHESTRA HALTS ABRUPTLY)
This is neither the time
nor the place.
These people should be aware
that there are cowards among them.
Will you please leave?
You are the cowards here, not they!
Leader, will you continue.
(ORCHESTRA STARTS PLAYING)
I'm in a uniform.
Wrong kind.
That was horrid, William.
I hope you won't let it upset you.
No, Your Ladyship.
Why are these women so unkind?
Of course it is horrid,
but when heroes are giving their
lives every day,
it's hard to watch healthy,
young men do nothing.
By the way, Sybil, very good news,
they do have a vacancy.
It's very short notice,
because someone dropped out.
You'd have to be ready to start
on Friday.
May I ask what this is about?
Cousin Isobel has got me a place on
a nursing course in York.
I want to work at the hospital.
We don't have to talk about it now.
She just turned up at my mother's
house.
Not long before she died.
So... what does it mean?
I think it means, at long last...
I'm able to get a divorce.
Mr Bates...
is this a proposal?
If that's what you want to call it.
And you might start calling me John.
Well, why are you sure she'll do it
now, when she's refused for so long?
Mother left me some money, much more
than I thought.
Vera's a greedy woman, she won't
refuse what I can offer her.
Will we have to leave Downton?
Not until we want to.
I've spoken to His Lordship
and he will find a cottage for us
near the house.
You told him you want to marry me?
I did.
Before you spoke to me?
You don't mind, do you?
Of course I mind!
In fact, I'd give you a smack
if I didn't want to kiss you so much
I could burst.
Branson says I'm ready for the road.
That's not what he told me.
Oh, how delicious, I love these.
How did you and Matthew meet?
Oh, in London. My father works in
London, so I've always lived there.
But I love the country, too.
Of course you do.
Daddy's a solicitor, like Matthew.
My, my. You're very well placed if
you're ever in trouble with the law.
Did I tell you I've been given
a colonelcy
in the North Riding Volunteers?
So I'm properly in the army again.
Oh, congratulations.
Yeah...
He won't go with them, will he?
When they're called to the front.
I hope not, but he seems to think
so.
What's it been like?
Do you know, the thing is...
I just can't talk about it.
Have you missed us?
What do you think?
You don't mind my bringing Lavinia?
On the contrary, I'm glad.
Glad to see you happy.
What about you? Are you happy?
I think I'm about to be happy.
Does that count?
It does if you mean it.
You'll be the first to know.
What are reading?
A photoplay about Mabel Normand.
She was nothing when she started,
you know.
Her father was a carpenter and
they'd no money.
And now she's a shining film star.
Ethel, I've a message for you
from Her Ladyship.
You're to go up and she her now.
What where?
In the drawing room, of course.
They're all in the drawing room.
What have I done wrong?
Nothing. Quite the reverse.
She's very pleased with the way
you've begun
and she wants to thank you.
Now?
Yes, now.
She's asked for you. How much longer
are you going to keep her waiting?
I don't know much about
life in the country,
but I do understand
how the law works,
so I believe I can be helpful
to Matthew there.
But you'll be immensely helpful.
Don't you think so, Mary?
Of course.
I beg your pardon, M'Lady,
for keeping you waiting. What?
I'm ever so grateful for your
appreciation
and I want you to know that it's
a privilege to work here.
Ethel, what are you doing in here?
Er... Her Ladyship sent for me.
And who gave you this message?
Miss O'Brien. She said I wasn't to
keep Her Ladyship waiting.
You may go back downstairs now,
thank you, Ethel.
Right.
Thank you, M'Lady.
Well...
do we think she's mad, ill
or working for the Russians?
She has plenty of time to learn.
Cousin Robert will be in charge here
for many years.
Lavinia will be a lawyer's wife far
longer than she'll be a countess.
That's if I get through the war in
one piece.
Of course you will.
Don't even think like that.
How long are you staying in the
village? Just tomorrow.
I take the six o'clock train on
Thursday.
And then you'll be in France.
Wherever I'm going, I'm so pleased
that we're friends again.
I still don't understand why it was
funny to make me look a fool.
You weren't even there to enjoy it.
Oh, don't worry.
We enjoyed it all right from down
here.
Miss O'Brien, Her Ladyship has asked
me to take the incident no further.
Don't tempt me to disobey.
Did I see Lady Sybil in the kitchen
yesterday?
She wants to learn some cooking.
She says she's going to train to be
a nurse,
so she needs to know how to cook
and clean and everything.
Has she told Her Ladyship about this?
It's supposed to be a surprise.
Mr Carson, it speaks well
of Lady Sybil
that she wants to help the wounded.
Let's not give her away.
Why shouldn't she learn how to cook
and scrub?
She may need it when the war's over.
Things are changing,
for her lot and us.
And when they do, I mean to make
the most of it.
(MRS PATMORE SNIGGERS)
I take it they ate all the pancakes
last night, then?
They did.
(WHISTLES)
Here you are.
What are we aiming at?
They'd like us to take 100 wounded
men.
Three times the number the hospital
was built for.
Well, that settles it. We'll have to
convert the second day room.
So there's to be no convalescence at
all?
I'm afraid not. Once they can stand,
they must go.
If only there was somewhere nearer
than Farley Hall.
I can't get there more than twice
a week at the most.
Ah, should he be doing that?
Why not?
I only meant with his condition.
What condition is that?
His lungs.
Old Lady Grantham told me he's had
a lot of trouble with his lungs.
And why did she tell you that,
particularly?
She wanted me to write to the
War Office.
She was anxious to spare him the
humiliation
of being refused on medical grounds.
And who else did she wish you to
take under your protection?
William Mason, the footman at
the big house.
He has a bad skin condition,
apparently, and hates people to know.
She wanted to spare him the physical
examination.
I'm sure she did.
What in Wonderland do you call that?!
I mean, I do not fully understand
what you're trying to do, M'Lady.
Oh, I knew it wasn't supposed to
look like this.
No, M'Lady. I would go so far as to
say
there is no food on the Earth
that is supposed to look like that.
Why does everything go so lumpy?
Tell you what, chuck it out and
we'll start again.
I don't think we should sell your
mother's house, not yet.
We could rent it out.
Then we can save.
When I've some time off, I'll go up
to London and get it ready.
Maybe I can come with you.
We could do it together.
I've got an idea,
that a bit later on...
if we want to...
if we want to start a family.
I thought, when the time is right,
we might sell.
And we could buy a small hotel.
Just... just a little one.
Maybe near here.
Then we could work together and
have the children with us.
What is it?
Nothing, it's just...
in my whole life, I never thought
I could be as happy
as I am at this moment.
Don't worry, I haven't come to undo
your good work of the other night.
You must have been up before
the servants.
They were rather surprised to see me.
I wanted to give you this.
It's my lucky charm.
I've had it always.
So you must promise to bring it back,
without a scratch.
Won't you need it?
Not as much as you.
So look after it, please.
I'll try not to be a hero,
if that's what you're afraid of.
Just come back, safe and sound.
Did you have a happy time yesterday?
I showed Lavinia the places I like
most. To give her a few memories.
Mary, if I don't come back -
But - No.
If I don't.
Then do remember how very glad I am
that we made up when we had the
chance.
I mean it.
You send me off to war a happy man.
Will you do something for me?
Will you...
Will you look after Mother,
if anything happens?
Of course we will, but it won't.
And Lavinia.
She's young, she'll find someone
else, I hop she does anyway.
But... until she does.
(WHISTLE)
Goodbye, then.
And such good luck.
Goodbye, Mary.
And God bless you.
Lady Mary was very much part of the
story, I can assure you.
But how do you know?
Well, you see I worked for Lady Flin-
Ethel...
I hope you've offered our visitor
some tea.
I'll go and ask Daisy.
What is the first law of service?
We do not discuss the business of
this house with strangers.
But she's not a stranger.
She's Mr Bates' wife.
Has anyone told him she's here?
So you're Anna.
I am.
You're the one who went to call on
my late, lamented mother-in-law.
Yes, I did.
I know you did.
Sorry to keep you waiting, Vera.
I was up in the attics, sorting out
some cupboards.
Don't worry. I've been having
a nice time
here with Ethel and Miss Smith.
Mr Bates, Ethel told me about your
visitor.
So I've had the tea put in my
sitting room.
I thought you might take Mrs Bates
in there.
That's very thoughtful.
It is.
But then you're all so kind.
I'm beginning to understand why
my Batesy's got so spoiled.
I'm sorry to trouble you, My Lady.
What is it, Carson?
Something has been going on
and I don't feel quite easy that
you've not been made aware of it.
Goodness. What is this dark secret?
Lady Sybil has spent
the last two days in the kitchen.
What? She asked Mrs Patmore
for some cooking lessons.
Now, steady. Even the most
experience cook can burn themself
if they're not careful.
Do you think it's ready?
I know it's ready.
Go on, you don't want to spoil it.
It seems she's made a cake for
Your Ladyship, as a surprise.
But I'm uneasy with surprises
at the best of times
and I wonder if the whole exercise
is entirely appropriate. Ta-dah!
I'm not comfortable with this,
My Lady. Not comfortable at all.
I was worried about Lady Sybil,
but I'm not worried any more.
So you don't mind, My Lady?
No.
I do not mind.
And I'm very grateful to you.
And, Carson, the cake will be a
surprise whether you approve or not.
So please don't give me away.
Sit down.
I don't want to sit down.
Suit yourself.
Look, I'm not saying it's all your
fault for how things were between us.
But I couldn't go back to that.
I'll take the blame. I'll go to some
hotel in Malton with a tart.
So why hold on?
Because I tried it on my own
and I don't like it.
You've got money now,
we'd be comfortable.
You're out of your mind.
What makes you think that I would
allow that to happen?
You went to prison for me once.
I must say, this is very good.
Does Lord Grantham have his own
blend?
Is that all?
Not quite.
You see, if you don't come back to
me,
I'm going to the newspapers with
a cracking story
and I'd like to bet the Grantham's
won't survive it.
Oh? And what nonsense is this?
The nonsense I heard when I used
your name
to get a job with Lady Flintshire,
his Lordship's cousin.
I know who Lady Flintshire is.
Well, when I arrived,
her maid asked me if it was true.
About Lady Mary Crawley and the
Turkish diplomat.
They thought I'd know, you see,
being your wife.
I hope you told them you knew nothing
about it.
Oh... As if.
I said, 'Why don't you tell me what
you think you know
and I'll tell you if it's true.'
Goodness me.
Wasn't my patience rewarded.
The public's bored with the war,
you see.
They like gossip.
And a diplomat dying in the bed of
an earl's unmarried daughter,
well, that takes the ticket for the
tale of the year.
It's a pack of lies! I assume
that's loyalty and not ignorance.
Because, you see, I heard
that Lady Mary needed
her maid to help her carry him and,
yes, you've guessed it,
your precious Anna's going to figure
in the story, too.
Not to worry too much.
It's not a criminal offence, is it?
Just a social one.
You bitch.
Please, be my guest.
But then you must excuse me
while I run into town and have it
photographed.
What do you want from me?
Firstly, hand in your notice...
tonight.
I'll put up at the pub in the
village.
And what reason do I give?
You don't need a reason.
Just tell them that you're going.
And then tomorrow we head back to
London.
We'll stay in your mother's house
for the time being,
till we get ourselves sorted.
And in case you're wondering,
whatever my future plans may be,
they will involve you.
Bates, when you first came here,
I fought to keep you!
Everyone was against me, everyone,
from Her Ladyship to Carson.
They thought I was mad.
But I said to them,
'After all that we've been through,
Bates and I,
I owe him my loyalty!'
I appreciate that, M'Lord, but...
But what? But loyalty doesn't matter
to you? It does matter, M'Lord.
Not enough to make you change your
mind. Not even enough
to make you stay until I've found
a replacement!
I can't. You won't take any more
money off me. You leave empty-handed!
I don't want money, M'Lord.
I'm sorry, Bates, that was a low
shot.
Of course you can have whatever is
owning to you.
I thought we were friends,
that's all.
I thought we'd crossed the great
divide, successfully.
Well, I've had my say,
it's your life.
But you've disappointed me, Bates.
I cannot remember being more
disappointed in any man.
I don't believe it.
You say my life is over
and your wife will collect you first
thing and that's it?
Have you mentioned this to anyone
else?
Only Mr Carson and Mrs Hughes.
The others can find out when
I've gone.
I know you've not told me the real
reason. You're wrong.
Vera has reminded me
that I'm a married man.
I must give my vows another chance.
I had not right to involve you in
my life. Yes, but you see,
that's just what I don't agree with.
You had every right.
I know you.
You're doing something gallant here,
making a sacrifice for my honour,
but I don't want you to.
I don't care. Don't you understand?
I don't care what people say.
I'd live in sin with you.
If she's threatening to ruin me,
then let her. It's nothing to me.
The only ruin that I recognise is to
be without you.
Forget me and be happy, please.
I couldn't. Not ever.
You should and you must.
I am nothing.
William? I thought everyone had gone
up.
I'm just looking for that magazine
Ethel were reading.
I hope you've noticed I'm not scared
of electricity any more.
Well, not much. I couldn't touch
a switch when it were only upstairs,
but I've got used to it now.
I hate to see you like this.
Even though I'm a dirty coward?
You're not. Not to me.
But why don't I enlist?
I could.
I know I promised my dad,
but he's not my owner.
He's not the law.
Am I frightened?
Is that it, honestly?
Don't be so hard on yourself.
No-one wants to go to war.
Oh, I wish you'd cheer up, please.
I'd do anything to cheer you up.
Like what?
Like this.
You just feel sorry for me.
William, I've kissed you!
You've wanted me to long enough.
Well, now I have. Enjoy it.
Does this mean you'll be my girl?
Daisy? Cos if you were my girl,
I know I could tackle anything.
We were supposed to be at rest for
ten days at least.
Orders arrived this morning, sir.
The King's Own were hit bad,
so they're out and we're in.
They've been shelling the trench
since we got here. Anybody hurt?
Rankin's dead and
Kent and Corporal Wright was hit.
Thank God the stretcher bearers were
there.
Let's see what the damage is now.
Sir.
All right?
Morning, sir.
Look out!
Medic!
Thomas?
It is Thomas, isn't it?
Corporal Barrow now, Mr Crawley.
You'll never guess
where I've just been.
Where's Anna? She's not feeling very
well today, Your Ladyship.
I've taken over for the time being.
Oh, that's so kind of you.
Just make sure Lady Sybil packs
things
she can get in and out of
without a maid.
Oh, I don't need that.
I'd never wear it.
But you must have something decent.
Suppose you're invited to dinner?
I know this is hard for you to
grasp,
but I'm not there to go out to
dinner. I'm there to learn.
Take one, just in case.
We'll miss you. Don't be silly,
it's only two months.
And I'll come home if I can.
Why don't I drive you? She's taking
enough chance with her life as it is.
Oh, Granny.
What is this driving mania?
It'll be useful.
They won't let a healthy man drive
us around for much longer.
And if Sybil can be a nurse,
why can't I be a chauffeur?
Well, I shall leave you.
I have been summoned by Cousin Isobel
for tea.
Goodbye, Sybil.
And good luck with it all.
Thank you for being such a sport.
It's a big step you're taking, dear.
But war deals out strange tasks.
Remember your great aunt, Roberta.
What about her?
She loaded the guns at Lucknow.
I'll come with you.
I'll tell William to fetch the bags.
The first of you to leave the nest.
Poor Mama. She always feels
these things so dreadfully.
That's her American blood.
I'm so glad we've settled everything
with Cousin Matthew.
Aren't you, Mary? Oh, please
stop treading on eggshells.
I've other fish to fry.
I make no apology.
It would be a terrible thing if poor,
old Mr Molesley's son were killed.
Wouldn't it, Molesley?
I'm sure it would, but...
And then I heard William's father
would be left on his own if anything
happened to the boy.
And what would become of Carson if
the last of his staff were to go?
That's not the point.
Do you want Molesley to die?
Of course I don't!
Well.
I don't want my own son to die,
either.
But this is a war and we must be in
it together!
High and low, rich and poor.
There can be no special cases,
because every man at the front
is a special case to someone.
Mrs Crawley is right.
I understand your motives,
Lady Grantham,
and I do not criticise them.
Thank you. But I shall write
to the Ministry at once,
correcting the misinformation.
Good day. I'll see myself out.
Molesley, you understand why I said
what I did?
Indeed. I do, ma'am.
You won't be called up at once.
Not while there are younger men to
be taken.
But they'll get you in the end,
Molesley.
And you can blame Mrs Crawley
when they do.
I wish you'd stop working
for one minute.
At least put the light on,
or you'll strain your eyes.
It's getting dark so early now.
Has she gone?
She has.
So... we've lost Mr Bates
and Lady Sybil in one day.
I can't believe it.
I suppose I'll have to look after
His Lordship now,
on top of everything else.
And I don't want any jokes
about broomsticks and sweeping
the floor.
His Lordship's got his regimental
dinner in Richmond tonight.
That means he'll be in the full fig.
You'll manage.
You know, when Mr Bates first came
to this house,
I thought he could never do the work.
But now I can't imagine the place
without him.
Did you see this coming?
Because I didn't.
I have a confession.
I let them have their tea
in my sitting room.
That was nice of you.
It was quite nice.
But I had my reasons.
There's a grating on the wall
which means you can hear what's
being said in the room.
Now if I was a gentleman,
I wouldn't want to know.
But you're not.
Fortunately.
It'll be hard to let you go.
My last link with home.
Not as hard as it is for me.
Branson - I know I shouldn't say it,
but I can't keep it in any longer.
I wish you would. I told myself and
told myself, you're too far above me.
But things are changing.
When the war is over,
the world won't be the same place
as it was when it started.
And I'll make something of myself,
I promise. I know you will.
Then bet on me.
And if your family casts you off,
it won't be forever.
They'll come around.
And until they do,
I promise to devote every waking
minute to your happiness.
I'm terribly flattered.
Don't say that.
Why not?
Because 'flattered' is a word posh
people use
when they're getting ready to say no.
That sounds more like you.
Please don't make fun of me.
No. It's cost me all I've got
to say these things.
Right.
I'll go. I'll hand in my notice
and I won't be there when you get
back - No, don't do that.
I must. They won't let me stay
when they've heard what I've said.
They won't hear.
Not from me.
Bloody hell.
There must be more to life than this.
You all right, Corporal?
I think so. Yeah, more or less.
My God.
They won't believe it back home
where I come from.
I thought, 'Medical Corps,
not much danger there.'
How wrong can one man be?
Here.
I think it comes down to luck.
If a bullet's got your name on it,
there's nothing you can do.
If not, then thank God you were
lucky...
Get these bodies away!
Come on, Corporal Barrow!
I cannot tell you how pleased I am to
be here tonight, sir.
Oh, we are very pleased to have you
here, Grantham.
You see, just to know that I'm with
you all, to sense that I belong here.
It's as simple as this,
I no longer feel like a fraud.
Mr Molesley, what are you doing
here?
I was waiting to see you, Doctor.
How can I help?
It's just I was wondering whether
you'd written that letter.
The one you spoke of this afternoon.
To the War Office?
Not yet. I'm sorry
you were involved in all that.
I should've checked with you first,
before I interfered.
That's just it. You see, I think if
you had checked with me,
you'd have found exactly what
Lady Grantham described.
I don't quite...
I have trouble with my lungs.
I get so...
breathless sometimes.
And...
I've noticed it's getting worse.
They haven't written to William yet.
The Ministry, I mean.
But they have discharged me.
Won't it just make extra work for
them
to have to fail me all over again?
Very well.
I shall correct my statement as
regards William,
but make no mention of you.
Thank you, Doctor.
It's all right.
But, Molesley...
I hope you will help the war effort,
in other ways.
When might the regiment be wanted,
sir?
The talk at dinner suggested
it would be soon.
Oh, pretty soon, I'd say.
Well, I'm as ready now
as I'll ever be.
For what?
To go to France, with the regiment.
Why would you do that?
Because I'm their colonel, of course.
Well, there must be some use for me
over there.
My dear fellow, we're not as
heartless as that!
The position's only an honorary one.
Nobody expects you to go to war.
An honorary one? We thought
it'd cheer things up a bit
to have the Lord Lieutenant
at our table.
And so it does. We're very glad
to welcome to you here.
I see. We old codgers
have our work cut out for us
keeping spirits high at home.
Someone must.
Oh, indeed, sir.
Is that Taxi Cavendish?
I must catch him before I go.
So Lady Sybil got off all right in
the end.
I'm afraid we have to admit
she knows what she wants.
Yes. She certainly does.
I don't suppose the war will leave
any of us alone
by the time it's done.
I got a letter from Thomas the other
day.
He writes that when he thinks about
how things used to be,
it seems like a dream.
It's not much more than two years
ago,
but he says it might as well be a
century.
So you hear from Thomas. Is he well?
Please give him my regards.
He's well enough, M'Lady.
But I don't think he'd mind coming
home.
Oh, how I wish he could, O'Brien.
Of course, if Bates hadn't been so
bloody selfish,
he would have let us plan for his
departure properly.
Your Lordship, I have information
that I have no proper claim to.
Well, what is it?
Well, if Your Lordship can assure me
that you will keep it to yourself?
I promise, Carson.
You can drop the last veil.
Well, I feel it only right to tell
you
that Mr Bates' leaving was not
selfish.
Quite the reverse.
It felt selfish to me.
As for the wretched Anna,
bedizened with dishonest promises.
Mr Bates left because had he not
done so,
his wife was planning to engulf
this house in scandal.
Scandal?
What scandal?
The point is, My Lord,
Mrs Bates would have made Downton
notorious.
The price of her silence was her
husband's return.
But I must know what story she was
planning to tell.
I'm sorry, My Lord,
I could not speak of it
without injuring you and
betraying myself.
But you are saying that Bates
fell on his sword
to protect the reputation
of my family?
Ethel, what are you doing?
Seeing to the plugs for the night.
What? Polishing the electric plugs
and checking them for vapours.
And why are you doing this?
Because you were too busy.
She said you usually did it,
but could I manage it tonight.
And 'she', I take it,
would be Miss O'Brien?
Go to bed, Ethel.
Next time she gives you an order,
ask me first.
Is anything the matter?
Nothing.
Except that today has shown me
I'm not only a worthless man,
but also a bad-tempered and
ungrateful one.
Well, we all know that.
Can I help?
I wonder how Sybil's feeling.
The war's reaching its long fingers
into Downton
and scattering our chicks.
But I'm glad we made peace
with Matthew.
I agree.
Let us thank Sir Richard Carlisle
for distracting Mary
at just the right moment.
By the way, she wants him to come
and stay. So we can all meet him.
She wants us to invite a hawker of
newspaper scandal
to stay as a guest in this house?
It's lucky I have a sense of irony.
(SNIFFLING)
Not you, too.
What's the matter?
Why ask? You don't care.
Ethel...
Perhaps if you stopped going on
about all the marvellous things
you're going to do when you leave
service.
But you've got to have dreams.
Don't you have any dreams?
Of course I do.
Big dreams.
It's just that I know now
they won't be coming true.
What do you want?
I think I left my book in here.
Is that all?
You were praying.
Don't be ridiculous.
What were you praying for?
Please go. I'm tired.
Dear Lord,
I don't pretend to have much credit
with you.
I'm not even sure that you're there.
But if you are,
and if I've ever done anything good,
I beg you to keep him safe.
You look very comfortable there,
Corporal.
Would you like some, sir?
We've got condensed milk and sugar.
I won't ask how you managed that.
Go on, sir.
Oh, that's nectar.
Are you sure you can spare it?
Gladly, if we can talk about
the old days
and forget about all of this
for a minute or two.
Do you ever hear from anyone?
Oh, yes.
Miss O'Brien keeps me informed.
Lady Edith's driving.
Lady Sybil's training as a nurse.
Miss O'Brien tells me the hospital's
busier than ever,
with the wounded coming in.
Is that true?
Certainly is.
They had a concert when I was there
to raise extra funds.
I'm curious, sir.
Do you think I could ever get a
transfer back to the hospital?
Seeing as it's war work.
Well, you'd have to be sent home
from the front, first.
And then you might have to
pull a few strings.
Thank you for that.
Thank you very much.
What would my mother say?
Me entertaining the future
Earl of Grantham to tea.
War has a way of distinguishing
between the things that matter
and the things that don't.
(GUNSHOT)
Thank you.
Thank you for my deliverance.
Do you know Sir Richard Carlisle?
Her uncle and I are old friends.
Well, old acquaintances, anyway.
How dare you threaten me. Oh, I assure
you, I dare a great deal more than that!
If you still love him, let him
know.
If you don't tell him, you could
regret it all your life long.
You're like a real soldier!
I am a real soldier.
Thank you very much.
Now come and give me a kiss.
You see, I want you to marry me.
(GROANS)
Carson!
You'll find there's never a dull
moment in this house.
Sync and Corrected by Mecano
www.MY-SUBS.com