WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Mary, the men are arranging
the concert now
and they are so anxious
for us both to be in it,
or there'll be no girls at all.
Please say you will.
Do I have to?
Yes, you do.
Keeping their spirits up
is an important part of the cure
and so very little to ask.
What's going on?
The men are putting on a concert.
Can I help?
Edith has it under control.
I do, if Mary's willing.
Oh, all right.
One song, and that's your lot.
What time is Doctor Clarkson's
round? It's already happened.
Without me? Why?
I'm not very late.
We didn't see the need to wait.
Mrs Hughes, I need to steal you
for a minute.
I have to check the linen books.
But I went over them last week.
Very good, m'lady. I'll get started.
Surely I can...
Anna, can you tell Mrs Patmore
it'll be easier for me to go through
the menus this afternoon?
Of course, Your Ladyship.
Cousin Cora - Please, can it wait?
I've a mountain to get through.
There's a parcel for you.
Thank you.
There's a little one for you.
This one looks as if it's been
opened, but it hasn't.
Ethel, have you nothing to do?
I was keeping her talking.
You mustn't blame her. I don't.
What a lovely day!
Are you quite sure about Lavinia?
She wasn't Sir Richard's mistress.
She gave him the evidence to settle
a debt of... someone she loved.
And this is your beau, is it?
A man who lends money, then uses it
to blackmail the recipient?
He lives in a tough world.
And will you be joining him there?
Richard Carlisle is powerful.
He's rich and getting richer.
He wants to buy a proper house,
you know - with an estate.
He says, after the war, the market
will be flooded and we can take
our pick. Oh?
And you can dance on the grave
of a fallen family.
They will fall, lots of them.
Some won't rise again,
but I don't intend to be among them.
That leaves Matthew.
That's done now, Granny. Finished.
It's time to move forward.
What about Sybil?
Does she have anyone in her sights?
Not that I know of. Are you sure
she has no chap in mind? How odd!
I had an endless series of crushes
at her age. I don't think so.
Not even some man she doesn't care
to mention? What do you mean?
Well, war breaks down barriers
and when peacetime re-erects them,
You cannot be so contrary.
I'm a woman, Mary.
I can be as contrary as I choose.
But I don't understand.
The patients are always served
their luncheon at 12:30.
Well, today they'll be served at one.
Is this something I can help with?
Mrs Patmore seems to be disobeying
my instructions and I can't get to
the reason why.
If you mean the patients' new
lunchtime,
Her Ladyship felt it made the staff
luncheon unreasonably early.
She moved it, so they could eat at
noon. But that will interfere with
the nurses' shifts.
Oh no, she's altered those, too.
Has she, indeed?
Well, we'll see about that.
It was always a question of when.
May I have a word?
Can it wait?
No, it cannot wait.
I've just come from downstairs,
where I learnt that my timetable
has been wantonly disregarded.
If you mean the new lunchtime,
the wretched servants were having
to eat at 11 and then starve until
their tea at six, so I...
You've also torn up
the nurses' timetable.
I haven't torn up anything...
It would be foolish to accuse you
of being unprofessional,
as you've never had a profession
in your life. Now, just a minute!
You may think you have the right
to ordain the universe,
but in this field -
No, not in this field - in this
house, yes, I do have the right,
given me by Doctor Clarkson
and by the law of the land!
This is my house, and I am in charge
right alongside you!
If you would stop your bullying -
That's enough!
I will not listen to this.
If I am not appreciated here,
I will seek some other place where
I will make a difference. Good.
I mean it. I cannot operate where
I am not valued. You must see that!
Certainly.
I shall go. I will.
Perhaps it would be best.
I repeat - I mean it.
I'm sure you do - and so do I.
Why did you promise Carson
not to stage any more protests,
when you wouldn't promise me?
I had my reasons.
But you won't be content to stay
at Downton forever, will you?
Tinkering away at an engine
instead of fighting for freedom?
I thought you'd join the rising
in Dublin last Easter.
I might have... if it hadn't been put
down in six short, bloody weeks.
But don't fret. The real fight for
Ireland will come after the war,
and I'll be ready for it.
The truth is, I'll stay in Downton
until you want to run away with me.
Don't be ridiculous.
You're too scared to admit it...
but you're in love with me.
Branson, could you take me
into Ripon at three?
I'm getting some things for Mama.
Is there anything you want?
Nothing you can find in Ripon!
Well... it IS her house.
Does that mean she's suddenly
received a medical training?
No - Or are you like everyone else
in thinking that, because
she's a countess,
she has acquired universal knowledge
by divine intervention?
Mrs Crawley, convalescent homes
are not about medical training.
They are far more to do with good
food, fresh air and clean sheets.
Very well. I've had a letter
from a cousin in Paris
who is working for the Wounded
And Missing Enquiry Department.
They've opened a branch
in Northern France
under the aegis of the Red Cross.
I shall offer them my services.
Well, that's... that's very drastic.
I have to go where I am useful
and that place, I'm afraid,
is no longer Downton Abbey.
You'll be missed.
By you, possibly.
I hope so, anyway.
But not, I think, by Lady Grantham.
♪ If you were the only girl
in the world
♪ And I were the only boy ♪
I wish we had a man.
Amen!
It would sound so much richer,
but all the volunteers
are spoken for.
How's it going?
All right, I suppose,
if you don't mind singers who can't
sing and actors who can't act!
It helps to keep their spirits up.
So they say,
although I can't think why.
I had a letter this morning
from Sir Richard Carlisle. Oh?
He...
He tells me he proposed
when he was staying here.
He apologises for not asking my
permission, but he's asking it now.
Have you decided?
Is that why he's written?
No... but I have made the decision.
Which is?
I think I should take him.
Do you really, my darling? I wish
I could believe in your motives.
Why? What were your motives
when you married Mama?
Your mother has made me very happy.
Perhaps Sir Richard
will make ME very happy.
What about Matthew?
Not you, too! Poor Matthew...
What must he do to persuade you
he's in love with Lavinia?
Open his chest and carve her name
on his heart?
Write to him. Tell him of your plans
with Carlisle. You owe him that.
I don't think I "owe" him anything,
but I'll write to him, if you like.
I'll try to send you an address,
but you can always get me through
the Red Cross. Very good, ma'am.
I'll try to contact Captain Crawley,
explain to him what's happened.
If he does get leave, he'll probably
come to me or stay in London,
but if I miss him and he turns up
here, I know you'll look after him.
Of course I will, ma'am.
Cook him what he likes -
not what's good for him.
You don't know when you'll be back?
I don't think one knows anything
in wartime.
I'll try to give you warning. In
the meantime, look after yourselves.
Now, I mustn't miss my train.
So, what now?
Ah, Anna said you were honouring us
with your presence at dinner.
It's easier here than the hospital.
I can always get changed back
into my uniform if I need to.
What were you talking to Branson
about when I came into the yard?
Nothing.
Then why were you there?
Why were YOU there?
Because I was ordering the motor.
That is why one talks to chauffeurs,
isn't it?
To plan journeys by road?
He is a person.
He can discuss other things.
I'm sure he can - but not with you.
What do you want from me?
Am I to see if Sir Richard Carlisle
has a younger brother -
one even richer than he is?
Darling, what's the matter with you?
I'm on your side.
Then be on my side!
'So there we have it.
I look forward to introducing
the two of you
just as soon as you are next
at home,
which naturally
I trust will be very soon indeed.
Please be glad for me,
as I will always be for you.
Your affectionate cousin, Mary.'
We don't need anyone with us.
The Sergeant knows what we're doing.
But what are we patrolling for?
You've been taking those logic pills
again! This is the army, Mason.
We're going on a patrol
because we're going on a patrol.
Has Mary set a date yet
for the wedding? She doesn't say.
I think she's hoping
the war will be over soon
and they can set a date then.
She could've waited and told you
when she saw you. She doesn't know
I'm due back.
Did you warn Daisy, or will it be
a surprise? No, I've told her we're
coming to Downton first.
Then I'll visit my dad and go back
to see her for a day at the end.
fresh Yorkshire air,
followed by London and Miss Swire.
All right for some, sir!
You'd never swap, though, would you?
No, I'd never swap.
Bates in a pub? I can't see that.
I think your pal's mistaken.
He met him here twice
before the war. Listen.
I said to him, "Hello,
Mr Bates," and he walked off
and wouldn't serve me after.
Next thing you know, we'll have Anna
running across the county and
dragging him back by his stick!
I'm surprised he isn't here of his
own accord,
with His Lordship having no valet
since the loony went.
Don't speak ill of Mr Lang.
You're a funny one!
Talk about sweet and sour.
Better get back.
Want a cup?
Not really.
What were you doing?
Oh, let me see.
I've tidied the study - twice
and I've rearranged the coats
in the hall.
I might check his clothes for moth.
What about you?
We've cleaned everything
three times over
and I've sent Beth into the village
for some eggs to pickle,
though the Mistress
doesn't really like them.
Well, she never eats properly,
anyway. Not on her own.
A butler can't do much
with supper on a tray!
Beg your pardon for troubling you,
only the door was open.
But the front gate was not.
No.
What do you want?
Have you got any spare food?
"Spare food"?
What's that, when it's at home?
Hang on, hang on. Wait.
From around here?
Not far.
I used to work on the farms,
but er... not any more.
Did you get that in the war? Don't
pity me. I'm one of the lucky ones.
I might have something for you.
Come on.
Hello, Mr Molesley.
They told me you were up here.
I hope you don't mind
my bothering you.
Not a bit. What can I do for you?
Well, actually, Mr Carson, I've been
thinking there might be something I
can do for YOU. Hm?
That brushing, for instance.
I don't like having nothing to do,
what with Captain Crawley
away at the war and his mother
in France alongside him.
And then, His Lordship's
without a valet and...
and your plate is piled so high!
I am quite occupied, it's true.
So I thought I'd look in
and give you a hand,
brushing, mending, cleaning shoes -
whatever's needed.
That's kind of you, Mr Molesley.
We shall have to watch ourselves, or
else His Lordship will want to pinch
you off Captain Crawley.
But he said he'd be here by now
and he's not.
You mustn't worry about him, Daisy.
I'm not "worried" like that, exactly,
but this is William.
I think we should all be worried.
Anything might have happened.
Maybe his leave was cancelled.
At times like these, people vanish
and turn up again
in the strangest places.
Like Mr Bates in that pub.
Working in a public house?
That's what he said.
I thought they'd have told you.
It doesn't seem likely
that a trained valet like Mr Bates
would be content to work
in a public house!
Well, that's what he said.
Have you mentioned this to Anna?
I haven't said anything to anyone.
I thought you all knew.
Perhaps you should ask Thomas.
Oh, I will ask Thomas.
Don't you worry about that, my girl.
Didn't it occur to you that
we might be interested to hear it?
Not particularly.
As far as I knew, Mr Bates had left
your employment.
You didn't think to tell Carson?
I am not under Mr Carson's command
now, Your Lordship.
Shoo! Daisy, go to bed
before you strain your eyes!
Thank you, Daisy,
for telling Mr Carson
all about my private letter!
I didn't know it was a secret.
Sorry if I was wrong.
There's no "if" about it.
Why answer His Lordship at all?
What did you want me to do?
Tell him to get knotted?
He doesn't pay your wages.
I see.
Well, I won't put you down
for a career in diplomacy, then!
What's he after? To get Bates back?
If Mr Bates wanted his job back,
he'd have written for it himself.
Why would he want his job back?
He's like you. He got away.
He's not very like me, thank you.
But you're both free
of all the bowing and scraping
and "Yes, m'lord," and "No, m'lord."
I envy him. I envy you.
Cos I'm ready for a new adventure
and I don't care who hears me.
"Be careful what you wish for."
'The truth is, I'll stay in Downton
until you want to run away with me.'
Ah. Good morning, Anna.
You sent for me, m'lord?
I did. Come in.
I have something to tell you,
but I hope I'm right.
Carson didn't want you
to be troubled with it.
Is this about Mr Bates, m'lord?
Yes, it is.
I have no wish to upset you, but it
seems he may be back in Yorkshire
working in a public house.
We don't yet know where.
The Red Lion in Kirby Moorside.
Oh.
You've seen him, then?
I have, yes, m'lord.
And he's well?
He is.
He's not been back to Downton
for two reasons.
He's hoping to settle certain matters
first... with Mrs Bates.
And does he think he can?
He believes so, m'lord.
Very good.
And what is his second reason
for avoiding us?
He says he parted with Your Lordship
on bad terms.
He felt it might be embarrassing.
Yeah...
It is for me to feel embarrassed.
I had to get out of that kitchen,
if I'm not to be found dead
under the table!
It's like cooking a banquet
three times a day.
It is a lot of extra work, whatever
they say - even with the helpers.
Don't think they lighten the load!
Mrs Bird? What's going on?
I knew I'd be found out,
sooner or later. At least it's you.
Found out doing what?
What does it look like?
I don't know what it looks like,
except some kind of soup kitchen.
You'd better come inside.
One at a time.
Now, take a piece of bread.
Right. Daisy, stand there.
Give them a bowl and a spoon.
When did all this start?
That fella turned up asking for food.
Then he came back next day
with a friend, and here we are.
What does Mrs Crawley say?
She doesn't know yet.
I suppose she'll put a stop to it
when she gets back from France.
I hope not.
To be honest, Mrs Patmore, I'm not
sure I can manage much longer.
How often do you do it? I planned
to get it down to once a week
and give them only the cheapest cuts,
but it is my money, and I don't know
how much - Now, hold it right there!
If we can't feed a few soldiers in
our own village,
them that have taken a bullet
or worse for king and country,
then I don't know what!
Sorry about this, m'lady, only
there's no footman to do it now.
I don't mind, but you'd better run
before Mrs Hughes sees you.
M'lady... could I ask something?
Only William, who was in service
here - I know William.
Well, he's missing.
That is, he was supposed to be back
on leave but he never turned up.
He wrote he was coming home for a few
days with Captain Crawley...
Is William your beau?
I won't say that, no, m'lady.
We're all very fond of William
downstairs. Of course you are.
Well, I'm sure it's nothing, but
I'll see what I can find out.
Thank you.
How do you know they
didn't change their plans?
Well, of course I don't,
but the poor girl
seemed quite certain.
Just when Isobel's away and none of
us know where she is. Typical!
I suppose Matthew might have heard
from Cousin Isobel and decided to
meet up in France, instead.
But that wouldn't explain
why William isn't here.
I'll do what I can.
No, don't stop stirring,
the bottom will burn!
You can leave those to Daisy.
That's it, Daisy. Put them
in the special storage area.
What do you want?
Can I borrow some baking soda?
"Borrow"? Why?
Are you planning to give it back?
I might go over to Malton tomorrow.
Agatha Spenlow is madly promoting
her charity fair.
Do you need the motor? I'm afraid
I do. Can you get Pratt to take you
in the other car?
It doesn't matter.
I can go on Monday. But why?
I'm told Bates is working
at a public house in Kirby Moorside.
I want to investigate.
I can't decide which part of that
speech is the most extraordinary!
Why can't someone else go?
Because I want to go myself.
So, Sybil, what are you up to, dear?
Nothing much. Working. I don't have
time to get up to anything else.
Only Mary and I were talking
about you the other day.
Oh?
Yes, you see, sometimes, in war,
one can make friendships
that aren't quite... appropriate
and it can be awkward, you know,
later on.
I mean, we've all done it. I just
want you to be on your guard.
"Appropriate" for whom? Well,
don't jump down my throat, dear.
I'm only offering friendly advice.
Why do you want to see Bates?
To give him his old job back?
Not entirely.
I mainly want to see him
because we parted badly.
Telephone call for you, m'lord.
If you did, I'm sure it's his fault.
No, it was mine.
Oh, really! It's like living
in a second-rate hotel
where the guests keep arriving
and no-one seems to leave!
I see.
Yes... Thank you
for letting me know.
Are you all right, Papa?
That was the War Office.
Matthew and William went out
on a patrol a few days ago
and they haven't been seen since.
Oh, my God.
Let's not fall to pieces quite yet.
It happens all the time, apparently,
and the men turn up
in one field hospital or another.
But they are treating them
as missing in action?
It's too early for that.
There could be lots of things
to explain it.
You mean they could have been taken
prisoner? It's possible.
Don't say anything to Mary...
or your mother,
or anyone, in fact - not yet.
I shouldn't really have told you.
What about Cousin Isobel?
I don't know how to contact her.
Anyway, she's in France.
She may hear before we do.
I'm not accusing her of anything,
but I did wonder if you were aware
of this "special storage area"?
I daresay Mrs Patmore has her own
system, like we all do.
Right. Well, I'll say good night.
Good night.
Ah, Mr Molesley. You're very late.
I was doing some invisible mending
on one of his coats.
I got a bit carried away, but I'm...
I'm quite pleased with the way it
turned out.
I don't see why you can't dress him
until there's a new valet.
It'd be a blessing to Mr Carson.
I'd be happy to, if it'd help.
Keep this up, and we won't be able
to do without you at all.
There's no reason why you should.
Oh, er, I may be wrong,
but I thought I saw one of the
officers by the maids' staircase
just now.
I'm sure there's a perfectly
reasonable explanation.
Let's hope so.
Good night.
What the bloody...
Ethel!
We were only...
I know precisely what you were doing, Major.
I may not be a woman of the world,
but I don't live in a sack!
Now, if you would kindly
take your things and go downstairs.
Ethel, you are dismissed without
notice and without a character.
You will please leave before
breakfast. I didn't think I was...
No. And that's the problem.
You never do.
And you're not nervous?
Well, I gather His Lordship
knows his own mind,
but I've no difficulty with that.
You'll enjoy working
in a big household.
Better than staring at me
night after night!
What would you say
if they ask you to stay?
It would be a big step up for me.
There's no point in denying it.
Because I think they might.
Do you really, Mrs Bird?
There goes Mr Molesley,
valet to the Earl of Grantham.
Stop it!
But why?
What could you have possibly done
that's so terrible?
Have I taken everything of mine
from there?
Would you like me to speak to her?
Because I can.
No. She wouldn't listen.
She's not a bad person, Mrs Hughes.
I know she can be strict, but she's
not - She wouldn't listen.
We're closed.
I know Ethel could be difficult,
Mrs Hughes,
but she was very sorry for
her mistake, whatever it was.
I'm sure. It's cost her her job.
But surely it can't...
Never mind why she's gone, she's
gone - and there's an end to it.
By the way, I hear
Mr Bates is back in the county.
Mr Carson says
you know all about it.
I gather His Lordship
has gone to see him.
I know. He told me he was going.
Why in heaven's name
didn't you mention any of it to me?
It wasn't my secret to tell.
I'm glad to hear it, but Carson said
your wife made all sorts of threats.
She won't carry them out - not now.
Since I left Downton,
I've discovered
that she was... untrue to me.
I may have been as bad in my heart,
m'lord, but I've done
nothing to be ashamed of.
The point is, I can divorce her now,
whether she likes it or not.
But what's to stop her blurting out
her stories to the press?
If she agrees to keep silent, I will
give her whatever she wants.
She can't hold me now, so her choice
is between poverty and plenty.
And what was the tale she was going
to tell? Carson never made it clear.
Some silly nonsense, m'lord.
I wouldn't waste your time with it.
What's the news from Downton?
Daisy, you're not to worry
about William.
I spoke to His Lordship earlier.
He says you're not to be concerned
until we know more.
But he is missing.
I mean, they don't know where he is,
or Captain Crawley, do they?
There could be a hundred
explanations. Yes - and one of them
is that they're dead!
Don't mistake me,
I hope very much they're not,
but we ought to face the truth.
What may be the truth.
And what very well may not!
Anna, do you think that Mr Bates
will come back?
That's for him to say.
I hope he does.
He always seems
a romantic figure to me.
Does he? How do you define "romantic"?
It's no good him thinking he can
turn up here without a moment's
notice and be cock of the walk!
Why is that, Thomas?
Because the place is already taken?
I hate the word "missing".
It seems to leave so little room
for optimism.
I tell myself
it's too early to despair,
but to be honest, Bates,
I don't think I can bear it.
Losing Patrick was bad enough,
but now the thought of Matthew gone
and the future
once again destroyed...
More than all that,
I loved him like a son.
No, I LOVE him. Let's stay in the
present tense, while we still can.
So, will you come back with me...
and help me through
the Vale of Shadow?
It's not what I expected, m'lord,
but... I will, if you want me to.
I misjudged you, Bates,
and I abused you when we parted.
I should have had more faith.
I'm sorry.
God knows, you've shown more faith
in me than I had any right to.
There we are. Get this basket
off my arm. It weighs a ton!
Sybil?
I never said anything to Granny,
honestly.
Then why did she start talking about
"inappropriate friendships"
out of nowhere?
She thinks you must have a beau and
if we don't know about him, then you
have to be keeping him secret.
It's just Granny being Granny.
Don't make such a thing of it.
I don't deserve to be told off - not
by her or by you. Nothing's happened.
Why? What might have happened?
I mean it.
We haven't kissed, or anything.
I don't think we've shaken hands!
I'm not even sure
if I like him like that. He says
I do, but I'm still not sure.
We are talking about...
Branson, yes.
The chauffeur, Branson?
Oh, how disappointing of you!
I'm just trying to get it straight
you and the chauffeur...
You know I don't care about all of
that. Darling, don't be such a baby.
This isn't fairyland.
What did you think?
You'd marry the chauffeur and we'd
all come to tea? Don't be silly.
I told you, I don't even think I like
him. What has he said to you?
That he loves me and wants me to run
away with him. Good God in heaven!
He's frightfully full of himself.
You don't say!
But I haven't encouraged him.
I haven't said anything, really.
You haven't given him away, though.
Will you?
Well, I won't betray him
on one condition:
You must promise
not to do anything stupid.
You must promise now,
or I'll tell Papa tonight.
I promise.
Mr Bates!
You're a sight for sore eyes.
Welcome home.
Thank you, Mrs Hughes.
I thought it was you.
Hello.
Come away in and give some substance
to the gossip of your return.
You'll find things a bit different
from when you left, Mr Bates.
Downton at war.
Precisely.
There's some extra help
in the kitchen, all very nice people
and the nurses, of course,
but they live down at the hospital.
Except for Lady Sybil.
Nurse Crawley, please!
So we've both returned, you and I.
A couple of bad pennies.
I haven't. Thomas means
he's not here as a servant.
He manages the house.
He's a sergeant now.
I take orders from Major Clarkson.
He runs this place on behalf
of the Army Medical Corps.
Yet another reason
to pray for peace!
I heard about William from His
Lordship. And Captain Crawley.
I'm sure they're all right.
Sorry I'm late!
Has the dressing gong rung yet?
You're not late, Mr Molesley,
but er...
Mr Bates is back,
and you reminded me.
I'd better ring it now.
Are you staying... for good?
I'd need a crystal ball to answer
that, but I'll stay for now.
Have you been standing in for me?
I was going to,
starting tonight, yeah.
Then you'll be relieved to see me.
Oh, tremendously.
What's that?
It's a new kind of shoehorn.
I bought it for His Lordship.
That's very kind of you,
Mr Molesley. Thank you.
Daisy, fetch me some more tea.
Thomas, I've got dinner...
Hot, this time,
and it's Sergeant Barrow to you.
Watch yourself, Mr Bates.
Thomas is in charge now.
It won't do to get on the wrong side
of him. Is there a right side?
I don't believe it.
Why would she sell food to Mrs Bird?
It makes no sense.
Well, I can't confirm
the details of the arrangement.
Maybe they both sell it
and divide the proceeds.
Either way, I felt you should know.
Have you said anything to Mrs Hughes
or Carson? I've tried with her,
but there's none so blind
as them that will not see.
I'm curious.
Next time, come and fetch me.
So Bates is back.
Papa must be pleased.
And Mr Carson won't be sorry.
Branson, there's something
you ought to know.
I've told Mary.
I see.
Well, that's me finished, then -
and without a reference.
No, she's not like that.
You don't know her.
She wouldn't give us away.
But she won't encourage us.
No.
Why are you smiling?
I thought you'd be angry.
Because that's the first time
you've ever spoken about "us".
If you didn't care,
you would have told them months ago.
Oh, I see. Because I don't want you
to lose your job,
it must mean I'm madly in love
with you. Well, doesn't it?
You say I'm a free spirit,
and I hope I am,
but you're asking me to give up
my whole world and everyone in it.
And that's too high a price to pay?
It IS a high price!
I love my parents - you don't know them...
and I love my sisters, my friends...
I'm not asking you
to give them up for ever.
When they come around,
I will welcome them with open arms.
And what about your people?
Would they accept ME?
And what about my work?
What work? Bringing hot drinks
to a lot of randy officers?
Look - it comes down to whether
or not you love me. That's all.
That's it. The rest is detail.
I've written to Vera, spelling out
the case and how she cannot win it.
Then I've told her I will be
generous, if she will co-operate.
Are you ready to give her everything?
Because I am.
Whatever it takes. I want a clean
break and not an open wound.
If we can just be patient
a little while longer.
We shouldn't be outside. It's cold.
I'll be patient and bear anything,
except for you to go away again.
No. That's done.
You're stuck with me now...
for good and proper.
There's something you ought to know.
Papa said not to tell you, but I
don't think he's right. Go on.
Matthew's missing.
He was on patrol
and he's just sort of... vanished.
Papa hasn't told anyone.
Not even Mama.
I only know because I was there
when he found out.
It didn't seem right
to keep you in the dark.
I'm not trying to upset you, truly.
For once in my life, I believe you.
They've told you, then?
Do they all know downstairs?
William's missing, too. I think
everyone knows except Her Ladyship.
I wish Edith had left it
till the morning.
I could have faced it all
with one more night of sleep.
Mind out, this is hot.
Daisy! Spoons!
Unless they're to drink
directly from the bowl!
Do you think there's enough?
You could feed about 50, I reckon.
Go for the vegetable one.
The vegetable...
May we come in?
Your Ladyship... What a surprise.
O'Brien seemed to think that you and
Mrs Bird were engaged in a commercial
venture of some sort,
so I came to see for myself.
We are not, Your Ladyship!
I agree
that's not what it looks like.
We feed these men once a week
and I'm not ashamed of it.
I'll be back before luncheon
at the big house. I'm sure.
But is it true
they are fed from our kitchens?
Only the stuff the army gives.
They ARE soldiers.
What did I tell you?
Daisy's right. We only use
the food the army pay for,
and all the men
have served their country.
In future, I would prefer it if you
would use food paid for by the house.
I don't want the army
to accuse us of mismanagement.
You're going to let them get away
with it? Oh, more than that.
I'm going to help them -
and so are you.
Molesley. Ma'am.
If you bring that table over,
I suggest we divide the food.
Then we can form two lines
and it will go faster.
O'Brien, you can manage the bread.
Daisy?
Of course, m'lady.
Mmm... What is it?
Beef stew, m'lady.
Stand in a line.
Sergeant, one moment.
I hear you're becoming
mighty imperious in your manner
with the staff here.
Er, Daisy in particular.
Just because you're a poacher
turned gamekeeper, there's no need
for rudeness. No, sir.
So mind what I say.
Carry on.
I've done as you asked, Mrs Hughes.
I think Barrow's taken it on board.
He's getting grander than Lady Mary,
and that's saying something!
Lady Grantham.
Hello, Doctor Clarkson.
It was Bates.
I saw him watching you.
He must have gone straight
to the Major and sneaked on you
the moment your back was turned.
Oh, well. Some things never change.
Don't worry. He's more vulnerable
than when he was last here.
Why?
Because we know more, that's why.
Why haven't you told me till now?
I'm not sure.
Perhaps I envied your ignorance.
I'm not giving up hope. Not yet.
Nor me, of course, but I think
we should start to prepare.
Isobel doesn't know?
I haven't been able to reach her.
Have you said anything to Mary?
Edith's already told me.
Has she? Well, I suppose
it was too tempting to resist.
Oddly enough, I don't think
she was trying to make trouble.
We ought to go down.
It's time for the concert.
Who cares about the stupid concert?
The men do, and we should, too...
because we have to keep going,
whatever happens.
We have to help each other
to keep going.
Cora tells me Matthew's gone
missing. Is that true?
There's no proof of anything yet.
I see.
Well, I need more than that
to make me anxious.
I'm glad you would be anxious.
Of course I would be.
We're used to Matthew now.
God knows who the next heir will be.
Probably a chimneysweep
from Solihull! Huh!
Most of you won't know
how rare it is
to see my sister Edith and I
pulling together in a double act...
A unicorn, if ever there was one.
But in wartime
we, like all of you, have more
important things to worry about.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I give you... the Crawley Sisters.
Well, now I've seen everything!
♪ Sometimes when I feel bad
♪ And things look blue
♪ I wish a pal I had
♪ Say one like you
♪ Someone within my heart
♪ To build a throne
♪ Someone who'd never part
♪ To call my own
♪ If you were the only girl
in the world
♪ And I were the only boy
♪ Nothing else would matter
in the world today
♪ We could go on loving
in the same old way... ♪
Thank God...
My dear boy. My very dear boy!
Come on, don't stop for me.
♪ I would say
such wonderful things to you
♪ There would be
such wonderful things to do
♪ If you were the only girl
in the world
♪ And I were the only boy ♪
Somehow, we got lost
and then we were trapped behind some
Germans for three days.
When we got out of that, we stumbled
into a field dressing station,
where we were immediately admitted.
We weren't in any danger,
so they didn't inform our unit.
They should have jolly well told us
when you got back to base.
I hope you weren't really worried.
Oh, you know us.
We like to be sure of our hero
at the front.
I beg your pardon, m'lord, but
the Dowager Countess is leaving. Ah.
What will you do
with the rest of your leave?
Well, since Mother isn't here, I'll
run up to London and see Lavinia.
I got your letter about Carlisle.
I hope you'll approve.
I know you don't like him much now -
I hardly know him,
but I'm sure I'll like him when I do.
That's if he's good to you.
If he's not,
he'll have me to answer to.
Who'd have thought
an amateur concert
could be the summit of all joy?
I've lived in such a fog of misery
since I left you,
I think I'd forgotten what happiness
is. Me, too.
But now we must get used to feeling
happy... and trust it.
God, I want to.
Love's young dream?
I don't think!
I'm not sure I care much.
Are you going soft in your old age?
I don't like him -
he's a patronising bastard
who sneaks behind my back,
but I've got other things to worry
about. Really?
That's interesting.
Why?
Because obviously,
I hold a grudge longer than you.
I knew nothing bad had happened.
I felt it in my waters!
What about you?
Did you have me boxed up and buried?
I am glad you're all right, honest.
You should be.
It's the thought of you
that keeps me going.
Hello? Hello?
Ethel? What on earth
are you doing here?
I had to come, Mrs Hughes.
I'm sorry to push in,
but I was sitting alone until
I couldn't stand it no more.
You've got to help me.
I haven't "got to" do anything!
But what do you mean?
Help with what?
Is this about Major Bryant?
I blame myself for not stepping in
earlier - that I will admit.
How long had it been going on?
Long enough to get me pregnant.
Mrs Hughes, I'm going to have a baby.
I wish I'd not written that letter
now, what with everything else
going on.
She'll come up here
and make trouble.
Don't badger me, please!
Sometimes a hard sacrifice must be
made for a future
that's worth having.
The cold and careful
Lady Mary Crawley!
Do you still expect me to marry
you... knowing this?
I'll sell my story anyway -
about Lady Mary, the Turkish
gentleman, Miss Smith here...
It's got nowt to do with me.
That's not what I heard.
M'lady, wake up.
What on earth...
You'd better come downstairs.
Subtitles by ITFC, MemoryOnSmells
www.MY-SUBS.com