WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Sub made possible
by Adriano_CSI
Oh, my God!
That's impossible.
I'll take it up there now.
Don't be stupid.
None of them will be up for hours,
and what difference will it make?
Jimmy'll do it when he comes in.
(BEEPING)
Six o'clock!
Thank you, Daisy... Anna?
(GROANS)
Huh... Just for once in my life,
I'd like to sleep until I woke up
natural.
Is your fire still in?
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
Ooh, my, will wonders never cease?
Have you laid the servants' hall
breakfast? Yes, Mrs Patmore.
And finished blacking that stove?
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
What about the bedroom fires?
All lit, Mrs Patmore.
Right, well, take the things
and start on the fires
on the ground floor!
(BUSY CHATTER)
Now hurry up.
Any sign of William?
No.
Where have YOU been?
I'm not late, am I?
You're late when I say you're late.
Daisy?
Whatever are you doing there,
crouching in the dark?
I didn't like to touch the curtains
with my dirty hands. Quite right too.
Why didn't you put the lights on?
I daren't.
It's not the devil's handiwork.
You'll have to get used to it
eventually.
At Skelton Park, they've even got it
in the kitchens. What for?
(BUSY CHATTERING)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Breakfast is ready, Mr Carson.
Ah, William. Any papers yet?
They're late.
They certainly are.
Get the board out, so you can do them
as soon as they're here.
Is the library tidy?
Yes, Mrs Hughes. Good.
I want the dining room given
a proper going-over today.
You can do it when they've finished
their breakfast.
Oh, heavens, girl! You're building
a fire, not inventing it!
How many have you done? This is my
last till they come downstairs.
Very well. Now get back down to the
kitchens before anyone sees you.
(BICYCLE BELL)
And they're off.
No rest for the wicked.
Lady Mary. Are the tea trays ready?
All ready, Mrs Patmore -
if the water's boiled.
Could you give us a hand?
I've got her Ladyship's to carry.
I'll help.
(BELL RINGS) Back door.
The papers. At last... William?
You're late!
I know, but -
But what?
You'll see.
Do the Times first.
He only reads that at breakfast.
And the Sketch for her Ladyship.
You can manage the others later.
Why are their papers ironed?
What's it to YOU?
To dry the ink, silly.
We wouldn't want his Lordship's hands
to be as black as yours.
(BELLS TINKLE)
Mr Carson!
I think you ought to see this.
I can't make myself believe it.
Me neither.
His Lordship's dressed.
William!
Will you stop talking
and take this kedgeree up?
And mind the burners are still lit.
Yes, Mrs Patmore.
Is it really true?
Afraid so.
Nothing in life is sure.
Good morning, Carson.
Good morning, my Lord.
Is it true what they say?
I believe so, my Lord.
I'm afraid we'll know some people
on it.
I don't suppose there are any lists
of survivors yet?
I understand most of the ladies
were taken off in time.
You mean the ladies in first class?
God help the poor devils below decks.
On their way to a better life.
What a tragedy.
When Anna told me,
I thought she must have dreamt it.
Do we know anyone on board?
Your mother knows the Astors.
At least, she knows HIM. We dined
with Lady Rothes last month.
There are bound to be others.
I thought it was supposed to be
unsinkable.
Every mountain is unclimbable
until someone climbs it.
So every ship is unsinkable
until it sinks.
Good morning, Papa.
Morning.
What's that?
Just arrived... Telegram.
Is her Ladyship awake? Yes, my Lord.
I'm just taking in her breakfast.
Thank you. (KNOCKS)
(FAINT) Hello?
May I come in?
Isn't this terrible?
When you think how excited
Lucy Rothes was at the prospect.
It's too awful for any words.
Did JJ Astor get off?
Course, his new wife
is bound to have been rescued.
I've had a telegram
from George Murray.
One of his partners is in New York.
Yes?
It seems James and Patrick
were on board.
What? But they weren't going over
till May.
Then they changed their plans.
They're on the passenger list.
Thank you, O'Brien.
That'll be all for the moment.
But...surely they were picked up?
Doesn't look like it.
What?
Neither of them?
You must tell Mary.
She can't hear about it
from anyone else.
Neither were picked up.
That's what he said.
Mr Crawley and Mr Patrick?
Her Ladyship was the colour
of this cloth.
Well, it's a terrible shame
if it's true.
It's worse than a shame.
It's a complication.
What do you mean?
What do you think?
Mr Crawley was his Lordship's cousin
and heir to the title.
I thought Lady Mary was the heir.
She's a girl, stupid.
Girls can't inherit.
But now Mr Crawley's dead,
and Mr Patrick was his only son.
So what happens next?
It's a dreadful thing.
Hello?
I've been waiting at the back door...
I knocked, but no-one came.
So you pushed in?
I'm John Bates, the new valet.
The new valet?
That's right.
You're early.
Came on the milk train.
Thought I'd get to know the place,
start tonight.
I'm Anna, the head housemaid.
How do you do?
And I'm Miss O'Brien,
her Ladyship's maid.
You'd better come along with us.
But how can you manage? Don't worry
about that. I can manage.
Because we've all got our own work
to do. I can manage.
Mrs Hughes, I'll take over.
Thank you.
Good morning, Mr Bates.
Welcome.
I hope your journey
was satisfactory?
It was fine. Thank you.
I am the butler at Downton.
My name is Carson.
How do you do, Mr Carson?
This is Thomas, first footman.
He's been looking after his Lordship
since Mr Watson left.
It'll be a relief to get back
to normal, won't it, Thomas?
(CLEARS THROAT)
I assume that everything is ready
for Mr Bates's arrival?
I've put him in Mr Watson's old room,
though he left it in quite a state,
I can tell you.
But what about all them stairs?
I keep telling you, I can manage.
Of course you can.
Thomas, take Mr Bates to his room
and show him where he'll be working.
Thank you, everyone.
Well, I can't see that lasting long.
Thank you, Miss O'Brien.
Oh, yes.
I shall be comfortable here.
Does this mean I'll have to go into
full mourning?
My first cousin and his son...
..are almost certainly dead.
We will all be in mourning.
No. I mean with the other thing.
After all, it wasn't official.
If you're saying you do not wish
to mourn Patrick as a fiance,
that is up to you. Well, no-one
knew about it outside the family.
I repeat, it is up to you.
Well, that's a relief.
There's some cedar-lined cupboards
in the attic
for things that aren't often worn -
travelling clothes and such.
Mr Watson used them to rotate
the summer and winter stuff.
I'll show you later.
What about studs and links?
Do I choose them or does he?
Lay them out unless he asks for
something in particular.
These for a ball,
these for an ordinary dinner,
these only in London.
I'll get the hang of it.
Yeah, you'll have to.
Snuff boxes. He collects them.
Beautiful.
Funny, our job, isn't it?
What do you mean?
The way we live with all this.
A pirate's hoard within our reach.
But none of it's ours, is it?
No, none of it's ours.
I can't believe I've been passed
over for Long John Silver.
You should have spoken up
when you had the chance.
Don't make the same mistake
next time.
Who says there'll be a next time?
Is this a public holiday
no-one's told me of?
She was certainly reluctant
to go into mourning.
Well, she'll have to. We all will.
O'Brien's sorting out my black now
and I've told Anna to see what
the girls have that still fits.
Of course, this alters everything.
You won't try to deny it? You must
challenge the entail now, surely?
Can't we at least wait until we know
they're dead before we discuss it?
Don't talk as if I'm not
broken-hearted, because I am.
Of course, I have never understood
why this estate must go
to whomever inherits your title.
My dear, I don't make the law.
What is it? The Dowager Countess
is in the drawing room.
I'll come now.
She asked for Lady Grantham.
I wonder what I've done wrong
this time.
And the new valet has arrived,
my Lord.
Has he? Hm... Thank you, Carson.
(CLEARS THROAT)
What is it?
I'm not entirely sure that he will
prove equal to the task,
but your Lordship will be the judge
of that.
I'd better go.
Tell her about James and Patrick.
She won't have heard.
Of course I've heard!
Why else would I be here?
Robert didn't want you to read about
it in a newspaper and be upset.
He flatters me.
I'm tougher than I look.
I'm very sorry about poor Patrick,
of course.
He was a nice boy.
We were all so fond of him.
But I never cared for James.
He was too like his mother and
a nastier woman never drew breath.
Will you stay for some luncheon?
Thank you.
I'll let Carson know.
I've already told him.
Shall we sit down?
Do you know the new heir?
Only that there is one.
He's Robert's third cousin
once removed.
I have never, to my knowledge,
set eyes on him.
Of course, if your late husband
hadn't forced me to sign
that absurd act of legal theft!
My dear, I didn't come here
to fight.
Lord Grantham wanted to protect
the estate.
It never occurred to him that you
wouldn't have a son. Well, I didn't.
No, you did not.
But when Patrick had married Mary
and your grandson been hailed
as master,
honour would have been satisfied.
Unfortunately, now...
Now a complete unknown has the right
to pocket my money,
along with the rest of the swag!
The problem is, saving your dowry
would break up the estate.
It would be the ruin of everything
Robert's given his life to.
And he knows this?
Well, if he doesn't, he will.
Then there's no answer.
Yes, there is,
and it's a simple one.
The entail must be smashed
in its entirety
and Mary recognised
as heiress of all.
There's nothing we can do
about the title.
No, she can't have the title.
But she can have your money...
and the estate.
I didn't run Downton for 30 years
to see it go, lock, stock and
barrel,
to a stranger from God knows where.
Are we to be friends, then?
We are allies, my dear.
Which can be a good deal
more effective.
Downton is a great house, Mr Bates,
and the Crawleys are a great family.
We live by certain standards
and those standards can at first
seem daunting. Of course.
If you find yourself tongue-tied
in the presence of his Lordship,
I can only assure you that his
manners and grace
will soon help you to perform your
duties to the best of your ability.
I know.
Bates! My dear fellow!
I do apologise. I should have
realised you'd all be at luncheon.
Not at all, my Lord.
Please, sit. Sit, everyone.
I just want to say a quick hello
to my old comrade-in-arms.
Bates, my dear man.
Welcome to Downton.
Thank you, sir.
I'm so sorry to have disturbed
you all. Please forgive me.
You never asked.
Thomas, take that up!
Leave it, Daisy! He's a grown man.
I suppose he can lift a meat pie.
Now, put that apple tart
in the lower oven.
Oh, and take that away! Mr Lynch
shouldn't have left it there!
What is it?
Salt of sorrel.
I asked him for some to clean
the brass pots.
So, put it somewhere careful.
It's poison.
It seems like a lot of food, when
you think they're all in mourning.
Nothing makes you hungrier
or more tired than grief.
When my sister died,
God rest her soul,
I ate my way through four platefuls
of sandwiches at one sitting
and slept round the clock.
Did it make you feel better?
Not much, but it passed the time.
Oh, my Lord, what was this chopped
egg supposed to be sprinkled on?
Was it the chicken?
It was. Take it upstairs now.
I can't go in the dining room!
I should think not!
Find Thomas or William
and tell them what to do.
For heaven's sake, get a move on,
before they get back from church!
Well, we've given them a memorial
in London and a memorial here.
I prefer memorials to funerals.
They're less dispiriting.
We could hardly have held a funeral
without the bodies.
I gather they're putting up a stone
to mark those whose bodies
were never found.
In fact, I hear the Canadians are
making quite a thing
of the Titanic cemetery. I'm
surprised at the number they found.
You'd think the sea would have taken
more of them.
So, Murray, what have you to tell me
about the lucky Mr Crawley?
Nothing too terrible, I hope.
I've only made a few enquiries but,
no, there's not much to alarm you.
Matthew Crawley is a solicitor,
based in Manchester. Manchester?
His special field is company law.
His mother is alive
and he lives with her.
His father, obviously, is not.
He was a doctor.
I know.
It does seem odd that my third
cousin should be a doctor.
There are worse professions.
Indeed.
(BUSY CHATTER)
Do me a favour. This must be
sprinkled on the chicken.
Isn't there more to go up?
Please! It won't take a moment!
Go on then, give it here.
We ought to talk about the business
of the entail.
As you know, on your death the heir
to the title inherits everything,
except for the sums set aside for
your daughters and your widow.
Yes. Owing to the terms of
her settlement,
this will include the bulk of your
wife's fortune.
It has been our sole topic of
conversation
since the day the ship went down.
Of course, it must seem horribly
unjust to Lady Grantham,
but that is how the law stands.
Is there really no way to detach
her money from the estate?
Even to me, it seems absurd.
Your father tied the knots pretty
tight. I'd say it's unbreakable.
I see.
Really, Edith. Do you have to put on
such an exhibition?
She's not.
I was supposed to be engaged to him,
for heaven's sake, not you,
and I can control myself.
Then you should be ashamed.
Don't tell me you've not sent up
the egg yet!
Oh God, help me!
Please, God, help me!
What on earth's the matter?
Run upstairs to the dining room
and find William, I beg you!
I can't do it now.
You've got to!
I'll be hanged if you don't!
What?
WILLIAM: Daisy? Is that you?
Is it the chicken in a sauce
or the chicken with sliced oranges?
Oh, thank you, blessed and merciful
Lord! Thank you!
It's the chicken in the sauce.
I'll never do anything sinful again,
I swear it! Not till I die!
Mr Murray, how lovely to see you.
Do come in.
You're very kind, Lady Grantham,
but I must get back to London.
But you'll stay for luncheon?
Thank you, but no.
I'll eat on the train.
In fact, if you'd be so good as to
ask for the motor to be brought
round?
But didn't you want the afternoon
to talk things through?
I think we've said everything
we have to say, haven't we, my Lord?
For the time being, yes.
Thank you, Murray.
It's given me a good
deal to think about.
Mary, try to get everyone
into the dining room.
Edith, make sure old Lord Minterne
sits down.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Mm-hm?
They've all gone?
They have, thank the Lord.
What about the lawyer?
He was the first away.
Didn't even stay for the luncheon.
I wish they'd make their minds up.
Gwen's put clean sheets
on the Blue Room bed.
Now she'll just have to strip it
again.
Can't you leave it
for the next guest?
Well, only if you don't tell.
(WRY CHUCKLE)
So, has it all been settled?
No, I don't know if anything's been
settled.
There's a fellow in Manchester with
claims to the title, I gather,
but it's all a long way
from settled.
You mustn't take it personally.
Oh, I do take it personally,
Mrs Hughes.
I can't stand by and watch our
family threatened
with the loss of all they hold dear.
They're not OUR family.
Well, they're all the family
I've got!
I beg your pardon.
Do you...ever wish
you'd gone another way?
Worked in a shop or a factory?
Had a wife and children?
Do you?
I don't know.
Maybe. Sometimes.
(KNOCK AT DOOR)
William's laid tea in the library,
but her Ladyship hasn't come down.
She'll be tired.
Take a tray up to her bedroom.
Is Thomas back?
Not yet, Mr Carson.
He asked if he could run down
the village. I didn't see why not.
It's iniquitous. They can't expect
you to sit by silent
as your fortune is stolen away.
Can't they?
His Lordship'd never let it happen.
How's Bates working out?
Well...
I don't like to say.
Only, it seems unkind to criticise
a man for an affliction, my Lady.
Even if it means he can't do his job.
How are you settling in?
Very well...I think. Unless your
Lordship feels differently.
No complaints?
If I had any, I should take them
to Mr Carson, my Lord, not you.
You're probably right.
And the house hasn't worn you out
with the endless stairs and so on?
I like the house, my Lord.
I like it as a place to work.
What happened?
It's only the old wound.
After I left the army, I had a spot
of bother
and just when I'd got through that,
about a year ago,
my knee started playing up.
A bit of shrapnel got left in
or something, and it moved.
But it's fine. It's not a problem.
And you'd let me know if you felt
it was all too much for you?
I would. But it won't be.
Thomas.
And where have you been?
The village.
To send a telegram,
if you must know.
Oh, pardon me for living.
Well, Murray didn't stay long.
Does her Ladyship know
how they left it? No.
They talked it all through
on the way back from the church.
If I was still his valet,
I'd get it out of him.
Bates won't say a word.
He will not.
I'd bet you a tanner he's a spy in
the other direction.
I wanted that job. We were all right
together, his Lordship and me.
Then be sure to get your foot in
the door when Bates is gone.
We can't get rid of him just because
he talks behind our backs.
There's more than one way
to skin a cat.
Perhaps she misunderstood.
No, it was quite plain.
O'Brien told her Bates can't do
the job properly.
Why was he taken on?
Oh, he was Lord Grantham's batman
when he was fighting the Boers.
I know that, but even so!
I think it's romantic.
I don't!
How can a valet do his work
if he's lame?
He's not VERY lame.
There.
Anything else before I go down?
No. That's it. Thank you.
Oh, I hate black.
It's not for long.
Ma says we can go into
half-mourning next month,
and to colours by September.
Still a lot for a cousin.
But not a fiance.
He wasn't really a fiance...
No?
I thought that was what you call
a man you're going to marry.
I was only going to marry him
if nothing better turned up.
Mary, what a horrid thing to say!
Don't worry.
Edith would have taken him,
wouldn't you?
Yes. I'd have taken him.
If you'd given me the chance,
I'd have taken him like a shot.
I just think you should know
it's not working, Mr Carson.
Do you mean Mr Bates is lazy?
Not lazy, exactly.
But he just can't carry.
He can hardly manage his Lordship's
cases.
You saw how it was
when they went up to London.
He can't help with the guests'
luggage,
and as for waiting at table,
forget that.
And what do you want me to do?
It's not for me to say.
But is it fair on William
to have all the extra work?
I don't believe you'd like to think
the house was falling below
the way things ought to be.
I would not.
That's all I'm saying.
I'm going down. Coming?
In a moment. You go.
I know you're sad about Patrick,
whatever you say, I know it.
You're a darling.
But you see, I'm not as sad
as I should be.
And that's what makes me sad.
Thank you.
(DROPS BRUSH)
I'll do that.
No. No, thank you, my Lord.
I can do it.
I'm sure.
I hope so, my Lord.
I hope you are sure.
Bates, we have to be sensible.
I won't be doing you a favour in the
long run if it's too much for you.
Whatever we've been through,
it has to work.
Of course, sir. I mean, my Lord.
Whatever we've been through,
it has to work.
Of course, sir. I mean, my Lord.
Do you miss the army, Bates?
I miss a lot of things,
but you have to keep moving,
don't you?
Ha! You do, indeed.
I'll show you, my Lord. I promise.
I won't let you down.
We've managed so far, haven't we?
Yes, we have. Of course we have.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
You look very nice.
Thank you, darling.
Did Murray make matters clearer?
Yes, I'm afraid he did.
O'Brien says Bates is causing
a lot of awkwardness downstairs.
You may have to do something about
it. She's always making trouble.
Is that fair, when she hasn't
mentioned it before now?
I don't know why you listen to her.
It is quite eccentric, even for you,
to have a crippled valet.
Please, don't use that word.
Did he tell you he couldn't walk
when he made his application?
Don't exaggerate. Doesn't it strike
you as dishonest not to mention it?
I knew he'd been wounded.
You never said.
You know I don't care to talk about
all that.
I understand what it must be like,
to have fought alongside someone
in a war.
Oh, you understand that, do you?
Certainly I do.
You must form the most tremendous
bonds, even with a servant.
Really? Even with a servant?
Oh, Robert, don't catch me out.
I'm simply saying I fully see why
you want to help him. But?
But...is this the right way to employ
him for a job he can't do?
Is it any wonder if the others' noses
are put out?
I just want to give him a chance.
Mama, I'm sorry.
No-one told me you were here.
Oh dear, such a glare!
I feel as if I were on stage
at the Gaiety.
We're used to it.
I wish you'd let me install it in
the Dower House. It's so convenient.
The man who manages the generator
could look after yours as well. No.
I couldn't have electricity in
the house. I wouldn't sleep a wink.
All those vapours! Even Cora won't
have it in the bedrooms.
She did wonder about the kitchens -
I couldn't see the point.
Before anyone joins us, I'm glad of
this chance for a little talk.
I gather Murray was here today.
News travels fast.
Yes, I saw him, and he's not
optimistic
that there's anything we can do.
I refuse to believe it.
Be that as it may, it's a fact.
But to lose Cora's fortune...
Really, Mama.
You know as well as I do
that Cora's fortune is not
Cora's fortune any more!
Thanks to Papa,
it is now part of the estate
and the estate is entailed
to my heir!
That is it! That is all of it!
Robert, dear, I don't mean to sound
harsh... But I bet you will.
24 years ago you married Cora,
against my wishes, for her money.
Give it away now, and what was
the point of your peculiar marriage
in the first place?
If I were to tell you
she'd made me happy,
would that stretch belief?
It's not why you chose her.
Above all the other girls who could
have filled my shoes so easily...
If you must know, when I think of
my motives for pursuing Cora,
I'm ashamed. There's no need
to remind me of them.
Don't you care about Downton?
What do YOU think?
I've given my life to Downton.
I was born here
and I hope to die here.
I claim no career beyond the nurture
of this house and the estate.
It is my third parent
and my fourth child.
(EMOTIONAL) Do I care about it?
Yes, I do care!
I hope I don't hear sounds of
a disagreement.
Is that what they call discussion
in New York?
I'm glad you're fighting. I'm glad
somebody's putting up a fight.
You're not really fighting Granny?
Your grandmother merely wishes to do
the right thing. And so do I.
Dinner is served, my Lady.
Does anyone else keep dreaming about
the Titanic?
I can't get it out of my mind.
Not again. Give it a rest.
Daisy, it's time to let it go.
But all them people,
freezing to death in the midnight,
icy water.
Oh, you sound like a penny dreadful.
I expect you saw worse things
in South Africa, eh, Mr Bates?
Not worse, but...pretty bad.
Did you enjoy the war?
I don't think anyone enjoys war,
but there are some good memories too.
I'm sure there are.
Mr Bates, could you hand me
that tray?
Blast!
I'll do it.
The ladies are out.
We've given them coffee
and his Lordship's taken his port
to the library.
Anna, Gwen,
go up and help clear away.
Daisy, tell Mrs Patmore
we'll eat in 15 minutes.
I keep forgetting. Does this go
next door or back to the kitchen?
Those go back, but the dessert
service and all the glasses
stay in the upstairs pantry.
Put it on here.
What is it? Her Ladyship's told him
she thinks Mr Bates ought to go.
She said to me, 'If only his Lordship
had been content with Thomas.'
Did she really?
What are you doing up here?
It's a free country.
Well, I'm going for my dinner.
You two can stay here...plotting.
So, the young Duke of Crowborough
is asking himself to stay.
And we know why.
You HOPE you know why.
That is not at all the same.
You realise the Duke thinks
Mary's prospects have altered?
I suppose so.
There's no 'suppose' about it.
Of course, this is exactly the sort
of opportunity
that will come to Mary,
if we can only get things settled
in her favour.
Is Robert coming round?
Not yet.
To him, the risk is, we'd succeed in
saving my money but not the estate.
He feels he'd be betraying his duty
if Downton were lost because of him.
Well, I'll write to Murray.
He won't say anything different.
Well, we have to start somewhere.
Our duty is to Mary.
Well, give him a date for when
Mary's out of mourning.
No-one wants to kiss a girl
in black.
Oh, do stop admiring yourself!
He's not marrying you for your looks.
That's if he wants to marry you
at all.
He will.
You look beautiful.
Thank you, Sybil.
(DOOR OPENS)
CORA: We should go down.
They'll be back from the station
at any moment.
Let's not gild the lily, dear.
(And Mary, try and look surprised.)
Are you all ready?
Very well.
We shall go out to greet them.
And me, Mr Carson?
No, Daisy, not you.
Can you manage, Mr Bates,
or would you rather wait here?
I want to go, Mr Carson.
There's no obligation
for the whole staff to go.
I'd like to be there.
Well, it's certainly a great day
for Downton
to welcome a duke under our roof.
Help me with the luggage.
Don't go running off.
I'll give you a hand.
I couldn't ask that, Mr Bates,
not in your condition.
How long do we have to put up
with this, Mr Carson, just so I know?
(DOG BARKS)
Welcome to Downton.
Lady Grantham,
this is so kind of you.
Not at all, Duke. We're delighted
you could spare the time.
You know my daughter Mary,
of course. Lady Mary.
And Edith. But I don't believe
you've met my youngest, Sybil.
Ah. Lady Sybil.
How do you do?
Come on in. You must be worn out.
Oh, Lady Grantham,
I have a confession to make
which I hope won't cause any bother.
My man was taken ill
just as I was leaving, so I...
Oh, well, that won't be a problem,
will it, Carson? Certainly not.
I shall look after his Grace myself.
Oh, no. I wouldn't dream of being
such a nuisance. Surely, a footman...
I remember this man.
You served me when I dined with
Lady Grantham in London.
I did, Your Grace.
Ah, there we are.
We shall do very well together,
won't we...? Thomas, your Grace.
Thomas...
Good.
I hope you had a pleasant journey.
Hm.
Bates, are you all right?
Perfectly, my Lord. I apologise.
Mr Bates.
That's better.
Please, don't feel sorry for me.
What shall we do?
What would YOU like to do?
I think I'd rather like to go
exploring.
Certainly. Gardens or house?
Oh, house, I think.
Gardens are all the same to me.
(POLITE CHUCKLE) Very well...
We can begin in the hall,
one of the oldest - No!
Not all those drawing rooms
and libraries.
Well, what, then?
I don't know...
The secret passages and the attics.
It seems a bit odd, but...why not?
I'll just tell Mama.
No, don't tell your mama.
But there's nothing wrong in it.
No, indeed.
I'm only worried the others
will want to join us.
Mary's settling him in.
Cora, don't let Mary
make a fool of herself.
By the way, I'll be going
up to London next week.
Do you want to open the house?
No, I'll just take Bates
and stay at the club.
I won't be more than a day or two.
I see.
Are things progressing?
What things?
It's just a regimental dinner.
It was a pity Bates spoiled
the arrival this afternoon.
He didn't spoil anything.
He fell over.
It was so undignified.
Carson hates that kind of thing.
I don't care what Carson thinks.
(CARSON CLEARS THROAT)
A message from the Dowager Countess,
my Lady.
She says she won't come to tea,
but she'll join you for dinner.
Look, Carson, I hope you weren't
embarrassed this afternoon.
I can assure you the Duke very much
appreciated his welcome. I'm glad.
Is Bates all right?
I think so, my Lord.
It must be so difficult for you,
all the same.
Don't stare.
Do you realise this is the first
time we've ever been alone?
Then you've forgotten when I pulled
you into the conservatory
at the Northbrooks'.
How sad.
No, I haven't.
It's not quite the same with 20
chaperones hiding behind every fern.
And are you pleased to be alone
with me, my Lady?
Oh, dear. If I answer truthfully,
you'll think me rather forward.
I don't think we should pry.
It feels rather...disrespectful.
Nonsense.
It's your father's house, isn't it?
You've a right to know what goes on
in it.
Where does this lead?
To the men's quarters,
with the lock on the women's side.
Only Mrs Hughes is allowed
to turn it.
(TURNS DOOR HANDLE) Mrs Hughes...
and you.
In here?
A footman, I imagine.
Should you do that?
Why not?
I'm making a study on the genus
'footman'.
I seek to know the creature's ways.
(CHUCKLES)
(DOOR BANGS)
Someone's coming!
Can I help you, my Lady?
We were just exploring.
Did you want Thomas, your Grace?
No. As Lady Mary said,
we've just been exploring.
Would you care to explore my room,
my Lady?
Of course not, Bates.
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
We were just going down.
Why did you apologise to that man?
It's not his business what we do.
I always apologise when I'm in
the wrong. It's a habit of mine.
The plain fact is, Mr Bates,
through no fault of his own,
is not able to fulfil
the extra duties expected of him.
He can't lift,
he can't serve at table,
he's dropping things
all over the place.
On a night like tonight,
he should act as a third footman.
As it is, my Lord, we may have to
have a maid in the dining room.
Cheer up, Carson. There are worse
things happening in the world.
Not worse than a maid
serving a duke.
So you're quite determined?
It's a hard decision, your Lordship,
a very hard decision,
but the honour of Downton
is at stake.
Don't worry, Carson.
I know all about hard decisions when
it comes to the honour of Downton,
don't I, boy?
William, you mustn't let Thomas
take advantage.
He's only a footman, same as you.
It's all right, Mrs Hughes.
I like to keep busy.
Takes your mind off things.
What things have you got to take
your mind off?
If you're feeling homesick,
there's no shame in it.
No.
It means you come from a happy home.
There's plenty of people here
would envy that.
Yes, Mrs Hughes.
Will that be all, my Lord?
Yes.
That is, not exactly.
Have you recovered from your fall
this afternoon?
I'm very sorry about that, my Lord.
I don't know what happened.
The thing is, Bates.
I said I would give you a trial,
and I have.
If it were only up to me...
It's this question of a valet's
extra duties.
Waiting at table
when there's a large party?
That, and carrying things, and...
You see that Carson can't compromise
the efficiency of his staff?
I do, my Lord. Of course I do.
Might I make a suggestion?
That when an extra footman is
required,
the cost could come out of my wages.
Absolutely not. I can't allow that.
Because I am very eager to stay,
my Lord. Very eager, indeed.
I know you are. And I was eager
that this should work.
You see, it is unlikely that I shall
find another position.
But in a smaller house,
where less is expected of you...
It's not likely. I mean to help
until you find something.
I couldn't take your money, my Lord.
Just wages for a job done.
Very good, my Lord. I'll go at once.
Don't rush out into the night.
Take the London train tomorrow.
It leaves at nine.
You'll have a month's wages too.
That I insist on.
It's a bloody business, Bates,
but I can't see any way round it.
I quite understand, my Lord.
I'm afraid we're rather a female
party tonight, Duke.
But you know what it's like trying
to balance numbers in the country.
A single man outranks
the Holy Grail!
No, I'm terribly flattered
to be dining en famille.
What were you and Mary doing
in the attics this afternoon?
I expect Mary was showing the Duke
the house, weren't you?
Are you a student of architecture?
Absolutely.
Then I do hope you'll come
and inspect my little cottage.
It was designed by Wren
for the first Earl's sister.
The attics?
Yes.
Mary took the Duke up to the attics.
Whatever for?
Why was this, dear?
We were just looking around.
Looking around? What is there
to look at but servants' rooms?
What was the real reason?
Don't be such a chatterbox, Edith!
I think we'll go through.
I still don't understand.
Will you hold your tongue?
How long do you think they'll be?
I'm starving.
Have you settled the ladies?
Yes, Mr Carson.
Then it won't be long
once they go through.
Do you think he'll speak out?
Do you think we'll have a duchess
to wait on? Imagine that!
You won't be waiting on her!
There is no reason why the eldest
daughter and heiress of the Earl
should not wear a duchess's coronet
with honour.
Heiress, Mr Carson?
Has it been decided?
It will be,
if there's any justice in the world.
Well, we'll know soon enough.
What are you doing, Anna?
I thought I'd take something
up to Mr Bates,
him not being well enough
to come down.
You don't mind, do you, Mrs Hughes?
I don't mind.
Not this once.
No, take him whatever he might need.
Mr Bates is leaving without a stain
on his character.
I hope you all observe that
in the manner of your parting.
I don't see why he has to go.
I don't mind doing extra -
It's not up to you.
I'll take care of his Lordship,
shall I?
Not while you're looking after
the Duke, you won't.
I'll see to his Lordship myself.
(MUFFLED CRYING AND SNIFFLING)
Mr Bates?
Are you there?
I brought something up,
in case you were hungry.
That's very kind.
I'm ever so sorry you're going.
I'll be all right.
Of course you will.
There's always a place for a man
like you.
Oh, yes...
Something'll turn up.
Tell us...when you're fixed.
Just...drop us a line.
Else I'll worry.
Well, we can't have that.
(SNIFFS)
We must go and let the servants
get in here.
I'd be grateful if we can stay
a minute more.
I have something to ask you.
I was terribly sorry to hear about
your cousins. You said.
Did you know them? Not well. I used
to see Patrick at the odd thing.
I imagine it will mean
some adjustments for you all.
To lose two heirs in one night
is terrible.
Indeed. It was terrible.
Awful.
But then again, it's an ill wind...
At least Lady Mary's prospects
must have rather improved.
Have they?
Haven't they?
I will not be coy and pretend I do
not understand your meaning,
though you seem very informed
on this family's private affairs.
But you ought perhaps to know that
I do not intend to fight the entail,
not any part of it.
You can't be serious.
It pains me to say it, but I am.
You'll give up your entire estate,
your wife's money into the bargain,
to a perfect stranger?
You won't even put up a fight?
I hope he proves to be perfect,
but I rather doubt it.
Ah...
Very odd thing to joke about.
No odder than this conversation.
So, there you have it.
But Mary will still have
her settlement,
which you won't find ungenerous.
(COUGHS) I-I'm sorry?
I only meant that her portion,
when she marries,
will be more than respectable.
You'll be pleased, I promise you.
Oh, heavens.
I hope I haven't given the wrong
impression.
You know the -
My dear Lord Grantham -
Don't 'My dear Lord Grantham' me!
You knew what you were doing
when you came here.
You encouraged Mary, all of us,
to think -
Forgive me, but I came to express
my sympathies and my friendship,
nothing more.
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
Lady Mary is a charming person.
Whoever marries her
will be a lucky man.
He will not, however, be me.
I see. And what was it that you asked
me to stay behind to hear?
(STEADY RAIN AND DISTANT THUNDER)
I forget.
Aren't you coming into the drawing
room?
I-I'm tired.
I think I'll just slip away.
Please make my excuses.
I'm afraid I've worn you out.
Tomorrow, we can just -
I'm leaving in the morning.
Good night.
Oh, you might tell that footman...
Thomas. Thomas.
You might tell him I've gone up.
So he slipped the hook.
At least I'M not fishing
with no bait!
I don't believe that!
Well, believe what you like.
He won't break the entail.
The unknown cousin gets everything
and Mary's inheritance will be
the same as it always was.
How was I to know?
When the lawyer -
You weren't to. You did the right
thing to telegraph me.
It's just not going to come off.
So what now?
Well, you, you know how I'm fixed.
I have to have an heiress - if it
means going to New York to find one.
What about me?
You...You will wish me well.
You said you'd find me a job
if I wanted to leave.
And do you?
I want to be a valet.
I'm sick of being a footman.
Thomas, I don't need a valet.
I thought you were getting rid of
the new one here. I've done it,
but I'm not sure Carson's going to
let ME take over.
I want to be with you.
I just can't see it working,
can you?
We don't have the basis of a
servant-master relationship, do we?
You came here to be with ME!
Among other reasons.
And...one swallow
doesn't make a summer.
Aren't you forgetting something?
What?
Are you threatening me?
Because of a youthful dalliance?
A few weeks of madness
in a London Season?
You wouldn't hold that against me,
surely? I would if I have to.
And who'd believe a greedy footman
over the words of a Duke?
If you're not careful,
you'll end up behind bars.
I've got proof.
Hm...
Do you mean these?
You know,
my mother's always telling me,
never put anything in writing.
And now, thanks to you,
I never will again.
How did you get them, you bastard?
No need to be a bad loser, Thomas.
Go to bed.
Unless you want to stay?
(DEEP BREATH)
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
I think I'll turn in.
No big announcement, then?
No, nor likely to be.
He's off on the nine o'clock train.
He never is?
And when we've had a turkey killed
for tomorrow's dinner!
I wonder what she did wrong.
She did nothing wrong,
not from the way his Lordship was
talking.
So his Grace turned out to be
graceless! Hm!
Good night, Mrs Hughes.
Goodnight, Mr Carson.
(DOOR SHUTS)
If you knew that was your decision,
why put Mary through it?
But I didn't know it was my decision,
my final decision, until tonight.
But I find I cannot ruin the estate
or hollow out the title
for the sake of Mary,
even with a better man than that.
I try to understand. I just can't.
Why should you? Downton is in
my blood and in my bones,
it's not in yours.
And I can no more be the cause of
its destruction
than I could betray my country.
Besides, how was I to know he
wouldn't take her without the money?
Don't pretend to be a child
because it suits you.
Do you think she would have been
happy, with a fortune hunter?
She might have been. I was!
Have you been happy? Really?
Have I made you happy?
Yes.
That is,
since you fell in love with me,
which if I remember correctly was
about a year after we were married.
Not a year. Not as long as that.
But it wouldn't have happened
for Mary. Why not?
Because I am so much nicer
than the Duke of Crowborough.
I'll be the judge of that.
Just don't think I'm going
to let it rest, Robert.
I haven't given up, by any means.
I must do what my conscience
tells me. And so must I.
And I don't want you to think
I'll let it rest.
(BIRDSONG)
my Lord, would it be acceptable for
Bates to ride in front with Taylor?
Otherwise it means getting
the other car out.
He and his Grace are catching
the same train.
Perfectly acceptable.
And if his Grace doesn't like it,
he can lump it.
You've been so kind, Lady Grantham.
Thank you.
Goodbye, Duke.
You'll make my farewells
to your delightful daughters?
They'd have been down
if they'd known.
Alas, something's come up which has
taken me quite by surprise.
Obviously.
Grantham, this has been
a highly enjoyable interlude.
Has it? And I feared it had proved
a disappointment.
Not at all, not at all.
My stay in your house
has driven away my cares.
We ought to go, my Lord,
if His Grace is to catch the train.
Goodbye, Bates. And good luck.
Good luck to YOU, my Lord.
(ENGINE RUNNING)
Wait!
Get out, Bates.
THE DUKE: I really mustn't be late.
Get back inside
and we'll say no more about it.
(MOTOR CAR DRIVES OFF)
It wasn't right, Carson.
I just didn't think it was right.
First post, Ma'am.
Thank you, Ellen.
One for you.
Oh. Thank you, Mother.
It's from Lord Grantham.
Really?
What on earth does he want?
He wants to change our lives.
Welcome to Downton.
Why are you so against him?
He isn't one of us.
I stole. I'm a thief.
You have my resignation.
For once in your life,
will you please just listen?
No-one can foresee the future,
Doctor. Not we
and certainly not Mrs Crawley.
Oh, no. You're far too busy,
and I wouldn't want to push in.
Adriano_CSI