WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
I shall have arms like Jack Johnson
if I'm not careful.
I'm strong enough to wheel myself.
I'll be the judge of that.
Morning.
I keep thinking about William.
How he should be here...
not exactly instead of me,
but sacrifice should be rewarded.
He was the brave one.
You were both brave.
I don't think we can say 'should'
about things that happen in war.
It just happens
and we should live with it.
Ought I to be jealous?
I'm sorry,
what were we talking about?
I was asking about Haxby Park. I'm
taking Mary over there tomorrow.
Our Haxby Park?
Why? Are the Russells selling?
Not officially, but I am told
they're open to offers.
Sad. The Russells and the Crawleys
have been neighbours for centuries.
They're not living there any more.
It'll be strange for Mary.
She's been going to that house since
she was a girl in a party dress.
We all have. There's nowhere better
near Downton.
I'm not sure how comfortable it is.
It'll be comfortable
when I'm finished with it.
Central heating, modern kitchens,
bathrooms with every bedroom,
it's all possible.
Sounds more like an hotel.
Major Clarkson.
Good morning, Lord Grantham.
Lady Edith. Sir.
We've had a request.
A Canadian Major has asked
to come here
because of a family link
with the house.
We've taken officers
from his regiment before,
but I wanted to be sure
you'd no objection.
What's his name? Gordon.
Patrick Gordon.
He was with Princess Patricia's Canadian
Light Infantry at Passchendaele.
Caught in a blast and burned,
rather badly, I believe.
Poor fellow.
Well, he's perfectly welcome.
I'm not aware of how we are
connected, but you never know.
Sir.
I hope it doesn't break us up.
Having you two set apart
in a home of your own, all special,
while the rest of us
muddle on for ourselves.
You sound as if you're jealous.
I'm not jealous. I just
don't want it to spoil things.
Why, because we've all been
such pals until now (?)
Give her time.
CORA:
Matthew's making such progress.
I think so,
but are we doing enough for him,
for all of them,
when it comes to rehabilitation?
They're going to have to face a
very different world after the war.
I agree, but they'll all
be leaving Downton soon.
Leaving?
Well, Turkey's about to capitulate
and Robert says
Vittorio Veneto will finish Austria,
so it's only a matter of weeks,
even days, before it's over.
We wouldn't send anyone home
too soon, of course,
but some time in the new year,
we will have our house back.
So you want it just to be
a private house again?
Shouldn't she?
Or would you like to abolish
private houses?
Well, that life of changing clothes
and killing things and eating them,
do you really want it again?
Wouldn't you rather Downton
was useful? The house is useful.
We provide employment. Oh, please...
Let me look into keeping it open
as a centre of recovery.
I could run it. The house could be
so much more than it was before.
What about you, Molesley?
Are you looking forward to
this brave new world of
Mrs Crawley's imaginings?
I'm glad of my job, m'lady,
and I should very much like
to hold onto it,
with Mrs Crawley's permission.
Servants are always far more
conservative than their employers.
Everyone knows that.
Then I must be
the exception that proves the rule.
EDITH: Hello.
My name's Edith Craw...
(CANADIAN ACCENT)
Lady Edith Crawley, I know.
Second daughter of the house.
In charge of non-medical welfare.
So whatever you need, in the way
of errands run or books to read,
then I'm your man.
Thank you.
I hope this doesn't put you off.
I can assure you, at this stage,
there isn't much that puts me off.
Did they tell you we're related?
Er... Er yes, but I'm afraid
I'm not much good at family history.
Although Papa's found an aunt
in 1860 who married a Gordon.
Perhaps that's a clue.
No, that isn't it.
Well, as I say, I'm hopeless.
I-I thought
you'd recognise my voice
but, of course,
I sound Canadian now.
You mean we've met before?
It was a long time ago.
Edith, I need you.
It just explains
what you're entitled to.
That's kind but, let's face it,
I'm not a widow, am I? Not really.
Of course you are. No I'm not.
How long was I married?
Six hours? Seven?
I shouldn't have taken his name,
except it were what he wanted.
Well, I'll leave it wi' you.
Daisy?
It wouldn't please William
if you don't take what's owing.
He wanted you to be looked after.
No. You made me a liar
while he was alive.
You'll not make me be false to
his memory.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
You can leave me, Brooks.
Yes, sir.
Mr Bates said you wanted to see me,
sir.
Ah, yes.
I asked you up here,
because I want to offer you a job.
I have a job, sir.
Yes, of course you do,
I'm sure you enjoy it.
I don't mean to suggest
I'm offering a better one.
Thank you.
Although it would mean
a considerable increase in salary.
Lady Mary and I intend
to buy a home near Downton.
It's a long way from London,
but I've made enough money
to please myself, these days.
I know she holds you in high regard.
I believe she would very much
appreciate your help
when she first sets up house
as a bride.
You mean you wish me to leave
Downton Abbey and transfer...
Tomorrow, we go to see Haxby Park.
If we buy it, we'll take on
the whole 12,000 acres.
No doubt you will discover
many interesting walks to enjoy.
Of course it's run down,
but there's nothing wrong with it
that money can't fix.
So... what do you think?
One thing I must ask.
Is Lady Mary aware
that you have approached me?
Not yet.
I wanted to surprise her.
She thinks highly of you, Carson.
I hope I won't be taking on a rival.
I await Lady Mary's instruction.
I don't dislike him, I just don't
like him, which is quite different.
Did he talk about Haxby?
He's got ghastly plans for the place.
Of course, Cora doesn't agree.
I'm an American. I don't share
your English hatred of comfort.
Downton's comfortable enough for me.
I can't wait to have it back.
That's if Cousin Isabelle allows it.
She turned up today with
a hideous list of projects
that stretched to 1920 and beyond.
Surely you can put her off.
I don't know how,
once the bit's between her teeth.
Well, change the bridle.
Find a cause that needs her
more than Downton.
She's such a martyr.
Then we must tempt her
with a more enticing scaffold.
We're safe.
We've got the Decree Nisi.
I'm sure it's all right.
Except you're not sure.
Not sure about what?
What about you, Sergeant? Have you
started planning for after the war?
Not really, not yet.
I know what you should be doing.
I know what we should all be doing.
Oh, yeah? What's that?
Hoarding.
It may be wrong, but
this rationing is starting to bite.
Even with everyone's books,
I had a battle to get enough sugar
for this week.
Are you suggesting the black market,
Mrs Patmore?
I'm shocked.
Oh, I doubt that very much.
I'm sorry I couldn't get down this
week, but we've had a house full.
Who's looking after the baby?
My neighbour.
She's lent me her bike,
so I can get back.
(RATTLING)
Oh, well, you'd best be off.
(GASPS)
I can't, darling,
I've got too much work.
We're losing two of the nurses
and they must rearrange the roster.
If Mary's out with Carlisle
and Edith's going to Mama's,
I'll be on my own.
What about Sybil?
Sybil's on duty. (SIGHS)
I wish you'd told me. I could've
fixed something up for myself.
You could always
ask Major Clarkson to join you,
if you really can't be on your own
for one luncheon. I'll manage.
MARY: It's so empty.
I didn't know they'd gone.
They've given up.
You can't blame them.
When Billy was killed, it knocked
the stuffing out of them completely.
What'll we do about furniture
and pictures and everything?
What does anyone do?
Buy it, I presume.
Your lot buys it,
my lot inherits it.
We ought to be getting back.
Why?
What's at Downton that needs
your attention so urgently?
So...
Shall we rescue it?
Shall we give the house
another chapter?
Well, I suppose
one has to live somewhere.
You're telling me we've
been feeding Ethel for some time?
We have, m'lady.
Well, supplementing her food.
I didn't think you'd mind,
what with the baby and all,
but Mr Carson suggested you'd like
to be informed, all the same.
Carson is right, Mrs Hughes.
But the girl was our employee
and, while she was in the wrong...
Indeed she was.
Men will always be men
but for any young woman to let her
judgement so desert her...
She's not the first girl
to be taken in by a uniform.
And, don't worry, Carson, the baby
will make sure she pays the price.
Has she tried to get the father
to assume some responsibility?
She's tried and failed, I'm afraid.
I wonder.
If I were to write to Major Bryant,
inviting him to visit us again,
maybe Lord Grantham
can prevail on his good nature.
I'm not sure
he's got one to prevail on.
Satisfied? I feel sorry for Ethel,
but I cannot condone
her inability
to pronounce a simple
two-letter word: 'No'.
The wine delivery
should've been here by 12.
Get me out of the dining room
when they come.
Serve the main course
and let Jane finish. He won't mind.
Has Carson abandoned me?
He's dealing with a wine delivery,
m'lord.
Shall I fetch him?
No, no. I daresay we'll manage.
I hope you're happy here
and that your family arrangements
are not proving too complicated.
Your Lordship has a good memory.
All our lives
are lived around our children.
How old is your son?
12, m'lord.
Is he at the local school?
He is, but he's trying for
a scholarship to Ripon Grammar.
Ah. Is that a realistic prospect?
I think so.
He has a real talent
for mathematics and...
his teachers believe
it's worth a try.
Well done him. I'm impressed.
Perhaps I can put in a word.
I'm sure I should say
'He wants to do it all by himself',
but I'm not proud,
so if you can say anything, m'lord,
then, for heavens' sake do.
Jane, have you finished in here?
I hope she wasn't talking
out of turn, m'lord.
Not at all, it was my fault,
I asked the questions.
(DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE)
But surely, if His Lordship
asks him, he must do something.
Why? What difference will it make?
We're not in the 14th century.
But when he hears that Lord
Grantham knows what he's done...
What's he done that all young men
aren't anxious to do
behind the bicycle sheds
every night?
What am I going to do,
if Major Bryant doesn't come round?
Who knows?
Go to a big city.
Invent a past.
You've broken the rules, my girl,
and it's no good pretending
they're easily mended.
Mr Bates, there's a telephone call
for you. It's your lawyer.
Shall I come with you?
Lady Mary was looking for you.
When was this?
When she got back from her outing.
Were you going to keep it a secret
all day?
I'm going to fetch my button box.
Thank you.
Any letters to post?
Look...
I know I've changed, and not
for the better, but even so,
do you really still
not recognise me?
I know. Why am I feeling so silly?
It's funny, isn't it?
I came here all the time
when I was growing up.
You were here?
At Downton?
You're not saying that you're...
Patrick.
Yes I am.
That's exactly what I'm saying.
I've just been hoping you'd realise
without my having to spell it out.
But Patrick's...
Dead? Drowned on the Titanic?
Of course, this must be
very hard for you.
BATES: That's ridiculous.
No, I'm sorry, of course,
I'm not saying it's your fault.
It's mine. It's all mine.
Yes.
Thank you.
Goodbye.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
She's gone and told the judge that
I paid her to agree to a divorce.
I suppose you did, didn't you?
Yes, I bloody well did.
So what does it mean?
Because we withheld it
from the court,
it means the judge can withdraw
the Decree Nisi.
It means I'm not divorced,
after all.
Above all it means that
I am a stupid, stupid, stupid man.
This won't change a thing.
We are going to be together,
whether she wants it or not.
If we have to leave here,
if we have to leave the country,
we are going to be together.
I was on the Titanic,
that much is true,
but I was pulled out of the water
by Fifth Officer Lowe,
the only one of them to come back.
At least,
that's what they said later.
When I properly came round,
they'd misidentified me as Canadian
and shipped me up to Montreal.
I don't understand.
Why didn't you just tell them
who you were?
Because I couldn't remember.
I don't know
if it was the blow to the head,
or the shock, or the cold,
but I had no memory.
As far as I knew, I was Canadian.
So... So what happened?
Well, I had no reason
to go back to England
so, in the end,
I took my name from a gin bottle.
Then, in 1914,
I joined Princess Pat's Infantry.
And what changed?
I was caught in
a big explosion at Passchendaele.
When I woke up,
it all came back.
Suddenly, I knew who I was.
I began to call myself
Patrick again.
Why not your whole name?
Why didn't you send a message
at once?
I nearly did
and then I heard that Downton was
an officers' convalescent home.
I thought that
if I came here and you knew me,
the hard part would be over.
But we didn't know you.
Precisely.
I must... talk to Papa.
We've Matthew the new heir
to think about.
Ah. The new heir, yes.
This will be very difficult
for him, of course.
It must be so hard for you,
what with Mary getting married...
Did I love her very much?
Well, I'm the wrong person to ask.
Because you were the one
who really loved me, you mean?
I... never thought Patrick knew.
(TEARFULLY) Well, he did.
I-I do.
(BIRDSONG)
It's big.
The staircase is prettier
than the one here,
but mainly, it's just big.
Can we stop?
I'd much rather see your face
when we talk.
So will you buy it?
Probably.
He says he wants to steal Carson
to come and run it for us.
I don't envy you, telling your Papa.
Mm.
Suppose Carson won't do it?
Since he would open his veins
for you,
I don't think there's much doubt.
I don't have to marry him, you know.
Yes you do.
If I thought for a moment that I was
an argument against your marriage,
I should jump into the nearest river.
And how would you manage that,
without my help?
I'd get you to push me. (CHUCKLES)
Seriously, I can only relax
because I know that you have
a real life coming.
If I ever thought
I was putting that in jeopardy,
I'd go away and never see you again.
You don't mean that. But I do.
I am the cat that walks by himself
and all places are alike to me.
I have nothing to give
and nothing to share.
If you were not engaged
to be married...
I wouldn't let you
anywhere near me.
CARLISLE: You'd think he was
in Mary's sole charge.
I worry it'll mean a big adjustment
for him, when we marry.
I don't believe Matthew
has any desire
to stop her marrying, Richard.
Quite the contrary.
Maybe, but is she as convinced
as he is that they have no future?
What are you saying?
I suppose I'm asking whether
you want Mary to have children.
Because, if you do,
isn't it time for Lavinia Swire
to come back into his life?
I wish I knew how an engine worked.
I can teach you, if you'd like.
(GRUNTS)
That's Edith's territory.
I thought you were avoiding me.
Of course not.
But you haven't come up with
an answer yet, have you?
Not yet, I'm afraid.
I know you want to play your part
in Ireland's troubles
and I respect that,
but I just can't think about it all
until the war is over.
It won't be long now.
So will you wait?
I'd wait forever.
I'm not asking for forever.
Just a few more weeks.
You know, Old Ma Patmore's
not as mad as I thought.
Why do you say that?
I've made some enquiries
and she's right.
There's a big demand for
rationed food if I can find it.
And can you?
Maybe. I've been given a name.
I'll have to come up with
the money though.
And can you find the money?
I think so.
I've a bit put by,
and I could borrow some.
It's a risk though, isn't it?
You've gotta speculate to accumulate.
Hadn't you heard?
No, but I know the one about
neither a borrower or a lender be.
LORD GRANTHAM: What do you think?
All the chaps are wearing them
in London.
Only for informal evenings,
of course.
I'm not sure you'll get much use
out of it, when the war is over.
Maybe not, but I can wear it when
Her Ladyship and I are on our own.
You're very preoccupied, tonight.
Papa, can I have a word? Now?
What is it?
I think you'd better sit down.
Mm.
I knew you'd be in here,
making last-minute adjustments.
'Never leave anything to chance, '
m'lady, that's my motto.
Mine too, really.
Sometimes, I wish it wasn't.
I gather Sir Richard's asked you
about coming with us,
when we're married.
I need to hear what you think.
It's a terrific idea.
If anyone can keep me
out of trouble, it's you.
What about His Lordship?
Of course, he'll kill me,
but I'm sure he'll understand.
Well...
I'll give you my answer
when you've spoken to His Lordship.
It'd be a huge wrench for me
to leave Downton.
Major Gordon...
Edith has given me
an account of your conversation.
She said she would.
I wish you'd spoken to me first.
Obviously, I need time
to consider what you've said.
Well, I can offer little proof,
except that I know things
only the real Patrick would know.
I was never fingerprinted,
or anything.
Presumably you understand that
people would be seriously affected,
should your story be true.
You mean Cousin Matthew?
It would be very hard on Matthew.
Of course it would but, Robert...
I-I mean, Lord Grantham,
if you'd prefer it.
I would, until we know more.
When I was in hospital,
I had my story written down.
(GRUNTS)
So you can have it checked,
as far as that's possible.
Thank you.
I'll send it to my lawyers in London
and I'll break the news
to the family tomorrow.
Where did you learn to do that?
Do what?
Never mind.
Am I really a stranger?
Do you not recognise me at all?
It feels very odd
to be talking so formally.
The whole situation is
certainly odd, that I freely admit.
(BIRDSONG)
The war may be at an end,
but the upheaval is only beginning.
Oh, how right you are.
That is why Downton Abbey still has
such an important role to play.
Oh, dear me.
There's so much to be done.
When you think of all
the children laid up with disease...
But they're making
such advances now, aren't they?
Could we talk about the lecture
programme? If we must, we must,
if only I wasn't haunted
by those women
whose jobs will be snatched
from them when the boys come home.
We have to find work
for our heroes, don't we?
That must be our priority,
however hard that might sound.
As you say.
And what about
those wretched refugees?
What will become of them?
Ah, now you've struck a chord.
Have I really? Oh, thank heaven.
What do you mean? Oh, nothing.
Only the thought of
those poor men and women,
flung across Europe,
far from their homelands
and so much in need of your help.
My help? Why do you say that?
When it comes to helping refugees,
your experience renders your value
'beyond price'.
One of the organisers said
those words.
Which organiser?
I forget.
But what about running Downton?
I mean, I can't do both.
Well, I suppose you must decide
what it more important.
Exercise classes
and lectures on pottery,
or... helping men and women
build a new life.
I must go,
but I will think about it.
Are you coming to
Cousin Robert's dinner tonight?
Are you?
Well, I didn't feel I could say no.
He sent a note this morning and was
most insistent. What's it about?
I have no idea,
but we'll talk there.
We're onto something for you.
We mustn't let the iron grew cold.
Thank you.
You know there is
nothing more ill-bred
than to steal
other people's servants.
But you're not 'other people'
and Carson brought me up.
What does he say? That he won't do
anything without your permission.
Which, of course, is so cunning.
How can I refuse a man
who says that?
What do you say, Bates?
I say Mr Carson must have the last
word on where he lives and works.
You're ganging up on me.
You're a darling and I love you.
Now, what's this dinner all about?
Won't you tell me? You'll find out.
I'm sorry if it's a bit of a crush.
I didn't want to be overheard.
Are we talking financial ruin?
Or criminal investigation?
Neither.
I'll get straight to the point.
We have a patient
who has been badly burned
who goes by the name of
Patrick Gordon...
but he claims to be
Patrick Crawley.
But I thought he was dead.
Didn't he drown on the Titanic?
Well, of course, it is
what we all thought, until now.
They never found a body.
They never found lots of bodies.
I'm so sorry,
but I'm not quite on top of this.
Who's Patrick Crawley?
The man who would displace me
as heir.
If he's alive, then I am no longer
the future Earl of Grantham.
It's ridiculous.
How can it be true? Where's he been
hiding for the last six years?
In Canada, suffering from amnesia.
He does have a story
that would explain it,
but I'm not quite sure about
how to test the facts.
He knows all sorts of things
that only Patrick,
or someone very close to him
would know.
What a stupid thing to say.
Any fortune teller at a fair
comes up with a dozen details
he couldn't possibly know.
There's no need to be angry.
This young man
is either Patrick of he's not.
There must be a way to find out.
Is he like Patrick to look at?
He isn't like anything to look at.
I've sent his account off to George
Murray in London, to ask his advice.
What a waste of time and money.
What's the matter?
We were all so fond of Patrick.
You were going to marry him,
for heaven's sake.
Aren't you glad, if he survived?
Dear me.
Should I be worried? Certainly not.
This man is a fake and an imposter.
I think it's a cruel trick to play,
when Matthew's been through so much.
Oh, my dear,
don't be too quick to decide.
You never know, this might be
a blessing in disguise.
What do you mean?
Well, he seems a nice enough chap.
He's not very pretty, of course,
but he can walk round the estate
on his own two legs
and sire a string of sons
to continue the line.
I'd say that's a great improvement
on the current situation.
Sybil, could I prevail on you
to take me back to my room?
Of course.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Mrs Hughes, we've had a letter
in the evening post
from Major Bryant's father.
He must have found it
hard to write, for it seems
the Major has been killed
in the Battle of Vittorio Veneto.
How sad. I'm sorry to hear it.
I know and right at the end,
but there we are.
I'm afraid
it's the end of our story too.
What story is that, m'lady?
A friend of Mrs Hughes
knew the Major.
Can you relay the news? Of course.
Will that be all? Yes, thank you.
Is that the Major Bryant that Ethel
always thought so handsome, m'lady?
Too handsome for anyone's good.
I beg your pardon, Your Lordship,
I thought everyone had gone up.
Not yet.
Is there anything I can fetch you?
Nothing that would help.
(SIGHS)
Never mind me. Good night.
(MAGPIE CHATTERS)
Not a shock, exactly, but obviously
it was a tremendous surprise.
So what happens next?
Papa sent your statement
up to his solicitor.
What is it?
Do you remember this place?
Of course I do.
How we used to hide over there?
Wasn't there a governess
none of you liked?
Fraulein Kelder.
That's it. (BARKS) Fraulein Kelder!
(GIGGLES)
What fun we used to make of her.
Do you know,
I do recognise you now.
Do you?
You haven't changed at all.
Not a jot.
God knows I have.
It's not important.
Edith, if you really mean it,
do you think once it's all settled,
we might talk again?
But, if they've read Her Ladyship's
letter, won't his parents know?
I don't think so. She only
invited him to pay a visit.
She thought the subject of the baby
would come better face to face.
(DOG BARKS IN DISTANCE)
Could I write to them?
You could try,
but where's your proof?
With him dead,
you've no evidence at all.
Then I'm ruined.
You were ruined already, my girl,
so don't let's us go overboard.
How's that new maid getting on?
The lady with the little boy.
Very well, thank you. Why?
Just thinking.
Everyone wants to help her,
to feed her, to find her work,
because her son's father is dead.
So is the father of my son.
Where's the difference?
(BABY CRIES)
The difference is Jane is
a respectable, married woman
that some man chose to be his wife.
Is that enough?
It is in the real world.
(CRYING CONTINUES)
Carson, now, I wonder if I could be
put on the London train
at 9 o'clock tomorrow morning?
His Lordship's valet
is catching that one.
Would you object to his riding
in the front with the chauffeur?
Not at all. Meanwhile, have you
given my proposition any thought?
A great deal, Sir Richard.
I'll be back on the night of 10th.
Perhaps you could
let me have your answer, then.
Answer to what? As to whether
Carson will be captain of our ship.
With you at the helm, there's much
more chance of a smooth crossing.
Your Lordship,
I need to go to London tomorrow.
I've spoken to Mr Carson.
He has no objection.
Please say this concerns property
and not the former Mrs Bates.
I only wish she was 'the former',
m'lord,
or better still, 'the late'.
Indeed?
I have to reason with her.
I've found no other choice.
She's found a reason
to delay things again.
No, not delay.
She's found a way to ruin things.
Be sensible, Bates.
Above all, do not lose your temper.
A German Republic?
No, I don't think so, Mr Branson.
The Kaiser will go, I'll grant
you... (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
and maybe the Crown Prince too,
but there'll be a Regency.
Mark my words.
Monarchy is the lifeblood
of Europe. Sorry, Mr Carson,
but I think you'll find the kings
and emperors have had their day,
if President Wilson
has anything to say about it.
I'll have to go up to London.
What will you say to her
that you haven't said already?
I don't know, but I know staying
here won't make any difference.
You're always going to London,
Mr Bates. I have business in London.
Oh, yes?
Well, judging by your expression,
your business
doesn't seem to be prospering.
The trick of business is
to mind your own.
I'm sorry to disturb you, but I...
I've just heard news
from the War Office
and I thought you'd all like
to know...
that the war is over.
(APPLAUSE)
The ceasefire will begin
at 11 o'clock on the morning
of the 11th of November.
Why can't it begin now?
The 11th of the 11th,
seems pretty tidy to me.
We will mark the moment
in the Great Hall
and I expect all of you - including
the kitchen staff and hall boys...
everyone to be there - and Carson.
Oh, it's such wonderful news.
Is there any more glasses up there?
We should make a toast together.
To peace.
ALL: To peace.
The truth is, Cora, there is a
reason for inviting you here today
and I fear I'm going to be
a great disappointment to you. Oh?
Cousin Violet is, in part, to blame.
Yes, I usually am.
It was she who drew my attention
to the plight of the war refugees.
I feel very guilty,
since I chivvied you,
and now I'm jumping ship,
but I can't run Downton as well.
You must go where
you can make a difference.
This is what I think,
but I hope you will consider
keeping the house open without me.
I must be honest with you,
it was your idea, not ours,
so I doubt very much
we'll go on with it, now.
But what does that matter
when one thinks of
the work you'll be doing?
Don't you agree, Mama?
I-I... cannot find the words
to say how I feel.
What - what do you think, Molesley?
Sometimes fate knows best, m'lady.
I couldn't put it better myself.
Well...
There really is
something for her to do?
Absolutely. It's all set up.
I had to promise to be a patron,
but it seemed a small price to pay.
I know it was
for Robert and the girls,
but I thank you, without irony,
from the bottom of my heart.
And I accept your thanks, my dear,
with no trace of irony either.
Lawyers take forever
to answer anything,
so they can charge more.
But the others don't believe me,
do they?
Not like you.
I think they want to be certain.
But how can they ever be?
If the lawyer casts
even the slightest doubt,
won't that give them the excuse to
cut me out and stay with Matthew?
If only one of them recognised me.
They will do, soon.
No they won't. They've forgotten me.
I'm a stranger to them now!
Well, you're not a stranger to me.
I wouldn't be Vera Bates.
He left here at dawn,
with a face like thunder.
I wonder if she knows
what she's started.
If I were you, I'd keep out of it.
Wise words.
How did you get on?
Yeah, it was interesting.
Daisy, I wish you'd let me
tell you about it.
There's no point. No point in what?
Jane keeps making out
I'm a war widow, but I'm not, am I?
You all know that.
I married William on his deathbed,
that don't count.
Course it counts. I don't think so.
And I wasn't good to him.
He thought I loved him,
but I didn't, not like he loved me.
I should never have married him
in the first place, only...
Marrying him was a great kindness.
No, it wasn't kind.
It was wrong.
Mr Bates, how did you get here?
I walked from the station.
You should've said.
We'd have sent someone to meet you.
I was glad of the walk.
I was glad of the air.
I never thought
you'd be back tonight.
How was it?
Worse than you can possibly imagine.
What's...?
I assume that whatever Mr Murray has
told you means the man is a fake.
You can't have asked Matthew to be
here, unless you know that.
It's very complicated.
Lowe was the only officer to go back
to the site of the wreck.
He did pull
some people out of the sea
and it seems one of the men
was unidentified. There.
One of the reports has him dying
before they reached the Carpathia.
Precisely.
Another witness says
the man did get to New York alive,
but there's no clear record
of his name.
Which could be Patrick Crawley.
There's more.
There was a Peter Gordon who worked
with Patrick at the Foreign Office.
Now, he emigrated to Montreal
in 1913.
Yes and when
his face was blown away,
he decided
every cloud has a silver lining.
He was perfectly placed
to impersonate his dead friend.
No doubt they shared confidences,
so he just brushed them up
and put himself forward for
a major inheritance.
Granny's right.
All he needed was a survivor
from the Titanic
who was unaccounted for
and he found one.
But the Titanic story bears out
Patrick's version in every way.
What do you think?
I don't know what to think.
How can you even hesitate?
But, Mary, you haven't heard
the things he remembers.
I don't need to.
I remember how we played,
and your pony, and your birthday,
and how we hid in the garden
from the nasty governess.
What other memories would you have
of a childhood spent here?
Murray will continue to investigate
so, Edith,
can we be polite to the man,
but nothing more?
The end of the war should make it
easier to unearth the evidence.
That is all for the time being.
I thought Carlisle was going to come
back for our ceremony tomorrow.
He's driving up. He'll be here
in time for dinner, tonight.
I'm sorry I can't be more decisive.
Don't be.
I meant what I said, the other day.
It'll take a man who is
more than I am now to follow you,
so don't think about me.
My dear chap, how can you say that?
I never think about anything else.
What do they make of this Peter
Gordon character they've uncovered?
Do they think that's who I am?
Do you remember him?
Very well.
Peter and I were good friends.
Very good friends.
Did you know he'd moved to Canada?
How could I, when I'd forgotten
who I was, until two months ago?
Of course.
So what will they do now?
Track him down, I imagine.
Find out what happened to him.
Suppose he joined
the Princess Pat Light Infantry?
I don't understand.
What are you saying?
Why would he?
You're very sweet, you know.
So sweet, you made me think
that all things were possible.
But perhaps the lesson is
you can't go back.
You're tired and I don't blame you,
but you're not to give up.
I won't let you.
We'll find this Peter Gordon,
I know we will.
Yes.
I expect you will.
They'll be going in to dinner
in a minute.
We've built a good cellar here,
you know.
I'm not saying it's legendary,
but it's nothing to be ashamed of.
You've made your mind up, then?
I think so, yes.
I think I have...
but, with a heavy heart,
Mrs Hughes.
And just when we thought
we were getting back to normal.
Don't tell me you'll miss me.
I will, Mr Carson.
Very much.
And it costs me nothing to say it.
Thank you.
That means a lot to me.
Shall we go through with the ladies
and let them get in here? Of course.
I wonder what happened to Richard.
He'll have started late and...
Oh, I do apologise, Lady Grantham.
We got stuck in Royston and
a cart had overturned in Baldock.
Hello, my dear.
How lovely to see you.
Are you sure?
Sir Richard said
you were expecting me, but are you?
Of course we are.
Can you take Matthew into
the small library? Are you hungry?
We've finished, but Mrs Hughes can
easily put something on a tray.
Carson?
Nothing's changed.
But, you see, it has,
because I've changed.
When I was last here,
I was so bowled over
that I let you send me away,
but not this time.
I love you.
I'm going to look after you.
That's all there is to it.
And if I refuse?
I'm sorry, but I mean it.
You won't frighten me away,
whatever you do.
It seems such a waste of time
to drive from London
and get stuck in every town
on the way.
I don't agree. I'd love to drive
and you'd better agree if Anthony
Strallen comes back into your life.
Before you scold me,
it's no good pretending
Mary is not too attached to Matthew.
So you summon Lavinia,
to be sacrificed
like some latter-day Iphigenia
doomed to push his chair
through all eternity?
Robert, it's quite simple.
Do you want Mary's marriage
to be a success?
Do you want grandchildren?
Sometimes, Cora,
you can be curiously unfeeling.
MARY: Suppose he doesn't want
her back? Have you thought of that?
He needs someone to look after him.
Yes, but...
You'll be too busy
with our new life.
I know you're used to having
your own way. Yes, I am.
I'll say something now
I hope I won't have to repeat.
If you think you can jilt me,
or in some way set me aside,
I tell you now, you have given me
the power to destroy you.
Don't think I won't use it.
I want to be a good husband
and for you to be happy,
but don't ever cross me,
do you understand?
Never.
Absolutely never.
What's happened to Major Gordon?
He's gone.
But he can't have.
When?
After breakfast.
I couldn't very well stop him.
The war's over.
He left this for you.
What does it say?
'It was too difficult.
I'm sorry.
P Gordon.'
P for Patrick or P for Peter?
I know what you think,
but I don't accept it.
We drove him away.
His own family
drove our cousin away.
But you believed in him,
whoever he was,
and that's worth something.
I think, while the clock strikes,
we should all make a silent prayer
to mark the finish of
this terrible war...
and what that means
for each and every one of us.
Let us remember the sacrifices
that have been made
and the men who will never come back
and give them our thanks.
(CHIMES)
Thank you, everyone.
Remember, this is not just
the end of a long war,
but it is the dawn of a new age.
God bless you all.
(HUSHED CHATTER)
Let me help you with that.
Can you get him back to his room?
I'll open the door.
My God.
Is something wrong, sir?
No, nothing.
Bates, if I felt...
If you felt what, sir?
It doesn't matter. Not yet.
Not until I feel it again.
I thought that was very dignified.
Very calming.
Thank you, m'lord.
I don't suppose you're having
any doubts about leaving?
I'm afraid not, m'lord.
Well, I can't say I'm not sorry.
I won't go until
we've found a proper replacement.
Whoever we find won't replace you.
Yes, of course. Mr Bates.
Telegram for you.
What was that about?
His wife's dead.
Someone found her,
earlier this morning.
I've found a dealer.
You mean black market business?
I'm anxious to make Lady Mary happy.
I've had a request from Sir Richard
that you ought to know about.
I think I've found a way to escape.
Nothing too drastic, I hope.
I want to tell you all something.
Girls! Cora! Come at once!
Does this mean
that you've made up your mind?
I'm a foolish man who's lost his way
and don't know how to find it again.
You said yourself,
there wouldn't be another chance.
I bought it. It was arsenic.
I've been thinking
that's what she must have taken.
Mary is still in love with you.
Subtitles by APOLLO