Rather than love, than money,
that glory, give me the truth.
Henry David Thoreau
John, it's me!
John, come on! Open the door !
I have your box.
Oh my God !
It smells good here!
When did you open a window
for the last time ?
John, where are you?
I do not have a lot of time.
It's dark here.
Did you ask for the place
where Sid Vicious is deceased
John?
John, are you there?
- What was the letter saying?
- Honey, I do not know.
What do you mean ?
You said to have reported it
at the reception.
I did not say I did not know.
You just did it.
You said, "I do not know."
Rupert
the letter was not for you.
The reception made a mistake.
And return it without showing it to me
was just irrepressible?
Rupert, that's enough!
This is my first opportunity
to meet him
after all these years.
Honey, I know,
but you have a big day.
- Did you open the letter?
- Yes.
You saw that it was not for me ...
Yes, I already apologized.
... and you just brought it back
at the reception ?
- Yes.
- Well...
The reception could not have
send me the wrong letter
if she did not have one for me.
They sent my letter
to the wrong person.
So, a letter is waiting for me at the hotel.
Yes.
Yes surely.
Take something to eat ...
what you want,
and I call them right away.
Listen, we'll go to the hotel,
and I'm sure
that a letter will await you there,
and that you will meet
this afternoon.
It was written in green ink?
What?
I do not remember.
Honey, everything will be fine, okay?
We were informed that the actor
John Francis Donovan is deceased
at the age of 29.
It has gained importance in
the American television industry,
first as Adam White
in  Hellsome High ...
I forgot to work on me.
It's anything.
No network.
What year are we fucking?
Shit.
Hal, it's me.
Do not do this to me.
I have a flight to London at 14:30.
My date in Paris
was shifted, right?
I got your email this morning.
I could not answer,
my router was messing up.
Listen to me.
I came to greet him because
I am a civilized woman.
But you can not force me
to write an article.
I do not care,
send another reporter,
postpones the interview.
Robert Turner of my two
do not go flying!
I do not care to scratch his name,
I will not do it.
I did not even read his stupid book.
How can I interview someone
if I have not read ...
You see me writing
on a trend actor
who exhumes his past
only to boost his career?
I'm better than that.
Okay.
Yes, I have nothing more to say to you.
I will do it.
One o'clock.
If this little brat
allow himself the slightest arrogance,
I do not answer for anything.
Yeah. Hi, Hal.
It's crazy that they still have
public telephones in 2017.
It's pretty coherent
with the rest of Eastern Europe.
Production gives us
rotten notebooks
who are always kidding.
I call
and I join you for the interview.
I'm really looking forward.
I will settle down ...
while you are calling.
an author
and Anglo-American actor
His mother settled
in England in 2006
"In September 2017,
Turner publishes a memoir
"containing all his correspondence
with Donovan.
"Donovan died of an overdose."
Donovan and Turner
have never met.
OF HIS TIME TODAY,
TIMELY TOMORROW
LETTERS TO A YOUNG ACTOR
Text selection
by Jonathan Francis Donovan
IN MEMORY OF MY MOTHER
Please, take your time.
We do not feed you, in the  Times?
Simple curiosity, of course.
There is no arrogance.
The arrogant actor rushes
in the Art Nouveau café,
disheveled, sporting
an old army jacket.
I feel it well.
I had forgotten
that we could smoke here.
It will be forbidden
in a few months, alas.
Did you like the book?
As you know,
I did not read it.
I was not supposed
do this interview.
But since we are here,
let's start, I have a plane to take.
Yesterday afternoon,
when I was told it would be you,
I read some of your articles.
Yesterday afternoon ?
You are versatile
for a political journalist.
You have co-authored an article
on the ecological apocalypse.
On what, already? The West Coast...
- The fault of Juan de Fuca.
- That's it.
An earthquake of 9.2
will devastate the West Coast.
And is it planned for when, already?
We are 50 years behind.
It could be 20 years from now,
and we will not have
started the interview.
Do not save?
Please ?
I would like a very big american.
Do you take something?
A double espresso, please.
A double espresso deca
for this triple idiot.
Thank you.
She spoke in foreign languages
and he was in his power.
I was afraid you were not talking
from you in the third person.
Now,
I would like us to start,
and I may have my plane.
If you miss it,
this device will take you to London.
You want
do I write this article?
Yes ? Well.
We all remember the scandal,
how the letters
have been made public, etc.
Can you go back to the beginning,
when it all started
with John F. Donovan?
In fact, we know it.
He answered one of your letters.
And an unlikely match
followed.
This is the fairy tale version.
We could come back ...
At the end of the fairy tale?
If you want.
It was in 2006.
The summer of my 11 years.
I still smell
of the felt pen he used.
I can still hear the pen
scratch the paper.
Our letters were handwritten,
no computer, no mails.
For John, everything collapsed
when he started to take off.
Everybody
noticed the new kid
and said he was going to box.
But for us,
who had followed it since the beginning,
it was evident
that he was already carding.
Really.
MY LIFE WITH JOHN F. DONOVAN
No, send me
a recap from our discussion.
You've been great.
We will choose the photos?
You really believe in Santa Claus.
What do you mean ?
You're at  Vanity Fair.
You say that you love
and you stop pissing off.
- Rhonda!
- Yes my darling.
Great, haystacks.
Thanks beauty.
- I have oil everywhere.
- Believe me, it's seller.
The minor bottom look a bit slutty,
it works in the Midwest.
Prada delivered the costume,
and Mel took it home.
Miuccia tells you "shit",
and she gabbled in Italian,
I did not understand anything.
John! The end of the season
was too stylish.
Hidden cameras, and everything.
Very good.
It's nice.
Are you going to play Jack Harvest?
It's my favorite superhero!
I cross my fingers, it's not sure.
I love you !
That's all for today.
I see Chris next week.
He knows George wants you
to play Jack Harvest.
It looks good, sweetie.
It's not just for me.
Larry would have loved you to come.
- You owe him that.
- I was not here.
I love Larry,
but I can not clone myself.
All the better, otherwise you would always have
your cock in your mouth.
Thank you for this picture.
Like you never thought about it.
It's the first
of the season of  Hellsome High.
I really have a huge chance.
Rupert!
Rupert?
- Rupert!
- Sorry.
I can not wait to read what you wrote down.
I'm sure
that it will be very complete.
He was on the gay planet!
Cedric, this obsession
for sexuality
of your comrade
really worries me.
Do not risk.
You will name three enumerations
and four figures of style
in the list
I gave you Tuesday.
Please,
I would like to remind you
you need to prepare
your presentations for Monday.
Do not forget to choose an object
who has an emotional value
in real life.
Do not tell me
your weekend at Hogwarts.
School has always
been a refuge for me.
In college, I discovered
the ordinary malice of the guys.
Finally, boys.
To survive in the jungle,
you had to become an animal.
But I preferred to live in my head
and in front of the TV.
Another little white guy
who survives the harassment.
Obviously!
No, for years,
I was only interested in John
and the series
in which he was playing,
my world revolved around that,
at the time.
Have you ever confided
this obsession to someone?
What kind of interlocutor
you speak ?
I do not know, a professional.
I have not seen...
What is the name of the series?
In short ... continue.
What's your name already?
- Sorry ?
- I forgot your name.
Audrey Newhouse.
Yes sorry.
It's not a common name, Audrey.
You seem to think
I'm talking about an icon
or a very respectable work,
or to promote
a cultural event.
But I thought
we were going to talk about influence,
identity and TV.
If you are looking for
artificial ideas
and stupid quotes
to make fun of me,
you will be disappointed.
It does not talk about the job,
it does not speak of art.
It's about a man
who saved the life of a child.
I do not care
that John did not have talent.
he made shit.
I do not care that his story,
today,
you seem appalling.
I know
that I do not rebuild Aleppo.
We are in the same camp.
And this coffee is a deca, Audrey.
Well, we move on.
My treasure,
I could not see you anymore.
I had to understand.
Mom, I'm 17 years old.
Rather 30.
I missed what?
I do not want to miss anything else.
Your shoes.
The mother knows.
She saw him use
her secret powers, she filmed it.
You could say hello.
What? Hello.
Ms. White knows?
Of course, hidden cameras
at the end of the season!
I can not believe !
Did you see what he did?
He shows his powers!
Look! Look at the keys!
The special effects are too good.
You received a package.
It must be a poster,
she is on your bed.
Okay.
Treasury
what are you?
You were right, mom.
I'm different.
The opening credits arrive.
That's it.
I can not believe !
It's a new power!
It's downright crazy!
Rupert, not so strong.
We have neighbors.
I do not believe it, I do not believe it.
The cow !
I'm so happy.
Mom, are you looking?
Wait, it's  Hellsome High!
I was born to see that.
I came out of you for that!
Less strong.
My father was gone
when I was 2 years old
and since,
I lived alone with my mother.
Our departure from the United States
had precipitated
an impetuous maturity.
My mother and I were barely talking.
But since our arrival here,
I did not go out of my room anymore.
In college, they made fun of me
because I was the new,
and besides, I was an actor.
But from my point of view,
all my dreams had vanished.
The only one who survived was ...
John.
It's hard, of course,
he does not have the accent
or the character of an Englishman.
So we're looking for roles
American living here,
or characters a little apart.
I would not tell you it helps him
to digest his arrival here.
But he will adapt.
I gave up a lot of things
leaving for England,
but the letters followed.
The night I saw the pilot
of the series in which he was playing,
I wrote a letter to John.
And to my surprise, he ...
-  He replied.
-  Yes.
And what was originally
that a single exchange
continued for years.
Until his death, actually.
"The style,
it's about who we are. "
Wait a minute.
And your mother did not know?
How could this
to go unnoticed?
She has never seen any
of these letters in the mail?
A lot of things have escaped
to my mother's attention at the time.
She was overwhelmed,
she was never home.
I took care of the mail,
anyway.
You intercepted them.
Yes.
Why? You were not proud?
I was, but more,
I was scared.
Afraid that this so special thing
be removed.
It was my only link
with the life I dreamed about.
So, I protected him.
Until the day I leave
this place to become an actor.
Work with John.
I knew there was
somewhere a world
where John lived his life.
Very, very far from mine.
Amy and John had grown up together.
They had always been friends.
Amy was going to New York to realize
her dream of being an actress,
and he followed it.
It surprised them that we believe them
together forever,
but they were playing the game.
And things got chained.
For John, especially.
He often mentioned loneliness.
I knew there were relationships
that he could not afford.
How's that, relationships
that he could not
to afford?
When you have a life like hers,
everything and everyone
is a risk.
The attention we so much wanted
becomes ubiquitous
and we want to run away.
John often slept in the hotel.
In one of the first letters,
I asked him why.
He said he felt less lonely.
What's weird,
the hotel being synonymous with loneliness.
He said that the feeling of loneliness
was relativized by the fact
that people from neighboring rooms
were often alone too.
It's pretty big for New York.
You know, it's modest,
it's pretty crappy,
but it's at home
since a while.
It's not too expensive either.
When Amy and I
have moved into town,
we lived in Queens,
near Flushing.
A real rat hole.
We could not afford
electricity the first months,
so we had to light the housing
with candles.
- Shit !
- Yes.
One of the neighbors was complaining
that he smelled smoke.
When the firefighters arrived,
they had to think
that virgins were sacrificed.
The virgins
have never interested us.
Do you work tomorrow?
Are you shooting?
I do not work right now.
I must be on the set
from  Hellsome  at 7:00.
A crazy day full of waterfalls.
Yes Yes.
I'm taking another beer
and I'm leaving.
I have to start studying,
anyway...
I auditioned for  Hellsome ...
I can not.
You can not ?
I have to get up early tomorrow.
Yes, you should rest,
anyway.
7:00 am, it's early.
Yes sorry.
It's good, I'm leaving.
Thank you for the beer.
You know all that
thanks to the letters?
Not everything.
John never wrote anything
that I can not understand.
He did not talk much about his private life.
Neither to me nor to others.
If certain rules were broken,
he said it would destroy him.
Mom, are you getting up or going to bed?
Faith comes Friday,
if you can free yourself,
and I make my boeuf bourguignon
that you love.
I do not love it
The 2.
I do not hate ...
Since when you do not love
the beef bourguignon, Jonathan?
Since
that you do not listen to people anymore.
And please,
do not call me Jonathan.
I'll do something else for you.
- The beef, it'll be fine.
-  Do not you like "Jonathan"?
It does not matter,
I can do something else.
I will eat beef.
Come on, tell us. Stop your bullshit.
You did not do 140 km in the middle of the night
to spend some time with me.
His name is Will.
- Oh I see.
- Will Jefford Jr.
I knew him this summer.
We saw each other two or three times.
Okay.
I do not know ... I like him.
He is cute.
What?
I should have said horny?
He is horny.
A guy so horny, it's rare.
Shut your mouth.
What is the plan?
There is no plan.
How many times will you show me
photos with your dreamy smile?
- I do not have a dreamy smile.
- If you do this...
And Amy?
She is used to.
And she continues to play the game?
Yes me too.
We're used to it, James.
- It's okay.
- Okay.
You still have not understood.
- No !
- Get out.
Jimmy! Kind of little junk.
Emerges. You know how it ends.
Are you stupid, or what?
Will Jefford Jr.
This guy will die
at least 4 minutes after me.
Shut up.
Did you see the seconds he wins
by contracting the words?
It's bluffing. It impresses you?
- He is intelligent.
- It is true ?
I give it back to you, my prince.
Or rather ... "I give it back",
since we contract.
John was going to see Jimmy at his garage
for their ritual for years.
It's Jimmy who told me.
I think it was one of the only things
that made John happy.
Hi ! It's okay ?
Even though we never wrote,
John and I had reached
a point of no return in our lives.
Invite Will to his world
was an unconscious way
to sabotage almost everything
what he had built.
Of course, he did not know it yet.
And you?
-  How?
-  And you?
You say that John and you
had each one
reaches a point of no return.
I would like to know what it is
when you are 10 years old.
It can be a lot of things.
But that's not the important thing.
So, what's the point?
I beg you, Mr. Turner?
What's important is that we say
to the children that they and their dreams
do not exist or do not count,
because they are young.
And most children
will believe the one who tells them that.
I was told over and over again.
But I decided not to believe it.
Hello Little Girl.
Rupert! What are you doing here ?
Mom is late.
You got hurt ?
I fell.
I see.
"You can only board
without your parents, young man!
"Another ship leaves for America
in three days."
What cruelty!
But I love !
Here.
You play well.
Stop, I'm bad.
Keep on going.
"I know you do not leave anyone
board without a ticket. "
"Indeed, nobody!"
Sorry, it's gone.
It is not serious.
It's a friendship necklace?
I had one.
No, surely not. My mother has the same.
I have the initial of his name,
and she has mine.
How beautiful it is !
Yes.
The party is over.
Where were you ?
I was dead with anxiety.
You were late,
Mrs. Kureishi brought me back.
No problem, I stayed
to correct copies.
Thank you, Mrs. Kureishi.
- You got hurt ?
- I fell.
Enter. I'm coming very soon.
My turn
to scold me, Rupert!
Not at all.
It did not bother me,
I live nearby.
I have Rupert in English class,
the afternoon...
I know who you are, Mrs. Kureishi.
thank you so much
to be busy with Rupert.
I want to know, Rupert.
Who did you do that?
And stop looking up.
- You do not know what happened.
- I am not blind.
What will it change?
Well, it's simple,
if you tell me the names of the kids,
I call their parents.
Mom, it's pathetic!
You disembark.
I am small,
I am new, I am an actor.
A tall, who has three girlfriends
and who plays in the football team,
Hurt on me.
I admire originality.
And Ms. Kureishi says
that scorn is the supreme weapon.
She should write a book.
She likes what she does
and she is a very reliable adult.
If I'm not cool enough
to help you,
make do, okay?
When we have fears,
we must confront them.
Alan Parrish's father said that
and Alan was sucked
by the game Jumanji.
It will be your turn soon.
It is you who say
that you have to face your fears?
You are the first to run away.
You fled dad
and your acting profession.
And the thing you put me
on the lips tastes piss!
Dirty kid!
That's it! You became a representative?
- I laugh.
- We are late.
What a good surprise !
I did not expect it.
Faith, come!
We had something planned,
but it was canceled.
Mom, not in the neck.
I can not hold back,
you feel so good.
I love Swiss Army!
Amy, it's been an eternity!
I changed perfume.
No ! Since when ?
Since puberty.
Stop and kiss me.
I already kissed you.
I know, but I still want some.
Come here, you.
You feel good too.
You smell good.
What is your perfume tonight?
The Air of Time.
You bought me on Canal Street?
They sell turned perfumes.
We do not care, no one feels it.
My favorite aunt.
- Shit !
- Here, ghosts!
Adam White?
Do not put a spell on me!
Watch out,
he does not like being kissed,
or touch it.
Nice to see you, Anne.
Me too darling.
- You smell good !
- Thank you.
Amy, what a beautiful coat!
On the road to success!
You said they were not coming.
I bet he did it on purpose,
to get noticed.
Who has ever seen it arrive on time?
This is the story of his life,
and that of his father.
I will open the wine.
Let's go.
Fee, fi, fo, fum,
I smell the blood
a beef bourguignon!
By popular demand,
Ina Garten's recipe
beef bourguignon
revisited by Grace.
John does not eat it,
it's not smart enough for him anymore.
But the others, serve you,
I bring the gratin
potatoes.
And I warm you up a little thing.
I told you to do nothing special.
Do not worry, it's nothing at all.
Just spaghetti bolognese,
with broccoli
and bacon.
I made you
when you played hockey.
Faith? You can tell me
if you have to add salt?
I never get dirty enough
I passed the stadium
from your college the other day.
And I was asking myself...
You still think of hockey,
you have regrets?
Excellent question. Let's examine it.
You regret
to become rich and famous?
I imagine so, yes.
Yes, while you could
have a head trauma.
Pat, we've told you a hundred times,
he hurt himself.
You were a great player.
You have a nature of sportsman.
I did not say anything, mom.
Faith?
You need salt.
- Just a little bit.
- I was sure of it.
Still need some wine?
It's okay ? No, I'll go get some.
So, the big news?
You will make me miss my sauce.
It's not official ...
He will play Jack Harvest.
Jimmy, shit.
Who's interested?
The whole earth.
It brings bad luck to say it.
No, damn,
Assure you like a beast!
Jack Harvest, who is it?
I bet
that he is a famous democrat,
they make a documentary
on his life.
It's a comic character,
a kind of superhero.
I see.
It's amazing !
These films work well
right now, no?
But it will not last, if?
And it's going well?
Nothing's happening.
I do not have the role yet.
- The director adores you.
- He chose me.
The studio will surely agree.
- We wait...
- The whole earth, serious.
They will negotiate.
Nothing is done.
You will have it,
it's folded, it's good.
I missed the sauce,
it's too liquid.
But it is good.
Don did not know
that Sissy's lover
was hidden in the closet.
He returns early, inflated to the block,
to the idea of ​​going skiing.
He opens the closet door
to take his things
and go skiing.
Sissy still remembers
of the head he made.
And his boyfriend
left in slalom.
The cow !
It reminds me
when you got your husband bastard
in the cabin with this girl.
I never trusted him,
but then I thought
that I was really right.
That's crazy.
I'm going to drink a little water.
Good idea.
Mom, if you let go of Jimmy
and that you helped Aunt Faith
to bring water?
Jonathan, do not take me high.
I do not take you high, Grace.
Yes.
Who wants water?
Some water ? Do you believe in church?
Anne, a glass of water?
Yes thanks.
You may be the only one
to want to drink.
I think we've been drinking enough.
We are adults.
OK so...
everyone wants whiskey,
except Anne and John.
No. And Amy.
No.
It's better that you do not drink,
with your treatment.
Malin.
We will stop there.
Why ?
There is whiskey, Jimmy.
Thank you for the support, Patrick.
I fuck you!
I have an idea !
Why do not you stay sleepy?
I have cinnamon rolls
at the freezer for tomorrow.
I think we'll go there.
It's a hotel evening?
You know, Pat,
John loves going to the hotel,
sometimes.
You do not come
to buy an apartment
to a billion dollars?
If, but you know, sometimes,
he needs tranquility.
To do what ?
Attention, Amy.
Like father, like son.
That's enough, mom.
Grace, I'll go there.
Can you pay attention to people?
To your sister, to Jimmy,
to me.
At all but this shitty whiskey!
I am not a kid!
I spend my life
to give you my attention.
Apart from you, everyone
love my beef bourguignon.
Everyone loves my coffee.
So, stop doing your snobbish
and sit down.
You are ridiculing yourself.
Good, gently.
Relax, Brad Pitt.
Shut your mouth !
It's you who will shut your mouth!
Good God,
how do you talk to your elders?
You're not telling me to shut up,
and you do not talk to your mother
on that tone.
After what you did to him.
Stamps, bills,
doctors, psys,
fights at school.
You and your shit hockey,
not to mention your filthy father.
Shut up !
It's not my style
to believe in synchronicity,
to destiny, to horoscopes
or that kind of bullshit.
Oh no?
But that night,
something in the universe ...
has obviously made a difference.
What do you mean exactly?
This kind of synchronicity
is not a coincidence.
I did not know everything about John's life
and I would not have guessed
that our mutual mistakes
coincide
so dramatically.
Damn, this is the keum
of the series that tears!
Oh my God !
A latte coffee?
My heart will explode.
No, I promise you.
Thank you.
You do not recognize me, actually?
It was a long time ago.
Before last summer.
Long before.
I'm from Pleasant Gap.
Near the University Park campus.
You kidding ?
It was your college, right?
You played with the Raging Badgers.
I followed your exploits.
I was reading stuff about you
in the newspapers.
Until you explode.
In fact, it's a bit like you
which made me want to be an actor.
I broke with my boyfriend.
Finally, my ex, now.
It went wrong.
I did not think I would see you again one day.
It's funny.
Yeah, it's funny.
Why did not you tell me?
I do not know, I thought ...
I dunno...
That you had forgotten me
or that you would like
I forgot you.
I dunno.
How are you, mother?
She came to see you play.
She was laughing really good.
It was funny.
She is fine.
And your brother ? Jimmy, right?
Jimmy?
I can not.
I can not continue there.
Listen, Will ...
You're nice, but ...
You're really nice, but ...
I can not.
It's not good, it's going to end badly.
I can not afford it.
You're adorable.
You too.
You're nice, but ...
Thanks for the coffee.
I did not understand his rules,
but now it's clear.
How can we live
constantly in the lie?
You have to escape.
A moment comes when the mask
is cracking, right?
I'm sorry, Mr. Turner ...
I'm coming back from Islamabad.
I will be in Nigeria in eight days.
All this conversation seems to me
very far from my world.
It's hard to bear?
Yes, very hard.
I am...
How to say it nicely?
I have a lot of respect for you,
sincerely,
and I would like so much
to feel sorry for Mr. Donovan.
I find that these are
small problems of the rich.
What are you doing in Prague?
I live here and in London.
No, sorry, I meant ...
Where are you from ?
You're not coming
Congo, the DRC?
I think I read that yesterday.
It's hard to know
who is interviewing who.
I was born in Bukavu.
But we move away from the subject.
No, we stop the pipe.
You think we do not come
of the same planet?
It's wrong.
Why would you fight
for the truth,
and me, what to slab?
I see that you have taken it badly.
You believe that stories
do not travel?
The story of a kid.
You are no longer a kid ...
So, do not treat me
like a child.
Its a story
who tells the intolerance
an industry
so scared of losing an audience
that she considers ignorant and obtuse,
that she keeps him in this state
for decades.
It's about us
What society do we want?
What do we aspire to?
In what way is it abstract or unworthy?
I did not want to annoy you.
No, you risk
your life for the truth,
and we, we play it
with our rich problems.
The idea that being privileged
determines what can be said,
and that you have to have a rotten life
to be able to sympathize,
it's a plague, damn!
Me, I come from there.
Right here.
You and me,
we want to change things,
to have an impact
about people's fears,
ignorance, sectarianism,
sexism, racism,
homophobia, etc.
You thought you had
the monopoly of these fights?
Where were we now?
So...
Go ahead, Rupert. We are all ears.
I started to document myself
about John F. Donovan five years ago.
And I discovered we had
a lot of things in common.
For example,
the fact that we have relationships
complicated with our fathers,
and that we dreamed
to be an actor from childhood.
I wrote him a letter.
I was crazy to think
that he would answer me,
but he did it.
Because you are
both homos.
Cedric, second warning.
He has answered.
And that's the object
which I chose to speak.
For almost six years,
John F. Donovan and I,
we write ourselves
once or twice a month.
He tells me everything
on his shoots, on the 7th art,
and explain to me its complexity.
He tells his previews,
his "press junkets" ...
It's a press conference
with lots of journalists.
How did he know his wife Amy,
his difficulties with his mother,
and what she thinks of her career.
But it was before
that he is really famous.
He never stopped writing.
I'm only 11,
but later, I'll be like him
and we will shoot together.
John, whom I prefer to call "J",
often quotes Gore Vidal,
great author, critic and essayist.
"Style is knowing who we are."
John knows perfectly who he is
and I know who I am.
I'm an actor,
and I am John F. Donovan's friend.
Big bobbins.
That's enough. You leave.
Madam, recognize him,
it's big shit.
It's not dumb, duck.
Stop this profanity!
Kind of little liar.
I have his letters here, con head.
You're just jealous.
Shut up, bitch.
Outside, fast.
In fact, I think she tells you
to fuck you!
Rupert, you stay here.
Cedric, I'll punish you tomorrow.
I will not tolerate
Incivility in my class.
Come on!
We activate.
Rupert, approach. Come.
You know, I'll put you
a bad grade.
- It was not good?
- Yes, excellent.
It would have been perfect
for your September writing.
You have a real talent for writing.
But I was very clear
as to the criteria of the exercise.
- A true story.
- John is real.
Yes, you're right.
But you invented this story.
Not at all.
You know that I appreciate your creativity.
Mrs. Kureishi, that's right!
- Rupert.
- I swear !
I have the letters,
but it sounded
and I could not show them.
I can see them ?
So ?
Shit.
Too good, the letters!
Thank you so much.
Magnificent !
Dad, are you listening to me, or not?
A moment.
Dad !
Jesus, Mary, Joseph!
Who are you ?
Hi, Phil!
How is it going ?
Have you had a good weekend?
- Yeah!
- Yeah?
Gil, how are you?
Happy to see you.
I think we're done.
Okay, perfect.
I do not know what's going on.
They would have met
in a bar.
It's been months
that they are together.
What?
- It's been a long time.
- My God !
You met him! It's blond
who came on the set.
It seems
that there is an article online.
- Ah yes ?
- Yes, I have not read it yet ...
That's it, Johnny.
"I am happy.
It's really a great role. "
You do not have the right
to read the letters.
Do not worry, buddy.
We will respect your privacy.
And my fundamental rights. Thank you.
Do you want us to pack them?
Sorry sir...
My son was arrested?
Liz, can I talk to you for a second?
I go to the canteen.
Yes, the thing is that ...
Me too, I need a coffee. Come.
What's going on there?
What?
It must be spam.
Besides, you were not
with Will Jefford Jr, this weekend.
Yes ?
You managed to disappoint me so much
in one evening
that it forces admiration,
Rupert Turner.
I am bluffing.
You lie to your teachers.
You make me leave my job
to come to the police station
after you have been arrested
in the act of breaking and entering.
How are you, Rupert?
Sorry mom.
No, it's too easy.
I want an explanation
right now.
I have a correspondence
with John F. Donovan.
The actor of the series?
Yes, I have been writing to him for five years.
He answered the first letter,
the one we wrote together.
- He has answered ?
- Yes.
You never told me!
What was he writing to you?
Nothing, stuff about movies,
his family and his friends.
His game.
- How many letters?
- A lot.
That is to say ? 5, 10, 20, how much?
About a hundred.
What? Damn, it's not true!
What's the matter with you ?
Do you hate me so much?
Why you lied to me ?
- I never lied.
- Stopped.
You're a liar, like your father.
I said nothing, that's all.
Sorry for my lack
vocabulary.
You have been lying for years.
I refuse to be treated
as a stranger, I am your mother.
You're sure ?
You never asked me anything.
You never ask me anything
on my game or my auditions.
Stop your bullshit, that's shame.
It's the shame we left
America to come here.
Why ? For who ?
Dad does not even have time
to see me.
So, what's the point
to be in England?
Other than lying to yourself
on your new super life
that you impose me far from my friends,
of my life, and of my college.
Because you noticed
that you had missed everything.
So, no,
I never talked about letters
because you would surely have freaked
and you would have forbidden me
to write to the only person
who seems to be interested in me
in this rotten life
from a banality to crying,
and that I can not wait to leave.
Far from you, far from this apartment,
far from your little dreams
and your mediocrity.
You can say goodbye
at your audition in London.
What a surprise!
I must miss everything, like you.
Rupert, shut up!
It is surely Scotland Yard.
Since when did your son
written to John F. Donovan?
He writes often? What is he writing?
Shit !
Tom, it's happening
a very weird story in Harrow.
How a TV star
and an 11 year old
are involved in an incident
forcing the police to intervene?
Can you enlighten us?
Are you sure of the age, Mike?
11 years is bullshit.
Go ahead, Rhys.
It was Richard who wrote it.
The cow ! It's bothering me a corner.
I'm 18, I have needs,
I need you.
I have visions all the time.
The ones you had
when I healed you?
Sarah ... That's normal.
When I saved you,
our souls have bonded,
I do not know why...
Shit !
What?
You had a busy weekend, Johnny!
Are you all right, huh?
Yeah.
- Billy!
- What's up mate ?
We repeat.
Sorry, Miss Jones.
This guy is really a jerk.
Adam. And Diego?
He asks questions.
He is aware.
We'll send Bella to visit her dreams
and erase his memory.
Whore ! Will not it stop?
Are we going to see the doctor on the set?
Let's go to the hosto, it will be discreet.
You wrote these letters?
- Speak louder.
- Sorry.
What's this,
this story of letters?
Which letters?
Do you write letters to a kid?
It's cute...
Repeat, we have time.
They make the settings.
You have 20 minutes ...
Thank you.
What did he say ? I did not hear anything.
Entertainment Weekly
People Magazine
From Barbara: "No nonsense.
I'm waiting for you outside. "
Do you read me Barbara's text message?
I hurt my eyes too much.
Strong, but not too strong.
"Letters to a child
and risky sex
"lift the veil
on the big secret of JFD. "
We should repeat.
"The case was revealed after a
brawl of college kids has degenerated
"in Harrow, near London,
in England.
"Rupert Turner, 11,
got into a house
"to resume letters
that a comrade would have stolen him.
"Letters that have been written
by John F. Donovan.
"This happens shortly after the announcement
"of his involvement in a case
male prostitutes,
"with actor Will Jefford Jr.
"No link with the letters ..."
Do you have stamps?
- What?
- Stamps.
Clonazepam, xanax.
You do not have...
lithium, by chance?
- What?
- Stamps.
I need stamps, damn it.
Do you have any?
I only have natural stuff.
Shit.
Do you want Rescue?
Out of 10, what do you rate me?
Tell me.
These morons say
that you will not put me more than 5.
Billy, you're really painful here.
Say, what is it?
that bullshit with the English kid?
Are you writing to a kid? Wow!
Busy weekend, huh?
It's okay ?
You're not cheating, Johnny!
It's bothering me a corner.
You want to know what I did
this weekend, asshole?
You think
I want to tell you?
Damn, you do not touch me!
Oh my God !
Johnny, I'm sorry.
Damn, do you call me Johnny?
What do you think I'm fucking?
Whore, who are you?
Come on, Brian.
Johnny is farting a cable. Shut up.
I thought we were friends.
No, we are not friends!
We are not friends, damn!
I come here, I say my text,
but you do not know who I am.
You know neither my life nor my past,
neither my secrets, damn!
And I have to tell you my weekend
because if not,
you'll go tell
that I am a pretentious asshole.
"He's like us, that asshole,
he shits every morning! "
That's right, Billy.
Obviously he's shitting.
And he is so grateful,
so nice,
and most of all, he is so happy
that he will tell you everything
on his fucking weekend!
Shit !
Then?
The word "correspondent", I believe.
- This one is my favorite.
- He's good.
It's so good that I want
hear the question.
So, do you have a correspondent?
A child, moreover.
Do your job.
You Correspond
with a child in England?
And why not?
Why not England?
He speaks English, too.
We are made for each other.
Continue!
Exchange your letters
with a child actor,
in England?
Is it written
for years?
It was in the article I read,
I read them all.
You have interest!
Yes, how else
I would know what I'm doing?
And I'm doing some stuff!
It's terrible.
Yes, it was not great.
And then, he wrote
to apologize, or explain?
Yes of course.
But he ignored me,
it was not the most painful.
I understood
he had no choice.
Even if it was painful.
But the consequences,
with the boys and my teacher,
were going to be horrible.
Are you going to miss your plane?
We can finish by mail
if you prefer.
No, do not worry. It's okay.
How much do I owe you
for that smile?
- I piss you off.
- Call an ambulance.
Sorry, excuse me.
Is there a doctor on the plane?
This behavior is unusual,
maybe a stroke start.
Audrey, does it smell like burnt?
It's okay ?
- Go to work.
- At work.
What happened next ?
You go to the retirement home,
today.
And I read in your agenda
that you have to wear the uniform.
So, I'll help you.
It's gonna be fun.
Nice and healthy.
You will do a good action
and it will change you a little
of all this madness.
Your feet.
He said he had not
write the letters.
They will smash me.
Everyone will make fun of me.
I want to stay here with you.
Please do not do this to me.
Do not let me down.
You will never write to this man again.
It's understood ?
Whether true or not ...
It is true.
Do you see what he's doing to you?
He let you go without hesitation
and he will do it again if necessary.
It always happens like that
in this place.
I know you love this job.
But we have to go back down to earth.
Think about your notes.
You can have a girlfriend,
or a friend.
You must forget all that.
Today's hearing
could change everything.
For once,
it was an American movie.
You will audition
at the end of the year, this summer.
If you disappear a moment,
you never come back.
Like you.
It is true.
It would be great
if you did not remind me all the time.
I know you think
that I have no ambition,
and that I am not strong.
You're happy ?
But if a kid
mocks you or hurts you,
or if an adult ridicules you,
me,
I will be the rabat-joy
service, tiny,
who will come to protect you, okay?
I was never afraid to miss
my career or losing your father.
But I will always be afraid
to hurt you.
Not today, not tomorrow,
surely not before very long,
but one day,
you will understand.
Hi, Olga. Hello, Catherine.
Timothy, Rodrigue, Kamal.
Celeste, pretty dress.
Cedric, giant shark.
Is someone missing?
Where is Rupert?
Rupert Donovan is gone!
Cedric! First warning.
No !
Sarah!
It's not true...
What is going on ?
No. Everything is fine.
I can enter ?
Okay, why not?
Rupert dropped it in college,
this morning.
What?
"Ms. Kureishi, do not worry,
I am in London for an audition. "
I forbade him
to go to this audition.
Ms. Turner,
I am certain
that you defended him ...
I'm fine, I'm not stupid, okay?
It'll be okay, will not it?
He has a cell phone?
- Call him.
- He wanted one.
But it's a little boy.
On the other hand, he knows London.
He goes to see his father
every month, all alone.
Finally, he went there often.
I have a lecture
in Bracknell this afternoon,
I will call his father,
he will put him back on the train
for Harrow.
Good.
Thank you, Mrs. Kureishi.
You're welcome.
I'll go.
- Mrs. Turner?
- Yes ?
Yes ?
I'm looking at Rupert,
and he has such a bright future
who is waiting for him.
You see...
This is not the case
of the majority of my students.
Let's say I see a future
for them,
but I rarely see
a destiny.
This is why,
I believe, that I came,
instead of phoning.
I know my son is different.
I am not blind.
Rupert must be so ashamed
of me.
He must tell
lots of stuff on me,
fuck me
with all his friends.
Rupert is a very lonely child.
He does not trust so much.
Before, he confided.
I went through their written homework,
the other night,
and I saw that you did not have
signed his writing,
the one on the models.
Rupert exchanged letters
with a guy of 30 years
for five years without anyone knowing
I understand that he did not hold
to have me read his writing.
I do not see why.
Have a good day.
Choosing your mother or father
as a model
no doubt lacks originality.
But the person
whom I know and admire most,
it's my mother, Sam Turner.
In recent years,
we moved away from each other,
but you'll tell me, it's life.
Sam was pregnant with me,
my father left her
for another shortly after
and moved to England.
So she raised me alone.
And for a moment,
it worked well.
My son Rupert
had an appointment at 13:30.
I took care of her
and I even called it "my love",
it made me feel
to be an adult.
But in truth,
it was only
my best friend.
She called me Larry
instead of Rupert,
and we watched movies together.
I think we saw  The Secret Garden
a billion times.
She stopped the theater
and I started to audition.
I thought she would be proud
that I do one thing
to which she had sucked.
Over the years, Sam was disappointed
to see his dreams vanish,
and we got here
in search of other dreams.
Sorry, my son is here ...
It's hard for me,
but I understand why
she wanted to be someone else.
It's only hard to admit it.
I know that I have instituted
this distance between us.
Sometimes I would like
that our problems
and the invisible wall between us
disappear.
Let's meet each other,
without having to worry about anything,
without pride and without lies.
Then I'll tell him the truth.
I'll tell him how much I love him.
Mum !
- Sorry !
- Sorry.
- I'm dumb !
- Are not you angry?
- I'm dumb.
- No, you're not stupid.
Your teacher has come,
I knew I was wrong.
Afterwards, I read your writing.
It is true ?
I did not want to hurt you
and I'm sorry
that you find me limited.
You're not limited. Sorry.
We will do it.
You, my Rupy, you'll be an actor.
I will be there
to support you, okay?
I guess you expected, right?
Barbara, it's a joke.
We have lived so many things together.
I need you and ...
Say it.
I need you ?
I need someone.
I carefully avoid needing
people for 40 years.
John, my big,
look around you.
Look at the paintings on the walls,
the carpet.
The chair in which you are sitting.
I chose this life.
She could have been different,
completely different.
I could have had everything.
If you knew how many times
I refused to work
with extraordinary actors,
artists.
I could have joined
to prestigious agencies.
I have no doubt about it.
I'm not done.
I chose this life.
Not for lack of ambition,
I like money
and everything he brings, I like that.
But I chose this life,
because it's the one I can live,
the one where I'm proud
to do my job well.
I could not handle
Careers of businessmen.
Not for lack of esteem
or respect.
I can meet them, meet them.
But I can not be them.
I am not a liar.
And if you become someone like that,
if you hire models
to be seen in restaurants,
or at charity nights ...
If you become someone
who despises others,
who says to the kids
that they do not exist,
I will not follow you in this way.
It's an impasse, I know it.
I'm not stupid,
I know you can do it,
I am sure.
If that's what you want.
But I will not do that with you.
I saw too many friends
get lost in this spiral,
this black hole of the swagger
which is only
a waste of talent.
And time never catches up.
I'm finished.
I have Eileen O'Neal on line 1.
You will find another agent.
It's better for you.
I will tell everyone
that you fired me.
Give it to me, Melanie.
What if I do not want to change?
Talk to your therapist.
Eileen, how are you?
I know, I wanted to call you.
I am overwhelmed. I'm very good.
Children, how are you?
At Disneyworld?
No, I'm fine
No, that's fine.
Shit, I should have called.
It is not serious.
They came by bus,
I bring them back tomorrow
for my brother's birthday.
It's great.
I can go later.
If they sleep at home,
we can go for a beer.
I need to talk.
With me ?
Yes.
No, you say nothing.
Listen, I believe
that all that ...
John, I love you,
but all that, this whole story,
this stuff pictures,
it's a little ... I do not know.
You're ashamed, right?
No.
But you, yes.
I wish you'd call me.
It was not the moment.
It is not serious.
Connor needs you!
A second, mom.
Sorry, I'm coming.
Do what you have to do.
I am young.
I know what I want
and who am I?
Being the secret lover of someone,
it's not part of my projects.
Okay ?
I'll let you in, but ...
I understand.
I am sorry.
I sent my book to Will,
but I have never heard anything.
John spoke of him with affection
in his letters,
but no one really knows
what it has become.
It seems he's back
and that he does everything except the actor.
Barbara Haggermaker
said in an interview
for an article
on women to be able to
that his great failure
was not to have fired John.
No?
It was not knowing him.
When his illness, his past,
when everything has been revealed,
a lot of people have felt that.
But do we have to know an artist?
What should he reveal about him?
Why is it important to us?
Derek O'Brien takes down
the role of Harvest at Disney.
And John, what has become of him?
He just disappeared.
They sold the apartment.
I think he has taken over
the life he led
not long before.
Hellsome High  shipped Adam White
on a spiritual journey in Africa
in the middle of the sixth season.
I remember this episode.
It was called  The Departure.
It was suitable.
The guy John had assaulted
on the set complained.
There was an amicable agreement
and it stopped there.
He wrote you
during those months of ...
What was it, you know?
These months of isolation,
addiction, depression?
No idea,
he did not write at that time.
I wish I could be there for John.
I lived far away,
and we were not in the same world.
Life has continued.
John had kept this habit
to eat in the kitchen
a restaurant he liked,
and from where he had written to me so often.
He had not cut all the bridges.
After the London episode,
my mother allowed me
to resume the auditions.
A series of happy chances
and an audition
had earned me
to be called back to New York.
Of course, I was delighted,
but mostly because,
as we had planned,
I would see John
for the first time.
In five years of correspondence.
But it's not  Hellsome High?
That's good, right?
Sorry, I know
that this is not your name.
No ... it's a high school.
- My name is...
- John F. Donovan.
I am not so old.
It must annoy you, but ...
my grandson is
one of your big fans.
I was with him
in Canal Street the other day,
he saw the poster of your series,
and he was no longer in place.
He stayed there
for five minutes.
He wants to be like you,
when he will be tall.
Magic powers included, of course.
Oh?
I assure you.
I do not bother you anymore.
No, you do not bother me. Stay.
You're really nice.
You settle there
to be a little quiet
and an old fool arrives
braying.
No, really, it's ...
We are waiting for your next
extraordinary adventure.
I do not know sir.
What?
I do not know anymore.
I feel ... Sorry ...
I have the impression ...
Talk to me.
I have the impression
that I ruined everything.
You understand ?
I keep telling myself ...
What if I did not have anything to do there?
If I had stolen another's place?
Say something.
Make fun of me.
Oh dear !
Who am I to collect
these confessions?
I know.
Sorry, you should leave,
I should not have bothered you.
In my opinion,
things are simple.
People, however,
have a mysterious propensity
to make them complicated.
You already know
that you were wrong,
what distinguishes you
from most people.
Personally, I look at you,
and all that I see,
he is a young man whose
my grandson enjoys the job.
How you chose
to fix your mistakes
is your business and that of God.
But the question is ...
How could you
stealing a place
who was created specifically for you?
Sorry,
but I have never seen you here.
You see me now.
Damn,
I think I should go.
Go home.
You are too young to eat alone
in shabby kitchens.
Mum !
What are you doing here ?
I must say that it's really
the ideal evening.
So, Amy is fine?
It's because
did you meet someone?
Someone else ?
No !
You will not do that to me. Stopped.
- Sorry.
- You're not leaving already!
In the middle of the game You laugh ?
I've got to go. Sorry.
Sorry.
I dunno...
Damn, I'm not good at it.
You know, John,
I read a lot of things about you.
Everyone passes me articles.
I read everything.
I see everything you do,
all emissions,
your job, everything.
I am your career and ...
There is something you said ...
Mom, what did you read?
You said it many times.
You said that ...
You said we ...
we did not come
from the same planet.
I come from this planet.
And you,
you come
of me.
And I know that...
I do not think a mother
is supposed to be the friend of his son,
but I know you.
And I was the first.
So we play cards, okay?
Mum ?
You could make me sink a bath
and ask me to spell words,
like before ?
If you want.
Can I sleep here?
Honey,
you can stay your whole life.
Really funny !
Stopped !
You should try.
Stop jumping on this bed.
You'll break it, you'll break everything,
and you will break a bone.
Who can dry their hair
in this blue light?
Do you want to go back to England?
- Mum ?
- Yes ?
You think John answered
to my letter?
The reception promised to call.
See the positive side, darling.
It's the full moon.
It is surely a sign.
I imagine.
It will be hard to avoid the fumette
between mother and son on my Myspace.
This one looks pretty good.
Prandrial?
What is that thing ? Pre-meal.
It's easy.
P-R-P-P-R-A-N-D-I-A-L.
"That occurs before the meal."
What a nerd!
That's it ?
Sorry. What?
It's written like that, is it good?
Honey, how are you?
I'm fine.
You're sure ?
There are some tips
who will change, that's all.
It's a little scary,
but you know, you only have to ...
you just have to be yourself.
The horrible thing!
Shut up, sweetheart!
Damn, how are you? Connard!
- Attention, boys!
- Get louder.
- Break.
- I love this song.
- Go ahead.
- Serious?
I know.
It's a great song!
I think that ...
My story stops
about here, Audrey.
That's right?
From what Grace Donovan told me,
it's the last time
that she and Jimmy,
and whoever to their knowledge,
have seen John.
In this case, if I can ask
one last question,
how did you know?
Yes ?
Yes, bring it.
Sorry.
If my son sees
the letter now,
it'll make him crazy.
It's from Mr. Donovan?
No, I do not think so, Mrs. Turner.
A young man has filed it
saying only
to hand it over to Rupert Turner.
I'm sorry.
- Sorry.
- Thank you.
Have a good day.
"Dear Rupert,
"I have not slept in a long time,
maybe several months.
"I'll have to find some time
to sleep and think.
"You know, I gave it my all
in my life.
"I took care of my job,
of my career, of my reputation.
"I took care
friends and family.
"And I was so busy
I forgot to work on me.
"By the time the boys
have become men,
"I became famous.
"Rupert
"I wish you to live a life
"full of success
and achievements.
"But above all,
I wish you to live.
"Live before you lie.
"It all boils down to that, fatally.
"Some lies are the most
beautiful interpretations of an artist.
"And some lies are
"of pure beauty.
"But you are too pure
to lie now.
"Because I know your dreams,
"because I know your desires,
"I also know the disappointment,
"the loneliness you will experience
inevitably.
"Rupert
"I can not imagine a young man
more impressive than you.
"I can not dream
of a more considerate confidante,
"a friend more singular.
"I was thinking
"that the greatest achievement
of our friendship,
"is that no one
"will not really understand it
"until you decide
otherwise.
"I'll find a way
to join you, promised .
"Soon, I will go back to life."
John, it's me.
"But for now,
"I have to sleep,
"I want to sleep and start all over again.
"Your friend.
"John."
I will not hide it from you,
after all that,
I am a little curious
to know if...
If he committed suicide?
We will never really know it.
I do not know anything else
than what he wrote to me.
Maybe...
he committed suicide
because he had dipped
in deep despair, etc.
It's a bit easy, right?
Either he really wanted to sleep
and he made a very serious mistake.
In his last letter,
he looks hopeful.
And you will understand
that, for obvious reasons,
this is the version
that I chose to believe.
All right, Rupert.
Thank you.
I'm sorry for this bad start.
Do not worry.
I take care of the bill.
- They come to get me.
- Go for it.
- Good luck.
- I just have a scene.
No, I'm not talking about today.
I want to say...
in your career,
your life.
I hope you will
what you want.
I already have what I want.
All the better.
See you soon.
Adaptation: Isabelle Audinot
Subtitling: ECLAIR