WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
My name is Aja.
I'm 22 years old.
I had to think about that.
And I'm from Brooklyn, New York.
[music playing]
I got my drag name
from a Bollywood movie.
I don't know what
it's called, but it
had that little song
that was like, (SINGING)
Jamie, Jamie, Aja.
And I was like, I like that.
And I absolutely have
no idea what it means.
But I like it.
I'm known for doing things
that other people don't do.
Not in terms of my drag,
but just in terms of I
will call everyone out and
always speak the truth.
That's good.
I went to church.
They always tell you
God don't like liars.
And I will not lie to your face.
So don't ask me if you
look bad because I'll
tell you you look bad.
I'm just a crazy person.
I'm crying now on the inside.
I'm not really competitive
at all, to be honest.
I just really like to have
fun and I'm kind of a joker
and I like to joke with people.
And sometimes, at people.
So I hope nobody gets mad at me.
My drag aesthetic is very
much like slutty, anime girl,
but also kind of ratchet.
She's from Brooklyn so she has
to uphold that hood status.
My look is very
Judy Jetson hooker.
And I'm just very inspired
by Gautier meets Mugler meets
furry monsters, but pastel.
Season 9 is going to
be, I don't even know.
These bitches are crazy.
My name is Alexis Michelle.
I am 33 years old and I was born
and raised in New York City.
When I'm not dressed like
this, my name is Alex Michaels.
So I decided to feminize
my name since Alexis
is really my female half.
Alexis Michelle is known
for her theatricality,
her lip sync talents,
her live vocals,
and being pretty thirsty.
I am a fierce competitor, but
I also know that my biggest
competition is myself.
So I don't need to
tear anybody down.
I can lend you something.
I can help you out.
And still be able to beat
you, like a good girl.
I'm a good girl, I am.
I am all about
body, curve, swerve,
glamour, class, a little
touch of prostitute,
and of course, this mug.
When I decided to go with this
bright vibrant neon yellow,
I said, I want to
feel structure.
I want to feel my shape.
Alexis is known for her
cinched waist and her hips.
So I wanted to really
bring that out,
but elevate it to more
of a high fashion,
almost McQueen-esque place.
I can sit down at that makeup
table and think, oh, god,
here we go again, another face.
And then something happens.
As the shapes start to
come out, as the contours
pop, as the lashes go
on, as I pout my lips.
Something comes over
me and all of a sudden,
Alexis has arrived.
Hi, I'm Charlie Hides.
I'm from Boston and London,
and I'm [coughs] years old.
I'm bicoastal.
I'm a transatlantic dame.
My side hustle is I'm a butt
double for Britney Spears.
How did I get my drag name?
It's the name on my passport.
So inventive.
Creative.
Pushed the boat out on that one.
I'm known for, apparently,
being the oldest
drag race contestant ever.
Why did I audition for the show?
Because I'm so old.
If I don't do it now, by
next year, I could be dead.
I'm so old, my ears are still
ringing from the Big Bang.
What I do to transform
is I take lots of makeup
and I throw it up
into the ceiling fan.
I get under it and
hope for the best.
My drag look?
Eclectic, lots of
different things.
It's high fashion.
I'm a crafty queen.
What inspired my look
today was Julie Newmar
meets Philip Treacy.
An inspiration for me is,
if I wake up in the morning,
I think this is a good day.
Let's make the most of it.
Let's have fun.
Let's look good.
Let's make a few people laugh.
And if I can get paid
for it, all the better.
I want to be known
for the person
that when someone was feeling
bad or had a rough day,
they saw one of my shows and
it made them feel better.
I'm a team player, so
I work with my team.
And when it's my time to shine,
I sparkle, Neely, sparkle.
Season 9 is going to be
the best season ever.
You heard it from me.
Don't quote me, but
I'm pretty sure.
My name is Eureka.
I come from Johnson
City, Tennessee.
I am 25 years old and
I am big, ready to jig,
and ready to win this gig.
I actually got my drag name,
my mother's name is Eureka,
but it's spelt the German form.
She's from Germany and I just
looked at my vacuum cleaner
and was like, Americans,
will be able to spell
that out and sound it out.
So I became Eureka.
Eureka's really known
in her profession
as someone who is high energy,
very smiley, very positive,
but also is a dancing queen.
I like to push the
boundaries and the molds
that the bigger
community has been given.
I like to wear things that
we're not supposed to wear.
I like to have the shape that
we're not supposed to have.
And I like to dance hard
and do things that they
don't expect a big girl to do.
She's just big and loud
and crazy, but fun.
She's going to entertain you on
and off the stage, regardless.
It's who she is.
I'm a perfectionist,
so everything
has to be perfect at all times,
especially aesthetically.
And it can cause me to be a
little introverted at times,
and sometimes a little snippy.
So the bitches better
watch out, because I
might cuss, cut, or eat them.
If I was going to
describe my aesthetic,
I would say the Kool-Aid man
meets Eureka's castle meets
Hobby Lobby meets the Grand
Duchess meets Mary Queen
of Scots meets fabulousness.
Today, I am inspired by
fire and the color red
because it dedicates
my passion and my drive
and the flame that I have
under my ass for a fat girl
to finally win this
[beep] competition.
My name is Farrah Moan.
I'm 23 years old.
Born and raised in Texas
and now living in Las Vegas.
My drag name Farrah comes from
my '70s idol, Farrah Fawcett.
And Moan comes from,
well, me being a whore.
When it comes to competing,
I am not that competitive.
I mostly just make sure
that whatever I'm doing
is true to what I like and
what I want to showcase.
I'm definitely not one
of those girls that
compares myself to
other people or wants
to be better than anyone.
I just want to be the
best me that I can.
My drag aesthetic
is on a spectrum
between fetish and showgirl.
I think I get a lot of
my fetishy inspiration
just from my own
fantasies and desires.
And then my old school
Vegas showgirl feel is just
from being so inspired
by feathers and sparkles
and rhinestones and glamour.
And just that whole iconic,
larger than life silhouette.
My look today is
inspired by old Hollywood
meets retro glam, mixed with
a little bit of the fetishy
aspect of my aesthetic.
Season 9 is going to
be absolutely insane.
Hi, my name is
Jaymes Mansfield.
I'm 26 years old and I'm
from the Antarctic prison
known as Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
[squeals] My drag name
comes from my birth name
being James and the
actress Jayne Mansfield.
I think I'm best known for
my YouTube channel, Jaymes
Mansfield, where I talk
about hair styling,
makeup, and even
drag queen history,
like I'm making right now.
I'm a drag foster child.
I have two drag
mothers, the first one
a legendary pageant
queen of Milwaukee,
Wisconsin, Rudy D'angelo.
And the third one, a legendary
trash queen of West Hollywood,
the Amazing Ruby Claire.
My side hustle is
hairstyling, babysitting,
and selling cookies at
the church bake sale.
I am very competitive.
I don't take things lightly.
I will hurt people.
But I think I'm going
to play nice this time
and give the girls a little
bit before I, you know,
slash their eyes out.
I transfer into Jaymes
Mansfield in one simple way.
I stand still and spin myself
around in a circle like Wonder
Woman and, poof, I'm there.
My entire look is inspired by
small children, big dreams,
and I'd say, my
puppetry and creativity.
I'm walking art.
But not vivacious.
I'm pretty.
My outfit was created by my
wonderful, long suffering
maid, Mr. Jaymes.
He stayed up many
long nights creating
this look last minute for me,
and I appreciate him for it.
My look is inspired
by, well, I wanted
to be big in the shoulders
without having to gain weight.
So, [squeals].
Season 9 is going to be mine.
My name is Kimora Blac.
I'm 28 and I'm from
Sin City, Las Vegas.
I picked Kimora because I
love Kimora Lee Simmons,
but she's irrelevant now.
So obviously, there has
to be someone younger.
And that's me.
But Kimora, no one has it.
It can't be duplicated.
Kimora just sounds hot.
When you hear Kimora, it's
like, damn, who's Kimora?
I am your life size
Barbie, you know?
Like out of the Barbie box.
Like I am your rich, hot,
platinum blonde Barbie.
Super bronzy, like
straight guys love me.
Gay guys love me.
Drag queens love me.
I'm a really hot guy.
Like, I would
totally date myself.
Like, this full blown,
like, beard and, like, hot.
But then, when I
get into Kimora,
it's such a long process
because I am so perfected.
Because I cannot go out of
the house looking like busted.
And some of the queens
are kind of like busted.
So that is like the
top of my list is like,
one, you cannot be busted.
My drag aesthetic is
just sexy and show girl.
I've come from the
city of showgirls.
My look today was actually
really inspired by this fashion
designer Marco Marco.
I love his stuff.
It's not Marco Marco, but
it's just inspired by him.
I had to tint my hair hot pink
because I bleached it too much
and the split ends
were kind of showing.
So I had to kind of
go in so real girls
don't get too jealous of me.
Hey.
Well, I am Nina Bo'Nina Banana
Fofana Osama on season 9 Brown.
And honey, I am
from South Carolina,
but I do reside in
Riverdale, Georgia.
My first drag name
was Beata Bitchass.
And then it was Lady Guinevere,
but people couldn't spell that.
They would call me
Lady Guinea Pig.
I was sleeping one
night and I had a dream.
And somehow, the word
Nina was just in my dream.
I would use that
name, go to the club.
Somebody would say,
come out, Nina Bo'Nina.
And I'm like, OK.
If 2 plus 2 equals 4,
that makes sense to me.
So that was Nina Bo'Nina
and I said Brown.
My aesthetic is
hard to describe.
Like really, I don't know
how to describe myself.
I don't know where I belong.
I don't want to be
in a box, either.
And I feel like
I'm a black queen
who does things that
a lot of black queens
haven't really done.
Even a lot of white queens.
I can give you glam.
I can give you sexy.
I can give you crazy.
I can give you a character.
It's whatever I choose.
I just don't want to be,
like, a one-note queen.
What inspired today's
look was grape Kool-Aid.
No, seriously.
What does-- a video
game, actually.
A video game.
I'm a big video
player, I'm a nerd.
I'm a guy.
So anybody out there who
plays some PlayStation, honey,
bring it on.
And in the game, you
get to make your--
build your own characters.
And there was this badass
purple alien bitch.
And I was like, cheekbones,
lips, eyes, that's me.
Kiddies, tune in because season
9 is going to be surprising
and you are not going to
know what to expect, baby.
So get ready.
My name is
Peppermint and I'm 37
years old from New York City.
I got my drag name because I
was sitting in a parking lot
with this guy I
totally had a crush on.
And I was eating my favorite
candies, which are peppermints.
And he just said,
you know, you should
call yourself Peppermint.
I honestly would have done
anything he said, and so I did.
Peppermint's my name.
It stuck.
I've been doing
drag for so long.
And I have done lots in drag.
I've done lots of shows.
I've done lots of people.
I've done it all.
And I really wanted
something new, something
that challenged myself.
And I think this is the perfect,
perfect place to do that.
My aesthetic is classy,
chic, uptown flair,
very urban, with a little
bit of sex pot thrown in.
Today's look, my
hair is inspired
by RuPaul herself from her
"Ho, Ho, Ho" Christmas album.
I think this is ho
number two, this hair.
And I just wanted to do
something fabulous and flowy.
And I'm giving a little bit
of Endora from "Bewitched."
I want to be known
for the confidence
that I have with
my drag being as
equal to the confidence that
I bring to my everyday life
as a trans woman and win.
The first transgender winner.
That sounds great.
Season 9 is going to be
epic because I'm here.
I'm a legend.
I'm fierce, I'm
fabulous, and I'm ready.
My name is Sasha Velour.
I'm 29 years old and I
live in Brooklyn, New York.
My drag name is my
actual name, Sasha.
That was the name
I was born with.
And my whole life,
I've had people tell me
that it's a girl's name.
So the logical conclusion
is just to become a girl.
Velour is a cheap
imitation fabric.
It's more useful and more
affordable than velvet.
So I think it's the
perfect metaphor for drag.
I'm an intense competitor.
I love to win.
I love to take a
challenge and transform
it to really work for me.
And I'm excited for
this competition.
To transform into my
fabulous drag persona
is about the physical
ritual of painting my face
and costuming my body and
shaving off all the hair
and strapping everything down.
That ritual really
does help me transform
into this fabulous being that's
so much more than just my body.
It's my ideas and
my imagination.
I think that drag is the art
form of the queer imagination.
So it's all about beauty
that goes beyond gender.
It's about experimentation
and remixing
and combining different
elements from different places.
So it's just a hodgepodge of
different fabulous and queer
things that I love.
Today's look is,
like, '60s meets '20s.
It's a bit of
Philip Treacy, it's
a bit of crazy, bald club kid.
And it's my absolute
favorite colors, red and pink
and everything in between.
Season 9 is going
to be revolutionary.
Hi, my name is Shea, Miss
Coulee if you're nasty.
I'm 27 years young and
I'm from the Windy City.
I got Shea because my
middle name is Shea
and in Swahili, it
means beautiful boy.
And I thought that
that was appropriate
and so I picked Coulee
because I wanted to sound
like a French supermodel.
I'm gorgeous, I'm talented,
I can sew, I can dance,
I can act, I can sing.
I can put my legs
behind my head.
I can speak French.
You know, the list
goes on and on.
I'm known for being a
really strong performer.
I'm known for having a very
editorial image online.
I love fashion.
I love clothing.
I love modeling.
And yeah, girl, I'm
just sickening the house
down, boots, Gaga, yes.
My aesthetic is equal
parts bougie and bangi.
I woke up like this.
So I mean, I just
literally rolled out of bed
and then walked my beautiful
little black ass over here
and sat in this chair.
What is drag?
I just wanted to give
you African goddess
realness, Queen Nefertiti.
Yeah, I just wanted to give you
a really good visual of what
a true queen looks like.
Up until this
competition, I always
downplayed myself in order to
make people feel comfortable
and less threatened.
But now that I'm here, frankly,
my dear, I don't give a damn.
So these girls better watch out.
Season 9 is going
to be unforgettable.
Hi, I'm Trinity Taylor.
I'm 31 years old.
I'm originally from
Birmingham, Alabama.
And now, I reside
in Orlando, Florida.
I really liked Trinity
from "The Matrix."
She was a bitch.
She had a strong personality.
She a strong look.
And at the time, I was
like, I want to be her.
And so I would wear jet
black hair with no hair line,
just horrible.
Looked like a brick.
But that's who I thought I was.
Yeah.
I come from pageants,
so I'm very competitive.
I came here to win.
So that's what I'm going to do.
I'm going to claw
my way to the top.
Putting makeup on other people
other than myself for my day
job is kind of boring
because it's all like, nude,
beige, and more nude.
You know, I like this.
I like the glam, the glitter,
rhinestones, big lashes.
They don't let you do that.
My aesthetic is fierce.
I love fashion.
I love body.
I love beauty.
I love hair.
I love makeup.
I love to be a transformation.
I was inspired for this look,
just this is my favorite color.
I love blues.
I love teals and turquoise.
And I was thinking, I want to
be a ferocious futuristic bitch.
I want to be known for the fact
that I'm very well-rounded.
That I can sew, that I
can do my makeup and hair,
and still be nice
to these other girls
and help them out
and still slay them.
Because I'm that good.
Hello, my name is Valentina.
I live in Los
Angeles, California,
and I'm a little girl.
My drag name came about
it, it just like, snapped.
It came to me.
It sounded like a character
out of a Pedro Almodovar film.
It sounded like the
protagonist from a telenovela.
There's actually a
salsa called Valentina.
And also, I love Valentino
and the color Valentino red.
So I felt like Valentina
was the perfect name.
I'm glamorous, I'm Latina, I'm
tall, I'm skinny, and luxury.
I love luxury.
And I'm a perfectionist and
I strive for perfection.
It's something
that's impossible,
but why not shoot for the stars?
Getting into drag,
I have a ritual.
Getting in drag, the process,
it's my favorite part.
So I turn on my candles,
I put on my music.
I sip on a glass of
wine and I just paint.
And I enjoy it.
And I take a really
long time getting ready.
I love to luxuriate
in the moment
and really get excited
when it comes time to put
my blush or my lip gloss.
And now lashes.
And girl, put those
contacts on and, boom,
the transformation is ready.
I love to get ready.
It's my favorite part of drag.
Today's look is
referencing Prada's
last season, the spring/summer.
I wanted to do a neoprene
and I wanted the color to be
mint and a [inaudible] coat.
I'm really going for, like,
this fantasy of just kind
of doing a modern take on '60s
glamour with the spiky lashes
and the teased hair.
Get into it.
Season 9 is going to be drama.