WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Previously
on RuPaul's Drag Race...
- You'll be acting
in 9021-Ho.
[cheering]
- Grandrea Zuckerwoman
will be played by Aja.
- I don't want
to be Grandrea.
- If it's going to be that
tense, I'll take Grandrea.
-Action.
- No wonder
I'm addicted to speed.
- I'm addicted
to speed, too.
-No, you're not.
- We're all going
to the same college.
We're gonna work
together again.
- Nina Bo'nina Brown
Carrington Colby.
- You weren't really
selling the lines.
- Where are the cool people?
-Aja.
-You were playing the bitch,
and it felt kind of flat
for me.
You basically handed Shea
a moment to shine.
- Trinity Taylor,
you're the winner
of this week's challenge.
Nina Bo'nina Brown,
shantay, you stay.
Aja, sashay away.
- Oh, that was
a rough, rough one, honey.
-Whoo.
-Oh.
- I feel heartbroken.
Aja was my Brooklyn boo,
and I'm really, really
gonna miss her.
- "Love you guys.
XOXO, Aja."
-Aw.
- Anybody got any Windex?
- [laughs]
The truth is, I'm thrilled
to see the room thinning out
because I know I'm the contender
in this competition.
- Aren't y'all two
neck and neck now?
- Well, I have two wins
and she has a win
and then a partnered win.
-Ooh!
- But also, weren't you
in the bottom two?
And I never even landed
in the bottom three, bitch.
What's up?
- Oh.
-Ouch.
-Oh!
[all laugh]
- I'm kind of jealous.
I want to win, too.
'Cause we're
at the point now
where if you haven't won
at least one challenge, then...
why are you here?
- Well, how do you feel being
told that you're perfect?
Again.
- They told you
you're perfect?
- One day, she'll run out
of perfection.
- Yeah, we'd all like
to be in the top,
but the cookie doesn't
always crumble that way.
- Thank you,
JonBenet Ramsey.
[all laugh]
- At this point,
there's only two girls who
have not won any challenges yet,
Peppermint and Farrah.
That ain't a good thing.
- Hey, Farrah, thanks for
looking like a drag queen today.
[all laugh]
- Peppermint's
for sure in trouble,
and Farrah's days
are for sure numbered.
Bye-bye,
do not collect $200,
no cab ride for you.
- Oh...
- The winner
of RuPaul's Drag Race
receives a one-year supply
of Anastasia Beverly Hills
cosmetics
and a cash prize
of $100,000.
With extra special
guest judges
Fortune Feimster
and Tamar Braxton.
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
- ♪ May the best woman ♪
- ♪ Best woman win ♪
- Hello, girls.
It's today.
- Good morning.
- It's a new day,
which means a new challenge.
[laughs]
- Hello, hello, hello.
-Oh!
- Ladies, I just came
from the eye doctor,
and she prescribed me
these new reading glasses.
And her timing
couldn't have been better
because in the great tradition
of Paris Is Burning,
it's time for
the reading challenge.
[all laugh]
Because reading is what?
-Fundamental.
- Thank you very much.
Sasha Velour, come on down.
- Whoo.
- The library is open,
darling.
- Okay.
[clears throat]
Alexis Michelle,
Broadway's calling.
In this case,
it's the one in Brooklyn
where the whores work.
[all laugh]
Shea Coulee, you remind me
of my favorite movies.
Your fashion,
Coming To America,
and your smile,
Jurassic Park.
[all laugh]
- I'm so happy
that we have on loan,
from Madame Tussaud's
RuPaul statue
and Miss Trinity Taylor.
Nina Bo'nina Brown,
your pads are so big,
you bend down to pick
something up off the street
and the garbage man says, who
left this raggedy couch here?
Goodwill pickup
is on Sundays.
[all laugh]
- Farrah Moan,
all those mens
that buy you
fancy designer shoes,
they're not your boyfriends.
They're called johns,
and they're your employers.
-Ooh.
Shea-Shea Coulee,
you sure are a scene stealer.
I guess gnawing on set pieces
explains those teeth.
-Ooh.
-Oh.
- That felt good.
-Valentina.
-Yeah.
- Your wardrobe
sure does look expensive,
but money can't buy talent.
-Ooh.
-Hey!
- Farrah. You really are
the social media queen.
Too bad you can't get a filter
for that personality.
-Oh!
-Oh.
- Peppermint, you assassinated
Cynthia in the lip sync,
but did you have to practice
on your wardrobe?
- Ha-ha!
- Nina Bo'nina Brown
Jurassica Parker.
- Hey, sis.
- You've had some ups and downs
in this competition,
and I cannot wait to read it all
in your biography:
Fifty Shades of Ashy.
[all laugh]
- Alexis Michelle,
you're oh, so ♪ Broadway ♪
but you're also very broad.
Trinity Taylor,
I once told you
that you're so beautiful
inside and out.
I lied, you ugly stripper.
[all laugh]
Ladies, we're going to do
an exercise.
Everybody raise your arms
up to the sky.
And, Shea, this is for you.
One word:
deodorant, bitch!
[all laugh]
Peppermint, you need one.
- I told y'all she's sneaky.
- Oh, my God, I hate doing
this kind of stuff.
- I know.
- Sasha...
[all laugh]
You and Ru
have a lot in common.
He's bald, you bald.
He wear glasses,
you wear glasses.
He's rich--
Never mind.
[all laugh]
Alexis, you're like a BMW.
Body made wrong.
- Oh!
- Valentina, you think
you're Miss Venezuela,
but you're more like
Miss Quinceañera.
- Oh, man.
- Alexis Michelle,
Pillsbury called.
They want their rolls back.
-Ooh.
-Oh.
- Okay, that's all I got.
- Thank you, Farrah Moan.
-Farrah.
-I can't do that.
- Oh, you did.
- The library
is officially closed.
Now, you're all
avid readers,
but one of you
is the head librarian.
Valentina.
- Oh, you did it!
- You've won a four-night stay
for you and a guest
at the Saguaro Palm Springs.
- Oh, I love Palm Springs.
- Now, reading one another
do take nerve,
but you need
titanium balls and tits
to read a legendary queen.
So for this week's
maxi challenge,
we're bringing back...
The RuPaul Roast.
-Oh.
- #RuPaulRoast.
But this time, our guest
of dishonor won't be me.
The person
you'll be roasting is...
Michelle Visage.
[all cheer]
And get this.
She has no idea.
-[gasps]
-Oh, my God.
- Now, Valentina, since you won
the reading challenge,
you'll decide the order
of the presenters.
And a word of warning,
ladies.
Michelle never forgets.
[evil laugh]
So don't fuck it up.
[applause]
- Whoo!
- Here we go, y'all.
- What are you thinking,
Valentina?
- Do you know what order
you want to go in?
- I want to go just
somewhere in the middle.
- Valentina, I know that,
like, first and last
are like
the hardest positions,
and I don't mind
either one of them.
- Okay. So going first,
it's going to be Shea.
- All right.
- Second is going to be Sasha.
- Okay.
- Third is going to be
the one and only me.
Going fourth, Trinity.
Fifth, Farrah.
Sixth, Peppermint.
Seventh, Nina Bo'nina Brown.
And closing our show
is Alexis.
- Time for us
to start writing jokes.
Be clever.
That's the goal.
- Here's a tip.
Don't make it about my body.
- Oh, my Lord.
- I was surprised.
You guys came from--
anything to do with my size.
I just, like,
would have preferred
not to do with body image.
So that's all I have to say
about that.
- People,
we can't be sensitive.
It's a comedy challenge.
- Girl, get over it.
You knew people
were going to read you.
You made fun of other people.
Calm down.
You're a drag queen, honey.
- I'm sorry about my joke.
- I don't want you to feel
that I think it's okay
to make you feel that way.
- I feel like right now,
Alexis is in her head,
and I'm concerned
that she's not going
to take it far enough.
And for a roast to be good,
you gotta go all the way.
- Coming up...
- Everybody's nervous.
-Oh.
No digo nada.
- Bye, bitch.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Oh.
- Oh, my God.
- We have to do a roast
of Michelle Visage.
Oh, my fucking God.
Everybody's nervous.
- Aja, you might have got lucky
getting out of here.
- I am frozen,
and I'm not even talking
about my face.
- So I have my pen
in one hand
and I have my hand
on a piece of paper,
and I just think.
And... nothing.
Oh...
Virgen de Gaudalupe, por favor,
ayúdame en este momento
porque no digo nada.
- Girl, Guadalupe ain't gonna
write these jokes for you.
You gotta do it
for your own self, girl.
So get to work.
- [whimpers]
- Hello.
-Hi!
-Hello.
- Hi.
- I brought Ross to help you
with your material.
- This is my first time ever
in the workroom.
Do you know that?
- You're kidding.
Oh, my goodness,
well, welcome.
- It's just like
I pictured it.
[all laugh]
- Alexis Michelle.
-Hi, gentlemen.
-Hi.
- Now, a little birdie
told me that you
were a little miffed off
by the reading challenge.
- I just thought
some of my sisters
could have come up with
more original material.
- Oh.
You were more disappointed
than miffed.
- No, the truth is, Ru,
body image has been
something I've struggled with
for a lot of my life.
And I have talked
with my sisters
and they know
what I've struggled with.
That's why it was
a little bit, um, hurtful.
- So you feel like it's okay for
you to make fun of someone else,
but not someone else
to make fun of you.
- Um, look, I will try,
you know,
whenever I come for anybody
on that runway,
to make sure that
we're all laughing together.
- Right. But that's
the thing about comedy.
You know, a lot of times,
especially people who've been
through hell and high water
with an issue,
the only way
to get through it
is to friggin' laugh at it.
- Laugh at it,
that's true.
- Mm-hmm. 'Cause look,
you survived.
- Yeah.
- Have you ever done comedy
before?
- I have.
Actually, at my weekly show,
I spend a lot of time
on the mic.
- And you're actually
going last in the lineup.
How do you feel about that?
- I honestly
was ready to open her
and set the tone
or close her out
and, uh, let them eat cake.
- Okay. All right.
- Well, listen, you have
experience in this.
A lot
of the other girls don't.
And because you do, we're going
to need you to bring it extra.
- All right.
We'll see you out there.
Make us laugh.
See you.
- Bye.
-Hey, Farrah Moan.
-Oh, hi.
- Now, you did
the reading earlier.
How'd that go for you?
- Honestly, I really
didn't like doing it.
You know, I did go for
a low blow with Alexis Michelle
and it did not feel good.
- Now, are you more worried
about what other people
will think of you?
- I just am more worried
about staying true
to my integrity
and not hurting anyone.
- You're 12. What kind
of integrity do you have?
- [laughs]
I get it.
I would go on
Chelsea Lately all the time,
and that show was really
about tearing down Hollywood.
And my nature is to be nice,
so I'd be
the one in the corner
going, but I like
Jessica Simpson,
you know, trying to...
- Oh...
- But it can be done.
Lube her up a little bit.
- Yeah.
- You know what I mean?
I love you, Michelle, but...
- Uh-huh, uh-huh.
- I'm the biggest fan
of Michelle Visage, but...
- Yeah, exactly.
- Then it's not as mean.
-Totally.
-Except it's totally mean.
- Yeah, right.
Now, you haven't won
any challenges.
- I know.
- Because at this point
in the competition,
if you haven't won
any challenges,
you may wind up
in the bottom.
- Oh, don't say that, Ru.
-You gotta come for it.
-Okay?
- All right, make us laugh.
- Yeah.
-By-eee.
[laughs]
Hey, Pep-Pep-Peppermint.
- Hey, yo, yo, Ru.
-Hi. How are you?
-Ross, hey, baby.
-Good to see you.
-Now, obviously,
Michelle is the target
of this roast.
Does this scare you?
Does this excite you?
- It scares the shit
out of me.
- Tell me about it.
- I've never roasted
anyone before.
- Are you a funny queen?
- I think so.
I mean, I think
people will laugh.
- I think you are,
but so far in this competition,
you've had some trouble
getting out of the gate,
so to speak.
- I feel like it's more like
crossing the finish line.
- Okay, all right.
- Ding, ding, dong.
Are you hungry for a win?
- I'm starving,
and this is the time.
- Well, that's up to you.
All right,
thanks, Peppermint.
Sasha Velour.
- Hi, guys.
- Now, you're very smart.
You're intellectual.
How are you going to pull off
a gutter roast?
- I feel like my worries
about not being funny
have been getting in my way.
- Are you funny in life?
- That's the big question.
I make people laugh,
but in my shows,
my edge is that
it's serious and analytical
and has a bit of philosophy
and politics.
- You gotta use
what you got.
Maybe you can use this
sort of intellectual thing
to make fun of yourself
and then go after Michelle.
You know what I'm saying?
- Yeah, yeah.
Now, how's the joke writing
coming along?
- I'm having some writer's block
with this one.
- Well, time's running out.
-I know.
-Have you written any jokes?
- I've written the words
"mutton dressed as lamb."
[all laugh]
Which could apply
to a lot of people.
- Yeah.
- This is going to be
very interesting.
- Just make sure
you make us laugh.
- Absolutely.
- And don't forget, please,
make us laugh.
[all laugh]
-See you.
- All right,
listen up, pretty girls.
Roast them good, ladies.
-Mm-hmm.
-[laughs]
Let's go, Ross.
- Okay, bye.
Bye, bye, bye.
- Whoo!
- So mutton is old sheep.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- And lamb is baby sheep.
But also people use it
to describe
when someone who is old
is dressing
to appear younger.
- Okay. Mm-mm.
[both laugh]
Bye, bitch.
[laughs]
- Coming up...
We challenged our queens
to perform in the second
RuPaul Roast,
but our guest of honor
isn't going to be me.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- This week's maxi challenge
is the RuPaul Roast
and this time, we'll be
roasting Michelle Visage.
-Farrah?
-Yes.
- I'm sorry I insinuated
you were a prostitute.
- Oh, thank you, baby.
I'm sorry
I made fun of your rolls,
and I'm sorry
for bringing it up now.
[all laugh]
- I'm sure that your johns
are really lovely people.
- Oh.
-Whoo!
- Okay, girl.
[all laugh]
- There's moments,
you guys,
where, like,
there's a joke said
and then everybody laughs
and I look around
and just start, like,
laughing to blend in.
[all laugh]
- That was my experience.
When I first lived
in Russia,
humor in another language
is so challenging.
- How long
did you live there?
- I lived there for, like,
two and a half years
altogether.
- Oh, my God.
I got stuck in Moscow.
I was presenting female
and my ID does not match.
And I was in Moscow airport
for a connection,
I think, like 30 minutes.
This was eight months ago.
- Oh, my God.
- And so we land
and we're supposed to go
to the little transfer desk
or whatever.
And the woman,
she didn't speak any English,
and she just kept looking
at my ID and looking at me.
And it was clear
that she was disagreeing
with the fact that
my ID looked male
and I looked female.
Okay, so that's what it was.
So she detained me.
- Oh, my.
That's really terrifying.
- I was terrified
to the point
where I had to snatch
my own wig off my head
in the line
with all these people.
- Oh, my God.
- Just to prove to her
that I'm...
this is me
and please let me go in.
It was so humiliating.
- That's really a tragedy.
There's a lot
of gender fear in Russia.
-Yeah.
-I feel for her.
When I was living in Russia,
I had to disguise myself.
I couldn't be Sasha Velour.
I had to think carefully about
what clothes I was wearing,
how I moved my body.
Queer people in Russia are
living in an oppressive system.
- I just have to
keep in mind
that it doesn't take away
my womanhood.
-Amen.
-A-woman.
[all laugh]
[RuPaul laughs]
- ♪ Covergirl,
put the bass in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
And what?
- Welcome to the main stage
of RuPaul's Drag Race.
Michelle Visage,
it's roasting time.
Hope you brought a pig.
- I sure did.
[snort snort]
- From Hollywood Today Live,
the hilarious Ross Mathews.
Are you ready to be read,
for filth?
- Good thing
I brought my sani-wipes.
- Eew.
[all laugh]
Writer, actress, comedienne
Fortune Feimster.
I hope you have
a thick skin.
- Yeah,
and I'm extra crispy.
[all laugh]
- And Drag Race favorite
of alltime.com,
Tamar Braxton.
Hey, girl.
- Hi, darling.
- [laughs] This week,
we challenged our queens
to perform in the second ever
RuPaul Roast.
But this time, our guest of
honor isn't going to be me.
I've challenged our queens
to roast...
Michelle Visage.
-Oh.
-What?
- Surprise!
- No.
Bitch.
- It takes one to know one.
[all laugh]
With cool cocktails provided
by Micky's West Hollywood,
let's get this
Michelle roast started.
Gentlemen,
start your engines,
and may the best woman win.
Coming up...
- It's me,
Mother Maybelline
Nina Bo'nina Banana Fofana
Osama bin Laden Brown's
great aunt.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
[cheers and applause]
- Welcome to the second annual
RuPaul's Roast.
This year, we are really
switching things up.
Instead of RuPaul,
we are going to roast
a man of true charisma,
uniqueness,
nerve and talent.
[Michelle laughs]
Unfortunately,
he was unavailable,
so it's going to be
Michelle Visage.
Michelle, we know you for being
a kind, patient she-ro.
And gonorrhea clinics
know you as Patient Zero.
[all laugh]
Girl, you have had
more shit in you
than a urinal
at Dodger Stadium.
The only difference is
they get cleaned up
after a grand slam.
Well, ladies and gentlemen,
just remember,
if you liked my performance,
my name is Shea Coulee.
And if you hated it,
it's Nina Bo'nina Brown.
[all laugh]
[cheers and applause]
- Thank you, Shea Coulee.
That was extremely
edifying humor.
Uh, sorry, am I using
that word correctly?
Not edifying.
I know that one.
It was humor that I wasn't sure
worked in this context.
Tonight, we really do have
an opportunity
to salute empowering
representation in the media.
We have an out and proud
lesbian comedian.
Thank you so much,
Ross Mathews.
[all laugh]
Ross Mathews has the face
of a young gay man
and the voice
of an adult woman.
So the opposite
of Tamar Braxton.
[all laugh]
- Bitch.
I'm gonna get yo ass.
- It's now come time to talk
about Michelle Visage herself.
Michelle is so Jersey,
her idea of classical music
is Lisa Lisa.
- Hey!
- Michelle Visage
is so Jersey,
she calls her pubic hair
the Garden State Expressway.
And let's not even get started
on the Holland Tunnel.
- Whoo.
Michelle Visage is--
I have more of these.
Michelle Visage
is so Jersey,
she wanted to call her
second child White Flight.
Oh, well. That one worked
in my mind.
And now, a queen who combines
all the excitement of smiling
with the thrill
of just standing there.
[all laugh]
Give it up for Valentina.
[cheers and applause]
- Mama RuPaul,
you are the shadiest queen
because you let Michelle Visage
look so busted on Season 3
and 4...
and 5 and 6 and 7 and 8.
[all laugh]
And girl,
that's your friend.
That's fucked up.
Michelle is such a cochina
that she knows how
to say and spell "harder"
in six different languages.
Michelle,
you is such a tired-ass ho
that when you got carpal tunnel
from giving out free hand job,
she just became left-handed.
- I'm so confused.
- Ross, you're just so cute
and so sweet.
You just remind me
of a cute hamster.
I just want to shove you
up my butt.
Boo!
- [exaggerated drawl]
Thank you, Paydro,
mo-wee bee-in.
(muy bien)
Please excuse
the way I'm dressed.
I have to go feed the chickens
after this,
and I didn't want to wear
my good things.
I sometimes even have
to wrestle a few of them.
Michelle, you know all about
wrestling cocks, don't you?
I think
we have a lot in common,
from the same tastes
in hairspray
to the same units
of Botox fillers,
lips, tucks, nips and hips.
Michelle, every time
I walk the runway,
you have this pungent look
on your face,
kind of like
you got to shit.
I reckon they have
some laxatives for that.
Just a secret.
We all poop.
[applause]
- Let's get this roast
a-cookin'.
[clears throat]
Can we please
put our hands together
for the one, the only
Michelle Visage...'s breasts?
They're the real star
of the show.
Sorry, RuPaul.
Hmm. I find it hilarious
that Michelle Visage
judges a talent competition.
I don't know about you,
but don't you actually have
to have talent to do that?
Ha. And I'm pretty sure
having one song in the nineties
that no one even remembers
doesn't qualify you
to be a judge
on such a big TV show.
Good thing she's been sucking
RuPaul's dick for so long.
-Oh.
-Whoo!
- Oh, and we've got
Tamar Braxton in the house.
Tay-mar Braxton.
However you say it.
She's Toni Braxton's less
talented, more annoying sister.
[clears throat] Anyways,
now that Michelle's dick breath
has stunk up
this entire stage,
I'd like to introduce our next
minty contestant, Peppermint.
[cheers and applause]
- Hey, y'all.
Thank you, Farrah Moan.
[all laugh]
Ross, everyone says
that your voice is annoying
and high-pitched,
but I actually love
the sound of your voice...
right now.
- [laughs]
- Shh!
Don't talk, don't talk.
Michelle Visage,
Michelle, Michelle.
Not since Destiny's Child
has a Michelle become so famous
for riding
somebody else's coattails.
[all laugh]
RuPaul, all smiles,
Ross, all smiles,
Michelle, poker face.
No, seriously.
Someone poke her face.
It doesn't even move.
Michelle says no
to everything.
Michelle,
you like my dress? No.
You like my makeup? No.
Bitch,
where the hell were you
when somebody asked you if
you wanted to write that book?
[all laugh]
It's a great book, Michelle.
Said no one.
[all laugh]
Honestly, I fell in love
with you, Michelle,
watching you and RuPaul
on VH1,
and I'm so honored to share
this moment with you,
so thank you.
Happy 90th birthday,
Michelle.
[cheers and applause]
- Hey, babies.
It's me, Mother Maybelline
Nina Bo'nina Banana Fofana
Osama bin Laden Brown's
great aunt.
Coming all the way from
the lions, tigers and bears,
and sheep of the Lord
Missionary Baptist Church.
Praise the Lord.
Moving on
to the man of the hour,
RuPaul's secretary
Michelle Visayge.
You know, Michelle,
your face reminds me of my hip.
Stiff.
Oh, Jesus.
What's your name, baby?
[laughter and groans]
You are
a whole lotta woman.
Mm-hmm.
Well, we normally save
the best for last,
but in this case, we had
to settle for Alexis Michelle.
[applause]
- Oh, Michelle,
Michelle, Michelle.
In honor of your big night,
I wore your favorite color,
girl. [laughs]
Um...
We have so much in common,
Michelle.
We have the theater running
in our veins, Michelle.
You also have several venereal
diseases running through yours,
but that's
besides the point. [laughs]
But, you know, you're also
an inspiration to me, Michelle.
As thin as you have become,
one area has stayed
the same, unchanged.
It's a Hanukkah miracle,
Baruch HaShem.
Oh, my goodness, Fortune.
You also know about
playing second fiddle.
You've been playing
bullshit
to Chelsea Handler's
alcoholic WASP for ages now.
Now, Michelle,
I have to congratulate you
on really being able
to take the piss.
Just ask the UK
men's water polo team.
- Okay.
- She loves water sports.
She loves the UK.
And we love you, mama.
Thank you,
ladies and gentlemen.
It's been real.
Good night, everybody.
[scattered applause]
- This is not
a happy ending.
- And it don't help that
you look like She Hulk.
- Coming up...
- The jokes, they seemed
more like observations.
- You just looked like
you were going to throw up.
- This is a roast.
You go hard or go home.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Welcome, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Nina Bo'nina Brown
Earl Jones.
Valentina.
You ladies are safe.
You may leave the stage.
Now it's time
for the judges' critiques.
Let's start
with Shea Coulee.
- I know a thing or two about
being somebody's opening act.
- Yeah.
- And, you know, you just
set the tone, you know,
to be funny, to be original.
- And your jokes
were really funny.
I'm probably gonna steal them
and put them in my next special.
- Have them.
- Thank you.
You did a great job.
- Next up, Sasha Velour.
- When you started
the roast,
I think you were
way too smart for the room.
But the minute
you started laying into me,
it was friggin' genius.
- You have
a very specific POV.
You know, what does a roast
look like through Sasha's eyes?
And I think
you gave us that tonight.
- Trinity Taylor.
- What I liked was that
you had a character.
- Mo-wee bee-in.
- But everything else
didn't work for me.
- You didn't have the jokes.
- I think even before
you got up there,
you just looked like
you were gonna throw up,
and you still
kind of have that look.
- It's the Botox, I promise.
- Oh, okay.
See, that's funny.
And, like, I would have
liked to have seen you
sort of trust yourself more.
- Up next, Farrah Moan.
- Farrah,
nothing landed, honey.
If you're gonna be harsh,
it has to land.
And I think everything that came
out of your mouth was harsh.
That's not a bad thing.
It's a roast.
But you gotta follow it up
with a punch line.
People have to laugh.
- Yeah, I fucked up.
- I wouldn't call it
fucked up, but--
- I would call it fucked up.
- Okay.
- Because we identified
the problem in the workroom.
You said being mean
is not my nature.
But if you don't like to say
that person sucks,
you can say,
I love Michelle so much,
I was dying to meet her.
And she was exactly like
I'd hoped she'd be,
horrible in every way.
It would have been a POV
that none
of the other girls had.
- All right, up next,
Pep-Pep-Peppermint.
- So by the time
you came up,
I was hungry for just
a good piece of roast,
and you served it.
- I was like Ross,
just waiting for somebody
to just come out there
and bring the energy.
And you just killed it.
- And you look beautiful.
It just all works
for me tonight.
- I would totally
take you to prom.
[all laugh]
- Alexis Michelle.
- My question the whole entire
time is why is she green?
- Well, Tamar, have you ever
watched the show?
- But going green
like you did,
I expected
like a Broadway thing
'cause you look
like Elphaba.
And then, like, this
Jersey accent comes out.
- She likes water sports.
- I was like, I don't know
what to do
with these two things.
- I literally forgot
there was an audience here.
That's how silent they were.
- And the jokes, they seemed
more like observations.
-You were almost too soft.
-Yeah.
- It was like you were
afraid of hurting us.
This is a roast.
You go hard or go home.
- Thank you, ladies.
While you untuck backstage,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
[car engine starts]
All right, now just between
us squirrel friends,
what do you think?
Shea Coulee.
- I thought
she set a great tone.
She didn't shy away
from her jokes.
I was a fan.
- But on the runway,
is it the most creative look
we've ever seen?
- Sasha Velour.
- I was panicked for her.
Then she got this formula
that she just inserted
the jokes in and it worked.
- The way she was like
analytical at first
didn't bother me because
it worked with her outfit,
and she was funny
on top of that.
You know, she was really smart
about being smart.
- Yeah, it was a real
breakthrough moment for her.
Trinity Taylor.
- The father, the son
and the holy ghost.
-Yeah.
-We're not with Trinity.
-No.
-Not today.
- The jokes
just weren't strong enough.
-Yeah.
-It was road kill.
- [laughs]
That's good eatin'.
- But the outfit
was on point.
It was super cute.
I'm from North Carolina,
so I felt like
she fit right in
with my white trash people.
- Farrah Moan.
- I thought she reminded me
of Marilyn Monroe
when she did the whole
birthday thing for JFK.
And I thought
she was gonna come up
and do her whole character
[breathy] like this
and it would've been funny.
But what it came across
as a really nervous kid
who came to tell people off
in a harsh way.
- You know, it hit me.
She would be perfect
at doing Elvira.
She's got the same
sort of vocal cadence.
- You know, the fact
that everybody's like,
oh, you look like this,
you look like this
means probably who she really is
isn't coming through.
- I think Fortune brought up
such a good point.
She doesn't know who she is.
- At all.
- She knows she's a cute girl
and can wear pretty clothes.
- Yeah.
- But there's nothing more
than that yet.
- All right. So let's
move on to Peppermint.
Tonight
she was really funny.
- Not only was she funny,
but she looked probably
the best we've ever seen her.
She was literally
a smiling assassin.
- Really, seriously.
From the hair, the makeup,
the gown, to the funny jokes,
I really, really
enjoyed her.
Like, she was really the
highlight of the evening to me.
- Alexis Michelle,
the Green Mile.
[all laugh]
- For to come out here
with her whole body green,
I was just trying
to figure out, what?
Who in the hell
left the gate open?
You know what I'm saying?
Like, what we gonna get?
- It was a long way to go
for a one-word joke.
Michelle doesn't like green,
so I painted my body--
except for my feet.
[all laugh]
It just was misguided.
-Yeah.
-Confused.
I actually drew a picture,
look, on my notes, of a bomb.
- Oh, my goodness.
- But we know
what Alexis can do
because she has delivered
in the Snatch Game,
as Kris Jenner.
- But she chose
this position to go last.
That's a big swing,
and it was a big miss.
- Silence.
I've made my decision.
Bring back my girls.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Welcome back, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Shea Coulee, you're safe.
You may join
the other girls.
- Thank you.
- Sasha Velour,
you're smarty, arty,
and tonight,
you turned the party.
Peppermint, we finally got
a taste of the real Peppermint,
and we loved it.
Peppermint,
con-drag-ulations.
You're the winner
of this week's challenge.
[applause]
- Aah!
- You've won a five-year
membership with Squarespace,
which includes a consultation
with their design team
for your own personal
website and online shop.
- Thank you.
- And Sasha Velour,
you're safe.
The two of you
may join the other girls.
[applause]
Trinity Taylor,
your barnyard humor
did not make us go,
hey, girl, hey.
Farrah, tonight
you made us moan,
but for all
the wrong reasons.
Alexis Michelle,
tonight you proved
it's not easy being green,
and comedy is even harder.
Trinity Taylor...
You're safe.
- [sighs]
- You may join
the other girls.
- [whispers] Thank you.
- Farrah Moan,
Alexis Michelle,
I'm sorry, my dears, but you
are up for elimination.
- My heart is racing.
Getting to Drag Race has been
an eight-year-long journey,
and feeling like this might be
the end of that journey
is devastating.
- Two queens
stand before me.
Ladies, this is your last chance
to impress me
and save yourself
from elimination.
The time has come...
[thunder]
to lip sync
[echoing] for your life.
- I just have to take
a deep breath and focus,
because this is it.
- Good luck,
and don't fuck it up.
[music plays]
- ♪ You look at me
that way ♪
♪ I know
what your eyes say ♪
♪ Your eyes reflect love
and desire ♪
♪ I see that you need me ♪
♪ I need you to please me ♪
♪ You touch me
and set me on fire ♪
♪ I cannot resist you ♪
♪ Each time I kiss you ♪
♪ Then everything
goes up in flames ♪
♪ Baby, I'm burning
out of control ♪
body and soul ♪
♪ Hot as a pistol
of flaming desire ♪
♪ Baby, I'm burning ♪
♪ You got me on fire ♪
♪ Baby, I'm burning
out of control ♪
body and soul ♪
♪ Hot as a pistol
of flaming desire ♪
♪ Baby, I'm burning ♪
♪ You got me on fire ♪
♪ Baby, I'm burning
out of control ♪
♪ Baby, I'm burning ♪
♪ You got me on fire ♪
[applause]
- Whoo!
- Ladies,
I've made my decision.
Alexis Michelle,
shantay, you stay.
You may join
the other girls.
- Thank you.
- Farrah Moan,
you're a beautiful queen
with a big future.
Shine on, showgirl.
Now sashay away.
- Thank you guys so much.
[applause]
I am so proud of myself
for never letting go
of my dream,
but I've got
a lot more to learn.
It's been nice, L.A.,
but now it's time
for me to go cook in Vegas.
Oh.
- My queens,
con-drag-ulations.
And remember,
if you can't love yourself,
how in the hell
you gonna love somebody else?
Can I get an amen
up in here?
-Amen!
-All right.
Now let the music play.
- ♪ Hey, kitty girl ♪
♪ It's your world ♪
♪ Hey, kitty,
kitty girl ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪