WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- How you doing,
mis amores?
Are you ready to see
my Coo-Coo again?
(laughter and applause)
I'm back, mis amores.
- Welcome back,
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- #JusticeForCooCoo.
- Guide me, Jesus.
- I'm back.
- Oh, my God.
Welcome back, Cynthia.
- Oh, God.
- Congratulations
to the winner.
- Thank you, doll.
Thank you.
And congrats on you getting
better with your health.
- It was a roller coaster.
- Right.
- But, you know, I'm here.
I was diagnosed with
liver cancer stage one,
but I'm in remission
and I feel healthier as ever.
My Coo-Coo
is fantastic, girl.
I'm not gonna take
the opportunity
that RuPaul has given to me
in granted.
This Coo-Coo is ready.
This is home.
- I don't want to sound
like a hater or anything,
but, like, is this,
like, a joke
or are you
legitimately back, sis?
- Baby, I'm back.
I know
I'm Miss Congeniality,
but I'm no came here
to play games.
- I'm happy that Cynthia
is getting her second chance,
but on the other hand,
I'm like, oh,
we got this bitch
that already knows
this competition,
and that can get you
very, very far.
- I'm afraid
of what's coming next.
This just got real, honey.
- Ha-ha!
- (sighs) I'm not very happy
that Cynthia is back.
She could take us out.
- Hallelujah, my pussy
and my Coo-Coo is burning.
- I haven't yet seen this
infamous Coo-Coo of yours,
and I need to see it,
because if you're gonna say
Coo-Coo around me,
you better make sure yours
looks better than mine.
- Ooh.
- The winner
of "RuPaul's Drag Race"
receives a one-year supply
of Anastasia Beverly Hills
cosmetics
and a cash prize
of $100,000.
With extra special
guest judges the B-52s.
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
- ♪ May the best woman ♪
- ♪ Best woman win ♪
- ♪ Guess who
back in the house? ♪
♪ Just click-clacking
about ♪
♪ Fine fresh feminine style... ♪
- Good morning.
♪ So heavenly,
gentlemen sweat ♪
- ♪ Woo, woo, woo,
wootity, woo-woo ♪
- I didn't know this Coo-Coo
was happening today.
(alarm)
- Ooh!
- She done
already done had herses.
- If you can't love
yourself,
let me.
I'm your biggest fan.
Your number one.
Well, technically, only one
of you can be number one,
so the rest of you
are, like, losers.
Sorry about it.
(all laugh)
- Hello, hello, hello!
(screaming and cheering)
- Lisa mother fucking
Kudrow.
I am gagged.
- Lady Gaga was just here,
and now Lisa Kudrow.
I'm really digging Season 9.
- Say hi to my pal
Lisa Kudrow.
(cheers and applause)
- Hi.
- I just ran into her
on the lot,
and she wanted to come over
and say hello.
- Yeah, you guys look great.
- Oh, my God, stop.
- (laughs)
- Lisa's character Val Cherish
from the brilliant show
"The Comeback,"
is the reason
I say hello, hello, hello
every time
I walk into the workroom.
Did you know that?
- No!
- I didn't know that.
- Neither did I.
(all laugh)
- Now, Lisa, would you mind
saying that one thing
that you say
for me, please?
- Well, I got it.
(all laugh)
- That was good,
but can you say it happier?
- Well, I got it.
- Bigger, bigger.
- Well, I got it!
(all laugh)
Now I look like a fool.
- (laughs)
Lisa, come back any time.
- Okay, thanks.
- Thank you, darling.
Mwah, mwah.
(cheers and applause)
- Bye!
- Ladies, I have
a little secret to tell you.
When I was a little kid,
I wanted to be a cheerleader.
(cheering)
I loved the short skirts,
the sassy comebacks
and the death drop splits.
So for this week's
maxi challenge,
you'll be competing
in the biggest, baddest
cheer battle in herstory.
#QueerCheers.
(all laugh)
First, you need to divide
into two squads.
Nina Bo'nina Brown, you won
last week's challenge,
and Cynthia Lee Fontaine,
you're back,
so I'm making you two
head cheerleaders.
Pick your squads. Nina.
- Shea Coulee.
- Ha! Aah!
- Ooh, you playing
the race card?
(all laugh)
Cynthia.
- Kimora.
- Oh.
- My team is going to be
the Coo-Coo team.
- Alexis.
- Eureka!
- Oh, come on.
- Aja.
(applause)
- Farrah Moan.
- Oh, team Coo-Coo,
team Coo-Coo, go!
- I choose Sasha.
- Yes!
(applause)
- Peppermint.
- Because I have a heart for
the underdog, I choose Jaymes.
- Aw.
- She was just doing
community service.
- Oh!
- I'm feeling
a little self conscious
about being labeled
an underdog,
because I consider myself
very much a competitor.
- All right.
Welcome, Trinity.
Yes!
- I choose Charlie.
(applause)
- Which means Valentina,
you're on Coo-Coo's team.
- I feel like Valentina
was picked last
because
she's already mentioned
she's only been doing drag
for 10 months.
So I think we're all like,
well, what can she bring?
- It doesn't feel good
to be chosen last,
but little
do these queens know
that in their team
they got the superstar.
- Team Nina Bo'nina Brown,
you'll be cheering
for the home team,
RuPaul's Glamazons.
- Yes, honey.
- Yes.
- And Team Coo-Coo,
you'll be cheering
for our extra special
guest judges, the B-52s.
- Yes!
(applause)
- Kate, Fred and Cindy
gave me a big break
when they cast me in their music
video for "Love Shack."
- Ooh!
- Oh, yeah!
- All right, gentlemen,
start your engines.
And may the best woman win.
- So anybody
have any insight so far?
- There's literally
like an adjective
for every single queen.
- Mm-hmm.
- So I think
we should go through that
and assess, like, who matches
the description the most.
- Doll, I want to be sassy.
- Okay.
- Can I be flirty?
- You can have that.
- I think that now
would be a great time
for Jaymes to--
if you want to, like--
- Yes, to really
show himself.
- If you do snoozy in funny way,
it would be funny.
- I think floozy
is more my role
'cause it's all about
high energy
and all about
being over the top.
- Impact, yeah, yeah.
- I want floozy.
- Ooh.
- Take snoozy, girl.
It'll be hilarious.
It'll be great.
I'm not snoozy.
I'm just--it's not me.
- Honestly, Alexis,
I feel like
even though, like,
snoozy may be a challenge,
I think it's a challenge that
you can definitely rise to.
- The other girls assure me
and encourage me that
I can make snoozy work.
You're right, girl.
I can do any of these.
- And these are characters.
- And you're sure you're
comfortable with that?
- I'll do whatever, yeah.
And they're right.
I'm an actress.
- Should we, like, stand up and
do it, just so we have like--
- Yeah, do you want
to get it off the--
- Ru call.
- I'm Charlie, I'm boozy.
- I'm Alexis, I'm snoozy.
- Jaymes, I'm Jews--ugh.
- I'm Aja, I'm sassy.
- I'm Nina, I'm assy.
- I'm Jaymes and I'm--oh.
I'm Jaymes and I'm a floozy.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
I don't think your part
comes in that late.
- You got to jump right in.
- Yeah, yeah.
- It's got a slow beat
to it.
- No, but you have to do
the first beat.
- You start in time
and then you stretch the floozy.
- I'm Charlie, I'm boozy.
- I'm Alexis, I'm snoozy.
- And I'm Jaymes
and I'm a floozy.
- Captain, may I speak out
of turn for a little bit?
- Of course.
Go ahead.
- Girl,
you gotta sell floozy.
If you wanted to be the floozy,
you gotta be the floozy.
- All right.
- I'm not seeing it yet, okay?
I'm not--
I want to encourage you.
I'm just saying, do it.
Do it, girl.
Come forward.
- Jaymes doesn't seem
to be here mentally,
and this is not the time
to be figuring out how to
get your mind in the game.
It already has to be there.
- It's gonna be a long day.
- Coming up...
- Whoo!
- Aah!
- Oh, my God!
I cannot believe what
they are asking us to do.
- There's gonna be a severe
injury on this episode.
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- All right, guys.
Five, six, seven, eight.
Let's go!
- Today's maxi challenge
is a straight up
"Bring It On" style
cheer battle, bitch.
- Why don't we do it
one more time.
I'm gonna sing it with you
so we can get it in time.
Let's do it again.
- This is gonna sound crazy,
but what if we go back
to your idea you had before?
- Of what?
- Oh, you want to switch?
- Where I do more of the
character and you do flirty.
- Do you want to try that?
Okay.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- 'Cause that way, if I'm
coming right behind somebody,
it's easier for me
to keep time.
- And that's a good idea.
Okay.
So I'm gonna--
we're gonna switch now.
- We'll switch it out.
- The decision to have Alexis
and Jaymes switch characters
is the right decision.
We're all thinking it.
It's gonna be better
for everyone concerned.
- I'm Charlie, I'm boozy.
- Jaymes, I'm floozy.
- We are actually rooting
for Jaymes
and want him to shine,
but he's gonna have
to believe in himself
to really sell
this challenge.
- One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight.
- It's time for rehearsal.
- One, two, three.
(cheering)
- Ay dios mio!
My Coo-Coo is just shaking
right now.
- All right, guys.
I'm Dom.
I'm a two-time
world cheerleading champion,
and I'm here to teach you guys
a competitive cheer routine.
- All right.
- It's gonna consist
of some tumbling,
some jumping, some stunts.
We're gonna
have to work together,
but you're also gonna have
to learn how to stand out
at the same time.
We're gonna start it
with stunting.
- I am so pissed.
I don't know who even
does cartwheels anymore.
It's not even the eighties.
- So what you're going to do
is dip down on one,
stand up,
lock out your legs,
squeeze your tush and hold.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Five, six, seven, eight.
One and three, dip one,
straight leg.
- Ooh!
- Wow!
- Oh, my God!
I cannot believe what
they are asking us to do.
- Dip one, then three.
- Oh!
- Okay, make sure
when you go back down,
you reach
for their shoulders.
- There's gonna be a severe
injury on this episode.
- Valentina, ready?
Dip one, up, three.
- I was literally shaking,
but I said to myself, Valentina,
when in doubt, smile.
- One, two, down three.
Okay. Can we switch out
the fliers now?
Ready.
And five, six, seven, eight.
Dip one, straight legs.
- Oh!
Bitch,
I'm scared of heights.
Oh, my God!
This is scary as fuck!
If I fall, it's gonna
fuck up my face.
- Then, three.
- Oh!
- My face
is definitely expensive
and I don't want
to mess that up.
No, ma'am.
Oh, that's not for me.
- We are feeling the pressure
and the burn.
Although the burn
might be something else.
- Oh.
- All right.
- Yes.
- We're back in the workroom
and we're all frantically
doing our part
to get our looks ready
for our cheer competition.
We have our work
cut out for us.
- We all have to look
amazing.
- I don't have bloomers.
- I'm gonna wear tights.
- Yeah, but you still
have to have panties on.
- No, I'm not wearing
anything underneath.
- What?
- So if you go like this,
it just looks like
Barbie crotch?
- Why am I being attacked
of being a woman?
- Women wear bloomers underneath
their cheerleading clothes.
- Not the slutty ones.
(all laugh)
Fine, I'll wear panties.
- (laughs)
- RuPaul Glamazons, we're gonna
teach you how to stunt
so we can do some pyramids.
Ready, and five, six,
seven, eight.
Dip one, two and three.
- Should the inside of the palms
be together?
- As close as you can.
- Okay.
- Don't think about looking
straight forward.
Turn your head to the side.
You're gonna get a face full.
- That's not a problem.
(all laugh)
- You think you got it?
- (sighs)
I'm thinking to myself,
it's probably not the sport
for people
with an AARP membership.
- And dip one in three.
Good. Straight arms.
Try and lift those knees
up to your chest.
And five, six, seven, eight.
Dip one, two, three.
How are we feeling?
- Fabulous.
(all laugh)
We're gonna need
stunt doubles.
- You guys, I can't even believe
I'm still stoning this.
Like, this is
hard labor work.
This is why
I pay people to do this.
- Stoning really does
feed my soul.
- It does me, too.
I love to put sparkle
on everything.
- I think
when you stone anything,
it's just an excuse
to look great
without really
even being great.
Stoning is for ugly girls.
Don't get me wrong,
but I think all of us,
we kind of grew up
differently, you know.
Like, some of us love to,
like, create things.
- Well, some of us
don't love it.
Some of us have to do this
to survive.
Sewing all day
makes my back hurt,
and I eventually get
so creatively exhausted
that I just despise
looking at my crafting room.
But I know that
if I don't go in there,
I'm not gonna be able to go to
the buffet that I want to later.
(all laugh)
- Sister, I'll take you
to the buffet with me.
- Well, bitch,
you take me to a buffet
and I'll sew you something.
- So can you finish this
for me then?
- Kimora is gorgeous,
but that attitude...
- I'm getting tired,
I'm getting thirsty
and I'm getting, like,
anxiety right now.
- Not cute, girl.
- Oh!
- Coming up...
- Wait!
- Uh, this is my
virgin de Guadalupe.
I've really been praying to her
every single night.
- You crazy, bitch.
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Yay!
- Yeah.
- Day two, whores.
- Glamazons are gonna kick
the B-52s asses.
- So today is the day
we're about to perform
this mother fucking
cheer challenge.
- Wait! Girl!
Do you really?
- Oh, this is my
virgin de Guadalupe.
I wish I could turn her on,
but I really been praying to her
every single night
just to watch over me
and guide me
through this process.
- Who, Madonna?
- No,
la virgin de Guadalupe.
- You crazy, bitch.
That's some crazy shit.
- Everybody
gets to have a drag mom,
but I feel like
la virgin de Guadalupe
is my drag mom.
She helped get me here.
She's gonna
help me win, too.
(praying in Spanish)
Please help me win
this challenge.
I need to win.
Love you, thank you.
- Did you do
high school sports?
- I played tennis and then
I did swimming and diving.
And I think the diving
kind of helped me out
with this a little bit.
- Yeah. Girl, I did
high school cheerleading.
- Yes.
- We never did no--
Girl, it was
a black high school.
We, like, you know...
- Right. (laughs)
- I'll never forget
I was in the gym
with all the cheerleaders.
Some of the girls were like,
oh, what do you think
about that basketball player
over there?
He was so fine.
- Boing.
- Like, gorgeous
cocoa skin.
And I was like,
oh, he's cute, he's cute.
And later on, at lunch,
I see the entire basketball team
looking at me
like I'm about to get it.
So I get up and I'm like,
let me get out of here early.
I'm by myself
in the stairwell,
and the entire basketball team
comes up the steps,
and one of the boys
beats the hell out of me.
- (gasps)
- No, Pep.
- It's true.
But afterwards, I was
talking to the secretary,
told her what happened.
And you know how
the high school offices
have, like,
all glass windows.
- Uh-huh.
- So I turned around,
and I swear,
the entire school
was just there.
It felt like
a circle of love.
Like, people were crying,
my friends were out there.
So I felt pretty good,
you know.
And he got expelled.
- Right on.
- I stayed captain
of the cheerleading squad.
- Come on.
- When I was in high school,
I was singled out
for being different.
After that incident,
I had strangers
reaching out to me,
and I knew right away
that I was loved,
and that felt great.
- Cynthia, your story
really touched me
because I have a lot
of people in my family
who have had cancer,
and, like, and who have--
who have passed
because of that.
- Oh, my God.
- I just wanted to make sure
that you're okay, because
I know your struggle
which was hard, and it really
touched my heart.
- Thank you.
Girl, whoo!
It's a challenge.
Everything was a real mess.
I get my results and it
was liver cancer stage one.
So I was like, what?
You know, I mean, I just...
I was living my dream,
and now I need to face,
like, liver cancer.
I was sad.
I was really sad.
It's hard when you know
that you have a disease
and maybe probably
could be, you know,
the last days of your life.
I mean,
the immune system goes down.
So even a cold,
it can possibly, like,
kill you, so, I mean--
- It's unreal to think
that you could die.
- At any moment.
- Any moment.
- But let me tell you.
I'm in remission.
- Cynthia is living proof
that cancer is not the end.
- Whoo! Group hug.
We need a group hug.
- If anything,
she's stronger competing now.
It has given her a drive
to really succeed,
and she's doing it
with beauty
and with a sense of humor,
and that's a drag we need.
- #KickingCancerintheCooCoo.
(cheering)
(RuPaul laughs)
- ♪ Cover girl,
put the bass in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
And what?
- Welcome to the main stage
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
My head cheerleader,
Michelle Visage.
How's your head?
- Haven't had
any complaints.
- (laughs)
And everybody's grooving because
it's the B-52s.
Hey, is your tin roof
still rusted?
- Ooh, yeah.
- Oh, yeah.
- Yeah, baby.
- This week,
our queens are competing
in the biggest, baddest
cheer battle ever.
Let's check in with
our very own Ross Mathews.
- Yes, Ru,
this is so exciting!
It smells like
queen spirit.
I'm actually
literally gagging.
Back to you.
- Thanks, Ross.
We'll be watching.
Gentlemen,
start your engines,
and may the best woman win.
Coming up...
- Whoo!
- Ow!
(bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- It's the "RuPaul's
Drag Race"
Cheer Battle Extravaganza!
RuPaul's Glamazons
versus the B-52 Bombers.
- Ru call.
- I'm Aja, I'm sassy.
- I'm Nina, I'm assy.
- I'm Shea, I'm flirty.
- I'm Sasha, I'm dirty.
- I'm Charlie, I'm boozy.
- I'm Jaymes, I'm snoozy.
- I'm Alexis
and I'm a floozy.
All: We are RuPaul's
Glamazons.
Got our tucking panties on.
Our beat is unstoppable.
Our wigs are unclockable.
All: All right, work it,
work it, all right.
- B-52 Bombers, let's go!
- I'm Coo-Coo, I'm naughty.
- I'm Kimora, I'm slutty.
- I'm Eureka, I'm wacky.
- I'm Trinity, I'm tacky.
- I'm Farrah, I'm thorny.
- I'm Peppermint,
I'm corny.
- I'm Valentina,
I'm also corny.
(all laugh)
All: Our lobsters
are rocking.
Our love is in the shack.
We're roaming
'cause we wanna,
so haters step back.
ALL: B-50-who?
Not as cool as Ru.
RuPaul is more fierce
than Kate could ever be.
More woman than Fred
and more man than Cindy.
All: RuPaul is shameless,
selling candy bars and more.
- Ugh!
All: She even had a perfume
and it was called Whore.
(all laugh)
All: Your beehive's busted.
Your songs are too slow.
You should go retire
in a private Ida-ho.
- And it's time
for the tumbling package.
(whistle blows)
- Yeah, big girl.
Come on, bitch, yes.
Holy fuck.
I land
and I feel my knee pop.
But I knew there was no way
I was stopping.
Bitch, I'm on a roll.
- Whoo!
- Aah!
- Now, that was impressive.
- Valentina surprised me.
I feel a little bit like,
oh, my God.
I choose her last,
but she came to slay.
- Ms. Jaymes? Girl.
- Whoo!
- There we go.
(horn blows)
- Now the ladies will move on
to the group dance.
- Whoo!
Whoo!
(cheers and applause)
- Five, six, seven, eight.
- Glamazons, Bombers,
the battle raging on.
This cheer ain't over.
Now bring it on!
- When I get all the way
up to the top,
I feel like, yes,
I'm a cheerleader.
- Oh!
- Whoo!
(cheers and applause)
- The judges are going to have
a tough time scoring this one.
I feel bad for them.
Oh, wait.
I'm a judge. Uh.
- The category is
white party realness.
Nina Bo'nina Brown
Zeta Jones.
- Glamazon Shazaam-a-zon.
- When Nina Bo'nina Banana
Osama bin Laden Brown
hits the runway, child,
I'm a bad bitch.
- Hungry, hungry hip pads.
- Ooh.
- Alexis Michelle.
- Do these earrings
make my ass look fat?
- I'm serving glamour,
but I've got it turned on
its ear just a little bit.
- Tin roof frosted.
(all laugh)
Shea Coulee.
- I'll have two
vanilla cones, please.
- I'm serving you chocolate
sixties bodacious babe.
- Remember when
we used to do white lines?
- Whoo!
- (laughs)
- Charlie Hides.
- Very Linda Evans
from "Dynasty."
- The outfit is amazing.
I look like a fashion
illustration of the Snow Queen.
- You know,
she's from the hood.
- Sasha Velour.
- I've taken a classic
silhouette and updated it
with a commitment to showing
women who are strong.
- You know what they say about
girls who wear white pumps.
- True hooker.
- Mm-hmm.
- Aja.
- Where's my fava beans
and chianti?
- I believe that's
a whitening strip, actually.
- I'm an Illuminati
princess.
They tried to silence me,
and I'm like, no, bitch,
I'm still gonna talk.
- Now you Khali-see me,
now you don't.
- Hmm.
- Jaymes Mansfield.
- Gentlemen prefer
a white muff.
- My look is fun.
It's campy.
I look fabulous.
- The girl can't help it.
- Oh, I'm sure she can.
- Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- Oh, my goodness, I think
I'm having a déjà Ru.
- I'm going to
the most expensive
white party ever, okay?
- My fair Coo-Coo.
- (laughs)
- Farrah Moan.
- I like the peek-a-boos.
- I'm giving you
a little bit of ass,
a little bit of class
and some broken glass.
- She is quite the hipster.
Valentina.
- Oh.
- Nice day
for a white wedding.
- I'm inspired by my mom
and dad's wedding video.
My mom was known as the
beautiful bride in her hometown,
and I want
to tell you that story.
- If anybody has any objections,
shut the fuck up.
- Yeah. (laughs)
Trinity Taylor.
- I think a UFO landed.
- My ass looks really good
in these white pants.
They look like two snowballs
just juggling.
- I hear she comes in piece.
(all laugh)
- Kimora Blac.
- Now that's
my kind of patriotism.
- I'm going to a white party
on a boat
with hot sailors,
and we're gonna have fun.
- I don't think she'll sink,
do you?
- She comes with
her own flotation device.
Peppermint.
Ooh, winter mint.
- I've chosen
an Elvis Presley-inspired
rock 'n' roll extravaganza.
- That pearl necklace
seems to be dripping.
- Eureka.
Honey, it's milking time.
- Uh-huh.
- I'm giving you glamour,
androgynous Glamazonian,
big tuna fish.
- Eureka,
like the vacuum cleaner?
- Yes, and she can suck.
- Maybe I won't have my mother
watch this show.
(all laugh)
- Coming up...
- You were so fun to watch.
- Space age fashion,
I adore it.
- You're like a drug dealer.
Gave me a little dose.
I wanted more.
(all laugh)
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Welcome, ladies.
This week
you competed as teams,
but you'll be judged
as individuals.
When I call your name,
please step forward.
Nina Bo'nina Brown.
Alexis Michelle.
Sasha Velour.
Aja.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
Farrah Moan.
Peppermint.
Eureka.
Ladies, you are safe.
- (exhales)
- Thank you.
- You may leave the stage.
It's time
for the judges' critiques...
Starting with Shea Coulee.
- Tonight, you are giving me
this futuristic look
with hair that hearkens back
to Barbarella,
and I'm really feeling it.
- And the routine you did,
you were fantastic.
- She did some amazing flips,
and I made note of that.
- You could see
the humor there, too.
- As a kid, I wanted to be
like Dominique Dawes so bad,
but my parents were like, uh,
you can do that in the backyard.
We ain't putting you
in no lessons.
(all laugh)
- Thank you, Shea Coulee.
Next up, Charlie Hides.
- I didn't remember you
from the acrobatic thing.
- I tried to star everyone
that I really thought stood out.
- Did Charlie have a star?
- No.
- But I'll tell you this,
you seized me on the runway.
This look is just so good.
- Thank you.
- Up next,
Jaymes Mansfield.
- Hi.
- The way you pad
is glorious.
You're giving me, like,
saddlebag and hips.
It's hot.
But in the cheer,
I don't remember you,
and that's not good.
I think you like to consider
yourself a comedy queen,
but I haven't found anything
funny coming from you.
I feel that
you're unsure of yourself.
You have to believe it
in order to sell us.
- You do
this airhead shtick,
and I think if you committed
all the say, it'd be great.
And I think that's what
Michelle's getting at,
is the confidence
to commit 100%,
and I feel like
it's at 20%.
- Next up, Valentina.
- I loved this
virginal Latina bride
down to the crossing
of yourself.
It was also beautiful
all the way down to the nude
and not white shoe.
But we won't bring that up.
(all laugh)
Now, the cheerleading,
what I loved the most
was that even when
the lights weren't on,
I was watching you, and you
were fully in character.
And it just--it was so,
like, "SNL" moment.
- I found myself
looking for you.
You're like a drug dealer.
You gave me a little dose.
I wanted more.
(all laugh)
Keep it up, or as you say
in Spanish--
I don't know how you--
I don't know how to say that.
(all laugh)
- Next up, Trinity Taylor.
- You had
the toughest job of all
as the ultimate flier,
and you were so fun to watch.
- And I think
this outfit's fantastic.
Beyond Mugler.
- Thank you.
- Up next, Kimora Blac.
- What stood out to me
was the wig you had on,
but you didn't really stand out
athletically.
- And that's not good.
- Tonight, probably my least
favorite on the runway.
If I looked at you,
I'd automatically think
nautical theme.
I wish the gloves were white
and the bra was white.
I know it sounds like
it's a lot of white,
but it's a white party.
- Thank you, ladies.
I think we've heard enough.
While you untuck backstage,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
All right, just between
us squirrel friends,
what do you think,
starting with Shea Coulee?
- I thought she was the best
in the athletic department,
and I thought
she looked great tonight.
I love that outfit.
- In terms of star quality,
she has it.
But I think she needs
to have some kind of padding.
She's got thighs,
but she ain't got no booty.
- All right. Let's move on
to Charlie Hides.
- In the cheerleading thing,
she had this great character
of Boozy.
You, out of everybody, Charlie,
could've taken it all the way.
- But Charlie
looked beautiful,
certainly carried herself well
on the runway.
- I'm eager to see what she
pulls out of her suitcase next,
but she better pull
personality out, too.
- Jaymes Mansfield.
- Listen, you got a name
like Jaymes Mansfield,
you better deliver.
- I used to watch
"The Match Game,"
and Jayne Mansfield would
come on every so often
and had a wiggle
in her walk.
Jaymes needs more voom
in his vah-vah.
- She wants to portray herself
as this comedic character,
when I don't think
that character's
completely realized yet.
- Jaymes' audition tape
was so funny, I got it.
I understood the shtick.
But I think that since she's
been in this competition
with the other girls,
she's thrown off.
- Yeah.
- Valentina.
- Valentina, rrrrrrr.
(all laugh)
As a cheerleader,
she really stood out
with her facial expressions.
She just made you
notice her.
- And I thought she was
the best dressed tonight.
I thought she was stunning.
- Michelle, you did clock her
on her nude shoes.
- I'm sorry,
I just couldn't let that go,
because she was
so flawless head to toe,
why wouldn't she put
a white shoe on?
Why would she throw
a nude clunker?
- Well, maybe she was thinking
something old, something new,
something borrowed,
something nude.
(all laugh)
- Someone you blew.
- Trinity Taylor.
- I thought
it was really impressive
how both characters
were completely different.
I wouldn't
have recognized her.
- Tonight on the runway, though,
it wasn't my favorite thing
'cause we've kind of seen
a lot of this over the years.
- I thought
it was very original.
- Space age fashion,
I mean, that's total B-52.
I adore it.
- Kimora Blac.
- I didn't remember her
from the competition,
and that wasn't
my favorite outfit.
- I thought
she was a newbie.
- I know why you got
that impression,
because she paired
so many different looks
onto that one look.
- Right.
- Where someone who's a
seasoned prostitute would have--
would have just chosen
the nautical hat.
It actually accented her
inability to tell a story.
- She's got so much
going for her,
the look, the face, the body,
the confidence on stage.
But in terms of who are you
as a performer,
I don't know,
but I know I want to know.
- All right. Silence!
I've made my decision.
Bring back my girls.
(RuPaul laughs, bell rings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Welcome back, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Shea Coulee.
You're safe.
- Thank you.
- Jaymes Mansfield.
On the runway, you gave us
bombshell floozy,
but your cheer routine
was a little too snoozy.
I'm sorry, my dear, but
you're up for elimination.
- It's frustrating.
What I'm trying to show
the judges isn't translating,
and I don't really know
what else they want from me.
- Trinity Taylor.
You're safe.
- Thank you.
- Valentina.
Your cheer engaged us,
and your bridal runway
made me say, "I do."
Sissy-boom-bah,
you're the winner
of this week's challenge.
You've won a custom wig wardrobe
from Rock Star Wigs.
- Thank you so much.
- You may join
the other girls.
Charlie Hides.
You scored on the runway,
but your cheer routine
did not meet our squad goals.
Kimora Blac, in the cheer,
you disappeared.
And in white, you got read
for being too blue.
Charlie Hides...
You're safe.
- Thank you very much.
- Kimora Blac, I'm sorry,
my dear,
but you are up
for elimination.
Two queens stand before me.
Prior to tonight,
you were asked to prepare
a lip sync performance
of "Love Shack"
by the B-52s.
Ladies, this is your last chance
to impress me
and save yourself
from elimination.
The time has come...
(thunder)
To lip sync for your...
(echo) life!
- It really starts
to sink in.
The pressure's on,
because I'm performing it
in front of
the B-52s themselves.
- To put me
on the bottom two first?
Jaymes, watch out.
- Good luck.
And don't fuck it up.
(music plays)
- ♪ If you see
a faded sign ♪
♪ At the side of the road ♪
♪ That says 15 miles
to the-- ♪
- ♪ Love Shack ♪
♪ Love Shack, yeah ♪
♪ I'm headin' down
the Atlanta highway ♪
♪ Lookin' for
the love getaway ♪
♪ Headed
for the love getaway ♪
- ♪ I got me a car
as big as a whale ♪
♪ And we're headin' on down
to the Love Shack ♪
♪ I got me a Chrysler,
it seats about 20 ♪
♪ So hurry up and bring
your jukebox money ♪
- ♪ The Love Shack
is a little old place ♪
♪ Where
we can get together ♪
♪ Love Shack, baby ♪
- ♪ A Love Shack, baby ♪
- ♪ Love Shack,
baby, Love Shack ♪
♪ Bang, bang, bang ♪
♪ On the door, baby ♪
- ♪ I can't hear you ♪
- ♪ Bang, bang ♪
- ♪ On the door, baby ♪
- ♪ You're what? ♪
- Tin roof...
rusted.
♪ Love Shack,
baby, Love Shack ♪
- ♪ Dancing and a-lovin'
at the Love Shack ♪
(cheers and applause)
- Ladies,
I've made my decision.
Kimora Blac,
Shante you stay.
You may join
the other girls.
(applause)
Jaymes Mansfield,
we're all rooting for you.
Now sashay away.
- Thank you. Bye.
(applause)
I came in first.
(all laugh)
Well, that didn't quite go
exactly as I hoped it would.
I wasn't fully representing
myself, and that's my fault.
But underneath
all this glamorous drag,
I'm still a human being,
so be kind.
- Con-drag-ulations, ladies.
And remember,
if you can't love yourself,
how in the hell you gonna
love somebody else?
Can I get an amen
up in here?
All: Amen!
- All right.
Now let the music play!
- ♪ Everyone
can be someone ♪
♪ If you want to ♪
♪ I can show you ♪
♪ Be someone ♪