WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
Tonight on "rupaul's drag race" reunited.
All the queens have gathered to
"race" reunited.
all the queens have gathered to
sound off.
Sound off.
If you can't roll with the
if you can't roll with the
punches, this is not career for
you.
You. And let you have it.
And let you have it.
Excuse me, I need to speak,
excuse me, I need to speak,
I'm not done speaking.
I'm not done speaking. No.
No. No.
No. ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ ♪ ♪
♪
the winner of "rupaul's drag"
the winner of "rupaul's drag
race's" wins one year's supply
"race's" wins one year's supply
of beverley hills cosmetics and
$100,000.
$100,000. ♪ ♪
♪
♪ welcome to "rupaul's drag"
welcome to "rupaul's drag
race" reunited.
"Race" reunited.
We are a week away from the
we are a week away from the
crowning of America's next drag
super star.
Super star.
Right hear on this stage at the
right hear on this stage at the
Alex theater.
Alex theater. Before we do.
Before we do.
The queens are back to spill all
the queens are back to spill all
the tea about this season's
biggest scandelous.
Biggest scandelous.
First up one of the season's
first up one of the season's
biggest controversy.
Biggest controversy.
It's not personal, it's reading.
Alexis Michelle, people online
said you could dish it out and
you can't take it.
You can't take it. Take a look.
Take a look.
Farrah moan, all the guys.
Farrah moan, all the guys
from buy you designer shoes,
they are not your friends they
are your jons.
Are your jons.
Alexis Michelle, pillsbury
called, they want their rolls
back.
Back.
Time for us to start writing
time for us to start writing
jokes.
Jokes.
Here's a tip, don't make it
here's a tip, don't make it
about my body.
About my body.
So, that's all I have to say
so, that's all I have to say
about that.
About that.
What do you say to that?
Um, regarding my sensitivity,
um, regarding my sensitivity,
my body is something that I have
struggled with my whole life.
Struggled with my whole life.
And we have have talked about
and we have have talked about
our body image issues a few
weeks before.
Weeks before.
Yeah, but the reading
yeah, but the reading
challenge is a safe place to let
it all hang out because you no
there's love in the room.
There's love in the room.
And the love came from me to
and the love came from me to
the girls too.
The girls too.
And because we talked about
and because we talked about
other eating disorders...
Other eating disorders...
Yeah, I got it.
Surely you can understand why
surely you can understand why
people online would say, waumt,
you know, having talked about
the other body sensitivities.
The other body sensitivities.
It was just, it did not feel
it was just, it did not feel
balanced.
Balanced. I talked about being
I talked about being
sensitive about my teeth, but
that doesn't stop you.
That doesn't stop you.
And I was still able to sit
and I was still able to sit
there and laugh about it and I
just felt like you were not
being a good sport.
Being a good sport.
I make fun of my size all the
time on stage at my shows.
Time on stage at my shows.
That's not her point.
I don't think that you come
off as like some huge size
queen.
Queen. I agree.
I agree. Yeah.
Yeah.
I think the gripe that people
had online, was that you dished
it out, basically calling Farrah
a prostitute and turnabout was
not fair play.
Not fair play.
My advice is girl you are a
my advice is girl you are a
drag queen, and if you can't
roll with the punches, this is
not the career for you.
Not the career for you.
You know, this won't air, but
you know, this won't air, but
lady bunny and I used the to do
acid together.
Acid together.
And we were custodies.
Inevitably, she'd say to me and
inevitably, she'd say to me and
look at me, and say, ru, the
devil's going to get you.
Devil's going to get you.
And I said, why are you doing
and I said, why are you doing
that?
That?
I'm tripping my balls off and
you are bringing up this stuff.
You are bringing up this stuff.
But in hindsight, what she was
but in hindsight, what she was
doing was taking away all the
things, and you are like, oh,
wait a minute, there's nothing
to it and that's what reading is
all about.
All about.
What I'm trying to do now is
what I'm trying to do now is
not take it all so seriously.
Not take it all so seriously.
I have a question, if you
were to get read right now,
could you take it?
Could you take it?
Well, I have reading glasses
well, I have reading glasses
right here.
Right here.
That's right, ladies the
that's right, ladies the
library is open.
Library is open.
Let's start with Trinity.
Alexis, I love your costume.
You look just like a honey baked
you look just like a honey baked
ham.
Ham. After all that.
After all that.
Here's... go right back.
You can take it now.
I can take it, I can take it.
Aja.
Aja. Here we go.
Here we go.
I love your costume, that's
why I call you the Joan of ark
of drag, great ideas and badly
executed.
Executed.
It's getting hot in here.
Oh, yeah, I had a good read
oh, yeah, I had a good read
for Valentina, but I can't
remember the word.
Remember the word.
That was good.
That was, good, girl.
Trinity is so fishy, all she.
Trinity is so fishy, all she
is serving is Fisher price.
Is serving is Fisher price.
Bitch, you look like fish, a
bitch, you look like fish, a
whale.
Whale.
Honey I'm James and the giant
honey I'm James and the giant
peach and not afraid of it.
Peach and not afraid of it.
Bitch, you ate James and the
bitch, you ate James and the
giant peach.
Giant peach.
Didn't know you were here
didn't know you were here
until your nose walked in,
bitch.
Bitch. Don't try it, bitch.
Don't try it, bitch.
All right...
All right... I had so much more.
I had so much more.
I know you did, the library
for season 9 is officially
closed.
Closed. Praise god.
Praise god. Amen.
Amen. This year was a season of
this year was a season of
shocking eliminations.
Shocking eliminations.
And I'm not talking about what
and I'm not talking about what
guess on between you and your
squatty potty, first up, Charlie
hides.
Hides.
I hate to say this, my dear, but
your lip sync for your life was
dead on arrival.
Dead on arrival. Girl.
Girl. Charlie, what happened?
Charlie, what happened?
Well, I think you all know
well, I think you all know
now, I injured myself during the
cheerleading, I cracked my rib.
Cheerleading, I cracked my rib.
And I was in pain.
And my British stiff upper lip,
and my British stiff upper lip,
I just said, don't show signs on
weaknesses and so, I you kept it
to myself.
To myself.
And lifting shea, shea... we had
and lifting shea, shea... we had
to lift you like 30 or 40 times.
To lift you like 30 or 40 times.
I'm sorry, I have to call [
I'm sorry, I have to call, how dare in the
, how dare in the
interview are you going to say
we don't lip sync, but now I
have a cracked rib.
Have a cracked rib.
I make Sushi, I do it twice a
year, and I'm not good at it.
Year, and I'm not good at it.
The things I do regularly I'm
the things I do regularly I'm
better at.
Better at.
We do Sushi on the show.
We do Sushi on the show. Yeah.
Yeah.
Cracked rib or not, girl, you
cracked rib or not, girl, you
gave up.
Gave up.
Do you know that I had duct
do you know that I had duct
taped my rib cage.
Taped my rib cage.
Girl, you walked all the way
girl, you walked all the way
down the runway, I saw you
moving around that work room.
Moving around that work room.
I'm sorry, I don't believe it.
All right, there was a side
all right, there was a side
of me that said, that you just,
if I had moved a little bit to
the left and a little bit to the
right, which is what I was
capable of, it was going to be
lame.
Lame. It's not about moving, lip
it's not about moving, lip
sync happens up here not down
here.
Here.
It's the passion, you looked
it's the passion, you looked
like you gave up.
Like you gave up.
I did the song, the brittney
Spears song is the sub text of
the song is masterbation, it was
a bad choice.
A bad choice.
This is the thing if you were
this is the thing if you were
masterbating, we were not
getting off, girl.
Getting off, girl.
I don't like her, but if she
can do what she did after her
knee injury, there's no excuse
for you.
For you.
If you are going to have an
if you are going to have an
excuse, pick one and not five.
Excuse, pick one and not five.
I did not have very much
I did not have very much left.
Left.
It was at the end of a long day.
At the end of a long week.
I was getting an hour and a
half sleep anight.
Half sleep anight. So were we.
So were we.
I'm trying to figure out is
it a broken rib, or...
It a broken rib, or...
I saw online that you said
you had diarrhea.
You had diarrhea.
On the first day of
on the first day of
rehearsing... but that was long
passed.
Passed. It was a rough day for
it was a rough day for Charlie.
Charlie.
I fainted in my hotel room
and I did the lip sync and I did
it a day after.
It a day after.
Did you give up because you were
did you give up because you were
ready to go home?
Ready to go home?
I said before, I was on
I said before, I was on empty.
Empty. Charlie did you tell Nina
Charlie did you tell Nina
that you wanted to go home?
That you wanted to go home?
I don't remember saying that,
no.
No. Well, let's take a look at
well, let's take a look at
this never before scene clip.
This never before scene clip.
Oh, lord.
Oh, lord. Charlie didn't you...
Charlie didn't you...
Can I get in there.
She threw the towel in.
She talked to me and said,
she talked to me and said,
she was not going learn the
words of the song, she didn't
really want to.
Really want to.
So I think she is ready to go
so I think she is ready to go
home if it's time.
Home if it's time.
She didn't know the words to the
she didn't know the words to the
song.
Song. So she was like...
So she was like...
I feel like the moment you
don't try for a lip sync is the
moment when you are saying I'm
too good for this.
Too good for this. Oh.
Oh. So, she did tell you that,
so, she did tell you that, then.
Then.
I never said that I was too
good.
Good.
And can I say I'm sorry if you
and can I say I'm sorry if you
thought I was disrespecting you
by giving up and not you have
doing everything that I had.
Doing everything that I had.
No, it's true with all of you
no, it's true with all of you
girls.
Girls.
I have seen your audition tapes
and some of you I have seen year
after year after year, and then
I see you in group.
I get inspired of what you give
to the competition.
To the competition.
And then when someone doesn't
and then when someone doesn't
give it their all, I'm
disappointed.
Disappointed.
Listen, you may not be the
listen, you may not be the
best lip syncer in the world,
you are fabulous on YouTube and
I think that you have made your
mark here.
Mark here. Thank you.
Thank you.
We will be right back.
Coming up, Eureka breaks
coming up, Eureka breaks down.
Down. You all made me feel so
you all made me feel so
belonged.
Belonged.
And the queen comes for
and the queen comes for
Valentina.
Valentina. ♪ ♪
♪
♪ welcome back to "rupaul's"
welcome back to "rupaul's
drag race'" reunited.
"Drag race'" reunited.
Another shocking exit came when
another shocking exit came when
we had to say goodbye to Eureka.
We had to say goodbye to Eureka.
Doctor's orders.
Doctor's orders. Take a look.
Take a look.
When I was doing the
when I was doing the
cheerleading challenge, I landed
wrong and my knee popped.
Wrong and my knee popped.
I've been able to push through,
but now it's hurtdhurting and I
to use crutches.
To use crutches.
I have made my decision.
Eureka, would you please step
forward.
Forward.
We have been in touch with the
we have been in touch with the
doctor.
Doctor.
And I cannot allow you to
and I cannot allow you to
continue in the competition.
Continue in the competition.
See, Eureka what was it like to
see, Eureka what was it like to
leave the competition that way?
Leave the competition that way?
It was hard because you know,
it was hard because you know,
I come from a small town, I
never really belonged anywhere
since growing up and you all
made me feel so belonged.
Made me feel so belonged.
So, it was hard.
So, it was hard. You know.
You know.
I want to ask Farrah moan,
why were you so upset?
Why were you so upset?
I had accepted mine or
Cynthia's fate, the last thing I.
Cynthia's fate, the last thing I
expected was for that to happen.
Expected was for that to happen.
I was like, no, no, take one of
us.
Us. Make it go away.
Make it go away.
You have seen that gift all
you have seen that gift all
you have seen that gif all
over the world.
Over the world.
Let's recreate it.
I'm sorry, Eureka, you have
to go home.
To go home. No.
No. No.
No. That's exactly what her
that's exactly what her
reaction is when they are sugar
daddy takes away her credit
card.
Card.
So tell me this, was anyone else
so tell me this, was anyone else
here that feels the opposite,
who was happy?
Who was happy?
You were amajor threat I felt
you were amajor threat I felt
so bad for you on a personal
level, but as a competitor, I
was just like...
Was just like...
And I still hope you lose
and I still hope you lose
season ten.
Season ten.
Now, I know that you had beef
now, I know that you had beef
with Trinity, did you guys ever
say goodbye to one another?
Say goodbye to one another?
Wherever everyone was hugging
wherever everyone was hugging
me, Trinity did look me straight
in the eye and she said, I'm
sorry, girl, I know how much you
wanted this.
Wanted this. You know?
You know?
And that's, literally the one
and that's, literally the one
Sincere moment I have had with.
Sincere moment I have had with
Trinity.
I want to say this, yes, I
think you are too loud and you
can be obnoxious, but I respect
you.
You. Thank you.
Thank you.
And you are an amazing
and you are an amazing
entertainer, I wanted you to
leave because you deserved to
leave not because of injury.
Leave not because of injury.
You feel robbed of my
you feel robbed of my
trinity/eureka lip sync.
Trinity/eureka lip sync.
I hear your head is fabulous.
How is your knee?
My head is fabulous, they
my head is fabulous, they
always ask for seconds and I'm
back to...
Back to... Get well soon, girl.
Get well soon, girl.
The shocking elimination, to end
the shocking elimination, to end
all shocking limitations.
All shocking limitations.
Valentina, bring me my mask.
Stop, holdup, holdup.
All right, enough.
All right, enough. Valentina.
Valentina.
This lip sync for your luf, we
this lip sync for your luf, we
need to see your lips.
Need to see your lips.
Take that thing off of your
take that thing off of your
mouth.
Mouth.
I would like to keep it on
please.
Please.
It's a lip sync, what part of
it's a lip sync, what part of
that do you not understand?
That do you not understand?
Okay.
Okay. So we are going to reset.
So we are going to reset.
Valentina what was going through
your mind at that moment?
Your mind at that moment?
I don't know.
I was just, I was not there.
Yeah, I was in a real state
yeah, I was in a real state
of shock.
Of shock.
The one thing that I will say
the one thing that I will say
about Valentina with her
elimination, she did not make
excuses like Charlie and you at
least owned up to not knowing
your words and you went home and
you deserved to go home had.
You deserved to go home had.
Did you ever learn the lyrics
did you ever learn the lyrics
at all?
At all?
Yeah, the night before I had
yeah, the night before I had
the lyrics with me, I stayed up
listening to the song and
writing them.
Writing them. I hand wrote them.
I hand wrote them.
Girl, it a seven-word chorus.
Seven words in that chorus,
seven words in that chorus,
girl.
Girl.
You can listen to the song and
you can listen to the song and
get the... you were sitting
there together, and you have one
earbud in, and she is mouthing
the words and you are just
reaching.
Reaching. I Valentina has a
I Valentina has a
lot of supporters out there.
Lot of supporters out there.
And I want to make it clear to
and I want to make it clear to
everyone.
Everyone.
That I saw the notebook with the
that I saw the notebook with the
words written out and I want
everyone to know that the girl
tried.
Tried.
I know you are trying to get
redemption from her fans, but
let's be real.
Let's be real.
You lip synced against her.
I don't get why there was so
much hate for me.
Much hate for me.
For doing what was asked of me
for doing what was asked of me
in lip sync of my life.
In lip sync of my life.
Why do you think your fans
why do you think your fans
came for the girls?
Came for the girls?
I represent something similar
to what salina represented in.
TO WHAT SALINA REPRESENTED IN
THE '90s.
Mexican, FIRST GENERATION,
Mexican, first generation,
talented, so they are over
protective of that and they will
fight anybody.
Fight anybody.
I don't agree with that kind of
behavior, it's not the kind of
person I am.
Person I am.
Why don't you say that on the
why don't you say that on the
media.
Media. Holdup.
Holdup. You are a role model.
You are a role model.
I don't approve of that.
You never said that.
I facetimed you in tears because
people said I should kill myself
because I'm ugly and fat and I
should volunteer to elimination
myself.
Myself.
I don't think she enkrenls
that, but you could say, I don't
agree with the way you are
treating this girl.
Treating this girl. Please stop.
Please stop.
I'm bad with social media.
I love to live my every day
life.
Life.
And I don't want to be involved
and I don't want to be involved
in what people think or say.
In what people think or say.
You can say that, but you
you can say that, but you
were on the phone checking every
like and every follow and every
single thing in Toronto.
Single thing in Toronto.
Whether you were reading the
whether you were reading the
comments verbatim or not, you
knew what was going on.
Knew what was going on.
When we were shooting the promo
when we were shooting the promo
for this show, you said to me,
shea, I just want to say, if
anyone comes for Nina, I told
her that I will stand up for her
and addresses my fans and make
it all right.
It all right. And I'm confused.
And I'm confused.
You don't need to be
you don't need to be
confused, you have a lot of
opinions of me tonight, shea.
Opinions of me tonight, shea.
There's no reason to get
there's no reason to get
upset, we are talking.
Upset, we are talking.
You are upset, I'm not upset.
Do I look upset to you?
Yes, you raised your voice
yes, you raised your voice
with me.
With me. Listen, it's a lot for
listen, it's a lot for anyone.
Anyone.
Especially someone who has
especially someone who has
300,000, 500,000 followers don't
you understand that may be
intimidating for her?
Intimidating for her?
I don't think it fair for you to
disconnect when they are coming
after us so hard.
After us so hard. No, excuse me.
No, excuse me.
Holdup, I'm sorry.
I need to speak, I'm not done
speaking.
Speaking.
Is there something that you
is there something that you
would like to say to the fans
right now?
Right now?
Yes, I don't agree with that
yes, I don't agree with that
type of behavior where it's
negative.
Negative. I'm very sorry.
I'm very sorry.
Like I don't want you guys
like I don't want you guys
thinking that I'm wok that.
Thinking that I'm wok that.
So, what do you want your
so, what do you want your
fans to do from here on out?
Fans to do from here on out?
I want them to respect you
I want them to respect you guys.
Guys. Because we are friends.
Because we are friends.
Thank you.
In that moment, I will be
in that moment, I will be
honest, I was disconnect from
everyone and everything, because
I'm trying to process my
elimination, I was torn for
months.
Months. I was lost.
I was lost.
I know, you called me, I
remember.
Remember. No, we did talk.
No, we did talk.
I couldn't leave the house.
I couldn't process the
disappointment that I felt from
you saying that you could have
gone all the way.
Gone all the way.
I felt like you stopped
believing in me.
Believing in me.
I chose every single one of
you girls to be on the show and
I have the highest hopes for all
of you.
Of you.
Buts that competition/reality
buts that competition/reality
show, it's not "rupaul's best"
show, it's not "rupaul's best
friend's race" and contrariy to
"friend's race" and contrariy to
what is happening in the world,
where people get a trophy for
showing up.
- Showing up.
- If you up, you are in
if you up, you are in
the bottom two, if you are in
the bottom two, you have to lip
sync for your life.
Sync for your life.
No matter how pretty or old you
no matter how pretty or old you
are, you are gone, that is how
the game is played.
The game is played.
There's so much to learn from
there's so much to learn from
my elimination about who I am
and there's so much that I want
to show now.
To show now.
Although, it's not the way that
although, it's not the way that
I wanted to leave.
But it was a darn good episode
but it was a darn good episode
and I got my telenovela ending.
And I got my telenovela ending.
Valentina, speaking of
telenovela drama, there were
choice words for you.
Choice words for you.
What did they say?
You are perfect, you are a
you are perfect, you are a
model.
Model.
Did you sew those tights, oh,
did you sew those tights, oh,
you are smiling, they eat her up
every time she is on that damn
stage.
Stage.
She doesn't... she could walk
she doesn't... she could walk
out in a diaper and they are
like, Valentina, you are smile
is beautiful.
Is beautiful.
I'm not going to say nothing.
Oh, my god.
Valentina, what did you think
of it?
Of it? I loved it.
I loved it.
I'm working on a number where I
come out and stand in a diaper
and smile.
And smile.
Aja what was going on there?
Here's the thing, you are in
here's the thing, you are in
the moment and you have
something to say, say it.
Something to say, say it.
So when Valentina was getting so
so when Valentina was getting so
much praise for being a gorgeous
beautiful model.
Beautiful model. Which she is.
Which she is. She is.
She is.
She is kind of a psycho, but
she is kind of a psycho, but
she is beautiful.
She is beautiful.
And that day, I really had felt
and that day, I really had felt
like she doesn't deserve to be
in the top.
In the top. And I was over it.
And I was over it.
I was like, girl, and then I,
you know, I don't want to say I
read her, I aggressively
complimented her and I let her
know how beautiful she was.
Know how beautiful she was.
You could see how happy I
you could see how happy I was.
Was. I was like, yes, girl.
I was like, yes, girl. Get her.
Get her. Get her aja, get her.
Get her aja, get her.
I think a lot of us had the
feeling that as you were saying
it, there was a bit of a silent
amen.
Amen. Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. There was.
There was.
We didn't understand why
we didn't understand why
Valentina was in the top that
challenge.
Challenge.
A lot of us didn't necessarily
a lot of us didn't necessarily
appreciate the charm that
Valentina was conveying to
camera, because to be honest,
girl, you are not making an
attempt to really get to know us
back stage at that point.
Back stage at that point.
It came on a bit later.
I wanted to win.
You wanted to be on the show
you wanted to be on the show
because you wanted to be a star.
Because you wanted to be a star.
I didn't want to be a star.
I wanted to show the star that I
am.
Am. You are secretly one little
you are secretly one little
bitch and that's why I love you
now.
Now.
But back then, bitch, I hated
but back then, bitch, I hated
you so much.
You so much.
And I was just like, I want to
and I was just like, I want to
send this bitch home so bad.
Send this bitch home so bad.
What is great about drag
what is great about drag
race, is even a melt down can be
turned in to a master piece.
Turned in to a master piece.
Take a listen to this bitch
take a listen to this bitch
track by Adam Joseph.
Track by Adam Joseph.
You are perfect.
You are beautiful, you are a
you are beautiful, you are a
model.
Model.
Oh, you are smiling Valentina
oh, you are smiling Valentina
your smile is beautiful.
Your smile is beautiful. ♪
♪
♪ ♪ hey.
Hey.
Coming up, shea puts Nina on
coming up, shea puts Nina on
blast.
Blast.
Someone came to my instagram
someone came to my instagram
and they said, Nina said that
you are a two-faced and you are
a fake.
A fake.
They were like, timestamp,
they were like, timestamp,
timestamp.
Timestamp. No.
No. And Kimora pops off.
- And Kimora pops off.
- You were talking.
You were talking
about the way I perform.
About the way I perform.
But you didn't say jk though.
Welcome back to "rupaul's"
welcome back to "rupaul's
drag race" reunited, my girls
"drag race" reunited, my girls
are back to let us have it.
Are back to let us have it.
Including this unforgettable
including this unforgettable
queen that can be described in
three simple words.
Three simple words.
Nina bonina brown, Robinson
Pete.
Pete. Ty a look.
Ty a look. You were a little bit
you were a little bit
difficult to work with
yesterday.
Yesterday.
My mind was set on black
my mind was set on black
China, and when it was given to
shea, I thought it was like a
set up.
Set up.
In a way, for me to like fail.
What we just heard was there
what we just heard was there
was a conspiracy theory that
sounded more like paranoia.
Sounded more like paranoia.
Girls are saying, she is not
girls are saying, she is not
original and she is not funny.
Original and she is not funny.
Who is saying that?
Who is saying that? You.
You. I don't play those games.
I don't play those games.
I have looked out for you and
defended you.
Defended you.
That hurts my feelings, I have
that hurts my feelings, I have
never done that.
Never done that.
Wow, Nina, do you still think
wow, Nina, do you still think
the queens are talking about you
behind your back?
Behind your back? A little bit.
A little bit. Sdm oh, girl.
Sdm oh, girl.
I mean, we all talk.
It's what queens do.
Did you see that the girls
did you see that the girls
were not trying to sabotage you?
Were not trying to sabotage you?
The camera does not see
the camera does not see
everything.
Everything.
None of us were out to get
none of us were out to get you.
You.
In fact, the only time and the
in fact, the only time and the
most I spoke about you with
other girls is, is Nina okay.
Other girls is, is Nina okay.
Why does she think we are coming
why does she think we are coming
for her?
For her?
She seems like she is giving up.
That's what was being said?
Is it possible that you
is it possible that you
imagined it?
Imagined it? No.
No. It's not possible?
It's not possible?
Girl, how many...
Well, then, yeah, let's talk
well, then, yeah, let's talk
about it.
About it.
Right now, I need you to call
right now, I need you to call
them out right now.
Them out right now.
We are here to talk about it.
Call who it is out.
Online, you did throw light
online, you did throw light
shade through shea coulee.
Shade through shea coulee.
You said that she was nice to
you said that she was nice to
you when the camera was on.
You when the camera was on.
The cameras were always on.
It's a reality show.
No, shea knows that I joke
no, shea knows that I joke
about her and stuff with people
online.
Online.
But sometimes the fans say
but sometimes the fans say
things and blow it out of
proportion.
Proportion.
They are timestamped and
they are timestamped and
someone came to my comments on
instagram and said, are you a
wear that she is saying you are
a two-faced and fake.
A two-faced and fake.
I said show receipts and they
were like, timestamp and
timestamp.
Timestamp.
You heard me say, I said you
you heard me say, I said you
are fake, for the game.
Are fake, for the game.
You are throwing me in the
you are throwing me in the
fire for fans that want drama.
Fire for fans that want drama.
I honestly...
Nina, I love you, but my
friends follow you and they are
like, she is live right now.
Like, she is live right now.
I peep through and you were on
my YouTube and you were talking
about the way I.
About the way I perform.
Perform. It was all jokes.
It was all jokes.
It was jokes, you would have
it was jokes, you would have
head ha, ha, jk.
Head ha, ha, jk. It was a joke.
It was a joke.
Girl, it's a joke.
Let's turn it around.
If you are saying, oh, I was
if you are saying, oh, I was
only joking with her... it could
be that what you saw was them
joking about you.
Joking about you.
Turn it around.
It hurt my feelings because I
it hurt my feelings because I
had nothing bad to saw about
you.
You.
When you talked to shea, shea
when you talked to shea, shea
gave you a platform to step up
and say something.
And say something.
You did not say who, so, we are
you did not say who, so, we are
here right now, reunion this,
who here of was talking [ Bleep
who here of was talking.
Nina call it out.
I'm going to stay quiet.
This is your platform.
Let's hear it.
Let's hear it. I'm good.
I'm good. We will watch it.
We will watch it. Okay.
Okay. You all know under the
you all know under the
pressure of the competition, it
is intense.
Is intense.
So, all of your inner demons
so, all of your inner demons
will come to the surface and try
to nip at you.
To nip at you.
And I will say this, Nina,
and I will say this, Nina,
too, in my career, the biggest
obstacles I have ever faced were
my own perceptions of myself.
My own perceptions of myself.
What I do is counter balance it
what I do is counter balance it
with positive voices that say,
bitch please, you are fabulous,
go for it.
Go for it.
Use what you got to get what you
use what you got to get what you
want.
Want.
Now, not everyone was upset
now, not everyone was upset
about the casting.
About the casting.
Alexis, you did a mean kris
jenner and I'm not the only one
who thinks so.
Who thinks so. Take a look.
Take a look. Hey, everyone.
Hey, everyone. Best season ever.
Best season ever.
And the best part was the
and the best part was the
Kardashian musical that I loved.
And Alexis Michelle, your kris
and Alexis Michelle, your kris
jenner was dope.
Jenner was dope.
So, have fun you guys and
so, have fun you guys and
congratulations.
Congratulations. Oh, my god!
Oh, my god! Oh, my god.
Oh, my god.
Kimora is ready to stab you.
Kimora is ready to stab you
in the throat right now.
In the throat right now.
Kimora, so jealous.
Don't take this moment from
don't take this moment from me.
Me. That's everything.
That's everything.
Y'all don't go away.
We have more queens when we come
we have more queens when we come
back.
Back. ♪ ♪
coming up, Alexis claps back at her
critics. Nobody canalexis Michelle
at her critics.
Nobody canalexis Michelle
nobody canalexis Michelle
like Alexis Michelle.
Like Alexis Michelle. ♪
♪
♪ welcome back to "rupaul's"
welcome back to "rupaul's
drag race" reunited.
"Drag race" reunited.
This year, our top five queens
this year, our top five queens
threw the gayest ball ever.
Threw the gayest ball ever.
But not everyone was feeling the
but not everyone was feeling the
sanity.
Sanity. Let's take a look.
Let's take a look.
Peppermint has a great
peppermint has a great
personality.
Personality.
She has a great personality.
Burkts her las... but her
burkts her las... but her
looks are not polished.
Looks are not polished.
Alexis needs to push her
aesthetics further.
Aesthetics further.
I feel like I can go to New York
and throw a stone and hit five
other queens that does what she
does.
Does. Sasha's rainbow look is.
Sasha's rainbow look is
pedestrian.
Pedestrian.
Shorts and a wife beater,
shorts and a wife beater,
really?
Really?
Does it look like a construction
does it look like a construction
worker?
Worker? No.
No. Who deserves to go home?
Who deserves to go home?
Alexis Michelle.
Alexis Michelle. Sasha velour?
Sasha velour? Alexis struggled.
Alexis struggled.
I would have to say Alexis as
well.
Well.
Interesting that they are not
interesting that they are not
supportive of my look right now
in front of the judges
considering they had nothing to
say to me about it in the work
room.
Room. Shady...
Shady...
Shea and Sasha, Alexis felt
shea and Sasha, Alexis felt
that you should have given
feedback, is it a given that you
all give each other feedback?
All give each other feedback?
No.
No. And, and to be realistic,
and, and to be realistic,
there was feedback that Trinity
was giving to you, Alexis, and I
did not see you accept or take
it on, so, for me in this
moment, I was just like, why
waste my breath.
Waste my breath.
You know, you were very much
you know, you were very much
committed to your vision and who
am I to sit here and tell you
not to follow your vision.
Not to follow your vision.
You know you are stubborn.
Don't you?
I do, I'm like a bulldog.
I want to say, shea, I do not
disagree with you, in that, I
did need to step up my forward
thinking eye.
Thinking eye.
But bitch I challenge you to
but bitch I challenge you to
find anybody that can do what I
do.
Do.
Nobody can do Alexis Michelle
nobody can do Alexis Michelle
like Alexis Michelle.
Like Alexis Michelle.
Sasha, Alexis thought your
look was pedestrian, what do you
think of that?
Think of that?
That is ironic, to my face,
that is ironic, to my face,
he was encouraging of the outfit
is what you accused us of doing.
Is what you accused us of doing.
What I was referring to was
what I was referring to was
the turtle neck and pencil
skirt, what makes Sasha Sasha is
how you put it together and make
it look elevated and artistic
with a message.
With a message.
You are back tracking now.
The competition was getting
the competition was getting
to me.
To me. It was.
It was.
Peppermint, how did you feel
peppermint, how did you feel
about Trinity saying that your
look was not polished?
Look was not polished?
She didn't say it to my face.
No, no, no, yes, I did, yes,
no, no, no, yes, I did, yes,
I did.
I did. I said, you need to pay
I said, you need to pay
attention to the details.
Attention to the details.
I did say that.
I felt like your garment was not
up to par to the rest of us.
Up to par to the rest of us.
I actually liked Alexis' outfit
more so than yours.
More so than yours. All right.
All right.
Now, shea, Trinity was not
now, shea, Trinity was not
feeling your construction worker
look.
Look.
How do you respond to that?
Well, bitch, you hoped me sew
well, bitch, you hoped me sew
it you shady [ Bleep
it you shady.
Sabotage, I think I look like a
sabotage, I think I look like a
construction worker,.
Construction worker,.
You do, all the time.
Let's take a look at some
let's take a look at some
never before seen moments with
our iconic guest judges.
Our iconic guest judges.
Listen, I know that you have
listen, I know that you have
got a plane to catch.
Got a plane to catch. Yeah.
Yeah. Sorry.
Sorry. So I have a ranged for a
so I have a ranged for a
ruber driver to take you to the
airport.
Airport. Oh.
Oh. It's a ruber black.
It's a ruber black.
Now, one more question about
now, one more question about
the essence chaps.
The essence chaps.
Have you ever worn them and are
have you ever worn them and are
you wearing them now?
You wearing them now?
I have worn them.
They are very freeing.
Feels really good.
Use that footage online.
And would you like to
and would you like to
re-enact it in the dressing
room.
Room. Done.
Done.
If she was able to figure out
if she was able to figure out
a way to lip sync without
moving, her faking was terrible.
Moving, her faking was terrible.
The make-up was no.
And the dress was no.
Remember shea and the peach
remember shea and the peach
pit and the maggots were in the
candy machine?
Candy machine? What?
What? You could put money in and
you could put money in and
get candy and it was filled with
maggots, I never got candy.
Maggots, I never got candy.
I was asking Carson if you
had a rib removed because you
are so tiny.
Are so tiny. Did you?
Did you?
Not yet, but that's on my
not yet, but that's on my list.
List. And when she the, she will
and when she the, she will
saute it in a peanut sauce.
Saute it in a peanut sauce.
Bitch, your nails.
Bitch, your nails. They are fun.
They are fun.
Definitely not lesbian
definitely not lesbian friendly.
Friendly.
Slicing... everywhere I go.
Um 22.
Um 22. I was born in '94.
I was born in '94. '94.
'94. I usually do not say it out
I usually do not say it out
loud, it's met with a...
Loud, it's met with a...
I will not make that noise, I
will just key your car in the
parking lot.
Parking lot.
Why can't everyone win?
Why can't everyone go?
We will all split the money.
Okay, done.
Don't go away, more fun to
don't go away, more fun to come.
Come. >>.
.♪
♪ ♪
♪ coming up, what?
Coming up, what?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, no, no,
wait, wait, wait, wait, no, no,
no.
No. ♪ ♪
♪ ♪.
.Welcome back to "rupaul's drag"
welcome back to "rupaul's drag
race" reunited.
"Race" reunited.
Lades, it's time to turn the
lades, it's time to turn the
tables and let each of you judge
each other.
Each other.
Oh, boy in a game we call toot
oh, boy in a game we call toot
or boot.
Or boot. Yes, yes.
Yes, yes.
If you like something, toot it
if you like something, toot it
if you don't, boot it.
If you don't, boot it.
All right, starting with Alexis
all right, starting with Alexis
Michelle's faux fur look.
Toot or boot?
Have to boot it, I'm sorry
have to boot it, I'm sorry
for the inconvenience.
For the inconvenience. Okay.
Okay. Aja toot or boot?
Aja toot or boot?
I have to boot it, your hat
looks like a hairy foreskin.
Looks like a hairy foreskin.
And that's a bad thing?
All right up next, is
all right up next, is
peppermint's look.
Peppermint's look. Toot or boot?
Toot or boot??
Super toot, she looks so
super toot, she looks so sweet.
Sweet. Valentina.
Valentina. Oh, peppermint.
Oh, peppermint. Oh.
Oh. Miss Trinity.
Miss Trinity.
An absolute toot, it will be
an absolute toot, it will be
the only toot I give peppermint
in the season, sorry, girl, but
I loved it.
I loved it. I will take it.
I will take it. All right, shea.
All right, shea.
It was initially a toot, but
it was initially a toot, but
seeing the way that she has sold
it as a nasty little lopy poll,
it turned in to a straight up
shoot.
Shoot. From a toot to a shoot?
From a toot to a shoot? Yeah.
Yeah. From a toot to a shoot.
From a toot to a shoot.
On to the next one, we have
on to the next one, we have
shea coulee's rainbow... toot or
boot?
Boot? Charlie hides is this.
Charlie hides is this.
It a boot for me, ru.
I don't see anything about it
that says rainbow.
That says rainbow.
It looks like a gay bird [ Bleep
it looks like a gay bird on her arm.
On her arm.
Up next, we have Sasha
up next, we have Sasha
velour's cowboy inspired look.
Velour's cowboy inspired look.
Eureka?
Being from east Tennessee
being from east Tennessee
where cowboys r on.
Where cowboys r on.
Roam and play, I like Sasha.
Shea.
Shea. I will have to say boot.
I will have to say boot.
Basically it's a dress form
basically it's a dress form
with a pin in the back.
With a pin in the back.
And I would have enjoyed to see
and I would have enjoyed to see
her step out of the box more and
challenge herself.
Challenge herself.
Let's go to Eureka's hair.
Let's go to Eureka's hair. Nina.
Nina.
She reminds me of a big match
she reminds me of a big match
that was lit.
That was lit.
So I want to say toot.
Toot or boot?
Toot, ru, I loved it.
Toot, ru, I loved it. Loved it.
Loved it.
She made a funny joke, and
she made a funny joke, and
delivered it beautifully.
Delivered it beautifully.
Give her a round of applause.
I'm so proud of you girl.
So, ladies, last toot or
so, ladies, last toot or boot.
Boot.
What do you think about the
what do you think about the
gorgeous chairs we are sitting
on from 2004 event.
On from 2004 event.
Because we have bills to pay.
They are perfect.
They are like Linda evangalista.
You are on a roll.
The moment we have been
the moment we have been
waiting for, which of the
bitches have the fans vod
congeniality?
Congeniality?
Cynthia, do you have any parting
words?
Words?
To all the fans of "rupaul's"
to all the fans of "rupaul's
drag race," it was a great and
"drag race," it was a great and
amazing experience.
Amazing experience.
Thank you for your love and
thank you for your love and
support.
Support.
Now, I have verified the
now, I have verified the
results and I promise you that
this election was not hacked by
the Russians.
The Russians.
The winners of Mr. congeniality,
the winners of Mr. congeniality,
season nine, is...
Season nine, is...
I'm so nervous.
I'm so nervous. Valentina.
Valentina. ♪ ♪
♪ ♪ hey!
Hey! Surprise.
Surprise. Awe.
Awe. >>
$5,000, courtesy of logo.
I dedicate this prize to my
mother.
Mother.
She taught me to be kind and
she taught me to be kind and
forgiving, so thank you to her
without her I would not even be
congenial.
Congenial. What?
What?
Wait, wait, wait, wait, no,
wait, wait, wait, wait, no,
no, no.
No, no.
Congenial, I don't want to be
congenial, I don't want to be
the one but I'm going to be the
one.
One. I just don't feel like you.
I just don't feel like you
I dedicate the prize to my
mother without her, I would not
even be congenial.
Even be congenial. What?
What?
Wait, wait, wait, I just don't
wait, wait, wait, I just don't
feel that you should be miss
congeniality.
Congeniality.
Do you have anything to say to
do you have anything to say to
respond to aja's claims?
Respond to aja's claims?
I have been kind to every one
of you.
Of you.
I will continue to be kind
towards success.
Towards success.
Can I say something?
Sure, go ahead.
Everyone else is.
You literally have not spoken
you literally have not spoken
to me in almost five months.
To me in almost five months.
And I miss my friend and it
and I miss my friend and it
hurts my feelings that you have
not spoken to me.
Not spoken to me.
I respect you and love you.
You don't love me.
I was a real friend to you.
You would not have just dropped
you would not have just dropped
me.
Me. You think that you want a
you think that you want a
friendship, text me, call me,
let's talk about it.
Let's talk about it.
I have texted you, you
ignored my texts.
Ignored my texts.
You finally responded when you
you finally responded when you
got eliminated, I texted you and
said, are you okay, and you said
let's talk about it.
Let's talk about it.
You don't seem to have time
you don't seem to have time
or desire.
Or desire.
You are clearly not focused
you are clearly not focused
on anything but yourself.
On anything but yourself.
Is it fan favorite or
is it fan favorite or
congeniality?
Congeniality?
Fan favorite, then she
fan favorite, then she
deserves it.
Deserves it.
Then we should call it fan
then we should call it fan
favorite.
Favorite.
But congeniality, I don't see.
Fan favorite, congratul
fan favorite, congratul
congratulations, let's make a
round of applause for fan
favorite.
Favorite. Fan favorite.
Fan favorite. Fan favorite.
Fan favorite.
All right, well the ladies
all right, well the ladies
have changed the title of the
award, but the cash is still in
U.S. currency.
U.S. currency. Thank you.
Thank you.
Wait, I have something to say
wait, I have something to say
too.
Too. Okay.
Okay. All right.
All right. Go ahead and say it.
Go ahead and say it. Yeah.
Yeah. Valentina on the show, I
Valentina on the show, I
thought you only thought about
yourself, which is partially
true.
True. What isn't true?
What isn't true?
But Farrah moan, shut up
but Farrah moan, shut up
already.
Already.
Regardless of what anybody
regardless of what anybody
thinks about you, you are fan
favorite.
Favorite.
And that's the true winner of
and that's the true winner of
the season.
The season.
You see what you did, girl?
All right, ladies, now it's
all right, ladies, now it's
time for major breaking news.
Time for major breaking news.
Next week, at the grand
next week, at the grand finale.
Finale.
For the first time in drag race
for the first time in drag race
history, the top four queens
will have to compete in a sudden
death lip sync smackdown for the
crown.
Crown.
This season proved that lip
this season proved that lip
syncs have never been more
important.
- Important.
- So ladies, don't it
so ladies, don't it up.
Up.
This is your last chance to let
this is your last chance to let
me know who you want crowned as
the next super star.
The next super star.
Get posting on all your social
get posting on all your social
media and let me know.
Media and let me know.
This is a finale you do not want
this is a finale you do not want
to miss.
To miss.
Lady it is thank you for
lady it is thank you for
making season nine the biggest
season ever and I will see
everyone here next week for the
grand finale of "rupaul's drag"
grand finale of "rupaul's drag
race."
Race."
Now, if you can't love yourself,
now, if you can't love yourself,
how in the hell you going to
love somebody else?
Love somebody else?
Can I get a... can I get an amen
can I get a... can I get an amen
up in here?
Up in here? Amen.
Amen. Okay, now, let's the music
okay, now, let's the music play.
Play. ♪ ♪