WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Aw, Jaymes.
- Oh, no,
the first lipstick message.
- I mean, Jaymes
was very insecure,
and she just wasn't sure
of herself.
And this is such
a high pressure competition,
you have to be sure
of yourself.
- You know,
the second she walked in,
I saw the fear in the eyes.
And I just saw her
get defeated.
- I honestly was really
surprised I was on the bottom.
Like,
I was really surprised.
I'm feeling so underdogged
because compared to Jaymes,
I was like a 10 to a one.
- How about you, Ms. Winner?
How are you feeling?
(cheering)
- I think you admittedly
have the least amount of
experience of all the queens
and you slayed.
- I'm very grateful,
but it's a lot of pressure.
So I'm very focused
to deliver to the next level
every single time.
- I'm really looking forward
to knocking you out
of your winner spot, okay?
(all laugh)
- Yes, she's won
a challenge. Whatever.
Her confidence
is definitely ballsy
for her only doing drag
for 10 months.
- Whoo!
- Is the bride sad
to take off her wedding dress?
- I really am.
- I'm not mad at you for that.
I understand.
- I've been praying so hard
to La Virgen de Guadalupe
and I feel like she's been
guiding me through it.
- It's not fun
being the bridesmaid.
I want to be the bride.
I'm not here to play games.
The next challenge is mine.
- The winner
of "RuPaul's Drag Race"
receives a one-year supply
of Anastasia Beverly Hills
cosmetics
and a cash prize
of $100,000.
With extra special
guest judges
Todrick Hall
and Cheyenne Jackson.
- ♪ "RuPaul's Drag Race" ♪
- ♪ May the best woman ♪
- ♪ Best woman win ♪
- Here were are again.
- It's today.
(all laugh)
- ♪ Ah... ♪
I'm coming off this high
of having won.
The first queen has gone home,
and it feels great.
It feels exactly
like I thought it would.
Okay, guys, after, like,
the gymnastic challenge,
what to expect?
- I'm still sore
from cheerleading.
- Girl.
- So I'm hoping
it's not anything physical.
- A knitting challenge.
(all laugh)
(siren)
- Whoo, girl!
She done already done
had herses.
- Oh, my God, oh, my God,
oh, my God.
- To become America's
next drag superstar,
you have to try on
a lot of glass slippers,
kiss a bunch of frogs,
but don't be an evil queen.
That role
has already been taken.
(evil laugh)
Hello, hello, hello.
(cheers and applause)
- Hello, Ru.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Just a little
leopard print.
- Now, what
do you guys think
of the wax figure of me
on loan from Madame Tussauds?
- Gorgeous.
- I pray to her
before a challenge.
- Really?
- Yeah.
- Don't you love
the way her eyes
follow you around the room?
It's almost like there's
a hidden camera in there.
- (gasps)
- Watching your every move.
Maybe there is.
- Oh!
- Ladies, don't let this
devastatingly beautiful queen
cast an evil spell
on your charisma,
uniqueness, nerve and talent.
Because for this week's
maxi challenge,
you need to create a totally
original fairytale princess.
- I have no problem
picturing myself
as a princess.
I'm a jappy girl
who likes nice things.
- First, you'll come up
with a memorable name
and a mythology.
Then you'll need to design
a fantasy frock
to debut on the main stage.
#DragPrincess
And to help you bring
your princess story to life,
you'll also be creating
a sassy sidekick.
- Rawr.
- And you'll be playing
both parts.
- What? We have create
a little sidekick
to have our heads
floating by our character.
This is nuts.
Who thinks of this?
- So, Cinderfellas, feel free
to use the magical materials
from the Fabric Planet wall.
Gentlemen, start your engines
and may the best woman win.
(cheers and applause)
- Whoo!
- Ooh. How are you feeling
about this challenge, girl?
- I feel like I have
the new age mindset
to kind of like make this
extremely avant-garde
and high fashion.
- Mm-hmm.
- So I feel like I might
have this one in the bag.
It's a design challenge,
and I sew 80%--
no, 95% of everything I wear,
so I'm known for
creating different looks,
and I feel really confident
that this might be my challenge.
- What the fuck
am I doing?
I do not sew.
I've only made tote bags
and pillows.
No.
- Are you okay?
- I'm gonna just try
and make something mermaid-y,
something under-watery.
- I'm doing
under the water, too.
- Are you doing a fish?
- I was gonna do a mermaid,
but then, like, I was like,
there's too many people
doing under the water stuff.
- Great.
- Yeah.
I don't--
Yeah, I'm terrified.
- Ooh. What's this
that you got here, Kimora?
- I'm going to be, obviously,
Tarzan's other wife.
- How are you feeling about
going into this challenge?
You were in the bottom two
last week.
- And you don't sew.
- I know.
I don't sew.
I like to pay designers
to make my stuff.
I'm your very spoiled
drag queen.
Would Kim K.
sew her own outfits? No.
- Well, if you pay designers
to do your stuff,
how much will you pay me
to make your challenge?
- I mean,
I have $400 right now.
- I'll see
if I have some time.
- I don't work
in a sweatshop.
That's not
what I signed up for.
This is not America's
Next Top Sweatshop.
- Where you gonna put this?
Like, on your shoulder?
- I just got the rat
for show.
- Just because.
- I don't even really want it.
- Can I have it?
- Yeah, take it, girl.
- Thank you.
I think with this challenge,
I'm wanting to show
that I'm not afraid
to go in a risky direction.
- What is all these
cockroaches, girl?
- That's for my look.
- What are you doing?
- Like, sewer
underground princess.
Like, very grungy
and gross kind of.
Have, like, some kind of shit
growing off of my face
and, like, very sewer rat.
- I have never heard
of a sewage princess
in my entire life.
What kind of princess
is that?
Here we go.
Better watch out, because
the judges don't play around.
She could go home.
- Thank you for the rat.
- You're welcome.
- Come on, Templeton.
- Aah!
- Coming up...
You came very close
to winning last week.
- Ms. Thang, she won.
She better watch out.
Fuck that bitch!
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- What's the story?
- Once upon a time....
- ♪ Ahh ♪
- There was
a beautiful princess.
- For this challenge,
we have to create
a fantasy fairytale princess
and a sassy sidekick.
Oh, my God, Trinity,
you've never looked
more beautiful
than you do right now.
- You're a bitch.
You're such a bitch.
- (laughs)
- So what are you going for?
You're going for, like,
sea princess?
- My whole
Instagram branding
is based on the fact that
I ride the subway to my gig.
- Okay, yes.
- So I'm Princess Subway Fish.
- We were given the brief
to come up with
a mythological background story
for our princesses.
- Introducing
Princess Forella.
- Someday,
she'll be the most...
What's an adjective?
What is an adjective?
Isn't an adjective
where you, like...
That's a noun.
- It's a word
that describes something.
- Like, what do you mean?
- You're beautiful.
"Beautiful" is an adjective.
- So beautiful
is the adjective.
- Mm-hmm.
- I'm going to put delicious.
Is that an adjective?
Yeah, that's
a super adjective.
- Come on, English lessons.
- Ah, thank God I'm pretty.
- Hey, kitty girls.
- Hey.
- Hello.
- So how are things going
in the magic queendom?
- Great.
- Good.
Hi, Farrah Moan.
- Ru!
- Rrrru!
- What kind of princess
will you be in this challenge?
- She's gonna be
an underwater socialite.
She's gonna be, like,
on all the underwater tabloids.
- Oh, okay.
Now, do you sew?
- I'm smart
in a lot of other ways,
but when it comes to fabrics
and needles and stuff,
I'm just not as, uh...
uh, what's the word?
- Proficient.
- Proficient, yeah.
- It's Season 9.
How do you walk
into the workroom
without knowing how to sew?
That's just sad.
- How will you make sure
that you shine through?
- Um...I'm just going to be
my cute little self
and pray to your
wax figurine over there
that y'all like it.
- Okay.
Can't wait to see her.
Thanks, Farrah.
- Thank you so much.
- Aja from the BK.
- Ah, Ru-Ru.
- Now, you know how to sew,
so you got lots of skills.
- Yes.
- So tell me
about your princess.
- Her name is Disastah.
She is a volcanic eruption,
basically.
She's kind of inspired
by my mom.
She's like an angry
Puerto Rican woman.
- Really.
- I have a tattoo of her.
It's right here.
- That's your mother.
- Yes.
When she got mad,
you see the red come up
and her baby hairs
will start crimpling up.
It's like an eruption, girl.
- Now, how are you
gonna shine?
- I just feel
so confident about it.
I'm just like, I'm gonna do this
and it's gonna be cute.
- You know
I've heard that before.
Well, I can't wait
to see Disastah.
I'll let you get to it.
Valentina.
- I'm ready for my close-up,
Mr. DeMille.
- Oh, my goodness.
Can I see your eyes?
- Um, well,
you see, the thing is,
it's my very first time
shaving my brows,
and I'm kind of like nervous
because I don't have
my Brooke Shields
"Blue Lagoon" eyebrows.
- Oh! Oh, my goodness,
look at there.
Why don't you just
shave them all off?
- Well, because I want to still
have a bit of boy brow to draw.
- Uh-huh.
- So that I don't look
completely crazy.
- Why are we looking at me
when you said that?
(laughs)
Okay, so I want to hear
about your princess.
- She's an ice princess.
She comes from planet Azula.
- And that's nowhere near
Azusa, is it?
- Not anywhere near
Azusa, California.
- Yeah. (laughs)
- I have a big imagination,
and I'm really excited
to get started.
- See you out there.
- Thanks, Ru.
- Trinity Taylor.
Now tell me
about your princess.
What's her name?
- Farella Aquapussy.
- She sounds juicy.
And salty.
- I kind of like it.
- I do, too.
- So tell me
about her sidekick.
- Well, her sidekick
is Stanky the Starfish.
And I was going to go with,
you know, a chocolate starfish.
- Uh-huh.
- But I decided, you know,
kids want
bright colors, so...
- Kids don't know
they want a chocolate starfish
until they've had
a chocolate starfish.
- Oh, right.
- You know?
- I love chocolate starfish.
- Are you kidding? I live
for chocolate starfishes.
But this is not
a chocolate starfish.
What kind of a starfish
is this?
- Well, he's going to be
a country starfish.
- Like from Cracker Barrel?
(both laugh)
Now, you came very close
to winning last week.
Any bitterness there?
- No. I came close,
but you know what?
I do know that Ms. Thang,
she won.
Even though
she's been doing drag
a whole lot less than me,
she's younger than me,
Fuck that bitch.
- (laughs)
- She better watch out.
- Okay.
- 'Cause Aquapussy
is coming.
- Well, I can't wait
to see Aquapussy
out there on that runway.
- Me, too.
- (laughs)
All right, ladies.
Tomorrow on the main stage,
you'll be debuting
your fairytale princesses.
So good luck
and don't fuck it up!
- I don't want to do this.
I don't know.
This is hard.
I don't know what I'm doing.
I just really want
whatever I make
to look good enough
to be safe,
because I know
I'm not going to pump out
no award-winning
mermaid gown, honey.
I just don't even know
where to begin.
- Why don't you find a glue gun
and your bra and work on that?
- You know, I kind of pictured
gluing fabric on a bra
being a lot easier.
This is, like,
complicated as fuck.
Like, I don't want to have
to cut any piece of fabric
and put it over this.
- No, you're not.
- This one won't fit.
I can't get it to fit over.
Look.
- It's okay. Move.
Sometimes you just
gotta jump in, girl.
- Oh, I love you.
- I love Farrah
and she's my bestie,
but she literally sounds
like a child all the time.
It would make
the world of difference
if she would just
stop bitching and do it.
Just do it, girl.
Don't be afraid
of hot glue, bitch.
You a drag queen.
So what I would suggest
you do
is, like, glue shit all
the way up this one side.
I'm going to give you
this base to work with,
and then I'm gonna
let you go shell from there.
Find, like,
your shiny stuff, seashells.
- Oh, I broke a piece
of this starfish.
- Farrah
is one of those princesses
that whines all the time.
Suck it up.
This is a competition.
We're here to compete
for $100,000.
One minute you're in and the
next minute, you're gone, honey.
- Coming up...
- Are you afraid of what
America is going to think
of your makeup
without face tone?
- Nope, 'cause I think
I look almost the same.
- Awkward silence.
(RuPaul laughs, bell rings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Oh, my God.
- Get to work.
- Here we go.
- Back here again.
- Good morning, cucu world.
- (laughs)
- It's elimination day.
I'm nervous,
but I'm also excited
about my fairytale princess
outfit.
I'm about to give them
Sewer Princess.
- So when you say cucu,
is like the hole
or is it like the butt?
'Cause
I'm a little confused.
- You know, it can be,
like, the butthole,
but let me explain
the story real quick.
When I was a child,
mom doesn't want us
to say bad words at home.
So one day,
I was three years old,
trying to tell her that
I need to go to the bathroom
'cause I need to
from my culo to go ca-ca.
She slapped me
with a chancleta.
She said, like, mira mijo,
let me tell you something.
You're not gonna say bad word
here in this house!
So I was, like, scared.
I was, like, what to do?
I mean, what do you call this
in your back?
So scared one day
after that situation,
I said, cucu, mama,
ca-ca, pee-pee. Okay.
And since that,
I say cucu.
- So do I have
a big cucu, too?
- Girl, you do.
Well, I have a cucu,
but you have a CuCu, girl!
- Oh, it feels so good
to have these brows back.
- I see you had
an eyebrow lift.
- Just a little.
- Are you afraid of what
America is going to think
of your makeup
without face tone?
- Nope, 'cause I think
I look almost the same.
- Awkward silence.
- Everybody can get quiet, but I
think I look the same in photos.
- Sometimes girls
that come up via social media
can get a lot of praise
for the way they
present themselves online.
You got your filters.
You got your Facetune.
You got all that.
However, it's how
you apply that makeup,
because sometimes when
people see you in person,
they can get a little bit
disappointed.
- So, Trinity,
when you were in Orlando
when that situation happened,
like, were you freaked out?
I mean,
I know you're from there.
Yeah.
- Um, I actually wasn't
in Orlando at that very moment,
but I'm a very former
Miss Pulse.
- (gasps)
- And I entertained there
literally the week before
on their Latin night,
'cause that happened
on their Latin night.
So it's scary
to think, like,
that literally
could have been me.
And so immediately
my thought is...
- Call your friends,
I'm sure.
- Oh, my God, who do I know?
- Did you lose
a lot of people, Trinity?
- Well, I didn't know
any of the people
that actually
lost their lives.
I knew several
of the entertainers
that were trapped in
the dressing room that escaped.
A lady that I worked with
in my day job,
one of her daughters had just
graduated nursing school.
And then
her life was taken over...
- Oh, my God.
- Like, for no reason.
- I'm so sorry, girl.
- Well, let me tell you
a story about the tragedy.
- I know you know--
you probably knew
a lot of them
because they were...
- June 11, I was supposed
to perform that night,
but I have to reschedule.
So Kenya Michaels, that is
the cast director that night,
she said, like,
it's okay, mija.
We can, like,
reschedule you.
And then, like, we were
performing in Houston
and we get, like,
the text message.
Like, oh, my God,
we are here in the bathroom.
We can't do anything.
There's a guy with a gun,
like, shooting everybody.
And I'm like, oh, my God,
are you serious?
And, unfortunately,
one of my friends
died in that incident,
Martin.
And he was, like--
I'm like
two or three hours before,
like, Cynthia,
you're not here.
You're supposed
to have a show.
That's why
I came here tonight.
And I'm like, baby.
- Oh, Cynthia.
- No, no, no.
I just rescheduled.
Oh. Do you want to go home?
And he was like,
no, you know what?
I'm going to stay.
I'm going to have a cute time.
I miss you so much.
And he was
one of my first dancers,
like, 10 years ago
when I started doing drag.
So it was a very traumatic
situation for everybody.
We never expect that
a tragedy like this
happen in our community
or happen in our clubs
because we thought
that we finally built
a safe place
for our community.
- We are not safe
completely yet,
and we're not
accepted 100% yet.
But we have to continue
to live our lives.
We can't be stuck in our houses
and afraid to go out and live.
- Preach, girl. Preach!
- What happened in Orlando
at Pulse Nightclub
was a defining and shocking
moment for gay people.
And the fact that
it was an act of violence
against LGBT people of color
is not insignificant here.
- Family, famo.
- Love you, girls.
- Family.
- It's so important as queer
entertainers to lead the way.
We need to come together
and be proudly visibly queer.
- And you know what?
Also, drag
is a brilliant place
to work through
feelings of pain.
- Girl, drag is therapy.
- It is.
- We can't move backwards.
We need to stay strong.
(RuPaul laughs)
- ♪ Cover girl,
put the bass in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
- At what?
- Welcome to the main stage
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
Look, it's my wicked
stepsister Michelle Visage.
- Always the wicked stepsister,
never the bride.
- Style superstar
Carson Kressley.
Hi-ho.
- Hi, ho!
It's off to work
with the Q we go.
- (laughs)
The prince of YouTube,
actor, singer, director
Todrick Hall.
- Hi, Ru. You left your
glass slipper in my bedroom.
- It's a size 12, right?
- Exactly.
- And the fairest in all
the land, Cheyenne Jackson.
- Serving you butch queen
since '75.
(all laugh)
- So glad you're here.
This week,
we challenged our queens
to bring their princess
fantasies to life,
and tonight,
they're bringing it to the ball.
Gentlemen,
start your engines
and may the best woman win.
Coming up...
- I literally
had no clue at all
what was going on tonight.
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Category is...
First up,
Cynthia Lee Fontaine,
Princess Cuculina.
- Hi, my name is Brulee.
I'm here to protect
Princess Cuculina
from any booty slap
and to show her that she can
bring peace, love and sex
to all the entire universe.
My advice is a happy cucu
is one that is clean for others.
- One in the pink?
(all laugh)
Peppermint,
Princess Carcinogenetta.
- My name
is Petey the Pilot Light
and I'm flaming.
I live to help make her dream
of fire unsafety come true.
My advice to her is simple.
Burn, baby, burn.
Rawr.
- Oh, it's not just her pussy
that's on fire.
(Michelle laughs)
- Farrah Moan,
Princess Pacifica.
- Well, it's the snatch
of the day.
- My name
is Fablina the blowfish.
I'm Princess Pacifica's
royal publicist.
When I first met
Princess Pacifica,
she was abusing
her royal privileges
by partying from the Atlantic
to the Pacific.
I'm here to protect her
from the grueling sharkarazzi
and transform her reputation
from swampy socialite
to responsible princess
of the Pacific.
- Charlie Hides,
Princess Climaxica.
- My name
is Isabella Snatchpacker,
and I'm Princess Climaxica's
lady in waiting.
I first met
Princess Climaxica
when she was studying languages
at Galaxy University.
Oh, she just loves
foreign tongue.
She's a cunning linguist,
you know.
I'm here to protect her from
bad puns and double entendres.
How am I doing?
- Copper? I hardly know her.
(all laugh)
- Eureka,
Princess You-Reek-of-Daria.
- Here comes
Princess You-Reek-of-Daria
from the sewer kingdom.
I am her faithful servant
Woof-train.
The princess
was kicked out of topland.
The army banned her
to reign only in the sewers.
I live to help make her dreams
of being on the top a reality.
- Alexis Michelle,
Princess #SubwayFish.
- My name is #SubwayTadpole,
Princess SubwayFish's
chief swimmer.
We met for the first time
when Princess SubwayFish
was taking the train to her gig.
Whenever she bugging, I just
tell her, just keep fishing.
- Aw, don't be so crabby.
- There's a cream for that.
- Kimora Blac,
Princess Banana Lady.
- My name is Funky Monkey,
Banana Lady's cute bodyguard
from Banana Kingdom.
I am here to protect her
from all the big bad jungle men
with small bananas.
I love to help her
make her dream
of banana digging come true.
She is so rich,
she got all the bananas
she's ever wanted.
- Nina Bo'nina
Brown-Pinkett-Smith,
Princess Zathena.
- My name is Ink.
I knew Princess Zathena
back when she was
a little hard-headed Martian.
She was always the wild one
of the bunch,
wanting to breed
with the human race.
I'm here to teach her
to love who she is.
You are from the planet
Bad Bitch Uranium,
so you have to represent
for the bad bitches.
- I actually had a bad batch
of Uranium once.
(Michelle laughs)
I sold it to the Russians.
- I remember that day.
- Sasha Velour,
Princess Uglina.
- Where my birds at?
(RuPaul laughs)
- My name is Lunk
from Self Doubtia.
I'm Princess Uglina's
imaginary friend.
It was I
who trapped her in a cage,
filling her mind with
self doubt and weakness.
But Princess Uglina
wasn't scared of me.
She embraced my darkness
and showed me love,
so I opened the cage
and I set her free.
- Shea Coulee,
Princess Aquaria.
- My name is Moon Pearl,
Princess Aquaria's
ice fairy from Uranus.
Princess Aquaria was born in
the battle for love and freedom
when her star mother fused
with the Queen Moon Diamond.
Whenever she's feeling lost,
I remind her
that her guiding star
lives within
and that she holds the key
to unlock it.
She'll be the most sickening
princess in the universe.
- Why don't you come up
and seaweed me sometime?
No? No?
Valentina, Princess Vira.
- Where is Vira's wang?
- My name is Netty,
Princess Vira's shady godmother.
I live
to help make her dream
of freezing over the universe
via shade come true.
My advice is simple:
hate everyone.
Someday
she'll be the shadiest,
most evilest queen of all
and live
hatefully ever after.
- Aja, Princess Disastah.
- I almost wore
that same outfit today, so...
- Did you?
- Yep.
- My name is Dasistah,
and I am Princess Disastah's
smoke cloud.
I live to make
her dreams come true
of coal mining
and becoming a gold digger.
Someday she'll be
the most ashy princess
and she'll live
flamingly ever after.
- Orange you glad
you got fire insurance?
(Michelle chuckles)
- Trinity Taylor,
Princess Aquapussy. Oh.
- Oh, surf and turf.
- My name
is Stanky the Starfish,
the royal redneck counselor.
We first met
when the princess
was in the waterland clinic
hitting her itch cream.
It was for her outbreak,
clam-idia.
I hope that someday
she can find the cure
for this WTD.
That stands for
water transmitted disease.
- (laughs)
Ooh, pass the tartar sauce.
(all laugh)
- Coming up...
- I'm no seamstress,
but that looks like
a piece of fabric
around your waist.
- Your sidekick
had no personality.
- Fucking go for it.
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Welcome, ladies.
When I call you name,
please step forward.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine,
Charlie Hides,
Eureka,
Alexis Michelle,
Sasha Velour,
Nina Bo-nina Brown,
Shea Coulee.
Ladies, you're safe.
You may leave the stage.
Ladies, you represent
this week's
beauties and the beasts.
- Oh.
- Let's hear
from the judges,
starting with Peppermint.
- I just liked the way you
created this kind of fire idea.
I think the details
on the dress are impressive.
- I loved
Petey the Pilot Light.
- Thank you.
When I was a teenager,
I was cooking at home alone
and the entire kitchen
caught on fire,
and I've been deathly afraid
of fire since.
So I said,
let me do something
that's going to tackle
my fear.
- Only you
can prevent grease fires.
- (laughs)
- Next up, Farrah Moan.
- Every year,
Ru and Michelle tell people
you cannot come out here
with a piece of fabric
wrapped around your waist.
And I'm no seamstress,
but that looks like
a piece of fabric
wrapped around your waist.
- The sidekick, the eye make-up
thing was distracting
'cause to me, it looked like
you were reading a script that
was maybe down in your hands.
- I was.
- Oh, see?
- I was just kind of let down
with the character.
Like, this is your chance,
so fucking go for it.
- Up next, Kimora Blac.
- Hello.
- You didn't really sell me
on what your princess is.
For me,
that was a little lacking.
- And then
your sidekick was robotic
and really
had no personality.
- You seemed like
you just couldn't wait
for it to get over.
- For so long,
I've been hiding behind
a breastplate and padding.
I'm pretty known
for my butt,
and I've been padding
for so long
that I'm kind of
uncomfortable again.
And it's been hard.
- Thank you, Kimora Blac.
- Thank you.
- Up next, Valentina.
- I wrote down
Linda Evangelista.
The smoky eye
and the nude lip, I like it.
(RuPaul laughs)
- This outfit
is really gorgeous,
and your sidekick,
I loved that it was about
shade and ice.
- Because oftentimes,
evil people
come in beautiful packages,
as we see every day.
- Oh, my God.
- (laughs)
- Thank you, Valentina.
- Gracias.
- Next up, Aja.
- I literally
had no clue at all
what was going on tonight
with your story
as your princess.
- She's a volcano,
she's from Brooklyn,
she's from bad side,
she's banji.
She's just going to the club
to go hang out with
her little clouds and stuff.
- Did anybody get that?
- No.
I think that even if
you wanted to be banji,
there was a way to do it
and have it just be
slightly more polished.
- I also think that
your makeup is very dark.
- Yeah, we can't really
see your eyes.
- And it's been kind of dark
this whole journey.
- Up next, Trinity Taylor.
Princess Aquapussy.
- When I first
heard your name,
I just kept thinking
of James Bond...
(imitating Sean Connery)
like Princess Aquapussy.
(all laugh)
- You know,
I loved this look.
I thought that
from a fashion standpoint,
that this is really fun.
And then you showed us
your starfish.
- Itch cream.
- You come across to me
as pageant girl,
so seeing you do
something like Stanky
is just going to bode
really well for you.
Keeping with that comedy
is a good road
for you to go down.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, my pretties.
I think we've heard enough.
While you untuck backstage,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
All right. Now, just between
us wicked stepmothers,
what do you think,
starting with Peppermint?
- Peppermint made me
very, very happy tonight.
The minute she stepped onstage,
you knew what she was selling.
- I love when someone
takes an inanimate object
and makes a character
out of it.
- She used something that
wasn't a really good memory
and turned it into a plus.
I thought
it was very smart.
Farrah Moan.
- Obviously, she's gorgeous,
but there was no presence.
It was just
a huge, giant mess.
- Her blowfish,
it was a great idea,
but I left
a little unsatisfied.
It just--that closed eye thing
didn't work.
I was more distracted by it
than I was entertained.
- I have a secret to tell you.
- What?
- My eyes have been closed
the whole show.
(Michelle laughs)
- What?
- Kimora Blac.
- Funky Monkey.
It was like that
Teen Miss USA pageant
who said, most US Americans
of the Korea
or the South Africa...
- It was hard to watch,
I have to say.
- I think we all need
to take a moment
to talk about
the bravest struggle of all,
coming out here and telling us
about her struggle...
- Her struggle.
- With not wearing hip pads.
- Not wearing hip pads?
My God!
Can you be alive
and still be made a saint?
- No, but I think
we can make arrangements.
- (laughs)
Valentina.
- Three for three.
Each episode, you look at her
and we've gotten
to this point
where we can't wait to see
what she looks like
because she's
so frigging beautiful,
we all just want to go up
and lick her face.
- Both of her characters
were stunning
as far as presentation.
- And I have to say,
I was really surprised
with her comedy.
I thought
she really went there.
- Aja.
- Aja definitely chose
the right name:
Princess Disastah.
- (laughs)
- Because that was an epic
proportion earthquake.
- I don't understand why
the chaps with the volcano.
- Well, the costume
didn't say volcano.
It said Heat Miser.
- (laughs)
- She's charming,
but it was a hot lava mess.
- Trinity Taylor.
- I liked the whole look.
It's very Kooky Sue.
- And then Stanky the Starfish
was a great counterpart.
- Clam-idia.
- It made me
so frigging happy.
I couldn't stop laughing.
- And I also feel that she
interacted with her character
more so
than all the other girls.
- Really, it can just be
summed up by one word.
- What's that?
- (imitating Sean Connery)
Aquapussy.
- Silence.
I've made my decision.
Bring back my girls.
(RuPaul laughs, bell dings)
(RuPaul laughs)
- Welcome back, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Peppermint...
You're safe.
- Thank you.
- Kimora Blac.
The judges were not a fan of
your banana.
I'm sorry, my dear, but you
are up for elimination.
- This is the worst feeling
in the world.
It sucks to be here again.
- Trinity Taylor.
You wished upon a starfish
and your dreams came true.
Con-drag-ulations.
You're the winner
of this week's challenge.
- Aah!
(applause)
- You've won a $2,000 gift card
from Casper.
- Thank you.
- You may join
the other girls.
- Girl, I finally won
my first challenge.
I have arrived,
and these other girls
need to watch out.
- Valentina, your ice princess
was totally hot.
You're safe.
- Thank you.
- Farrah Moan.
I hate to burst
your bublina,
but your blowfish blew.
Aja, the judges did not lava
your princess storyline.
Aja, I'm sorry, my dear,
but you're up for elimination.
- I feel confused.
I definitely think Farrah
should be in the bottom two,
not me.
- Farrah Moan, you may join
the other girls.
- Thank you, guys.
(sobs)
- Two queens
stand before me.
Ladies, this is your last chance
to impress me
and save yourself
from elimination.
The time has come
to lip sync
(echoing) for your life!
Good luck,
and don't fuck it up.
(music plays)
- ♪ Doo doo doo ♪
♪ Ah ♪
♪ Where have all
the good men gone ♪
♪ And where
are all the gods? ♪
♪ Where's the streetwise
Hercules ♪
♪ To fight
the rising odds? ♪
♪ Isn't there a white knight
upon a fiery steed? ♪
♪ Late at night
I toss and I turn ♪
♪ And I dream
of what I need ♪
♪ I need a hero ♪
♪ I'm holding out for a hero
till the end of the night ♪
♪ He's gotta be strong
and he's gotta be fast ♪
♪ And he's gotta be
fresh from the fight ♪
♪ I need a hero ♪
♪ I'm holding out for a hero
till the morning light ♪
♪ He's gotta be sure
and it's gotta be soon ♪
♪ And he's gotta be
larger than life ♪
♪ Up where the mountains
meet the heavens above ♪
♪ Out where the lightning
splits the sea ♪
♪ I could swear there
is someone, somewhere ♪
♪ Watching me ♪
♪ Through the wind
and the chill and the rain ♪
♪ And the storm
and the flood ♪
♪ I can feel his approach
like a fire in my blood ♪
- ♪ Like a fire
in the blood ♪
♪ Like a fire
- ♪ I need a hero ♪
♪ I'm holding out for a hero
till the end of the night ♪
♪ I need a hero ♪
(cheers and applause)
- Ladies,
I've made my decision.
Aja, shantay, you stay.
(applause)
- Work, girl.
- You may join
the other girls.
- Thank you so much.
- You did that, bitch.
- Kimora Blac,
you bravely bared your soul
and your ass.
- (chuckles)
- Stay strong, sister.
Now sashay away.
- Love you guys.
- We love you.
(cheers and applause)
- I'm pretty.
(laughs)
I'm a little surprised.
It's too early for me.
The judges hated my monkey.
I hated that monkey, too.
I think
what I would do differently
is to research
on how to be a monkey,
'cause that is something
that I would never think
I would do in my entire life.
But I did my best,
and I looked gorgeous.
And I want to be known
as one of the pretty ones.
- Con-drag-ulations,
my queens.
Now, remember,
if you can't love yourself,
how in the hell
you gonna love somebody else?
Can I get an amen
up in here?
- Amen.
- All right.
Now, let the music play.
- ♪ Everyone can be someone
if you want to ♪
♪ I can show you ♪
♪ Be someone ♪