WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Previously
on RuPaul's Drag Race...
You will create
your own TV pilot.
-Oh!
-Action.
- See you next Tuesday.
- [Russian accent]
At midnight, motherfucker.
[both laugh]
- We're gonna play off
each other's adlibbing.
- Oh, you're gonna adlib?
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- We need to become
drag queens!
- [laughs] Okay.
- Do you think maybe
a script would have helped?
- The clever wordplay
and the writing
I do think came from me.
- I have to speak up
right now.
That is not the case.
- Sasha Velour,
Shea Coulee,
you're the winner
of this week's challenge.
Valentina
and Nina Bo'nina Brown,
you are up for elimination.
Stop. Hold up, hold up.
Valentina, this is
a lip sync for your life.
We need to see your lips.
Take that thing
off of your mouth.
- I'd like
to keep it on, please.
- It's a lip sync.
What part of that
do you not understand?
Nina Bo'nina Brown,
shantay, you stay.
Valentina, sashay away.
- Girl.
- What just happened?
- Valentina
was just eliminated,
and we are all shocked.
- "I love you
with all of my heart.
Kisses."
- Oh, Valentina.
- I'm so stunned, though.
I don't know
what got into her head.
- But that being said,
Nina, you earned that.
Not only
did you know the words,
you like
put on a fun show.
-Come on, Nina.
-Go, Nina.
[chanting] Nina! Nina! Nina!
- Yeah, I mean, it was cute.
I did what I had to do.
But for me, this is, like,
not, like, a happy moment.
I feel horrible.
I feel bad
because I feel like maybe
if she wasn't
in the group with me,
she probably
would still be here.
-No.
-No, Nina.
- You can't take that on,
girl.
That ain't your fault.
- Oh, my God.
Not again.
- I'm just saying,
hear me out, y'all--
before y'all curse me out,
the negative one is still here
and the positive one--
- But, Nina,
we're rooting for you.
The way you just fought,
that was beautiful.
- Yeah, but I just feel bad.
- It's tough
being in the bottom,
but is there
a little piece of you
that feels victorious
after this?
- No.
I can't explain it.
- Can we stop talking
about this, actually?
-This is--
-Sorry,
I'm not having
this conversation.
I love you.
That's all I have to say.
I've never heard of that
in any situation in humanity.
I need to make you feel good
about the fact
that you did a great job?
So I'm not gonna do it.
Bitch, snap
the fuck out of it.
- I guess I don't really care,
that's the thing, like I should,
but I don't.
I'm not asking
for anybody to go, like,
oh, Nina, it's okay.
I mean, that's
what they chose to do.
- We've asked ourselves
how many times
did we try
to snap her out of this,
and the answer is it's over.
- These conversations
are not helping her, clearly.
It may even
be doing more damage.
This is not group therapy.
This is a competition.
We just cannot
fight for her
in a way that she's not willing
to fight for herself.
I'm tired of spending
all of our time
together as a group
trying to build someone up
who doesn't want to hear it.
I am over it.
- That doesn't mean
we don't support Nina,
but it's time to move on.
I'm over it, I'm over it,
I'm over it.
She needs to go home.
No, no, no.
I'm over it.
[car engine starts]
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
- The winner
of RuPaul's Drag Race
receives a one year supply
of Anastasia Beverly Hills
cosmetics
and a cash prize
of $100,000.
With extra special
guest judges
Emmy nominated designed
Zaldy
and Kesha.
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
- ♪ May the best woman ♪
- ♪ Best woman win ♪
-Oh.
-Another day.
-We're back.
-Whoo!
- Top six, bitches.
Yes.
- Hello, hello, hello.
[cheers and applause]
- It's Ru.
- Now, in the past,
I've challenged my queens
to do some
pretty special makeovers.
Gay veterans,
Stonewall heroes,
and Little Women,
just to name a few.
But this season
promises to be the most
extra special one of all.
And we don't have to look
any further
than just behind the camera.
For this week's
maxi challenge,
you'll be giving
our beloved crew members
the chance to strut a mile
in your shoes...
[laughter and screaming]
In a makeover sponsored by
Anastasia Beverly Hills.
Oh, crew?
[all laugh]
Now who do I want to see
all prettied up in drag?
Sarge.
[all laugh]
Aaron.
[cheers and applause]
Rizzo.
[laughter and applause]
Brady, come on over here.
Josh.
- Yes!
- Okay, just one more.
Duncan.
[screams and laughter]
Gentlemen, say your name
and what you do.
- I'm Sarge.
I'm a camera operator.
- I'm Aaron
and I'm an art coordinator.
- I'm Rizzo.
I am a set P.A.,
and I pretty much
make sure that they're in drag
when we tell them
to be in drag.
- Oh, how the tables
have turned.
[all laugh]
- My name's Brady.
I work in the audio department,
and I make sure
you all sound
as beautiful as you look
every episode.
-Aw...
- Hey, queens.
My name is Josh.
You see me around.
I'm a P.A.
- I'm Duncan.
I'm the associate director.
We're all in Ru's house.
When Ru's not here,
it's my house.
[all laugh]
- Ladies, these men
are like family to me.
Now I want you
to share with them
firsthand
the miracle of drag.
#RuCrewMakeovers
[all laugh]
And we've got these gorgeous
RockStar wigs
to top things off.
Shea and Sasha, since you both
won last week's challenge,
you get to pair the queens
with the crew.
First, who do you choose
for yourselves?
Shea first.
- Josh.
- Oh, damn!
- I picked Josh
because obviously
we share the closest
family resemblance.
- I like a strong
and powerful woman,
so I'm going with Duncan.
[all laugh]
I feel like Duncan's
so serious
when he's being our A.D.,
and I want to see
his playful side.
- Nina,
we're going to pair you
with the lovely,
artistic Aaron.
- All right.
- Ain't no shenanigans here.
We really try
and match the girls up
with someone that
at least feels like
their personality
will match up well.
- With Peppermint,
we are putting Sarge.
[laughter and applause]
- Who do you choose
for Trinity?
-Rizzo.
[laughter and applause]
- Which means Alexis
will be making over Brady.
[applause]
-Come to mama.
-Yes.
- Now, remember,
the judges will be looking
for a strong
drag family resemblance.
So don't fuck it up.
- So you said
you're an artist.
- I'm a graphite artist,
you know, outside of work,
you know, a pencil artist.
- 'Cause I do drag,
but I don't just do drag.
I do like artistic
and different kind of things.
- Dope. I dig this.
Do you want to do
like creature like?
- Yeah. I'm thinking--
- I think that would be
fucking cool.
- And I keep having this vision
of like a white rabbit.
- Hell, yeah.
- But the thing is
getting the garment together.
That's where
the trick comes in.
Y'all know I don't sew.
For me,
my drag is my face,
but I wanted to show that
I can try to create
something from scratch.
So I decide to sew.
[laughs]
- Hip.
- One of my major
inspirations for drag
is Naomi Campbell.
That strength, that power,
that confidence.
So, like, what are some,
like, female celebrities
that, like, come to mind
when you're just, like,
I like the way she looks
when I see her
on the red carpet?
- I have a thing
for Natalie Portman.
- Natalie Portman?
She don't really match
with the Coulee brand.
I want you to just give me,
like, your best runway walk.
Let me have it.
I know your mama
don't walk like that.
Don't think about putting
the emphasis in your shoulders.
Take all that energy
and channel it
into your hips.
You really want to, like,
loosen, like, all of this up.
So try it again.
I'm gonna watch you
from behind.
- Have you ever seen a dog
walk in snow?
- Ooh.
- It's just like that.
Your sister looks strong.
- She is strong.
- And I'm talking
about that walk.
- [laughs]
- Bye, girl.
- Coming up...
Oh, and one more thing.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Oh, fuck.
- Walk naturally.
Go to the store.
- Okay. Oh, God.
- Oh, Jesus.
- This week's maxi challenge
is to turn
the "Drag Race" crew
into our drag sisters.
Okay, I'm known for body,
so I would like to make
a swimsuit for you.
How do you feel
about tucking?
- Gonna hurt.
- But with a swimsuit,
it's, like, it's very there.
You gotta pull it back
or I'm gonna
pull it back for you.
- Oh...
- With Rizzo,
I'm gonna crack the whip.
I haven't won a challenge
in a few weeks,
and so I have to work hard
and show them
that I'm gonna go
all the way.
- Hey, kitty girls.
-Hey.
- How's my
2 Live Crew doing?
-Good.
- [laughs]
Hey, Brady.
- Well, hello there, Ru.
-Hi, Alexis.
-Hi.
- Now, you've just sort of
dipped your toe in so far.
What personality traits
are emerging?
- Oh, the bitch and the diva's
already coming out.
- Really?
- You know, we're supposed
to adopt the same personality.
I think it's happening
naturally.
- Well, like I've
always said, you know,
drag actually reveals your--
I knew I was powerful
in drag.
It didn't occur to me
that I could utilize that
in other areas of my life.
- So you telling me that
I'm co-hosting next season?
- [laughs]
- Fuck you,
Michelle Visage.
We don't need you.
- Aah!
Oh, no!
- I know your girlfriend
is a big fan of the show.
Is that why you're doing it?
- No. I mean, before
I started working with you,
I really kind of thought
that it was just
a man dressed like a woman
and that kind of was it.
But I'm starting to see
all the different aspects
of drag or others,
the comedic drags,
and there's
like the runway drags
and the fish.
-Yes.
-That's a new one for me.
That was new this season.
- Uh-huh.
- There's no way I could say no
to this opportunity.
- Now, Alexis, you were in
the bottom three last week.
- Yes. I don't
want to be there again,
and I know that we're going
to put our best foot forward.
- We're already a good team.
- All right.
Get back to work.
-Will do.
-Thank you.
- Well, well, well.
Duncan and Sasha.
Now, you're cinched.
How does that feel?
- Feels good, Ru.
- [all laugh]
- She's a natural.
- Now, you have a boy
and a girl.
I've met them.
They're lovely.
What's your family going to
think about daddy in drag?
- I think my son
will probably have pointers
on how I walk in heels.
Since he was two,
he loves clomping around
in my wife's, so...
- It is so much fun.
If I had a daddy
who was brave enough
to use all the colors
in the crayon box,
that would have been
life changing.
So thank you so much.
- I want to do RuPaul proud
with my Duncan makeover.
The two of them
have a great love
and respect for each other,
and so I really, really
cannot disappoint.
- Now, Duncan, you have seen
the queens come and go
for years and years.
What advice
have you given Sasha?
- To try and stay out
of your own head.
- Mm.
- We talked about
over-intellectualizing things,
and that getting in the way
of just being free.
- How do you do that?
- Drugs.
- You know, I'm pretty sure
this is going to be
my favorite
all-time challenge ever.
-Can't wait, Sasha.
-I'm excited.
- Turn it out.
- Right. I know we both
have the same battle here.
- Gorgeous.
- Oh, my goodness.
- Oh, hello, Ru.
How are you?
- I am over the moon.
Sarge, how long
have you been here?
- Since Season 4.
- You know, you and I joke.
Sometimes I'll shoot a look
over to you,
and there's an intellect
and there's a fun energy
that comes from you.
- I would agree with you
tenfold.
I definitely caught
a really open vibe
from Sarge right away.
- Yeah. I've never seen
any sort of judgment
about our girls here.
- No, no, no, no.
Absolutely not.
I never thought
before doing this show
I would have as much respect
for drag queens as I do.
I'm just
absolutely flattered
to be able to document
those life experiences.
- Now, how did you get
the name Sarge?
- I was a sergeant
in the army.
- Well, if you've
been through all of that,
doing drag
is a piece of cake.
-Uh-uh.
-No?
- Huh-uh.
[all laugh]
I'm scared shitless, Ru.
- I think you'll be great.
But, you know,
we're in the home stretch
of this competition.
Gotta bring it, mama.
- I'm gonna bring it hard,
girl.
- Okay.
I can't wait to see it.
- I can't wait to show you.
- Say it with
a little more sass, honey.
- Girl, I cannot wait
to show you.
[all laugh]
-I can't wait to see it.
-Okay.
-How'd I do?
-You did great. You did great.
She's into you.
- All right, ladies,
gather round.
Gather round, ladies.
Now, tomorrow, in addition
to your runway presentation,
you and your new
sisters in drag
need to prepare
a lip sync performance
to my song "Click Clack."
[screams and laughter]
So don't fuck it up.
- Oh, Trinity,
I didn't realize
that you were serving
some shrimp cocktail
with your makeover.
That's cute.
- You worry about
your man's feet, okay?
You don't worry about
our man's feet, honey.
- One could wear,
like, overalls,
and then I could have,
like, a hoodie.
It shouldn't be that hard.
- Nina wants to sew
two whole outfits from scratch,
and Nina
don't know how to sew.
Hey, I'm all for ambition,
but ambition is nothing
without execution.
- Ah, here we go.
Yeah, I'm having
a hard time here.
- Oh, I just hope we can
execute this right, man.
Don't curse me out.
No, I'm sorry.
No, I apologize, no.
If you can just show me
how to thread the machine,
then I'm good, y'all.
- Okay.
Even though me and Nina
had our moment,
I still feel for Nina,
so I'm here to help
as much as I can.
But I got to help Josh.
- Let me watch this
completely.
- And then
you just hit the gas,
and it'll spin the bobbin.
- Oh, I got it.
Thank you.
Okay, here we go.
- This is the top six.
This is not the time
to learn how to sew,
especially when you're having
to make two of everything.
- Am I even on it?
Oh, shit.
- Coming up...
- [sighs]
Fuck, this hurts.
- What the--
Get the--out of here.
- [laughs]
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Yes. Work.
- I'm just gonna tighten it
one more time.
- Okay.
-Oh, my God.
-Hold on tight, Sarge.
Our maxi challenge this week
is to make over
the crew of "Drag Race."
- [groans]
- That's great.
You're walking like Pearl now.
That's perfect.
He looks stoned
and very fashionable.
I was a little scared
of Duncan
'cause he's so strict
with us.
But Duncan
is feeling the fantasy.
- Mm-hmm.
- Oh, my goodness.
Look at those little shoes.
These are real drag heels.
[laughs]
- Oh, yeah, Sarge? Uh-huh?
- Mommy's taking you to church
for the first time?
Working with him,
it's amazing how
I'm not in my head at all.
I haven't had this much fun
or felt this relaxed.
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
It's like The Little Mermaid.
-It's The Little Mermaid.
-Exactly.
- Except she was a big dude.
[all laugh]
- See, that was good.
That was shade.
- Okay.
[all laugh]
- So you got
your foot pedal.
- But this needs
to come down.
- That's, uh...
I don't know.
Does the foot pedal
bring it down or no?
- Yeah, this thing is like
jammed or something.
-Do you wanna ask the--
-I can't ask anybody.
It's like everybody's so into
their own thing right now.
- I don't know what to say,
to be honest.
We used
all our lifelines here.
- Right.
- For help.
- Now it's kind of like,
bitch, you're on your own.
Aaron didn't feel confident,
and it finally
got to a point
where I was like,
you know what?
This ain't gonna work.
It's not going to work.
So we need to change
our outfits.
It's sad. I thought
I was finally sewing something.
- This is gonna be fun
for you.
- Yeah, The reason
I particularly was doing this
was because
I've never really agreed
with how we've divided
men and women
when it comes
to what's strong.
So to me, like,
this is very encouraging
to anyone who doesn't fit
in that specific mold.
-Right.
-I know what it's like
to kind of not particularly
fit the jock mold.
That to me is not what I've
placed value of strength in.
It's like beauty and strength
are kind of synonymous,
and I think
you need to be surrounded
by numerous
different walks of life.
Otherwise you just
will never understand
certain aspects
of this world.
- Exactly.
I'm definitely surprised
by talking with Rizzo.
I feel the same way.
Being a human being
is so much more
than being put into a box
or a label.
You are who you are.
-Yeah.
-New day.
We have to get
our crew members shaved,
paint their faces,
get them in their dresses,
and also get ourselves
completely into drag,
and there is no time.
- Nina, in the last
previous two episodes,
you were on the bottom, right?
- Mm-hmm.
- What got you there,
you feel?
- Um, it's been a challenge.
- I think my vibe with it
is what's keeping you down
is yourself.
That's what I get off you.
Even yesterday,
you talk yourself down
almost to the point
of jeopardizing yourself.
-Right.
-You know?
No matter what,
people are trying to
encourage you, you know.
It's just like one ear,
out the other
or your fucking pride's
in front of you
or you just
too blind to see.
- And after a while, people
can't keep telling you,
you know, you're great.
Being my own worst enemy
is like-it's a struggle.
It is. And no matter how many
people tell me you're good
and we're here for you,
I'm not gonna believe it
until I believe it
for myself.
It's just...it's me.
- Because you've always
been this way growing up?
- Yeah, I have just--
I don't know.
I've been through a lot.
Depression
is a serious thing.
- Mm-hmm, I know.
I was addicted
to pain killers
because I liked the way
they made me feel.
It just made me happy
all the time.
-Right.
-Because I also get in my head
and I get depressed and--
But I feel more confident
in who I am.
When I got clean...
- Right.
- What does Ru say
at the end of an episode?
- If you can't
love yourself?
- Yeah, how the hell
you gonna love anybody else?
[laughs]
Sue me. Right. [laughs]
You know, people
are on your side
more than I think
you think you know.
- It's a hard thing
to overcome,
but with this competition,
before it's too late,
I really hope I can find
the magic in me
that I know I have
and really just be
a truly happier person
so that it shows
on the outside.
That looks really good,
like--
- Yeah, look at
the both of us.
- So go back there,
take off your underwear
that you have on now,
put those on.
- Okay.
- And then like I told you,
pull everything back,
wedgie it.
- Right.
- And then we'll see
if we need a piece of tape.
For anybody
in my drag family,
the number one rule
is a fierce tuck.
- Jesus, Jesus, Jesus.
- How's it going?
- I don't think it--come on.
- You ain't supposed
to be playing tug-o-war.
- Fuck. I mean flip.
I mean ouch.
- Not a wrestling match.
You haven't even got
to the duct tape part yet.
-Hold on!
-[laughs]
Ball keeps, like, trying
to poke out more than the other.
-We're gonna use tape.
-Damn it!
- We planned the costume
around this.
The judges know that
I can do a fierce tuck.
This has to be right.
Okay, let me see.
- Uh.
- I mean,
it's not great still,
so we're gonna do
another piece.
- Okay.
- [imitates tearing tape]
- Ow! This hurts.
What the--
Get the--out of here!
[RuPaul laughs]
- ♪ Covergirl, put the bass
in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
- Yay!
- Welcome to the main stage
of RuPaul's Drag Race.
My BFF on and off camera,
Michelle Visage.
- Besties forever.
- The hilarious
Ross Mathews.
- To show support
for all our crew members,
[grunts] I wore heels.
[all laugh]
- My favorite designer,
Zaldy.
- I'm so happy you wore
that dress for today.
You know it says
"sashay away,"
all your phrases on there.
- You are kidding me?
In Japanese?
-Yes.
-I love that.
And the stunning
and super talented Kesha.
- I'm so excited
to be here, Ru.
- So glad you're here.
This week,
we challenged our queens
to make over
our hard-working crew members.
And as an act of solidarity,
the entire crew
is working in wigs and heels.
- Oh!
Yes, queens.
- Gentlemen,
start your engines,
and may
the best woman win.
- Coming up...
- It's just really fun
to look at.
- I really, really loved it.
- I was blown away.
- Really?
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Category is...
Let's meet
the new Ru crew.
First up, Trinity Taylor
and Glittafa Dayz.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Cheetah Girls.
-Whoo!
-Oh.
- Glittafa Dayz
looks like a true Taylor.
This tuck is fucking fierce.
- I think the store's
all out of Aquanet.
- Are we sure
this is his first time?
[all laugh]
- Shea Coulee
and Bae Coulee.
Oh, it's Beyonce
and Solange.
- Oh, yes.
- I am terrified.
This runway
is a bit of a disaster.
But I helped my sister
the best I can
and get my ass
off that runway.
- Looks like a pump.
- Yes, it does.
- Alexis Michelle
and Rye Anne Stardust.
- Looks like Barbarella
to me.
- I hear they both give
good headband.
- Those glutes
are made for stomping.
[Michelle laughs]
- My little sister
and I's pussies
are defying gravity
in outer space.
- Judy Jetson
and her sister Booty Jetson.
[all laugh]
Nina Bo'nina Brown
and Ariana Bo'nina Brown.
- I wonder where she's got
her carrot?
[all laugh]
- From head to toe,
we have the ears,
the teeth and the face.
We are S&M bunnies.
You know, fierce.
- I can see a little hare.
-Mm-mm.
-Get it?
- Yeah, yeah.
- That's a bunny reference.
- This is her hare.
She don't wear weave.
- Mm-mm.
- Sasha Velour
and Dunatella Velour.
That hat
is on my bucket list.
[all laugh]
- We're two East Coast sisters
in the 1940s
looking to make it big
in Hollywood.
I think these are really,
really fashionable looks,
and Dunatella
looks beautiful.
- Love.
-Aw...
- Wait. Wait a minute.
-Oh.
-What?
- Velour.
- That look
really said something.
- What label whores.
Peppermint and Winter Green.
-A sleeve belt.
-Yeah.
- I think she's got a trick
up her sleeve.
- Sleeve her alone.
- We're sashaying,
we're shantaying,
and Ms. Winter Green,
she's feeling it.
I'm like, okay, girl.
- She's sleeving on
the Midnight Train to Georgia.
[all laugh]
- You have the best job
in the world.
-I know.
-So fun.
- The time has come...
[thunder]
for you to lip sync
for your job.
Just kidding.
Sort of.
[music plays]
- Whoo!
[all laugh]
- Oh!
- ♪ Gonna walk right through
that door ♪
♪ High heels
on a hardwood floor ♪
♪ They all coming back
for more ♪
♪ It's a party tonight,
hey, hey ♪
♪ Get it up and do it right
this time ♪
♪ Never gonna stop
till the beat is mine ♪
♪ Come round
if you're so inclined ♪
♪ It's a party tonight,
yeah ♪
♪ Where my girls go
gonna be a good show ♪
♪ Hey, girl, you go,
gonna, gonna ♪
♪ Make that,
make that money ♪
♪ Where my girls at? ♪
♪ Make your heels clap ♪
♪ Click clack,
click clack, uh ♪
♪ Everybody, everybody,
do you hear that? ♪
♪ Click clack,
click clack, uh ♪
♪ Why, that's the sound
of a sling back ♪
♪ Peanut butter head,
kiss my grits ♪
♪ Yo mama's in the kitchen,
but her oven on the fritz ♪
♪ Yo daddy's in jail
raising hell ♪
♪ And yo sister's on the corner
selling something for sale ♪
-Whoo!
[cheers and applause]
- Coming up...
- It feels like
a Ricky's Halloween costume.
- I need you to bring it
at a 10.
- It's time
to really dig in.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Welcome, ladies.
It's time
for the judges' critiques.
First up, Trinity Taylor
and Glittafa Dayz.
- The family resemblance
is hard to deny,
and you did the most
intricate choreography.
- Yeah, so impressive.
I can barely walk
in those shoes,
let alone, like, dance.
-Glittafa.
- If I didn't know better,
it'd look like you've been
doing this for a minute.
- But beyond, I think,
having a great partner,
it's about how
you communicate and guide,
and I think this was probably
the tightest presentation.
-Is that code for tuck?
-Yes, exactly.
- How's your tuck
holding up?
- The pain is real.
The pain is real.
- Now, what do you think you're
gonna take from this experience?
- I'm gonna take
this tape off.
[all laugh]
- Up next, Shea Coulee
and here is Bae Coulee.
- I love the dresses,
like, kind of old school
Hollywood glam.
- But there's something
about this attention to detail
and about paying attention
to your sister.
- Bae, when she turns around,
you could see her hairline.
Her bra straps
are hanging out the back.
It felt like, you know,
there's the star sister
and then there's
the other sister.
- Oh. I hate
that it came across,
like, you know,
Bae was an afterthought.
- I think Shea
did a great job.
I'm proud to be her sister.
-Aw.
- Up next, Alexis Michelle
and Rye Anne Stardust.
- Your brows are glitter.
That's fucking awesome.
- The nails scream
I am a slut.
- Big voluptuous slut.
- But the outfits
are kind of real basic.
- It feels a little bit
like a Ricky's
Halloween costume in a bag.
- Look, we're
intergalactic whores.
Can we have some candy,
you know?
Look how close we are
to the end here.
It's time to really dig in.
- Up next, Nina Bo'nina Brown
Faye Bakker
and Ariana Bo'nina Brown.
- Well, I love animals,
so I think it's really cute.
[all laugh]
I really do.
- Now, was it challenging
doing this drag transformation
in front of
your co-workers?
- No. In fact,
the teams were so sweet,
and the art department,
they made little tags
that said Team Aaron,
you know what I mean? So...
-Aw.
- Well, we always say
a family that drags together,
slays together.
- But this is kind of,
you know, a letdown for me.
It's you out here in a leotard
with thigh-high boots
and not really doing
anything innovative.
I was screaming
for a little cottontail
or a little colored glove
or something
just to bring this to this
so there wasn't
such a disconnect here.
- And then, with
the performance, too,
I thought was a little bit
underwhelming.
- I'm so excited by what you
bring to this competition, Nina,
but I need you
to bring it at a 10.
- Up next, Sasha Velour
and Dunatella Velour.
- This looks
so high fashion.
It looks like
Miu Miu on acid.
- The proportion of the dress
and the coat
and all these pops of color,
I really, really loved it.
- Now, Dunatella, there is
something that you're doing
that's strangely
turning me on.
- I learned it
from watching you, dear.
[all laugh]
- Up next, Peppermint
and Winter Green.
Gorgeous.
- I know.
[all laugh]
- Winter Green, your face
is just really fun
to look at.
You're just so funny.
I don't know why.
But you're, like, beautiful,
but, like, you make me--
but, like, you're beautiful...
[all laugh]
- What is it, dear?
- Let me roll back.
You just look...
- Go on.
[all laugh]
- I just can't.
- But the outfits
clash so horribly,
I don't even want to look
at them in the same frame.
- But guess what?
I don't care because
you were so fun to watch.
- And Peppermint,
you should thank Winter Green,
because she was the one
who pulled you through.
- Now, Winter Green, do you
think you'll ever do drag again?
- Who knows?
Season 10?
[all laugh]
- "All Stars."
Thank you, ladies.
And to my crew
standing on stage,
to see you men do this,
it says that we as a people
are moving forward,
and it's beautiful.
Thank you from
the bottom of my heart.
Now, while you ladies
untuck backstage,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
[car engine starts]
All right.
So just between us squirrel
friends, what do you think?
Trinity Taylor
and Glittafa Dayz.
- They had the most
incredible choreography.
The whole look,
the attitudes,
like, I bought
everything they had to sell.
- It was just so apparent
that their connection
was, like, on another level
than anybody else's.
- Yeah, and you know, Zaldy,
Trinity is a real showgirl,
so to teach her sister
that routine
and for her to hit it so hard,
very impressive.
- In those heels, Ru.
- In those heels.
Shea and Bae Coulee.
- Shea kind of failed
for me tonight.
She let her sister down.
- In Shea's defense,
I felt like she did come
to her sister's aid
when she saw the problems
going on.
And I thought
she looked beautiful.
- Shea has wowed us.
Tonight, that was not wow.
- But is what Shea did reason
enough to put her in the bottom?
-Not for me.
-To me, yes, 100%.
-Not for you?
-No.
- Not to me. I didn't think
her look was the worst.
I didn't think their performance
was the worst.
I would put Alexis.
- Not me.
- That's who I would put
in the bottom.
- All right.
Let's talk about Alexis
and Rye Anne Stardust.
- Something about
how unfresh this was.
It was hard for me to,
like, really enjoy it.
- Though it was not
my favorite look,
it was meticulously
put together.
- But I was at least
a little more interested
in what Shea
brought to the table
than I was with Alexis.
- Really?
Shea's was sloppy.
This one was not sloppy.
- Well,
Michelle knows sloppy.
[all laugh]
- I feel like Alexis
and Rye Anne,
even if you don't like
the aesthetic,
but I do find them more original
than just frumpy gowns.
- Thank you. Tonight,
toilet paper, paper towel.
- [laughs] All right.
So let's move on to Nina Bo'nina
Brown Tyler Moore and Ariana.
- That bunny had absolutely
no connection with the rest.
And we've been getting
the same silhouette
with a bodysuit
and thigh-high boots.
I'm done with it.
- Yeah.
Even the bunny part
was just sort of half done.
- And, like, the ears,
it looked like
they'd been rained on.
- It's more arts and crafts
than it is Comic-Con.
- Sasha Velour
and Dunatella Velour.
- I really enjoyed
the connection
between the two of them.
And are her looks
always so modern-feeling?
- She's very fashion.
- Because
it really worked for me.
- She's been so serious,
but she looked like
she was really
enjoying herself this week.
-Really letting go.
-Yeah.
- I'm super proud
of Sasha tonight.
- Peppermint
and Winter Green.
- I think we can all agree
tonight
that Winter Green
gets the MVP.
[all laugh]
She's a superstar.
From the minute
she came out here,
I bought it.
The only think I did not buy
was those outfits.
- So hard to look at.
Just the choice in the fabrics,
they felt so disparate.
- Peppermint better be kissing
Winter Green's feet.
Because
if it weren't for her,
I could see Peppermint
in the bottom this week.
- All right, silence.
You've been no help at all.
[all laugh]
Bring back my girls.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Welcome back, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Peppermint, you're safe.
Trinity Taylor,
you gave us Glittafa Dayz,
months, years.
- [laughs]
- Con-drag-ulations.
You're the winner
of this week's challenge.
-Congratulations.
-Oh, my God.
- You've won
two custom gowns
from celebrity fashion designer
David Meister.
- Thank you.
- And your drag sister
has won
a $2,000 gift certificate
to Klein, Epstein & Parker,
suits made to measure.
- What?
- You may step
to the back of the stage.
- Thank you so much.
- Sasha Velour,
you're safe.
- Nina Bo'nina Brown,
your bunny looks
did not make the judges hoppy.
I'm sorry, my dear,
but you are up for elimination.
Alexis Michelle,
your Barbarellas were basic.
Shea Coulee, your makeover
of Bae was not okay.
- Come on, Shea,
come on, Shea, come on, Shaea.
Alexis Michelle...
You're safe.
- Thank you very much.
- Oh, no.
- Shea Coulee,
I'm sorry, my dear,
but you are up
for elimination.
- To see the judges
looking at me
as if I let them down,
I'm scared.
- Ladies, this is your
last chance to impress me
and save yourself
from elimination.
The time has come...
[thunder]
to lip sync
[echoing] for your life.
- I almost want
to just stand on stage
and just point
and do a Charlie number,
but I'm also thinking,
you know what?
This is what
I signed up for,
so here we go.
- Good luck,
and don't fuck it up.
[music plays]
- ♪ Tell me what you want ♪
♪ What you like,
it's okay ♪
♪ I'm a little curious,
too ♪
♪ Tell me if it's wrong ♪
♪ If it's right,
I don't care ♪
♪ I can keep a secret,
can you? ♪
♪ Got my mind
on your body ♪
♪ And your body
on my mind ♪
♪ Got a taste
for the cherry ♪
♪ I just need
to take a bite ♪
♪ Don't tell your mother ♪
♪ Kiss one another ♪
♪ Die for each other ♪
♪ We're cool
for the summer ♪
Ha!
♪ Ooh-ooh-ooh ♪
♪ Take me down
into your paradise ♪
♪ Don't be scared,
'cause I'm your body type ♪
♪ Just something
that we wanna try ♪
♪ 'Cause you and I,
you and I ♪
♪ We're cool
for the summer ♪
Shh...
♪ Got my mind
on your body ♪
♪ And your body
on my mind ♪
♪ Take me down ♪
♪ We're cool
for the summer ♪
♪ Don't be scared ♪
♪ 'Cause
I'm your body type ♪
♪ Just something
that we wanna try ♪
♪ 'Cause you and I,
you and I ♪
♪ We're cool
for the summer ♪
[applause]
- Whoo!
- Brava!
- Ladies,
I've made my decision.
Shea Coulee,
shantay, you stay.
Join the other girls.
- Thank you so much.
Thank you.
- Nina Bo'nina Brown
Andre Charles,
baby, you are part
of my family now.
Now sashay away.
- Thank you.
Sue me.
[all laugh]
- I think I might.
- I was trying to be a voice for
the African American community
who think all they can do
is just do one type of drag,
but I guess I just wasn't
strong enough mentally.
- You fucking changed my life.
You're part of the family.
Give me a hug and then get
the fuck out of here.
- Yeah, this thing is heavy.
- No, no, no, no.
I know, I know, I know.
- Thank you so much,
man, for real.
-Yeah, yeah.
-For being a true friend.
Bye.
- Bye.
- Wait,
give my damn leggings back.
- Top five, bitches.
- Ow!
[cheering]
- Now, remember,
if you can't love yourself,
how in the hell
you gonna love somebody else?
Can I get an amen
up in here?
-Amen!
- Right.
Now let the music play.
- ♪ Hey, kitty girl ♪
♪ It's your world ♪
♪ Hey, kitty,
kitty, girl ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪
- [laughs]