WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Previously on
"RuPaul's Drag Race..."
- There's always been tension
with me and Eureka.
Maybe she has an issue
with the fact
that every pageant
that we've been in,
I beat her.
- You need to create
a totally original
fairytale princess
and sassy sidekick.
Trinity Taylor.
- This is really fun,
and then you showed us
your starfish.
- Itch cream.
[RuPaul laughs]
- Aja.
- I am Princess Disastah's
smoke cloud.
- I literally had no clue
what was going on tonight.
I also think that
your makeup is very dark.
- Kimora Blac.
- My name is Funky Monkey
from Banana Kingdom.
- Trinity Taylor, you're the
winner of this week's challenge.
Aja, shantay, you stay.
Kimora Blac, sashay away.
- Yes! Finally!
- Oh, Kimore.
- Oh, Kimora's gone
and I am so sad.
- How do you feel after that
lip sync for your life, baby?
- I just feel like
I walked into here
thinking like
I was unstoppable,
and now I feel like
I really need to reevaluate.
- For Aja, the challenge
is going to be
not becoming bitter
because she sees herself
as a superstar.
And to be told
your makeup is off,
your outfit isn't great is a bit
of an ego check for her.
- So Trinity,
last week when you said
that you were coming
for Valentina's spot,
how does it feel to be coming
for Valentina's spot?
-Uh-oh.
-Ooh!
- Shade.
- Well, as long
as we're being real,
I don't think Valentina
should've been top three.
- Valentina,
you know I live for you,
but I think it was
a little misjudged tonight.
- These girls can continue
to talk about me.
They're not the judges.
I'm ready to be,
like, hmm, hmm.
Whew. I'm focused.
- Shea, I can't.
- Bitch, I wore four items.
I wore a panty,
a chap and a coat.
- Valentina
came down the runway--
I'm talking about you,
bitch--
In a leotard.
I just don't understand
the hype about Valentina.
Listening to the judges
critiques, I felt ugly.
To hear someone constantly get
praised for just being pretty
when I'm trying
to compensate
with everything else I have,
it sucks.
People always undermine
my drag.
But you know what, girl?
I think that I'm amazing.
That there's people
who think I'm amazing.
I deserve to be
in this competition.
- Aja's true colors
are coming out.
She presents herself
as this person that's confident,
but there's a lot
of insecurity there.
- I'm going to win
next challenge, mark my word.
Coming for you, Ms. Trinity!
[car engine starts]
- The winner
of "RuPaul's Drag Race"
receives a one-year supply
of Anastasia Beverly Hills
cosmetics
and a cash prize
of $100,000.
With extra special
guest judges
"Unreal's"
Jeffrey Bowyer-Chapman
and Naya Rivera.
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
- ♪ May the best woman ♪
- ♪ Best woman win ♪
- ♪ Can you feel the love? ♪
- Hi, hi-hi.
Aah! [all laugh]
- I pass
the third episode. Yes!
You know, three is not
my lucky number from Season 8.
Ha-ha!
- Hello, hello, hello!
[cheering]
Now, when most of you
are just crawling home
from being up in the club,
"Good Morning America"
and the "Today" show
are ruling the airwaves.
Now it's your chance
to join the cutthroat
morning talk show wars.
-Ooh.
-Oh, my God!
- You'll be cohosting
two rival morning shows.
- Oh, my God.
- #MorningBitches.
[cheers and laughter]
Now, Trinity, you won
last week's challenge
and Aja, you survived
the lip sync,
so you two
are team captains.
-Oh!
-Yes!
- Now, remember,
in morning television,
chemistry is everything.
So pick your morning teams,
starting with Aja.
- Valentina.
Even though I'm still giving
Valentina the side eye,
I am really curious
what the judges see in her
and maybe be able
to channel that in myself.
-Trinity.
-Peppermint.
[applause]
- Slay Coulee.
- Charlie.
- Sasha Velour.
- Ms. Cucu.
- Whoopi Goldberg is not ready
for her replacement.
[all laugh]
- Alexis Michelle.
-Eureka!
-Aah!
- Outside of this competition,
Eureka and I have a very
up and down relationship,
but I picked Eureka
because I know
she's gonna work hard,
and I want to show Ru
that I can work
with anybody.
- That leaves Farrah Moan
and Nina Bo'nina Brown.
- I'm going to say
Farrah Moan.
We needed a fish.
- Which means Nina
is on Team Trinity.
- Come here, girl.
- Team Aja, you're the host
of "Good Morning Bitches."
And Team Trinity, you're
the host of "Not On Today."
- Yeah!
- Oh, and just
one more thing.
Your show is going to be
broadcast live.
Gentlemen,
start your engines
and may the best woman win.
- #TeamNotOnToday.
- Nina, do not let the fact
that you were picked last
in your head
because I'm glad
that you're on our team.
- Okay.
But at the same time,
if you're, like,
saying that we love you,
when we have
to choose groups,
why would you run past me?
I think the other queens
see me as a Debbie Downer,
the girl
who gets in her head.
But I can't just pretend
when I'm over it.
I kind of wear my emotions
on my sleeve.
- So Team Captain,
is our television station
set in the South?
- There's three
Southern Belles here.
- But "Not On Today" I feel
like is kind of ghetto.
Do you think we should do
ghetto accent?
- No, no.
- I think the biggest
challenge for Trinity
is going to be keeping
everybody in line
'cause she's got
some big personalities.
Let's just--
She's got Eureka on the team.
[laughs]
And it may be kind of tough.
- Ghetto fierce
like, not on today.
- This--okay, so first
of all, as Team Captain,
I don't want anybody
to talk over each other.
So raise your hand
and let the person
that's talking
finish what they're saying.
- Ha-ha.
Here it comes, girl.
Step one
of competitive Trinity.
- Also, I think we would
have really good chemistry
so we're gonna be
the news anchors.
- Okay.
- Then, because you're
really good at building stuff,
you're really gonna
be good at the DIY.
And then, y'all are
definitely entertainment.
- We don't talk about
who wants to play what role.
Trinity is, like,
you're doing this role,
you're doing this role.
So, to me, it wasn't a leader,
it was a dictator.
- When Ru was like
"Not On Today,"
it did give that,
like, tinge of shade.
- Okay, I'm so sorry.
- God, please.
This is typical Eureka.
- You know, something shady.
- Maybe we each could--
- Maybe not
towards each other.
- This is me
holding my hand up
and following the rules
that we set in place.
If you're gonna set the rules,
follow the rules.
- Eureka needs to shut up.
I'm trying to be
a good Southern Belle
and not punch this bitch
in the face.
- So all three of us
just need to have our own vibe.
You all need...
- If y'all want to be
that ghetto--yeah.
- We're over-talking
each other, remember?
- [squawks]
- What I think
we should do now
is break
in our smaller groups
and then we'll reconvene
after we go over everything.
- Yes, Miss.
- Eureka wants it to be
the Eureka Show,
but that's not happening.
Girl, no, ma'am.
- Coming up...
- Live in three, two...
- First up,
we have Raja and Raven.
- Let's move on
to the next one--oh.
- And next, we have
Coco Montrese and--
- Next!
[imitates bomb dropping]
[RuPaul laughs, bell dings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- We're going to give you
the scoop
about Justin Bieber's
shocking new sex tape
with Dame Maggie Smith.
The challenge this week
is to cohost two rival
morning chat shows.
With my experience working
with "Live," I'm excited.
But also, I don't want
to be just known
as that guy that does Madonna,
Cher and Lady Gaga.
I'd like to be known for me
because there's only one
Charlie Hides in the world.
Google it.
- Trust me, you are going
to watch this.
- You're going
to want to see this.
- Okay. You're want--
You're going
to wanted to see this.
- You're going--
You are going...
- Trust me. You are going
to want to see this.
- Cynthia has sometimes
a haphazard approach.
And with comedy,
if you add an extra word,
you can blow the joke.
If you drop
a couple of words,
you can blow the joke.
- Trust me, you are going
to want to see this.
- And just say want.
- Want.
- You're going to want
to see this.
- Okay. Trust me, you are
going to want to see this.
- You're going
to want to see this.
- Want to see this, okay.
- Yeah.
- Okay.
- Yeah. But with a big smile.
- Charlie's very strict.
She's trying to correct,
like, all the pronunciation,
and I appreciate that.
But that's what made
my character funny,
when I just pronounce words
that are mispronounced.
I'm Cynthia Lee Martinez
Valles de la Flores
filla de Orlando Fontaine.
- But we call her Maria.
- [chuckles] Charlie.
- I wouldn't--
I don't know if I'd laugh.
- Aye dios mio.
- Trust me, the laughing
is going to be dead air.
- Part of the challenge
is to show personality,
like how to be yourself.
And Charlie, in certain way,
is blocking me to be myself.
- Just smile,
just like, like,
like I want to knife you.
- Don't try to make me
something that I'm not
because that's gonna be
a disaster.
-Yeah?
-Yes.
- Hello.
- It's time to shoot
our rival morning shows.
"Good Morning Bitches."
- Welcome to your beautiful set
furnished by 204 Events.
Isn't is gorgeous?
-Gorgeous!
-Yes.
- This is live.
There are no take twos.
Embrace the mistakes
because some of the best magic
comes out of the stuff
that went wrong.
All right.
Take your place at the table.
We're almost live.
And we are ready
in five, four, three...
- Good morning, bitches.
It's the top of the hour
and time for today's headlines.
- The world's
hottest fashion trend
is acrylic
toenail extensions.
- Oh, dear.
- I actually just got
mine done yesterday.
- Oh, my!
I may have to give it
another thought, Farrah.
- You won't regret it,
Alexis.
-I'll drink to that.
-Cheers.
- [chuckles]
- All right. We're in
commercials. Let's move on.
Enter-taint-ment reporters,
take your places.
- I don't really know where mine
and Aja's relationship stands,
but I have to do
the best that I can
to connect with her
at this moment.
- Live in three, two...
-Good morning, bitches.
- The latest meme
taking over the internet
is drag queens
without eyebrows or teeth.
-Oh, my God.
-Can you imagine?
First up,
we have Raja and Raven.
-Next.
- Let's move on
to the next one--oh.
- And next, we have Coco
Montrese and Alyssa Edwards.
- You sure--I thought
that was Laganja Estranja.
- Oh, my God!
- The resemblance
is uncanny, girl.
- True.
- Next!
- And we're clear.
Commercial, guys.
- [imitates bomb dropping]
They have chemistry
all right,
but sometimes things can
combust in a chemistry lab.
You know what I'm saying?
- Here we go.
Coming out of commercial.
DIY, you're next. Go!
- Today, I'm going
to be teaching you
how to work in a RuPaul's
chocolate bar into your diet.
- I feel like people just
don't eat enough chocolate.
- You know, I agree.
I love eating chocolate.
-Sasha!
-[laughs]
- Do you have a solution for
people who love to eat dessert,
but hate waiting
till the end of the meal?
- Why not take
a RuPaul's chocolate bar
and put it in a salad?
-Yeah, toss that salad.
-Stir it up.
You want to try some?
- I thought you'd never ask.
- Do you like that?
- Mm-hmm.
No.
Sasha?
-Uh-huh.
- For queens that love
the gym--for queens--mm.
-[laughs]
-Tastes great, doesn't it?
-Oh, so good.
-[laughs]
- Sasha and I are really
leaning on each other.
We're having fun.
The jokes are landing.
It feels right.
- So you take
a RuPaul's chocolate bar...
- Get out of town.
- And you hide it
in a stalk of broccoli.
- You're just a magician.
- [laughs]
- It's a chocolate
revolution.
- And we're clear. Cut!
[all laugh]
Chew and swallow.
All right.
Reset for the celebrity
interview. Let's go.
- How are you?
-Hello.
-Hi!
- When I see Naya Rivera,
I'm like, yes!
Come through.
She was always one of
my favorites on "Glee."
- Are you ready to go live?
In three, two, go!
- Please welcome
our special guest,
actress and singer
Naya Rivera.
Good morning, Naya!
- Hi, good morning, bitches.
[all laugh]
- Well, Naya, what advice
would you have
for a starlet
who's trying to stick out.
- When I first started
on "Glee,"
I didn't have,
like, any lines,
so I would just sit
in the back of that classroom
and, like, roll my neck
and do anything I could
to get that camera on me.
And it worked.
- Congratulations
on your new book.
"Sorry Not Sorry"
is an amazing title.
Where did that come from?
- The book is all about,
you know,
learning from your mistakes
and being sorry
about some things
and not sorry
about some other things.
-Same here.
-Right?
- So, Naya, what advice
do you have
to young aspiring actresses
who want to make a career
in show biz.
- Find something else to do.
[all laugh]
- Well, Naya,
we cannot thank you enough
for being with us today.
-Thank you for having me.
-It was so much fun.
- We'll be sure to see you
tomorrow morning for...
-"Good Morning Bitches."
-And we're clear.
-Best show on television.
[all laugh]
- Coming up...
- I don't want
any extra breast
other than--unless
they come with, uh, two--
two biscuits--two breasts
and two biscuits.
- I'm confused.
Peppermint's confused.
We're all fucking confused.
[RuPaul laughs, bell dings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- It's time for my team
"Not On Today" to go live.
- Get ready!
Five, four, three, two, go!
- Good morning.
It's time for the biggest
stories of the day.
- The Center
for Infectious Diseases
has announced there's something
in your makeup bag
that could be killing you
right now.
- I wonder what it could be?
- I don't know, but whatever's
in your makeup bag,
you should throw it away.
- That's okay, because I'm sure
whatever I have in my makeup bag
would certainly kill you.
Uh, like your husband's
business card.
- [fake laugh]
- And in health
and science news,
all of Michelle Visage's fans
have come together
to create
a crowdfunding campaign
to pay for her
breast reduction surgery.
You know, I don't want
any extra breast
other than--unless
they come with, uh, two--
two biscuits--two breasts
and two biscuits.
Jesus.
- Now for
the enter-taint-ment report
with Charlie Hides
and Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- Good morning.
Today, we're talking
social media.
There's a fun new game people
are playing on the internet
called #SophiesChoices.
I give you two scenarios.
You tell me which one
of the two you'd choose.
You have to lick ice cream
off Nick Jonas' abs
or eat fudge off
Chris Hemsworth's chest.
- Let me tell you something.
I'm intolerant lactose.
I don't mind to go
all the way to the hospital
just only to eat
that banana split.
- [laughs]
- Do you have
a question for me?
-I got a question for you.
-Good.
- You get one night with
Justin Bieber totally naked
or one night with
Justin Bieber's money.
- So I would probably
have sex with him,
have a hidden camera,
send the pictures to TMZ
and then keep the money.
- I'm gonna keep the money
because
I don't know if Justin
had the opportunity
to deal with my cucu.
It's time for...
-Who Done Wore It Better.
- Detox, the drag queen
or Detox, the pussycat?
- The cat looks incredible.
- [laughs]
- I'm looking at
Detox the pussycat's hair
and it looks a little bit
like Winifred from
"Hocus Post--Pocus"?
- Charlie, what's going on?
He is cold as a dead body.
He's so tense, so nervous.
- I think
we're gonna earn favor
of our--one of
our favorite drag queens,
Bob--uh, sorry, Thorgy Thor.
Shantay...
-You stay!
- And finally--
well, that's about all--
that's about all the time
we have for right now.
- Don't touch the dial!
- Don't touch me.
- And we're clear.
Commercial, guys.
We're live
in three, two, go.
- Welcome back.
It's eight past the hour.
- Eureka and Nina Bo-nina Brown
are here
to give us some--
give us some tips
on how to do drag on a dime.
- All right, Nina.
Now, this lace right here,
it is 100% human hair,
but it costs $7,300.
- Girl, what you need
to do is, honey,
get your platinum EBT card,
girl.
- Okay.
- And go on down
to the Dollar Store, girl,
and get you a lavish
ramen noodle wig, girl.
- Oh. Is it beef flavor?
- Ooh, chicken, bitch.
Goes for a mere price
of $6.00.
- Oh, it looks good
and tastes good, girl.
-Hey.
-Okay.
Now, let's move on.
We've got these
ass cheek pads, honey.
Gel. Per cheek, $200.
- Girl, a cheek.
You're doing it
all wrong, mama.
Get this ham, girl.
For the mere price
of $8.00, honey.
- $8.00, bitch.
- And stuff her up.
Oh, oh!
- Well, all right.
Oh, she's edible, too.
She look good and she...
-Tastes good, girl.
- Great, and we're
in commercial.
We're moving on
to the celebrity interview.
- Me and Nina
fucking killed it.
The ham's good.
Can I have another piece?
- We're coming back
in three, two...
- Please welcome
our very special guest,
actress and singer
Naya Rivera.
Are you happy to be here?
- Hi. "Not On Today."
[all laugh]
- Now, I heard somewhere
that when you were 19,
you lied on your resume
to get a job
at Abercrombie & Fitch?
-I did. I--
-Did you fudge the truth at all
to get onto "Glee"?
- No. I had to actually--
I had to sing and act
for that one.
- What's the name of your book
and when is it coming out?
- It's called
"Sorry Not Sorry:
Dreams, Mistakes
and Growing Up"
and it comes out
September 13th.
- I'm thinking
that Trinity and Peppermint
are not noticing that
it's time to wrap it up.
- My publishers and I,
we just kind of really loved it
and thought it was clever.
- It's not my job.
I'm not the anchor,
but I'm just thinking Joy Behar,
what would she do?
- I can't wait to read it.
- Thanks very much
for joining us.
It's time
to go to commercial.
- Do I get up now?
- I'm confused.
Peppermint's confused.
We're all fucking confused.
- Am I leaving?
- Okay.
All right, ladies,
we're off the air,
but nobody said goodbye.
- This is definitely bad.
Bad, bad, bad.
That's all I'm thinking,
bad.
- Coming up...
- You're making a really bad
first impression with me.
- Why are you
talking over me, girl?
- I can hear you
talking about me.
- Because I'm upset.
[RuPaul laughs, bell dings]
[RuPaul laughs]
-Good morning bitches.
- It's elimination day
and our runway today
is naughty nighties.
- How are you doing, girl?
- I'm okay.
I just don't want to go home.
-Right.
-Me and Valentina
didn't have chemistry
in the challenge,
and it makes me feel
really nervous
because I just came off
the bottom.
I think it's going to affect
how the judges see me.
You know me, Alexis.
- Yeah.
- You know
what I'm capable of.
Like, it's not my 100%.
- It's really hard when
you're in a pressure cooker.
- But I don't feel
like I'm under pressure.
I feel maybe
I'm overconfident.
- Aja, I'm not gonna lie.
You're, like,
oftentimes negative.
You're making a really bad
first impression with me
because I can hear you
in the corners talking about me.
Maybe some advice is that,
like, don't focus on me.
Don't focus on other girls.
Focus in on you.
- I just feel like
I've been such a disappointment
while I've been here,
and I took it out
in all the wrong ways.
- All we can do
moving forward
is to be kinder
to each other, you know?
- Yeah, I agree.
I really genuinely
like Valentina.
I'm just really frustrated
because I really
want this so bad,
and I feel like
I'm fucked up.
You're a really good person.
I'm really sorry.
- I accept
your apology, babe.
Just let me finish
doing my makeup
'cause it's more important.
-Aah!
-[laughs]
- Tell me about the work
you were doing
from HIV prevention.
- I do referrals for clients
who--they were
newly diagnosed with HIV.
- And it's so important
that people know.
I'm of the era when people
would be spreading the virus
before we even knew
it had a name.
I came out just before
AIDS became known.
So none of my friends
were playing safe.
I buried all my best friends,
most of my best friends,
and...that's probably
the hardest thing.
Sometimes
I have survivor's guilt.
Like why did I survive?
It was a death sentence.
I've seen so many smart,
beautiful, talented people
go the route of the pills,
drugs, the bottle.
Society was telling them
they are not good enough.
The one message
I try to get across
is you're worth it, you're
special, you're beautiful.
And you're worth
taking care of yourself.
[sobbing]
So you gotta stay strong,
and you gotta rely
on your friends.
- Thank you for sharing
that story.
Because of your generation,
we appreciate what we have.
- It's important
to not forget
what happened
in the eighties and nineties
during the AIDS crisis
and how many
brilliant voices
in the world of art and drag
we could have
without those losses.
- My makeup is going to be
fucking ruined on the runway.
- Do a smoky eye, girl.
- [laughs]
- Does anyone here have
psoriasis or just me?
- I have bad acne.
- I have really bad breath
in the morning.
- Eew.
- Can I tell you guys about
one of the disorders that I have
that I'm struggling with?
- Eating.
- Don't joke about that.
Eureka,
it's really inappropriate
to joke about that.
- Sasha, okay, I realize,
but why push it
straight to negativity?
- I don't think she's pushing it
straight to negativity.
I think that she's trying to
keep the levels respectful.
- By trying to make me
look like a bad person?
- I have nothing
against you,
but I have a long history
with eating disorders.
You don't know now
by looking at me--
- There are other types of
eating disorders besides--
- But so many times
in my life--
Why are you talking
over me, girl?
- Because I'm upset.
I make the joke to try
to make the air light.
I'm not trying
to be malicious
and I'm all of a sudden
not a good person.
- Can I tell you how many times
people have looked at me
and been like, oh, my God,
you're anorexic.
It's really hurtful.
- I never come
at any of you all
with a nasty tone,
so when I--
- I really didn't think
I was being nasty.
- Let me finish, please.
But you had a nasty tone,
and that's what upset me
about it.
- Look, I'm coming over here
because if it came off
as an attack,
I do truly apologize.
I would never want that.
I am just trying--
- Well, I apologize that you
were offended by what I said.
- I wasn't.
- You obviously were offended
at what I said, right?
What do you want
from me, girl?
Do you want me
to get down on my knees
and beg you to forgive me?
- Girl, please.
- I think I want you guys
to focus on getting ready
for the runway.
'Cause
it's going in circles.
[sighs]
[RuPaul laughs]
- ♪ Cover girl,
put the bass in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
And what?
- Welcome to the main stage
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
Good morn-ting, Michelle.
Girl, did you wake up
like that?
- Actually,
can I have five minutes
so I can go
put some makeup on?
- You should.
[all laugh]
And the hilarious
Ross Mathews.
Now, would you wake up
with my girls?
- Morning, would I?
- From the TV show,
"Unreal,"
"Drag Race" superfan
Jeffrey Bowyer-Chapman.
Are you hungry?
- Positively ravenous.
[all laugh]
- And the beautiful
and talented Naya Rivera.
- This is truly the most
magical of experiences.
- Well, make sure you still
have your pocketbook.
- Oh.
- This week,
we challenged our queens
to rise and shine on their
very own morning talk show.
And tonight, they're gonna
sleepwalk down the runway
in their naughty nighties.
Gentlemen,
start your engines,
and may the best woman win.
Category is...Farrah Moan.
Alexis Michelle.
Aja.
Valentina.
Shea Coulee.
Sasha Velour.
Trinity Taylor.
Peppermint.
Charlie Hides.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
Eureka.
Nina Bo'nina Brown
Joyner-Kersee.
Now, she's reminding me to
always use my night cream.
[Michelle laughs]
Coming up...
Who deserves to go home
tonight and why?
- [sobs]
[RuPaul laughs, bell dings]
[RuPaul laughs]
Welcome, ladies.
The judges and I
watched your morning shows
and I've made
some decisions.
When I call your name,
please step forward.
Shea Coulee.
Sasha Velour.
Ladies...
Con-drag-ulations.
You are both the winners
of this week's challenge.
- It feels great
to win with Sasha
because I really feel myself
developing
a friendship with her.
- You've each won $1,000
and a year's supply of burgers
from Hamburger Mary's,
where you can eat, drink
and be merry, Mary.
[all laugh]
Team "Good Morning Bitches,"
you're all safe.
[applause]
You may leave the stage.
That means
Team "Not On Today,"
you're all up
for elimination.
It's time
for the judges' critiques,
starting
with Trinity Taylor.
- I think you look stunning.
I'm incredibly jealous
of your ass.
- But your performance
in the challenge,
it seemed very uptight,
very mean
and I don't think
anybody wants to watch
anybody bitchy and mean
in the morning.
- The storyline
that we went with,
she slept with my husband,
and so there was all this
underlining despise.
- On a morning show,
it has to be a little bit
more light-hearted.
If I were flipping the channels,
I would keep flipping.
- Peppermint.
- Your makeup
does look gorgeous.
I do, however,
hate the outfit.
I think that you could have
put a lot more effort into it.
- I think
it's a little short,
so when you turn around,
like, we're seeing stuff.
- Though you fumbled
the ball a few times...
- A breast and two biscuits.
- I thought your character
was fun-loving.
I don't know
whose job it was
to, I guess,
excuse me from the table
so that, as the guest,
I knew that I could leave.
I don't know who dropped
the ball on that one.
- Can I take responsibility
for that?
I was a little confused
at the end.
- Okay.
- I'll take responsibility
for it, too.
I'm sorry,
I don't want you to think
that you were, like,
an afterthought.
- No, no, no, not at all.
But you could get
some real bitches
that would take it
personal, so...
- Dame Charlie Hides.
- I love the look tonight.
I was worried
you were gonna fall over.
Those are some high heels.
-They are very high.
-Very high.
- But what I noticed
about your performance
is that you are
a control freak.
You were so married
to those cards.
Cynthia didn't even finish
her line
and you already, like,
look, look, look.
And when you were
interviewing Naya,
when you ask somebody
a question,
you need
to let them answer it.
- It felt like you were
stepping on her lines
and the timing was off.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- To me, this does not read
as nightie,
but what I loved about you
in the challenge
was that even when Charlie
was trying to direct you
in her controlling way,
you were funny
and you messed the words up.
You were
intolerant lactose and...
-[laughs]
-You are a star.
I really think that you've,
like, come into your own.
Really well done.
- Thank you.
- Eureka.
- Again, this doesn't read
nightie to me.
This reads dominatrix.
It's so funny how this end
is really nightie
and that end is just whores.
- [laughs]
- Well, surprise, surprise,
I disagree with Michelle.
You're clearly going to bed.
You're just doing
different things
on that side of the runway.
- You two
were my favorite to watch.
Chemistry is not something
you can buy.
That's why this one
has me around still.
- [laughs]
- Up next, Nina Bo'nina Brown
Rodham Clinton.
[all laugh]
- [sniffling]
I'm gonna probably be like
the cry baby of the season.
-It's okay, mama.
-I'm sorry.
I'm just so grateful
to be here.
[sobs] I'm happy.
- Well, Nina,
if those are tears of joy,
I'd hate to see you
when you're upset.
[all laugh]
We love you, girl.
Let's go to the critiques.
- Again, it doesn't scream
nightie to me.
It screams
streetwalking whore.
And I love it!
- In the talk show,
you were serving me
the Lady Chablis realness.
The painted on spit curl
was just like
the cherry on top.
- But you're gonna need
a thicker skin
to get through
this competition.
I so appreciate
what this means to you.
I just want you to be ready
for how tough
this is gonna get.
- You all worked so hard
on this challenge,
but I have to ask
one question.
Who deserves to go home
tonight and why?
Trinity Taylor.
- Just from your critique,
it would be Charlie.
- Peppermint,
same question.
- Based on the critiques,
Charlie.
- Charlie Hides.
- Peppermint's look is a bit
more basic, so Peppermint.
- Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- Because I believe she's
a strong competition for me
and her total look,
Peppermint.
- All right, Eureka,
you're up.
- I would say Trinity.
I feel like
the ending wrap-up
might have been
a little more controlled
if we worked as a group.
And I also felt like
she was focused on herself
and not really so much
of everyone else.
- I call shade.
I take responsibility for
the things that I did wrong
and if that's the reason
why I should go home,
then I understand.
But don't tell me that
I didn't do my job as a leader,
because I did.
And I included everybody,
including you, Eureka.
- Well, I was asked
my honest opinion,
and that's my honest opinion
and I stand beside it.
- All right. Nina.
- Trinity, because
she was the captain.
But she did her job.
It's just that we didn't really
feel a part of it sometimes.
- Thank you, ladies.
Thank you for your honesty.
While you untuck backstage,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
[car engine starts]
All right.
Well, just between us squirrel
friends, what do you think?
Let's start off
with Trinity Taylor.
- Her morning talk show host,
I just didn't get it.
- I think Trinity
really tripped up
with that gag
they were doing
because it didn't allow her
to be her charming self.
Peppermint.
- My first thought
was that
it seemed like a rehearsal.
- For me, it was more about
her outfit tonight.
- The black lace shirt
with a pink wrinkled nightie,
it just was a whole bunch
of a mess.
But I liked her better of
the two in the anchor position.
- Charlie Hides.
- The walk
on the runway tonight,
she seemed tired or bored.
She just wasn't shining.
- She was my least favorite
in the challenge.
- My notes next to her name
say dead behind the eyes.
Gave up.
- [laughs]
- I'm just disappointed
that a seasoned vet like that
doesn't understand
how TV works.
She didn't allow
the moment to happen.
In fact, it almost impeded
on Cynthia Lee's performance.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- She was so fierce tonight.
She was giving, like, X-Men
weird angel/devil realness.
- In her challenge,
she was so much fun.
I couldn't
stop watching her.
Dare I say that we are crazy
for cucu puffs?
[all laugh]
-Eureka.
-I liked her immediately.
She was funny, she was real,
she was believable.
- If I see a poster
for Eureka's show,
I'm buying a ticket
and I'm showing up.
- When I find
where her show is,
do you want to go with me?
- Girl, yes.
- Nina Bo'nina Brown
Bowyer-Chapman.
- [laughs]
Walking down the runway,
she was incredible
and in the challenge,
she was on fire.
- But the vulnerability
is so raw,
I just worry about her.
- This industry
can be quite challenging,
and you can't show up to work
crying every day.
- All right. Silence.
I've made my decision.
♪ Bring back my girls-uh ♪
[Michelle laughs]
I got that
from the "Glee" show.
- You got it
[RuPaul laughs, bell dings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Welcome back, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine...
you're safe.
- Thank you.
- Trinity Taylor,
as a morning anchor,
you nearly sank your team.
I'm sorry, my dear,
but you are up for elimination.
- Okay.
- Eureka,
Nina Bo'nina Brown,
you're both safe.
- Thank you.
- You may join
the other girls.
Peppermint.
You're a good sport,
but this week,
you fumbled the ball.
Charlie Hides,
you are one fierce queen,
but this week, you put
the ain't in enter-taint-ment.
I'm sorry, Charlie,
but you are up
for elimination.
Peppermint,
join the other girls.
- Thank you.
- Two queens
stand before me.
Ladies, this is your last chance
to impress me
and save yourself
from elimination.
The time has come...
[thunder]
to lip sync
[echoing] for your life!
- This is my chance
to show the other girls
that if you go up against me
in a lip sync,
you better bring it,
because I'm going
to send these bitches home.
I want to win.
I don't care
if we're friends.
- Good luck
and don't fuck it up.
[music plays]
- ♪ Lately I've been stuck
imagining ♪
♪ What I wanna do
and what I really think ♪
♪ Time to blow out ♪
♪ I've been told
who I should do it with ♪
♪ To keep both my hands
above the blanket ♪
♪ When the light's out ♪
♪ Shame on me ♪
♪ To need release ♪
-What the hell?
-♪ Uncontrollably ♪
♪ I-I-I wanna go-o-o
all the way-ay-ay ♪
♪ Taking out
my freak tonight ♪
♪ I-I-I wanna show ♪
♪ All the dirt ♪
♪ I got running
through my mind ♪
♪ Whoa, I-I-I wanna go-o-o
all the way-ay-ay ♪
- Trinity
is selling the song.
Charlie, on the other hand,
it looks like she's telling
children to get off her lawn.
- ♪ All the dirt ♪
♪ I got running
through my mind ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪
- Come on, Charlie.
Do something, Charlie.
- I'm not
a lip sync performer.
99% of the acts
in London sing live.
So I just need Ru to say it.
Sashay away.
- ♪ I-I-I wanna go-o-o
all the way-ay-ay ♪
♪ I got running
through my mind ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪
[cheers and applause]
- Oh, my goodness.
- Ladies, I have made
my decision.
Trinity Taylor,
you went all the way tonight.
Shantay, you stay.
- Thank you.
[applause]
- You may join
the other girls.
- Thank you.
- Dame Charlie Hides.
London, Boston,
and now the world.
Sashay away.
- Thank you, Ru.
It's been a pleasure, girls.
I am a control freak.
I make no apologies
for that.
And I don't lip sync.
I sing live.
I always said,
if I get in the bottom two,
I might as well
just turn around and walk out
because I don't lip sync.
Older queens,
I'm laying down the gauntlet.
Send in
your application tape
and do better than I did,
please.
- Con-drag-ulations,
my queens.
Oh, and remember,
if you can't love yourself,
how in the hell
you gonna love somebody else?
Can I get an amen
up in "herre"?
-Amen!
- Let the music play.
- ♪ Hey, get it, girl ♪
♪ It's your world ♪
♪ Hey ♪
♪ Get it, get it, girl ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪