WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
- Whoo, that was intense.
- That was something.
- Oh, look.
- [laughs]
- Damn, she didn't waste
no time.
- I'm relieved I have
survived this lip sync.
The only thing is,
I wonder why Charlie
didn't really put up a fight.
- She threw the towel in.
She just gave up.
- Yeah, she gave the fuck up.
- There was no effort.
- Part of this competition
is knowing that
there's potential
that you're gonna lip sync,
and that is part of it.
- We all learn those songs
every single time.
- Right.
- How did it feel
to have everyone
throw you under the bus?
- I just don't agree
with everything
that everybody said.
I was the team captain,
and that should be the reason
why I was in the bottom,
not for other reasons.
- Well, I'm sure that was why
you were in the bottom.
- So moving on.
I call shade.
Eureka is sabotaging me
because
I think she's threatened.
And so now, I'm wishing
I would've thrown her
under the bus
and said
for her to be sent home.
- Shea!
- Congratulations.
- Congrats.
[cheering]
- The winner!
- Yes!
- Nice try, lady.
[laughs]
- Shea and Sasha
have definitely bonded,
and they really slayed the game.
Good for them.
But it's now time
for me turn up the volume.
I have to rise to the top.
- There's some girls who
are so cocky and confident.
I wouldn't mind
seeing certain people
struggle a little bit
and be in the bottom.
Sue me.
- The winner
of "RuPaul's Drag Race"
receives a one-year supply
of Anastasia
Beverly Hills Cosmetics
and a cash prize of $100,000.
With extra special
guest judges Todrick Hall
and Meghan Trainor.
- ♪ RuPaul's Drag Race ♪
- ♪ May the best woman ♪
- ♪ Best woman win ♪
- ♪ Do, do, do them all ♪
- Ready, pet?
- I'm ready, pal.
Good morning, bitches.
We're back.
- Hello, hello, hello.
[cheering]
- Come on, Mama Ru.
- All right.
Who's up for a mini challenge
featuring hot,
bulging, menseses?
[cheering]
Oh, pit crew.
[gasping and cheering]
Now, for today's mini challenge,
each of you needs to shoot
a sexy selfie
with Jason, Jared, and Yadir,
as in, frankly, "Ya-deer,"
I do give a damn.
[all laugh]
Time to slip into quick drag.
Ready, go!
[footsteps]
- You always know it's Aja
when you hear them hooves.
- First up is Peppermint.
- Hey, boys.
All right, let's do it.
I'm gonna get right here.
- This is complicated.
This looks like the cover
of the September issue
of something.
Surf's up, Peppermint.
Alexis Michelle.
- Boys, we're gonna lift me.
- Uh-oh, here we go.
- Can you get under my leg?
- [laughs]
Oh! All hands on deck.
- I think I'm just gonna
kind of get on my knees.
- How many times
have you said that, Aja?
- It's one of my catch phrases.
- Chins up, all of them.
- Let's get soaking wet.
- Careful. There's
no lifeguard on duty.
She don't do anything
nice and easy.
- Hola, Mama RuPaul.
- Let me guess.
Is this gonna involve
your cucu at all?
- Aiy,
how you got it? Yes.
There's cucu for everybody,
guys.
Do not have to fight, okay?
- Yes, honey, I've got
a lovely bunch of cucu nuts.
Valentina, come on round.
- Wait, Ru, Ru, Ru, can you
present me as Miss Venezuela?
- Yes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the reigning Miss Venezuela,
Valentina.
Ah.
[laughter]
- I just want to show diversity,
so I give them, like,
cholo homeboy, like...
[RuPaul laughs]
- Ladies, one of you
really out-selfied yourself.
The winner is...
Alexis Michelle.
Con-drag-ulations.
- Sorry that my swimsuit
selfie game is so strong.
Not sorry.
- You've won a $1,000 gift card
from FierceQueen.com.
[applause]
- Great.
- Now, taking a sexy selfie
was the perfect way for you
to get into character,
because for this week's
maxi challenge,
you'll be starring in Broadway's
newest mega sensation.
Kardashian: The Musical.
[cheering and laughter]
- I love the Kardashians.
I would say
it is a guilty pleasure,
but I don't feel guilty
about it.
- It's a hip-hop
herstory lesson
and a lip sync extravaganza
all rolled into one.
- Ooh!
- ♪KardashianTheMusical.
- ♪ You're really Kardashian ♪
[laughter]
- Alex Michelle, since
you won the mini challenge,
you get to choose your role.
Then you get to assign
the others.
Gentlemen, start your engines,
and may the best woman win.
- Whoo!
[cheers and applause]
- Let's give her a listen.
- We're listening to the track
and it is ha-larious.
There's all the Kardashians.
There's even Britney Spears.
- I want to be Britney or Paris.
- I made the Banji moment,
please.
I want to be Banji.
- I am all for it,
and I want to be Kim.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
I shall be your mama-ger,
Kris Jenner.
- Yes.
- Playing the part
of North West, Eureka.
- Aw.
[applause]
- Playing Kim Kardashian,
Cynthia.
- [whistles] Uh-oh.
How the freak I'm gonna do her?
- Miss Kylie,
with your selfie game
and your makeup skills,
Farrah Moan.
- The one with the lips.
- Playing the part of Kendall,
the fashionista, Miss Valentina.
- Oh, why, thank you.
- Oh, my Kendall.
- Kourtney, Aja.
Lindsay Lohan, Sasha.
- Yes!
- Paris Hilton, Trinity Taylor.
That's the one I wanted!
- Playing the part of Britney
is Peppermint.
- Bitch, I don't even get
a Jenner.
In Kardashian: The Musical,
my black ass is playing
Britney motherfucking Spears.
- Playing the part
of Blac Chyna,
the newest Kardashian,
Ms. Shea Coulee.
- Yes!
- Really, bitch?
- Playing the part of Khloe,
Nina Bo'nina Brown.
- I love Khloe.
- I don't see it for me,
but okay.
- Tough crowd.
- I'm not too happy with
the role that I'm given.
She knew I was whispering to her
that I wanted Blac Chyna,
and so that kind of
puts me in a place
of I can't trust these hoes.
- Can't please them all.
- Coming up...
- Nina's in a bad mood,
Aja doesn't know the moves
and I don't know
what Cynthia's doing.
- Don't give me that look.
We're fucked.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- We're not famous for nothing.
♪ We're the Kardashians ♪
- That's hot.
- Duh.
- I'm so excited for
Kardashian: The Musical.
I'm obsessed
with the Kardashians,
and I can't wait to get in
my Kylie Jenner fantasy
and hopefully slay
this challenge.
- Why don't they have Tyga
in this?
- Who's that?
- He's Blac Chyna's baby daddy.
He got Blac Chyna pregnant,
then started dating
Kylie Jenner,
and now Rob Kardashian's
marrying Blac Chyna.
- It's scandalous.
- All right. Come on over here,
Miss North West.
- Come on, Blac Chyna.
[laughs]
- This should prove to be fun.
- Yes.
How are you feeling?
- Honestly, I feel okay.
My knee's a little swollen.
I have to use crutches,
but I'm not
gonna let it stop me.
When I was doing
the cheerleading challenge,
I landed wrong
and my knee just popped.
The last couple weeks,
I've been able to push through,
but now it's hurting,
so I have to use crutches.
But I have a positive attitude.
I'm going to do
whatever they throw my way.
You give me a role, honey,
and I'll make it work.
- Where's the outfit
you're gonna wear to do Khloe?
Oh, girl, you never unpacked?
- You know.
- I mean, don't be so
discouraged about your part.
Like, I think you'll do fine.
- I should have been Blac Chyna.
I'm not being funny,
but, I mean, I love Shea,
but, like, she has a weird body,
and Blac Chyna
is known for her body.
She's not shoo.
Blac Chyna was my role.
That's what I wanted.
I had no other character
in mind except Blac Chyna,
and I'm very upset.
Now I know there's gonna be
a lot of favoritism. Shoo.
- Bo'nina, you shouldn't
say things like that.
I think you're great.
- Oh, it is what it is.
- Nina Bo'nina wants Blac Chyna,
but there's only one Blac Chyna,
and there's three black people.
You're gonna play a white girl.
- Hi, ladies.
- Hey.
- It's time to work
with our choreographer
and director to the stars,
Todrick Hall.
- Are you ready for a little
choreography with a K?
[laughter]
- Yes!
- This is Chester.
He's gonna be assisting me
today.
I'm gonna throw choreography
at you really, really fast.
Are you feeling okay?
- Yeah, girl, nothing
holds big girl down.
I'll give you a one-legged hop
move like "Saved By The Bell."
[laughter]
- Okay, so we're gonna go over
all of you guys' main parts.
- Cool.
- Eureka, North West,
you represent the future
of North West.
How do you perceive playing her?
- Well, first of all,
she's 403 pounds and 6-foot-4.
She's crippled, obviously.
- [laughs]
Make sure that
you're doing whatever you can
with your upper body
and with your face.
- Okay.
- Ready.
- ♪ I became the best of rest ♪
♪ By nursing on Kim's breast ♪
I'm the new...
- You can stop the music.
I would love to see
some subtle choices
that feel regal
and command us to watch you
without it being,
like, such a predictable,
like, titty-squeeze moment,
you know what I mean?
- Okay.
- It's gonna be hard
for Eureka to stand out
hobbling through the moves.
I don't know what she gonna do.
- Shea, do you have any
old school nineties moves
you would like to pull out?
Or can you give us, like,
one of these, like...
- Oh, yeah.
♪ I'm stealing the spotlight ♪
♪ And no one can stop me ♪
♪ Now you riding my coattails ♪
♪ And liking my selfies, uh ♪
- Yeah, that's great.
- All right, cool.
- I was kind of hoping
she would trip a little bit.
- I have high expectations
for you tomorrow.
- But she didn't trip,
so what can I say?
- Can we have Alexis, Aja,
Cynthia, Nina.
- Kourt, so just a couple steps
and then I think
I just made up a word.
- Yeah, perfect.
- ♪ Kourt, Khlo, I think
I just made up a word ♪
- ♪ Mama-ger ♪
- Okay. Cynthia,
you got to remember
to come up to the front, 'cause
it's gonna look very clumsy
if you don't make it
up to the front.
- Okay.
- Make sure you don't let
your sisters upstage you,
'cause that's not
what Kim is about.
Can we try all that
from the beginning?
- Wait, is it one?
- On two.
- Two, that's it, right?
- No, no, no, no, no.
Maybe it's a cha-cha.
One, two, three, four,
five, six...
- So wait.
One, two... wait, what?
- Girl, how you Puerto Rican
and don't know how to do that?
- Three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, I want to...
- That's what
I was doing, bitch.
- No, no, no, no.
You were doing like...
[laughter]
- Okay, ladies, we're gonna have
to move to the next section.
Can you grab her arm like this?
And can you be here like this?
Like, can you have your hands,
like, maybe on her shoulders?
I know.
It's a tough life, baby.
Black lives matter.
Let's do this one more time.
- ♪ And we'll
rake in the dough ♪
- ♪ Mama-ger ♪
- And you're here.
- I'm here, yeah, got you.
- Yeah, 'cause
she's gonna go down.
- Got you, I got you.
- Can we stop the music?
You...
Nina, you got to make sure
that even if you mess up,
that you don't show that
on your face.
Because if you do that face
tomorrow...
Nina?
- Hmm?
- How do you feel about today?
- Um, I was kind of down
about my character.
- Why would you be down
about being Khloe?
- Because I wanted
Blac Chyna, so...
- Tomorrow, we got to have
all that gone.
I could sense that energy
right now.
It's a little sketchy boots.
- Nina just can't seem
to let it go.
- You are
the three main sisters.
Right now, it looks
a little bit all over the place.
- Nina's in a bad mood,
Aja doesn't know the moves,
and I don't know
what Cynthia's doing.
And they are the main characters
of the piece.
They are the Kardashians.
This is a problem.
- Let's move forward.
Can you all give a hand thing?
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight,
like that.
- [laughs] Love it.
- ♪ We love our big sisters ♪
♪ They're, oh, so adoring ♪
- Just make sure
when you hit your hands
that they actually hit
and you're, like,
not missing each other.
- ♪ We love our big sisters ♪
♪ They're, oh, so adoring ♪
- I was never a clapper.
- Y'all think y'all can do this?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- We can do it.
- ♪ We love our big sisters ♪
♪ They're, oh, so adoring ♪
- Don't give me that look.
- You also
have to stay in character,
because right now
I'm seeing you two,
but I'm not seeing
Kylie and Kendall.
You've got a lot of work to do.
Like, a lot.
- We're fucked.
- Coming up...
- Did my nose get thinner?
Oh, my God, I think I've
lost weight in my nose.
- It's a Hanukkah miracle.
Aja's nose got smaller.
- Ha!
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs
- Yay, yay, it's today!
- Come on, cripple.
- Come on, hobble, hobble.
- Today's performance day.
It's really important for me
to do well in this challenge
because my knee is hurt
and if I happen to have
to lip sync for my life,
I'm gonna be at a disadvantage.
- Look at these little
petite ballet shoes.
Who do these belong to?
- How you feeling today,
Miss Thang?
How's your knee?
- I feel good.
I'm trying to rhinestone
my little ballet slippers
'cause I have to wear flats.
There's just something
about flats
that make me not feel
like a drag queen.
- When life gives you lemons...
- You take rhinestones
and cover up that lemon.
- Absolutely.
- I am not a huge fan of Eureka,
but seeing
what she's going through,
I feel really bad for Eureka.
If you can get through
the things
that you've been through in
your life, this is a cakewalk.
- Trust, girl.
- Even if you're hobbling.
[laughter]
- Did my nose get thinner?
Did I have a nose job
while I was here?
It does look thinner.
- Oh, my God,
I think I lose weight
in my nose.
Am I bugging?
- It's a Hanukkah miracle.
Aja's nose got smaller.
- Ha!
- I'm having a day today
where I just really
want to clear the air
and approach Sasha and Valentina
and apologize
for being disrespectful.
- Can I tell you guys about one
of the disorders that I have?
- Eating.
- Don't joke about that.
- Sasha?
- Yes.
- Can I talk to you
and Valentina really quick?
- Yeah, of course.
- I never really got a chance
to apologize
specifically to you all
over the joke that I cracked
about eating disorders.
You were having
a vulnerable moment,
and it's not respectful of me
to diminish anyone else's.
- Mm-hmm.
- And I'm really sorry for that.
- I also apologize to you.
It's a sensitive issue for me
because I was severely anorexic
for my entire early twenties.
I was so, like,
unhealthy looking.
People would, like,
call me E.T. and stuff
'cause of the way that
I looked on the street.
It was like I have...
I still have a lot...
I have a lot of hurt
from it still.
- Are you okay?
- This is just such
a touchy subject for me
because I do probably still
have an eating disorder.
- Oh, sweetheart.
- And before I left,
I promised my mom
that I would eat
every single day.
It's so hard because sometimes
I feel like
I'm force feeding myself.
- I applaud you guys
for opening up
because in the past,
I've had a deep, deep battle
with bulimia.
About three years ago,
I was feeling
all these pressures
by just the beauty standards
that exist
within the gay community,
and it's something that I've
had a lot of shame about.
Sometimes
people don't understand
that though we come across
as these really strong,
beautiful creatures,
that sometimes we're really
struggling on the inside.
- Underneath.
- I honestly never thought
I'd be able to talk
to other drag queens this openly
about these issues.
- Yeah, 'cause it's not
just a thing with women,
I'll tell you that.
It's very prevalent
in the gay community
to have an eating disorder.
- I'm surprised
about how many girls
have struggled with this.
There's power in being able
to confide in your sisters
and have them support you.
- This is RuPaul's
Best Friend Race.
- This RuPaul's
Best Group Therapy Race.
[laughter]
[RuPaul laughs]
- ♪ Cover girl,
put the bass in your walk ♪
♪ Head to toe,
let your whole body talk ♪
[cheers and applause]
- Yeah!
- Welcome to the main stage
of "RuPaul's Drag Race."
Michelle Visage,
seen any good shows lately?
- I just starred in
"The Best Little Whorehouse
in South Plainfield."
- Oh, con-drag-ulations.
- I was the house.
- [laughs]
Fashion superstar
Carson Kressley,
how'd you get a ticket?
- I waited in line for 16 days.
[laughter]
- And Broadway baby
Todrick Hall,
how'd my girls do yesterday?
- I smell a Tony.
- Like Tony Danza?
- More like a Tony Braxton.
- Oh, I can breathe again.
[laughter]
And the mega talented
Meghan Trainor.
I love your latest album,
"Thank You."
- Thank you.
- You.
- This week,
we challenged our queens
to a lip sync extravaganza,
and now they're ready
to make herstory
with Kardashian:
The Musical.
Gentlemen, start your engines,
and may the best woman win.
Coming up...
- Bitch, you turned it out.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- ♪ How could one woman
take her family of girls ♪
- ♪ And make a media dynasty
that took over the world? ♪
- ♪ You can criticize
and player-hate ♪
♪ And say you don't care ♪
♪ But the Met Ball would suck ♪
♪ If their asses weren't there ♪
- ♪ So would E!, Instagram,
Snapchat and the S-vies ♪
- ♪ They fuss and fight
and disrespect ♪
♪ But always end up besties ♪
- ♪ These Calabasas queens
give us life ♪
♪ They're so glam ♪
- ♪ And here is how this clan
became the new royal fam ♪
- ♪ Ily ♪
- ♪ Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ I'm Britney and you
should hear how I sing ♪
- ♪ I'm Lindsay ♪ [coughs]
♪ And fire crotch is my thing ♪
- ♪ That's hot. I'm Paris ♪
♪ And I don't
have to do anything ♪
♪ But bitches bow down
'cause I'm the new Miss Thing ♪
- ♪ Paparazzi popping pictures ♪
♪ 'Cause we're dressed
so fancy ♪
♪ The press only posts when
we're not wearing panties ♪
- Oops, I think
I just did it again.
[laughter]
- ♪ Hey, you, get out the way ♪
♪ Our pussies are on fire ♪
- ♪ No, they're just on
display-yay-yay-yay-yay ♪
- Oh, my God, she's right.
- Oh, my God.
- It's totally hot.
- Yeah.
- Anyways, who are you?
- I'm Kim.
- Kim who?
- Ahem.
- ♪ Kimberly Kardashian ♪
- Who?
- That's what
I thought you said.
- ♪ Hey, Britney,
can I be in your gang? ♪
- ♪ If you hold her Birkin bags
♪ Then maybe you can hang ♪
[coughs]
- ♪ Hey, Paris,
how'd you get so famous? ♪
- ♪ You make a home movie
and you just act shameless ♪
- What kind of movie?
[RuPaul laughs]
- ♪ Kimmy,
I should be your manager ♪
♪ You know, since I'm your mom ♪
- ♪ Mom, you're
such an amateur ♪
- ♪ You're definitely mom ♪
- ♪ Mama-ger ♪
- That's me.
♪ Is that absurd? ♪
♪ Kourt, Khlo, I think
I just made up a word ♪
- ♪ Mama-ger ♪
- ♪ I'll get you on a TV show ♪
♪ I'll film you eating salad ♪
♪ And we'll rake in the dough ♪
- ♪ Mama-ger ♪
♪ We're sisters ♪
♪ A-whoo ♪
♪ Sisters ♪
- ♪ I'm Kim
and I'm the bombshell ♪
♪ Banging booty you know well ♪
♪ There's Ray J and then Kanye ♪
♪ With a pit stop in the NBA ♪
And I break the internet
every other day.
Suckas.
- ♪ I'm Khloe
and I only date ballers ♪
♪ Big sweet butt
that makes them all holla ♪
♪ The gay boys' favorite,
you know it's true ♪
♪ Puts us large and in charge ♪
♪ But you already knew-ooh ♪
- ♪ Sisters ♪
- ♪ Are you keeping up?
I'm Kourtney ♪
♪ I'm the little big sister
in the family ♪
♪ I'm educated
with a college degree ♪
♪ So why do I let Scott
stick his Disick in me? ♪
- ♪ Sisters ♪
♪ A-whoo ♪
♪ We're the OG-3 ♪
- ♪ Don't you mean four,
like four sisters? ♪
- Mom!
- ♪ Sisters ♪
♪ A-whoo ♪
♪ It's the U.S. of K. ♪
♪ No one's gonna come
to get away ♪
♪ Sisters ♪
[telephone rings]
- Hello.
- Kendall, Kylie,
please report to your...
- ♪ Mama-ger ♪
- ♪ We love our big sisters ♪
♪ They're, oh, so adoring ♪
♪ But your storylines ♪
♪ Were starting to get
a little boring ♪
♪ We were in the background ♪
♪ But we've come a long way ♪
♪ Now, you can't spell
Kardashian ♪
♪ Without a big, fat J ♪
- Get it?
- Yeah.
- ♪ Hey, my name is Kendall
and I'm a supermodel ♪
♪ I took to the runway
like a baby with the bottle ♪
♪ I've walked for Oscar,
Karl and Diane von Furstie ♪
♪ I shun the limelight
while my sisters are thirsty ♪
- ♪ I'm Kylie ♪
♪ I'm the one with the lips ♪
♪ 80 million fans
want my makeup tips ♪
♪ I've got my own
clothing line ♪
♪ And my own mouth plumper ♪
♪ Got a Jenner face
and Kardashian dumper ♪
- ♪ We've got
the best selling apps ♪
♪ We're an online addiction ♪
♪ Sisters ruling the world ♪
♪ And we'll keep on kicking ♪
- Yes.
- ♪ Don't think y'all
could do this without me ♪
♪ Blac Chyna up in here ♪
- Whoo!
- ♪ Blac Chyna ♪
♪ I'm the video vixen
of the Kardashians ♪
♪ In a couple weeks
I'm trashing that ♪
♪ Had a baby with Tyga,
but he dumped me for Kylie ♪
♪ I'm the Kardashian
wrecking ball ♪
♪ But don't call me Miley ♪
♪ I'm stealing the spotlight
and no one can help me ♪
♪ You're riding my coattails
and liking my selfies, uh ♪
♪ All right, I'm out, I'm out ♪
[laughter]
- Whoo!
- ♪ This new American dynasty
has only just begun ♪
♪ Next is the galaxy,
so step aside, hon ♪
♪ My name is North West ♪
♪ Don't be acting
all distressed ♪
♪ I became the best of the rest
by nursing on Kim's breast ♪
♪ I'm the new face
of reality royalty ♪
♪ Had my first fragrance out
when I was only age three ♪
♪ President at nine ♪
♪ Then queen of the Milky Way ♪
♪ Then I cured cancer ♪
♪ Yes, it started with a K ♪
♪ Now, Kim is my mama-ger,
but Kris is still here ♪
♪ She gonna be running the show
for 3,000 more years ♪
- Selfie. Click.
- Do we still take selfies
in the future?
- That's hot.
- ♪ The greatest story
ever told ♪
♪ And we've only just begun ♪
♪ We're not famous for nothing ♪
♪ We're the Kardashians ♪
- ♪ Kardashians ♪
- Now streaming on DVD.
[applause]
- Coming up...
- Everyone was looking at you.
- I would definitely
nominate her
at least for a Tony Award.
- She totally
blew an opportunity.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Category is faux fur fabulous.
Peppermint.
- No poodles were killed
in the making of this garment.
- She's a Power Puff Girl.
- Trinity Taylor.
Here she's savage beauty
and here's she's
childlike savage beauty.
- I know it's faux fur,
but I believe she just
flashed us some beaver.
- Sasha Velour.
Slow down.
Why you always Russian?
- Dr. Zhiva-go, girl, go.
- I'd love to take a peek
behind her iron curtain.
- Alexis Michelle.
Oh, a touch of mink.
- She's so cold.
- All of a sudden,
I want some honey.
- What becomes a legend most?
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- Clearly, she wants to be
spotted in this.
- Is that snow leopard because
I think I just downloaded that?
[Michelle laughs]
Nina Bo'nina Brown Girly Brown.
Well, you've heard
of Cruella DeVille?
This is Coupe DeVille.
- Someone called
in the clydesdales.
[laughter]
- Aja.
- She's frozen.
Let it go.
- Oh, these aren't frozen.
- No, that's what I call
a winter's tail.
Valentina.
Her anaconda do.
- Touch the snakeskin.
Touch all of the snakeskin.
- 10, 10, 10, 10.
- Farrah Moan.
I think she's a member
of the green party.
- With that ass.
- Yeah.
- I'm green with envy.
- Fraggle Rock fashion week.
Shea Coulee.
- Oh.
- She's got a mouth on her.
- I think her boobs
just winked at me.
- She's serving face.
- Eureka!
There's a whore in Whoville.
[laughter]
Stop relying on those crutches.
- [laughs]
- Welcome, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
When I call your name,
please step forward.
Peppermint.
Alexis Michelle.
Farrah Moan.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
Nina Bo'nina Brown
Kennedy Onassis.
Shea Coulee.
Ladies, you represent the peaks
and the pits of the week.
The rest of you are safe.
You may leave the stage.
Now it's time
for the judges critiques,
starting with Peppermint.
- Let's talk about
your Britney Spears.
You had the body language
and you were committed
to the character.
Totally nailed it.
- And I think you looked
beautiful on the runway tonight,
but there's something
about the skirt.
It almost feels like
an afterthought to the top half.
- Up next, Alexis Michelle.
- I know Kris Jenner
and I think you embodied her.
- I just want to be
your best friend
because of that performance.
- Bitch, you turned it out.
But on this main stage,
it could not be more basic.
- I was thinking, like,
this is a Studio 54 night out
on a winter night.
- This is literally
something that you can buy
at any store in the mall,
shoes included.
Just step it up,
because that Kris Jenner
was the business.
- Up next, Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
- This kind of fur,
like, maxi gown,
I do think it swallows you
a little bit,
which is not always a bad thing,
but it is in this case.
- We need to talk about Kim.
What upset me the most
was that
you didn't know the words.
- And it's tough,
because you were Kim.
Everyone was looking at you.
- When it's a lip sync number,
you kind of
have to know the words.
- Up next, Nina Bo'nina Brown
Champagne King.
- This runway look,
it's a very, like, Mary J. Blige
nineties, going to get milk
in the middle of winter
in Chicago.
I get what you're selling.
I'm not sure I want to buy it.
- You got the role
of Khloe Kardashian.
You knew your words,
you were on it,
you had the choreography,
but I didn't get much Khloe.
- You were a little bit
difficult
to work with yesterday.
Can you please tell me
what was going on?
- My mind was very set
on Blac Chyna,
and when it was given to Shea,
I thought it was like a setup
in a way for me to, like, fail.
- What we just heard
was that there was
a conspiracy theory
that sounded more like paranoia.
Is this an ongoing theme
throughout your life?
- I've always mentioned how
the Atlanta scene has treated me
and I felt like
they never embraced me,
and so I just feel like people
just have something against me.
- I've seen so many people
wear their victimhood
as a badge of honor.
Don't let that sabotage
your opportunity here.
- Sorry.
Thank you.
- Up next, Farrah Moan.
- Your makeup's always flawless.
I just think you're
a little heavy-handed
on your highlighter.
So every time you turn,
all I see is, like,
metal, metal.
- I felt like there was no
personality in the performance
and it did take me a minute,
even with the turquoise hair,
to be, like,
which one was Kylie.
- You could have made
some character choices,
pouty faces,
to, like, do something
that was signature Kylie.
It was just very underwhelming.
- Up next, Shea Coulee.
- This look, I love it,
and I felt like
I was at
a Jeremy Scott runway show.
And you were a dream
to work with.
I just love everything
about your energy,
and you came out here
and nailed it.
- You stole the entire show.
That's all
I was talking about, too,
that dance break and how
I want to be you so bad.
- Yeah, girl,
we'll go to the club.
- Yes, girl.
- All right, thank you, ladies.
I think we've heard enough.
While you untuck backstage,
the judges and I
will deliberate.
[car engine starts]
Just between us mama-gers,
let's talk about Peppermint.
- I though she did great.
She was channeling Britney.
She was thinking
of Britney poses
that were signature,
and it was a slam-dunk.
- She didn't really
look like Britney at all,
but she embodied the carefree
feeling of Britney.
- On the runway tonight,
I just didn't like that skirt.
And it happened last week, too.
These plain pink bottoms
are getting boring.
- Like, I'm right here.
- I'm sorry, Carson.
- Alexis Michelle.
- The runway look
was a really boring effort.
- But Alexis
was a dream to work with.
She was great on stage.
I would definitely nominate her
at least for a Tony Award.
- Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
She's so charming,
but she wasn't able
to apply that to Kim.
- Not knowing the lyrics
was inexcusable.
- I'd be willing
to give her a pass
if she knew a certain chunk
of the lyrics.
And also,
her faking was terrible.
- Nina Bo'nina Brown.
- I'm a fan of Nina,
but I feel like
she was a little pouty
and kind of just said, like,
oh, this wasn't the role
that I wanted,
so I'm really not
gonna try very hard.
- It was very difficult for me
to find the energy
to work with her.
She would not give eye contact.
When you gave her a correction,
she would be like, I heard you.
That would be her response.
- This happened last week.
We started to get into it.
But tonight it was like,
oh, uh-oh,
this is actually
a really big red flag.
- Mm-hmm.
Farrah Moan.
- She couldn't maintain
simple choreography.
- I didn't get anything from her
during the musical number.
- She could have done
so many things with her lips.
She could have done
the bottle...
That looked really obscene.
I didn't mean that.
- It looked very natural
for you, actually.
- I know, I definitely
would've sucked on a cup.
- She totally blew
an opportunity right there.
- Shea Coulee.
I was so impressed with her
dropping it on that stage.
- Shea killed it as Blac Chyna,
and then she came out here
on the runway
with her faux fur challenge.
It's super fun.
She presented it great.
Tonight is a stellar night
for Shea Coulee.
- Silence.
I've made my decision.
Bring back my girls.
[RuPaul laughs, bell rings]
[RuPaul laughs]
- Welcome back, ladies.
I've made some decisions.
Peppermint.
You're safe.
Alexis Michelle.
Your Kris Jenner was spot on,
but your faux fur
was a faux pas.
You're safe.
Shea Coulee.
Girl, your Blac Chyna
done broke my internet.
Con-drag-ulations.
You're the winner
of this week's challenge.
[applause]
You've won a Caribbean
cruise package for two,
plus airfare
from All Out Vacations.
- Thank you so much.
I really appreciate that.
And, mama, you look
so good tonight,
it's damn near sinful.
- [laughs]
Nina Bo'nina Brown.
You hit the runway
looking like Mary J. Blige,
but please, girl, no more drama.
Cynthia Lee Fontaine.
As Kim Kardashian,
you didn't keep up.
Farrah Moan. As Kylie,
the judges weren't a sucker
for your pucker.
Nina Bo'nina Brown,
you're safe.
You may join the other girls.
- Thank y'all.
- Cynthia Lee, Farrah,
I'm sorry, my dears, but
you are up for elimination.
- [whimpers]
- Two queens stand before me.
Prior to tonight, you were asked
to prepare
a lip sync performance
of "Woman Up" by Meghan Trainor.
Ladies, this is your last chance
to impress me
and save yourself
from elimination.
The time has come...
[thunder]
To lip sync
[echoing] for your life.
- Cynthia Lee Fontaine,
hey, this is
your chance to stay.
Just slay that lip sync.
- Good luck,
and don't fuck it up.
[music plays]
- ♪ Put your favorite heels on ♪
♪ 'Cause they make you
feel strong ♪
♪ When you're lookin' good ♪
♪ You know you're gonna
have a good time ♪
♪ Don't forget mascara ♪
♪ And to keep your head up ♪
♪ Like Madonna would ♪
♪ Rub her lipstick
redder than wine ♪
♪ So let's go ♪
♪ Roll your bumper
and whine slow ♪
♪ Show the world
you can shine, glow ♪
♪ 'Cause you got the light now ♪
♪ You got
the light now, ow! ♪
♪ All my girls raise your hand ♪
♪ If you don't need a man ♪
♪ 'Cause you're more
than good enough ♪
♪ You gotta woman up, woman up ♪
♪ All my girls,
we show, we groove ♪
♪ Just make them remember you ♪
♪ This one's for all my girls ♪
♪ My girls who woman up,
woman up ♪
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
♪ Woman up, woman up ♪
♪ Mwah ♪
♪ Hey ♪
- ♪ All my girls
raise your hand ♪
- ♪ Raise your hand ♪
♪ Time to take a stand ♪
♪ Mm-hmm ♪
♪ You gotta woman up, woman up ♪
♪ All my girls,
we show, we groove ♪
♪ Just make them remember you ♪
♪ This one's for all my girls ♪
♪ My girls who woman up,
woman up ♪
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
[cheers and applause]
- Ladies...
I need a moment.
Would you please excuse me?
- Ru walks off the set.
What's going on?
- I am so confused.
- I'm nervous.
Like, shit is going down.
- Thank you for waiting, ladies.
I have made my decision.
Eureka.
Would you please step forward?
We've been in touch
with the doctor.
You need time to heal,
and in good conscience,
I cannot allow you
to continue in the competition.
- [sobs]
No.
- Please know
that you are loved here
and that you have
an open invitation
to return next season.
- Thank you.
- But for now, I'm so sad to say
sashay away.
- Thank you guys so much.
And I will be back.
I love you guys.
[sobbing]
- I'm so sorry.
- I love you guys so much.
Thank you all so much.
I love you.
- Te amo.
- Yes, bitch.
[applause]
- I'm starting to crutch off
and I hear
the whole crew behind me...
Just applauding.
Well, you found it once
and you'll find it again.
[laughter]
- Yes, bitch.
- I just feel sad that...
I understand doctor's orders.
All I can do
is move forward, you know.
The love that I've been given
during this entire situation,
I finally feel like
I'm a part of something
that's bigger than me,
you know, and I don't know
how the hell that's possible.
'Cause y'all know mama
is big as hell.
I have an open invitation
for Season 10,
so y'all watch out.
- Ladies, there has been
too much loss here tonight.
Shantay, you both stay.
[applause]
Remember, if you can't
love yourself,
how in the hell you gonna
love somebody else?
Can I get an amen up in here?
- Amen!
- All right,
now let the music play.
- ♪ Hey, get it, girl ♪
♪ It's your world, hey ♪
♪ Get it, get it, girl ♪
♪ Whoa-oh-oh ♪