Welcome to The Kelly File, everyone.
I'm Megyn Kelly.
Breaking tonight,
polls are moving, the race is changing,
and more than a dozen
Republican candidates
are trying to make themselves heard
with a little more than one week left
till the debate
that could change everything.
And we're the gateway.
We, the questioners, are the gateway.
We at Fox and CNN
and everybody else who gets a chance
to actually moderate
a presidential debate with these guys.
I mean, these guys,
they deserve to face tough questioning.
As Chris says, and I agree,
they want George Washington's job
and they better earn it.
They better show the American people
they're worthy of it.
A lot of folks assumed
Donald Trump would flame out by now.
They have been proven wrong. Now wait.
Here. We gotta get to this
because this is just breaking
on The Daily Beast.
The headline is,
"Ex-wife: Donald Trump
made me feel violated during sex.
Ivana Trump once accused
the real-estate tycoon of quote, 'rape.'"
Somebody who speaks for Donald Trump
has come out and denied it as well
and added that legally, he says,
"you cannot rape your spouse."
Here's the one thing
you probably know about me.
I have a big mouth.
Roger, you have Megyn on line one.
- Megyn.
- Morning, Roger.
What'd you do to piss off Trump?
We did a segment on recent coverage
of his ex-wife's rape claim.
You're giving that oxygen
before the first goddamn debate?
Roger, we had a full-screen
of Ivana's recantation. Which is soft.
She accused him during a divorce.
Well, his lawyer, Michael Cohen,
claims you can't rape a spouse.
It pissed me off.
Great. The future of Fox News
is now a goddamn feminist.
- No. I'm not a feminist. I'm a lawyer.
- We need him.
Clean this up. Now.
Unfortunately, when it comes
to politicians and the media,
Roger Ailes knows his shit.
Appointed head of the Fox News channel
by media mogul Rupert Murdoch,
Roger transformed cable news,
pushing Fox to the forefront.
Years before, to get Nixon elected,
he created the modern town-hall debate.
To get Reagan elected, he made him
address the elephant in the room.
I will not make age
an issue of this campaign.
I am not going to exploit
my opponent's youth and inexperience.
To get George H. W. Bush elected,
somebody did the Willie Horton ads.
Roger denies it was him... a lot.
I have been astounded
at the number of Americans
who are fine with our country moving
in a socialist direction.
Here we go.
Their views on capitalism
are quite alarming.
News is like a ship.
You take your hands off the wheel
and it pulls hard to the left.
Hey, look at this. James Murdoch.
Tell me those lips haven't sucked cock.
This is what nepotism gets you.
Roger rules Fox from behind these doors,
on the second floor.
When employees say, "the second floor,"
they mean Roger,
or the many VPs paid to enact his will
without qualms or questions.
Now, I know what some of you
are thinking, and, no,
Roger does not tell us what to say on air.
He doesn't have to.
- Love that dress, Megyn.
- Thank you.
No, really. I love it.
He's not horny. He's just ambitious.
Roger is always watching.
The Eagles postponed their appearance
because co-founder, Glenn Frey,
is too ill to travel.
In a statement, the band announced...
Morons.
The phone in his office
connects directly to the control room,
which is down on the first floor.
- Yes, sir?
- You fucking idiots!
That's not Glenn Frey, it's Don Henley!
- Dump the B-roll.
- Dump it.
Back to anchor. That's not Glenn Frey,
that's Don fucking Henley!
- Oh, shoot.
- What the fuck, Kayla?
I'm sorry. I don't know secular music.
The Eagles?
- Only the biggest band of the '70s.
- When my mom was a toddler.
- They all look the same. They're just old.
- Oh, my God.
Down in the basement is the Fox newsroom.
All our shows have crews
who work in these pods.
This is my staff.
Hey, guys.
We're below the city,
so it smells like mold.
But there hasn't been a rat sighting
in four months.
- Four months.
- Yeah!
The anchors and their key producers
have base camps.
Here, on 17 and 18.
Often decorated with viewer art.
And everyone in this building,
even Roger, answers to eight.
The eighth floor is home
to CEO Rupert Murdoch and his sons.
This is the power behind the power.
The actual studios
are scattered around the building.
Most anchor and show offices are here.
Above are Fox Business, radio,
New York Post and The Wall Street Journal.
Most of the American
conservative establishment.
In one building.
The stage is finally set for
tonight's Republican debate in Cleveland.
All the candidates
are looking for a boost tonight,
but only ten of them have a chance
to appeal to voters in prime time.
Trump has a real problem with women.
I wanna ask about it.
You can back that up?
Yes.
Good morning.
Morning, Chris.
Excuse me.
Do you think that's it?
Sorry.
It's probably nerves.
No. When I'm nervous, I hear my heart.
I can't hear it.
That's your first question?
Is this some feminist thing?
- She's not a feminist.
- It goes to his electability.
Did you run it past Tom Lowell?
We can go after Trump.
- The second floor said that?
- No.
The eighth. The Murdochs.
Rupert called Roger and said, about Trump,
enough is enough.
Look, all Trump does is watch Fox.
Roger gave him air for his crazy theories
and idiot grievances.
Why? 'Cause Roger shares a lot of them.
Are you sure you wanna take that on?
Yes.
It's the new look of politics...
Okay, I don't know if these are
strong enough, but they help me.
- Nausea?
- Yeah. You go live in five hours.
- I'll be fine.
- Okay.
Okay.
Donald Trump feeds his own narrative.
Oh, fuck. So nauseous.
If you can try to keep them down.
Yeah.
Fuck. Stop making that face, Julia.
I-I'm not making a face.
Five hours?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
Don't worry. We're behind you.
Way behind you.
There's a blanket on the chair
and, just in case, a trash can beside it.
Welcome to the first
Republican primary debate.
Tonight's moderators
will be Bret Baier, Chris Wallace
and Megyn Kelly.
Mr. Trump, one of the things
people love about you
is you speak your mind
and you don't use a politician's filter.
However,
that is not without its downsides.
In particular, when it comes to women.
You've called women you don't like
"fat pigs," "dogs,"
"slobs" and "disgusting animals."
What is she doing?
- Your Twitter account...
- Only Rosie O'Donnell.
Great TV. She knows what she's doing.
Your Twitter account...
For the record,
it was well beyond Rosie O'Donnell.
Yes, I'm sure it was.
Your Twitter account has several
disparaging comments about women's looks.
You once told
a contestant on Celebrity Apprentice
it would be a pretty picture
to see her on her knees.
Does that sound to you
like the temperament
of a man we should elect as president?
- And how will you answer the charge...
- She's calling him out.
...from Hillary Clinton, who is likely
to be the Democratic nominee,
that you are part of the war on women?
Call me stupid,
but I thought he'd respect the challenge.
Trump is pissed.
He was up all night, tweeting.
Crap. Really?
What was he tweeting?
"Fox viewers give low marks
to bimbo @MegynKelly."
I hate that word.
Yeah. It says you're too sexy to be smart,
but not smart enough to be sexy.
2:40 a.m.
"Wow, @MegynKelly really bombed tonight.
People are going wild on Twitter!
Funny to watch."
- 3:07 a.m. "Dear @Megyn..."
- Go, Trump. Donald Trump.
Okay.
How many times did he tweet?
Like, 15.
Yeah.
He's never gonna be president.
Wait. Am I gonna be the story?
- No.
- I'm gonna be the story.
No. No.
I can't let you go
without talking about Donald Trump.
Gretchen's giving this two blocks?
It's that far down the food chain?
We should get you a security team.
Think it over.
Trump called me before the debate.
He said he knew
that your first question was harsh.
- How could he know that?
- No idea.
I sure didn't.
It was good TV. Unexpected. Goddamn tough.
Proud of you, Megyn.
Thanks, Roger.
Heard you were sick.
Yeah.
I think it was my coffee.
- Where'd you get it?
- My driver.
He insisted on some fancy coffee joint.
You know this guy?
No. He's a driver, Roger.
- Did you know him?
- No.
You know better than that.
Okay, yes, Roger Ailes is paranoid.
But his parents were nuts.
As he drove off to college,
they filed for divorce
and didn't tell him.
At Christmas, he came home
to find strangers in his house
and all his things, photos and yearbooks
and trophies thrown out.
I mean, is it any wonder the man created
a nostalgia machine for lost America?
This is crazy.
We're sitting here wondering
if a candidate for president
poisoned my coffee.
It's only crazy until it happens.
And it happens.
I hate being the story.
I'll call Trump.
You go on vacation. Stay above it all.
He won't dent your ratings.
Nobody stops watching
because of a conflict.
They stop watching when there isn't one.
- Some viewers will listen to him.
- Well, some.
But as long as he keeps saying
Megyn Kelly is unwatchable,
that means he's watching it.
They know that.
And they'll watch what he watches.
You'll be okay.
See you in a week.
Drink up, buddy boy.
- Thank you.
- Here's to a week of no kids but my own.
- Cheers.
- Okay, Frank Bruni in The Times.
- Boo.
"The debate was riveting.
It was admirable.
It compels me to write a cluster of words
I never imagined writing:
hooray for Fox News."
Well, that's gotta make you happy,
praise all tangled up in an insult.
It does make me happy, Gil.
And, you know, you could see
there was blood coming out of her eyes,
- blood coming out of her... wherever.
- No. Oh, my God.
Did he just accuse me
of anger-menstruating?
Yes. Are... Yeah.
- Yeah.
- I'm calling Roger.
No. I'll talk to him.
Take your vacation. I'll handle this.
- Oh, my God.
- Do you hear the phones?
- Doug.
- I have to call you back.
Would you like to correct yourself
on that other talking point
about men being dominant?
We don't have any time.
I wish we did. We're running over.
Yeah, well, HR is on the phone
'cause you called me a skirt.
I gotta read that manual again.
I'll bring it to your office
right after the show.
Some guy came up to me and said,
"I saw you on Fox & Friends this morning.
Is Gretchen as cute in person
as she is on TV?"
- And what did you answer him, Eric?
- Oh, come on.
Beautiful dress. You look wonderful.
Great color.
In summary, Gretchen's beautiful.
- Beautiful. You look beautiful.
- Well, you look fabulous too.
Did you get a wax?
Does the waxing hurt?
He looks at me for that!
We'll try that.
Women are everywhere. We're letting 'em
play golf and tennis now.
- It's outta control.
- You know what?
You know... She's out.
You read the headlines,
since men are so great.
She needed a shower.
The attitude off-camera was even worse.
Steve simply started ignoring me.
What did Mr. Ailes say
when you complained?
He said,
"You act like it only rains on women.
Stop getting
goddamn offended by everything.
You're a man-hater."
And, "Learn to get along with the boys."
- Then he took me off the show.
- But gave you your own.
Well, in the afternoon dead zone.
I mean, it was a demotion
and we both knew it.
Even though
I did increase the ratings by 15%.
He moved me to second base.
Back in Minnesota, before
I graduated summa cum laude from Stanford,
before I was crowned Miss America,
I played second base
in the sixth-grade softball league.
I hate second base.
Did he ever offer to reverse that decision
if you made yourself sexually available?
Not directly.
With Roger it's always about loyalty.
He says he can fix things if you're loyal.
And you can guess
the ultimate expression of loyalty.
We don't guess.
Oral sex.
Roger likes to joke,
"To get ahead,
you gotta give a little head."
Really.
But Mr. Ailes never
unambiguously asks for oral sex?
I mean, it was always
just a joke, a put-down.
Like, "You're sexy,
but you're too much work."
You're... I mean...
I have a whole list in here
because that's just how Roger is.
What do you want out of a lawsuit?
What do I want?
I want this behavior to stop.
Someone has to speak up.
Someone has to get mad.
Well, that may not be you.
Your contract will have a clause
requiring secret, mandatory arbitration.
You familiar with Rudi Bakhtiar's case?
- Yes.
- Well, you're supposed to be.
My first act as DC bureau chief...
I want you down here full-time.
Oh, my God.
That's amazing. Yes.
You do know what this means for you?
Shit. He doesn't think I'm ready.
Brian, I will not let you down.
I'm gonna bust my ass for you.
Well, Rudi, come on, that's a given.
So, what's the problem?
But, uh...
Look, you do get
how I feel about you, right?
Oh, fuck. Fuck, fuck, fuck.
Well, I'm glad you said that, Brian,
because I really respect you too.
No. No. I mean...
how I really feel.
Just look confused.
All I want from you, Rudi,
is to see the inside of your hotel room.
Goddamn it.
That's all it's gonna take.
Don't react. Make it your fault.
Brian, if I've done anything
to make you think
I feel that way about you, I apologize.
Friends.
- We're friends.
- Professionals.
We have a great professional vibe.
Now sell it.
I just don't do that.
I've never had to do that for a job.
I know, I know.
You know I'd kill for DC,
but there's no way
I'm showing you my hotel room.
This is gonna ruin my career.
Well, now I feel like a creep.
No. No, you're so not.
Fucking creep.
They fired me.
I'm a lousy reporter apparently. Assholes.
She proved what they wanted her to prove.
No one really wins by suing Fox News.
It's been our experience
that once you go public in your job...
no one will hire you.
If you're able to stick it out at Fox,
gather more evidence,
you might be able to sue Ailes himself
instead of Fox.
And that is why I'm here.
Because Marty Hyman told me
that over here in New Jersey
I can avoid arbitration
by suing Roger personally.
He says that
you've managed to change the law,
and that we could call other women
and show a pattern.
Will other women come forward?
Yes, they will.
You live and work in New York.
Roger has a house in Bergen County
where he stays
when he can't make it upstate.
You do your homework, Ms. Carlson.
No fingerprints.
That's how much
I practiced the violin as a child.
If Roger finds out you came to us,
he won't just fire you.
He will bang us
with a million-dollar lawsuit.
He will attack you personally.
These men, they care more about
their reputations than they do money.
Roger won't stop.
- I know.
- You know that.
Colleagues you admire will say publicly
you're a superior, ambitious woman
who's suing because her career stalled.
Let 'em.
Okay.
If we work hard, you might be lucky enough
to watch the most powerful man in TV
go after you with everything he's got.
Thank you.
I'm telling you,
other women will come forward.
Let's hope.
Frankly, I think you have
a gap in the network, Mr. Shine.
There are millions
of young conservatives in this country.
I mean, you can look
at my Instagram account. There are.
They don't have a voice on our network.
I see myself as an influencer
in the Jesus space.
And don't get me wrong,
I've learned a ton from Gretchen,
I truly have, of course.
But no judgment here,
my perspective
as an evangelical millennial?
It's just not that helpful to her.
To be honest, Mr. Shine,
she's sort of Establishment.
With a capital E.
That's why I wanted
to talk to you in private.
Kayla, before we move you up...
I want to ask you something personal.
Mm-hmm.
What do you think of our slogan,
"Fair and Balanced"?
I'm glad you asked.
Look, our news shows
and our opinion shows are very different.
Our news is impartial,
it's top-of-the-line.
Our opinion shows,
Roger gave a voice
to people who didn't have one.
And he balanced the American conversation.
So, our newspeople are fair.
Our entertainers
are a very necessary form of balance.
Attagirl. Perfect.
But today we're sticking up for girls
on International Day of the Girl.
And, for the first time on cable news,
here I am,
makeup-free for a reason.
Tomorrow I'll be back
in my regular makeup.
And I thank the other brave women
who came on today's show sans makeup.
But let's continue to tell our girls,
"Just be yourself."
Shep.
- And clear.
- Yes.
Great show.
Get me some makeup.
I have some bad news.
Kayla is leaving us for the asshole.
O'Reilly?
It is our highest-rated program.
And we can't be?
No, I believe in Real Story, I do.
Did you just see that segment?
Did you see it?
We're doing something unique here.
Together. All of us.
- Can you just...
- Sure.
Listen to me.
I can get you where you wanna be.
I can protect you.
Just don't get ahead of yourself.
You have a lot to learn. I can teach you.
I'm not getting ahead of myself, Gretchen.
- I'm taking the next step.
- No. Listen.
- I learn by doing.
- Come on, please.
I'm confused.
You want me to pass on a promotion
so you can help me get the same promotion
- on a show with worse ratings?
- No.
I want a little loyalty. I need loyalty.
Women, together.
I'm loyal to the network.
It's not us versus them, Gretchen.
Miss America.
Roger.
Hi there.
- This is a treat.
- What the fuck are you doing?
A segment on how we oversexualize women.
You said be more myself, so, ta-da.
You know what makeup does?
Keeps everybody from seeing you sweat.
Well, it's... Most of the mean tweets
that I receive are about my appearance,
so it is important that we fight back
against this kind of bullying.
Bullying isn't meanness.
Bullying is people with more power
hitting people with less.
These jackasses have cell phones.
You have a fucking TV show!
We have to fight
the objectification of women.
Bullshit.
Listen, mouth shut, ears open.
Nobody wants to watch a middle-aged woman
sweat her way through menopause.
What?
Not on national fucking television!
Thank you for the advice.
Objectification.
- All right.
- Gretchen, I really appreciate...
Shut up.
Good luck.
Drift.
Go, go, go!
- Whoo!
- Good one, honey.
- I got it!
- It's right on the line!
Hey.
It's a zoo here.
The phone's ringing off the hook.
Anyone care he called me a bimbo?
- Not really. He tweeted the GQ photo.
- I saw.
- And?
- Torn.
God, I'd love to be slut-shamed.
Gil wants to ask again
if we should make a statement.
No. No response. Zero.
Ah...
Doug just lost. I gotta go.
- Next time, honey.
- Nice.
- Good game.
- Trump, '16.
Excuse me.
You talk to my wife again,
I will beat you to a fucking pulp.
- That was weird.
- Mm-hmm.
- You're getting some action.
- Oh, really?
Oh, man.
Asshole.
You don't have to worry about Trump.
You're tougher than all those guys, okay?
You just gotta worry about the crazies.
- I can handle a few crazies.
- I know.
Mommy.
Trump will stop
once he feels he's won the argument.
I feel like he's less interested
in winning the argument
than just having the argument
with you in public
to prove he can take on the establishment.
I'm not the establishment.
Honey, get real.
You are the establishment now.
- Mommy!
- Not yet!
You do understand
I have to be above this, right?
I have to be an anchor first,
then a woman.
You know the entire country
is talking about your period right now?
- Mommy!
- What?
- There's a man.
- Yardley!
- Look. He's right there.
- Yardley, where is he?
- Look. There he is.
Jesus. He's got a fucking camera!
Come here, honey.
No! Don't open the door.
They can't sell them if we're inside.
Get out of here! Go!
Are you okay?
What were you guys doing?
- Mommy and Daddy?
- Mm-hmm.
It was a cross... crossword... Um...
Mommy was just taking a quick little nap.
- Quick one.
- It wasn't that quick.
I'm gonna have to
call Roger about security.
It's as clear as a bell that Mayhem Kelly
has gone over to the dark side.
The more she sells out,
the wider her nostrils have become.
Listen to what I've just said to you.
- Have you seen them flare?
- He's here.
This woman was once pretty,
and the more she has sold out,
the wider her nostrils have become.
They're almost porcine.
She snorts her insults at America...
Roger!
...and, as I say, it's now
the portrait of Dorian Kelly,
not the portrait of Dorian Gray.
Give me a day to figure out
how we hit Trump back.
Stop by later.
I don't want my kids hearing this crap.
Ignore the damn morons.
I'm old, fat, and ugly.
Christ, they call me Jabba the Hutt.
Hemophilia swells my joints.
Can't exercise.
I feel fine, but I look like shit.
I look the opposite of how I feel.
Do I let it affect me? No, I do not.
This isn't entirely true.
Roger is also fat because he'll get
a room-service menu and order page two.
No goddamn orange on Fox!
But he cares a lot about looks.
Fucking idiots.
Let's turn our attention to South Korea.
South Korean officials say talks with the
north have adjourned until tomorrow...
Early on, he realized
for a network to stay on 24 hours a day,
you need something to hold an audience.
Joining me to discuss the Korean peninsula
is Seth Choy...
That something is legs.
There's a reason for clear desks.
We need you in a shorter dress.
But you know that they're gonna take...
Wide shot! Wider!
Go to the wide shot!
I want to see her goddamn legs.
Why the fuck do you think I hired her?
But this might be seen by racial
activists purely through the racial prism.
Stand up and give me a spin.
- Really?
- Yeah, it's a visual medium.
Yeah. That's good. Sit down.
I support the wall. I do.
But mass deportations, come on.
That'll never work
because of the 14th Amendment.
You want me to quote it?
"If you were born in America,
you're an American, period. Period."
Get me a demographically friendly
Hispanic woman on immigration.
But hey, she needs to be
very demographically friendly.
Okay. New girl's up. Kayla.
Hi, sir.
So, I was listening to
Rush Limbaugh this morning.
He said something kind of cool
about Anthony Weiner.
How he's an exhibitionist
in every aspect
of how he presents himself politically.
- Oh, my God.
- Is she the best you can do?
Bill Shine asked us
to give her a try, so...
Okay, let's not lose focus.
Back to immigration.
Oh, my gosh.
I can't get fired.
This is the only job I have ever wanted.
I don't wanna be on TV, I wanna be on Fox.
Uh-huh.
My family, every day,
every holiday, especially holidays,
they watch Fox News.
We're like addicts.
Fox is how we do church.
You know when
they made the corner logo turn...
The bug.
...because folks had "Fox"
burned into their TV screens? That's us.
Kayla, you're not getting fired.
He cannot scale his anger.
He's a perpetual outrage machine.
That's why crazies love him.
No offense to your family.
You want to do the folders?
No crying at Fox.
No crying.
Let me explain your mistake here.
So, Rush is on Hannity's team.
They're the competition.
They're GOP party hacks.
So, he thinks he's way ahead of them,
so steal from Drudge and Breitbart,
not talk radio.
Okay.
Also, stop worrying if the story's legit.
If you can't source it,
just go with, "Some are saying."
Seriously?
You have to adopt
the mentality of an Irish street cop.
The world is a bad place,
people are lazy morons,
minorities are criminals,
sex is sick but interesting.
Ask yourself, "What would scare my
grandmother or piss off my grandfather?"
And that's a Fox story.
Are you writing this down?
It makes so much sense.
- Frighten, titillate.
- Right.
Frighten, titillate. Frighten, titillate.
When you're starting the story,
you need to start with a clear villain.
Mm-hmm.
Liberal judge, pinhead mayor,
Vermont, Hollywood.
Conservatives want to conserve.
You're the last defense against...
Jesus-hating, trans-loving,
Clinton-controlled Armageddon, baby.
Oh, come on.
You do believe some of that, right?
Yeah.
- That's quite a face you have.
- Really?
Thank you.
- I'm drunk.
- I'm drunk as well.
You have a Hillary poster in your house.
I guess I do.
Okay, my parents would be horrified
if I went home with a Democrat.
The lesbianism, however?
Oh, I'm not a lesbian.
I'm not a Democrat.
I just have
two giant Hillary posters in my kitchen.
As a joke though, right?
No. That's who
I'd like to be the president.
Are you serious?
I'm a closeted Democrat.
At Fox News?
Oh, my God. I thought that you knew that.
No, I didn't know that.
Does anyone know that?
Can you not tell? You can't tell anyone.
- Of course I won't tell.
- No, I'm so serious.
- Can I ask something?
- Mm-hmm.
Why do you work at Fox?
Why don't you work at MSNBC or something?
I think I thrive in toxic environments.
I never know if you're kidding or not.
I am kidding.
I applied everywhere,
and I got a job at Fox.
And I keep applying to other places
and they keep not taking me
because I work at Fox.
Oh, my gosh.
It's okay.
One day I'm gonna be free.
What? It's not that bad.
If you're gay, it's pretty bad.
Well, yeah, you don't wanna be gay at Fox.
You work for Bill O'Reilly
and you have a Hillary poster?
You do know he likes to call up
female producers and whack off, right?
Bill?
Yes, Bill.
No.
You haven't heard about
the Andrea Mackris lawsuit?
- No.
- Oh, my God.
This should be in the welcome packet.
She was one of his associate producers.
He took her, and only her,
to the Republican National Convention.
Called her up at 11 p.m.,
touching himself
and telling her what he wanted
to do to her with the old falafel.
Are you kidding?
It's on the Internet.
And then, quote,
"using a vibrator upon himself."
Like, he brought a vibrator
from home to the convention?
Yes, you have to bring a vibrator
from home to the convention.
The question is,
what does a man do with a vibrator?
Do you place it alongside the shaft?
I don't wanna hear that.
"Fucking die, bitch."
"If I see you, you better run."
"I wouldn't be sleeping too soundly
if I were you."
Trump's lit the torches.
You're getting security tonight.
All I want is for this to go away, Roger.
Look, every general in history
has gone into battle feeling the same.
Right.
I'll read a statement at the top, saying,
"Yes, Trump is attacking me,
but I'm not going to respond."
Any defense will come from you.
Not right now.
You set a record on viewer e-mail.
Let me guess.
None of it on my side.
No.
Our audience loves Trump.
A hell of a lot more
than the Murdochs realize.
More than Trump knows.
He's tweeting we made peace.
He'll come on Fox & Friends tomorrow.
He needs us. We need him.
It's got nothing to do with you.
All right. It's late.
I have dogs to feed.
Just to be clear...
I will not be kissing Trump's ass
at nine o'clock.
We fight tomorrow's fights tomorrow.
Can I see that statement again, Bill?
Heard there was
a dust-up involving yours truly
and presidential contender Donald Trump.
How you doing, Megyn?
Hanging in there.
Give him hell, Megyn.
Okay, quiet on the set.
We go live in five, four, three, two...
I just got back from a weekend at the
beach with my husband and my three kids.
Did anything happen
in the news while I was gone?
You may have heard there was a dust-up
involving yours truly
and presidential contender Donald Trump.
Mr. Trump was upset
with a question I asked...
Oh. Cute baby.
I gotta say, I can't stand your show.
Oh.
You guys at Fox, you're doing
terrible things to our country.
Well, I hope that makes you feel better.
How you treat people you disagree with
says everything about you.
Jesus was a white man too, you know?
It's like, he was an historical figure.
I mean, that's a verifiable fact.
As is Santa. I just want
the kids watching to know that.
But my point is, how do you just revise it
and change Santa from white to black?
I mean, you can't. Not really.
Wow.
Nice dress.
I hope you don't wear that
to Sunday service.
Please. I have church jeans,
so I can hold a latte on my knee.
- Oh, my God. Kayla. Did you see this?
- What?
I'm a creep.
- That is gross.
- I know.
I love that.
Are you crazy?
What?
That's my friend from college.
I'm just looking out for you.
- Who are you stalking?
- No one.
I feel for you. That show.
Oh, his bark is worse than his bite.
Well, I work for Roger.
We have two-, three-
and four-doughnut days.
Sugar does make everybody crazy.
No, these aren't doughnuts he eats.
They're doughnuts he throws. At somebody.
No, he's a pussycat.
Come say hi.
We're always looking for on-air talent.
- Oh, really?
- Mmm.
Now?
Sure.
That's Roger's private elevator.
Hang on a sec.
Hello.
- Have a seat.
- Thank you.
Liberals don't get Megyn.
She's a star
not because she thinks Santa's white,
- but because she'll say it.
- That's right.
Yeah, few have courage in the spotlight.
It's powerful to watch.
And she went up 30% that quarter.
Well, that too.
All audiences want is authenticity.
Mmm.
For 200 years, Santa's a fat white guy.
- They think Santa, that's what they see.
- Right.
You want to change that? Fine.
Let's discuss it
without you calling my people racist.
Exactly.
A liberal is somebody
who wants to live in a future
that he is too lazy or too arrogant
to actually create.
Well, in my family,
Santa's always been white
and, according to my granddaddy,
a communist.
So, that's my family.
So, what can I do for you, Kayla?
Why did you drop by to see me?
Well, the thing is, sir,
I actually started on-air during college
in Central Florida. Weather.
I want to convince you
that that is where I belong, Mr. Ailes.
I think I'd be freakin' phenomenal
on your network.
Well, it's Mr. Murdoch's air...
but I did create it. I do run it.
Right.
You have a pretty face.
Here, stand up and give me a twirl.
Now?
Yeah. Just a quick spin.
Oh. Sure.
Well, that's very good.
Now, pull your dress up
and let me see your legs.
Um...
It's a visual medium, Kayla.
Come on.
Higher.
Come on. Higher.
That's fine, Kayla.
Why don't you sit down?
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
You have a great body.
Thank you.
Mr. Ailes...
I'd appreciate it
if you didn't mention this...
- No, no, of course.
- ...to anyone.
I'm here to help my employees,
- not hurt them.
- It would just sound...
Anything that happens here, in this room,
is strictly between you and me.
- Okay.
- Of course, it cuts both ways.
I'm discreet...
but unforgiving.
Success in broadcast television is hard.
It's arbitrary.
This is the most competitive
industry on earth.
- You understand what I'm saying?
- Mm-hmm.
We could work together.
I could pluck you out and move you
all the way to the front of the line.
But I want something in return.
Do you know what that is, Kayla?
- Uh...
- Loyalty.
I need to know that you're loyal.
I need you to find a way to prove it.
Mm-hmm.
You think about that, all right?
So, we'll talk again?
Faye can show you the way out.
Thank you, sir.
Jess. Jess.
Something really weird just happened.
I just went to say hi to...
I just... I met...
I was invited to meet Roger.
I mean, nothing...
nothing happened.
Kayla.
It's actually better for you
if you don't involve me in this.
Um, 'cause they know that we're friends.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
This place is crazy.
No Trump! No KKK! No fascist USA!
- Jesus.
- Okay, we're here.
His assistant's name is Rhona.
The security guard is Keith.
Got it.
Gil, last words?
Yeah, don't piss him off. I need this job.
- Good luck.
- I'll be waiting right here, okay?
No Trump! No KKK! No fascist USA!
Are you happy now, bitch?
During the day, if I'm in the office,
I have a number of people
that I'll just call out a tweet to.
It's always my right.
You probably had
some pretty nasty tweets sent your way.
I don't want that to happen.
I have fans that really love...
But you retweet some of those.
It's notjust the fans.
But not the more nasty ones.
You would be amazed
at the ones I don't retweet.
- "Bimbo"?
- Uh...
Well, that was a retweet.
Yeah, did I say that?
- Many times.
- Okay. Excuse me.
But not the most horrible thing, you know.
Over your life, Megyn,
you've been called a lot worse.
- Is that right?
- All right, that's enough.
It's not about me. It's about the...
Well, what do you think?
I think you're too solicitous.
Thank you.
But this once,
I can handle a straight-up positive.
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
He attacks you for a year straight
and you let him off with a fucking "oops."
What? I don't let him off.
I confront him. I used Donald Trump.
Honey, you absolved him.
Doug, there are internal
political pressures at play here as well.
Yeah, yeah. I bet. I get it, Gil.
You know what, can we have a second, guys?
Please.
I'm not trying to be critical.
Well, you are. I made this go away.
I stopped his harassing bullshit. For us.
I never asked you to do that.
He is going to be
the Republican candidate for president.
I'm a news anchor. I need access to him.
You need access? At what fucking price?
At what price?
The price of our apartment. My salary.
That pays our fucking bills.
- Look. For the record...
- No. You know what?
It's been a shitty year!
Really fucking shitty year,
and I'm allowed to want it over.
You are.
Fuck.
So, what I'm saying is, do we really need
AR-15s to be able to hunt deer,
protect our families?
I'm in favor of people
being able to carry handguns.
Some of these mass shootings
would have been less deadly
if that had been the case.
But I'm also with the majority today,
taking a stand
against semiautomatic assault weapons.
Which brings us back
to the question of the day.
Should Congress reinstate
the Assault Weapons Ban?
I know a lot of you don't agree with me.
That's fine.
Huh.
89% of you say no.
And that's what makes America great.
Clear.
Great.
The second floor wants to see you.
- Now?
- Yeah.
This is Kayla.
Hi.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah. I'll come right up then.
Ladies.
Hi.
Phew. Hot in here.
Gretchen. Well, how are you?
Faye, I miss our lunches.
Mmm.
Roger wants to see me?
Oh. Uh, no, I think it was Dianne.
I just saw her in with Bill.
All right. Well...
See you ladies later then.
Bye.
Roger's ready for you, Kayla.
Okay.
Never stops.
Gretchen, you've been such
an instrumental part of the Fox family.
Absolutely.
We just wanted to tell you
that we appreciated the work...
He's firing me, isn't he?
Yes.
You wanna tell me why?
What could they say?
"You're sexy, but you're too much work.
You're a man-hater.
To get ahead
you gotta give a little head."
Good luck, Ms. Carlson.
Do you know why
we dress soldiers the same?
So everybody knows they're replaceable.
I refuse to be replaceable.
Well, they finally did it. I'm out.
- Did they give you a cause?
- No.
Good. Ready to go to war?
Oh, yeah. I'm ready.
Murdoch here.
Funny. Have you seen the lawsuit?
Which lawsuit?
I'm not stopping.
Roger's being sued for sexual harassment
by Gretchen Carlson.
Where's Dad?
Paris.
- Yeah.
- I have your father's attorney for you.
Thank you.
Morning. So, this employee
has sued Roger personally.
He doesn't know who she is.
Are you familiar with Ms. Carlson?
No. Until two hours ago,
I'd never heard of her.
More importantly, no one heard from her
after she was fired.
Wait. Not even to negotiate a severance?
No. And that suggests
she knew it was coming and she had a plan.
As News Corp attorney,
I recommend you conduct an internal
investigation into Roger's behavior.
I know you two have had issues with him.
I need everyone's attention.
Listen up, people.
A Post employee
has received a package of anthrax.
That's just above us.
Close the goddamn vents!
All of them!
- Roger.
- And nobody opens the mail!
- We're under attack!
Roger! Hey!
Everything upstairs is under control.
You need to calm down.
Do not give orders in my newsroom.
If it were yours,
you'd own it.
It's okay, everyone.
Everything's gonna be fine.
You can go back to work.
Thank you.
Uh-huh. Yeah, let's look into her claims.
Done.
- Hi.
Oh, my God, it's Anchor Barbie.
I'm testing for Fox Business.
Holy fucking Christ!
I'll call you right back.
Pull up The New York Times right now.
- Whoa.
- What's going on?
- Holy shit!
- Did you see this?
- Jesus!
- Fuck.
Jesus Christ.
Holy shit!
Oh, my God.
The Times?
No way.
Josh. Get me a nice shot from Main Street.
- No Priuses in it.
- Right.
When you're photographing for my paper,
don't wear a hoodie.
Okay.
Hoodies are creepy.
Thank you. Thank you.
What is that?
Oh, uh, just grocery-store sushi.
Mmm.
Sushi's not liberal food.
I... didn't say that it was.
Hi, love.
Go home right now
and don't talk to anybody.
What? Wait, Roger...
I'm leaving now.
Go home. I'll meet you there.
What?
Fox News host Gretchen Carlson
has filed a lawsuit
against the network's CEO Roger Ailes,
claiming she was fired because she was...
Fox News chairman Roger Ailes
is responding to a lawsuit
filed by lawyers for Gretchen Carlson...
Alleges she was fired
after turning down sexual advances.
Carlson claimed in the lawsuit
that Ailes took her off the popular
morning show, Fox & Friends, in 2013,
cut her pay and placed her
in a less desirable afternoon time slot
because she refused
to have a sexual relationship with him.
The lawsuit was filed
in New Jersey State Court. She also...
Champ's making his rounds.
Good boy.
Are you okay?
No.
Beth, I just talked to TheWrap.
It's an online publication.
I said, how sad it is we've got this woman
making these complaints
when there are real victims out there.
I know, Roger. I told People magazine
we've been in your office alone
a lot over 15 years.
I've never seen anything
like what I'm reading about.
I said, "I don't think Gretchen Carlson
has a friend in the building."
- I know, Roger. Someone would've told me.
- They're gonna quote me on that.
Not a ring of truth.
Maria Bartiromo
sent Variety a stock chart.
- Hey, we're up.
- Whoo-hoo.
Hannity tweeted, "I talked
to hundreds of women at Fox this week,
both on air and off.
They say it all BS."
- Brit Hume, too.
- Brit?
"Why didn't Gretchen quit and sue
instead of suing only after she got fired?
Why didn't she complain?"
- Why didn't she complain? Really?
- He means the anonymous hotline.
- There's a hotline?
- Yeah.
I did the harassment seminar twice.
- I never heard about a hotline.
- Because it's bullshit.
They have a contractual right
to monitor our communications.
A hotline in this building
is like a complaint box in occupied Paris.
It's like we're telling women,
"Go on. Speak up for yourself.
Just know
the entire network is with Roger."
No one will believe you.
They'll call you a liar.
And as for your career,
you want assignments and air time?
Go ahead. Call the paranoid man
who decides your salary a pervert,
and do that on a fucking
anonymous hotline he controls.
On a phone
he has a contractual right to record.
Jesus fucking Christ,
do you think women are idiots?
It's like somebody stripped you naked
and they want you to walk through
this office just to fucking prove it.
Okay.
Can I see you for a minute?
What the fuck was that?
I don't know, but I liked it.
I won't call you a feminist,
but say there's a spectrum, you are...
Roger harassed me.
Ten years ago.
I had turned down a law-firm partnership
for an entry-level job here at Fox.
Roger would call me up to New York
to dangle prospects.
I wanted his help.
Did you...
do anything?
No.
Will you talk?
- Megyn?
- I don't know.
I don't know.
I mean, going on the record...
Jesus.
It's basically admitting
you're the weak one in the herd.
No, it's admitting you're the hot one.
It has nothing to do with that, Gil.
- Say women.
- Oh, my God.
Look, there is a reason
certain women can defend Roger.
If I report this and it leaks, it will
follow me for the rest of my career.
I don't wanna
be defined by Roger's bullshit.
I refuse to be the fucking poster girl
for sexual harassment.
He can't still be doing that crap, right?
I mean, the man has a walker.
- Viagra?
- Gil.
Help me here.
Please. How do I play this?
Well, you only ask when you already know.
If I learned anything this year,
it's to not get sucked into a fight
with someone who has better reason
to be in it than you do.
Okay.
So, what is it you wanna do?
For right now, nothing.
- Good.
There she is.
Hi, Roger.
Hello, sweetheart.
Hi.
Sit, sit.
- You've met Mayor Giuliani before?
- Of course.
There's an internal investigation,
but I'm not gonna wait for it to clear me.
The Republican convention
is less than two weeks away.
This is bullshit. I'm gonna fight it.
The charges are absurd.
I'm in, Roger.
I love that fate has given me
a chance to repay you
for when I was in intensive care.
Roger called my idiot doctors
every day for four weeks.
Told them he'd put me on the air
live from the hospital bed
if they didn't fix
every stitch of damage done.
But I'm also here as someone
who has dealt with this issue for years,
years on the side of women.
I don't wanna see
sexual violence trivialized.
I don't wanna see it become
some damn political football.
In that spirit, I need to ask,
will an investigation find anything,
well, uncomfortable?
Well, define uncomfortable.
Roger, quote,
"I think you and I should have had
a sexual relationship a long time ago.
And then you'd be good and better
and I'd be good and better."
- Did you say that?
- No, I'm not a fool.
"You missed your chance
for me to harass you"? Come on.
I think they'll argue it's solicitous.
Telling a woman
she was fuckable "a long time ago."
Who the hell thinks that works?
Why's she suing, Roger?
Gretchen is a very competitive woman
facing a severe likability issue.
One that I shielded her from for years.
Her career's over, I'm afraid.
And she can't take a joke.
Roger is very salty.
I find it amusing.
It's my fault. I encourage it.
James Murdoch could be behind this.
His wife openly supports Hillary.
And it could go deeper.
I have good reason to believe
that inside the Obama White House
there have been discussions,
on what level I do not know...
of having me killed.
Oh, Jesus.
- Hi, there.
- Hey.
Roger needs you.
Your silence is being noticed.
Well, the whole point of an investigation
is to find the truth, Jeanine.
Until that happens,
I don't have a lot to say.
If this charge sticks,
the working assumption will be
every woman at Fox got down on her knees.
Even you.
If we sweep this thing under the rug,
Jeanine, and it happens again,
under Title Seven,
Fox will be liable
for compensatory and punitive damages.
That could be hundreds of millions.
Let's worry about the law
before we do the PR, okay?
Does Roger want us?
Yes. He's a man.
He also gave us time.
He gave us opportunity.
We benefited from that kind of attention.
I mean, Jeanine Pirro?
She's the founding member of Team Roger.
- You're not answering your phone.
- No, I'm holding it.
Everybody's still looking for you.
Where were any of these people
to defend me from Trump?
Bill Shine told them not to.
What the fuck?
Our boss.
Why are you guys in the hall?
I got a call from Roger's lawyer
saying to, quote, "relax."
They're convincing Rupert to limit the
investigation to Gretchen and her team.
That's only five or six women.
Are you gonna let that happen?
I like Roger. I do.
I know.
Even if he can be controlling
and vindictive.
Those sins aren't really the problem, Meg.
I mean, there were hundreds of stories
of Roger paying an employee's rehab,
or keeping somebody terminally ill
on payroll.
You remember when Shep came out.
All Roger said was,
"I don't care where you put your pecker,
as long as you don't
tell me where to put mine."
Again, not the most redeeming.
He promoted me,
he looked past the rejection,
he looked past the risk
of this exact conversation.
He handed me the power to hurt him.
- Morning.
- Hi, Megyn.
We need to get
Gerson Zweifach on the phone.
Gerson, I'm calling for Roger.
He wants me
to be part of your investigation.
We've decided on an outside firm.
No, why?
Gerson, we can handle this ourselves.
- I'm asking Paul/Weiss.
- Paul/Weiss?
You tell them
that I can actively participate.
Mr. Giuliani,
you're an old friend of Roger.
You married them.
Sharing information with you will remove
the cloak of attorney-client privilege,
making the testimony of any woman
who comes forward subject to discovery.
I understand. You get me a waiver.
I will not structure this investigation
so Roger isn't perceived of as its target.
You want him to look guilty?
Well, that depends on what we find.
You know a reporter, Gabe Sherman?
- No.
- You're about to.
He's found six women
who claim Roger Ailes harassed them.
All from before Roger founded Fox News.
This was years ago.
He said he would put me on the show,
but I had to go to bed with him.
And I just said,
"Yeah, right. You and who else?"
And he said, "Just me
and a few of my preferred friends."
I came in and he closed the door,
turned, and kissed me.
Like I was his girlfriend.
Like he knew it was coming.
He grabbed my tits and he said,
"Look, no girl gets a job here
unless they're cooperative."
"If you wanna make it
in New York City in the TV business,
you're gonna have to fuck me.
And you're gonna have to do that
with anyone I tell you to."
He finishes the test,
which is me pretending to cook,
then he pulls out a garter belt
and stockings
and says, "Put these on."
So, yeah, well, I put them on.
And he said,
"You know, I can really help you,
but if you wanna play with the big boys,
you have to lay with the big boys."
It was very transactional.
It was quiet. He stared at me.
He undid his pants
and took out his penis very gingerly.
I had never seen one. I was scared.
Then he said, "Kiss it."
I was 16.
Former anchor Gretchen Carlson
filing a sexual-harassment lawsuit
against Fox News chief Roger Ailes.
More women are coming forward.
Ailes is denying the allegations
and getting some high-profile...
The accusations
against Roger Ailes...
I have never run
a goddamn Dairy Queen.
You don't get to go
and get whatever you want.
Everybody on my shows
knows the meaning of decency,
and I do mean everybody.
A TV outfit needs tough, confident women.
Do I push them? You bet your ass I do.
But have I ever demanded sex
during a casting session?
Have I offered extra pay for blow jobs?
Give me a goddamn break!
Why the hell would I do that?
You know the look in a woman's eye
when she's interested.
Walk into casting
back then as the decider.
There was a look they gave.
I did not always look like this.
I never had to harass anybody
and it's fucking offensive
to say that I did!
Well, they're trying to change history.
For their families.
Some of them probably
don't even remember what happened.
That's gracious of you, Beth.
But this is political.
I defy you to find any evidence
that a single part
of what these women are saying is true.
Get ready. More will come.
We need to let Rupert know
what it means if I lose.
Gretchen Carlson could kill Fox News.
This is a fight for your jobs.
If I go, you go!
If you'd asked me what type of
sexual fetish Roger Ailes had,
I never would have come up with
garter belts, but it's fucking perfect.
Their stories are so similar.
That doesn't prove much.
Sherman met them all
through Gretchen's lawyer.
They could have been coached.
The blow job thing feels real to me.
Does Roger seem like a guy who would
get off on that particular power dynamic?
Yes.
A guy who maybe thinks
oral doesn't really count? Maybe.
A guy who has reasons to prefer a sex act
that lets him keep his clothes on?
Sure.
Still doesn't make it true.
Well, if true, these incidents
all happened before Fox started.
Should that matter?
No.
Yes.
I talked to Gerson Zweifach.
And?
He asked me to encourage women
who have claims to come forward.
You remember what happened last time
you got between Rupert and Roger?
Before I speak out,
I need to know if this happened
to other women at Fox.
You understand that?
Is this one where you really wanna know,
or you wanna look like
you really wanna know but don't?
I really wanna know.
I'm not always like that.
No one around here believes
Roger would want to harass Gretchen.
I will send you
some of her soapy notes to Roger.
"Last night Sandra filled in for Megyn.
Why not me? Smiley face."
Who sends a harasser a smiley face?
Martin.
- Hey, Nancy. Thanks for coming.
- Of course.
Hi, Nancy. Coffee?
Thank you.
So, what do you got?
So, no one from Fox has come forward.
No one?
Rudi Bakhtiar.
But no one who's still there?
There's been nothing but praise for Roger.
Except from Megyn Kelly.
She's been unusually silent.
Right. Well, something must've happened
to Megyn in the past with Roger.
She's way too ambitious
not to support him.
Possibly.
Should you call?
Tell her this is a spotlight
you'd be happy to share?
Megyn, share?
No. She wouldn't do it.
- What makes you say that?
- Because I wouldn't.
I mean, Roger plays his women
off against each other.
He's always done it. He'll say, "Megyn
thinks that Lisa should get your spot."
Or, "Megyn suspects
that you're screwing Cal."
And then he'll offer advice on how to
get back at her, as if you brought it up.
She's renegotiating her deal.
I can think of roughly 15 million reasons
to stay quiet.
We do need some collaboration.
Well, that would certainly help
with the other networks.
Oh, God. What?
What, Marty?
Well, we've not had
a lot of incoming job interests from them.
What's not a lot?
None.
They're afraid of Roger.
No.
No woman gets to sue her boss.
Rule number one of corporate America,
you don't sue your boss.
I jumped off a cliff.
I thought one of them would stand with me.
- Hey, Mom.
- Hey, we're home.
God.
Hey, honey.
There's a snack in the kitchen.
- Okay.
- Thanks.
We're gonna get him.
Megyn doesn't want to release
a statement.
It could be seen
as influencing the investigation.
Have her say that to Roger's face.
Look, let us know
who else hasn't spoken up for him,
and maybe she can
encourage them, privately.
No! Jesus.
We need our anchors. We need her.
Let me talk to her.
Yes, please.
Look, sweetheart.
This is an island of safety and truth.
I wear pants.
No one has ever told me not to wear pants.
I'd love to know where that came from.
It's obnoxious. It's toxic.
We need everyone on Team Roger.
Everyone.
- Hi.
- Good morning.
Come on.
No one makes me wear short skirts.
He was the first to put a female on
as host of a prime-time show.
Roger Ailes champions women.
No. There is no leg cam.
No. Could you just hold on for one sec?
Maggie? I have to wear pants tomorrow.
Not without authorization
from the second floor you don't.
We never fitted her for pants!
You can print whatever story you like,
but there is no leg cam.
Lily?
Beth needs me to talk to Megyn.
I'm gonna do an on-air statement
while all the Fox women come out
one by one behind me for Roger.
That will never happen.
Ains?
Hm. Well, you know why Roger's got
that door blocking his office?
Well, yeah, 'cause a Bangladeshi from
Accounting wandered in one day by mistake.
Hm. Please.
It's so girls can come in from
the back elevator and no one sees 'em.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
We get talent coming here all the time
looking to get their faces done.
"I'm going to see Roger.
I gotta look my best."
Yeah. One came back out
with it rubbed off her nose and chin.
Who was that?
My memory's horrible.
You should go see Janice in Weather.
I mean, nobody wants to talk.
Can you blame them?
No.
Where'd you disappear to?
I've got names.
Women rumored to have stories about Roger.
- From who?
- Janice.
- Weather Janice?
- Everybody confides in her.
Nobody from Weather wants your job.
- What are you gonna do with them?
- Tell them this time's different.
- Wait.
- No, don't wait. Don't listen to him.
Look, it's not only your job here.
I got kids, okay? Lily has a baby now.
Julia'll lose her visa
and have to go back to Canada.
And we know that
you've been talking to broadcast networks.
Yeah, you can get a job anywhere.
But we can't.
And no offense,
but who the hell will you be?
Nobody leaves Fox, Megyn.
Not really.
It's in your DNA now.
So, think about
what you're blowing up here.
I say find the truth.
Well, that face tells me nothing.
Well, if they come after you,
it won't be you they come after.
Gretchen Carlson,
your old colleague at Fox News,
has issued some allegations,
some sexual-harassment allegations
over your boss, Roger Ailes.
What is your position on this?
What did you think when you heard this?
In this country, every famous,
powerful or wealthy person is a target.
You're a target. I'm a target.
Anytime, somebody could come out
and sue us, attack us,
go to the press or anything like that.
And that's a deplorable situation.
I've worked for Roger Ailes for 20 years.
Best boss I've ever had.
Well, I've never been told
what I can't wear.
Well, I know you didn't ask,
but I think it needs to be said.
It's a very confusing time right now.
Tonight is Manhattanhenge.
Sunset will align perfectly
with the city's grid.
The best viewing streets are 14th, 34th
and 57th. Good day, New York.
And clear.
- See you tomorrow, Jimmy.
- Yep. Have a good one.
A babe with no geezer?
This can't be a Fox affiliate.
Megyn. My God. How are you?
Good. How about you?
Good. How's your mom?
She's good.
She's training to be a security guard.
Is that because of the Trump stuff,
or is that...
No. She just wants a job
where she gets to carry a gun.
So, did you come up here
to talk about Roger?
What would make you say that?
I've been at local for two years,
nobody's ever come to see me.
You miss us?
The network I worked at for 14 years?
That my dad helped build?
Where my brother's a reporter?
Juliet, did Roger ever...
No.
I heard things, but nothing firsthand.
Good.
- I miss you.
- I miss you more.
- We should go have a drink.
- Yes.
Um...
Roger...
he... he has detectives on staff.
Up on 14.
They look into enemies, follow them,
post negative stories online.
It's called the Black Room.
I don't want you in danger, all right?
No, no. I'm not talking about me.
I'm talking about you.
Be careful who you ask questions
about Roger Ailes.
My lawyers are negotiating with Fox.
Not that Bill will pay any of it.
Bill?
O'Reilly.
And Jack.
Jesus.
Sorry.
Fish rots from the head.
I'm gonna talk to the outside firm
investigating this, Paul/Weiss.
I heard you had some issues over here.
I did.
If you have a name to give.
Roger.
I wouldn't ask
if I didn't think it was safe.
Roger.
Jack. Roger. Roger.
Doug. Roger. Jack.
Roger. Francisco. Doug. Bill. Jack.
Jack. Francisco. Bill. Roger. Roger.
It's Kayla, right?
Yeah.
- Hi.
Megyn.
I know.
You used to work with Gretchen, right?
Mm-hmm.
Did you learn a lot from her?
I did, yes.
I have nothing but good things
to say about her.
That's great.
You know, I always find it so interesting
who history chooses
to do something important.
I guess.
Listen, I wanted to ask you...
I wanted to ask you
if Roger is harassing you.
How did you know?
We find each other.
You too?
Long time ago.
Wow.
You okay?
Mm-hmm.
You should report Roger.
You'll be protected.
Did you?
I took it to his superior.
Nothing happened. I had to drop it.
Why?
I wanted to be on television.
Did you think
what your silence would mean?
For us? The rest of us?
Roger is not my fault.
It would've been nice if...
if somebody told us
that he's after more than legs.
It's nobody's job to protect you, Kayla.
That's all of our job.
I don't get you. You're...
You have power.
Why are you still playing by old rules?
You're Megyn Kelly.
Look around, snowflake.
How do you think I succeeded?
How do you think a woman
gets a prime-time Fox show?
So, you had sex with him?
Jesus fucking Christ.
One thing to keep in mind
about the prospect
of Indiana governor, Mike Pence,
becoming Donald Trump's running mate...
Hello.
Hey, it's me.
Oh, my God. What the fuck? Kayla.
It said "Bill" in my phone. What the fuck?
Sorry. I saved my number
under his name in your phone as a joke.
- I forgot.
- Oh, my God. Jesus Christ.
I had a heart attack.
Where are you?
Uh, I'm on a date.
Oh. Okay.
Hey. Did you, um...
Did you give my name
to Megyn by any chance?
I... I may have, um...
worried about you out loud once or twice.
Why didn't you just...
support me?
I don't even know.
I don't... I just...
I couldn't do anything. And I...
I can't fuck up
because I'm a lesbian at Fox News.
So?
So, who's your date with, Kayla?
I can'tjust go on a date with a dude
and make it go away, you know?
I think I'm...
I think I'm gonna call Paul/Weiss.
Okay. That's good.
That's... That's really good.
I'm really glad you're doing that.
I think that's absolutely
what you should do.
Okay, great.
I just, um... I just...
I didn't... I...
I can't call anyone else and I just...
I need someone right now
to tell me that that's what I should do.
Oh, my God, yes.
I heard it was, like, an outside firm
and they're taking it really seriously.
Okay, great. Thanks.
Kayla.
What happened?
I did it.
I, um... I...
I did it. I gave in to him.
Kayla, I... I...
I'm so sorry.
He kept talking.
He just kept talking.
He kept saying...
"Good girl.
That's a good girl. Be a good soldier.
Earn your place."
Fuck.
He didn't even...
Didn't even unbuckle.
He couldn't get...
I feel so filthy.
No, Kayla.
You didn't do anything wrong.
I'm sorry.
I better go.
Roger can sense vulnerabilities.
In those days, our meetings
were career-strategy sessions
mixed with good advice
and comments like...
The most basic thing is confidence.
Feel at home in your own skin.
If you're confident, you're sexy.
I'm sure you have some sexy bras.
I'd love to see you in those.
It was a cat-and-mouse game.
But he always gave me good advice,
and let me deflect...
tell him to dream on.
The more I let him get away with...
the more he pushed my buttons.
I don't know
if women can be good interviewers.
Men have that killer instinct.
We do bad things.
And we do not feel guilty about it.
How can I be sure
you have that kind of drive?
Finally, in January...
This is '06?
Yes.
He grabbed me.
Tried to kiss me.
I pushed him away twice.
As I was leaving, he asked,
"When's your contract up?"
After the third time, I left.
And he never tried anything again?
No.
I ignored his calls. Stayed in DC.
Two years later, I had a show.
Any long-term consequences?
Yeah, um...
Am I Witness W?
Yes.
Why?
It's the 23rd letter in the alphabet.
Have 22 other women come forward
since I first spoke to you?
Have they?
Will there be more?
A major bombshell
this morning.
Star anchor, Megyn Kelly
has informed lawyers
that Fox News CEO, Roger Ailes,
sexually harassed her.
For her to level these allegations
is devastating against Ailes.
We are seeing
the end of an era at Fox News.
The dagger in his heart, in some ways,
was the notion that Megyn Kelly
was among his accusers.
What?
Yes. Yes.
Roger, what's the matter?
- Megyn's claiming I harassed her.
- What?
You saw Gabe Sherman's post?
James has been feeding him bullshit.
Comb through Megyn's press.
Find every single positive thing
she's said about me
and get it out, now.
Roger, I can't discredit
an anchor I'm paid to promote.
Glad I'm not in a foxhole with you.
Well, we'll leak something
to Breitbart or to Drudge.
I'm sorry, Roger.
Well, do something!
At least get some shit
about Gretchen out there.
These women are trying to fuck me!
I have no answers for you
that you don't already know.
It's out of my hands at this point.
We will be e-mailing you guys.
Please just hold tight.
Thanks.
Hey, Gil.
Hey, Greta.
What's Megyn's endgame?
This part of her contract negotiation?
It's not economic.
Or political.
Okay, Gil.
No, this is scaring me.
It's like the whole world's on fire
and no one can be trusted.
- Hey, Geraldo. CNN, line six.
- Can't talk.
These are the end-times.
- Why aren't you on the phone?
- To comment on sexual harassment?
We work for Bill.
Team Roger.
Hey. We need you to wear it.
- No.
- Are you kidding?
- Doesn't she have a job?
- Get it on.
Megyn Kelly has no comment.
She's traveling.
To Cleveland.
For the Republican convention, remember?
Look, I've known him for 40 years,
and he's about as flirty
as the grizzly from The Revenant.
Let me tell you something.
I called these allegations sick
because they are sick.
Hey, why wasn't I let in on the pact?
What pact?
Breitbart is saying there's a pact
among our top 50 on-air talents
- that if Roger gets fired, we all walk.
- Great. Where do I sign?
Wait, I never heard of a pact.
Me either.
Roger placed it.
Fake news.
Come on.
How bad does it look for Roger?
Bad.
Doesn't feel like I imagined it would.
Gretchen, you achieved
something remarkable.
Yes, I did.
Mom?
I think it's time we finish this.
Okay. I'll let you know.
Mom, are you done with that?
Mm-hmm. I'm done.
I made the Murdochs 1.5 billion
in profit last year.
Pure profit.
Fox News is the most successful
cable franchise in history.
Gretchen Carlson's lawyers.
She wants to settle.
It's a lot less appealing
to sue you personally
without Rupert's money behind you.
Hey, Ken.
Ken.
- Hey! Look who's here.
- Oh, my gosh!
- I brought you some small people.
- Yard! Yatesy!
- I've missed you guys so much.
- We practiced that scare for two weeks.
Look at you.
- Hi.
- I love you, Mama.
- My little chubble-wubbles.
- We got her.
- All right.
She was so scared.
- Ah.
- Thank you.
How are you, sweetheart?
I'm either damned for doing it
or damned for not doing it sooner.
Tell me my big mouth didn't ruin our life.
Not yet.
Can I speak to Roger alone, please?
Are you sure you want Beth here?
Well, of course.
Gretchen taped your conversations.
That's a goddamn lie.
For over a year.
But...
you don't believe her?
Your quotes in her lawsuit,
they're from tapes.
Wha...
Why didn't they tell us before?
So you'd issue complete denials.
So you'd have no credibility.
Apparently, she did her homework.
God bless our next President,
Donald Trump,
and God bless
the United States of America!
USA!
Mr. Giuliani's fired up.
When we come back,
we'll discuss his speech
with the man who helped write it.
Clear.
- Don't react, okay?
- Mm-hmm.
Roger's out.
Is that sourced, Gil?
Yeah. The New York Post.
They put him on the cover.
Rupert's telling him to let go.
Then it's a scoop.
We're gonna win.
We're gonna win so big.
Thank you very much, everybody.
There is some breaking news tonight
in the worlds of media and politics.
A blockbuster shakeup at Fox News.
A dramatic fall from grace.
Roger Ailes is out as top boss.
They want us to circle the block.
No. Hold on.
- What's going on?
- Go around.
I've been shut out.
It's true.
Everything Gretchen said, it's all true.
Roger lied to me.
Why? Because I'm a manager here,
so I have concerns
my public defense of Roger
could be construed as coercive.
Hey. Huh. Pants.
Fuck off, Neil.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
No, no, no, no, no, sit down.
Appreciate you driving up here, Roger.
Susan Estrich.
Susan.
I hate that it's come to this.
Me too.
We gave these women jobs.
Put them on the air, made them famous.
Do you think for a goddamn second
I did any damage to any of them?
No, you don't.
You don't, Rupert.
There's no audience
for that side of the story.
To begin with,
half this you already owe him
from last year's bonus.
And we're paying it.
And paying off your contract.
Consider yourself lucky.
It's a contractual obligation.
I created the Murdoch family's
most profitable asset.
A third of your margin.
There are three of you.
I guess that means I pay for the food
that one of you puts in your mouth.
What if it's you?
I'd have fired you for cause.
Roger, you built an amazing business.
No one can take that away from you.
But under the circumstances,
this is a lot of money.
And it won't look good to the people
that don't know your worth.
Take it.
Honor your non-compete.
I never cared about the money.
We know, Roger.
Okay.
I'd like to go to the newsroom with you.
I'd like us to announce
my leaving together.
No.
The end of the leg man.
I won't miss him.
Boys.
Hope you two know what you're doing.
Once Roger's office
is cleared of handguns, I'll move in.
I'll run the network
till the ship's aright.
Donald.
How's our speech coming?
Yeah.
Megyn's gotta go!
Ho, ho, ho!
Megyn's gotta go! Ho, ho, ho!
Megyn's gotta go!
- Please.
- Convention's downstairs, folks.
- What's going on at Fox?
- Would you say people are shocked?
Can Rupert afford to dump Roger?
What did he do to you? Megyn. Come on!
Of all the ways this could end,
I didn't see this one coming.
Gretchen Carlson got the Murdochs
to put the rights of women above profit,
if only temporarily.
And I found myself
with a job I didn't want
or couldn't really leave...
even when I did.
You should keep that out.
People, can I get your attention, please?
Mr. Murdoch is joining us today.
He has a very important statement
he'd like to say.
Excuse me, everyone.
I won't take long.
Roger Ailes is leaving Fox.
Now, I want to start by thanking Roger
for his remarkable contribution
to our company and to our country.
Twenty years ago...
Here's the thing about
being sexually harassed at work.
It condemns you to questions.
You keep asking yourself,
"What did I do?
What did I say?
What did I wear?
What did I miss?
Am I seen as weak?
Will they say I'm after money?
Will they say I'm after attention?
Will I be left out?
Will I be defined by this
for the rest of my life?"
I will take over
as Chairman and acting CEO
with the support of our
existing management team,
under Bill Shine.
If I stay, do I just
have to put up with it?
Will the next place be different?
Or can I make it different?
Roger always said, "Everyone
on television only has one real job.
To be likable."
Well, I don't care if you like me,
only that you believe me.
A lot of people, even women,
are skeptical of harassment claims
until they experience it themselves,
or know someone who has.
Let me be that person for you.
As you can see, it's 20 million.
Plus the apology.
Correct.
I can't believe Fox agreed to the apology.
I mean, it's unheard of.
I mean, that never happens.
But you will have to sign that.
It's a strict confidentiality agreement.
Money will establish you told the truth,
but no one can ever hear it
directly from you.
You will be muzzled, Gretchen.
Maybe.