Captain!
-Eddie, my briefcase?
-Here.
Hang on to it.
All right, already. Come on, come on.
This way, Mr. Brock.
Mr. Brock, welcome to
the Washington Statler. Your wing--
-I ain't got a whole floor?
-You've got an entire wing.
I don't want one wing.
I want the whole bird.
-Your private elevator.
-Private? That's more like it.
-Hello.
-How are you?
Mr. Brock--
I thought you said this
was private. Take off.
You should be satisfied.
The public corridor and elevators--
-West, East and South Suite.
-Which one's mine?
The South Suite.
Each a private apartment.
Sleeping quarters upstairs,
terrace overlooks Washington.
-I'd like to point out--
-It's all right.
I'd like to point out
that this suite--
This suite is usually reserved
for foreign diplomats.
Oh, I almost forgot.
We thought you'd like this.
-Compliments of the management.
-Okay. Don't bother me.
May I?
May I show you the rest
of the accommodations?
Hey, Billie!
-What?
-Not bad, huh?
-It's all right.
-You know what this place costs a day?
Four hundred, you told me.
-Mrs. Brock seems delighted.
-It's not '' Mrs. Brock.''
Ain't no Mrs. Brock except my mother.
She's dead.
I see.
-Now look, don't get nosy.
-Oh, not at all.
She's a fiancée. Mine, in fact.
Eddie, take care of him.
Pardon me, sir.
-Thank you, Mr. Brock.
-Okay. Don't bother me.
How's the monarch of all he surveys?
-You plastered again?
-Still. Welcome.
I got things that can't wait.
-I got this ticket to get fixed.
-What about?
Some louse, just as we blew into town.
-I'm a lawyer, I don't own the law.
-What'd I do?
I'll see what I can manage.
-How'd we do?
-May cost a shade more.
-How much?
-It's negligible.
-Why more?
-Supply and demand, Harry.
Crooks are rare in these parts.
Don't worry.
Don't worry?
This stuff ain't deductible.
I'm not so sure.
'' ltem: One bribe, $80,000.''
Eighty! You're very handy
with my dough!
Fellow's coming up here any minute
to interview you. Paul Verrall.
Freelance snoop. Political stuff.
I don't wanna talk to no writer.
Eddie!
-You better talk to this one.
-Why?
He's one to look out for.
Take him in, then he won't go poking.
What's so important?
What we're after is important.
Listen, to get by in this town
takes power. You got some.
Takes money. You got plenty.
But above all, it takes
judgement and intelligence.
That's why you pay me
1 00,000 a year.
-What's all the excitement?
-Just making it clear where I fit in.
-Eddie, get me a shave up here.
-Right.
-Harry.
-What?
Barber shop!
Tell Billie to wear something plain
for the congressman.
Tell her yourself. You ain't pregnant.
Send up a barber
and a manicure right now.
Harry Brock! That's right.
Okay, make it snappy.
-And a shine!
-And a shine! Be right up.
Look, don't you worry about Billie.
One thing, she knows how to dress.
Probably Verrall.
-Hello, Paul.
-Hello, Jim.
Harry Brock, Paul Verrall.
-How do you do?
-How are you?
-Ain't I seen you before?
-I'll leave you.
What'll you drink?
-Scotch, if you got it.
-lf I got it? Eddie.
Where do you think you are?
Where you been?
Get him a Scotch and--
-Soda?
-Water.
-Rye ginger ale for you?
-Right. He knows.
Worked for me many years.
He's my cousin. He knows me.
-Right.
-Maybe I'll interview Eddie.
Pretty good. Maybe you
got something there. Sit down.
What's it gonna be, pal?
A plug or a pan?
I know how to talk
if I know your angle.
-No angle, just facts.
-A pan?
-Not exactly.
-Write whatever you want.
Come up. I wanna get shaved.
Nobody can hurt me.
I'm only talking because Jim asked me.
Pay him 1 00 grand for advice,
I'm a sucker not to take it.
-That's right.
-Butt out, will you?
Devery likes it
when I get wrote about.
-What do you wanna know?
-How much money you got?
What?
-How much money?
-What am l, an accountant?
-You don't know?
-Not exactly.
-Fifty million?
-I don't know.
-Ten million?
-Maybe.
-One million?
-More.
-How much more?
-Plenty.
-I made every nickel of it.
-Nice work.
You're gonna give me the business.
That's all right.
-You got me all--
-Tell how I'm a roughneck.
Everybody's scared.
For me, that's good.
Well, not everybody.
Enough. You can't hurt me.
All you can do is build me up.
-Hey, Eddie. Have a drink.
-No, thanks, really.
Do what I tell you.
Who pays you around here?
At home, he shaves me.
I got my own barber chair, right?
That's right.
-Go ahead, pal. lnterview me.
-Where were you born?
Plainfield, New Jersey. 1 907. I went
to work when I was 1 2 years old.
I been working ever since.
My first job was a paper route.
I bought a kid out with a swift kick.
And you've been
working ever since.
Tell you how I'm top man in my racket.
Been in it 25 years.
-Steel.
-Not steel, junk.
-And I ain't ashamed to admit it.
-All right.
Here's some advice:
Never bull a bull artist.
I can sling it with the best of them.
-For 25 years, you say?
-Yeah. I'm a kid with a paper route.
I got a wagon. Going home,
I pick up junk in alleys.
I'm not the only one.
Other kids do it too.
Difference is, they keep it.
Not me. I sell it.
I'm making eight dollars in junk
and three from papers.
I see which is the right racket.
I'm a kid, but I see that.
Soon the guy I sell to
is handing me 20 a week.
Then he turns around,
offers me a job for 1 0. Dumb jerk.
I'd sell him his own stuff
and he never knew.
-How do you mean?
-Look....
In the night,
I drag it out, I load it up.
In the morning I go in
the front and collect.
-Twelve years old?
-Something like that.
-Pretty soon you own the yard.
-Right.
The jerk works for me now.
Know who else does?
The kid whose paper route I swiped.
I figure I owe him.
Good last few years
for the junk business.
-I ain't kicking.
-Do you anticipate any decline now?
-Talk plain.
-Is it still going to be good?
-We'll make it good.
-Who?
-Me, that's who.
-I see.
-Fancy talk don't go with me.
-Come in.
-Good evening.
-Hello.
-I'll get out--
-No, don't go. I like you.
Play your cards right,
I'll put you on the payroll.
Once over light, no talk.
I get a manicure every day.
Over there someplace.
Okay, fellow, go ahead.
I wonder what you're doing
in Washington.
What are you, a wonder boy?
Not so tight.
Sightseeing, that's what I'm doing.
Some talk you've come
to find out--
So far I've been nice to you.
Don't pump me.
How's it going? How are you getting
on with King Junk?
He was born in New Jersey.
Sure is a tough man to dig.
I can't believe that.
He loves to talk. Billie!
This is Paul Verrall.
Billie Dawn.
How do you do?
-Wait.
-What's the matter?
Where you going? Put it back!
-I just wanted--
-Put it back!
-Why--?
-Because I say.
Somebody's coming.
I don't want you stinking.
-Can't I just--?
-Go change. Don't give me no trouble!
Do what I'm telling you!
Barber, what'll you take
to cut his throat?
Some jokes I don't like.
-Don't get excited.
-Don't tell me what to do!
-Just a joke, Harry.
-That's all. I said beat it.
Eddie, take care of them.
-I'll be going too.
-No, don't.
You're the only friend
I got left.
I live around the corner.
lf anybody beats you, scream.
I'll come running.
-Goodbye, Jim. Thanks.
-Goodbye.
I need Billie's signature.
Sure. Billie!
-You sore?
-Not sore, Harry.
-You look funny.
-I know.
-You want an aspirin?
-No, no, I'm fine.
Considering I've been dead
for 1 6 years...
...I'm in remarkable health.
-Billie!
-What?
Billie!
-Come over here right away!
Honey, would you please
fix the safety catch?
-He sure got good lungs.
-Yeah. Thanks.
There's a shortcut through
the service. This way.
-That's the door, honey.
-Thanks, honey.
Sometime I don't understand you.
-Sometime?
-What do you want?
Jim.
Few things I want you to sign, honey.
-That's all I do around here.
-Too bad about you.
-When's this congressman coming?
-Anytime.
I better get fixed up, huh?
-She look all right?
-Look who's talking.
You tell me. I don't wanna start off
on no left foot.
What got into him?
Nothing. Wants to make
a good impression.
So let him.
Two places on this one, please.
What happened to all that stuff
I signed last week?
All used up.
I must've signed
about a million of these.
What you get as corporate officer.
I am? What do you know?
Come a long way from the chorus.
I wasn't only in the chorus.
I spoke lines.
-Really?
-Of course.
-How many?
-How many what?
-Lines did you speak?
-Five.
-I never knew that.
-Ask anybody.
I believe you.
I could've been a star
if I'd have stuck to it.
-Why didn't you?
-Harry didn't want me in the show.
He didn't wanna share me
with the general public.
I see.
Harry's changed. Don't you think so?
-How?
-He used to be more satisfied.
Now he's always
running around like this.
What'd he have to come
to Washington for?
-Long story.
-Well, don't tell it to me.
-I just wish he'd settle down.
-He's ambitious.
He talks all the time now.
He never used to.
Now he always tells me how
he's gonna be bigger, run everything.
-He may, at that.
-I don't care one way or the other.
-Take it easy.
-Now don't you start!
Better to drink after they're gone.
-This congressman?
-And Mrs. Hedges.
-This fella works for him.
-In a way.
So what's he putting it on for?
Just be nice. No rough language.
-I won't open my mush.
-I didn't mean that.
I don't have to be down here.
I could go back to my place.
In fact, I think I will.
-I tell you, Harry wouldn't like it.
-All right, all right!
How are you, Norval?
Haven't seen you in ages, Anna.
-You haven't.
-Come in.
You remember this little lady.
She used to be Billie Dawn.
Oh, yes. Yes, indeed.
This is Mr. Hedges
I've told you about.
-How do you do?
-And this is Mrs. Hedges.
-Glad to meet you.
Glad to meet you.
-How about the terrace?
-That'd be nice.
-A drink?
-Love one.
-Sounds all right.
-Scotch?
-Scotch all around, Eddie.
-Right.
He's awfully tired.
-Stand over a hot resolution all day?
-Just about.
How do you like Washington,
Mrs. Brock?
-I haven't seen it yet.
-This is the first time you've been?
That's what I mean.
I never went on the road.
Well, we must show you around.
Beautiful city.
Too bad the Supreme Court
isn't in session.
What is it?
Lots of people'd
like to know that.
-Hello.
-Mr. Hedges, Harry Brock.
It's about time we got together.
Mrs. Hedges, I'm happy to meet you.
-Thank you.
-Sit down. Congressman.
-Have a good trip?
-I come in my car.
Stopped in Baltimore.
I got a junkyard there, second one.
-Before, I only had one.
-How many do you have?
I couldn't answer that, baby.
-Excuse me.
-That's all right.
I don't know why I like Baltimore.
I get a feeling from it.
-Sentimental.
-Yes, I'm sentimental.
I think we're all a bit sentimental.
Well, it's a free country.
-Do you play bridge, Mrs. Brock?
-No, only gin.
-I beg your pardon?
-Gin rummy.
Oh, yes, of course.
I was going to ask you to join us.
A few of the girls meet.
I don't play bridge.
-You could learn!
-I don't think so.
She couldn't play till I learned her.
Now she beats my brains out.
How're you fixed for time tomorrow?
-Ten o'clock?
-Pretty early for me.
I'll say.
-Eleven?
-Okay.
-I can drop by here.
-Sure, it's on your way.
We can discuss the operation
and get a head start.
Wanna wash your hands
or anything, honey?
NO, thank yOu.
I hope you're free
for Friday night dinner.
-People I want Harry to meet.
-Who wanna meet him.
-Thank you for everything, Mr. Brock.
-Call me Harry.
I haven't written you....
You understand.
You know I'm interested
in scrap iron.
I wanna sell it and not get stuck
with falling prices.
-I have a copy--
-Boil it down and give it to me.
I didn't come here to do paperwork.
The way I work is this:
Get the other guy
before he gets you.
I got in mind a worldwide
operating combo. Enough for everybody.
Up till now, everybody's lined up
and understands everybody.
-I wanna move.
-You understand that legislation--
That's a lot of hot air.
I ain't talking about peanuts....
Give them enough rope. I've said so.
The trouble with these do-gooders is--
They never seem to know when to stop.
I've said--
We can do this.
It's up to you to find out how.
One amendment, for example...
...guarantees government support
of scrap iron price levels.
We want to get it through.
See that you do. I'm here
to see that I get what I paid for.
-How do things look to you?
-Generally?
This country has to decide if
the people will run the government...
...or the other way around.
That's sound thinking.
-Thank you.
-Worthy of Holmes.
Great man, Holmes.
-My personal god.
-Who?
-Oliver Wendell Holmes.
-A wonderful man.
He gonna be here Friday night?
-I don't think so.
-Too bad.
-We mustn't keep you.
-We mustn't.
-Good night.
-Good night. See you tomorrow.
-That's right.
-Good night, Anna.
-Thank you so much.
Wait a while. I'll give you
something to thank me for.
Good night, all.
Drips.
-They're drips.
-Who are you to say?
-I'm myself.
-Nobody asked you. Shut up.
-Pardon me for living.
-Get lost.
-Not yet.
-Get lost, I told you.
-She'll be in the way.
-What are you gonna do?
-I'd like to give her the brush.
-Complicated.
-I know.
-She owns more of you than you do.
She's gonna louse me up down the line.
Dumb broad.
You may be right.
-Listen, Harry. Send her home.
-No.
Why not?
-I'm nuts for her.
-Can't have your cake and eat it.
Just a saying.
-That don't make any sense.
-All right.
-What's cake got to do with it?
-Nothing, Harry.
-Must be a way to smarten her up.
-I guess so.
-Some kind of school?
-I doubt that.
Then what?
We might find someone
to smooth the rough edges.
-How?
-Let me think about it.
I want you to think about something.
About marrying her.
Why marriage all of a sudden?
A wife couldn't testify
against her husband.
You've been engaged for seven years.
Why wait?
I didn't wanna be rushed.
We get married,
she'll think she's got it coming.
-She's different.
-A broad's a broad.
-You'll be sorry.
-I'll let you know.
We still gotta do something about her.
She opens her kisser,
something wrong come out. Talk to her.
-Take more than a talk.
-Then what?
It's not easy to make a person over.
Wait. That interview guy.
He's a smart cookie.
Paul Verrall.
He knows this town. He's classy.
-But he won't do it.
-Why?
-I'll pay him what he wants.
-I don't think so.
I bet you. What's his number?
-I'm not sure--
-What's his number? Come on.
-You ate already?
-Yeah.
-Piece of pie?
-No.
-Sit. How about a drink?
-No, thanks.
Okay, pal.
-I wanna ask you something.
-Sure.
-How much you make?
-Am I an accountant?
-I love this guy. Your name again?
-Verrall.
-Your regular name.
-Paul.
I got a friend, a good kid--
Maybe you seen her around. Billie?
She's a little on the stupid side.
I got her out of the chorus.
She'll be unhappy here,
never been with such kind of people.
-Know what I mean?
-I don't.
-You could help her out. Me too.
-How?
Explain things to her in your
spare time. What do you say?
-I don't think I could handle it.
-Mean an awful lot to me.
I'll give you 200 bucks a week.
-I'll do it.
-I love this guy.
-When do I start?
-Now.
Come with me and I'll introduce you.
You can take it from there.
Billie!
-What?!
-Come down here a minute. Come on in.
She's a nice kid.
You're gonna like her.
-I'm getting dressed.
-He's a friend of the family.
Come on, I'm telling you!
-This is Paul Verrall.
-I know.
He wants to talk to you.
-What about?
-You'll find out.
Jim and I got work to do.
I'll have to leave you two.
Your friend, Mr. Brock, has an idea.
He'd like us to spend
a little time together.
You and me, that is.
-You don't say.
-Yes.
-What are you, a gigolo?
-Not exactly.
-So what's the idea?
-Well, it's nothing special.
He'd like me to put you wise
to a few things, show you the ropes.
-Answer any questions.
-I got none.
-I'll give you some.
-Thanks.
It might be fun for you.
There's a lot to see here.
I'd be glad to show you around.
-You know the Supreme Court?
-Yes.
-I'd like to take that in.
-Fine.
-We're on, then?
-How you mean?
The arrangement.
-I don't mind. Got nothing to do.
-Good.
-What's he paying you?
-Two hundred.
You could've got more.
He's got plenty.
Oh, I'd have done it for free.
-I would.
-Why?
This isn't work. I like it.
-He thinks I'm too stupid, huh?
-No.
He's right. I'm stupid and I like it.
-You do?
-Sure.
I got everything I want.
Two mink coats, everything.
lf there's something I want, I ask.
And if he don't act friendly...
...I don't act friendly.
As long as I know how to get
what I want, that's all.
-As long as you know what you want.
-Sure.
-What?
-As long as you know what you want.
-Are you trying to mix me up?
-Well, no.
-I'll tell you what I would like.
-Yes?
-I'd like to learn how to talk good.
-All right.
-Is it hard?
-I don't think so.
What do I have to do?
I might give you
a few books to start with.
Every now and then I'll correct you.
-Go ahead.
-Well, that is, when I know.
-I don't talk so good myself.
-You'll do.
-Good.
-I never say ''ain't.'' Did you notice?
-Oh, I do.
-I'll correct you then.
-Do that.
-Since I was small I never say it.
Our teacher used to slug you
if you did.
-Did what?
-Said ''ain't.''
-I got out of the habit.
-Was it worth the slugging?
Oh, not hard.
There's too much slugging.
I don't believe in it.
-I don't believe in it either.
-Good.
-I learn fast.
-You're great, Miss Dawn.
-Billie.
-Billie. An odd name, isn't it?
Half the kids I know are named it.
-Anyway, it isn't my real name.
-Oh? What is?
Holy cats. Emma.
-What's the matter?
-Do I look to you like an Emma?
No. You don't look
like a Billie either.
What do I look like?
-To me?
-Yeah, you.
You look like a lovely girl.
Let me ask you....
Are you one of these talkers, or would
you be interested in a little action?
-What?
-I got a yen for you right off.
-Well, do you get many?
-Now and then.
-What do you do about it?
-You'll find out.
-I will.
-Want a tip? Sweet-talk me, I like it.
Like that '' lovely girI'' line.
Don't worry, he don't see a thing.
He's too dizzy from being a big man.
This is gonna be different
than I thought.
-Do you mind?
-No.
It's only fair.
We'll educate each other.
-About those books.
-Yes?
I'll look around. lf there's anything
interesting, I'll drop it back.
You can drop it back even
if it's not so interesting.
-You two gonna get together?
-I think we're all set.
-Great, great. Appreciate it.
-So do l.
Well, I guess-- I guess I'll be going.
So long, kid!
So long, kid.
Gin!
Forty-one.
-Forty-one?
-Forty-one.
Pay attention, that Verrall guy
can do you some good.
All right.
You're in the big league.
You should watch your step.
All right.
You gotta learn to fit in.
Can't have you around if you don't.
Have to be careful
of what you do and say.
Three.
Twenty-eight.
-Twenty-eight?
-Twenty-eight!
You could use a little
education yourself.
-Who asked you?
-Nobody.
So shut up!
-Can't I talk?
-Go on, play your cards.
-It's a free country.
-That's what you think.
Do you mind?!
Gin.
Thirty-four.
-Thirty-four?
-Thirty-four!
-Schneider!
-What?
$55.60.
-All right, that's enough.
-Pay me now.
-Don't you trust me?
-Sore loser!
Shut up!
Fifty-five dollars and 60 cents.
Thanks.
-You gonna play like that all night?
-What?
Hurt your eyes.
-Hello.
I tried your suite. No answer.
Yeah, I know. I'm not in.
-Morning papers.
-Oh, I don't read papers.
-Never?
-Once in a while, the funnies.
I think you should.
The not-so-funnies.
Why?
-Well, it's interesting.
-Not to me.
How do you know?
lf you're gonna turn out
to be a pest, we can call it off.
Sorry.
I look at the papers sometimes,
but I never understand it.
So what's the sense?
Look through these, and anything
you don't understand...
...make a circle around it.
Then I'll explain.
-Whatever I can. All right?
-All right.
And I thought you might like these.
Well, I'll try.
Start reading. lf you don't
like it, start something else.
One thing, my eyesight isn't so hot.
Why don't you wear glasses?
-Sure, why not?
-Because it's terrible.
Of course, they're not so bad on men.
-Good night, Billie.
-Good night.
Hello!
Miss Dawn around?
-Have you seen Miss Dawn?
-In her room.
-Hello?
-Yes?
-Ready to start.
-Come on up!
-Hello.
-Been reading, huh? That's good.
-Yeah.
-Sit down.
-Thanks.
-Did you have your breakfast yet?
-And lunch.
-There's a few things here.
-Which?
Read it out.
You want me to read?
Billie, things
are complicated enough...
...without complicating them further.
I ought to take this pencil
and make a circle around you.
-Here are a few places you should see.
-A few?
The Capitol. I'll tell you all I know,
then we'll join a tour.
Senate's in session today.
Let's go to the rotunda.
It's famous for its--
-Come on. You'll find it interesting.
-I'm coming.
--now before Congress.
On the walls of this rotunda
are eight historical paintings....
--with the landing of the Pilgrims....
--Revolutionary War paintings,
depicting the start...
...and finish of that war,
and its two greatest battles.
The east wall contains paintings
predating the Revolutionary period.
--The GlOrificatiOn
Of the Spirit Of GeOrge WashingtOn.
Washington is the figure
with the purple robe on his lap.
The figures around him
represent Liberty and Victory.
Brumidi did most of that work
lying on his back...
...on a scaffold built
from the floor to the dome...
...a distance of 1 80 feet
and 3 inches.
Now if you'll follow me....
How could anybody paint
upside down like that?
Hey, give me one of those.
-Hello.
-How are you?
Come here.
I wanna show you something.
There's the Constitution...
...the Declaration of lndependence.
And come here.
And the Bill of Rights.
Know how old these are?
-Oh, about 1 60 years.
-Who told you?
-What else do you know about it?
-What else?
-This whole country...
...is founded on these
three pieces of paper.
This whole country?
''The right of the people
to keep and bear arms...
-...shall not be in-fringed.''
-lnfringed.
Good thing it's covered with glass.
I'd be making circles all over it.
How about some ice cream?
Anything but tutti-frutti.
-How's chocolate?
-Fine.
-I like you better with them on.
-What?
Your glasses!
Thanks. You know, chocolate's
the most popular.
I read that.
It's interesting how many things
a person could learn if they read.
I don't suppose you read my piece.
What are you talking?
Of course I read it. Twice.
What did you think?
It's the best thing I ever read.
I didn't understand one word.
-What didn't you understand?
-None of it.
Here. Show me what.
What's so funny?
That I'm blind, practically?
Practically blind.
-Practically blind?
-You're wonderful.
-I'm sorry I look funny to you.
-You look lovelier than ever.
You sound like one of those
ads for eyeglasses.
What didn't you understand?
Well, like the name of it:
''The Yellowing Democratic Manifesto.''
-Simple.
-To who? Whom? Who?
Well, anyway, not to me.
-You know what ''yellowing'' means.
-Not this time.
When a piece of paper gets old,
what happens to it?
-Throw it away?
-No, it turns yellow.
-It does?
-Of course.
What do you know?
-You know what '' Democratic'' means.
-Not Republican.
Well, not exactly.
It means pertaining to our form
of government, which is a democracy.
-What's pertaining?
-'' Has to do with.''
Pertaining. Nice word.
-All right. '' Manifesto.''
-I don't know.
-Why didn't you look it up?
-I did. I still don't know.
By ''manifesto'' I mean the rules,
principles, ideals and hopes...
...on which the United States is based.
The ideas of the men who
wrote the Constitution.
-You think it's turning yellow?
-Yes.
The original inspiration
has been forgotten.
-And that's bad?
-And that's bad.
'' Even a--''
-'' Cursory''?
-Cursory.
''--examination of contemporary...
...society in terms of the Greek...
...philosophy, which defines
the whole as a representation...
...of its parts,
sends one immediately...
...to the consideration of
the individual as a citizen...
...and the citizen as an individual.''
-Well?
-I looked up every word.
Listen.
Thousands of years ago,
a Greek philosopher said...
...the world could only be
as good as its inhabitants.
-Makes sense.
-So I said...
...take one look at America...
...and you figure you better look
at the people in it. One by one.
That's all.
-That's this?
-Sure.
Well, why didn't you say so?
-What's the name of this number?
-Beethoven's Second Symphony, Opus 36.
I didn't ask you who made it up.
I just asked the name of it.
Here. Wait a minute.
-There.
-Thanks.
-I can't get over it.
-Music that bad?
-The music? Oh, it was swell.
-Well then, what?
I got a letter today, from my father.
-New York?
-Yeah.
-I can't get over it.
-Why?
It's the first time he wrote me
in about eight years.
We had a fight, sort of.
He didn't want me to go with Harry.
What does he do?
-My father?
-Yeah.
Gas company. He read metres...
...but he can't get around
so good anymore...
...so they gave him a different job.
Elevator man.
He's a goofy old guy.
He used to take a frying pan...
...to work every day
and cook his lunch.
He said everybody
should have a hot lunch.
I don't know how he did it.
Four of us. Me and my three brothers.
He did everything.
My mother died. I never knew her.
He used to feed us and give us
our bath and buy our clothes.
Everything.
All my life I used to think how
someday I'd like to pay him back.
It's funny how it worked out.
Once I brought home $1 00 and gave it
to him. You know what he did?
Well, it sure didn't
do the plumbing no good.
I thought he'd hit me, but he didn't.
His whole life, he never hit me once.
How'd he happen to write you,
after all this time?
Because I wrote him.
He says he's thought about me
every day.
Gosh!
I haven't thought about him,
I bet once even, in five years.
Oh, that's nothing against him.
I haven't thought of anything.
Be nice to see him, maybe.
I guess so.
He says I should write again, and
I should have a hot lunch every day.
And I should let him know how I am.
But he won't see me if I'm still
living in any way unethical.
I looked it up.
He always said, '' Never do nothing...
...you wouldn't want printed
in the New YOrk Times. ''
I practically told you the whole
story of my life by now.
I enjoyed it very much.
-How about the story of your life?
-Oh, no.
Much too long...
...and mostly untrue.
This is even more gorgeous than
the Radio City Music Hall, even.
And do you notice? It smells nice.
It does!
-Come on. Sit down.
-No.
You're tired.
I'm not a bit tired.
See?
You know the thing you gave me
about Napoleon?
-What?
-By Robert G. lngersoll?
-Oh, yes.
-I'm not sure I get it.
-There's no deep meaning.
-There must be.
He goes and looks in Napoleon's tomb...
...and he thinks
of Napoleon's sad life.
And then he says he himself
would have rather been a happy farmer.
'' I would rather have been a French
peasant, and worn wooden shoes.
I would rather have lived in a hut
with a vine growing over the door.
And the grapes growing purple
in the kisses of the autumn sun.
I would rather have been a poor
peasant, with my wife by my side...
...knitting as the day
died out of the sky...
...with my children upon my knee
and their arms about me.
I would rather have been that man...
...and gone down to the tongueless
silence of the dreamless dust...
...than to have been that imperial
impersonation of force and murder...
...known as Napoleon the Great.''
How do you remember
all that stuff?
So he'd rather be a happy peasant
than Napoleon. Who wouldn't?
Harry wouldn't, for one.
-What makes you think that?
-Ask him.
He probably never heard
of Napoleon.
What's worse, he probably never
heard of a peasant.
Do you hate him like poison?
-Who? Harry?
-Yeah.
-No.
-You don't like him.
No.
-On account of me and him?
-One reason. There are lots more.
-What?
-Think about it. Harry's a menace.
He's not so bad. I seen worse.
Has he ever thought of anyone
but himself?
Who does?
History is the story
of the struggle between...
-...the selfish and the unselfish.
-I can hear you.
All that's bad is bred by selfishness.
Sometimes selfishness can get to be
a cause, an organized force.
Even a government.
Then it's called fascism.
-Can you understand that?
-Sort of.
-Well, think about it.
-You're crazy about me, aren't you?
-Yes.
-That's why you get so mad at Harry.
I hate his life, what he does,
what he stands for. Not him.
-He just doesn't know any better.
-I go for you too.
I'm glad of it.
'' I've sworn upon the altar of God...
...eternal hostility against
every form of tyranny...
...over the mind of man.''
So that's Thomas Jefferson, huh?
I heard quite a bit about him.
I mean even before
I hit town, even.
Come in.
What are you trying to do
with those books, hatch them?
Blue?
Nice, that.
Beethoven. Op 36.
-What's up?
-It's because of you I'm doing this.
-I guess you know.
-No, I didn't.
A lot of good it did me.
I never had this trouble before.
-Trouble?
-Sure.
When I met you, I figured everything
is gonna work out dandy.
Then when you wouldn't
step across the line...
...I figured maybe the way
to you is through your head.
Well, no.
Well, anyway, what's the diff now?
Difference.
But I like you anyway.
It's too late for the rest.
-Why?
There's a certain time
between a fellow and a girl...
...when it either comes off or not.
lf it doesn't then, it never does.
-Maybe we haven't got to our time yet.
-I think so. You dropped the ball.
Don't be so sure.
I never thought I'd
go through a thing like this.
-Like what?
-Like getting all mixed-up.
Like wondering and worrying
and thinking. Stuff like that.
Last night I started thinking.
I couldn't fall asleep for 1 0 minutes!
I don't know if it's good
to find out so much so quick.
Nobody's born smart. Know what
the stupidest thing on earth is? A baby.
What have you got against babies?
I've got nothing against a brain
that's three weeks old.
But if it's still empty after
30 years, I begin to wonder.
-Who says I'm 30?
-I didn't--
-You did!
-I swear.
-You sure can get me sore.
-Sorry.
-Do I look 30 to you?
-No.
-Then why'd you say it?
-I don't know.
-How old are you?
-Twenty-nine!
Don't stop.
I meant, don't stop studying.
Will you?
I don't know why
it's so important to you.
Sort of a cause.
I want everyone to be smart.
As smart as they can be.
A world of ignorant people
is dangerous.
-That's why I wish I was doing better.
-You're doing wonderfully.
Most people would laugh
if they knew what I was trying....
-I'm not laughing.
-I am. I'm sort of laughing at myself.
Who do I think I am, anyway?
Once in a while, for a change.
Don't try so hard.
You miss the whole point.
-I wanna like what's best to like.
-You have room for a lot.
One learns to be bigger, not smaller.
-I'm getting bigger?
-Yes.
Glad to hear it.
But all them books!
I told you, it's not only books.
-It's mostly.
-It is not.
Who said, ''The proper study
of mankind is man''?
-Who?
-You should know.
-Why?
-I told you.
-I forgot.
-Pope.
-The pope?
-Not ''the pope.'' Alexander Pope.
-''The proper study--''
-''--of mankind is man.''
-Of course, that means women too.
-Yes.
Yes, I know.
I've been studying
different mankind lately.
Like the ones you told me.
Thomas Jefferson and Tom Paine.
And all by myself
I got to thinking about Harry.
He works so hard
to get what he wants, for instance.
But he doesn't know what he wants.
-More of what he's got, probably.
-Money.
Money, more people to push around,
more money.
He's not so bad as you think he is.
We were just talking about you.
That ain't why I pay you.
She knows enough about me. Too much.
Jim phone? I had a date with him.
-What about Paine?
-He was quite a fellow.
-Where was he born?
-London or England. A place like that.
-London or--? It's the same thing.
-It is?
London's a city
in the country of England.
-You got patience.
-Take it easy.
-How can she be so dumb?
-We can't all know everything.
-Who's Tom Paine, for instance?
-What?
-You heard me. Tom Paine.
-What do I care?
I know.
lf I wanted to know who he is,
I'd know. I don't care.
-Don't let me butt in.
-Which book did you like?
I didn't read by him.
Only about him. I made a list.
-Who's '' Rabbit'' Maranville?
-Who?
-'' Rabbit'' Maranville.
-I don't know rabbits.
-Think you're smart, huh?
-He was shortstop for the Braves.
-What are you? Some kind of genius?
-No.
-I hire and fire geniuses every day.
-I'm sure.
-Where's the list?
-Here.
Suppose you start
with The Age Of ReasOn.
-The Age Of ReasOn?
-Then, next--
-Who's Willie Hop?
-Billiard champion.
-It's pronounced '' Hoppe.''
-I asked her.
-Sorry. Where were we?
-The Age Of ReasOn.
-Yes. Next, The Rights Of Man.
-The Rights Of Man.
-I think--
-What's a peninsula?
You think you're so smart?
What's a peninsula?
-Not you. Her.
-It's that new medicine.
It is not.
-What then?
-A body of land...
...surrounded on three sides
by water.
-So what?
-So what about Sam Paine?
Some difference between--
Tom Paine! Not Sam Paine!
Tom Paine practically started
this whole country.
-You mean he's dead?
-Of course.
I want you to learn her how to act
with live people.
Education's difficult to control--
-Work on her.
-No extra charge.
-I don't need nothing you can tell me.
-We could...
...tell each other some
interesting things.
-What's the idea?
-Being friendly.
Who asked you?
The more I see you
I don't like you as much.
You're awful fresh.
-Watch out. I got my eye on you.
-Okay. We'll both watch out.
-I could knock your block off.
-Yes, I know.
Just do what you're supposed
to do, that's all.
We'll stop now.
-Go on. I wanna see how you do it.
-Not now.
I've gotta lie down.
You don't realize how hard I work.
Some joke!
-200 bucks a week and I can't watch.
-Take you on separately. Glad to.
Got a special course
for backward millionaires.
'' London or England.''
Why don't you give up?
-Harry?
-What?
What's this business we're in
down here? Could you tell me?
What do you mean, ''we''?
-I figure I'm a partner, in a way.
-A silent partner.
-So?
-So shut up.
I got a right to know.
Keep out of my hair.
Put your nose in a book.
I don't want to do anything
against the law.
Do what I tell you.
I think I know what it is,
only I'm not sure.
What's the matter?
You do all right.
Something you want
you ain't got, maybe?
-What?
-I wanna be like the happy peasant.
All right, I'll buy it for you.
Now will you quit crabbing?
I finished finally.
Thanks loads for the loan.
-How'd you like it?
-Oh, not me.
I don't like when everyone
has a beef against the world.
-I like to look on the cheerful side.
-Well, the point--
-Can the coffee klatch. You, knock off.
-Sorry, Mr. Brock.
-Don't get so pally.
-Paul says it's okay.
-Never mind him. I don't like it.
-Know what you are?
What?
-Antisocial!
-You can say that again.
Where you guys been?
-Sorry.
-You're always sorry.
-My fault. How do you do?
-How do you do?
-How are you, Billie?
-Superb. A new word.
-All right, what happened?
-It may take more time--
-And more money.
-Why more?
The amendment has to be redrafted.
-You make me feel like a sucker.
-NorvaI's doing his best.
-It ain't good enough.
-There are a lot of votes.
-NorvaI's just one guy.
-He's the wrong guy.
I'm sick of waiting.
Pull your weight in this deal
or I'll get somebody who can.
Quite a temper.
Don't mind him. He's always lived
at the top of his voice. So long, Norval.
Harry shouldn't talk to you like that.
You're a congressman.
Oh, well.
No one should talk to a congressman
like that, or be able to.
-Being a congressman is wonderful.
-Thank you.
I think I could use a drink.
Oh, sure, congressman. Come on in.
lf he pushes you around, he's
pushing a few million people around.
-Who?
-The ones who picked you.
-Not quite that many.
-How many?
306,434.
That's quite a few to push around.
You're not one of my constituents
by any chance, are you?
-One of the people who voted for me?
-Oh, I never voted for anybody.
-Why not?
-I wouldn't know how.
-Simple. You just press a button.
-Yeah. But which one?
You listen to the speeches.
You make up your own mind. That's all.
Why do you take it from Harry?
You're more important than him.
You're a congressman.
Yes, and as such,
I have a great many duties...
...and responsibilities and....
The operation of government
is very complex.
Why should it be? I understand it in
the books, and when Paul tells me.
But when I see this
happen, it's different.
How?
When it's a matter of the law,
is Harry more important than others?
No.
Then how come he's got so much to say?
Who ever voted for him?
Well, we'll have a nice,
long talk about it sometime.
All right.
-Goodbye.
And thank you.
Quite a little girl.
-Billie?
-Come in.
Will you come inside?
A few things for you.
Sign those, will you, honey?
-What is this?
-Same old stuff.
-What?
-Take too long to explain.
I like having things explained
to me. I found that out.
-Some other time.
-Now.
-It's an agreement about a merger.
-Merger?
-What's that?
-Several companies becoming one.
-All Harry's?
-No.
Whose, then?
A few of Harry's and some others.
French, ltalian and so on.
A cartel!
-What are you talking about?
-Cartels. I'm against it.
Paul explained it to me.
-It's perfectly all right.
-Are you sure?
-Ask Harry.
-I will.
-He won't like it.
-Why not?
-He doesn't like people butting in.
-I'm not '' people.''
Listen to me. Be smart.
How can I be smart if nobody
telIs me anything?
I'll tell you something.
-Sign this. Don't start with him.
-Tomorrow.
Why tomorrow?
-I wanna look it over.
-It's all right.
Must be fishy or you'd tell me.
Take my word for it.
No.
I know you feel bad.
You don't like doing his dirty work.
-You know you're better than him.
-That's enough!
But I'm not so sure.
Maybe you're worse.
-lnteresting?
-Not very.
You're used to reading
more high-toned stuff.
Yes, I am.
-What's the matter, kid?
-Nothing.
-All of a sudden--
-I don't like that Jim.
Why? What'd he do to you?
He didn't do anything to me.
It's what he's done to himself.
Done what?
Paul said he could have been Assistant
Attorney General of the United States.
-Who?
-Jim.
-So what's wrong with that?
-So nothing's wrong. Look at him now.
Hangs around. Helps you promote.
Lets you walk all over him
just because you pay him.
So we finally get around to me.
I'm not sure I like you, either.
You're selfish, that's your trouble.
-Since when is all this?
-Since now.
I used to think you were a big man.
I'm beginning to see you're not.
Through history there's been bigger
men than you. Now too.
-Who?
-Thousands.
Name one.
My father.
Twenty-five a week.
Don't get nervous just because
you read a book.
-You're as dumb as ever.
-Think so?
Yeah, but I don't mind. You know why?
Because you're the greatest--
-Leave me alone!
-Come here!
-I feel like I wanna go away someplace!
-Where?
-We'll go to Florida.
-I mean alone.
-You've gone nuts! Calm down!
-I can't!
-Why not?
-I don't know!
I hate my life.
There's a better kind.
lf you'd read some books you'd know.
Maybe you're right. I'm still dumb.
But I know there's a better
kind of life than the one I got.
Or you!
You'd rather be with
that saxophone player?
-At least he was honest!
-He was a chump.
-He worked for a living.
-I worked since I was 1 2.
-Nobody give me nothing.
-Robbing a house is work too.
In my whole life--!
I never robbed a house in my life!
-What are you talking about?
-You can't understand.
Get off that high horse,
you dumb pot!
You...
...menace!
You never had a decent meal
until you met me!
But I had to eat with you!
You got no manners.
Taking your shoes off all the time
and picking your teeth.
You're just not couth!
I'm as couth as you are!
-And that cheap perfume you put on.
-Cheap?
I don't own nothing cheap except you.
You don't own me. Nobody can
own anybody. The law says.
-lf I was scared, I wouldn't be here.
-Where are you?
You don't like it here, beat it!
-Wait a minute! First this.
-Not now.
-Right now!
-No!
I won't sign anything
till I know what it is.
Do what I'm telling you!
Harry, please don't!
There.
All right, now go on. Blow.
I don't want you bawling here.
You don't appreciate nothing.
Go sit on a park bench until you learn
how to behave. Go on, beat it!
This way out.
I gotta put something on.
Hurry up. I don't want you around.
You bother me!
Big fascist!
All set?
You think I'm gonna
let a broad talk back?
-Where is she?
-She's leaving. I can't stand a crier.
-What's she crying about?
-How do I know?
Becoming a strange girl.
She's all right. It's these books.
They got her nervous.
Educating her was a mistake.
I didn't know it would be like this.
I'll fire that Verrall skunk.
Why blame him?
He taught her too much. You know
what she called me? A ''fatch-ist'' !
That don't make sense. I was born
in New Jersey. She knows that.
What's the matter, Harry?
I love that broad.
You think we could find somebody
to make her dumb again?
Don't be late if you don't
want no bloody nose.
-Would you do me a favour, Harry?
-What?
Drop dead.
I have swOrn upOn the altar Of GOd...
... eternal hOstility...
...against every fOrm Of tyranny...
... Over the mind Of man.
Oh, hello. Chestnut-7 1 80.
I'd like to speak to
Thomas Jefferson, please.
Oh, no. I mean Thomas Verrall.
No, Paul Verrall. Paul Verrall.
Well, it's very important.
Well, I'll hold on.
-Jim!
-Yes?
-What time is it?
-1 1 :30.
-I'll slug her when she gets back.
-lf.
-She always winds up where I want her.
-I hope so.
Jim!
-What time is it?
-1 1 :30.
-You said that before.
-1 1 :31 .
-She's been gone eight hours.
-Maybe she's seeing a double feature.
That don't take eight hours.
-Could've had an accident.
-You'd hear.
Could have got attacked.
Happens all the time.
Not to Billie. Maybe the other
way around. But not to her.
She here?
What do you mean?
No. Look some more.
-I been all over town.
-Well, go over it again.
-Do what I'm telling you.
-Sure. Just changing my socks.
-Harry.
-What?
Marry her.
Still harping?
I'm thinking of your legal safety.
She--
I know what she owns.
You've got to do it, Harry.
Broads always hook you in the end.
All this because a dame reads a book.
It's the new world.
Force and reason changing places.
-What?
-Knowledge is power.
I don't like this. You stewed,
that broad out of line.
-And some congressman!
-I think he's cute.
I'd like to trade him in.
-On what?
-On a senator!
On a senator?
Take the blinders off and let in
the light. Just for a second.
You can't buy senators and congressmen
as if they wore price tags.
These guys are honest.
Sincerely trying to do a job.
Sometimes you find
a rotten apple, like Hedges.
But just once in a while.
In a great while.
Are you sure you're ringing
Mr. Brock's suite, operator?
Well, how about the bedroom?
Ring a few more times.
I wanna make sure.
-He's not in.
-Just one more ring.
Let's go.
The stuff's in his briefcase.
In his bedroom.
I probably won't see you again, Paul.
-I wanna say goodbye.
-What?
-And thanks.
-Where are you going?
-Away from here, that's all I know.
-Where?
You can tell me.
I don't know. I thought
I might go see my father for a while.
-I've got a better idea.
-What?
Let's get married.
You must be daffy.
I love you, Billie.
You don't love me.
You just love my brain.
That too.
I'll think it over, but I can
tell you now, the answer's no.
What are you doing?
lf you don't know,
I must be doing it wrong.
Fine time!
-Hello, Harry.
-Where you been?
I took a walk, like you told me.
I met Paul.
Okay, buster, knock off.
Good night, Paul.
Good night, Billie.
Good night, Harry.
What's the matter, Harry?
You miss me?
I got something to say
and I don't like to wait.
I know.
-Now I'm not so sure.
-Why not?
Talking fresh, slamming doors.
I knew you'd be back.
-You did?
-Jim was worried, not me.
Not yet.
-What took you so long?
-I had a lot to think.
-For instance?
-Where I stand around here.
-I'm trying to tell you.
-What?
Where you stand.
First, Verrall is out.
I don't like to see you upset.
-Next, we'll get married.
-No.
But you gotta behave--
No?
-What do you mean, '' no''?
-I don't wanna, that's what.
-In fact, I've never been so insulted!
-Who are you to say no?
Don't knock yourself out.
You got a lot of surprises coming.
-Just tell me.
-What?
-How can you not wanna marry me?
-For one, you're dumb.
I got a different kind of life in mind.
Sorry, you wouldn't fit in.
-I don't understand!
-I do.
What did I do?
I talked rough to you. Maybe I hit you
a couple of times. Easy.
Is that any reason
to treat me like this?
I done good too.
Can't we straighten it out?
-No.
-Why not?
All that stuff I've been studying,
it just mixed me up.
But when you hit me before...
...it was like it all knocked
together in my head and made sense.
I realized what it means.
How some people are always giving it,
and some taking. And it's not fair.
So I'm not gonna let you anymore.
Or anybody else.
Listen, kid. I got an idea.
You wanna come to Florida?
We used to have some good times
together. Remember?
I think you should
marry me. Don't you?
I want you to marry me.
Do what I tell you or you'll be sorry.
-I'm not scared of you anymore, Harry.
-You're not, huh?
-And something else. I'm leaving.
-What?
For good.
You just can't walk out.
You're in too deep. I was wrong
hooking you in, but you're in.
-I'm not gonna be.
-You wanna wash it up?
Fine! I'm too important
to monkey around with you.
Jim! Jim, wake up!
What is it?
-Come on, you've got some work to do.
-All right. Be right with you.
Okay. Well, get a move on!
I'll fix it so you're out.
You're spoiled. I spoiled you.
I was gonna make you be a real partner.
You don't want it? Fine!
And you don't look like you used to.
I'll be glad to be rid of you.
And as far as I'm concerned....
Vice versa.
You're back.
-All set?
-Shut up!
Settle things up
and get her out of here.
-Are you sure?
-First time I am.
-Where's that stuff?
-In your bedroom.
-No!
-What do you mean, '' no''?
I mean, let's take the shortcut.
The sooner, the better.
They're in the bottom drawer.
-Blue covers?
-Yeah.
-Three copies?
-That's right.
Paul took them.
-When?
-Just now.
What for?
Why do you think?
To put in the newspapers.
-Some jokes I don't like.
-It's no joke.
Paul says it's
the biggest swindle...
...since ''the teapot.''
Something like that.
Why are you getting so white?
You told me it was perfectly
all right.
-You double-crossing--
-It's not like that.
lf there's a fire and I call
the engines, who am I double-crossing?
The fire?
lf this breaks,
nobody will play with us.
-What's to do?
-Might be best to call it off.
-What?
-Let him publish--
I've spent a lot of dough.
Just let that ride?
-Play it safe.
-I want my deal.
-Gonna be tough to get.
-Because of some weasel?
-Harry--
-You're chicken!
-Think so?
-Yes.
-I've been right and you've been wrong.
-Shut up!
I'll handle this.
All right.
-Looking for someone?
-Billie.
Come on in.
-Billie!
-Gee, I'm tired. I was down--
-I think you got something of mine.
-That so?
How about it?
Sit down.
-Hello.
-How you been?
-Fine, you?
-Fine.
-Go to his place and get the stuff.
-It's not there.
Where then?
You wanna play rough?
I can do that too.
I mean business.
I got too much at stake.
You wanna get out alive,
you better give it back.
-I'm no blowhard. Tell him.
-He's no blowhard.
He's had people killed before.
About six years ago--
You ain't gonna tell
nobody nothing soon.
-Double negative! Right?
-Right.
You're gonna be in trouble
unless you do what I say.
Wait. There's another way
to handle this.
You've pulled a boner, friend.
My advice is lay off.
Stop sticking your noses
in my business.
You're the biggest buttinsky
I ever met.
That's my job. Your papers are
in the mail, addressed to myself.
-Your job? Getting in my way?
-Not exactly.
What, then? I'd like to know.
To find out what goes on
and get it to the people.
-What people?
-''The'' people.
-Never heard of them.
-You will.
They're more well-known
all the time.
-And if we're operating within the law?
-Then the law needs revision.
-Are you the government?
-Yes.
-Since when?
-Since 1 7 7 9. Right?
Right.
What do you think you've got?
Harry's connection
to Hedge's amendment.
-Why single us out?
-Yeah, why?
What we're doing is done every day.
Murders could go undiscovered
every day. What does that prove?
Undercover pressure, bribery,
corruption, government between friends!
It's tough to crack.
Ask me, I've tried for years.
You need more than knowing.
You gotta have facts.
-And most important, the names.
-He's got them.
All right. Let's get down to it.
What will you take, Paul?
I'll take a drink.
I ain't met a guy
didn't have his price.
-I have.
-I mean big numbers!
You'll be wearing
a big number across your chest!
I'll get to you later.
There's two ways to do this. One,
play ball. Two, watch your step...
...because there's no place you can
live if you monkey-wrench me.
What do you say?
-I'd like to think it over.
-All right. You got two minutes.
Come on, Billie.
Wait a minute, Harry!
Cut it out, Harry!
-Operator!
-Behave yourself.
You stupid fool.
What do you think you are?
This muscle stuff is a thing
of the past. Cut it out!
I got mad.
Who are you to get mad?
-Be grateful you're free!
-You don't know me to talk like that!
I know you. A kick in the keister
and your problems are solved.
Bigger problems, bigger kicks.
Who's next? The nation?
Don't blow your top.
I'm still ready to do business.
How's 1 00 grand?
A hundred grand is beautiful,
but I can't take it.
Why not?
-My girl wouldn't like it, would she?
-No, she wouldn't.
Then what's your idea?
No idea. Legislation's
not meant for buying and selling.
''This country belongs
to the people who inhibit it'' !
-lnhabit.
-lnhabit it!
-I'll do what I want.
-Try it.
-Who'll stop me?
-Us two.
Youse two? It'll be some day...
...when a hundred-a-week hick
and a dumb broad can stop me.
And you, standing around like
you're deaf! Say something!
-All right, I'll say something.
-Well?
They're right.
Whose side are you on?
What do you want?
-Rye ginger ale.
-Who asked you?
Tell that congressman he's
alI washed up. I guarantee.
You won't
get away with it either.
-Don't worry about me.
-But I do. I worry like the devil.
When you live in Washington
it's enough to break your heart.
You see a piece of machinery,
the democratic structure...
...and somebody's always
tampering with it.
Steal from the government and
you steal from yourself, you dumb ox!
I'm going right ahead.
-I'll tell you where you're going.
-You?
In this whole thing, I guess you
forgot about how I'm a partner.
Jim once told me.
1 26 different yards I own.
Control.
Same thing. Here's how it is.
I don't want them.
I don't want what's yours,
so I'm signing them back.
-All right.
-Only not all at once. One at a time.
One a year.
Only you gotta behave!
lf you don't,
I could let go on everything.
For what you've done,
even since I've known you...
...I bet you could be put in jail
for about 900 years.
You'd be a pretty old man
when you got out.
What's going on around here?
A revolution.
Come on, Paul.
I'll send for my things.
You little crumb. You'll be
sorry for this. Wait and see.
Go ahead.
You don't stand a chance.
You'll outsmart yourself.
-Goodbye, all.
-And you!
-Me?
-Yeah!
-You're fired.
-Sorry. I enjoyed working for you.
-Open up.
-All right, Harry?
Do what I'm telling you!
How do you like that?
He could've had 1 00 grand.
She could've had me.
Both wind up with nothing.
Dumb chump!
Crazy broad.
To all the dumb chumps
and all the crazy broads...
...past, present and future...
...who thirst for knowledge
and search for truth...
...who fight for justice
and civilize each other...
...and make it so tough
for crooks like you.
And me.
License, please.
-No, not this license.
-Sorry.
Forget it.
My wedding present.
-Take it easy, or you'll never make it.
-We'll make it.
It's a clear case
of predestination.
'' Pre'' what?
Look it up.
Odwied www.NAPiSY.info