When shall I pick you up, sir?
Give me time for a couple of cocktails.
Half an hour.
- Yes, sir.
Mrs Farnsworth asked me to remind you
of your dinner engagement tonight.
A half-hour will just give me
time to change and make it.
By the way.
Did Mrs Farnsworth mention
with whom we dine?
With the Lindens, sir.
- Oh.
The Lindens.
You'd better make it an hour, Williams.
I find I'll need more
cocktails than I thought.
I beg your pardon .. but
aren't you Joyce Heath?
No.
- But I ..
You've made a mistake.
Perhaps I have .. pardon me.
Gentlemen.
How are you, Mr Farnsworth?
- Evening, Roger.
Anthony, a Sidecar with just a
splash more brandy than necessary.
I suppose you know what brandy
does to your liver, Roger.
Yes. That's why I stopped
port and turned to brandy.
Your liver is far less
conspicuous than your nose.
Do you chaps remember
an actress Joyce Heath?
I'll never forget her
as Camille .. Sappho.
I saw her only once,
but I'll never forget her.
What a vitally tempestuous
creature she was.
It's amazing how a powerful personality
can project itself over the footlights.
That night I was in
the rear of the theater.
Yet couldn't have been closer
if I held her in my arms.
Not closer perhaps,
but more interesting.
Quiet .. let the gentleman confess.
Joyce Heath never knew it.
But she prompted me to make a decision
that remade the course of my whole life.
The career my family planned for
me in Wall Street I discarded.
I suddenly got the urge to create.
I gave up writing as I couldn't write,
and music because I couldn't play.
But I could draw.
Three years in Paris taught me ..
Not defeat .. but compromise.
I still had enough of the
urge left to try architecture.
I saw her tonight, just as I came in.
Dowdy, down and out.
And ashamed of being Joyce Heath.
She was tops.
What's the matter, Mr Hanley?
Isn't the Highball right?
Oh .. the Highball. Yes, perfect.
Why?
You looked as if something
tasted or smelt bad.
I would rather you wouldn't mention
that. I was reading my own column.
Ted.
- Yeah?
We want to ask you something.
Yes, it's a toupee.
What about Joyce Heath? She was a star.
She was too brilliant.
Too startling for a star.
She was a comet.
Which appeared suddenly.
Fell spectacularly.
And disappeared completely.
That, gentlemen, is a metaphor.
One of the great actresses.
And Joyce Heath.
That's why I can't read his column.
He writes that way too.
Yes, but what happened to her, Ted?
Fantastic as it may sound .. a jinx.
One she put on other people.
A jinx?
It started when her leading man
was killed on an opening night.
From then on .. everyone associated with
her was haunted by failures, divorces ..
Suicides and scandals.
That's right. She practically
lived on the front page.
At first, she laughed
at the superstition.
Then she believed it.
Last time I saw her, she was
on a cheap Vaudeville tour.
Then she vanished.
Like the magician's lady.
Sounds almost unbelievable, doesn't it.
But it happened.
I have to break into a trot if I want
to change and pick up Gail in time.
We have a dinner date.
- The Lindens?
The Lindens.
I think they get most of their guests
from the tomb of Ramses The Second.
There's quite a few valuable
civil war relics among them too.
Goodnight.
- Night.
A clever boy.
One of the best architects
in the country.
With his reputation and Gail Armitage
connections he'll come out alright.
By the way, when will they be married?
It hasn't been arranged yet.
- How do you know?
Mrs Farnsworth hasn't heard.
Maybe they're keeping it a secret?
What, from my wife? Impossible.
Good evening, Cato.
- Good evening.
I'm late, Cato. You'd better draw me a
bath, lay out my dinner jacket and ..
Never mind the bath.
Did you ever try putting celluloid fish
in the tub to entice him into it, Cato?
Gail, what are you doing here?
I finished early, so I came over to save
you the bother of driving out to get me.
Good for you.
Cato .. stew up a cocktail.
I don't want a cocktail, thank you.
Some hors d'oeuvres, Cato.
- They always spoil my dinner.
Cato, you fix the young lady a ham
sandwich whether she wants it or not.
Gail, what do you think?
- That I love you.
I'm pretty fond of myself this evening.
The bank is going to
make the building loan.
Don, how marvelous.
- Miraculous is the word.
All I have to do is put a
hundred thousand in escrow.
But they could let you
have the land now.
Don't worry about the petty cash.
It will come out alright.
Think of really starting on the estates,
after dreaming about them for years.
I know exactly how
they're going to look.
Unless I fall down, they'll be the most
beautiful estates in the whole country.
And I can't fall down.
I've worked too hard,
I've waited too long to flop.
It seems as though it's all really
going to come through, doesn't it.
I guess we have everything, young lady.
And best of all, we have us.
Ham sandwich, please?
No mustard.
- No mustard?
- Cato, go look for some mustard.
If you find it and bring it here, you'll
go out of here looking like a hot-dog.
Happy?
- Ecstatically.
Why?
Because dear, I have a very good sense.
You ineffable cad, you.
You adorable darling, you.
Darling, hurry. Get dressed or
we'll be late for the Lindens.
Can't we get out of it somehow?
- No, we cannot.
You'll meet a lot of people there
who can afford to buy your houses.
People who go to the Lindens don't
need houses, they need tombs.
[ Meow ]
Woof, woof.
- Meow.
Gail and I couldn't stand it any longer.
Being the extra man at a Linden party
is like being a spare corpse at a wake.
I could kiss you for
getting us out of there.
I could too, if you didn't look so much
like a horse that threw me once.
Be exact. There have been so many.
Delightful women you take up with.
Where to, shrew?
What can I do?
Steal watermelons?
- Get tattooed?
Paint mustaches on a library lion.
One of you are bound to say
something rude if this goes on.
I'd like to go to shooting galleries
and Honkytonks and things.
An idea.
I'll send my driver home, and
we'll all go with you in your car.
No you won't. I've a tough day tomorrow.
I want to get up early.
I don't want to spend tonight escorting
you in, and carrying you out of a club.
Say, listen. I've never been
carried to any place in my life.
Thrown, yes .. but carried, never.
Well, whisk away and I'll follow.
Come on. Let's not go home.
Let's go in here and splash
about in some birds nest soup.
How about a little high
class sharpshooting?
A harbor for flotsam and jetsam.
A bit of O'Henry's.
You win.
A smart looking place.
Whose idea was this?
We can sit here.
I guess we'd better stand at the bar.
You'd better sit where
he tells you to, dear.
Oh Don, this is such a depressing place.
- You don't want to stay?
No, let's get out of here. Come on.
Some other time.
You can chalk one up against me.
I certainly can pick them.
Now where?
It's after 12 o'clock.
Don has to get to bed.
He's been working like a Trojan lately.
Why don't you go on with Teddy.
Let him take you home.
It would save me an hour,
getting out and back.
Do you mind, Teddy?
No. Not if you don't talk about Don.
- Alright. Why don't you do it then?
I think I will. I've got an early
meeting in the morning.
I'll call you after that.
Don't forget.
- No.
Listen, you're coming out to the club to
see me play Polo next week aren't you?
You mean to see the horseplay
until you get tired? I might.
Goodnight.
Goodnight, darling.
- Goodnight.
Do you mind if I sit down?
Not if you buy a drink.
- Two of whatever the lady is drinking.
Straight gin.
I've seen you before.
Which doesn't make us old friends.
Well you see, one time, I ..
It really doesn't interest
me, if you don't mind.
Thanks.
Not at all.
Rather ironical, isn't it?
Are you going to drink that?
Haven't you had enough?
Quite enough.
Goodnight, Joyce Heath.
What did you say?
Joyce Heath.
I ..
Joyce Heath, the actress.
Sitting in a dive like this
swilling down cheap gin?
You must be drunk too.
No, there isn't much similarity
except in appearance.
Lots of people look alike.
Joyce Heath was full of life.
I'll never forget the time I saw her.
She was playing Juliet.
Do you remember the scene where you
were told you had to marry Count Paris?
And you took the sleeping draught to
pretend death until Romeo's return?
As your mother kissed you goodnight ..
And left you.
You began:
'Farewell'.
'God knows when we shall meet again'.
Farewell.
God knows when we shall meet again.
A faint, cold fear thrills my veins.
And almost freezes out the heat of life.
I shall call them back to comfort me.
Nurse.
What should she do here?
My needs must act my dismal scene alone.
Come, vial.
What if this mixture do not work?
Shall I, by force, be
married to the Count?
No.
No .. this shall ..
This shall ..
Passed out?
Seems so.
I'll call the wagon.
They'll throw her in the tank until
she comes to in the morning.
Waiter.
I'll take her home.
Okay buddy. Pay me twenty cents
for them two drinks and she's yours.
Keep the change, boss?
- Yes.
Okay.
[ Door knocks ]
Yes?
You look poorly.
Then it won't surprise you to be
told that I feel poorly.
No.
Figuring the moist condition
you arrived in last night.
And just where did I arrive? I'm not
asking you to betray a confidence.
This is Mr Bellows' place.
He's an architect.
One of them fellows who draws pictures.
Thank you.
I suppose you are Mrs Bellows?
Or are you just one of his sketches?
Nope.
I'm his housekeeper for when
he comes down here weekends.
How cozy. And Mr Bellows, where is he?
He's having breakfast.
And if you want to see him, you better
look perky. He's got to get to town.
I'm looking forward
to seeing Mr Bellows.
Stop that.
- Leave me alone.
I wasn't going to push you ..
- Do you mind leaving me alone?
Nope .. in fact, I'd like it.
Well, she's up.
Oh.
I bet the Mahoney boys are having
a parade for her this morning.
There weren't no-one in her room.
I don't know the Mahoney boys anyhow.
You never heard of the Mahoney Boys?
You're very fortunate.
Tiny men with purple beards.
That play tunes with nail-files
on your teeth with one hand ..
And keep time with mallets
inside your head with the other.
At the same time they run around your
stomach planting jumping beans.
You wouldn't be pulling my
leg would you Mr Bellows?
Please .. Mrs Williams.
Feeling better?
- I'd like a drink.
Before breakfast?
Get me a drink.
Why don't you lay off that stuff?
Because I'd rather be drunk than sober.
I gathered that last night.
Last night?
Oh, you must be quite
proud of your conquest.
You're very wrong. You see, I ..
Don't bother with alibis.
It really doesn't matter.
You are a perfect alibi.
Take a look at yourself.
Take a good look.
Drunken. Ill-kept.
The only feeling you can
arouse in a man is pity.
Pity?
Pity? You dare to feel sorry for me.
You with your fat little
soul and your smug face.
Picking your way so cautiously
through a pastel existence.
Why, I've lived more in a day
than you'll ever dare live.
Pity for me?
That's very funny, when I've
never had any for men like you.
You know, just now you are
as I imagined you would be.
Playing a second act speech
in a third-act coat.
When you boast to your friends
about seeing me here ..
I shouldn't mention that
I've become a has-been.
It would detract frightfully from
the glamour of your adventure.
Look here, Miss Heath.
The reason I brought you here ..
I know. Because you were sorry for me.
You've already said that.
No.
Because I was grateful to you for
something very important in my life.
I suppose you always loved the theater.
It was more than that.
The beauty and fineness of one of your
performances moved me so strongly ..
That the whole pattern
of my life was altered.
I've had plenty to be grateful for.
But first of all I owe you
my deepest gratitude.
Well?
Then I'm humiliated to the
point where I must thank you.
Breakfast .. breakfast ..
Oh.
Smoking before breakfast.
You'll spoil your appetite.
Being here already has.
Restful here, isn't it.
The whole countryside
seems to have found peace.
A person could find peace too.
- No.
You only find that in yourself and
when you do you may as well be dead.
Dead?
'Rest In Peace' is for tombstones.
And for the living?
Desire .. to want something ..
You'll tame that desire and
live up to every moment of it.
And then go on leaving yesterday behind.
On and on .. higher and higher.
Frustrated actress reads
lines for small audience.
You could go on.
Talent like yours doesn't die.
You were a star once. You can be again.
Uhuh .. an evil star, a jinx.
You'd better run for your life.
You can't possibly believe that
silly theatrical superstition.
Well, two men who loved me are
dead and some financially ruined.
Shows have folded.
How can I possibly ignore it when
producers won't give me parts?
Your breakfast is getting cold.
And you'd better be getting back to
town if you want to change your duds.
You know, there is
something in what you say.
I don't want breakfast. I go with you.
- Why don't you stay out the week?
No-one will be using the house, so I can
come down Saturday, and take you in.
The rest and quiet will do you good.
Helping me is like shaking hands with
the devil. The worst luck in the world.
That's ridiculous.
Do you really want to go back to town?
I don't care.
You wouldn't feel obligated
if you stayed, would you?
Why should I?
What difference does it make?
Of course. It doesn't make any
difference. Then you'll stay?
Yes, yes! But stop asking me questions.
Go on and boast to your friends about
fishing Joyce Heath out of the gutter.
I won't mention it, I can assure you.
Better watch her pretty closely. She's
on the verge of going off the deep end.
Come and have your
breakfast before it gets cold.
May I please have a drink?
Fresh milk? Country sausage?
Come and get it.
There's lots to tuck away.
I asked for a drink. Where's the bottle?
Yes dear .. after you've eaten.
I don't want your greasy food.
I want a drink.
Where is it?
Now, it will only make you
more sick and fidgety.
You're worn to a frazzle.
What you need is rest and food.
Where is it?
- Uh ..
I don't know.
- You're a liar.
Now, now, now, now.
- Give me the key.
I haven't got it.
My dear ..
- Leave me alone.
My dear.
You've cut yourself.
I reckon it isn't the first time you've
been hurt getting things you shouldn't.
Oh stop nagging me .. get out.
Get out will you.
Ah.
'Phantom of delight' as Wordsworth says.
That's a little thing
I thought up myself.
And not bad either.
And what's the little woman been doing?
- Shopping. You?
Getting a check for a theater job.
Next week I go in escrow.
Grand, isn't it?
And those estates will be your
masterpiece, Don. I know it.
I've talked to more people
that are interested.
They'd better be.
When my creditors get through
subdividing my shirt ..
There won't be enough of it left
to show on a blue serge suit.
Stop worrying.
By the way, I've come to take you to
the Polo matches. Teddy's playing.
Teddy?
You know, I often wonder why he
doesn't use a croquet mallet.
He's on the ground most of the game.
Will you hurry up?
We've missed the first chukka as it is.
I'll take 4-1 on Teddy's collarbone.
Nope. But I'll take 2-1 on a rib.
Oh, I can't go.
Why not?
I've just remembered I've promised to
go down to the country this afternoon.
Why?
It's rather an interesting .. case.
Remember the night you and I and
Teddy sneaked out of the Linden party?
Well.
Oh I forgot .. I promised not to tell.
It sounds intriguing.
Well it was a peculiar incident.
I don't see any reason
why I shouldn't tell you.
Nope, better not.
A promise is a promise.
Will you be home by Sunday?
- Tonight.
If you ask me to breakfast
Sunday morning ..
I take you on the golf course, give you
a stroke a hole, and beat the pants ..
We call them 'slacks'.
You may kiss me.
Goodbye. See you Sunday.
Good evening, widow Williams.
Staying to dinner Mister Don? Pot roast.
Pot roast? With all those potatoes
and carrots and onions around it?
It's a shame to disturb them.
They look so cozy.
And turnips.
Turnips?
And what's the matter with turnips?
Turnips are good for you.
They grow hair on your chest.
Do you eat them?
Sure.
Mr Don, don't be pesky.
How did you guess?
She isn't exactly chatty.
You'll get more folksy
conversation out of a snowman.
Where is she now?
- Gone up the hill towards the barn.
I'd better go and try and find her.
It looks like rain to me.
Now that corn of mine has been
prophesying rain for 30 years.
Excepting once.
That was my own fault for trimming him.
I'd better hurry then.
When are you going to fetch
her home, Mister Don?
Whenever she wants to go. Why?
Nothing. I was just .. talking.
I'll be glad when she's gone though.
Why?
You know, it's different
for a man like you.
But a woman knows an awful
lot about another woman.
And she's dangerous.
A bad woman's got something
a good woman ain't.
And a good woman is jealous of
that something, and afraid of it.
I don't know what it is, but ..
She's got it.
Sounds to me as if you've been reading
bad translations of French novels.
In the first place, I don't find Miss
Heath especially attractive off stage.
And in the second place,
it's no concern of yours.
I guess he's right. I'm an old fool
getting to be a regular busybody.
Miss Heath.
Hey .. wake up.
Oh, it's you.
On Saturday, I ..
I fell asleep in a bar.
It all comes back to me now.
Yes, it's also going to rain. It would
be good sense to come in out of it.
That's merely hearsay.
Would you hand me my
shoes and stockings please?
Thanks.
You know, you are looking much better.
I've enjoyed this afternoon.
Going barefoot and sleeping in the sun.
Playing a sort of a Naiad in the jungle.
What do you mean? What's a 'Naiad'?
It's some sort of a wood nymph.
I'm not .. I'm not very
much up on my sprites.
I must say a 'Naiad' becomes
you better than a 'Maenad'.
Fancy.
What's a 'Maenad'?
They were mythical women,
famous for their beauty and charm.
Who attended the Dionysian rebels.
They were always so carried
away by the wild madness that ..
They ended up by dancing hysterically
over the edge of a cliff to destruction.
Sorry, but I'm too tired
to be hysterical, and my ..
My feet are much too sore
from going barefoot ..
To stand the jar of
dancing over the cliff.
By the way, I ..
I got the sermon.
Ha.
There's one little piggy that's going to
market in a shocking state of nudity.
I hope you don't mind me
borrowing some of your clothes.
Not at all.
Sorry.
[ Thunderclap! ]
Looks as if we're going
to have a cloudburst.
What do you find so amusing?
What do you find so disturbing?
Come on, before we get drenched.
Naiad or Maenad, nothing. Mermaids ..
Ha .. come on.
Land's sake, you're soaking wet.
It's all your fault.
If you'd used a corn-plaster,
this wouldn't have happened.
You'd better be going back to town
Mr Don, before you have to go in an ark.
You can't drive back in this rain.
And why can't he, may I ask?
Driving on that road will be
like touring in a full bathtub.
I never thought of that.
You'd better turn down
my bed, Mrs Williams.
I'll get up early and drive in.
Listen to that rain.
You know, I saw you on the
opening night of your Juliet.
Did you?
I think it was one of
your best performances.
Yes.
Which play would you prefer
to do more than any other?
One I've never done.
A thing called 'But To Die'.
I'd give anything in
the world to play it.
I wouldn't have to
act it, I could live it.
Why hasn't somebody produced it for you?
With the 'Jinx woman' of the theater?
Don't be silly.
I noticed a very interesting
play on your bookshelves.
Which one?
It's called .. 'Forever Ends At Dawn'.
'Forever Ends At Dawn'?
I don't think I've ever read it.
It's a beautiful last act.
You wouldn't read it to me, would you?
Are you sure you would like to hear it?
- It would be a treat to listen to you.
Well, just the last act then.
The scene of the play
is the French Riviera.
The story is about a man and a woman.
She's not a very nice person.
But a fascinating one.
The man has a wife or a
fiancée, I've forgotten which.
With whom he's very much in love.
He's intrigued by this woman but
quite nobly resists her charms.
Here it is .. 'Forever Ends At Dawn'.
You may find the dialog a bit
awkward in spots but I'll ..
I'll try and make it convincing.
- I've never heard you when you weren't.
Thank you.
This scene takes place in the
woman's room late at night.
The man has to go home
in the morning so he ..
Comes to say goodbye to her.
I'll read from here.
Richard:
'I had to come and say goodbye'.
'And tell you it's been
swell knowing you'.
Joan:
'Well I .. thought that our goodbye
would be different from this'.
Richard:
'Yes, but you see .. there's always ..'
Joan: 'I know'.
'That girl in the back of your heart'.
Joan:
'Her 'forever' lasts until
death do you part'.
'My 'forever' only until dawn'.
'Tomorrow is where
regrets lie, Richard'.
'But there will be no tomorrow for us'.
'Only tonight'.
'Which we steal from no-one'.
'And forget as a dream which
has no part of our normal lives'.
'Over which we had no control'.
'And for which we need
feel no obligation'.
Is that the end of the play?
Almost.
Let's have some music.
You know, you read that beautifully.
Now you know.
I know it won't do.
Where are you going?
- Out for a walk.
In this rain?
- I like walking in the rain.
So do I. I think I'll go too.
- There is only one slicker.
Why don't you go back?
Kidneys and bacon and cornbread
this morning, Mister Don.
That's fine.
Miss Heath not down yet?
- No. I called her 15 minutes ago.
Mrs Williams, would you mind ..?
Good morning.
Do you like the negligee I
borrowed from Mrs Williams?
It's fine.
Rather cruel, aren't you?
Why do you say that?
You might at least have smiled
at me as I came down the stairs.
Even if it were a lie.
I don't think this is any time to lie.
Or to speak the truth or
to say anything, in fact.
Could I pour you some coffee?
Joyce.
I hate loose ends.
They .. they tangle your
life, they trip you up.
Yes, Don.
Well, last night ..
I'm sorry I kissed you
and said the things I did.
How very gallant of you to say so.
No, you don't understand.
You see, I'm engaged to someone.
And you blame me?
No. It was unfair to you too.
You are so very ..
Fascinating. I think it was that ..
The storm and our nearness
that made me lose my senses.
I've got them back this morning
and I'm asking you to forgive me.
And.
For what I'm saying now if I hurt you.
Hurt me?
You delight me.
You have the most amazing lack
of humor of anyone I've ever known.
I shouldn't laugh at you, should I.
But I can't help it.
You were so awkward I almost
laughed in your face at first.
Then it made me sick
to think that anyone ..
Could be stupid enough to be
taken in by a lot of old tricks.
I thought you might at least be amusing.
But you turned out to be dull
and stupid and so afraid.
You needn't be.
I won't hurt your Sunday School
romance or your oh-so-nice career.
Hurt me? Ha.
Get out of here before
you give me hysterics.
Sorry friend, but I think you stop here.
It does seem advisable, doesn't it.
How soon will you have it repaired?
Oh the lumber will be here about noon.
And I think you ought to get
across early this evening.
Too bad you didn't get off last night.
Yeah.
Can one of your men get across and
telephone for me from the other side?
Why, sure.
- Have him call 'Miss Armitage'.
At Austin 9532.
Say Mr Bellows has been delayed and
can't see her until this evening.
And I'd be much obliged if you let
me know the minute I can get across.
I'm up at the old Quinn Farm.
- Okay. The first thing.
[ Crying sounds ]
Joyce.
Don.
You did come back.
I was praying you would.
I had to. You see ..
It doesn't matter why.
You did, you had to.
You didn't believe what I
said this morning, did you?
Did you?
I guess I had it coming to me.
Oh no, Don. It was a lie.
Let's forget about it.
You can forget that.
But I want you to remember this.
I know you belong to somebody else.
And I don't want you, really I don't.
But last night was mine and ..
And I made it ugly this morning.
I don't want you to
think of it that way.
I won't.
You will, unless I tell you the truth.
You've seen me drunk and disgusting.
You took me in out of pity.
Well, that hurt my pride.
And because I'm a good deal of
a shrew, I wanted to hurt yours.
I was going to tease you
with all the tricks I knew ..
Until you tried to kiss me, and ..
Then I was to laugh in your face.
I was an actress playing a part.
I played it too well.
But when you took me in your
arms .. I didn't want to laugh.
I wanted to cry.
I'm sorry.
- I'm not. I'm glad.
Last night was beautiful.
It will always be beautiful.
And now that it's over.
It's not over, Joyce.
Oh yes, Don. It's got to be over.
Your career is on the verge
of permanent success.
You'll have someone who
can help you. I can't.
I'm the kind of woman
who destroys, not builds.
I'm Joyce Heath, Don.
A Maenad who ..
Who doesn't want to dance over the
cliff with a man as fine as you.
Now come on, let's finish up
the rest of the day very fine.
I'll get dressed. You go down.
I got it.
No, no, Don. That's not fair.
You must be playing by pinochle rules.
- It's just you're slow, that's all.
No wonder.
These cards are so thick and old I could
be playing with Encyclopedia Britannica.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
The recipe said it was toffee.
But that's not what we've got.
I'll never get my jaws apart.
I'm going to bite the
person that said so.
Pardon me a minute, while
I get out a piece of toffee.
I've lost a couple of molars and
a bicuspid that are sticking to it.
Did you get it?
- Yes, but I think I lost a nail.
Perhaps we should put some sand in that
mess to give it something to hold on to.
I wonder if Mrs Williams
would like some.
It would certainly take the rattle
out her uppers and lowers.
I wish I'd never seen you.
Never kissed you.
Never held you in my arms.
Because every time I do, I hate myself.
I hate you.
I can kill every emotion except the
desire to hold you just once more.
[ Door knocks ]
You can get across the road now, sir.
- Thank you.
I got that phone call
through alright too.
Much obliged. Goodnight.
Goodnight.
You can go now?
- Yes.
Then you must.
Because if you stay,
it will be too late.
I love you.
You may never love me but .. you'll
find you always come back to me.
And each time you return it will
cost you more and more until ..
When you've spent your career,
your ambitions, your dreams.
I am bad for people.
I don't mean to be
but I can't help myself.
So I'm being generous to you, Don.
Kind. Kinder than I've ever
been to anybody before.
But I can't be much longer.
So go.
Leave me.
You can leave me, can't you?
I don't know.
I've got to find out.
Mister Don gone, Miss?
Yes.
He's coming back?
Yes, I think he will.
[ Door knocks ]
Yes?
Mr Bellows.
- Huh?
Miss Armitage is on the telephone.
Put her on.
No.
Tell her I'm still out of town.
I'll call her when I get back.
Very well, sir.
Mr Haynes of United Quarries called many
times to ask if you have a decision.
Tell him I haven't been
able to make up my mind.
He said he'd have to have an answer
one way or the other. Yes or No.
He's right.
It's got to be Yes or No.
Thank you Miss Seals.
[ Door knocks ]
Come in.
Mr Bellows, Miss Gail.
Oh.
Show him in, Betty.
And we'll have coffee.
- Van Houtte for Mr Bellows?
That's right.
Well, hello Mr B.
It's about time you were getting back.
Don .. something has happened?
Yes Gail .. something has happened.
Even if it's all for the
worst, it can't be so bad.
Because you've got the most
enthusiastic assistant in the world.
To help you laugh it off.
Or .. to work it out.
Whichever we're going to do.
Gail, it would make me prouder
to have you as my wife ..
Than to have any other
woman in the world.
If I could respect you a little less, it
would all be very simple, but I can't.
So I must ask you a question.
I'm afraid I know the answer already.
What is it, Don?
If we were married, there is one
humiliation you would never know.
That's having me deceive
you with someone else.
I know that.
- But if there were someone else?
Someone I didn't love, that I'll
never even see again, but who ..
But who had a strange,
exotic fascination for me.
An appeal I couldn't kill.
Would that make any difference to you?
Yes Don, it would.
Whether you ever went to
her or not, wouldn't matter.
But the fact that you'd want to would.
It mightn't make me love
any less .. perhaps more.
The agony of wondering every time you
kiss me whether you're thinking of her.
The hate and dread I'd have
for that other woman.
And the terrific loneliness of that
little part of you which I wouldn't own.
It would be unendurable.
I can't tell you Don, how much I
admire you for .. for being so honest.
And thank you for coming to say goodbye.
You're a ..
Goodbye.
Has Mr Bellows gone, Miss Gail?
Is he coming back?
Yes.
Yes, I think he will.
Mr Sheffield.
I've come to see you for some
advice on producing a play.
That's something I know nothing about.
An angel is a celestial being
after death, Mr Bellows.
But before .. he's a sucker.
Thanks for the warning.
What I want is an opinion.
Have you ever heard of a
play called 'But To Die'?
A magnificent script.
Which with the proper lead
would make a great play.
However, miscast ..
It would close so fast the third act
curtain would snag in the stage door.
Who do you see in the lead?
Only two women could have played it:
Jean Eagles and .. Joyce Heath.
Eagles is dead .. Heath has disappeared.
So, forget it.
If I made both the script and Miss Heath
available to you, would you produce it?
Mr Bellows, I have great
respect for the script.
And almost a reverence
for Miss Heath's talent.
But I wouldn't hazard
$80,000 to defy a jinx.
Surely an intelligent man like you won't
take any stock in a legend like that?
When you ask $80,000 for
a share of it I do.
Suppose I pay the $80,000?
Then I would produce
and direct it myself.
Will you have your lawyer
draw up the contract?
Very well.
By the way.
Do you bite your fingernails?
No.
- You will.
[ Dog barking ]
You did come.
You knew I would.
Yes, I knew.
Let's go inside, I only have a minute.
I've got to get right back.
Tonight?
- Yeah.
Darling.
- Joyce.
I want to talk to you.
Now listen ..
You and I are both artists.
I deal in permanence. Things that last.
You in emotions, moments, and things
that flame and burn and leave ashes.
So we're not the same. I know that.
But is there any consistency in
the way you feel towards me?
Couldn't we ask questions afterwards?
No .. I can't build without plans.
Answer me, Joyce. Is there consistency
in your feelings towards me?
Tonight I love you so much that nothing
else matters. A love you couldn't kill.
But that's tonight.
Tomorrow should be the same.
I want it to be.
But I've been betrayed so often by
tomorrows, I don't dare promise that.
It's the only honest answer
I can give you darling.
That's a gentleman's answer, Joyce.
I guess I'm not lady enough to lie.
No, I don't think you would.
I broke my engagement.
Why?
- Because of us.
What about her?
Let's leave her out of it.
All I know is, she's stronger than us,
as if she weren't, I wouldn't be here.
And I'm glad I'm weaker.
You are too, aren't you? Say you are.
No, I'm not.
I'm here.
That's all I care about.
There's other things that
are important to me.
First of all, your career.
Why should you concern
yourself about that?
Because you don't belong in
the audience, but on the stage.
Your emotion, your restlessness,
have beauty and poetry there.
Off the stage they'd be brutal.
They would ruin us both.
I hope that in the theater you'll find
enough release to be content with me.
Why should I find contentment?
I don't want it.
Well I do.
I want you and I want peace too.
They wouldn't let me inside a theater.
They'd be afraid it would fall down.
You start rehearsing 'But To Die' for
George Sheffield on Monday morning.
What?
Me?
But To Die?
Oh you're mad.
Sheffield wouldn't risk it.
You get the script from him tomorrow.
Don .. did you put your money in it?
Yes.
Oh you fool .. you crazy fool.
Something will happen.
I've told you a million
times I'm a jinx.
You are no such thing.
You're a great actress.
I'm so sure, I'll risk the money that's
to realize the one ambition I ever had.
You'll be better than you ever were.
If I'm going to marry Joyce Heath,
it's got to be the real Joyce Heath.
Marry?
Yes.
I can't compromise, and I
won't sneak and apologize.
I'm playing you a game but
I'm playing it for keeps.
What's the matter?
Nothing, only ..
Well, it's all happened
so quickly you know.
Being told about doing the play.
And you wanting to marry me.
You see.
It would ruin your career, Don.
You are society. I am theater.
They just don't mix.
There is still marriage.
Yes, I know. But ..
Let's not talk about it just now.
Think, Don.
Going on the stage for the first
time in two years to play for you ..
Your career and mine.
Our lives, our success,
depending on one performance.
When the lights go out
and that curtain goes up ..
Don, that's being alive.
I love you. I love you for
bringing me back to life.
Are you going back to town tonight?
- Right away.
I'm going with you.
- Why?
To leave two years behind.
Faster.
So that's all it's been to you, Charles.
Just a shipboard romance.
No it wasn't.
- Oh yes.
Just a man telling a woman that the moon
and ocean aren't half as lovely as she.
Swearing devotion, eternal as the tides.
Sweeping the girl off her feet.
All to be forgotten.
That isn't what it's meant to me.
No Charles. It has meant far more.
Your every word, your every
kiss, your every caress.
I've treasured.
Because I've always pretended they
belong to the man I really love.
Now that's something for you to forget.
If you can.
That's fine.
How about it, Miss Heath?
Too tired to go through
that scene again?
No, I'd love to.
I'm sorry .. I've got to beg off.
I'm all in.
You've got too much vitality for me.
And for me too .. we'll call it off.
No rehearsal tomorrow. And we'll run
through it again at 10 o'clock Monday.
I don't like to work on the
day of the night we open.
But there's some things I
must change .. that's all.
Alright boys.
Give me a cigarette.
- Sure .. what do you think?
I've spent a fortune and
misspent a life in the theater.
But this is the only time on
the eve of a dress rehearsal ..
I have nerve enough to say I had a hit.
- You're pretty positive.
So positive that I'll buy your
piece of it for $100,000.
Oh no. Here's one angel who isn't afraid
to tread. I'm as certain as you are.
Isn't she magnificent?
Even in rehearsal, it's the greatest
performance I've ever seen.
With the stimulus of an audience.
Monday night ought to make
her immortal in the theater.
What about that jinx?
Jonah himself couldn't
jinx a talent like that.
Like it?
It's alright I guess.
Needs a lot of work though.
You know darling, if I could get away to
the country and go over this on Sunday.
I think I'd get a better perspective.
Can you run me down tonight?
Certainly. Not a bad idea.
We'd better get under way.
I want to stop by my apartment
to get my clothes.
Alright. Goodnight.
Goodnight, and keep her out of
the poison ivy and the fresh air.
I don't want her to open in a whisper.
Darling.
We can't go on like this.
I could .. forever.
Don't be evasive, Joyce.
You know what I mean.
Getting married?
Well ..
Of course. Sometime, darling.
But right now there is the ..
The show to think of.
- Look here, Joyce.
You always find some reason
to change the subject.
Tell me the truth.
Why are you putting me off?
Don't be so intense, Don.
You know I love you and
that there is no-one else.
Isn't that enough?
No, it's not enough. What's the matter?
Are you afraid to marry me?
Afraid? Why should I be?
I don't know, unless you think marriage
will make me a bit harder to get rid of.
Don't say that Don. Don't.
That night you asked me a month ago.
I said I couldn't promise you tomorrows.
I can now.
I love you enough to
give them all to you.
At least as many as you want.
Then we'll be married right after
the opening on Monday night.
So soon?
If you meant what you said just
now that wouldn't seem soon.
It's not that, Don. Only ..
- Only what?
Well.
Marriage seems to make such
an issue out of everything.
Why can't we wait a while?
- No.
I'm not going to trail around after
you like a stage-door Johnny.
And make a sap out of myself
waiting for you to get out of a mood.
I want you .. but I'm through begging.
It's either Monday night or never.
Well of course, darling.
Alright.
I'll marry you Monday,
right after the show.
We'll go down to the
park for one glorious day ..
And I hope it rains and washes the
bridge and the road and everything away.
So we'll be marooned forever.
Put your arms around me
and tell me you love me.
Look, Joyce. You're almost hysterical.
What's the matter?
Oh nothing. Excitement, nerves.
Worrying about the show.
Listen, I've changed my mind.
I'm very tired from rehearsing.
I'd rather go to the country alone.
Would you lend me your car?
Sure. If you want. But I'd hate to
have you driving alone at night.
Don't be silly.
Now be a good boy, and
go now or you'll see me cry.
Hey, what's the matter?
- Nothing I tell you, but stage fright.
Go on now, there is
always a taxi out front.
I can see the old southern hospitality
and the artistic temperament don't mix.
Goodnight, drive carefully and
leave the jitters down there.
I got your bag packed for you, honey.
- Well, put it down and get out of here.
Yes, ma'am.
Joyce.
I hoped you'd come
like this so many times.
And you have, haven't you?
- Yes.
On business.
Come in.
I rather hate to have
you see my quarters.
Spare yourself any embarrassment.
I didn't come here out of curiosity.
You'll find this one more comfortable.
I shan't be here long enough
to find this one uncomfortable.
Cigarette?
No thank you.
You still hate me, don't you?
- No, Gordon. I don't.
There is an element of respect in hate.
The only feeling I have
for you is contempt.
You are very fortunate.
Contempt is much easier to carry in your
heart than a love you can't destroy.
You do love me, don't you Gordon?
When a man ruins his life for something,
it's liable to be pretty real.
I'm a bookkeeper now, Joyce.
In a company I used to own.
The worst of it is, I can't hate you.
I don't suppose you can understand that.
I never could before. I do now.
You see, I loved somebody
that way too, Gordon.
Heaven help you.
Heaven help me if .. if you won't.
You want me to divorce you?
Oh yes, Gordon.
I've told you time and
time again that I won't.
You are my wife.
Something you will never
be to any other man.
Being your husband is the only thing
I've got left and I won't lose it.
You'll be my wife until the day I die.
Then I'll divorce you.
You can't, Joyce.
You haven't any grounds.
You never will have.
Gordon.
I know I've ruined your happiness,
but don't ruin mine.
If it's revenge you want,
I'll give it to you.
I'll beg, I'll crawl. I'll do
anything. Anything.
Gordon.
Gordon, look at me.
If you want to humiliate me,
you know how.
But set me free, give me my
one chance of happiness.
Please Gordon.
Please, please!
Oh you cheap, petty bookkeeper, you.
Every time I think of those sticky hands
of yours touching me it makes me sick.
'Sick' do you hear?
You are everything that's
repulsive to me. Your wife.
I've never been a wife to you,
you poor, simpering fool.
If you had any pride, if you were a
man, instead of a drooling milksop.
You'd throw me out and be ashamed
to admit you ever married me.
I guess I'm better protected
against you than I used to be.
Neither that, nor what
you said, seemed to hurt.
Gordon.
Gordon .. you can't still love me.
When you know how I feel.
Yes, I do.
And .. and you ..?
And I won't divorce you .. no.
Gordon.
Gordon, I guess we are
ordained never to be happy.
So perhaps it would be better to make
the best of what we have and ..
To try and find contentment together.
That's all I'd ask, Joyce .. ever.
I'm going down to the
country over the weekend.
Come along if you like.
May I, Joyce?
May I?
Gordon.
Would nothing in the world
induce you to divorce me?
Nothing.
Not even to save your life?
- No.
Then we're going to settle
this thing once and for all.
If I can't have him, I'd rather be dead.
It's going to be your life or mine.
- Good.
We're coming to a tree in the
middle of the road. We're taking it.
If you're killed, I'll be free.
If I'm killed, it really doesn't matter.
If we both die .. good riddance.
Good.
You've taken everything but my life.
I don't want that without you.
Go ahead .. crash it.
Well, I heard a crash.
And I came a-running.
Then I saw Miss Heath with this fellow.
And that's all I know.
I wonder how badly
the little thing is hurt.
How do you know it was Joyce Heath?
Well, she's been staying
at Mr Bellows' farm.
I ought to know. I'm his housekeeper.
Mr Bellows? You mean
Donald Bellows the architect?
That's who I mean.
And if you want to know more
you'd better ask him yourself.
He should be here by now. I phoned.
Yeah thanks.
It may be a good idea to ask.
Listen, I need First Aid.
I'm a reporter, I got a lead.
I don't want to use the payphone
because of the other reporters, so ..
Can I use yours?
- I suppose so.
Another Florence Nightingale.
Hello. Give me Rewrite.
Eddie?
Listen, get this and don't squeeze it
because it will squirt in your eyes.
Yeah, juicy.
Joyce Heath who's opening a new show on
Monday was hurt in an auto accident.
With her was an, as yet,
unidentified man.
The housekeeper for Don Bellows,
socialite and architect.
Just admitted Joyce had
been living at his farm.
Bellows recently broke his engagement to
Gail Armitage of the 'Utter Armitages'.
Yeah. Better check that
last and I'll call you back.
And get your bucket and spade ready,
as I think we'll dish up some dirt.
Okay.
Well .. it's better than collecting
garbage. It's not so heavy.
Pardon me.
- Yes?
I'm Donald Bellows.
What about Miss Heath?
It isn't serious, is it?
Well.
There's the Doctor now. Doctor.
Doctor, this is Mr Bellows
about Miss Heath.
How is she?
- Badly shaken up.
Suffering from shock and
a very slight concussion.
She may be on her feet
in a couple of weeks.
The man however, is very seriously hurt.
It may be more than a year
before he'll be able to walk.
What man?
- Gordon Heath.
Gordon Heath?
Yes. He's been identified
as her husband.
Her husband?
Mrs Heath is conscious if you would
care to see her for a few minutes.
No, I don't want to see her.
Please see they both
get every possible care.
Anything. I'll be responsible.
I think you just handed him one, Doc.
It will sure look swell in print.
[ Telephone ]
Yes?
Oh yes, Don.
We've got to open without her.
What else can I do?
The understudy.
And she'll put the show right back
on the truck for Keynes warehouse.
Yes, she's jinxed you out of $80,000,
me out of the best show I ever had.
And herself out of a performance that
would make her a great American actress.
Sorry, old boy.
[ Door knocks ]
Yes?
Mr Elmont is here.
You got here in a hurry.
- It's important.
Yes?
Bellows.
We're unable to make the loan.
Not make it?
Why, it's almost a million dollars.
You can't sell me out.
I'm ready to start.
It's rumored that you put $80,000
in a show that's doomed to fail.
Is that correct?
- Fail?
Yes .. it will fail but ..
I can borrow that someplace else.
That's only a technicality.
We're forced to take advantage
of that technicality.
The board of directors, most of whom
are socially prominent .. insist on it.
Would you mind being
specific instead of subtle.
They feel the people who would've bought
the estates are prejudiced against you.
In other words, they don't
think you can sell them.
Because they're going to stop you.
Stop me?
Those snobs?
They won't. They or anybody else.
I put ten years in. Poured in everything
I ever earned into those estates.
I'm not going to lose them.
I'll get the money somewhere.
Well .. I hope you do.
But I don't think you can.
Well, Miss Seals. Let's have the
rest of the unfinished business.
The Roma Cement Company called.
Ignore it. We're not building anything.
Mr Darrell called and a Mr Wilson.
And Miss Heath from the hospital.
She said it was urgent.
Yes, I guess that does come
under 'unfinished business'.
Are you sure you've called
his office, his home?
Yes dear, don't worry.
Everything will be alright.
It's not, I tell you. It's not.
He couldn't let me lie here
like this unless he hated me.
Don.
Why have you waited so
long to come and see me?
You blame me for what happened.
I knew you would.
That's why you didn't come.
Yes, I blame you.
Don't say that, Don. Don't.
It's the jinx. I warned you.
I can't help it. I can't.
You mean you can't help
being rotten and selfish.
You'd do anything to get your own desire
and go on, leaving someone else to pay.
That's the jinx you put on people.
I was willing to sacrifice
my life for you.
Is that selfishness?
Yes, as you were afraid to risk losing
me by telling me you had a husband.
So, instead you lied and ruined me.
And your husband.
What it's cost him to love you.
You never paid for any happiness
in your whole life. You owe for it.
It cost everybody else but you.
I can't afford any more.
There's one thing I know.
If you'll ever be anything but  a jinx
you'd better start paying off.
Because you're in debt
for the rest of your life.
Mrs Heath.
I was just in to see your husband.
He's been inquiring about you.
My husband.
Yes. My husband.
I must get up today.
But you can't. It's much too soon.
I must .. I've got some debts to pay.
Of course you know.
To reopen a play that's failed
and make a success of it.
Is next to impossible.
- The play wasn't a failure.
The only failure was mine to appear.
I can make that play a success.
You're quite confident?
More than confident. I'm positive.
Why?
Four very distinct reasons.
Any one of them so important to
me that it makes failure impossible.
First, I'm the only actress
suited to that part.
Second. Don must get his money back.
Third, I have a husband who's
injured for life because of me.
I must support him.
And last but most important.
I found out how to break my jinx.
By paying my debts.
Are you strong enough to
start rehearsing Monday?
Yes.
I've got to be.
Monday morning at ten, then.
Monday morning at ten.
Thanks so much.
Pardon the coincidence.
It's no coincidence, Joyce.
I've been looking for you.
They told me you'd come here.
I want to talk to you.
You were very frank the
last time we talked together.
Everything I said was the truth.
Let me be just as frank
and just as honest.
You're no longer important to me.
Your importance ended
when the show closed.
You mean, I was just a means to an end?
Why not call it that?
How cheap.
- No, I ..
I'm rather expensive.
Remember what it cost you.
Darling.
Oh, darling.
..t-g..