ELENA
Get up.
– Good morning.
– Morning.
If they don't look after themselves,
they'll pile on the weight
and have lots of other
illnesses to deal with.
So take a good hard
look at your lifestyle.
Adjust your tastes.
The easy way to eat healthily
is to eat salads!
Bon appetit.
The porridge is perfect.
What have you got planned today?
I've got to go pick up
my pension at the bank,
then I'm going to see Sergei.
He should be coming here.
He needs the money, not you.
It's not about the money.
That's exactly what it's about.
What are you always
traipsing over there for?
He should drag himself
over here. He's a big boy.
Just drop it.
I don't tell you, how
to treat your daughter.
Dropped.
I hope you're not staying over?
No.
– Good morning.
– Hello.
There you are.
See you later.
Good afternoon, ladies and gentlemen.
Today we've got a fine selection
of glossy magazines
for the lovely ladies,
also crosswords,
adult magazines and today's press.
No sense in a boring ride;
just stop me as I come by.
1, 425 roubles.
Nadya! Come take care of this.
– Hello.
Is someone gonna get
that? Sasha! Are you deaf?
Whatever…
– Oh, Sasha. Hi.
– Hi.
Where're you going?
Take these to the kitchen.
– Hi, Ma. Come on in.
– Hey.
You need a trim!
Right, here's the money.
Thanks.
Hi, Tanya.
Here he comes, here he comes!
Oh, look who's here?
– Tanya, I brought some money.
– Elena, thank you.
Give it here.
Can't see through you, woman.
Tanya, put on the kettle.
Just a sec.
– Where are you off to?
– Gonna see Vitya.
Your Vitya isn't going anywhere.
– Back in a sec.
– I know your 'sec'.
He needs these disks now.
You two are going to wind up
in prison or in the army. Got it?
You want me to sit
here like an idiot?
Not like an idiot, like
someone with a future.
Or don't you care about that?
OK, whatever…
Don't 'whatever' me!
Take out the rubbish.
Gimme a sec!
– What 'sec'?
– Nothing.
– What did you say?
Go drink tea with your grandmother.
Well how am I supposed
to talk to him?
I'll talk to him.
I'm coming, Dad. Can't get
past this stupid level!
Just a sec.
– Lemme.
– Dad!
Watch and learn.
Elena, I'll be right back.
Tanya, coming.
Sergei.
I'm talking to my son. Hold on.
Go talk with your mother.
I said, hold on.
Ma, have you talked
with him about Sasha?
Not yet. But I will.
What are you dragging it out for?
We have to know if we
have the money or not.
You know how he feels about that
sort of things. I haven't forgotten.
He knows Sasha.
They're even friends, sort of.
We're family after all.
He's a friend to everyone,
but friends with no one.
He's just a tightass.
Come on, Sergei, stop it.
If it wasn't for him, we
wouldn't have what we do.
Mam,
and what have we got, exactly?
We have to get Sasha
off the draftees list.
He's gotta know what's next for him
– university, or fuck…
… where are they
fighting now – Ossetia?
Right, Tanya?
– More tea, Elena?
– Thanks.
– Sasha, when's the football?
– At nine.
We wouldn't be so worried,
but we'll need money
to talk to the right people
at school and university
before the 20th.
I'll talk to him, I promise.
If you're watching this
and you want to meet up,
I'd be glad to, because…
I want you to know that I'm here.
It looked like he didn't try.
It's pretty disappointing.
It's not the first time…
He's disappointed, too.
What's there to be disappointed
about? He chose to run like that.
But on the other hand, 09: 80…
It's good, but he
should be running faster…
I'm looking for my two brothers.
My parents split up in 1960.
I didn't know I had a dad,
until he wrote to me. I was 13.
He said, that I have two brothers.
I've been looking for them for years.
If only they knew I existed.
Finding them is, like, my life's work.
It's a typical Soviet strategy:
pile the pressure on,
hoping that he'll…
Maybe he'll get there
by the end of the season.
He's already performing differently,
but you can't see
it in the results yet.
Good morning.
I read your note. I understand,
of course, that Sasha
won't get in anywhere
on his own, will he?
I'm afraid not.
Why not serve in the army,
then? Best school there is.
Volodya, you know what it's
like in the army these days!
Why am I supposed
to support your son's family?
Why should I be burdened with paying
for someone's – effectively
a stranger's – education?
I live with you, not
with your relatives.
You know how I feel about this.
And your Sergei still
hasn't returned the money,
he borrowed from me three years
ago, if you haven't forgotten.
I remember. But you know about
Sergei's situation right now.
I know your Sergei
and his 'situation'.
His whole life is one big 'situation'.
I refuse to indulge him anymore.
Let this be a lesson for him.
You don't force lessons
like that on your daughter.
And I'm sure, you never did.
Elena, we're talking about your son.
It's like you're not listening.
He needs to get his ass up
off the couch and find a job.
Feed his family.
If we were talking about
the boy's health – God forbid –
the money would be
on the table tomorrow.
But we are talking about his health!
If you had a grandson, there's no way
you'd let him serve in the army.
Sasha just needs
help. Give him a chance.
Leave my daughter out of this!
Why did you bring her up?
It's not my fault,
I did everything in my power,
but unfortunately she turned
out just like her mother,
only interested in life's pleasures.
A goddamn hedonist!
I don't know, what that word means.
Do you know the word 'selfish'?
Volodya, you'll help
Sasha though, won't you?
I don't know. Need to think about it.
I hope, you aren't pulling money
off your credit card for them.
I can account
for every rouble, if you want.
No, no need for that.
I'm sorry. I shouldn't
have said that.
OK.
When do they need the money?
No later than the 20th.
I'll give you my answer in a week.
Make me a coffee, please.
What have you got planned for today?
House cleaning.
I'm going to the gym.
I know.
Come on you.
Let's go, come on.
Elena!
Bring me my things.
Coming.
Good afternoon.
Enjoy Fitness, this is Irina speaking.
Just one moment, I'll put
you through to the manager.
Here you go. Enjoy your workout.
– Good afternoon.
– Hello.
Your towel.
Anton!
Put them down there.
This is for you, this is for me.
– Thank you.
– Bye.
Hello.
Yes, speaking.
– Hello.
– Good afternoon.
Remember, this is how we met.
Of course.
What year was that?
It'll be 10 years in December.
I would give everything to wake up
not here and now, but there and then.
No matter how you look at it, appendicitis
is still better, than a heart attack.
That was hardly appendicitis.
More like peritonitis.
A born nurse.
Of course, it was better.
If only because you
were looking after me.
Though the girls here aren't bad.
Go on, keep talking,
I'll cut off your oxygen,
we'll see what happens then.
You'd do it too.
– Did you talk to the doctor?
– Not yet.
All he does is try to keep me calm,
tells me they won't
keep me much longer.
So, it's not that bad.
Or the other way around.
Elena, please, call Katya.
Yes, of course.
Hello, Katya, this is Elena.
Yes, hello.
I'm sorry to say I have some bad news.
Your Dad's in the hospital;
he's had a heart attack.
He wants to see you.
You will come, won't you?
Can't today. Tomorrow.
Well, alright. I'd like
to meet you first to talk.
Is that really necessary?
Yes, I think it is.
Fine, where?
Wherever's best for you.
Hello, Elena.
Hello, Katya. Do you want anything?
I'll do without.
What I wanted to say is this:
your Dad had a heart attack.
I got that part.
He's very weak.
– He's conscious, though?
– Yes, conscious, thank God.
He's probably felt his way
through all the nurses already.
– Katya!
– Yes, Elena?
I want to ask you to go easy on him.
Right now he needs rest.
He needs your love.
Show him, that you love him.
You see each other so rarely,
which I don't understand
at all, but that's your business.
Indeed, it is.
Katya, you never call him.
You should…
Maybe this attack…
Right, the prodigal daughter's fault.
In part, I'm sure that's true.
Listen, Elena.
You're playing the role
of the worried wife.
You do it very well, congratulations.
So that's that. Finished?
I love Volodya.
Sure, to death do you part.
I don't doubt it.
Like a true nurse,
you're trying to cure me,
but I'm fine, I don't
need your treatment.
I am what I am.
Are you not at all
sorry for your father?
I understand that's
a rhetorical question,
but as far as you're concerned,
I don't give a flying fuck.
Oh, my Lord.
What room is he in?
Maybe it's not such a good
idea for you to see him today.
Another time. When he's better…
Well that's interesting.
Why call me yesterday,
and not when he's better?
Your father asked me to.
What room is Dad in?
– Excuse me.
– Hello.
Could you tell me…
Please, cover your head
in the house of the Lord.
I wanted to ask which saint
I should light a candle to?
For health, or for
one who has passed on?
My husband's in hospital.
A prayer for health, then.
Write his name on a slip of paper,
and the priest will pray
for his health during service.
And place a candle in
front of Saint Nicholas
and Mother of God.
And while you're lighting it,
ask the Lord to bring
him health and assistance.
Could you tell me
where those icons are?
Straight ahead and
to the right of the altar.
Thank you.
I barely see you, Katya.
You can barely see me 'cos
I'm standing against the sun.
I didn't mean it in that sense.
Dad, you know that nothing
like sense even exists.
Looking at you, sometimes I
think, that might even be true.
So, it's OK that you barely see me.
I was never your reason to live.
And 'thank God', as they say.
You're wrong about that.
Money, Dad, has always been
your only reason for living.
What are you, tallying up my life?
Money's important to you, too.
Not that important.
Maybe that's because you've
never earned any yourself.
Maybe that's because you spoiled me,
gave me everything on a plate.
Sounds like a complaint.
Come on, Dad, you know I adore you.
Keep it coming, please.
I don't know, why I do this.
You don't know, what
you're paying for?
What I've been paying
through the nose for.
Well, just don't start
sniffling on me, OK?
You've always loved those word games.
Games help
children come to terms with
the cruel laws of reality.
– Children?
– Nope.
Not going to happen.
I'm not pregnant,
if that's what you were asking.
Too bad. It'd sort you out.
I'm sorted.
Alcohol and drugs
only on the weekends.
It's clean living now.
Of all the pleasures I'm still
getting sex and food under control,
but I'm working on myself, trust me.
What, are you going
to smoke in here?
Why not?
– It's a hospital, Katya.
– So what?
You paid for the big suite,
you can do whatever you like.
Are you serious?
Fine, I'll go smoke,
where I'm allowed to.
Hold on.
What now?
Where does all this come from?
Where do you think?
Genes, Dad, heritage.
Rotten seed. We're all
bad seeds. Subhuman.
Go on and have some babies.
Maybe they'll turn out different.
Different from everyone else?
There's no such thing as 'different'.
And I don't feel like
experimenting in that area:
it's painful, and
expensive, and pointless.
What is it with you and 'pointless'?
Dumb excuses. You're just trying
to avoid being responsible.
Dad, it's irresponsible
to produce offsprings
that – you know – are going to be
sick and doomed, since the
parents are just as sick and doomed.
And only because cosi fan tutte;
because there is some apparently
'higher meaning' to it all,
which is not ours to comprehend.
After all we are merely the
executors of this higher purpose.
Shit's gotta be tasty,
millions of flies can't be wrong.
And, anyway, the world will end soon
enough, in case you haven't heard.
You know, it's strange,
but listening to you,
I feel a lot better.
See, that's exactly why you breed:
to suck the life from your children.
And then you're surprised:
"Where does all this come from?"
Katya, you're such a twit sometimes.
Thanks.
I love you very much.
Can we do without that?
What one won't do for money!
See. Now, at last
you're starting to see the point.
Just don't loose sight of it yourself.
Parasite.
Oh? I thought, it was a heart attack.
Get over here, let me give you a kiss.
Dialling mama? Go on, give her a ring.
Let's see, what's
going on in the kitchen.
Have a look outside, and
see what's there.
See, if there are any sparrows about…
Needs to boil some more. Right…
Where are those sparrows at?
Bless you.
Above all, observe the
medication schedule closely.
Next, diet is critical.
And take it easy, nothing stressful.
Plus, I would recommend
hiring a qualified caretaker.
I worked in a hospital,
looking after patients for years.
So the better.
See you around, doctor.
You too. Take care of yourself.
All the best.
So long.
I think, we're seeing our refs…
I'm not talking about today's refs,
but all this talk about
referee's mistakes,
it's making them hedge their bets.
If we filed the tapes of this show
and watched them in 5 years' time…
The country would be shocked
at the way it's all repeating.
You'll pay for what you have done.
You won't get away with it, either.
But I wish you, our
audience, all the best.
Goodbye.
Elena.
I have something…
I need to tell you.
Your pills.
In short, I've
decided to write a will.
Volodya, I'm sorry, but this
makes me really uncomfortable.
Elena, this is important.
I need to be straight with you.
It's the right thing
to do, and after all,
everyone's thinking about what'll
happen after I'm gone, right?
No, it's not like that.
All the same, it's
a talk we need to have.
Fair enough.
Except for you and my daughter,
I don't have anyone
else in this world.
After I die, my daughter will
inherit almost everything.
And you, as my spouse,
will receive a life-annuity,
monthly payments. And I'm confident
they will be more than enough.
That's it, really.
I built up to this for so long,
and fired it all out in 10 seconds.
Is there… something
you want to say?
Yes… there is.
It's not about what you were saying,
but it seems like the right time.
What is it?
– The thing.
– What thing?
The thing with Sasha.
I think that his father,
your son, should be
taking care of his own son.
Volodya…
What were they thinking
when they had him?
It was an accident.
Both times? Don't make me laugh.
It's no laughing matter.
It just happened, like
it does with everybody.
First one kid by
accident, then another.
And now I'm supposed to feed them?
Elena, it's not the money
that bothers me.
Of course, not.
You're giving all of it to
your thoughtless daughter.
Here we go again!
First of all, not all of it.
And second of all, you don't know
her. She's actually quite sensible.
Thoughtless and derailed.
I don't want to hear it.
And apparently infertile, too.
Nonsense!
She's just… different.
She's not like you and me.
Of course, she's nothing
like my son and his children!
You said it.
Dear God…
… what gives you the right?
What?
What right do you have
to think you're special?
Why?
Just because you have
more money? More things?
All that can change.
What exactly can change?
"… and the last shall be the first".
Ah, heard that one.
Biblical fairy-tales
for poor foolish people.
Equality and fraternity
are only to be found in
your Heavenly Kingdom, Elena.
Well, you probably have a lot to do.
Yes, quite a lot.
Do you want anything?
I only want for you
to have understood me.
I did.
Elena, let's deal
with this like adults.
We are adults. We'll get through it.
And I'm glad, you understand.
Can you, please, bring
me a pen and paper.
The lawyer is coming tomorrow,
and I want to sketch
out a draft of the will.
Sergei, hi.
Fine, thanks.
Better, but still weak.
Listen…
… I talked to him about Sasha.
I'm afraid, we'll have to
deal with this on our own.
Yes, that's it.
He says, it's your job, as a father,
to deal with the problem.
Stop it.
Stop, would you?
I'm upset myself.
But I think, there's some
truth to what he says.
We'll figure it out ourselves.
We'll think of something.
I'll call later, OK?
Shit. The Tightass!
Tanya, where's my beer?
Did you get the baby's formula?
There was a damn bottle in here.
Did you finish your homework?
Yeah.
Did you do you homework?
I did it already!
What a mess in here.
I can't concentrate, it
all just comes out wrong.
Medicine first.
He's through! He shoots!
Many of you are probably wondering
if everything here
is strictly above board…
Elena!
I've had enough. Thanks.
Do you want to take a nap?
Think I will.
I can't believe it.
You really weren't warned,
no one told you to abstain?
Drugs like this are strictly
prohibited after a heart attack.
I'm telling you, I didn't
even know that he had it.
Like little kids, I swear.
Dumb teenagers have more sense.
You could be a bit more tactful.
How much more tactful?
Dear friends, relatives and
colleagues of the deceased,
it's time to say farewell…
Final farewells.
Sausage number 4 is the best,
though it's too salty for me.
I think, the one
closest to milk sausage
is number 4.
It's got some sausage taste,
unlike number 3…
Well, tastes differ…
I vote for number 3.
Please.
Our jurors here are regular shoppers.
They can only vote for one sausage.
All of the labels
have been covered up.
I voted for the sixth,
it was pretty edible,
I mean you don't even
notice the bread-rusk,
there's no starch, and
there's no taste of cardboard.
So it's an OK sausage.
This one's too moist, too watery.
Cook it a little more.
It's a sign,
that it wasn't made right.
Sausage just shouldn't be like that.
The contest will continue
in the laboratory,
where the winner will be chosen.
I liked number 6, I'm not sure…
I'm not sure about number
1, I don't know, who made it,
or what they made it from,
but I'd never buy a sausage
that looked like that.
Number five is a waste,
don't spend your money
on plastic like that.
Hello. Yes. Thank you.
I'll be right down.
– Hello.
– Good afternoon.
Well, he sensed his
demise ahead of time.
As his personal attorney,
I know, how he wished
to dispose of his property.
He himself requested that
I visit him in the hospital,
and we discussed the matter.
Alas, we failed to document
his wishes in writing,
as required by law.
I am, therefore, forced
to acknowledge the following:
he did not leave a will.
So the principle of legal
succession enters into force.
First of all, I would like
to advise, that he left no debts.
Otherwise, you would be liable
to creditors for his debts.
Further, it is my duty
to inform you, that under the law
should one spouse die,
the surviving spouse
has the right to a portion
of the property
acquired during the marriage.
That is, to their share of the
property, held in common by the spouses
during the marriage, on an equal
basis along with the other heirs.
This portion is included
in the inheritance,
along with the personal
property of the deceased.
However,
in this case, during the time
that you were formally married,
which was just over two years,
no common property was acquired.
Therefore, there can be no
talk of a spousal share here.
You will inherit a portion of
the property of the deceased
on an equal basis with Katya.
Since, to the best of my
knowledge, there are no other heirs
besides the two of you,
the entire estate
will be equally divided between you.
If anything is unclear
or you have any questions,
I can explain further.
I know that my father
always kept a sizeable amount
of cash in his home safe.
What happens to that?
I already checked, there's nothing.
Right.
Believe me, Katya.
Of course. Anything else?
We've only started.
I've described the overall situation.
Let's look at the details.
If you like, we can take a break.
No need, let's go on.
Right, Elena?
Yes, let's go on.
OK. Let's get started.
So, how shall we carve up Dad's pad?
We'll be carving according to the law.
That's that.
Mama.
We should drink to this!
I agree.
– Have we got anything?
– Of course, we do.
Well, come on then!
Don't cry, mama'll be right back.
You know what?
Let's drink to Volodya.
He did
at least one decent thing in his life.
Better still, to Sasha.
Sasha! Sash!
– What?
– Don't you 'what' me. Get in here.
College boy. Sit down. Here. You're
going to college for sure now.
What the hell.
What? I've got it under control.
The kid's 17 already.
What, is this real?
Never seen anything like
that, huh? Put it down.
Damn!
Well, come on.
To new life.
Mama. We have a surprise for
you! We're pregnant again!
Are you serious? Really?!
Goodness, that's wonderful!
– If it's a boy, I'll call him Volodya.
– Oh, please.
– Why not?
– Well, I hope, it's a girl.
Yeah, a girl would be better.
A girl would be better.
Yeah?
Here.
Hey, go easy!
Cut it out, woman,
you're pissing me off.
Game over.
Probably just the circuit breaker.
What's with you?
Mama, you're going to break my arm.
Give him to me.
Let me go have a look.
Easy, little one, easy…
Looks like the whole building's out.
The whole world!
The assholes.
– Hey, Aleskei.
– Hey.
– What's up with it?
– Fuck knows.
The whole block's been cut off,
I guess. They'll probably
turn it back on soon.
Assholes, second time this month.
OK, Sergey. Take care.
Hi!
Hey, you lot.
– Where are you off to?
– For a walk.
Be home by 11.
Tanya, have we got candles?
Why would we have candles?
Vitya, Lesha, you there?
Hey, guys.
What took you so long?
My grandma was getting on my case.
Thought, you chickened out.
Almost went without you.
You should have then. Shut it.
Whatever, chill out. Here, juice up.
Hey, leave some for us.
– Are they there?
– Yeah.
– Then let's go.
– All right.
Yuri, hurry the fuck up!
Fuck off, fucker!
Die, fucker!
You cunt!
Dima, let's go!
Mama!
Quiet!
Mama, what do we need this crap for?
If we put a wall in here,
a door over here, then
Sasha can have his own room.
We still haven't decided
anything with Katya.
We'll work something out.
I doubt it.
We will, I'm telling you.
Ma, have we got any beer?
Look in the fridge.
Even the upcoming
Olympics has not broken
the stagnation in Sochi…
I'm worried, waiting for his decision.
I think, it doesn't
matter whose prize you are.
I like the fact, that he
leads an interesting life,
full of adventurism and activity.
He's got kind eyes.
I'm worried about Yulia,
she's got that child…
Choose Katya or Dasha,
there's no difference,
whichever one takes your fancy.
You're cool,
you were better than all of them.
Don't listen to anything they say.
Is he asleep?
Elena, this is amazing!
Tea anyone?
I think, there's about a 98%
chance he'll come into my room.
Let me help you.
I'll even leave with him.
Tanya, bring me some nuts.
My god, come over here, come to me.
He can't even speak,
he's overwhelmed…
Come here! Come on!
Today I feel like I'm 90 years old,
and I want to give you a hard time,
because you're all younger than me.
I think that you're
empty-headed bimbos.
Keep it in perspective, otherwise you'll
be sitting here until your pension.
She wants a lot, but giving…
She doesn't know, what
she's going to give yet.
Zhenya, what did you think of Lena?
I don't know what to tell you…
Basically, there's nothing I can say.
NADEZHDA MARKINA, ANDREY SMIRNOV
YELENA LYADOVA, ALEKSEY ROZIN
EVGENIYA KONUSHKINA, IGOR OGURTSOV
Directed by ANDREI ZVYAGINTSEV
Produced by ALEXANDER RODNYANSKY,
SERGEY MELKUMOV
Director of Photography
MIKHAIL KRICHMAN
Written by OLEG NEGIN,
ANDREI ZVYAGINTSEV
Original Music by PHILIP GLASS