- Oh!
- Come on.
Come on.
What's the rush?
I'm supposed to wait for Bonnie.
She can catch up with you later.
Where? You guys wouldn't let us
look for a place to stay.
Listen, we didn't bring you
chicks in from Vegas
to go apartment hunting. Let's go.
GO, go: go'
No one knows where, but we gotta go.
Mmm.
Hey, what is this? Come on, get out of here.
- Where's the girl?
- What girl?
All right, come on out, duchess.
You heard me. I said come out.
What, may I ask, are you two gentlemen
doing in my room?
- No sale, sister.
- Oh, come on.
Let's not make a federal case out of it.
It is a federal case.
Ever hear of the Mann Act?
Transporting a woman across
a state line for immoral...
- What are you talking about?
- Look, you drove the girl
in from out of state this afternoon.
Don't you think we check on those things
first with witnesses?
All right, get your stuff. Let's go.
Just a minute, Copper.
Did you and your runny-nosed witnesses
check on who was gonna pay for the room?
Me!
So...
There we are.
You know what you're saying?
What you'll be charged with?
Yeah, I know, and it's a misdemeanour.
No federal rap.
I've been there before.
All right, come on.
Get your paws off.
I soil easy.
Thanks, kid.
Don't lose this.
Gee, life's a funny thing.
Compared to what?
Left! March!
Hup, hup, hup, left, march!
- Hup, hup, left, march!
Now hear this!
I want to propose a toast
to those two grand little seagulls,
Peg and Bonnie.
They made San Diego
a port the men of the U. S. S. Pompano
- will always remember.
- Hup, march!
Hup, march!
Oh, you goofed.
Ok, pay up, dogface.
That will be a sawbuck.
Where'd you girls learn
close-order drill like that?
- In the W.A.C.S.?
- No.
The W.A.V.E.S.?
In Ventura.
California's most exclusive finishing school.
Very tough to get into, huh, Peg?
I always say there's nothing
like a good education
to get ahead in the world.
- Hey, Joe!
- And, furthermore,
I'd like to add a serious note.
Oh, sit down. You're rocking the boat.
Here you are.
I was just going to yell "girl overboard."
You can't hear yourself think in there.
Well, here's somethin' to think about.
I got me a three-day pass startin' Friday.
How about me and you go down to Tijuana?
- Negative.
- Why not?
I'm going on a weekend cruise.
Yeah? How's about inviting me along?
Oh, you wouldn't fit in.
I'm joining my mother and her friends
on a private yacht.
What are you handing me?
Your mother on a yacht?
Yeah! My mother on a yacht!
Besides, you're too young.
For what?
Am I still too young?
Well...
Hello, young lovers, hello.
Don't you ever knock
before entering a balcony?
Guess who's here?
Mac and Stuey.
- From Frisco?
- Uh-huh.
Ten-hut!
Forward, march!
Bury yourself!
So it looks like we finally made the bucket.
- Well, what happened?
- Remember the delicatessen
over on Bloom Street
we always wanted to knock over?
- Yeah.
- Well, we did.
- And they know we did.
- But can they prove it?
Well, they got a pretty fair case,
a witness even.
Well, one witness, that's all?
No, no fingerprints? Nothing like that?
Not unless I left them on the pickles.
So, you see, if we had an alibi...
Well, like, if you'd say we were with you,
- why, 1 O to one, we'd beat the rap.
- Sure.
Perjury's a felony.
That's what I told them.
There's three bills in it for you and Peg.
And all your expenses while you're in Frisco.
I don't know.
One thing about you, Bonnie.
You never let your pals down.
Come on. What do you say, huh?
- Okay, it's a deal.
- Oh, God.
I knew she'd do it!
It'll be like old times.
- Peg, we'll have a ball in Frisco.
- No, Bonnie.
I can't go with this kick.
Oh, don't be like that. They're nice guys.
Sure.
I guess I just haven't got your guts.
Uh-uh. This is where I cut out.
Okay, you guys, there's a party goin' on.
Let's live it up!
That's my Bonnie!
Hey, George!
Some liquor for my friends.
Bongos away!
Go, go, go!
Come on, Joe,
put a head on it!
You've done your time.
You're getting out. So watch yourself.
You're on probation for five years.
Don't leave the San Francisco area
or otherwise violate
your probation in any way,
or you'll be back here quick enough.
Oh, no, ma'am. I won't.
I hope you mean it.
I see one section juvenile morals,
four vagrancy, one vagrancy quarantine,
three soliciting, perjury,
not to mention the two years you spent
at the Ventura Reform School for Girls.
As long as you're adding up the score,
my mother was in Ventura before me.
That oughta be worth extra points.
What I'm trying to say is,
you do have a choice.
People have managed to be fairly happy
by not getting into trouble.
Get a job, maybe get married.
I have been...
Occasionally.
Your way doesn't seem to be going too well.
Why don't you try the other?
Thanks.
Maybe I will.
Oh, no. No, Mr. Thomas.
I couldn't let you do that.
Now, don't be silly, Miss. Baldwin.
Why not?
It is such a bother having just that one
account in San Francisco.
I should open one down here.
San Francisco! Then we're neighbors.
I go to Stanford.
- Oh.
- Now I claim it as a right to cash your check.
Well, if you insist.
- How's 20?
- Anything you say.
Just make it out to "cash."
- Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
- Oh, God!
Oh, allow me, miss. Allow me.
Are you in some kind
of an earn-while-you-learn job?
- Cop.
- What?
Vice cop.
Oh, look at these, all wet.
Oh, here, use one of mine. Just...
I feel as though I've just been through
a laundromat.
I'll be right back.
I don't know, Hank.
Pickin' on a vice-squad cop to kite a check.
That's not much of a recommendation
for a job in this place.
Well, she just got in town.
- Yeah, how was I to know...
- Where you from?
Fflsco.
Your occupation. What do you do?
The best I can.
Maybe you can do it for me.
Come here.
See you, and I'll raise you.
I'm out.
You chicken?
PERK". Your end comes
to $100 and a quarter.
Together with certain other activities
of the past month,
that makes...
$642.
I'll put it in the safe for you.
Uh-uh.
You want it?
I'm quitting.
- Oh.
- To get married.
Young Lochinvar, from behind the bar?
Uh-huh.
You've been married three times now.
Let's assume divorced as many.
You ought to have it figured by now,
no white knight's
going to come riding through your life.
Yeah, that's right.
There isn't space on my library card
for all my names.
You think as Mrs. Henry Graham
you'll be so ritzy you can't
work for me, is that it?
I'm tired of it, Perk, all of it.
Used to be fun, but it isn't fun anymore.
You know, I go past the markets now
and envy the housewives carrying
out the groceries.
- Eh.
I used to think they were stupid
squares, too, but...
I get so tired of going out
with a quarter to buy ice.
Okay, okay.
So congratulate the bridegroom for me.
Wait till you taste my cooking.
Good luck, Bonnie.
You crumb, lay off!
You little fool, give it here!
- It's our last $10!
- Oh, don't give me that.
- You cashed a check.
- I wasted it on food.
Listen to me, Hank.
When I got pregnant, you promised
to kick the habit.
I've tried, Bonnie. I've tried.
But tonight...
Aw, have a heart.
Just, just one more fix,
and that's it, I swear.
No.
Please, Hank, for the baby's sake.
Oh, the baby, the baby!
I got some rights, too!
Give it!
It's all right, honey. Shh.
Shh, here, here, aw, look at the tigey.
Look at the “gay.
Here, sweetie. Look at the tigey.
Please, honey, let...
Let me have the $10.
I just wanna put it on a horse.
- Horse?
- I got a tip.
I could score big.
Shut up!
Daddy didn't mean it, darling. Shh.
Daddy didn't mean it.
Oh, you...
You're so holy.
You're worse than me.
You're nothing but a no-good, fancy...
Daddy didn't mean it, darling.
He's sick.
Oh, don't you tell him about me.
Tell him about yourself!
- And you got a record to prove it!
- All right!
As long as we're all bellied up
to the bar for treats,
here's something for you.
I'm sick of supporting you and your habit!
I'm sick of your smell!
This is a real dream house I've been running,
and no junkie's worth it!
Take it!
Go on, take it!
It's the last you'll ever get from me!
You mean that?
So help me.
I'm through.
Oh, it's nice to see you, Mr. Bixle.
Come on in out of the rain.
I could evict you right into jail,
giving me this check.
Now, calm down, Mr. Bixle.
Maybe you'd like a little drink
on a day like this, huh?
You're in serious trouble.
You don't even have an account
in that bank.
How careless of me.
I used to.
I guess I got my Checkbooks mixed up.
- I'll write you out another.
- No. Cash.
Mr. Bixle, give me until tomorrow.
My husband's been away all week.
I expect him back tonight.
All right. Tomorrow.
But after that, I'm going to the police.
Hello?
Babs, I was just gonna call you.
Of course you can.
Come on over. I'll be waiting.
Yeah.
That's a hot one. She calls me.
Takin' her along, you must be nuts.
I'll go to my grave saying you're nuts.
You play it my WaY-
Maybe we'll all get out of this world alive.
...and I thought if Bobby and I
could stay here for a while,
I might be able to work things out.
Stay as long as you want.
Only thing is, Santo and me is
taking a powder.
What's up?
All I know is, the police
contact says we're hot.
Are the cops liable to show?
"Are the cops liable to show?"
I wouldn't worry.
Good-looking dame like you.
Not worry?
I've got half a dozen bum checks around,
a busted parole, a...
A landlord on my neck...
I'm broke, Hank's disappeared.
And it's rainin'.
Take me with you, Perk.
With the baby?
I can leave him with Hank's mother.
She'll be back in a week.
How about it, Perk?
If I'm picked up with Bobby,
they'll put him in a foster home sure.
I got the answer.
She comes with me to Acapulco. Simple.
I told you once, King.
I don't think Mexico's a smart idea.
I don't care what you think.
What do you say, hon?
It's nice down there, and sunny.
I'll rub oil all over your body,
so's you don't get too bad a burn.
It so happens I'd take a rap
to avoid a trip with you.
Why? We could have lots of fun together.
You're not my type.
I heard there was no such thing
as not your type.
Until I met you.
And believe me, it's purely personal.
Don't get sore, glamour boy.
You can't win 'em all.
Anyway, she's coming with us.
I'll send the three of you postcards.
You let me know which pen.
Watch out!
Spotter to control.
Boarding Lynwood bus.
2659 southbound.
One tail with her. Over.
Good work, spotter.
Control to walker.
If feasible, call intersecting streets.
All right, let's go.
Excuse me, sir. Is this cross street Burgess?
Yeah, this is Burgess.
Royal and Burgess.
That Ethel's on the ball.
Minns to mobile 3. Royal and Burgess.
Wait at Royal. Take number one position.
Out.
Minns to control.
At destination, call in all division one units.
Destination is where she goes to cover.
Read me?
Cut that screamer, Ted.
For once, write it the way it happens,
eh, Montgomery?
Don't worry, Inspector.
I'll spell your name right.
A tramp, but smart.
Good-looking girl, too.
The kind that fools you.
Ha, not me.
I've seen angel pusses who'd shoot
their own grandmothers in the back
and take bets on which way they'd fall.
Excuse me.
Getting off at Barham Plaza.
Getting off.
Control to walker. Drop off.
We're putting the sergeant on Graham.
We wanna play safe.
Don't work too close yourself, please.
Meanwhile on the local scene,
I've just been handed a news flash
on the Monahan murder.
Police announce an important break
in the brutal slaying
of Mrs. Mabel Monahan,
found beaten to death 11 days ago
in Burbank.
Bruce King, a self-styled steeplejack,
was picked up last night
on the Mexican border.
According to one source,
he has given authorities
several highly significant leads.
Have you ever wondered whether
distant grass really does look the greenest?
Tomorrow, we move further out.
But that's gonna make it tougher
to visit Bobby.
Are you still on that kid?
What's for chow?
Champagne and winter strawberries.
- Why, you...
- I'm not your maid!
All right, you two!
What do you know?
Santa Claus' workshop is finally
taking a breather.
SANTOI What the...
I'm not the only one
who doesn't pay his light bill.
Get down!
This is
the Los Angeles Police Department.
You are surrounded.
We are authorized by Iavv
to apprehend you dead or alive.
Dead or alive.
She was tailed.
She let herself get tailed!
h' you wish to surrender peaceably,
come out singly as your names are called,
hands above your head.
Come out singly, hands above your head.
Emmett Perkins, come out.
Emmett Perkins.
We will not wait, Emmett Perkins.
That is a warning.
Maybe you asked 'em here, huh?
Yeah. I'll show you
the engraved invitations.
Come out, John R. Santo.
MAN; John R. Santo.
You have 60 seconds, John R. Santo.
Obey orders, and nobody will be hurt,
John R. Santo.
Oh.
Barbara Graham.
Come out, Barbara Graham.
Barbara Graham, you have 60 seconds.
If you do not come out, Barbara Graham,
we will come in and get you.
We are warning you
not to attempt anything, Barbara Graham.
Your friends are in custody.
It is over.
For the last time, Barbara Graham,
come out.
Keep your hands
above your head.
You heard me, Graham.
Hands above your head.
I won't warn you again, Graham.
Get those hands up.
Miss! Ed Montgomery.
Listen, give me a statement,
I'll write your angle.
Grrr!
Brother!
That's the one to print.
"Bloody Babs, the tiger woman."
Did she confess?
Not yet.
They've been grilling her all night.
I'm going over there now.
For your own sake,
Mrs. Graham, tell the truth.
I've been trying to, for once.
You want a lie detector test?
I want a lawyer.
If you're innocent, a lie detector test
can only help you.
Innocent of what?
What's the charge?
Open charge.
Could be any one of a number of things.
Like what, for instance?
For instance, $251 worth of bad checks,
parolee consorting with known criminals,
suspicion of robbery.
And, of course, that other thing.
What other thing?
Mrs. Mabel Monahan.
I never even knew the dame.
You know she's been murdered, don't you?
Yeah, so was Julius Caesar.
I didn't know him, either.
Ever use narcotics, Babs?
- No.
- No?
Well, your husband does.
You know, if you cooperate,
maybe we can let you have a fix.
There's no monkey on my back.
Never has been.
Then what's with your legs?
Why are you squirming?
I got a worse habit,
like goin' to the powder room
every six or eight hours.
- You mind?
- Sit down.
Lousy hop-headed slut!
I'd like to spread you out
and stamp you into the ground.
Everybody gets his kicks
some way.
- Why, you dirty...
- Mrs. Graham,
we have a tough, ugly job to do,
and you're making it tougher
- and uglier for all of us.
- My heart bleeds for you.
How can I help, Inspector,
buy a few tickets to the policemen's ball?
You're being very foolish.
We're giving you a chance,
not only to help the law for once,
but save yourself.
What do you mean?
If you turn state's evidence,
tell us everything you know
about the Monahan job,
you can walk out of here a free woman.
We're offering you complete immunity.
All you have to do is sign
a full statement naming names,
we won't even call it a confession.
And you go free.
So that's why you been playing
the mama bull, Inspector.
You think I'm a stoolie, huh?
No dice!
I'm sorry for you.
Dumb.
Just plain dumb.
Right now, your playmates
are spillin' their guts.
Don't let 'em make you the patsy.
You heard the inspector.
Minute you sign a statement,
you're off the hook.
All right, I'll name names.
Now we're cookin'.
The inspector, the lieutenant, the sergeant,
especially you, Sarge, are jerks!
But I'll say this for you, Sarge.
You sweat.
I'm getting tired of fooling around with you.
She's the hardest cookie
I ever ran up against.
Worse than her boyfriends.
Yeah, what about them?
I have nothing for the papers yet.
Bear with me, huh?
Next on your phone, Ed.
Charlie, she won't confess,
so I'm gonna play up her vice record.
Dope, prostitution,
any other kick I dream up.
Nope. I'll keep Santo and Perkins
in the background.
Graham's the one who'll sell papers.
Yeah, of course she is.
She's had a record ever since
she was knee-high to a slot machine.
Oh, I'll paste together my usual valentine,
cold-blooded sadist, titian-topped tigress.
Titian.
Titian. Skip it.
I'll have it for you in an hour.
Is that how you got your Pulitzer?
It's Mrs. Graham's tough luck
to be young, attractive, belligerent,
immoral, and guilty as hell.
Ever been arrested?
- No. Hey!
What is this, a striptease?
Whom do you wish notified
in case of death or serious illness?
Marlon Brando.
Hey, how about letting me
have that tiger back? Hmm?
He's housebroken.
After I check it, it will be placed
with your property.
Well, what are you doing?
No!DoNfl
My bonnie lives over the ocean
My bonnie sails over the sea...
All right, Jenny Lind,
I have to look you over for soars,
wounds, open sores.
Turn around.
Slow.
Put your arms out.
So, look for scars.
You don't have to count my pores
one by one, do you?
What's that?
Push-button control.
Looks to me like someone
used you to put out a cigarette.
Don't touch the merchandise.
Think you're pretty hot stuff, huh?
This will cool you off.
Aah! Ooh!
Come on, honey.
You're gonna pad with me.
"Stone walls may not a prison make,
nor iron bars a cage."
But they sure help.
What I still don't get is,
why your kind of bail
just for hanging some bad paper
around town?
What I mean is, it's way out of line.
$25,000 for a chicken crime like forgery?
Unless they got something else
on you, huh?
Look,hon“.
You keep your sympathy to yourself,
and I'll keep my business to myself.
Okay?
Graham, front and center.
Something for you.
- Barbara Graham?
- Yeah.
"Subpoena..."
"Appear before the grand jury
for the crime..."
"Murder?"
What is this? They're crazy.
Oh, no, they don't!
They don't pull a raw one like this!
They don't pin a murder rap on me!
I've done a lot of things in my time,
a lot of things, but not murder!
I told those cops,
I know nothing about any murder!
Nothing! Do you hear me?
Nothing!
"I know nothing about any murder.
Do you hear me? Nothing!"
shouts Barbara Graham
as she is indicted this afternoon
by the grand jury for the murder
of Mrs. Mabel Monahan,
a crippled Burbank widow.
Indicted along with her
are the other three members
of the so-called Monahan murder mob.
Bruce King, Emmett Perkins,
and John Santo.
Don't know who it is except
the name I told you on the pad.
Peg!
Bonnie.
Well, of course, Mrs. Ciesilwicz.
- You're married.
- Uh-huh.
His name's Joe. He's an aircraft worker.
Any kids?
A boy and a girl.
Would you believe it? I'm a real square.
Thursday afternoon club,
the Holy Rosary Society,
community chest, the works.
Well, me, too, almost.
I have a boy, 13 months.
And smart.
You shouldn't have come here, Peg.
Oh, don't be silly.
If the newspapers get hold of it,
your husband's liable to find out.
He knows.
Yeah, but...
Does he know about us, how we were?
I came clean about everything long ago.
When I told him I was coming to see you,
you know what he said?
He said, "That's what friends are for."
- He, he did?
- Sure.
Oh, Bonnie, are you gonna be all right?
Well, we might as well face it,
I'm in a real jam this time.
I'm the little ball bouncing around
a roulette wheel,
everyone betting me to land
where it's gonna do them the most good.
Votes for the D.A.,
circulation for the newspapers,
promotions for the cops.
That still don't give them the right
to hang a bad rap on you.
You didn't ask me if it was a bad one.
I didn't have to.
Thanks.
You'd do the same for me
if it was the other way around.
It could have been, Bonnie.
Oh, believe me, it could have been.
We were, we were so alike.
All right. Stop that.
You're a different person now.
You have been, ever since you
got smart in San Diego and cut out.
All the stuff I read...
And I could...
Never read the handwriting on the...
Wall.
Well, is there anything I can do?
Could bring your boy around for a visit.
No. I don't want Bobby down here.
Maybe you could go and see him, though.
Oh, sure.
Barbara Graham, time's up.
But I only just got here.
Visiting room closes at 3:00.
Thanks for coming, Peg.
See you soon.
Oh.
What about a lawyer? Have you got one?
Nothing to worry about.
I'll use the public defender.
No, sir.
No court-appointed attorney for me.
I don't want you, Mr. Tibrow, period.
I want the public defender.
I assure you, I'll do the very best I can
with the $500 given me
to investigate your case.
500 bucks. That's not enough to investigate
who's pinching soap from a
Look, at least with the public defender,
I could put up a fight,
even if he doesn't have the men
and the dough that D.A. has.
Why can't I have the public defender?
Because, as I've tried to explain to you,
the district attorney
has pre-empted him for Bruce King,
and your interests are adverse.
Well, he's a defendant, too, isn't he?
Yes, but he claims that you did
the actual killing.
Why, that crummy, no-good...
- Mrs. Graham...
- ...dirty, double-crossing...
Can't we spend our precious time
on something more constructive?
Yeah, you're right.
I should be thanking you
instead of fighting with you.
All I ask is complete honesty between us.
That's a deal.
Now, then.
You stated that on the evening of March 9,
you were at home
with your husband and baby,
but in your testimony to the grand jury,
you said your husband couldn't be found.
- Don't you believe me?
- A jury won't.
You can't simply tell them, "I wasn't there."
You've got to say,
"I couldn't have been there,
"because here is where I was,
"and these are the people
who were with me to prove it."
Well, I can't do that.
So, let's level.
What chance have I got?
With an uncorroborated alibi?
None.
There is.
I'm the someone.
You shouldn't read other people's mail.
There's a lot of things I shouldn't do.
Step into my office.
Little Rita will take care of the pretty lady.
You really weren't there?
That's right, Your Honor.
Well, then, you've only got
one problem, sweetie.
You weren't with anybody
some other place.
I was with my husband, but he skipped.
And my son.
Age one.
I've got a friend. His name's Ben.
He could use money.
Yeah?
Ben's coming to see me Friday.
Maybe he should try to see you, too.
No, thanks.
It's something to think about.
Look, you're in for manslaughter yourself.
Why would you wanna do this for me?
You're a friend in need.
Tomorrow's Friday.
Just another wild prison rumor.
My friend Ben comes on Friday.
Have you thought about it?
Yeah. A lot.
It's an awful big chance.
It's a big rap.
One slip-up, that's all I'd need.
You can trust Ben.
How about you?
You know about me.
Make it easy. Bet it hard.
Four trey, seven away.
Mamas gem' home to stay.
You made your point, sweetie.
Yeah.
I guess I did.
I'm gonna need a password.
This line. Here.
BEN".
"I came like water."
"And like wind, I go."
Ben?
That's me.
Rita told you about the deal,
the money part?
You'll get it as soon as I'm out of here.
I guess it's all right,
as long as you're okay in Rita's book.
Now, one other thing.
Is there any physical evidence,
fingerprints, blood on your clothes?
Are you nuts? I wasn't even there.
Look, will you play it straight with me?
I'm going way out on a limb for you.
Way out.
I wasn't there.
All right, now, let's get with it.
We don't have much time.
Thirty minutes, that's all.
That's long enough. Easy.
There's time to
run through it just once more.
All right.
It was the Encino Arms Motel.
I picked you up in town,
near your house on 54th Street.
You were in a cab.
I was awaiting for you at the corner
of 54th and Sunset.
We went out to the motel, and we...
Poor Aunt Maude.
But she shouldn't use a mustard plaster.
I guess so.
All right. We went out to the motel...
And we registered under the name
of Mr. and Mrs. J. Clark.
- Mmm-hmm.
- We stayed there till 7:00 the next morning.
In cabin 20.
And then you took me home afterward.
And if they ask me why you've kept quiet
about it until now...
I'm married,
but now that I see that it's a matter
of life and death...
It sure is.
Nothing better go wrong with this.
Don't worry.
Where were you that night, really?
Look, I've gotta know.
If someone saw you where you really were,
and they show up at that trial,
where does that leave me?
Huh.
Nobody saw me.
How can you be sure?
You're not even sure where you were.
I'm sure, but I can't prove it.
If I could, I wouldn't need you, would I?
Uh-huh. Well, suit yourself.
Much as I'd like to save
that gorgeous hide of yours,
I just can't take that kind of a chance.
We better forget the whole thing.
Come back.
Yeah?
You got something you wanna say?
You've really got the hammerlocks on me.
- What do you want?
- You were there, weren't you?
Is that all you'll believe?
It would be an easy thing to believe,
and I wouldn't have to worry.
I'll double your money.
On, baby.
Ben!
Have it your way.
You were with them?
With Perkins and Santo?
Because if you were, it's okay.
It will be my story against Bruce King's.
You were with them, huh?
All right, all right, all right.
I was with them.
Then from here on in, you just relax.
You're a cinch to beat the cyanide.
May it please the coun',
counsel for the defendants,
ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
we will prove that on the night
of March 9, 1953,
King, Santo, Perkins, Barbara Graham
brutally murdered Mrs. Mabel Monahan,
a crippled widow, 61 years of age.
You will see why they needed a woman
to gain admittance to the Monahan home.
We will show you how they searched
every nook and oranny of her house,
looking for a hidden cache of money.
And in conclusion of his opening statement,
district attorney Milton cries,
"We mean business.
"You, ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
have sworn you have no scruples
"about the death penalty,
"even though one
of the defendants be a woman.
"So now I say to you,
invoke the extreme penalty.
"Let justice be done."
Very well.
You arrived in front of the Monahan house.
It was dark.
Santo tells Barbara Graham,
"You go ahead in."
You see Mrs. Graham enter the house.
Then what happened?
Well, after Mrs. Graham
entered the Monahan house,
Santo and Perkins insisted that I follow her.
And did you?
About a minute later.
When you went in, what was the first thing
that attracted your attention?
Well, Mrs. Graham
was striking Mrs. Monahan
in the face with a gun.
In the head and face.
In what position was Mrs. Monahan?
She was standing up.
Mrs. Graham had her by the hair
with her left hand
and was striking her with her right hand.
Then what did you do?
Well, I told Mrs. Graham
to cease hitting her anymore,
put my hand in the way.
Mrs. Monahan collapsed.
And then?
Well, they tied Mrs. Monahan up
and searched the house.
Who did?
Santo, Perkins, and Mrs. Graham.
Oh, and me.
You may examine.
Don't let him get away with that.
Tear him apart.
TIBROWI Mr. King,
was an offer made to you
by the district attorney's office
to testify at this trial?
It was.
Would you state what that offer was?
Mr. Milton told me that if I would
tell the truth,
he would ask the court
to dismiss this case against me.
And that's the reason for the testimony
you have given, is it?
Oh, no, sir.
What is the reason for it, then?
To bring justice.
To all persons concerned,
including yourself?
Yes, sir.
And you feel it is justice for you
to be released,
and perhaps the others condemned?
I do.
Mr. King, you testified earlier
that Emmett Perkins gave you a gun
about five minutes before you reached
the Monahan house.
Is that correct?
Four or five minutes. Yes, sir.
Well, Mr. King, if you did not intend
to participate in violence,
even if you were there only on...
How shall we say, your mission of mercy...
Objection!
Your Honor, he's characterizing
the testimony.
Sustained, as to the last phrase.
Mr. King...
Pray tell, why did you take the gun?
You know something,
I've often wondered myself.
That sure rocked the jury.
Look at them.
And as the trial of Barbara Graham
goes into its third day,
the nationwide interest in the fate
of the so-called queen of the murder mob
continues to mount.
Tonight, the police
have been alerted by a tip-off
that there's a gangland
plot to spring her.
Extra precautions will be taken
in the courtroom tomorrow.
Hey, leave us in, pops.
We wanna see Babs.
Go on home.
Ain't you kids got nothing better to do?
Ah, your mother wears army boots.
Psst. Bonnie.
Hi, Peg.
I saw Bobby this morning.
- How is he?
- Wonderful. He'll be walking soon.
Oh, I've gotta be there to see him
take that first step.
Oh, you will. You will. It's going fine.
Yeah, sure.
I just haven't had my innings yet, that's all.
Ah, Mrs. Graham,
I'm Ed Montgomery from...
I've seen the name.
Who's she?
Some autograph hound.
Me, too.
How about signing an exclusive interview?
I'll pay.
OK, scoop.
Here's your first installment.
"Bloody Babs shuns press."
Please remain seated,
and come to order.
Court is again in session.
The record will show the jury, counsel,
and defendants present.
You may proceed, Mr. Prosecutor.
Our next witness will be here
in a moment, Your Honor.
He's just outside.
Hey, that's my man.
Your who?
That's Ben. Ben, the one I told you about.
Raise your right hand to be sworn.
That's the fella who was with you
at the motel?
That's my witness.
Your witness?
He's just been called by the prosecution.
But that's Ben Miranda. That's my alibi.
State your name, please.
Benjamin Miranda.
What is your occupation, Mr. Miranda?
Police officer for the city of Los Angeles.
Now, sometime before today,
were you given a special assignment
by the Los Angeles police department
to work on the investigation
of the Monahan murder case?
Yes, sir, I was.
What was that assignment?
On August the 7th,
I went to the women's division
of the county jail for a meeting
with Mrs. Graham.
Was this meeting at
Barbara Graham's request?
They crossed me.
The both of them crossed me.
That dirty, stinking little tramp.
Shut up!
Now, at the time and place
you first saw Barbara Graham,
did you give her some kind of password?
Yes, sir. I did.
Can't you do something, Mr. Tibrow?
I'll do something.
What was the password?
Your Honor,
may we approach the bench?
You may, Mr. Tibrow.
May it please the court,
I have repeatedly warned my client
against deceiving me in any way,
but I have been deceived.
I've been lied to. I've been misled.
For the record,
I ask permission to withdraw.
I am sympathetic with counsel.
However, since no person
could be better qualified
than the attorney who has proceeded
in the case so far,
the court does not feel
that it should relieve you.
Just so the court understands my position.
Oh, it does indeed.
Proceed.
Read the last question, Mr. Reporter.
Question.
"What was the password?"
"I came like water, and like wind I go."
BEN". It'd be my story against Bruce King's.
You were with him, huh?
All right, all right, all right.
I was with him.
Then from here on in, you just relax.
You're a cinch to beat the cyanide.
Those are the words which go echoing
through the courtroom today
at the trial of Barbara Graham.
A written transcript is used
in court for the prosecution,
but you are hearing the actual voices
as originally recorded
on the wire inside a
tiny mini-phone like this,
which Police Officer Miranda
conceals on his body
during his rigged prison meeting
with the alleged murderess.
It's all taken down on the miniature
recording device.
Her desperate attempt
to establish a false alibi,
her faltering admission she was there
at the scene of the crime.
The flaming redhead finally crumbles
into a shattered, frightened woman.
She is led crying from the courtroom
after the brutal session.
Curious onlookers, photographers,
and reporters, including this correspondent,
crowd around her.
Have you anything to say
for TV, Mrs. Graham?
I'm innocent.
What about the testimony of Bruce King
and Police Officer Miranda today?
I'm completely innocent.
I was home with my family that night.
They'll all die violently.
The spies, the liars, all the ones
who want me dead.
I'm innocent.
Do you swear it?
I swear it.
I swear it on my baby's life.
May God strike him dead if I'm guilty.
And what happens to Rita,
the blond prison siren,
the inside girl who so invaluably
aided the police,
while herself serving
time for manslaughter?
Her sentence is suspended,
and she is released on probation,
as the woman she helped entrap
takes the stand tomorrow
to fight for her life.
And now, despite what
you told Mr. Miranda,
you claim the truth is that you were
at home with your husband
on the night of March the 9th.
Is that correct?
So, help me God.
And yet you made no effort
to contact your husband.
While at the same time,
you went to great lengths
to make use of the services of Mr. Miranda.
Is that correct?
The same goes for you!
Just answer the question!
I wrote Henry one letter
while I was in the county jail,
and I never got an answer.
And in that letter, did you say anything
about being with him on the all-important
night of March the 9th?
You're hesitating, Mrs. Graham.
I'm trying to think.
You do that.
May the record show
that I have here a letter
addressed to Henry L. Graham,
postmarked May 20th, 1953,
and stamped on it,
"Mail censored, Los Angeles County Jail."
I will ask that this be marked next
in order for identification.
So ordered.
People's exhibit 73.
I ask you to read this letter,
and tell us whether or not you wrote it.
That's her husband.
Henry L. Graham.
Oh, thank God.
I will clear
the courtroom
if there's another such
outburst from anyone.
Proceed, Mr. Prosecutor.
Did you write that letter
to your husband, Mrs. Graham?
Yes, I did.
And in that letter,
did you say anything
about where you and
he might have been
on the night of
March the 9th,
or whether you
were together,
or anything about
establishing your alibi?
No.
I offer into evidence,
if the court please,
this letter
marked exhibit 73.
Accepted into evidence,
letter marked exhibit 73.
But I remember
now why I didn't.
I wanted Henry to
come and see me.
You also asked Mr. Miranda
to come and see you
and testify falsely that he was
with you March the 9th.
I didn't exactly want him.
I just felt that I had no other choice.
You told him that
you were really
with Perkins and Santo that night,
didn't you, Mrs. Graham?
I kept telling him that I wasn't
at the scene of the crime,
and he acted like
he should insist I was,
and I thought,
well, this is my last chance.
I can't prove where I was,
and if he walks out on me,
then I won't have anybody.
I didn't know what to do,
which way to turn.
Just respond to the question!
All I could think of
was that I couldn't
prove my alibi
and I was gonna go
to the gas chamber,
- and I was desperate!
Mrs. Graham...
Have you ever been desperate?
Do you know what it's like?
Mrs. Graham!
Your Honor, I move that be stricken!
So ordered.
- Mrs. Graham, you...
- I know.
I'm sorry. I know.
Proceed.
Mrs. Graham, perhaps
one of the reasons
you were so "desperate,"
as you call it,
during all this time,
was that you knew
you were already
on probation.
I guess I still am.
From where?
San Francisco.
Of what crime
were you convicted?
You're hesitating
again, Mrs. Graham.
Of what desperate crime
were you convicted?
Perjury.
Barbara Graham.
He's here.
How's the Dior? Okay?
Oh, elegant.
Hey.
Tell him to come up
and see me sometime.
Captain's given
you permission
to see him in the
attorney's room.
That's swell of her.
I've seen him, Barbara.
He's a doll.
Thank you, ma'am.
Ask him
if he's got a friend.
I'll do that.
Aw, don't cry, honey.
Hey, here she is.
Now, give your mama
a kiss, like I showed you.
Oh, sweetheart.
Oh, sweetheart, don't cry.
Don't cry. Don't cry.
- Peg, what happened?
- It's the cameras.
Why don't you be decent
and give us a break, huh?
Oh, mommy missed
you, sweetheart.
Mommy missed you.
Tell us, Barbara,
how does it feel
seeing your baby,
knowing that you
face the gas chamber?
How the hell do
you think it feels?
Damn them!
Damn them! Damn them!
Get your mitts off!
Back to your cell! Come on!
Damn you! Damn you!
Therefore, while there
are certain practices
I don't think police officers
should indulge in,
in this instance,
I see no grounds for criticism.
Motion for a new trial is denied.
May the record show
that I appeared
for the motion for a new trial
only since Mr. Tibrow
has taken ill?
All right, Mr. Matthews,
you'll be relieved of further
responsibility in this case.
Thank you, Your Honor.
The defendant, Barbara Graham,
is remanded to the custody
of the sheriff of
Los Angeles county,
to be delivered by him
to the California Institution
for Women at Corona.
It is the judgment and
sentence of this court
that the defendant,
Barbara Graham,
suffer the extreme penalty,
to wit, the death penalty.
And that said
penalty be inflicted
within the walls of
the state penitentiary
at San Quentin, California,
in the manner and means
prescribed by law,
to wit, the administration
of lethal gas
until said defendant is dead.
Bring her over
here for T.V., boys.
Please step aside.
Hey, Babs!
Now your husband's dried out,
I hear he wants to
change his story.
Come on, will you?
Give it a break, huh, Montgomery?
You didn't, Counselor.
You just dropped her.
Any comments on that?
From what I read in the papers,
she ain't my type.
Uh-huh. Big boy like you.
Maybe you shouldn't believe
everything you read.
Have you
anything to say?
Uh, how about it, Babs?
Just a short statement.
Yeah, Babs, why so quiet today?
I wanna thank
the gentlemen of the press.
You've chewed me up
in your headlines,
and all the jury had to do
was spit me out!
You're all invited
to the execution.
That's only fair.
You led the pack, Montgomery.
Bring your wife.
She'll enjoy it.
For once, how about
a statement from you?
Are you satisfied now?
Hey, it looks
like a college.
Yes.
In fact, the
girls at Corona
refer to the grounds as
"the campus."
Rah, rah, rah.
Well, I've gotta admit,
this place is a
big improvement
over some of those
other menageries I've been in.
Every dress
different, huh?
Yes, because no
two girls are alike.
We want our girls
to walk tall with their heads up.
Hi, Barbara.
HI.
She knew me.
Guess I'm sort of the,
what do they call it,
"big man on campus," huh?
This is your room.
Here we go again.
Just show me where you
keep the hammerlocks,
and I'm all set.
We have to put you in isolation
because of your...
Death sentence?
First time I ever heard
it was contagious.
Sorry, Barbara.
It has to be this way.
Ah, I probably wouldn't have
made the team anyhow.
Never have yet.
Is that Shelly Manne?
Yeah. You like him?
Knocks me out.
They electrocuting somebody?
That means two minutes
to lights out.
Got to scoot.
Solong.
Good night, Bar...
Oh, no, I'm sorry.
You can't wear that here.
Well, why not?
It's too... provocative.
Provocative?
There's nothing
but dames here.
Not a man within miles.
And I've got these
for a chastity belt.
Oh, boy, would I love to have
somebody to provoke.
It's very foolish to make trouble
on your first night, Barbara.
I'd advise you to
wear the nightgown
we've provided you.
- Well?
- Okay.
Okay, I'll take it off...
But I won't wear
your burlap job.
I'll sleep raw.
Well?
Cover yourself.
She refused
to take a lie detector test.
She wrote Tibrow
she wants to take one now, Carl.
Yes, now she does as
a last-ditch gamble,
but she wouldn't
risk it before.
Could be she had
other things to hide.
Probably quite a lot.
I still say there's
something about her.
When you meet her...
Hello, Mr. Matthews.
How's Mr. Tibrow?
Better, but still in the hospital.
He asked me to reconsider
taking your appeal.
Oh?
I want Mr. Palmberg
to talk to you.
Then I'll decide.
Hello, Barbara.
Sit over here, please.
Carl is gonna make
some tests on you.
He's a psychologist as
well as a criminologist.
That's his problem.
I don't like my mother.
I never knew my father.
Where's your hammer?
Sky, blue.
Monday, wash.
How's that?
They're responses
to the word test.
All right, Al.
I'll see you later.
Oh, sure.
What's the book?
Poetry.
"There was a young lad
from Japan
"Whose verses they
never would scan
"When he was asked why,
he said with a sigh
"Darn it all, I just can't
help trying
"To get as many words
in the last line
"As I possibly,
possibly can"
We might get along.
I hope so.
I'd like to start
with a Rorschach Test.
Do you know
what that is?
Oh, yeah. lnkblots.
They'll tell you
what's on my murky brain.
Right.
Go ahead.
What do you see?
A rain cloud.
Bobby.
This one, this one
looks like a bed.
What about her, Carl?
She's totally amoral.
She's a compulsive liar
with no regard
for law and order
or the conventions
of society.
You must have
been reading my stuff.
Then I shouldn't even...
I think you should
take the appeal.
- What?
- I think she's innocent.
If she's innocent, why don't
Santo and Perkins speak up?
What have they
got to lose now?
The only cure
they can think of
- for the cyanide.
- Come again?
They believe that in the end,
her sentence will be commuted.
A young, attractive woman,
a mother...
And if you don't send
the actual killer to the gas chamber,
how can you send
the ones who just stood around?
That's why they decided
to keep her out front
and say that she did it.
And that's why they're
gonna keep her there,
right up to the
chamber door.
Now, that's just
your own opinion.
Just my own opinion,
Montgomery.
Unfortunately,
I can't print it
under a byline
and make it a fact.
There's the reverse, Carl.
The State has to gas her,
if they wanna get
Santo and Perkins.
I'm convinced
she couldn't have done it.
She has a positive
aversion to violence,
physical violence,
not emotional.
Forgery, perjury, vice,
these are her crimes.
They're not crimes
of violence.
They're the crimes of those
for whom violence is impossible.
Also, she's left-handed.
- I never noticed that.
- No.
I didn't see it mentioned
in any of your articles.
Bruce King testified
that she did it
with the gun in her right hand.
Well, you can't use that
in an appeal.
It's evidence that was
available during the trial.
Look, you
didn't bring me out here
to tell you
how to appeal,
only whether.
Well, we shall have to...
What do you mean "we"?
Even if I take it,
there's no money
for an investigation.
Besides,
in your present
state of health...
Stop interrupting.
We'll have to develop
a great deal of new evidence.
That's my job.
You'll translate it into
your highly
incomprehensible legal prose.
But evidence
and jargon alone
will not save the lady.
That's where you come in.
The press created the climate
which condemned her.
You'll have to change
that climate.
Now, whatever
gave you the idea
that I'm on your side?
You're here, aren't you?
To get a story,
that's all.
You could have concocted
your usual story
without making the trip.
So it strikes me
you already had it in mind
to change your
point of view.
Hmm.
I'm not sure what
I had in mind.
I am.
You remind
me of the man
who was looking for his hat,
when it was on his head
the whole time.
Maybe,
but at least I...
I haven't lost my head yet.
But today, Peg,
things are looking up.
Mr. Matthews has
taken my appeal.
There's a man with
him, a Carl Palmberg.
I can't describe the
effect he has on a person...
But there, that's it.
I'm a person again,
not a condemned person.
You can imagine
how upset I am, Al,
that after all our efforts
for the last six months,
they positively refuse
to give me a lie
detector test.
Surely, by now, there's
some word on my appeal.
The suspense is killing me.
Ha, ha!
I guess you're
beginning to realize
what an impossible
client I am,
especially for
a nonpaying one.
Could be my upbringing.
And another thing, Carl,
thank Montgomery for
his latest article.
You were right.
The interviews are
beginning to pay off.
I don't know what's
making him change
toward me in his old age,
but he sure seems to have.
Most important
of all, though,
please, please,
please, Carl,
you must bring
me definite news
about my appeal,
or I'll go insane.
Please, Mrs. Graham,
you must sit still.
You ain't got rhythm,
Doc. that's your trouble.
My trouble is 15 other
appointments today.
These inlays take time.
Pretty funny,
putting in gold inlays
when they've already got
some of those cyanide eggs
marked with my initials.
Such talk.
Barbara.
Carl.
I'd like to talk
to Mrs. Graham.
It's all right.
Don't just stand there, give.
Your appeal has been denied.
Did they set a date?
December 3, but, uh, Al immediately
put in for a stay of execution.
No!
I don't want any stay!
If you can't get my
sentence commuted,
then don't get me a stay!
At least I know it will be over
on December the 3rd!
- Barbara...
- You heard me!
I can't stand it anymore!
I can't!
Barbara.
Oh, Carl.
What am I gonna do?
You're gonna get your teeth fixed.
Come on.
Bad dreams again, Barbara?
Oh...
Go away, and
leave me alone.
There's your mommy.
Oh, Bobby.
Sweetie!
On, Bobby. Baby, baby.
Mommy's so happy to see you.
How is she?
With four days left,
how would you be?
Oh, you're such
a big boy now.
And you must weigh
at least 25 pounds, I bet you.
Yeah.
You remember how
we used to play
wibbleton to wobbleton?
This is a game we used
to play every night, hmm?
Yeah, and here we go.
From Wibbleton to
Wobbleton is 15 miles.
From Wobbleton to
Wibbleton is 15 miles.
Do you like that?
See, Peg? He remembers.
Okay, sport,
here we go again.
From Wibb/eton
to Wobb/eton is 15 miles
From Wobbleton to
Wibbleton is 15 miles
From Wobbleton to Wibbleton
From...
Come along, sonny.
Let's get some ice cream.
Oh, don't, don't,
honey. You mustn't.
Oh, Peg, anything but losing him.
Maybe I could stand it if it,
if it weren't for losing him.
You won't. Now, you won't!
Sometimes I think
everything inside rne
is gonna bust wide open,
and I feel as though somebody's
pulling out my guts
with their bare hands.
Shh,honey.Shh.
I never should
have had him, Peg.
Even if I do miss
the gas chamber, I'll...
I'll rot in prison.
I'll only cause him to suffer
by staying alive.
I'm glad I'm gonna die.
Barbara.
Barbara, listen to me.
You've been granted
a stay of execution
by the United States
Supreme Court.
Oh...
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
If I'd known you were
in the hospital, Carl,
I wouldn't have sent
that last silly letter.
Guess I shouldn't
have anyhow,
but waiting these
past two months
for the supreme court
to review my petition
has been a strain.
I've been lying
here thinking
about what you said
on your last visit.
I do want to live, Carl.
Life does seem
very dear to me.
I want to live,
and you're my greatest hope.
I can't believe it...
Carl dead.
And we were counting heavily
on his investigation.
He didn't leave any notes
on his new stuff.
It all went with him.
Everything went with him.
Well, don't say that.
You've got a lot
going for you.
Al Matthews, those committees,
and me.
That isn't what you came
to tell me, Mr. Montgomery.
Yeah.
The supreme court has
denied your petition.
What's the new date?
June.
June 3.
Yesterday, I found
two gray hairs.
Not bad, huh? Only two.
You've still got a couple
of legal shots to fire.
Al is in court right now
working on them.
And tomorrow
I'm gonna make a pitch
to the Governor's
clemency secretary.
I've even gotten the paper
to come outwith an editorial
in favor of commuting
your sentence.
Why not?
Win or lose,
I sell a lot of papers.
Yeah.
Barbara, I...
Barbara, what
I wrote about you
during your trial...
- The way I feel now...
- No!
Ah, this is a
hell of a sendoff
you're giving me.
Everything but confetti.
And here in the southland,
today marks the
beginning of the end
for Barbara Graham.
Our newsreel cameraman
catches her leaving
Corona this morning
on what may be her
last trip anywhere.
As I watch Barbara
enter the car
that will speed her to the
death cell at San Quentin,
I think how little she looks
like a condemned murderess,
who will lead off California's
first triple execution.
More like the pretty girl
who, a long time ago,
took the wrong fork
in the road of life.
Thoughts like these
discourage me from
crowding up to her
with the other reporters
with the usual
barrage of questions.
Do you still think
you have a chance, Babs?
Hey, Babs.
Whafll you wear tomorrow?
But even now,
hope eternal rides with her.
At any time before her
scheduled appointment
in the gas chamber
at 10:00 a.m. tomorrow,
the courts, or the
Governor himself,
may yet decide to
halt the execution.
Here she comes!
Babs! Babs!
Hey, Barbara,
look this way!
We're with you, hon!
Want to see her
with me, Ed?
Five minutes with Perkins
is what I want.
Five lousy minutes, Warden.
He's refused you.
Since when are you
so sensitive to his whims?
It's his last night, too.
Yeah, but it doesn't
have to be Barbara's.
That louse
could clear her!
Will you stop giving me
a hard time?
Any execution is tough enough
on the prison as it is,
but with a woman in
the death house...
At least will you tell Perkins
I'll be standing by?
- Yes. Yes.
- All night, if necessary?
Yes! You can wait here, but...
Please lay off the pressure.
Hello, Barbara.
My name's Barbara, too.
I'm Mrs. Graham to you.
Whatever you like,
Mrs. Graham.
- This is Mrs...
- Let's skip the introductions.
This isn't a garden party.
I would get
someone like you,
fat stuff.
Now, now, Barbara.
That's the wrong attitude.
Sign her over
on the D.W., please.
I wish you luck, Barbara.
We all do at Corona.
This is your cell.
- You take the first watch.
- All right.
I'll get the coffee started.
And turn off that schmaltz.
Might as well get into
something comfortable.
I'm sure you'll be more
comfortable in these.
What's eating you?
You'll have to undress
so I can give you a
complete shakedown.
You won't find anything
hidden on my body.
If I was gonna kill myself,
I'd have done it a year ago.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Graham,
but we have orders to follow.
- No!
- Mrs. Graham...
Get this straight,
Miss Bedpan.
Nobody's gonna go
pawing over me!
I'm through with
all that stuff.
Now get outta here!
Just leave me alone!
Here, you! Don't get fresh
with us, or we'll...
You'll what?
What can anyone
threaten me with now?
All right to come in?
- It's the warden.
- Yes, sir.
Do you have a cigarette
for me, Barbara?
Ooh, that's a switch.
Hmm, thank you.
You know, we'd like you to be
as comfortable as possible.
Do you have any
special requests?
I just wanna see my lawyer
the minute he gets here.
That's all that
counts right now.
We've already arranged for that.
Thanks.
You haven't heard anything?
No.
One more thing.
The gas chamber...
Now, there's no use
dwelling on that.
Just hope for the best.
It's right around here
someplace, isn't it?
You can order anything
you like for dinner.
I don't feel like eating.
If you'll excuse me,
I think I'll retire.
Yes, of course.
- Warden?
- Yes?
Don't forget to
call me at 10:00.
- Warden?
- Yes?
She refuses to
let me examine her.
Must I?
All right, all right.
Forget it.
Very sharp.
Well, I mustn't
disappoint my public.
I can just imagine
what those papers
are gonna say...
"Bloody Babs spent
her last night
"decked out in
lounging pajamas
"of her
favorite color,
"flaming scarlet."
That's what they
always call red
when I wear it.
Or any other
color, I'll bet.
Would you like some
coffee, Mrs. Graham?
Yeah.
Barbara...
My name is Barbara, too.
Ah, come on, come on.
They sent some dinner over
for you anyway, Mrs. Graham.
Take it out of my sight.
You should keep
up your strength.
It doesn't come
from the belly.
Ah! Ah!
I thought we agreed
not to count the hours.
Sorry.
Where's that lawyer?
He'll be here.
He'd better.
He's liable to lose
an important client.
It's Father Devers.
- Hello, Barbara.
- Hello, Father.
I'm glad to see you.
My, mY-
I suppose those are
what is known as
the Hepcat's Pajamas.
- Yes! You dig 'em?
- The most.
I don't know why I
should feel so upset.
- I'm not afraid to die.
- Of course not.
You know, I think
it would be rather nice
to come face to face
with the one person
in all the world who
knows I'm innocent.
None of us are
wholly innocent
or guilty in
the eyes of God.
I meant Mrs. Monahan.
I brought you this, Barbara.
Thank you, Father.
What a lovely
going-away present.
Saint Jude.
Saint of the impossible.
I'd like to go to
confession, Father.
All right, Barbara.
Forgive me, Father,
for I have sinned.
- Gerry Mulligan.
- Could be.
I know all of his
sides by heart.
Flaming scarlet.
Now they'll announce it,
and you'll see.
- Want me to relieve you?
- Shh!
A K.L.l. G. special
news bulletin.
Four couples have
made overtures
to adopt the 3-year-old
son of Barbara Graham,
who, barring an Nth-hour
reprieve from the courts...
Shut that thing off!
...will die in the gas chamber
tomorrow morning at 10:00.
Those crumbs!
What right have they
got to take my boy?
- I'm sure they only meant...
- I don't care what they meant!
What time is it?
Never mind. Just tell
me what day is it?
Thursday or Friday?
It's Friday.
Mr. Matthews here
to see Mrs. Graham.
Now, you listen to me!
Nobody's gonna adopt my kid.
Where did you hear that?
On that radio!
Don't pay any
attention to it.
- That always happens.
- Not to me!
It's all been arranged
as you wanted.
Bobby stays on
with his grandmother.
- You swear?
- I swear.
Things look good.
I filed that writ
in federal court.
Got the clerk to open
the office for me.
That's where I've been.
- The judge is studying the petition now.
- And?
He won't give out
with anything tonight.
I'll argue it first thing in the morning.
That's exactly what I wanted.
Keep as much pressure
on him as possible.
Just this once, I wish
it wasn't ladies first.
Montgomery's sticking
around all night
trying to get a
statement from Perk
that will clear you.
An exclusive statement,
I presume.
He's wasting his time.
There's a good chance
of getting the order switched around.
If Perk and Santo
have to go first,
they might just break down.
Wanna bet?
I still have a couple of rabbits
to pull out of the hat,
so keep your chin up.
The Governor turned down
your plea for clemency,
but if he'll see me in person,
I'll charter a plane to Sacramento.
- No.
- Huh?
Anything in the courts, okay,
but don't beg for my life.
- Barbara.
- Don't beg for my life!
Deliver this for me, will you?
- You'll have to clear that letter.
- He knows!
What are you trying to do?
Teach my lawyer the law?
Keep it there.
See you around,
mouthpiece.
Here, sit on this.
That floor must be getting hard.
- Sure you don't need it?
- Uh-uh.
Thanks.
Look, you don't have to stay up
all night yakking with me.
Tell fat stuff to relieve you
if you want.
No, it's all right.
Music all night continues
after the late news.
Off he goes.
The head basketball
coach of Hampton High
surrendered to police today
on a morals charge.
There, leave that.
There's lots
of long-hair music I like.
Me, too.
Sometimes I find
it very relaxing.
You got any kids?
Two boys, three and six.
What kind of a guy
is your husband?
Well, right now
I'm sewing him
with divorce papers
for desertion.
I don't believe in divorce.
I'm separated.
Divorced or separated,
the way men are
these days,
that's about the only way
you can live with them.
Oh, no.
No, my Henry was a
wonderful husband.
He brought home
flowers or candy
almost every night,
and he was always
giving me money
to buy things with.
And talk about
doting fathers.
No sacrifice was too
great for our boy.
No, I've...
I've got to admit...
I had an ideal marriage.
Well, then, what happened?
Sorry. I didn't mean to be nosy.
That's okay.
I left my husband
because I was holding him back.
You see, he was up
for a vice-presidency
in the bank
where he worked,
and I was afraid
he wouldn't
get the promotion
because of me.
For an important
job like that,
they consider the
wife as carefully
as they do
the husband.
Yeah, I guess they would.
Don't you think
you should rest?
I don't wanna rest.
It was a very big bank.
You'd know the name if I told you.
Come in.
Good morning, Mrs. Graham.
Good morning.
Hot fudge sundaes
for breakfast.
What won't I think of next?
They're scrumptious.
Let me tell you about a,
a champagne breakfast
we had once in Vegas. We...
It was in the back
room the whole time?
It never rang once.
Maybe it will.
Gas chamber. Phone check.
Ring back in ten seconds.
Okay.
Is the warden's direct line
to the Governor open?
Check.
Remind the others to stop
all outgoing calls at 9:00.
I know they know,
but tell them again.
Now give me
Western Union.
Western Union,
this is San Quentin.
Give me a time check, please.
Thank you.
We're three seconds slow.
Record it, huh?
Right.
I wish we could
give her the benefit.
Oh, they're awake,
but they still won't see you.
Well, did they say anything?
Yeah. Santo said to tell you
he'd managed to stay alive so far
by keeping his mouth shut.
Those two are the
dirtiest, slimiest,
- no-good apes I've ever had...
- Agreed.
What was she doing shacked up
with them in the first place?
Air lock test okay.
What time is it?
It's 9215.
Barbara,
you've gotten a stay
from the Governor.
Oh.
Does this mean that I...
...might get to live?
No. It's just a delay
to give your lawyer time
to argue in court
this morning.
- We wouldn't want you to think...
- That I'm not going to be executed.
I like that word much better
than "gassed," don't you?
It's all up to the courts, Barbara.
Why, thank you, gentlemen.
The saint of
the impossible.
Oh, he's certainly got a
pip to work on this time.
- More coffee, anyone?
- Yeah, thanks.
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir, I understand.
We'll make it 10:45.
I'm sorry, Barbara.
Your writ has been denied.
The stay is vacated.
Do I have time to dress?
15 minutes.
- Can I help?
- No. No, loan do it.
- Is my seam straight?
- Yes.
- Do I look okay?
- Very nice.
Those earrings are just the touch.
A pair of fake earrings.
That's all I wound up with.
You've been swell, Barbara.
Here, you give this to your kids.
But that belongs to your boy.
Oh, I suppose he's forgotten
all about it by now.
You know how kids are.
What are you doing?
- Floor's cold.
- What?
You'll have to take
your shoes off, Mrs. Graham.
That's out.
I look better with them on.
Well, what's that thing?
You have
to put it on, Barbara.
- What's it for?
- Nothing to be afraid of.
It's just part
of a stethoscope.
You're lying.
No stethoscope looks like that.
It attaches to a tube
that leads to the rest
of the stethoscope outside the chamber.
All right, nurse.
Do I have to go
out there like this?
Do I, Father?
It's time.
Her shoes.
All right, let it go.
Oh!
Yes, sir. Yes, sir.
Until further word from you.
Oh, Father, why do they torture me?
Why do they torture me?
Gentlemen,
an amended writ has been filed
in the State Supreme Court.
The witnesses and press
are to go back to the waiting room
until you hear from me.
Gentlemen, I have
told you all I know.
Anytime.
We'll make it 11:30.
Barbara, I'm very sorry.
Goodbye, and God bless you.
I want a mask.
A mask?
I don't want to look at people.
I don't wanna see
them staring at me.
I have one.
My sleep mask.
Father,
I didn't do it.
Step up.
When you hear
the pellets drop, count ten,
take a deep breath.
It's easier that way.
How do you know?
Okay.
Ed!
Ed.
It's over.
BARBARA".
"Dear Mr. Montgomery,
"there isn't much I
can say with words,
"they always fail me
when most needed.
"But please know that
with all my heart,
"I appreciate everything
you've done for me.
"Sincerely, Barbara."