Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org
What do you see
beyond this wall?
Picture it.
You've got an imagination.
Go ahead.
What I see is a small town
in the Midwest.
Handful of churches.
Some places for the farmers
to get drunk together.
Maybe a salon
for their wives to do their hair
on the holidays.
I visit these places.
These are the people
who send us our profits,
who send us your wages.
I make movies, Judy,
but it's your job
to give those people dreams.
The economy's in the gutter,
and they pay for you.
And I'll tell you
something else.
In every one of those towns,
believe me,
there's a girl
who's prettier than you.
Maybe their nose is a little
thinner at the bridge.
They have better teeth than you.
Or they're taller
or they're slimmer.
Only, you have something
none of those pretty girls
can ever have.
You know what that is?
No, sir.
You have that voice.
It'll maybe take you to Oz,
someplace none of those pretty
girls can ever go.
Still, I'm told you're unhappy.
Well, no, sir, not unhappy.
I'd just maybe like a little
more time.
Time? For what?
I don't know.
Maybe to go to the pictures
like those other girls do.
The thing is, those other girls
will grow up to be cashiers
and farmers' wives
and elementary school teachers.
And they'll see their skins
roughed up through housework.
Is that what you want, Judy?
To be just a housewife?
To be just a mother?
Out there,
you'd have to put away
that voice of yours.
Forget it exists.
But here, with us,
with your family,
that voice will make you
a million dollars
before you're 20.
Those average kids,
they're all loved, in their way.
I can see how you
may be drawn to it,
from time to time.
Their small lives.
Not too dangerous.
Not too exciting.
They're where they belong.
And maybe you feel like
you're like them.
But really, you're not.
You live in another world
entirely.
They just look like you.
But if you truly wanna
go join them,
it's your decision.
We'll shake hands and you
can walk through our gates.
I guarantee it's all there,
the rest of America,
just waiting to swallow you up
and forget all about you.
Like a raindrop
falling into the Pacific.
Who cares? Who even notices?
Of course I wanna stay
with the studio, LB.
Any girl would kill
to be Dorothy.
I'm just terribly sorry if...
I didn't even say anything
to anyone.
You're my favorite, Judy.
- Who else have we had in?
- Shirley Temple this morning.
Everybody loves Shirley.
Let's see how Judy measures up.
Joey, did you grow again?
I guess.
Oh! Well, could you at least
do it all at once?
Just get it over with
one weekend?
'Cause it's a new pair of pants
every time you add an inch.
Dad says vitamins
make me grow.
So, we'll cut those out.
Oh, I'm kidding, darling.
It's a wonderful thing
to have a son big enough
he can carry his mother
to the car.
Lorna, sweetheart,
let me see you.
What are we doing first?
Oh, the usual. Is that okay?
- Yeah.
- You look gorgeous, sweetheart.
- So, I have your money.
- Oh.
Crowd's gonna go crazy
- out there.
- Aw.
So, it's $150.
Uh, I know it's not maybe
- what you're used to, but...
- No, no, I appreciate it.
- All right.
- I do.
- Okay, you ready?
- Sure.
- Follow me.
- Go on.
All right, folks...
We'll just do what we did
in New York, yeah?
Hope you're ready.
Put your hands together.
Okay, let's go, let's go.
How are you tonight, Altadena?
One of Hollywood's
true legends,
Miss Judy Garland.
Well, I've got something
very special
planned for you this evening.
I've brought my children along.
What a journey.
I'm sorry it's so late.
How you doing, Georgie?
I'm okay, thank you,
Miss Garland. And you?
Oh, stumbling along.
Any messages
while we were out of town?
Uh, I don't think so.
Okay. Well, could I just
have my key, please?
Let me check something
with Mr. Horowitz. One moment.
Can we get room service, Mama?
I missed dinner.
Sure, sweetheart.
Anything you want.
- Miss Garland.
- Oh, please. I'm Judy.
- Could I have a word?
- Can it wait?
We're just desperate
to get to bed.
Lorna, darling,
tell Peter what you want
and he'll take care of it.
A hamburger and fries, please.
Oh, and, you know,
I'd love a bowl of soup.
And a drink.
Vodka rocks.
You know what, forget the soup.
I'm too tired to even
wield a spoon.
I'm very sorry, but your suite
has been released.
What do you mean, "released"?
It's not still attached
to the building?
Where exactly has it gone?
I believe your account
was in arrears.
Oh. No. No, I don't...
I don't think that's the case.
- The room got released.
- So un-release it.
Hand it back.
We need to sleep in it.
- Is everything okay?
- No. No, darling.
These people have let us
down very badly
leaving us stranded without so
much as a change of socks.
Everything is in storage.
I could have rooms
anywhere in this city,
but I chose this hotel.
Well, not anymore.
I wouldn't let my worst enemy
stay here.
Let's just go.
Outraged.
Come on, sweetheart.
- Please don't go to sleep now.
- No, no, no.
These are the other ones.
- Where are we going?
- The Roosevelt.
Didn't we stay there last year?
Sure.
But they like us.
Mama.
Could we head toward Brentwood,
please?
Joe, get the bell,
would you, darling?
So, you wanna stay?
No.
And they're only
staying tonight.
- So, they have school tomorrow.
- I know that.
They slept in the cab.
They'll be fine.
I probably paid more
on cab fare tonight
than I would've on a hotel.
- What about tomorrow night?
- What about it?
- Come on. Don't play that game.
- Well, you're needling me, Sid.
- Just ask me a straight question
- All right,
where are my children
gonna sleep tomorrow night?
Wherever I tell them.
Hi, sweetheart.
- Something wrong?
- Hey.
- I... I can't sleep.
- You want some milk?
- Come here.
- No, you go to bed.
We'll bring it to you, okay?
Don't worry.
Where are the mugs?
I moved them.
They're where the glasses were.
Ridiculous.
Couldn't you just take a role
in something?
I'm "unreliable."
And "uninsurable."
That's what the ones who like me
say to my face.
So, thank you for that.
Leave me out of it.
"Judy, leave it to me
and you'll be back on top."
- Look how that turned out.
- "Where is she, Sid?
Is she sick?
- Is she coming in today?"
- Don't.
- "Where's your star?"
"You realize we're gonna have
to sue you both, Sid."
- Don't start.
- "Why are you
even protecting her, Sid?
- What's going on?"
- Oh, shut up, Sid!
You can't turn up here
at one o'clock in the morning
- and expect...
- I know they should be in bed!
It just doesn't always
work that way.
And it gets late because nobody
wants to pay to see me
at 2:00 in the afternoon.
And I have to work,
because they need things.
They need an education, Judy.
They need ten hours of sleep.
Oh, just to hell with this.
Just call me a cab.
I want custody
during the school year.
Over my dead body.
Well, no one would be surprised,
believe me.
Give me the milk.
Give me the milk!
It's a little late for all that,
don't you think?
Why don't you see yourself out?
Can we go here, please?
♪ Got to tell you true ♪
Thank you.
♪ I got to tell you true ♪
♪ Oh, brother Jack ♪
♪ You goin' with sister Sadie ♪
♪ When you ought to be home ♪
♪ With your old lady... ♪
This house is fabulous.
Look at that. She shows.
What, am I early?
- You look fabulous.
- Liza, darling,
you look beautiful.
I can't believe you came.
What are you doing here?
Well, I wanted to see you,
darling.
Are you in L.A. for a while?
Well, I never know, you know,
these days.
I have a show
opening in two days.
- You do? Really?
- Mm. Yeah.
- And how do you feel about it?
- I don't know.
I know my lines
and it's all in my range.
I guess I haven't really
thought about it that much.
You're not even
a little anxious about it?
- Well, should I be anxious?
- Well...
I mean, no.
No.
Um, we were off to go dance.
Will you come with us?
No, no.
No, you go.
I'll catch up to you.
Excuse me. This is for you.
We can't have the world's
greatest entertainer
out here without a drink.
Frank Sinatra's here?
Frank is great,
but he is no Judy Garland.
I bet it kills him.
- I'm Mickey, by the way.
- Judy.
So, you live in Los Angeles,
Mickey?
Mm. No, I manage a bar
back in New York.
I'm out here looking
at a business opportunity.
Hmm.
You ever make your own
cocktails?
- Hmm.
- This place, we sell the booze,
and all the mixings and stuff
is on the tables,
so you get to invent
something of your own.
You know, it's fun.
People drink more
'cause they wanna be part
of the next new thing,
you know.
- Oh?
- I don't know.
You have to have ambitions,
right?
Well, I used to have them.
I found they gave me
the most terrible headache.
Well...
if you wanna create
the Judy Garland martini,
that's me.
- Mr. Mickey Deans.
- Yep.
Hmm.
You have kids, Mickey?
Uh, no. No, I don't.
Hmm. Well, you shouldn't.
It's like living with your heart
on the outside of your body.
Find a hobby or something,
like canasta or birdwatching.
Well, I play piano, actually.
- Oh, you do?
- Yeah.
You play anything
or you just sing?
Just sing?
Sorry.
That's not what I...
- Did that come out wrong?
- My entire childhood
I must've slept five
hours total.
It's a wonder
I learned to use cutlery,
let alone play the violin.
We've changed our minds. We're
gonna head to Andy's place.
Will you come?
I don't know.
I think I might stay.
Well, you don't know
anyone here.
Well, everybody
seems to know me.
Besides, I wanna stay somewhere
for longer than five minutes.
You go. Have fun.
- Mom?
- I'm fine.
Go.
I love you.
- I love you.
- Voilà.
- The masterpiece.
Well, what now?
You can't!
Wanna hear something?
Yeah, sure.
I've nowhere else to be.
All right. If you don't like it,
just toss a drink at me
or something, okay?
- I'll get the message.
- I will, don't worry.
Do you wanna join me?
Hell, no.
I'm the audience.
It's very good.
This has been
a good time, huh?
Well, we're not done yet,
are we?
I hope not.
If you ever wanna get together,
just... click your heels.
That's how it works, right?
You gotta at least
eat some.
I don't know.
Oh!
Those are too good.
You're gonna have to,
I don't know,
tie my hands to the chair legs.
Only then
I'd probably lean forward
and grab 'em with my mouth.
Hey, I'm eating those.
You wanna see if I can manage
a whole hamburger?
Mickey?
Are we dating?
I just wanna know
so as I know how to look at you.
So...
I think we're just pals
who might be something more
sometime in the future.
You gotta ask Mr. Mayer.
I think it's just pals.
I'm not kissing you
if that's what you're after.
Your loss.
- Don't I know it.
- And anyways,
after a mouthful
of onion rings?
No, thanks!
No hamburger.
Mr. Mayer said very specifically
you were not to eat the food.
I'm honestly very hungry.
Those'll take the edge off.
No, I gotta sleep tonight.
Halpert will give you something
for that later. Down the hatch.
Okay, boys, here we go.
- ...get set up.
- Let her at least take a bite.
We can't have a Dorothy
who puts on weight
halfway through the picture.
- His words, not mine.
- Can you take another bite
with your head to the side,
Mr. Rooney?
- Yeah. That's our shot!
- That's great stuff.
That's great, Judy!
Okay. Right.
Okay.
So, that was Sid's lawyers
on the phone.
- Why?
- He wants them
Sunday through Friday
during school time.
- No.
- He claims you're homeless.
How's he even
paying for a lawyer?
He's not making money
off me anymore.
So, where are you staying?
I love my children.
I take care of them.
Where'd you stay last night?
With a friend.
And is that somewhere maybe
you could take the kids to stay?
I don't have a home.
I can't even get a manager.
Step right up
and take 10% of my debts.
You know what I'm gonna say.
London would offer you
- a lot of money
- No.
See, they're crazy for you.
It's because the English
are insane.
Look, start earning again.
Then Sid's people
will have nothing on you.
Lorna does adore London.
Honey...
the courts won't let you
take them out of the country.
So, you're saying
I have to leave my children
if I wanna make enough money
to be with my children?
I know it's hard.
But I think you have
to take this seriously.
I can't.
Thank you.
Oh, God.
You'll miss Christmas.
Well, you see, darling,
the problem is that...
I don't currently own a chimney
for Santa to climb down,
so I'm no good to you kids.
But I'll be back
for New Year's, okay?
Joey.
Joe.
Darling, I have to fix things,
okay,
so I can see you every day,
the whole of every day.
I just need a little money
to make that happen.
Where would we live then?
I'm going to find us a new home
for the three of us,
so don't you get
too comfortable here.
I'm coming straight back
for you.
I am.
Or maybe...
I could...
just hide out in here...
with Nibbles instead.
Okay.
Shh.
Ooh, it's very spacious in here.
I might just have a bathroom
plumbed in.
You wouldn't mind,
would you, Joe?
I'd love it.
Well, maybe I'll stay put, hmm?
Would you visit me
once in a while?
In Joey's wardrobe?
Oh, sure.
There's room for three.
Well, come on in.
Do you wanna... Do you guys
wanna play tennis or something?
There's a court over there.
Aw.
I do like it here.
I would very much like to stay.
Judy!
Hello, darling. Hello.
- I love you.
- I love you too, darling.
- Welcome to the Picador.
- Thank you very much.
Thank you.
- Hello.
- Welcome, Miss Garland.
Oh, thank you.
Ah, there she is.
- The fabulous Miss Judy Garland.
- Oh.
- Bernard Delfont. How are you?
- How wonderful. I'm good.
I just adore London,
- my home away from home.
- Marvelous.
- Come with me.
- Thank you.
- Hello.
I'm Rosalyn Wilder.
I'll be looking after you
- while you're in London.
- Wonderful.
Oh, lovely.
We have a schedule
printed for you.
How old are you?
I'm... I'm 28.
Oh, it is a little cold in here.
Oh, I'm terribly sorry.
I'll have somebody
look into that right away.
Thank you.
Everywhere else I go,
it seems they just
knock the place down
and start over as soon
as I leave.
I come back the next year
and I have no idea where I am.
London just sort of slaps on
another coat of paint.
I suppose we're rather
old-fashioned.
Oh, no, I like it.
I like it.
It's comforting.
Call me if you need anything.
I'll leave my card
for you on the table here.
It's beside the schedule.
- Hadn't forgotten the...
- schedule.
I... I really do appreciate it.
- We'll see you tomorrow morning.
- See you tomorrow.
Thank you.
Right, here we are.
Here?
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
We do all our rehearsals here.
The acoustic is wonderful.
This way.
♪ So... So... Somewhere ♪
♪ Over the rainbow ♪
Well, that sounds familiar.
Judy,
this is our band leader,
Burt Rhodes. Burt, Judy.
- It's...
- Hello, Burt.
...an honor to be working
with you, Ms. Garland.
I've been an admirer
for a long time.
Well, I like this one.
He can stay.
The whole town
is talking about you.
Oh, well,
let's not dwell on that.
Oh, no.
It's completely sold out.
Hmm!
Miss Garland?
Do you need anything
or should we dive in?
You know,
it's really damp in here.
I don't think rehearsing
is a good idea.
Right.
- Uh...
- You understand, darling?
Okay, well, how about we talk
about the band positions?
Okay.
Well, I'm going to be here.
And this, this is the mark-up
for the stage.
Hmm.
Right.
And where's the audience?
Wrapped around you,
all three sides.
Mm-hmm.
- And they're on one level?
- Four.
How many tiers
was Carnegie Hall?
Five.
We can discuss the songs
if you really want to.
I have all your charts.
Any changes
you might like to make?
No, everything the same.
Is there anything
to discuss, then?
Sweetheart, that's up to you.
I don't particularly need
to discuss anything.
Judy, I'm afraid the critics
- will review opening night.
- Sure.
Of course.
- It's tomorrow.
- I'd like to rest.
Hi. It's Judy.
Are the kids there?
Will you tell them
that I called?
And that I'll try them again
at this time tomorrow?
And I'd like them
to be on the line
next time I call, okay?
- Good evening, Miss Garland.
- And to you.
Oh, do... Do you have the time?
It's 3:00 in the morning, ma'am.
- Oh.
- Can I get you anything?
I am having a little trouble
sleeping.
Some warm milk, perhaps?
Sure.
Thank you.
I'll try anything once.
I'll have them bring it
up to you straightaway.
Thank you.
- Has the stage door called yet?
- Not yet.
She's late.
Hello. Can we
go to the Picador, please?
Judy?
Judy, it's Rosalyn.
How are you?
I don't feel too good.
Do you know what time it is?
I said I don't feel good.
What kind of goddamn
lock is that?
If I lock a door,
I like it to stay that way.
That's completely
understandable.
Now, this is Vivian. She's going
to take your temperature.
Take a sip of this.
Tongue out for me.
Lips together for me, darling.
What's the prognosis?
No spots, no fever,
throat's fine.
Go for a nice red lippy.
What do you
think of this, Judy?
Oh, it's very pretty.
Put some silver dust
on your cheekbones.
You'll look incredible.
Are you a nurse or what?
Yeah, if you like.
Take an arm of this,
Vivian. You can finish that
- on the way.
- Yeah.
Now, oopsy-daisy.
- There we go. One leg in.
- Oh, God.
That's it.
Shoes.
- There we go.
- Hey!
You look
absolutely incredible.
All right!
All right, all right
We can't wait
to show you off.
I felt so terrible earlier.
Well,
you do work very hard.
You're under a lot of pressure.
Since I was two.
Judy Garland,
born in a trunk.
That's what I say.
Right.
Now...
Wait, wait. What are we...
It's opening night, Judy.
Oh, yes, of course.
Well, here we are.
Judy!
Hello. Hello, darling.
- Hello. Hello, darling.
- Excuse me. Thank you.
- I love you too, darling.
- Yes, yes. Thank you.
Let... Let us through, please.
- Hello, Judy.
- Are those for me?
- These are for you.
- Oh, they're beautiful.
- You mean so much to us.
- We wanted you to know.
Gentlemen, sorry, but Judy
is running extremely late now.
Thank you, ladies.
Clear the way.
Thank you. Thank you.
Thank you.
It's right up here, Judy.
Okay, here we go, boys.
What's the matter?
- Ladies and gentlemen...
- I can't.
What? No, no, no.
What do you mean, you can't?
There's an audience out there
waiting to hear you sing.
My mouth's dry
and it could fall apart.
- No. Listen to me.
- I can't.
You'll be fine.
Now, on you go.
- We love you, Judy!
- Oh, say!
And I love you, too.
In fact, I love this whole town.
Though you will always be
special.
You know, the first time...
I sang...
on a stage,
I was all of two years old.
They say my papa
had to come and drag me off
after I started singing the same
song for the fifth time.
Oh.
It seems we have a band here.
We may as well
put them to use.
♪ I'll go my way ♪
♪ By myself ♪
♪ This is the end ♪
♪ Of romance ♪
♪ I'll go my way by myself ♪
♪ Love is only ♪
♪ A dance ♪
♪ I'll try ♪
♪ To apply myself ♪
♪ And teach my heart ♪
♪ How to sing ♪
♪ I'll go my way by myself ♪
♪ Like a bird ♪
♪ On the wing ♪
♪ I'll face ♪
♪ The unknown ♪
♪ I'll build a world ♪
♪ Of my own ♪
♪ No one knows better ♪
♪ Than I myself ♪
♪ I'm by ♪
♪ Myself ♪
♪ Alone ♪
♪ I'll go my way ♪
♪ By myself ♪
♪ Here's how the comedy ♪
♪ Ends ♪
♪ I'll have to deny myself ♪
♪ Love and laughter ♪
♪ And friends ♪
♪ Grey clouds in the sky above
♪ Have put a blot on my fun ♪
♪ I'll try to fly ♪
♪ High above ♪
♪ For my place in the sun ♪
♪ And I'll face ♪
♪ The unknown ♪
♪ I'll build a world of my own
♪ No one knows better ♪
♪ Than I myself
No ♪
♪ No one knows better
Than I myself ♪
♪ How I wanted love
And fell ♪
♪ Now I say
"What the hell?" ♪
♪ All of those ♪
♪ Dark days are gone ♪
♪ 'Cause it's solo ♪
♪ All alone ♪
♪ By myself ♪
♪ From ♪
♪ Now on ♪
Judy?
Yeah.
Judy, we're locking up.
Hmm. Okay.
There's absolutely no rush.
Take your time.
Can I, uh, get you anything?
No. No, no.
I thought you were very good.
What if I can't do it again?
Oh.
- A mess.
- Here. Let me have a go at it.
There.
- Perfect.
- Brand new.
Right. Well,
can I get you anything?
No. No, thanks.
A glass of water or...
No, no. I'll get my bag
and I'll meet you outside.
Of course.
Get up.
I can't sleep at all anymore.
Please, I can't sleep.
Please. Please.
That's not my department.
But I can't remember the steps,
and the others
keep pushing me to the back,
and everyone shouts at me
when I have a hard time with it.
Get up.
- What's this?
- Judy Garland turns 16.
- But that's not for two months.
- Gotta be today.
Scheduling issues.
Nobody splash her hair.
So this is really...
I mean, it's not really a party?
In the middle of a shoot?
You would have to be kidding.
There is a cake. Don't eat it.
Is it fake?
Pretend to eat it.
You know I get an hour
for lunch?
- It's in my contract.
- What are you talking about?
I get an hour. I wanna have it.
I don't see why I shouldn't.
Nobody takes it. Come on.
Judy.
Don't you dare.
Who wants to have some real fun?
Yeah!
What do you have in mind?
Is he propositioning me?
Who wants to hear
"The Trolley Song"?
Well, bring us in, boys.
♪ Clang, clang, clang
Went the trolley ♪
♪ Ding, ding, ding
Went the bell ♪
♪ Zing, zing, zing
Went my heart strings ♪
♪ From the moment I saw him
I fell ♪
♪ Chug, chug, chug
Went the motor ♪
♪ Bump, bump, bump
Went the brake ♪
♪ Thump, thump, thump
Went my heart strings ♪
♪ When he smiled You
could feel the car shake ♪
♪ He tipped his hat
And took a seat ♪
♪ He said he hoped he
hadn't stepped upon my feet ♪
♪ He asked my name
I held my breath ♪
♪ I couldn't speak because
He scared me half to death ♪
♪ Buzz, buzz, buzz
Went the buzzer ♪
♪ Plop, plop, plop
Went the wheels ♪
♪ Stop, stop
Went my heart strings ♪
♪ As he started to leave ♪
♪ I took hold of his sleeve
With my hand ♪
♪ And as if it were planned ♪
♪ He stayed on with me and
it was grand just to stand ♪
♪ With his hand holding mine ♪
♪ To the end of the line ♪
Yeah?
Fan mail.
Is there anyone
at the stage door?
I'll go and check.
That's okay. I'll just go.
We could have a drink
if you like.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Well, your television
interview's all confirmed.
It's a prime slot, so...
Oh, marvelous. Thank you.
- Well, good night.
- Good night.
Good night, Norman.
Good night, Miss Garland.
- Aw! Evening, fellas.
- Bravo.
- You were wonderful again.
- Thank you, darling.
- Would you mind?
- Oh, of course.
Coming to see you every night
next week. You're just...
I, um... What was it
that I said earlier?
- About Judy?
- Yes, about Judy.
- Of course about Judy.
- Uh, it was about
how you seem to bypass the ears
and land here.
- That was the gist of it.
- Thank you.
Um...
Uh, do you...
Do you wanna, um...
get some dinner or... I mean,
if you're not doing anything.
- You mean with us?
- I don't wanna impose.
- No. Yes. I mean...
- I mean, that would be beyond...
- Where's gonna be open?
- On a Tuesday after midnight...
- If it's trouble, I don't...
- No, no, no. No.
- We'll find somewhere, won't we?
- Of course.
Great, okay, well...
Lead on, my good gentlemen.
- Your bag.
- Thank you, dear.
Oh!
I thought they'd be open.
Perhaps it was terrible
dragging you
- through the streets like this.
- Oh, no, don't.
I haven't had a chance
to see any of the city.
And, well,
now I've seen all of it, so...
Sweet.
Would you like me
to make you an omelet?
Obviously, we'll try
for something a little better
than an omelet.
We're just round the corner.
You won't believe it,
but it was twice
with Mickey Rooney.
You are outrageous.
You all right
- with the green plates?
- Yes, please.
- Great.
- I like those.
- Me too.
- Mm.
I think I messed this up.
You can't really mess up
an omelet.
I put cream in it.
- Why would you put cream in?
- To make it more special.
And instead you've simply
made it not work.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
If it won't settle
for being an omelet,
just give it a shove,
and we'll have scrambled eggs.
- Would you mind?
- For goodness' sake,
has there ever been so much
drama over half a dozen eggs?
I mean, we invite you
over for dinner,
all we offer you are eggs,
and now you're doing
the cooking.
I always do the cooking.
No, I can't. I can't bear it.
Come on.
- I'm a very good cook.
- I'm sure. Put that spoon down.
- You don't trust me.
- I do.
Put that spoon down,
would you?
Please, for me. Put the spoon...
Let's give you a drink. Come on.
I'm always going to use cream
from now on.
It'll be fine.
Let's get you a drink. Come on.
You sit yourself down.
Are you gonna come through
or hide in there all night?
I'm not sure
that was even scrambled eggs.
Well, we know some eggs
went into the pan.
- We witnessed that.
- Mm-hmm.
It was delicious.
Whatever it was.
Shh.
It's sweet
that you come to see me.
Sometimes I spy the two
of you out there.
I feel like I have allies.
Well, we missed you
in '64, so...
- You couldn't get tickets?
- Not together, no.
Stan was otherwise engaged.
Six months for obscenity.
In jail?
They've changed the law
since then.
Turns out we didn't do
anything wrong after all.
They hound people in this world.
Anybody who's different.
They can't stand it.
Well, to hell with them.
Sweetheart, I'm sorry.
We decided to make up for it
in style this time,
and it is money well spent.
♪ Forget your troubles ♪
♪ Come on, get happy ♪
♪ Better chase
All your cares away ♪
♪ Shout, "Hallelujah" ♪
♪ Come on, get happy ♪
♪ Get ready
For the judgment day ♪
♪ Sun is shining ♪
♪ Come on, get happy ♪
♪ Lord is waiting to take ♪
♪ Your hand ♪
♪ Shout, "Hallelujah" ♪
♪ Come on, get happy ♪
No, thank you.
What?
- Room service.
- I didn't order anything.
It's the first sleep
I've gotten in weeks!
And you woke me up.
There's a man under the trolley.
What?
Hey, baby.
Surprise.
Mickey?
What are you doing here?
I can't believe it.
What a wonderful surprise.
Oh!
Oh. Well...
- this is me.
- Yeah, it's nice, it's nice.
- When did you get here?
- Just now.
- Yeah?
- Literally.
I just walked off the plane.
- I'm just passing through.
- Where are you staying?
I don't know. I don't know.
I literally just showed up.
I haven't thought
about anything.
Well, stay here.
Yeah?
I'm drowning in space.
Yeah, no, I mean, that...
That sounds great.
Okay. I'll stay here, then.
It's so good to see you again.
You ever tried a crumpet?
- Mm.
- It's like a pancake
that's had the living shit
kicked out of it.
You gonna eat something?
No, no. No, I'm fine.
Well, have some eggs.
The tomatoes are pretty good.
I'm fine.
Come on, have a bite.
What do you wanna do?
I'm easy.
Maybe, uh... get a drink
- with your friends.
- Sure.
We could get the gang together.
I'll make some calls.
Yeah, it's okay.
It's just okay?
It's a little old-ladyish.
I'm just saying.
You got great legs.
Show them off.
Yeah?
Yeah.
Wow.
Wish there was a little more
of them.
So, let's go shopping, baby.
Hmm?
- Get you dolled up.
- I don't know.
Oh, come on.
A woman's gotta wear something.
Or not, right?
Look out.
Don't kill America's sweetheart
here.
All right. Oh, boy, oh, boy.
Oh, yeah, I have a great idea
for a new shop.
Oh? What's that?
It's great to meet you guys.
I've heard so much about you.
How are you enjoying London,
Mickey?
It's one of the world's great
cities, you know, it really is.
And there's a lot of
opportunities here, too.
Like with The Beatles
new record. You've heard it?
It's good.
It's very, very experimental.
And it's still number one
on the charts, you know?
That tells me that
there is an appetite out there.
For The Beatles?
Well, for great artists
trying new things.
Like, I don't know you, Burt.
Judy says you're great.
These are just new ideas,
you know.
But what if it's not
Judy and Burt?
What if it's... What if it's Judy
and The Rolling Stones?
What is that?
I don't know.
Maybe it's something, right?
Are you going to ask them
or should I?
Maybe somebody should.
That's all I'm saying for now.
That's the most
fascinating conjecture.
- Thank you.
- Don't you think?
Oh, absolutely.
Ha!
All right, yeah, cool.
Another round?
- Yeah, great.
- Great.
You don't think I could do it.
Well, I just...
Well, I'm trying
to take the idea in.
Well, he thinks I could do it.
Isn't that sweet?
Judy, what you having?
- Gin and tonic?
- Yes.
The studio portrayed you
as the sort of typical
American teenage girl next door.
Is that how you remember things?
Louis B. Mayer.
Oh, MGM put out all these
stories about how I ate pizza
like any other girl.
They didn't let me have
any pizza at all.
Every lunchtime for a year,
they had me eating
Louis B. Mayer's chicken soup
till I was thin enough
to play Dorothy.
The truth is,
those years left their mark,
- though, isn't it?
- Oh, sure.
Hollywood's chicken population
never recovered.
Very good.
But your childhood
at the studio,
it did lead to problems,
didn't it?
Well, what matters to me now
is my children's happiness,
that's all.
Are they here with you
in London?
They have school.
Well,
they must miss their mother.
Hopefully they're having an
easier time of it than you had.
Well, we all...
Everybody has their troubles,
and I've had mine.
I've probably had everybody
else's too.
Has it affected
your children, do you think?
What?
The fights over custody.
Your children
living away from you.
I mean, if I'm this terrible
mother they like to write about,
well, you tell me how I end up
with such incredible kids.
But I wasn't suggesting...
Well, no,
everybody suggests things,
like I'm not a real person,
but I am, you understand?
I'm only Judy Garland
for an hour a night.
The rest of the time,
I'm part of a family.
I just want
what everybody wants.
I seem to have a harder time
getting it.
I didn't mean to upset you.
Thank you.
Have you seen Judy?
Gill, you haven't seen Judy,
- have you?
- No, I'm sorry.
- Judy?
- Miss Garland
to the stage, please.
Miss Garland.
Judy, it's twelve o'clock.
And?
And there's a thousand
people upstairs
- waiting to hear you sing.
- So bring 'em another drink.
And have 'em bring me one, too.
I know...
- I know it's not easy.
- Oh, you do, do you?
I mean, the shows
- have been a huge success.
- So what?
It doesn't change anything.
What difference does it make?
Look.
I'll do all I can to help you
resolve whatever's going on.
But, please... for my sake,
just... Just... Just do the show.
You're a classy little number,
aren't you?
Just get up and sing!
You wanna serve me up to them
like I'm their goddamn dinner.
Judy, I'm sorry, but that is not
what I'm trying to do.
- I'm trying to help you.
- Don't Judy me.
You're not my friend.
You don't care about me.
Listen, it's fine.
It's fine. We'll just
have Lonnie Donegan perform.
Over my dead body!
- If you don't want to do it...
- It's my show.
It's my name up there.
No, Lonnie Donegan
is a peach of a man,
but he can go fuck himself if he
thinks he's having my billing.
- She's upset.
- Yes, I gathered that.
Evening, Lonnie.
No! No time for that, Burt.
We've got a show to,
you know, put on.
- You're late.
- So what?
It's a party.
Where are you?
Oh! What, do you have to be home
for your mommy
to put you to bed?
Be a man,
have another drink.
Have one on me.
He's gonna have one on me.
- What you let her on stage for?
- Wonderful to be here.
There you go.
Yeah.
Is this... Is this Chicago?
What is it?
The set list says San Francisco.
Chicago, San Francisco...
What the hell town
are we in anyway?
Sing us a song.
Is that you again? I thought you
were gonna have a drink.
You drank the bar dry.
Oh!
Why did you just
spoil it for everyone?
How am I supposed to do this
up here with you harassing me
like that down there?
Why don't you
come up here
and you do the show?
And I'll take the chair
and do the fatuous backtalk,
you goddamn fucking baboon!
I want her changed
and ready in five minutes.
I'd like a moment with Judy.
I had a swim.
How was the water?
Cold.
That's because it's a prop.
It's not meant to be enjoyed.
I did 18 hours yesterday.
I mean, I couldn't hardly
remember my own name.
Your name is Frances Gumm.
You're a fat-ankled,
snag-toothed rube
from Grand Rapids.
Your father was a faggot,
and your mother only cares
about what I think of you.
Now, do you remember
who you are, Judy?
I'm sorry if I slowed things
down a little.
We like you loyal.
You're the best friend.
The girl next door.
- You're faithful.
- I'm sorry.
You sing from the heart, Judy.
You know where the heart is?
It's there.
Now, I want you
to look me in the eye
and tell me you remember
we made a deal.
I know I did.
You made that choice.
I was there.
I heard you make it.
I'm sorry.
You wanna go swimming,
you come over to my beach house.
You can swim there all night.
Now, say thank you.
Thank you.
Don't ever hold up
a movie of mine.
You know what?
You need your own place.
A club or something.
Someplace...
people are gonna come to anyway
because it's a cool place.
And if you sing, it's a goddamn
perfect miracle of a night.
And if you don't, it's no foul,
it was a good time.
People just wanna be around you.
You have that.
You know, I talk to people.
You don't hear it.
They all love you.
I'm serious.
You don't see it.
People talk about
what's next for you
because maybe they
could get in on it.
Because you're a big deal.
I... I have a perspective on this
that I think you don't.
I see how great you are.
I don't see the problems.
You'll get it perfect next time,
all right?
Sweetheart?
You can't stay there forever.
Sweetheart.
I really feel just terrible
about last night.
I sincerely believed that I was
coming down with something.
And I took a syrup for the flu.
And I was off with the fairies.
And I just... I got so upset.
And, Rosalyn, I wanna thank you
for... For looking after me.
Oh...
If I'd have known
you were unwell,
I wouldn't have asked you
to sing.
And the press
might've been more forgiving.
But can you forgive me?
It's forgotten.
The question is...
how are you feeling today?
Well, as it happens,
I feel terrific.
We have a man
I'd encourage you to see.
He does vitamin injections.
Whatever you'd like me to do.
Right.
Would you sing for me,
- please?
- Sing?
Any scale will do.
Good, and up.
Right, well...
it's not in a good way, is it?
Have there been any surgeries?
Tracheotomy.
Two years ago.
Tried to kill myself.
That won't have
helped your voice.
Hmm.
Hepatitis as well.
Look, do you take anything
for depression?
Four husbands.
Didn't work.
I'd say you're underweight.
Well, you're flirting
with me now.
Mr. Delfont asked me
to give you something,
so I'm going to give you
a vitamin injection
and some anti-inflammatories
for your vocal cords.
What you really need is rest.
Mm!
At home, with my children.
- Precisely. With your feet up.
- Mm-hmm.
Good.
Ooh!
Do you know, I, uh...
I had an absolute thing
for Dorothy Gale.
My goodness.
A lot of boys
liked her pigtails.
Yeah. For me, it was...
It was more about
how she took care of her dog.
You might be the most English
man I've ever met.
Judy...
you need to take better care
of yourself.
You understand?
- Do you understand?
- Mm.
So there's a guy
I mentioned.
Mm-hmm.
Desperate to do a deal with you.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay.
His thing is a chain of maybe
500 movie theaters, okay?
Each one is called
a Judy Garland Picture House.
Every one?
All you gotta do for each one
is you open it,
and you get 10% of sales.
- Ten percent?
- Ten percent.
He tried to make it seven,
but I pushed him up.
And I don't have to
do anything else?
No touring, nothing.
You get to pay off your debts,
you buy that house,
and you see your kids
every single day.
- Mickey.
- You're free.
Isn't that the greatest thing
you ever heard?
Yes, it's the greatest thing.
Oh, darling.
- Good news, right?
- Yes.
Yeah, just had to tell you that.
This isn't so bad, is it?
I mean, I know it's not family,
but...
You're family.
That's how I feel.
Yeah?
I have an incredible feeling
about you, Mickey.
Look what you're doing.
Look how you take care of me.
I mean, it's completely crazy,
- but...
- But it's very real.
Yeah, I know.
I know.
Are you happy?
Yeah... I am.
You and me.
I want us to get married.
I feel like any moment
we're not married is wasted.
I mean, do you
remember Scotty Beckett?
He played my kid brother in
Listen, Darling in '37 or '38.
He was the sweetest kid.
And last year, just like that,
he's dead from something
or other.
That and...
I'm happy with you.
And shouldn't we
grab hold of that?
I... I'm here, aren't I?
That's a hell of an answer.
Sweetheart, I already said
I love you nine times today.
Well, maybe I need ten,
or 12, once an hour,
like a cuckoo clock.
Cuckoo!
I love you!
Well?
Mm.
To the happy couple.
- Cheers.
It's our present to you,
so you just trust me, okay?
Judy, Judy, you go to the front.
It's a surprise.
Burt, are you ready?
I think the bloody
matches are damp.
Matches?
I'm a little terrified.
This way you can say you've had
an English church wedding.
Here we go!
♪ For once in my life ♪
♪ I have someone who needs me ♪
♪ Someone I've needed so long ♪
♪ For once in my life ♪
♪ I can go
where life leads me ♪
♪ And somehow I know ♪
♪ I'll be strong ♪
♪ For once I can touch ♪
♪ What my heart
Used to dream of ♪
♪ Long before I knew... ♪
No, no, no.
We can tie this off. Look...
Well, then, let me come
and see you, all right?
Any points we need to look at
we can do in person, all right?
That mean...
That's the way I do business.
Yeah, All right. Don't make any
decisions now, all right?
I mean, you gotta give me that.
All right, yeah, well,
I'll be on the red-eye.
All right, see you soon.
Thank you very much.
♪ For once in my life ♪
♪ I won't let sorrow
Hurt me... ♪
I just wanted to give you
something to look at,
show you what
I'm thinking about,
percolating on for a few weeks
right now...
♪ For once I have something
I know... ♪
She is a rare thing.
There's only one of her.
♪ Anymore ♪
♪ For once I can say
This is mine ♪
♪ You can't take it ♪
♪ Long as I know I have love ♪
♪ I can make it ♪
♪ For once in my life ♪
♪ I've got Mickey ♪
♪ Who needs ♪
♪ Me ♪
Hello, Judy.
Sid?
Got time for a drink?
So I hear you got married again.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
How have the shows been?
They've been wonderful.
I'm a hit.
Well, maybe you'll make it
as a singer after all.
- I think I at least have a shot.
- Hmm.
Who's looking after the kids?
They're being looked after.
By whom?
A maid?
Maybe we, uh...
Maybe it's time we...
put all the lawyers aside.
Can't afford them either, huh?
You and I need to work out
what's best for the kids.
They need to know...
how their general
situation's gonna be.
- I'm coming back for them.
- The kids need a home.
- I can give them that.
- I know what kids need.
- They need their mother.
- They also need school,
and friends
they can rely on seeing.
No.
- Come on.
- No, Sid.
- Judy.
- No. No!
I'm working harder
than you would ever believe.
- Are you?
- And right now,
my husband is making
a deal for me
- that means I can start over.
- You're not listening.
I have someone
I can rely on now.
Someone who's helping me
make money
instead of losing it
at the track.
- Can we not...
- I'm going to get a place.
And they're going
to live with me.
I don't want them
on stage with me,
in this phony business,
and I don't want them anywhere
near the bastards who run it.
But you have to let me be with
them, Sid.
I'm a good mother.
I know you try.
That's a sneaky little jab
in the guts.
I know what a bad mother is.
I lived with one.
They love you.
They do.
They miss you,
and they wanna see you.
And they also wanna stay put.
That's what they want.
- That's the truth.
- Stay put?
- That's what they told me.
- Stay put with you.
- I see.
And I'm just supposed
to take your word for it.
- What, you think I'm an idiot?
- Judy.
You think I'm an idiot?
Do you think I'd take your word
for anything,
you lousy son of a bitch?
That my children would wanna
live anywhere that I'm not?
- Keep it down.
- It's not true!
- Keep your voice down.
I knew you were low,
but, Jesus, Sid.
No.
- Sit down.
- No.
Mickey?
Hey.
Thank God you're back.
Never again. Do you hear me?
You can't leave me like that.
- All right
- Did you miss me?
- Of course.
- Yeah?
- I got you something.
- You did?
- No.
- The shop didn't carry wrapping.
I love it. I love it.
Oh, darling, thank you.
Thank you.
What time is it?
- Uh...
- They'll be waiting for me.
Oh, the day I've had.
- What happened?
- I just...
I need a drink.
- Would you mind?
- Of course.
How was New York?
How'd it go?
You know, we need to send some
of the advance money
to my lawyer straight away.
I wanna reopen custody.
And I feel like, you know,
I should...
at least pay him something,
you know?
Um... sweetheart?
Yeah?
What's wrong?
It didn't, uh...
turn out like I wanted.
What do you mean?
The deal.
It... It didn't work out.
- I don't understand.
- Yeah.
You have to keep singing
for a while, I think.
You have more dates
at Talk of The Town.
No, I can't keep touring.
I have to go home to my kids.
I have to go home.
You promised.
- I tried my best, Judy, okay?
- No, you promised.
Look, I tried to make
something happen,
but they had other ideas,
all right?
- Why?
- I don't know.
- Yeah, why? Why, Mickey?
Showing up late,
cursing at the audience.
Their wives read about that
in the papers.
They got cold feet.
So I messed it up?
That's their opinion about it.
If you wanna know, yeah.
And what's your opinion,
Mickey?
Look, I'm sorry, okay?
I'm sorry.
I don't think
it's anybody's fault.
I think maybe I could've asked
more questions upfront.
Oh, my God.
Maybe you could have laid off
the stuff a little bit.
Oh, so you do think
it's my fault?
- I didn't say that.
- You do.
- You think it's my fault.
- Of course it's your fault!
So, uh...
what is it...
What is that you do,
anyway, Mickey?
What does that mean?
You're just like
all the other ones.
You sit on the sidelines
and you watch the show,
and you think that's making
things happen.
You think that's working.
What have you ever done
that would make anybody
wanna listen to you?
I shouldn't have come back here.
You shouldn't have come
in the first place.
I'm not gonna be here
- when you get back.
- I don't care!
Judy!
Miss Garland
to the stage, please.
Miss Garland to the stage.
Miss Garland to the stage,
please.
Miss Garland.
You're late, Miss Garland.
Miss Garland,
you should be on stage, please.
I'm here.
Hey, there's a lady up here.
London, I love you.
It's true, it's true.
- Of all the towns I've loved...
- Get off the...
...I love London best.
♪ San Francisco ♪
♪ Open your Golden Gate ♪
♪ You'll let nobody wait
Outside your door ♪
♪ San Francisco... ♪
I do have a beautiful show
for you.
I have...
I have a beautiful show
for you.
for you tonight.
I always have a beautiful show
- for you.
- Come on!
You know I do. I always have
a beautiful show for you.
Always!
Hey!
It's Mama. Hang... Hang on.
Mama?
Mama, are you there?
Hello, sweetheart.
How are you?
- I'm okay.
- Yeah?
And... And... And how's school?
I drew a really amazing
picture today, actually.
You did?
Oh, it's just...
There's a tree, and me and you
are at the bottom.
That's wonderful, darling.
I'm... I'm...
I'm proud of you.
Yeah, it was cool.
Um...
Listen, um...
I spoke with your papa.
And...
And he...
He feels that you and Joey
have a right to know
where you're going to be living
for the next few years.
And...
I agree. And...
I think...
I think that if...
If you're happy where you are,
if that's working out,
that maybe you'd like to know
that it's okay to say that.
How does that sound?
That sounds good, Mama.
Is that what you and Joe want?
Yeah.
I guess it's nice
not to move so much.
Would you be okay?
Oh, sure.
I'll be great.
I love you, okay?
I hope you know that.
Yeah.
Okay, okay.
Bye, darling.
Bye, Mama.
Well, that's all I could find
in your dressing room.
Thank you.
Well, if Delfont's going to
sue me for everything I own,
you might wanna
hold onto those...
'cause that's it.
Are you angry with me?
Not really. Just...
- You are.
- No, I just...
I wish... I wish things
had been different.
You did a very good job
trying to...
Nobody's blaming you?
No.
Everyone knows you're
impossible.
Oh, good.
So I've a little surprise
for you,
if you can bear it.
Oh, no kidding.
- It's the least we could do.
- Aw!
We can't send you off
without a cake.
Oh, it's so pretty.
No, no.
Maybe one of you should do it.
Every time I cut a cake,
I find I've married some jerk.
I'll do it.
Thank you.
It looks delicious.
- Mm.
That's good.
That's really good.
I think maybe I was just hungry.
Here's to you.
So, what's next?
Well, there'll be something.
Or maybe I'll just wait tables.
I might come with you.
Maybe we'd meet some nice
fellows who tip heavily.
Half the world
wanna take you out.
Oh, no.
The first man I ever asked out
was Mickey Rooney.
- Hmm.
I mean, you look at him now
and he's this little
bowling ball
kind of guy.
But, uh...
Oh, I was mad about him.
And he turned me down flat.
Hmm.
At least, that's how
I remember it.
Are you going to be all right?
Sure.
It's snowing outside,
which I like.
I have three beautiful children.
I have a lot to be grateful for.
Could I come back with you?
You want to see the show?
I still believe in it, you know?
The love you find
with an audience.
On a good night.
And I hear Lonnie's one hell
of a performer.
Are you sure?
Sorry, what do you mean,
Lonnie Donegan?
We bought tickets
to see Judy Garland.
- Yes.
- There's nothing I can do.
These cost an arm and a leg.
You call the manager now!
- A refund. Just get us a refund.
- Call him now!
Well, I'll be out front
if you need me.
Enjoy it.
- Thank you.
- No.
Come on, come on.
Let's get out of here.
We're done.
You wanna get some dinner?
You know, uh...
maybe we could...
I mean, listen to that.
Come on, Judes.
Really, we're done.
Maybe some other time.
- Hello.
- Hi, Lonnie.
I didn't think I'd see you here.
Oh, well, I'm just here
to watch the show.
Go, go and be wonderful.
Thank you.
That's very kind of you.
Lonnie.
Yeah?
Do you think...
Could I give them just one song?
I... I don't think
that I'll be here again,
and I didn't do so well
at my last show.
Ladies and gentlemen,
please give a very warm welcome
to tonight's Talk of The Town
headline attraction,
Mr. Lonnie Donegan.
Well, I suppose they have bought
their tickets hoping to see you.
Go on.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Knock them dead.
Well, I'm back.
Your choice.
♪ I'm gonna love you ♪
♪ Like nobody's loved you ♪
♪ Come rain
Or come shine... ♪
I know that song.
She's on, she's on.
Tickets. Tickets.
- Hurry up.
- I'm coming.
♪ Or come shine ♪
♪ I guess when you met me ♪
♪ It was just
One of those days ♪
♪ But don't ever bet me ♪
♪ 'Cause I'm gonna be true ♪
♪ If you let me ♪
♪ You're gonna love me
Like nobody's loved me ♪
♪ Come rain
Or come shine ♪
♪ Happy together
Unhappy together ♪
♪ Won't it be fine? ♪
♪ Days may be cloudy
Or sunny ♪
♪ We're in or we're out
Of the money ♪
♪ I'm with you always ♪
♪ I'm with you rain ♪
♪ Or shine ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you ♪
♪ Come rain
Or come shine ♪
♪ High as a mountain
And deep as a river ♪
♪ Come rain
Or come shine ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you
I'm gonna love you ♪
♪ I'm gonna love you... ♪
What on earth is she doing?
I don't think she can help it.
♪ I'm with you, baby ♪
♪ I'm with you always ♪
♪ Come rain or shine ♪
Bravo!
- Bravo!
Wonderful!
Thank you.
Oh, boy!
Oh! I don't know...
I don't know
what's left in there...
after that one.
But, uh...
Let's find out, shall we?
Yes!
This next one,
it isn't a song about getting
anywhere.
It's about...
walking toward somewhere
that you've dreamed of.
And maybe,
maybe the walk...
is every day of your life.
And the walking has to be
enough.
It's about hope.
And we all need that.
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ Over the rainbow ♪
♪ Way up high ♪
♪ There's a land
That I've heard of ♪
♪ Once in a lullaby ♪
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ Skies are blue ♪
♪ And the dreams
That you dare to dream ♪
♪ Really do come true ♪
♪ Someday
I'll wish upon a star ♪
♪ And wake up ♪
♪ Where the clouds
Are far behind me ♪
♪ Where troubles
Melt like lemon drops ♪
♪ Away above the chimney tops ♪
♪ That's where ♪
♪ You'll find me ♪
♪ Somewhere ♪
♪ Over the rainbow ♪
♪ Bluebirds... ♪
I'm sorry.
I can't.
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ Way up high ♪
♪ There's a land
That I heard of ♪
♪ Once in a lullaby ♪
♪ Somewhere over the rainbow ♪
♪ Skies are blue ♪
♪ And the dreams
That you dare to dream ♪
♪ Really do come true ♪
Oh! I love you all.
You won't forget me, will you?
Promise you won't.
Subtitles by explosiveskull
www.OpenSubtitles.org