This story is about Howard Beale...
...who was the Network
News anchorman on UBS TV.
In his time, Howard Beale had
been a mandarin of television.
The grand old man of news, with a HUT
rating of 16 and a 28 audience share.
In 1969, however, his
fortunes began to decline.
He fell to a 22 share.
The following year his wife died,
and he was left a childless widower...
...with an 8 rating and a 12 share.
He became morose and isolated,
began to drink heavily.
And on September 22,
1975, he was fired...
...effective in two weeks.
The news was broken to
him by Max Schumacher...
...who was the president
of the news division at UBS.
The two old friends got properly pissed.
I was at CBS with Ed Murrow in 1951.
Must've been 1950, then.
I was NBC, uh, associate
producer, Morning News.
I was just a kid, 26 years old.
Anyway...
Anyway, they were building the lower
level of the George Washington Bridge.
We were doing a remote from there.
And nobody told me.
Then after 7 in the
morning, I get a call.
"Where the hell are you? You're supposed
to be on the George Washington Bridge. "
I jump out of bed, throw
my raincoat over my pajamas.
I run down the stairs, I run
out in the street, hail a cab.
And I say to the cabby, "Take me to the
middle of the George Washington Bridge. "
And the cabbie turns
around and he says...
He says, "Don't do it, buddy.
You're a young man.
You got your whole life ahead of you. "
Didn't I ever tell you that one before?
I'm gonna kill myself.
Oh, shit, Howard.
I'm gonna blow my brains
out right on the air.
Right in the middle of the 7:00 news.
Well, you'll get a hell of a
rating, I'll guarantee you that.
-50 share easy.
- You think so?
Well, sure. We could
make a series out of it.
Suicide of the Week.
Hell. Why limit ourselves?
Execution of the Week.
Terrorist of the Week.
I love it.
Suicides.
Assassinations.
Mad bombers, Mafia hit men...
...automobile smashups.
The Death Hour.
Great Sunday night show
for the whole family.
We'll wipe that fucking
Disney right off the air.
Hmm.
Let's do the Lenin deportation
at the end of three.
That strong enough to bump?
In one then, I'll do a lead on Sara
Jane Moore to Mayberry in San Francisco.
In the film I saw, it was
the chief of detectives.
I think we've got about 10
seconds on the shooting itself.
The whole thing is 1:25.
- What does that come out? About 4:50.
We using Squeaky Fromme?
Let's do that in two.
Squeaky, Ford at the airport, bump.
Now, you using a map
going into San Francisco?
Um, I prefer our news pics.
What have we got left?
Gun control, Patty Hearst affidavit.
Guerrillas in Chad, OPEC in Vienna.
All right, fine. I'll see you later.
- Hello, Howard, how are you? Hi. Okay.
Don't forget, Howard, Ron
Nessen is now 16, okay?
Mm-hm.
The first attempt on President
Ford's life was 18 days ago...
...and again yesterday in San Francisco.
In spite of the two attempts...
...Mr. Ford says he will not become
a prisoner of the Oval Office...
...a hostage of would-be assassins.
The American people are good people:
Democrats, Independents,
Republicans and others.
How the hell you always get mixed up...
Under no circumstances will I...
...and I hope no others, capitulate...
...to those that want to undercut...
...what's all good in America.
Two, cue Howard.
Ladies and gentlemen...
...I would like to announce that I
will be retiring from this program...
...in two weeks' time
because of poor ratings.
Since this show was the only thing
I had going for me in my life...
...I have decided to kill myself.
So, what did she say?
I'm gonna blow my brains out right
on this program, a week from today.
Ten seconds to commercial.
So tune in next Tuesday.
That should give the public-relations
people a week to promote the show.
We ought to get a hell of a rating
out of that. A 50 share, easy.
Take Tellison.
- Listen.
- Uh, did you hear that?
- What was that about?
Howard just said he was going to
blow his brains out next Tuesday.
What are you talking about?
- Didn't you hear him? He just said...
- What's wrong now?
Howard just said he was going
to kill himself next Tuesday.
What do you mean, "Howard just said he
was going to kill himself next Tuesday"?
He was supposed to do
a tag on Ron Nessen...
He said, "Tune in next Tuesday.
I'm gonna shoot myself. "
What the hell's going on?
He said he was going
to blow his brains out.
What the fuck's going on, Howard?
They wanna know what
the fuck's going on.
- I can't hear you.
- Turn the studio mike on.
- We're back on in 11
seconds. Ten seconds.
Howard, what are you doing?
- Have you flipped?
- I think we better get him off.
- Get him off.
- What's the matter with you?
- Get your fucking hands off.
- Turn the sound off. He's going out live!
We're in a lot of
fucking trouble down here.
- This is the dumbest thing
I've ever seen. That's my head.
Go to standby. You dumb schmuck!
Lou, can't we clear out
that downstairs lobby?
- There must be a hundred people.
- How?
Every TV station and wire service
in the city. I could barely get in.
- Arthur, anything litigable?
- Not so far.
How many spots were wiped out?
- Frank just walked in.
We had to abort. What could we do?
He's talking to Wheeler.
Over 900 phone calls...
- ... complaining about
foul language. Shit.
Come on, Mickey, what
page are you putting it on?
Hackett just walked in.
- ABC again, they want the tape.
Tell him to go fuck himself.
That goes for you too.
You're off the air as of now.
He wants to talk to you.
- Who's replacing Beale tomorrow?
- We're flying Snowden up from Washington.
- Everybody, hold it.
Let's see how the other
networks handle this.
Ten o'clock news opened with it.
Good evening. Howard Beale,
one of television's...
They're all gonna make
it their lead story.
Howard Beale interrupted his
Network News program tonight...
...to announce that he
was gonna kill himself.
An unusual thing happened at one of
our sister networks, UBS, this evening.
How are we handling it?
Halloway's going to make a brief
statement at the end of the show...
...that Howard's been under
great personal stress, et cetera.
I'll call you back, John.
All right. We've got a
stockholders' meeting tomorrow...
...at which we're gonna announce
the restructuring-of-management plan.
I don't want this grotesque
incident to interfere with that.
I'll suggest Mr. Ruddy open with a short
statement, washing this whole thing off.
You, Max, you better
have some answers...
...for those nuts that come
to stockholders' meetings.
Mr. Beale has been under
professional and personal strain.
I've got some surprises
for you too, Schumacher.
I've had it up to here with your cruddy
division and its annual $33 million deficit!
You keep your hands off
my news division, Frank.
We're responsible to
corporate level, not you.
- Well, goddamn, we'll see about that.
- All right, take it easy.
Right now, how do we
get Beale out of here?
I understand there's at least a hundred
reporters and camera crews in the lobby.
We got a limo at the freight exit.
Howard, you're gonna spend
the night at my place.
There's bound to be press around yours.
I want Snowden here by noon.
Have Lester cover the CIA hearings...
...and give the White House to Doris.
You're late for your screening, Max.
Right. Okay.
If John Wheeler calls, switch
him to Projection Room 7.
Margot, come in here a minute.
- I'm sorry. This Beale business...
- It's all right.
Sit down. Diana asked if
she could sit in on this.
Fine. How's it going?
I think you'll like this footage better
than the stuff I showed you last time, Max.
Max Schumacher.
Goddamn it. When, Louise?
Laureen?
Well, did he say anything?
...Communist Party to be these...
All right, thank you.
...splintered underground groups?
The Communist Party believes...
...that the most pressing
political necessity today...
...is the consolidation of
the revolutionary, radical...
...and democratic movements
into a united front.
Harry, Howard Beale left my house about
20 minutes ago. Has he come in yet?
...of the bourgeois democratic state...
Well, let me know when he arrives, huh?
That's Laureen Hobbs, isn't it?
Yeah. This is from a David
Susskind thing a while back.
I think we can use some of this stuff.
...by the broadest possible coalition...
What we're going to see now is
something really sensational.
The Flagstaff Independent Bank of
Arizona was ripped off last week...
...by a terrorist group called
the Ecumenical Liberation Army.
They actually took movies of the
rip-off while they were ripping it off.
- Wait till you see it.
- The Ecumenical Liberation Army.
That's not the one that
kidnapped Patty Hearst?
No, no. That's the
Symbionese Liberation Army.
This is the Ecumenical Liberation Army.
They're the ones who kidnapped
Mary Ann Gifford three weeks ago.
There's a lot of liberation armies
in the revolutionary underground...
...and a lot of kidnapped
heiresses. This is Mary Ann Gifford.
That's the Great Ahmed
Kahn, he's their leader.
You mean, they actually
shot this film...
...while they were ripping off the bank?
Wait till you see it. I don't know
whether to edit or leave it raw like this.
This is terrific stuff.
Where did you get it?
I got everything through Laureen Hobbs.
She's my contact for all this stuff.
- Yeah? I've got Howard
on the other line.
All right, put him on.
Howard, I've got Max
on 4. Would you pick up?
- Listen, Max, I'd like another shot.
- Oh, come on, Howard.
I don't mean the whole show...
I'd just like to come on, make
some brief farewell statement...
...and then turn the
show over to Jack Snowden.
I have 11 years at this network, Max.
I have some standing in the industry.
I just don't wanna go out like a clown.
It'll be simple, dignified.
You and Harry can check the copy.
I think it'll take the
strain off the show, Max.
Well, what do you think?
Well, okay.
And no booze today, Howard.
No booze.
Summaries have been received.
We're forwarding them...
George, can, uh, you come
into my office for a minute?
Right.
- Barbara, is Tommy around anywhere?
- I think so.
I'd like to see the
two of you for a moment.
Uh, this is Bill Herron from our West
Coast Special Programs Department.
George Bosch, Barbara
Schlesinger, Tommy Pellegrino.
Look, I just saw some rough
footage of a special Bill's doing...
...on the revolutionary
underground. Most is tedious stuff...
...of Laureen Hobbs and two fatigue
jackets muttering mutilated Marxism.
But he's got about eight
minutes of a bank robbery...
...that is absolutely
sensational. Authentic stuff.
Actually shot while the
robbery was going on.
You remember the Mary
Ann Gifford kidnapping?
It's that bunch of nuts. She's in
the movie shooting off machine guns.
Really terrific footage. I think we can get
a hell of a Movie of the Week out of it...
...maybe even a series.
A series out of what?
What are we talking about?
Look, we've got a bunch
of hobgoblin radicals...
...called the Ecumenical
Liberation Army...
...who go around taking home
movies of themselves robbing banks.
And maybe they'll take movies of
themselves kidnapping heiresses...
...um, hijacking 747s, bombing
bridges, assassinating ambassadors.
We'd open each week's segment
with that authentic footage...
...hire writers to write some
story behind that footage...
...and we've got ourselves a series.
A series about a bunch of,
uh, bank-robbing guerillas?
What are we gonna call
it, The Mao Tse-Tung Hour?
- Ha, ha! Why not?
They've got Strike Force, Task
Force, SWAT, why not Che Guevara...
...and his own little mod squad?
Look, I sent you all a
concept-analysis report yesterday.
Did any of you read it?
Well, in a nutshell, it said the
American people are turning sullen.
They've been clobbered by Vietnam,
Watergate, inflation, the Depression.
They've turned off, shot up and fucked
themselves limp. And nothing helps.
So this concept-analysis report concludes
the American people want somebody...
...to articulate their rage for them.
I've been telling you people since
I took this job six months ago...
...that I want angry shows.
I don't want conventional programming
on this network, I want counterculture.
I want antiestablishment.
I don't wanna play butch
boss with you people.
When I took over this department...
...it had the worst programming
record in television history.
This network hasn't
one show in the top 20.
This network is an industry joke.
And we better start putting together
one winner for next September.
I want a show developed based on
the activities of a terrorist group.
Joseph Stalin and his
merry band of Bolsheviks.
I want ideas from you people.
That is what you're paid for.
And, by the way, the next time I send
an audience research report around...
...you'd all better read it, or I'll sack
the fucking lot of you, is that clear?
I'll be out on the
coast in, uh, four weeks.
Will you set up a meeting
with Laureen Hobbs?
Sure.
But the business of
management is management.
And at the time CCA took
control of the UBS TV Network...
...it was foundering with less than 7
percent of national television revenues...
...most network programs
being sold at station rates.
I am pleased to announce I am
submitting to the board of directors...
...a plan for the coordination
of the main profit centers.
And with the specific intention...
...of making each division
more responsive to management.
Point one.
The division producing the lowest rate
of return has been the news division...
...with its $98 million budget and its
average annual deficit of 32 million.
I know that, historically, news
divisions are expected to lose money.
But to our minds, this philosophy
is a wanton fiscal affront...
...to be resolutely resisted.
The new plan calls for local news to be
transferred to owned stations' divisions.
News radio would be transferred to
the UBS Radio Division and in effect...
...the news division would be reduced
from an independent division...
...to a department
accountable to network.
- What was that all about, Ed?
- This is not the time, Max.
Why wasn't I told about this?
Why was I led up onto that
podium and publicly humiliated...
...in front of the stockholders?
Goddamn it, I spoke to
John Wheeler this morning...
...and he assured me the
news division was safe.
That's one hell of a
way to get me to resign.
We'll talk about this tomorrow
at our regular morning meeting.
Eleven, 10... Roll VTA.
...nine, eight, seven, six.
In five, four, three, two...
One. One, cue VTA.
Cue announcer.
The UBS evening news with Howard Beale.
Ready, two?
Two, cue Howard.
Good evening. Today is
Wednesday, September the 24th...
...and this is my last broadcast.
Yesterday I announced on this program
that I was going to commit public suicide.
Admittedly an act of madness.
Well, I'll tell you what happened.
I just ran out of bullshit.
- All right, cut him off.
- Leave him on.
Am I still on the air?
If this is how he wants to go
out, this is how he goes out.
...except I just ran out of bullshit.
Mr. Schumacher's right
here. Wanna talk to him?
Bullshit is all the
reasons we give for living.
If we can't think up any reasons of
our own, we have the God bullshit.
Holy Mary, Mother of Christ.
- Tom, what is it?
...through all this pointless
pain, humiliation and decay...
...so there better be
someone who does know.
That's the God bullshit.
He's saying that life is bullshit and
it is. What are you screaming about?
Man is a noble creature that can
order his own world. Who needs God?
If there's anybody out there...
...that can look around this
slaughterhouse of a world we live in...
...and tell me that man
is a noble creature...
...believe me, that
man is full of bullshit.
- What's so goddamn funny?
- I can't help it, Harry. It's funny.
Max, this is going out
live to 67 affiliates.
Leave him on.
And I was married for 33 years
of shrill, shrieking fraud.
- Mr. Hackett's trying to get through to you.
- Tell Mr. Hackett to go fuck himself.
So I don't have any bullshit left.
I just ran out of it, you see.
Mr. Ruddy, could we have
just one statement from you?
Sorry, I don't have
all the information yet.
One question.
Could we...? If we could just
have one statement about Mr. Beale.
Max.
I'll want to see Mr. Beale after this.
The way I hear it, Max, you
were primarily responsible...
...for this colossally stupid prank.
- Is that the fact, Max?
- That's the fact.
It was unconscionable.
There doesn't seem to
be anything more to say.
I have something to say, Ed.
I want to know why that whole
debasement of the news division...
...announced at the stockholders' meeting
this afternoon was kept secret from me.
You and I go back 20 years, Ed.
I took this job with
your personal assurance...
...that you'd back my autonomy
against any encroachment.
But ever since CCA acquired control
of UBS Systems 10 months ago...
...Hackett's been
taking over everything.
Now who the hell is running this network?
You or some conglomerate called CCA?
I mean you're president
of the Systems Group...
...and Hackett's nothing
but a hatchet man for CCA.
Nelson here, president of a network...
...and he hasn't a thing to
say about anything anymore.
I told you at the
stockholders' meeting, Max...
...that we would discuss all that at
our regular meeting tomorrow morning.
If you had been patient...
...I would've explained that I
thought Frank Hackett precipitate...
...and that the reorganization
of the division...
...would not be executed until
everyone, specifically you, Max...
...had been consulted and satisfied.
Instead, you sulked off like a
child and engaged this network...
...in a shocking and
disgraceful episode.
Your position is no longer tenable...
...regardless of how
management is restructured.
I will expect your resignation
at 10:00 tomorrow morning...
...and we will coordinate our statements
to the least detriment of everyone.
Bob McDonough will take
over the news division...
...until we can sort all this out.
I'd like to see Mr. Beale now.
They're looking for him, Ed.
They don't know where he is.
Every day, five days a week for 15
years, I've been sitting behind that desk.
The dispassionate pundit...
...reporting with seemly
detachment the daily parade...
...of lunacies that constitute the news.
And just once I wanted
to say what I really felt.
Knock it off, Arthur.
It was, after all, my last...
- Did the overnight ratings come in yet?
- They're on your desk.
Have you still got
yesterday's overnights?
Shall I bring them in? Yeah.
These are those four outlines submitted
by Universal for an hour series.
You needn't bother to read
them. I'll tell them to you.
The first one is set in a large
Eastern law school, presumably Harvard.
The series is irresistibly
entitled The New Lawyers.
The running characters are a crusty
but benign ex-Supreme Court Justice...
...presumably Oliver Wendell
Holmes by way of Dr. Zorba.
There is a beautiful
girl graduate student...
...and the district attorney who is
brilliant and sometimes cuts corners.
Next one.
The second one is
called The Amazon Squad.
Lady cops?
The running characters include
a crusty but benign lieutenant...
...who's always getting
heat from the commissioner...
...a hard-drinking detective who
thinks women belong in the kitchen...
...and a brilliant and
beautiful young girl cop...
- ... who's fighting the feminist
battle. We're up to our ears in lady cops.
The next is another one of those
investigative reporter shows.
A crusty but benign managing
editor who's always...
You know, Barbara...
...the Arabs have decided to jack up
the price of oil another 20 percent.
Uh, the CIA has been caught
opening Senator Humphrey's mail.
There's a civil war in
Angola, another one in Beirut.
The... New York City's
still facing default.
They finally caught up
with Patricia Hearst.
And the whole front page of
the Daily News is Howard Beale.
There's also a two-column
story on Page 1 of the Times.
Helen, call Mr. Hackett's office.
See if he can give me a
few minutes this morning.
KTNS, Kansas City, refuses to carry
our Network News show anymore...
...unless Beale is taken off the air.
Did you see the overnights
on the Network News?
It has an eight in New York, a nine
in L.A. and a 27 share in both cities.
Last night Howard Beale went on the air
and yelled "bullshit" for two minutes...
...and I can tell you right now that
tonight's show will get a 30 share, at least.
I think we've lucked into something.
For God's sakes. Are you suggesting
that we put that lunatic...
...back on the air yelling "bullshit"?
I think we should put Beale back
on the air tonight and keep him on.
Did you see the news this
morning? Did you see the Times?
We've got press on this you couldn't
buy for a million dollars. Frank.
That dumb show jumped five
rating points in one night.
Tonight's show has gotta be at least 15.
We just increased our audience by
20 or 30 million people in one night.
You're not gonna get
this dumped in your lap...
...for the rest of your
days. You can't piss it away.
Howard Beale said what
every American feels...
...that he's tired of all the bullshit.
He's articulating the popular rage.
I want that show, Frank. I can turn that
show into the biggest smash on television.
What do you mean? It's a news
show. It's not your department.
I see Howard Beale as
a latter-day prophet.
A magnificent, messianic figure inveighing
against the hypocrisies of our times.
A strip Savonarola,
Monday through Friday...
...that I tell you, Frank,
could just go through the roof...
...and I'm talking about
a $6 cost per thousand show.
I'm talking about a hundred...
A 130,000-dollar minutes.
Do you wanna figure out the
revenues of a strip show...
...that sells for
100,000 bucks a minute?
One show like that could pull
this network out of the hole.
Frank, it's being handed to us
on a plate. Let's not blow it.
Yes?
Tell him I'll be a few minutes.
Let me think it over.
Frank, let's not go to committee
on this. It's 20 after 10.
We want Beale in that studio.
We don't wanna lose the momentum.
For God's sake, Diana...
...we're talking about putting a manifestly
irresponsible man on national television.
I'd like to talk to Legal Affairs
at least and Herb Thackeray...
...and certainly Joe Donnelly
in Standards and Practices.
And you know, I'm going to be eyeball
to eyeball with Mr. Ruddy on this.
If I'm going to the mat with Ruddy, I
wanna make sure of some of my ground.
I'm the one whose ass
is going on the line.
I'll get back to you, Diana.
I don't believe this. I
don't believe the top brass...
...of a national television network
are sitting around their salads...
The top brass of a bankrupt
national television network...
...with projected losses
of close to $150 million.
I don't care how bankrupt.
You can't be seriously proposing, and
the rest of us seriously considering...
...putting on a pornographic
Network News show.
- The FCC'd kill us.
- Sit down, Nelson.
The FCC can't do anything
except rap our knuckles.
I don't even wanna think about
the litigious possibilities, Frank.
- Could be up to our ears in lawsuits.
- The affiliates won't carry it.
Affiliates will kiss your ass,
if you can hand them a hit show.
The popular reaction...
We don't know the popular
reaction. We have to find out.
The New York Times...
The New York Times doesn't
advertise on our network.
All I know is this violates every
canon of respectable broadcasting.
We're not a respectable network.
We're a whorehouse network.
We have to take whatever we can get.
Well, I don't want any part of it.
I don't fancy myself the
president of a whorehouse.
That's very commendable of
you, Nelson. Now, sit down.
Your indignation has been duly
recorded. You can always resign tomorrow.
Now look, what in
substance are we proposing?
Merely to add editorial comment
to our Network News show.
Brinkley, Sevareid, Reasoner,
all have their comments.
Now Howard Beale will have his.
I think we ought to give it a shot.
Let's see what happens tonight.
Telephone, please.
I don't wanna be the messenger
that has to tell Max Schumacher.
Max doesn't work at
this network anymore.
Mr. Ruddy fired him last night.
Bob McDonough's running
the news division now.
Bob McDonough in News, please.
Oh, I don't know.
I may teach or I may write a book...
...whatever the hell one
does when one approaches...
...the autumn of one's years.
My God, is that me?
- Was I ever that young?
- Ha, ha.
No. Howard just brought in
a picture of Ed Murrow...
...and the whole CBS
gang when we were there.
You wouldn't believe it.
Walter Cronkite, Harry
Reasoner, Hollenbeck, Bob Trout.
- Is that you,
Howard? - Mm-hm.
Yeah.
- Okay, Dick, we'll be in touch. Right.
- You remember this kid?
He's the kid I think you once sent out to
interview Cleveland Amory on vivisection.
What's so funny?
So I jump out of bed in my pajamas,
I grab my raincoat, I run downstairs.
I run out in the
street and I hail a cab.
And I jumped in and
I yell at the driver:
"Take me to the middle of the
George Washington Bridge. "
And the driver turns around and he
says: "Don't do it, buddy, don't do it.
You're young, you got your
whole life ahead of you. "
Ha-ha-ha! Wait a
minute! Wait a minute!
If you think that's funny...
No, if you think that's
funny, wait till you hear this.
I've just come back from
Frank Hackett's office.
He wants to put Howard on the air.
- You're kidding.
- Apparently...
...the ratings went up
five points last night...
...and he wants Howard to go back
on and do his angry-man thing.
What are you talking about?
I'm telling you. They want Howard
to go back on and yell "bullshit. "
They want Howard to go on
spontaneously letting out his anger.
A latter-day prophet denouncing
the hypocrisies of our times.
Hey, that sounds pretty good.
Who's this "they"?
Hackett. Chaney was there.
The Legal Affairs guy.
Oh, and that girl from Programming.
Christensen? What's
she got to do with this?
You're kidding, aren't you?
- I'm not kidding.
I told them. I said:
"Look, we're running a news
department, not a circus.
And Howard Beale's not a bearded lady.
If you think I'm gonna go along
with this bastardization...
...you can have my resignation along
with Max Schumacher's right now.
I think I'm speaking for Howard
Beale and everybody else... "
That's my job you're turning down.
I'd go nuts without some kind of work.
What's wrong with being an angry prophet
denouncing the hypocrisies of our times?
What do you think, Max?
Do you want to be an angry prophet
denouncing the hypocrisies of our times?
Yeah, I think I'd like to be an angry prophet
denouncing the hypocrisies of our times.
Then grab it. Grab it!
- Afternoon, Mr. Ruddy.
- Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, Mr. Ruddy.
- He's waiting for you,
Mr. Ruddy. Thank you.
Nelson Chaney tells me Beale may
actually go on the air this evening.
As far as I know,
Howard's going to do it.
You going to sit still for this, Ed?
Yes. I think Hackett's
overstepped himself.
There's some kind of corporate
maneuvering going on, Max.
Hackett is clearly
forcing a confrontation.
That would account for his behavior
at the stockholders' meeting.
However, I think he's making a serious
mistake with this Beale business.
I suspect CCA will be upset
at Hackett's presumptuousness.
Certainly Mr. Jensen will.
So I'm going to let Hackett
have his head for a while.
He just might lose it
over this Beale business.
I'd like you to reconsider
your resignation, Max.
I assume that Hackett
wouldn't take such steps...
...without some support
on the CCA board.
I'll have to go directly to Mr. Jensen.
When that happens, I'm going
to need every friend I've got.
And I certainly don't want Hackett's
people in all of the divisional positions.
So I'd like you to stay on, Max.
Of course, Ed.
Thank you, Max.
This has been the UBS evening
news with Howard Beale.
The initial response to the new
Howard Beale Show was not auspicatory.
The press was without exception hostile
and the industry reaction negative.
The ratings for the Thursday
and Friday shows were both 14.
But Monday's rating dropped a point...
...clearly suggesting the
novelty was wearing off.
Did you know there are
a number of psychics...
...working as licensed
brokers on Wall Street?
Some of them counsel their
clients by use of tarot cards.
They're all pretty successful, even
in a bear market and selling short.
I met one of them last week and
thought of doing a show around her.
The Wayward Witch of Wall
Street, something like that.
If her tips were any good,
she could wreck the market.
So I called her this morning and asked
her how she was on predicting the future.
She said she was occasionally prescient.
For example, she said:
"I just had a fleeting vision of you...
...sitting in an office with
a craggy middle-aged man...
...with whom you are, or will
be, emotionally involved. "
And here I am.
And she does all this with tarot cards?
No. This one operates on parapsychology.
She has trance-like episodes and
feels things in her energy field.
I think this lady could
be very useful to you, Max.
- In what way?
- Well...
...you put on a news show and
here's somebody who can predict...
...tomorrow's news for you.
Her name, aptly enough, is Sibyl.
Sibyl the Soothsayer.
You could give her two minutes of trance
at the end of a Howard Beale Show...
...say, once a week, Friday...
...which is suggestively
occult, and she could oraculate.
Then next week everyone tunes in to
see how good her predictions were.
Maybe she could do the weather.
Your Network News is going to need
some help, Max, if it's gonna hold.
Beale doesn't do the
angry-man thing well at all.
He's too, uh, kvetchy. He's being irascible.
We want a prophet, not a curmudgeon.
He should do more apocalyptic doom.
I think you should take on a couple of
writers to write some jeremiads for him.
I see you don't fancy my suggestions.
Hell, you're not serious, are you?
Oh, I'm serious.
The fact is I could make your Beale
Show the highest-rated news show...
...in television, if you'd
let me have a crack at it.
- What do you mean, "have a crack at it"?
- I'd like to program it for you. Develop it.
I wouldn't interfere with the actual
news itself, but TV is showbiz, Max.
And even the news has to
have a little showmanship.
My God, you are serious.
Oh. I watched your 6:00 news
today. It's straight tabloid.
You had a minute and a half of that
lady riding a bike naked in Central Park.
You had less than a minute of hard
national and international news.
It was all sex, scandal,
brutal crimes, sports...
...children with incurable
diseases and lost puppies.
I don't think I'll listen to any protestations
of high standards of journalism...
...when you're soliciting
audiences like the rest of us.
All I'm saying is, if you're
gonna hustle, at least do it right.
I'm gonna bring this up
at tomorrow's meeting.
I don't like network hassles. I was
hoping you and I could work this out.
Now that's why I'm here.
And I was hoping that you were
looking for an emotional involvement...
...with a craggy middle-aged man.
Oh, I wouldn't rule that out entirely.
All right, Diana.
You bring up all your ideas
at the meeting tomorrow...
...because if you don't, I will.
I think Howard's making a
goddamn fool of himself...
...and so does everybody that
Howard and I know in this industry.
It was a fluke. It didn't work.
So tomorrow, Howard goes
back to the old format...
...and all of this gutter
depravity comes to an end.
Okay.
I don't get it, Diana.
You hung around until 7:30 and
then came all the way down here...
...just to pitch a couple
of loony showbiz ideas...
...when you knew goddamn well I'd
laugh you right out of the office.
I don't get it.
What's your scam in this?
Max, my little visit here tonight...
...was a gesture made out of
your stature in the industry...
...and because I personally admired you
since I was a kid majoring in speech...
...at the University of Missouri.
Sooner or later, with or without you...
...I'm going to take over
your Network News show...
...and I figured I might
as well start tonight.
I, uh, think I once gave a lecture...
...at the University of Missouri.
I was in the audience.
I had a terrible schoolgirl crush
on you for a couple of months.
If we could get back for
a moment to that gypsy...
...who predicted all that about, uh,
emotional involvements and middle-aged men.
What are you doing for dinner tonight?
I can't make it tonight,
love. Call me tomorrow.
- Do you have a favorite restaurant?
- I eat anything.
Son of a bitch, I get a
feeling I'm being made.
You are.
Ah, I've got to warn you, I don't
do anything on my first date.
We'll see.
Schmuck, what are you getting into?
I was married for four years
and pretended to be happy...
...and had six years of analysis
and pretended to be sane.
My husband ran off with his boyfriend...
...and I had an affair with my analyst.
He told me I was the
worst lay he'd ever had.
I can't tell you how many men
have told me what a lousy lay I am.
I apparently have a
masculine temperament.
I arouse quickly,
consummate prematurely...
...and can't wait to get my clothes
back on and get out of that bedroom.
I seem to be inept at
everything except my work.
I'm good at my work. So
I confine myself to that.
All I want out of life is
a 30 share and a 20 rating.
You're married, surely?
Twenty-five years.
I have a married daughter in
Seattle who's six months pregnant...
...a younger girl who's starting
at Northwestern in January.
Well, Max, here we are.
Middle-aged man reaffirming
his middle-aged manhood...
...and a terrified young
woman with a father complex.
What sort of script do you
think we can make out of this?
Corridor gossip, uh, says that you
are Frank Hackett's backstage girl.
Ha, ha. I'm not.
Frank is a corporation
man, body and soul.
He has no loves, lusts or allegiances
that are not consummately directed...
...toward becoming a CCA board member.
So why should he bother with
me? I'm not even a stockholder.
What about your loves,
lusts and allegiances?
Is your wife in town?
Yes.
Well, then, we better go to my place.
I can't hear you. You will
have to talk a little louder.
Yes. I hear you.
Yes.
Why me?
I said, "Why me?"
Okay.
Howard in his office?
Oh, Harry, I'm killing this whole
screwball, angry-prophet thing.
- Tonight we go back to straight news.
- Okay.
Fifteen seconds, 14, 13...
Yeah? What?
Max, I'm telling you, he's
fine. He's been sharp all day.
He's been funny as hell. Had everybody
cracking up at the rundown meeting.
I told him. I told him.
Up. Cue VTA.
Ready, two.
Cue announcer.
The UBS Evening News with Howard Beale.
Take 2, cue Howard.
Last night, I was awakened
from a fitful sleep...
...shortly after 2:00 in the morning...
...by a shrill,
sibilant, faceless voice.
I couldn't make it out at
first in the dark bedroom...
...and I said, "I'm sorry, you
will have to talk a little louder. "
- What do you want me to do?
- Nothing.
And the voice said to me, "I want
you to tell the people the truth.
Not an easy thing to do because
the people don't want to know. "
And I said, "You're kidding.
What the hell should I
know about the truth?"
But the voice said to me,
"Don't worry about the truth.
I will put the words in your mouth. "
I said, "What's this, the Burning
Bush? For God's sake, I'm not Moses. "
The voice said to me, "And I'm not
God. What has that got to do with it?"
The voice said to me:
"We're not talking about eternal
or absolute or ultimate truth.
We're talking about impermanent,
transient, human truth.
I don't expect you people
to be capable of truth...
...but at least you're
capable of self-preservation. "
And I said, "Why me?"
And the voice said, "Because
you're on television, dummy.
Beautiful.
You have 40 million
Americans listening to you.
After this show, you could have 50.
I'm not asking you to walk the land
in sackcloth, preaching the Armageddon.
You're on TV, man. "
So I thought about it for a moment...
...and then I said, "Okay. "
Close the door, Harry.
Howard, I'm taking you off the air.
I think you're having a
breakdown. Require treatment.
This is not a psychotic episode.
This is a cleansing moment of clarity.
I'm imbued, Max.
I'm imbued with some special spirit.
It's not a religious feeling at all.
It's a shocking eruption
of great electrical energy.
I feel vivid and
flashing, as if suddenly...
...I'd been plugged into some
great electromagnetic field.
I feel connected to all living things.
To flowers...
...birds, all the
animals of the world...
...and even to some
great unseen living force.
What I think the Hindus call prana.
It is not a breakdown.
I've never felt more orderly in my life.
It is a shattering and
beautiful sensation.
It is the exalted flow of
the space-time continuum...
...save that it is
spaceless and timeless and...
...of such loveliness.
I feel on the verge of
some great ultimate truth.
And you will not take me off the air
for now, or for any other spaceless time.
Oh, boy.
Is he okay? He's just fainted.
I'd better get him back
to my house again tonight.
Help me get him up.
Everyone's going crazy.
The whole place has gone crazy.
Sitting in their house and
they don't do anything about it.
Wake up, Max, because Howard's gone.
I'll make you some coffee.
You don't know where he is?
The son of a bitch is a hit,
goddamn it! Over 2000 phone calls.
Go down to the mail room. As of
this minute, over 14,000 telegrams!
The response is sensational! Tell him.
Herb's phone hasn't stopped ringing.
Every goddamned affiliate
from Albuquerque to Sandusky.
The response is sensational!
Yes. All right. For you,
Herb. Get back to your office.
Moldanian called me.
Joe Donnelly called me.
We got a goddamn hit, goddamn
it. Diana, show him the Times.
We got an editorial in the
holy goddamn New York Times.
- "A call to morality. "
- I don't know where he is.
That son of a bitch Beale has caught on.
- Don't tell me you don't know.
- Could be jumping off a roof for all I know.
The man is insane. He's
not responsible for himself.
He needs care and treatment.
And all you grave robbers
think about is that he's a hit.
You know, Max, it's just
possible that he isn't insane.
That he is, in fact, imbued
with some special spirit.
My God, I'm supposed
to be the romantic...
...you're the hard-bitten realist.
All right. Howard Beale
obviously fills a void.
The audience out there wants a
prophet, even a manufactured one...
...even if he's as mad as Moses.
By tomorrow he'll have a
50 share, maybe even a 60.
Howard Beale is processed, instant God.
It looks like he may just go
bigger than Mary Tyler Moore.
I am not putting Howard back on the air.
It's not your show
anymore, Max, it's mine.
I gave her the show, Schumacher.
I'm putting the Network
News show under programming.
Mr. Ruddy has had a mild heart
attack and is not taking calls.
In his absence, I'm making
all network decisions...
...including one I've been
wanting to make a long time.
You're fired. I want you
out of this building by noon.
I'll call the security guards and have
you thrown out, if you're still here.
Well, let's say, "Fuck you, Hackett. "
You want me out, you're gonna have to
drag me out kicking and screaming...
...and the whole
division kicking with me!
Gonna quit their jobs for
you? Not in this recession.
When Ruddy gets back
he'll have your ass.
I got a hit, Schumacher, and
Ruddy doesn't count anymore.
He was hoping I'd fall on my face
with this Beale Show, but I didn't.
It's a big, fat, big-titted hit and I don't
have to waffle around with Ruddy anymore.
If he wants to take me up
before the CCA Board, let him.
Think Ruddy is stupid enough
to go to the CCA Board and say:
"I'm taking our one
hit show off the air"?
And comes November 14, I'm
going to be standing up there...
...at the annual CCA management meeting.
I'm gonna announce projected
earnings for this network...
...for the first time in five years.
And believe me, Mr. Jensen's going to be
sitting there rocking back and forth...
...in his little chair and he's going to
say: "That's very good, Frank, keep it up. "
Don't have any illusions about who's
running this network. You're fired!
I want you out of your office before
noon or I'll have you thrown out.
You go along with this?
Max, I told you I didn't
want a network hassle on this.
I told you I'd much rather work the
Beale Show out just between the two of us.
Well, let's just say,
"Fuck you too, honey. "
Howard Beale may be my best
friend. I'll go to court.
I'll put him in a hospital before
I'll let you exploit him like a freak.
You get your psychiatrists,
I'll get mine.
I'm gonna spread this whole reeking
business in every newspaper...
...on every network, group
and affiliate in this country.
- I'm gonna make a lot of noise about this.
- Great. We need all the press we can get.
Something going on
between you and Schumacher?
Not anymore.
- How do you do, Mr. Beale?
- I must make my witness.
Sure thing, Mr. Beale.
Oil ministers of the OPEC nations
meeting in Vienna still haven't decided...
...how much more to
increase the price of oil.
- Ready, VTA?
- Yeah. Okay.
He came in the building
about five minutes ago.
Tell Snowden when he
comes in to let him go on.
Did you get that, Paul?
Six, five, four, three, two...
- ... one. VTA?
This has been the most divisive
meeting the oil states have ever had.
The 13 nations of OPEC have still
not been able to decide by how much...
...to increase the price
of oil. Saudi Arabian...
How much time we got?
...yesterday for further
consultations with his government.
He returned to the Vienna...
- This is Ed Fletcher in Vienna.
- Take two, cue Howard.
I don't have to tell you things are
bad, everybody knows things are bad.
It's a depression.
Everybody's out of work or
scared of losing their job.
The dollar buys a nickel's worth.
Banks are going bust. Shopkeepers
keep a gun under the counter.
Punks are running wild in the streets.
There's nobody anywhere who seems to
know what to do, and there's no end to it.
We know the air is unfit to breathe
and our food is unfit to eat.
We sit watching our TVs while
some local newscaster tells us...
...that today we had 15
homicides and 63 violent crimes...
...as if that's the way it's supposed
to be. We know things are bad.
Worse than bad, they're crazy.
Everything everywhere is going
crazy, so we don't go out anymore.
We sit in the house and the world
we're living in is getting smaller...
...and all we say is, "Please, at least
leave us alone in our living rooms.
Let me have my toaster and my
TV, and my steel-belted radials...
...and I won't say anything.
Just leave us alone!"
Well, I'm not gonna leave you
alone. I want you to get mad!
I don't want you to protest, to riot.
Don't write to your congressmen.
I wouldn't know what to tell you.
I don't know what to do
about the depression...
...and the Russians, and
the crime in the street.
All I know is that first,
you've got to get mad.
You've got to say, "I'm a human
being, goddamn it. My life has value. "
So I want you to get up now.
I want all of you to get
up out of your chairs.
I want you to get up right
now and go to the window...
...open it and stick
your head out and yell:
"I'm as mad as hell and I'm
not gonna take this anymore!"
- I want you to get up right now, get up...
- Stay with him.
...go to your windows, open them
and stick your head out and yell:
"I'm as mad as hell and I'm
not going to take this anymore!"
- Things have got to change...
- How many stations does this go to?
Sixty-seven. It goes to
Louisville and Atlanta.
"We're not going to take this!"
Then we'll figure out the
depression and the inflation...
...and the oil crisis, but first
get up out of your chairs...
...open the window, stick your
head out and yell and say it!
"I'm as mad as hell and I'm
not gonna take this anymore!"
- Who are you talking
to, Herb? WCGG, Atlanta.
- They yelling in Atlanta?
- Are they yelling in Atlanta?
But first you've got to
get mad. You've gotta say:
"I'm mad as hell and I'm not
going to take this anymore!"
They're yelling in
Baton Rouge. Goddamn it.
Get up, get up out of your chairs.
Son of a bitch, we
struck the mother lode!
Stick your head out of the
window, stick your head out.
And keep yelling and yell:
"I'm as mad as hell. I'm
not gonna take this anymore!"
Just get up from your chairs,
right now, go to the window!
- Where you going?
- I wanna see if anybody's yelling.
Open it, and stick your head
out, and yell, and keep yelling...
I'm as mad as hell and I'm
not gonna take this anymore!
not gonna take it anymore!
I'm as mad as hell and I'm
I'm as mad as hell. I'm
not gonna take it anymore!
I'm as mad as hell and I'm
not gonna take it anymore.
I'm not gonna take it
anymore. I'm mad as hell!
I'm mad as hell!
I'm mad as hell! I'm not
gonna take this anymore.
By mid-October...
...the Howard Beale Show had
settled in on a 42 share...
...more than equaling all the
other network news shows combined.
In the Nielsen ratings,
the Howard Beale Show...
...was listed as the fourth
highest rated show of the month...
...surpassed only by The
Six Million Dollar Man...
...All in the Family and Phyllis.
A phenomenal state of
affairs for a news show.
And on October 15, Diana
Christensen flew to Los Angeles...
...for what the trade
calls powwows and confabs...
...with our West Coast
programming execs...
...and to get production rolling
on the shows for the coming season.
Christ.
You brought half the William Morris
West Coast office along with you.
Hi, I'm Diana Christensen, a racist
lackey of the imperialist ruling circles.
I'm Laureen Hobbs, a
bad-ass commie nigger.
Sounds like the basis of a firm
friendship. We're gonna need more chairs.
- Anybody want coffee? I'd love some.
You changed your tailor.
Coffee? Okay.
Want to come take some coffee orders?
This is my lawyer, Sam Haywood,
and his associate, Merrill Grant.
Ms. Christensen, just what
the hell's this all about?
Because when a national
television network...
...in the person of
booby here, comes to me...
...and says they want to put the ongoing
struggle of the oppressed masses...
...on prime-time television,
I have to regard this askance.
What Mr. Haywood was saying, Ms.
Christensen, was that our client...
...Ms. Hobbs, wants it up-front that
the political content of the show...
...has to be entirely in her control.
She can have it. I don't give a
damn about the political content.
- What kind of show did you have in mind?
- I'm interested in a weekly dramatic series...
...based on the Ecumenical Liberation
Army. And I'll tell you right now...
...what the first show has to
be: a special on Mary Ann Gifford.
Let me tell you what I want.
I want a lot more film like the
bank rip-off the Ecumenical sent in.
The way I see the series is...
...each week we open with an
authentic act of political terrorism...
...taken on the spot,
in the actual moment.
Then we go to the drama behind
the opening film footage.
That's your job, Ms. Hobbs.
You gotta get the Ecumenicals to
bring in that film footage for us.
The network can't deal with them directly.
They are, after all, wanted criminals.
The Ecumenical Liberation
Army is an ultra-left sect...
...creating political confusion with wildcat
violence and pseudo-insurrectionary acts...
...which the Communist
Party does not endorse.
The American masses are not
yet ready for open revolt.
We would not want to
produce a television show...
...celebrating historically
deviational terrorism.
I'm offering an hour of
prime-time television every week...
...into which you can
stick whatever propaganda.
The Ecumenicals are an
undisciplined ultra-left gang...
...whose leader is an
eccentric, to say the least.
He calls himself the Great Ahmed
Kahn and wears a hussar's shako.
Ms. Hobbs, we're talking about
30 to 50 million people a shot.
It's a lot better than handing out...
...mimeographed pamphlets
on ghetto street corners.
I'll have to take this matter
to the central Committee...
...and I'd better check it
out with the Great Ahmed Kahn.
I'll be in L.A. until Saturday,
and I'd like to get it rolling.
Okay?
Well, Ahmed, you ain't
gonna believe this.
But I'm gonna make a TV star out of you.
Just like Archie Bunker.
You gonna be a household word.
What the fuck are you talking about?
Thirty seconds. All right, ready VTA.
One, you have the audience to pan.
- Two, you have the window to pull. Twenty
- five.
Three, you're on the announcer.
Twenty.
Stand by, VTA.
Fifteen, 14, 13, 12...
- ... eleven, 10, nine,
eight, seven... Roll VTA.
...six, five, four, three...
- ... two, one. Three, cue announcer.
Ladies and gentlemen, let's
hear it. How do you feel?
We're mad as hell and we're
not going to take this anymore!
Ladies and gentlemen, the Network
News Hour with Sibyl the Soothsayer!
Jim Webbing and his
It's-the-Emes Truth Department.
Ms. Mata Hari and her
Skeletons in the Closet.
And tonight, another
segment of Vox Populi.
And starring the Mad Prophet
of the Airways, Howard Beale!
Edward George Ruddy died today.
Edward George Ruddy was
the chairman of the board...
...of the Union Broadcasting Systems
and he died at 11:00 this morning...
...of a heart condition, and woe
is us, we're in a lot of trouble.
So a rich little man
with white hair died.
What has that got to do with
the price of rice, right?
And why is that woe to us?
Because you people...
...and 62 million other Americans
are listening to me right now.
Because less than 3 percent
of you people read books.
Because less than 15 percent
of you read newspapers.
Because the only truth you know
is what you get over this tube.
Right now, there is a whole
and entire generation...
...that never knew anything that
didn't come out of this tube.
This tube is the Gospel.
The ultimate revelation.
This tube can make or break
presidents, popes, prime ministers!
This tube is the most
awesome goddamn force...
...in the whole godless world!
And woe is us if it ever falls
into the hands of the wrong people.
And that's why woe is us
that Edward George Ruddy died.
Because this company is
now in the hands of CCA...
...the Communication
Corporation of America.
There's a new chairman. A
man called Frank Hackett...
...sitting in Mr. Ruddy's
office on the 20th floor!
And when the 12th largest
company in the world...
...controls the most awesome,
goddamn propaganda force...
...in the whole godless world...
...who knows what shit will be
peddled for truth on this network.
So you listen to me. Listen to
me! Television is not the truth.
Television's a goddamned amusement park.
Television is a circus, a carnival,
a traveling troupe of acrobats...
...storytellers, dancers, singers,
jugglers, sideshow freaks, lion-tamers...
...and football players. We're
in the boredom-killing business.
So if you want the truth, go to God.
Go to your gurus.
Go to yourselves.
Because that's the only place you're
ever gonna find any real truth.
But, man, you're never
gonna get any truth from us.
We'll tell you anything you
want to hear. We lie like hell.
We'll tell you that, uh,
Kojak always gets the killer...
...and that nobody ever gets
cancer in Archie Bunker's house.
No matter how much trouble
the hero is in, don't worry...
...just look at your watch, at
the end of the hour he's gonna win!
We'll tell you any
shit you want to hear.
We deal in illusions,
man. None of it is true.
But you people sit there, day
after day, night after night...
...all ages, colors, creeds.
We're all you know.
You're beginning to believe the
illusions we're spinning here.
You're beginning to think the tube is
reality and that your own lives are unreal.
You do whatever the tube tells you.
Dress like the tube,
you eat like the tube...
...raise your children like the
tube, you think like the tube.
This is mass madness, you maniacs.
In God's name, you
people are the real thing.
We are the illusion.
So turn off your television
sets. Turn them off now.
Turn them off right now. Turn
them off and leave them off.
Turn them off right in the middle of
the sentence I'm speaking to you now.
Turn them off!
UBS was running at a cash
flow break-even point...
...after taking into
account $110 million...
...of negative cash
flow from the network.
It was clear the fat on the
network had to be flitched off.
Please note an increase in projected
initial programming revenues...
...in the amount of $21 million...
...due to the phenomenal
success of the Howard Beale Show.
I expect a positive cash flow for
the entire complex of 45 million...
...achievable in this fiscal year,
a year, in short, ahead of schedule.
I go beyond that.
This network may well be the
most significant profit center...
...of the communications complex.
And based upon the projected rate
of return on invested capital...
...and if merger is
eventually accomplished...
...the communications
complex may well become...
...the towering and
most profitable center...
...in the entire CCA empire.
I await your questions and comments.
Mr. Jensen?
Very good, Frank. Exemplary. Keep it up.
Buy you a cup of coffee?
Hell, yes.
- Do you have to get back to the office?
- Nothing that can't wait.
I...
I drop down to the news
studios every now and then...
...and ask Howard Beale about you,
and he says you're doing fine. Are you?
No.
- Are you keeping busy?
- Oh, in a fashion.
This is the, uh, third funeral
I've been to in two weeks.
I have two other friends in the
hospital whom I visit regularly...
...and, uh, been to a
couple of christenings.
All my friends seem to be
dying or having grandchildren.
You should be a grandfather
yourself about now.
You have a pregnant daughter
in Seattle, don't you?
Any day now. My wife's
out there for the occasion.
I've thought many times of calling you.
I wish you had.
You know, I bumped into Sibyl the
Soothsayer in the elevator last week.
I said, "You know, Sibyl, about
four months ago you predicted...
...I would get involved with
a craggy, middle-aged man...
...and so far, all that's happened
has been one many-splendored night.
I don't call that 'getting involved. "'
And she said, "Don't worry, you will. "
It was a many-splendored
night, wasn't it, Max?
Yes, it was.
Are we going to get involved, Max?
Yes.
I need to become involved
very much. How about you?
I've reached for the phone
to call you a hundred times.
I was sure you hated me for my
part in taking your news show away.
I probably did. I don't know anymore.
All I know is, I can't
get you out of my mind.
Marty. Marty, I know
what NBC offered them...
...so I'm saying go to 3.5...
...and I want an option for
a third run on all of them.
Marty, I'm in a big hurry and you and
Charlie are supposed to be negotiating this...
...so goodbye, good
luck, I'll see you Monday.
Jimmy Caan's agent just
called and says absolutely nix.
Can't win them all.
- Where can I reach you later?
You can't. I'll be gone all weekend.
NBC's offering $3.25 mil...
...per package of five
James Bond movies...
...and I think I'm gonna steal them
for $3.5 million with a third run.
And I'm gonna stick The
Mao Tse-Tung Hour in at 8...
...because we're having a lot of
trouble selling The Mao Tse-Tung Hour.
This way...
That Mao Tse-Tung Hour's turning
into one big pain in the ass.
We're having heavy legal problems
with the federal government right now.
Two FBI guys turned up in
Hackett's office last week...
...and served us with a subpoena.
They heard about our Flagstaff
bank rip-off film and they want it.
Hackett told the FBI to fuck off.
No, but we're getting around the FBI...
...by doing the show in
collaboration with the news division.
We're standing on the First
Amendment, Freedom of the Press...
...and the right to protect our sources.
Walter thinks we can knock out the
misprision of felony charge. Ha, ha.
But he says absolutely
nix on going to series.
They'll hit us with conspiracy
and inducement to commit a crime.
Christ, it's cold in here.
See, we're paying these nuts from
the Ecumenical Liberation Army...
...$10,000 a week in order to
turn in authentic film footage...
...of their revolutionary activities...
...and that can constitute
inducement to commit a crime.
And Walter says we'll all
wind up in federal prison.
I said, "Walter, let
the government sue us.
Let the federal government sue us.
We'll take them to the Supreme Court.
We'll be front page, mm, for months.
The New York Times and
The Washington Post...
...will be writing two
editorials a week about us.
We'll be front page for months. We'll
have more press than Watergate. "
All I need is six weeks'
federal litigation...
...and The Mao Tse-Tung Hour can
start carrying its own time slot.
What's really bugging me now
is my daytime programming.
NBC's got a lock on daytime...
...with their lousy game shows...
...and I'd like to bust them.
I'm thinking of doing
a homosexual soap opera.
The Dykes.
The heart-rendering saga about
a woman hopelessly in love...
...with her husband's
mistress. What do you think?
How long has it been going on?
A month.
I thought it was a transient
thing, blow over in a week.
And I still pray to God it's
just a menopausal infatuation.
But it is an infatuation, Louise.
There's no sense in my saying I
won't see her again, because I will.
Do you want me to leave?
Check into a hotel?
Do you love her?
I don't know how I feel.
I'm grateful I can feel anything.
I know I'm obsessed with her.
Then say it.
Don't keep telling me that you're
obsessed, that you're infatuated.
Say that you're in love with her.
I'm in love with her.
Then get out!
Go anywhere you want. Go to a hotel,
go live with her, but don't come back.
Because after 25 years...
...of building a home and raising a
family and all the senseless pain...
...that we have inflicted on each other,
I'm damned if I'm gonna stand here...
...and have you tell me you're
in love with somebody else.
Because this isn't a convention
weekend with your secretary, is it?
Or some broad that you picked
up after three belts of booze.
This is your great
winter romance, isn't it?
Your last roar of passion before
you settle into your emeritus years.
Is that what's left for me?
Is that my share? She gets the
winter passion and I get the dotage.
What am I supposed to do?
Am I supposed to sit home knitting
and purling while you slink back...
...like some penitent drunk?
I'm your wife, damn it.
If you can't work up a
winter passion for me...
...the least I require
is respect and allegiance.
I hurt, don't you understand that?
I hurt badly.
Oh, say something, for God's sake.
I've got nothing to say.
I won't give you up easily, Max.
I think perhaps it is
better if you move out.
Does she love you, Max?
I'm not sure she's capable
of any real feelings.
She's television generation.
She learned life from Bugs Bunny.
The only reality she knows
comes to her over the TV set.
She's very carefully devised
a number of scenarios...
...for all of us to play,
like the Movie of the Week.
My God, look at us, Louise.
Here we are going through the
obligatory middle of Act 2...
...scorned-wife-throws
peccant-husband-out scene.
But don't worry, I'll come
back to you in the end.
All of her plot outlines
have me leaving her...
...and coming back to you,
because the audience won't buy...
...a rejection of the
happy American family.
She does have one script
in which I kill myself.
An adapted for television
version of Anna Karenina...
...where she's Count
Vronsky and I'm Anna.
You're in for some dreadful grief, Max.
I know.
The Mao Tse-Tung Hour
went on the air March 14.
It received a 47 share.
The network promptly committed to
15 shows with an option for 10 more.
There were the usual
contractual difficulties.
"Equal to 20 percent, 20, except that
such percentages shall be 30 percent, 30...
...for 90-minute or longer
television programs. "
Have we settled that sublicensing thing?
- No.
- We want a clear definition here.
"Gross proceeds should consist of
all funds the sublicensee receives...
...not merely the net amount remitted after
payment to the sublicensee or distributor. "
We're not sitting still for overhead
charges as a cost prior to distribution.
Don't fuck with my distribution costs.
I'm making a lousy 215 per segment.
I'm already deficiting
$25,000 a week with Metro!
I'm paying William Morris
10 percent off the top!
I'm giving this turkey $10,000
and another five to this fruitcake.
Don't start no shit
with me about a piece.
I'm paying Metro 20 percent for all foreign
and Canadian distribution after recoupment.
The Communist Party's not gonna see
a nickel until we go into syndication!
Come on, Laureen. The Party's in
for 7500 a week production expenses.
I'm not giving this pseudo-insurrectionary
sectarian a piece of my show.
I'm not giving him script approval. I'm not
cutting him in on my distribution charges.
You fucking fascist!
Did you see the film we made
of San Marino jail breakout...
...demonstrating the rising up of the
seminal prisoner-class infrastructure?
You can blow the seminal prisoner-class
infrastructure out your ass!
I'm not knocking down my
goddamn distribution charges.
Man, give her the
fucking overhead clause.
How did I get here?
Who's gonna believe this?
I'm sitting here in a
goddamn farmhouse in Encino...
Let's get back to Page 22, 5,
small "A", Subsidiary Rights.
Where are we now?
Page 22, middle of the
page. Subsidiary Rights.
"'Subsidiary rights' means without
limitation any and all rights... "
Over the past two days, you've all had
opportunity to meet Diana Christensen...
...our vice president
in charge of programming.
This afternoon, you all saw some of the
stuff she's set up for the new season.
You all know that she is the
woman behind the Howard Beale Show.
We all know she's beautiful.
We all know she's brainy.
I was thinking, before we start
digging into our Chateaubriands...
...let's show her how we feel about her.
We have the number-one
show in television!
At next year's affiliates' meeting...
...I'll be standing here telling
you we've got the top five.
Last year, we were the
number-four network...
...next year we're number one!
We're number one! We're number one!
We're number one!
It is exactly 7:00 here in Los Angeles.
And right now, over a million homes
using television in this city...
...are turning their dials to
Channel 3 and that's our channel!
Howard Beale!
Stop it, stop it!
Now you listen to me.
And listen carefully because this is
your goddamn life I'm talking about today.
In this country, when one company
wants to take over another company...
...they buy up a controlling
share of the stock...
...but first they have to file
notice with the government.
That's how CCA took over the
company that owns this network.
But now, somebody's buying up CCA.
Somebody called the Western
World Funding Corporation.
They filed the notice this morning.
Well, just who in the hell is the
Western World Funding Corporation?
It is a consortium of banks
and insurance companies...
...who are not buying CCA for themselves,
but as agents for somebody else.
Who is this somebody
else? They won't tell you.
They won't tell you, they
won't tell the Senate...
...they won't tell the SEC, the FTC,
they won't tell the Justice Department...
This is Mr. Hackett. Do you
have a New York call for me?
The hell it ain't!
- Do you wanna turn that down, please?
I will tell you who
they're buying CCA for.
They're buying it for the Saudi
Arabian Investment Corporation.
They're buying it for the Arabs!
Clarence? Frank Hackett here.
How's everything back in New
York? How's the good lady?
All right, Clarence, take it easy. I
don't know what you're talking about.
When? Tonight's show?
Clarence, take it easy.
The Howard Beale Show is
just going on out here.
You guys get it three hours earlier
in New York. Clarence, take it easy.
How the hell could I see
it? It's just going on now!
And there's not a single law
in the books to stop them.
When did Mr. Jensen call?
We all know that the Arabs control
$16 billion in this country.
They own a chunk of 5th Avenue...
...twenty downtown pieces of Boston.
A part of the port of New Orleans.
An industrial park in Salt Lake City.
They own big hunks of the Atlanta Hilton,
the Arizona Land and Cattle Company...
...part of a bank in California...
...the Bank of the
Commonwealth in Detroit.
They control Aramco, so that puts
them into Exxon, Texaco and Mobil Oil.
They're all over! New Jersey,
Louisville, St. Louis, Missouri...
...and that's only what we know about.
There's a hell of a lot
more we don't know about.
Because all of those
Arab petrol dollars...
...are washed through
Switzerland and Canada...
...and the biggest
banks in this country.
For example, what we don't
know about is this CCA deal...
...and all the other CCA deals.
Right now the Arabs have screwed
us out of enough American dollars...
...to come right back and, with
our own money, buy General Motors...
...IBM, ITT, AT&T, Dupont, U.S. Steel...
...and 20 other American companies.
Hell, they already own half
of England. So listen to me.
Listen to me, goddamn it. The
Arabs are simply buying us.
There's only one thing
that can stop them. You!
You!
So I want you to get up now.
I want you to get up out of your chairs.
I want you to get up right
now and go to the phone.
I want you to get up from your chairs,
go to the phone, get in your cars...
...drive into the Western
Union offices in town.
I want you to send a
telegram to the White House.
- Oh, my God.
- By midnight tonight...
...I want a million
telegrams in the White House.
I want them wading knee-deep
in telegrams at the White House.
I want you to get up right now and write
a telegram to President Ford saying:
"I'm as mad as hell and I'm
not gonna take this anymore.
I don't want the banks selling
my country to the Arabs.
I want the CCA deal stopped now.
I want the CCA deal
stopped now. Come on.
I want the CCA deal stopped now!
- Look, could we have the room? Sure.
Well, I'd like to see a typescript
and run through a couple more times.
But as for this whole CCA
deal with the Saudis...
...you'd know a lot more about
that, Frank, than I would.
Is it true?
The CCA has 2 billion in
loans with the Saudis...
...and they hold every pledge we've got.
We need that Saudi money bad.
Disaster. The show is a disaster.
Unmitigated disaster. The death knell.
I'm ruined. I'm dead. Finished.
Maybe we're overstating
Beale's clout with the public.
An hour ago, Clarence McElheny
called me from New York.
It was 10:00 in the east and our
people in the White House report...
...they were already
knee-deep in telegrams.
By tomorrow morning, they'll
be suffocating in telegrams.
- Can the government stop the deal?
- They can hold it up.
The SEC could hold this deal up
for 20 years, if they wanted to.
I'm finished.
Any second that phone's gonna ring and
Clarence McElheny is gonna tell me...
...Mr. Jensen wants me in
his office tomorrow morning...
...so he can personally
chop my head off.
Four hours ago, I was
the sun god at CCA.
Mr. Jensen's hand-picked
golden boy, the heir apparent.
Now, ha, ha, I'm a man
without a corporation.
Let's get back to Howard Beale.
You're not seriously gonna
pull Beale off the air?
Mr. Jensen's unhappy with Howard
Beale and wants him discontinued.
But he may be unhappy, but
he isn't stupid enough...
...to withdraw the number-one
show on television out of pique.
Two billion dollars isn't
pique! That's the wrath of God!
And the wrath of God
wants Howard Beale fired!
Every other network will
grab him the minute he walks.
He'll be back on the air for
ABC and we'll lose 20 points...
I'm gonna impale the son of
a bitch with a sharp stick!
Forty million loss in revenues.
- I'll take out a contract.
- Let's not discount federal action...
- I'll hire professional killers.
No, I'll do it myself. I'll
strangle him with a sash cord!
...and a breach of the consent decree.
I don't think Jensen's gonna fire anybody.
Hackett.
Yes, Clarence. I've
already booked my flight.
Uh, well, can you give me a
little more time than that?
I've got the red-eye flight,
I won't be back in New York...
...till 6 tomorrow morning.
That'll be just fine.
I'll see you then.
Mr. Jensen wants to meet
Howard Beale personally.
He wants Mr. Beale in his
office at 10:00 tomorrow morning.
The final revelation is at hand.
I have seen the shattering
fulgurations of ultimate clarity.
The light is impending. I
bear witness to the light!
Good morning, Mr. Beale.
- They tell me you're a madman.
- Only desultorily.
- How are you now?
- I'm as mad as a hatter.
Who isn't?
I'm going to take you
into our conference room.
Seems more seemly a setting
for what I have to say to you.
I started as a salesman, Mr. Beale.
I sold sewing machines
and automobile parts...
...hairbrushes and electronic equipment.
They say I can sell anything.
I'd like to try to
sell something to you.
Valhalla, Mr. Beale. Please, sit down.
You have meddled with the primal
forces of nature, Mr. Beale.
And I won't have it! Is that clear?
You think you've merely
stopped a business deal.
That is not the case.
The Arabs have taken billions
of dollars out of this country...
...and now they must put it back!
It is ebb and flow, tidal
gravity, it is ecological balance.
You are an old man...
...who thinks in terms
of nations and peoples.
There are no nations, there are
no peoples. There are no Russians.
There are no Arabs.
There are no Third Worlds.
There is no West!
There is only one
holistic system of systems.
One vast and immane...
...interwoven, interacting,
multi-variate...
...multinational dominion of dollars.
Petrol dollars,
electro-dollars, multi-dollars.
Reichsmarks, rins,
rubles, pounds and shekels.
It is the international system
of currency which determines...
...the totality of life on this planet.
That is the natural
order of things today.
That is the atomic...
...and subatomic...
...and galactic
structure of things today.
And you have meddled...
...with the primal forces of nature!
And you will atone.
Am I getting it through
to you, Mr. Beale?
You get up on your
little 21-inch screen...
...and howl about America and democracy.
There is no America.
There is no democracy.
There is only IBM and ITT and AT&T...
...and Dupont, Dow,
Union Carbide, and Exxon.
Those are the nations
of the world today.
What do you think the Russians talk about
in their councils of state? Karl Marx?
They get out their linear
programming charts...
...statistical decision
theories, minimax solutions...
...and compute price-cost probabilities
of transactions and investments...
...just like we do.
We no longer live in a world of
nations and ideologies, Mr. Beale.
The world is a college
of corporations...
...inexorably determined by the
immutable bylaws of business.
The world is a business, Mr. Beale.
It has been since man
crawled out of the slime.
And our children will live, Mr. Beale...
...to see that...
...perfect world...
...in which there's no war or famine...
...oppression or brutality.
One vast and ecumenical
holding company...
...for whom all men will work
to serve a common profit...
...in which all men will
hold a share of stock...
...all necessities provided...
...all anxieties tranquillized...
...all boredom amused.
And I have chosen you, Mr. Beale...
...to preach this evangel.
Why me?
Because you're on television, dummy.
Sixty million people watch you every
night of the week, Monday through Friday.
I have seen the face of God.
You just might be right, Mr. Beale.
That evening, Howard
Beale went on the air...
...to preach the corporate
cosmology of Arthur Jensen.
Last night I got up here
and asked you people...
...to stand up and fight for your
heritage, and you did, and it was beautiful.
Six million telegrams were
received at the White House.
The Arab takeover of
CCA has been stopped.
The people spoke, the people won. It
was a radiant eruption of democracy.
But I think that was it, fellas.
That sort of thing is not
likely to happen again.
Because at the bottom of
all our terrified souls...
...we know that democracy
is a dying giant...
...a sick, sick, dying, decaying, political
concept writhing in its final pain.
I don't mean that the United
States is finished as a world power.
The States is the richest
and most powerful...
...the most advanced country,
light years ahead of any country.
I don't mean the communists
are gonna take over the world.
The communists are deader than
we are. What is finished...
...is the idea that this great
country is dedicated to the freedom...
...and flourishing of
every individual in it.
It's the individual that's finished.
It's the single, solitary,
human being that's finished.
It's every single one of you
out there that's finished.
Because this is no longer...
...a nation of independent individuals.
It's a nation of some
200-odd million...
...transistorized, deodorized...
...whiter than white steel-belted bodies,
totally unnecessary as human beings...
...and as replaceable as piston rods.
Well, the time has come to say...
...is "dehumanization" such a bad word?
Whether it's good or
bad, that's what is so.
The whole world is becoming humanoid,
creatures that look human but aren't.
The whole world, not just us.
We're just the most advanced
country, so we're getting there first.
The whole world's people are
becoming mass-produced, programmed...
...numbered insensate things.
It was a perfectly
admissible argument...
...that Howard Beale advanced
in the days that followed.
It was, however, also
a very depressing one.
Nobody particularly cared to hear
his life was utterly valueless.
By the end of the first week in June...
...the Howard Beale Show dropped
one point in the ratings...
...and its trend of shares dipped under
48 for the first time since last November.
You're his goddamn agent. I'm counting on
you to talk some sense into the lunatic.
Nobody wants to hear about dying
democracy and dehumanization.
I'm sorry I'm late.
We're starting to get
rumbles from the agencies.
Another couple of weeks and the
sponsors will be bailing out!
This is a breach of contract. This
isn't the Howard Beale we signed.
Get him off that corporate universe kick,
or so help me, I'll pull it off the air!
I told him, Lou! I've been
telling him every day for a week!
I'm sick of telling
him. Now you tell him!
Jesus Christ.
You could help me out with
Howard if you wanted to.
He listens to you.
You're his best friend.
I'm tired of all this
hysteria about Howard Beale.
Every time you come from seeing
somebody in your family...
...you come back in one
of these middle-aged moods.
I'm tired of finding you on the
telephone every time I turn around.
I'm tired of being an
accessory in your life.
And I'm tired of pretending
to write this dumb book...
...about my maverick days in the
great early years of television.
Every goddamned executive fired from
a network in the last 20 years...
...has written this dumb book about
the great early years of television.
And nobody wants a dumb,
damn, goddamn book...
...about the early days of television.
Terrific, Max! Maybe you can start
a whole new career as an actor.
It's the truth.
After living with you for six months,
I'm turning into one of your scripts.
Well, this is not a script, Diana.
There's some real,
actual life going on here.
I went to visit my wife today because
she's in a state of depression...
...so depressed that my daughter flew
all the way from Seattle to be with her.
And I feel lousy about that.
I feel lousy about the pain that
I've caused my wife and my kids.
I feel guilty and
conscience-stricken...
...and all of those things
that you think sentimental...
...but which my generation
calls simple, human decency.
And I miss my home...
...because I'm beginning
to get scared shitless.
Because all of a sudden it's closer
to the end than it is to the beginning.
And death is suddenly a
perceptible thing to me...
...with definable features.
You're dealing with a man that
has primal doubts, Diana...
...and you've got to cope with it.
I'm not some guy discussing male
menopause on the Barbara Walters Show.
I'm the man that you presumably love.
I'm part of your life.
I live here. I'm real.
You can't switch to another station.
What exactly is it you want me to do?
I just want you to love me.
I just want you to love
me, primal doubts and all.
You understand that, don't you?
I don't know how to do that.
I'll be with you in a minute, Max.
By the first week in July...
...the Howard Beale
Show was down 11 points.
Hysteria swept through the network.
He's a plague. He's smallpox.
He's typhoid. I don't wanna
follow his goddamn show.
I want out of that 8:00 spot.
I've got enough troubles without
Howard Beale as a lead-in!
Scheduled me against
Tony Orlando and Dawn.
NBC's got Little House on the
Prairie. ABC's got The Bionic Woman.
Do something! You gotta do
something about Howard Beale!
Get him off the air! Get him off!
Do something! Do anything!
We're trying to find
a replacement for him!
I'm going to look at
audition footage now!
And how when the sicks heal...
...man, I tell you I saw it!
It was heavy, baby.
I saw the earth quake.
And I saw the moon became like blood.
And every mountain and island
was moved from its place.
No, no, no. Damn it.
If we wanted hellfire
we'd get Billy Graham!
Don't want faith healers, evangelists
or Oberammergau passion players!
What about that messiah that ABC
was supposed to have signed up...
- ... as our competition
for next year? That's him.
- The bottomless pit
is here. That's him?
His ass ending.
Jesus. Turn him off!
I've got three more, but you've
already seen the best ones.
I've got a guru from Spokane
and two more hellfires...
...who see visions of the Virgin Mary.
We're not gonna find a replacement for
Howard Beale. Let's stop kidding ourselves.
Fully fledged messiahs
don't come in bunches.
We either go with Howard
Beale or we go without him.
My reports say we'll
do better without him.
It would be disaster to let this
situation go on another week.
By then, he'll be down 16 points...
...and the trend irreversible,
if it isn't already.
I think we should fire Howard.
Arthur Jensen has taken a strong personal
interest in the Howard Beale Show.
I'm having dinner with him tonight.
Let me have another crack at Jensen...
...and then let's meet in
my office at 10:00 tonight.
Diana, give me copies of all
your audience research reports.
I may need them for Jensen. Is
10:00 convenient for everyone?
I think the time has come to
re-evaluate our relationship, Max.
So I see.
I don't like the way this
script of ours is turning out.
It's turning into a seedy little drama.
Middle-aged man leaves wife and family
for young heartless woman, goes to pot.
The Blue Angel with Marlene Dietrich
and Emil Jannings. I don't like it.
- So you're gonna cancel the show.
- Right.
Here, let me do that.
The simple fact is, Max,
that you're a family man.
You like a home and kids. That's beautiful.
I'm incapable of any such commitment.
All you'll get from me is a couple
months of intermittent sex...
...and recriminate and ugly little
scenes like the one we had last night.
I'm sorry for all those things
I said to you last night.
You're not the worst fuck I've ever
had. Believe me, I've had worse.
You don't puff or snorkle...
...and make death-like rattles.
As a matter of fact, you're
rather serene in the sack.
Why is it that a woman always thinks...
...that the most savage thing she can say
to a man is to impugn his cocksmanship?
Well, I'm sorry I
impugned your cocksmanship.
I gave up comparing genitals
back in the schoolyard.
You're being docile as hell about this.
Oh, hell, Diana, I knew it
was over with us weeks ago.
Will you go back to your wife?
I'll give it a try, but I
don't think she'll jump at it.
But don't worry about me. I'll manage.
I always have, I always will.
I'm more concerned about you.
You're not the boozer type.
So I figure a year, maybe
two, before you crack up.
Or jump out of your
14th floor office window.
Stop selling, Max. I don't need you.
I don't want your pain. I don't
want your menopausal decay and death!
I don't need you, Max.
- Now get out of here!
- You need me! You need me badly.
Because I'm your last
contact with human reality.
I love you.
And that painful, decaying love
is the only thing between you...
...and the shrieking nothingness
you live the rest of the day.
Then don't leave me.
It's too late, Diana.
There's nothing left in
you that I can live with.
You're one of Howard's humanoids...
...and if I stay with
you, I'll be destroyed.
Like Howard Beale was destroyed.
Like Laureen Hobbs was destroyed.
Like everything that you and the
institution of television touch...
...is destroyed.
You're television incarnate, Diana.
Indifferent to suffering,
insensitive to joy.
All of life is reduced to
the common rubble of banality.
War, murder, death...
...all the same to
you as bottles of beer.
And the daily business of
life is a corrupt comedy.
You even shatter the
sensations of time and space...
...into split seconds
and instant replays.
You're madness, Diana.
Virulent madness.
And everything you touch dies with you.
But not me.
Not as long as I can
feel pleasure and pain...
...and love.
And it's a happy ending.
Wayward husband comes to his senses...
...returns to his wife...
...with whom he's established
a long and sustaining love.
Heartless young woman left
alone in her arctic desolation.
Music up with a swell.
Final commercial.
And here are a few scenes
from next week's show.
How did it go?
Mr. Jensen was unhappy at the idea
of taking Howard Beale off the air.
Mr. Jensen thinks Howard Beale is
bringing a very important message...
...to the American people.
So he wants Howard Beale on the
air and he wants him kept on.
Mr. Jensen feels we're too
catastrophic in our thinking.
I argued that television was a volatile
industry in which success and failure...
...were determined week by week.
Mr. Jensen said he did not like
volatile industries and suggested...
...with a certain sinister silkiness...
...that volatility in business
usually reflected bad management.
He didn't care if Howard Beale was
the number-one show or the 50th.
He didn't really care if
the Beale Show lost money.
He wants Howard Beale on the
air and he wants him kept on.
I would describe his position
on this as inflexible.
Where does that put us, Diana?
That puts us in the shithouse,
that's where that puts us.
- Do you want me to
go through this? Yes.
The Beale Show Q score's down to 33.
Most of this loss occurred in the
child and teen and 18-34 categories...
...which were our key core markets.
And as the AR department's carefully
considered judgment and mine...
...that if we get rid of Beale, we
should maintain a respectable share...
...in the high 20s, possibly
30, with a comparable Q level.
The other segments of the
show, Sibyl the Soothsayer...
...Jim Webbing, the Vox Populi, have
all developed their own audiences.
Our AR reports show that
it is Howard Beale...
...that is the destructive force here.
Minimally, we're talking about a
10-point differential in shares.
I think Joe ought to
spell it out for us. Joe?
A 28 share is 80,000-dollar minutes.
I think we can sell complete
positions on the whole.
We're just getting into the
pre-Christmas gift sellers...
...and I'll tell you the agencies
are coming back to me with $4 CPM's.
If that's any indication, we're talking 40-,
45 million-dollar loss in annual revenues.
Wanna hear the flak from the affiliates?
We know all about it, Herb.
And you would describe Mr. Jensen's
position on Beale as inflexible?
Intractable and adamantine.
So, what do we do about
this Beale son of a bitch?
I suppose we'll have to kill him.
I don't suppose you have
any ideas on that, Diana?
Well, what would you fellows
say to an assassination?
I think I can get the Mao Tse-Tung
people to kill Beale for us...
...as one of their shows.
In fact, it'll make a hell of
a kickoff show for the season.
We're facing heavy opposition on the
other networks for Wednesday nights...
...and The Mao Tse-Tung Hour
could use a sensational opener.
It could be done right
on camera in the studio.
We ought to get a fantastic
look-in audience...
...for the assassination of
Howard Beale as our opening show.
Well, if Beale dies, what would
our continuing obligation...
...to the Beale corporation be?
I know our contract with Beale
contains a buy-out clause...
...triggered by his death or incapacity.
There must be a formula for the
computation of the purchase price.
Offhand, I think it was based
on a multiple 1975 earnings...
...with the base period in 1975.
I think it was 50 percent of salary plus
25 percent of the first year's profit...
...multiplied by the unexpired
portion of the contract.
I don't think the show has any
substantial syndication value...
...would you say, Diana?
Syndication profits are minimal.
We're talking about
a capital crime here.
The network can't be implicated.
I hope you don't have any hidden
tape machines in this office, Frank.
Well, the issue is, shall
we kill Howard Beale or not?
I'd like to hear some
more opinions on that.
I don't see we have any option,
Frank. Let's kill the son of a bitch.
Ladies and gentlemen, let's
hear it. How do you feel?
We're mad as hell and we're
not going to take this anymore!
Ladies and gentlemen,
the Network News Hour...
...with Sibyl the Soothsayer.
Jim Webbing and his
It's-the-Emes Truth Department.
Ms. Mata Hari and her
Skeletons in the Closet.
And tonight, another
segment of Vox Populi.
And starring the Mad Prophet
of the Airways, Howard Beale!
The Network News anchorman on
the UBS Network News show...
...known to millions as the
Mad Prophet of the Airways...
...was shot to death tonight in a
fusillade of automatic-rifle fire...
...just as he began
this evening's broadcast.
We never compromise, so why should you?
Canada Dry mixers, why compromise?
...identified themselves as the
group responsible for the killing.
Ahmed Kahn, a massive man of well over
6 feet, carrying an automatic weapon.
...supposed to be good for you.
- Did you try it? I'm not
gonna try it, you try it.
- I'm not gonna try it.
- Let's get Mikey.
Yeah. He won't eat it.
He hates everything.
The extraordinary incident...
...occurred in full view
of his millions of viewers.
The assassins were members
of a terrorist group...
...called the Ecumenical Liberation
Army, two of whom were apprehended.
The leader of the group, known
as the Great Ahmed Kahn, escaped.
This was the story of Howard Beale...
...the first known instance
of a man who was killed...
...because he had lousy ratings.