Gentlemen, I wanna welcome
you medical schoolmen...
...to our new operating theatre.
As you can see,
it isn't exactly what you'd call new.
Used to be a library
when this was a school...
...and maybe before that
some kind of a sugar warehouse.
Makeshift or not, the important
thing is that we got it.
The first to be devoted
to psychosurgery in this state.
And that is a great step forward.
Now you're going
to witness an operation...
...never performed before
in this state.
A lobotomy on a woman's brain...
...suffering from acute
schizophrenic withdrawal.
Our new staff member,
Dr. John Cukrowicz from Chicago...
...will perform this operation.
Swab.
Sew up, will you?
You have just witnessed a delicate
operation on the human brain...
...performed under the most
primitive surgical conditions...
...that I hope any of you
will ever encounter.
Excuse us, please.
- Son, I know how you feel.
- For six months...
...I have listened to you
promise me this and that.
- But I am not...
- I know, I know, I know.
You are not the state board of health.
I am not a witch doctor.
I need properly trained assistants.
I need an operating room
that doesn't fall apart.
At least lights that stay lit.
I know, but this is a state hospital.
There just isn't
enough money for us.
I can't promise
that there ever will be enough.
I'll go back to Chicago
or someplace where there is.
John.
Before you do that,
read this.
Who is Violet Venable?
You reveal your ignorance
of our fair city...
...of which Mrs. Venable
is the richest lady.
At one time, her husband owned most of
it. Now she's a widow and she owns it.
"...and was very interested
in the work of your Dr. Cukrowicz."
She must have read your
write-up in the Herald.
"And I wonder if the foundation
I am establishing...
...might be of some assistance."
Son, with one signature
on one check...
...she can solve
all the problems we got.
"Also there is a matter
of some urgency...
...I should like to discuss with him.
Would 4:30 on Tuesday be convenient?"
That's today.
What is her urgency, do you know?
No, but I know what ours is.
Lack of money. Her money.
She is serious?
4:30 this afternoon, you'll know.
I can tell you this much.
I've been trying for years
just to see the Venable lawyers.
You've been invited by her.
That's a command performance.
That's how serious I think it is.
And this is serious too.
More than 1200 mental cases
Lions View can't afford to handle.
Good afternoon.
- Dr. Cukrowicz.
- Yes, sir.
- Take a seat, please.
- Thank you.
Mrs. Venable?
I am Miss Foxhill,
Mrs. Venable's secretary.
And you are Dr. Cukrowicz?
- Your appointment was for...?
- 4:30.
You are 23 seconds early.
Sit down, please.
Thank you.
Sebastian always said,
"Mother, when you descend...
...it's like the goddess
from the machine."
- Mrs. Venable's on her way down.
- I feel just like an angel...
...coming to earth
as I float, float into view.
Sebastian...
...my son, Sebastian, was
very interested in the Byzantine.
Are you interested
in the Byzantine, Dr...?
Cukrowicz.
I don't know very much
about the Byzantine.
The emperor of Byzantium,
when he received people in audience...
...had a throne which,
during the conversation...
...would rise mysteriously in the air
to the consternation of the visitors.
As we are living in a democracy,
I reverse the procedure.
I don't rise. I come down.
How do you do, Dr...?
Oh, I'm sorry, your name?
Cukrowicz.
It's a Polish word meaning "sugar."
Am I only wearing one earring?
Have I forgotten my lip rouge?
Excuse me, I...
I guess I had been told
you were a widow.
I am. I'm in mourning.
White was my son's favorite color.
Perhaps, Dr. Sugar...
...you expected an old widow.
With a garnet brooch, a cane
and an ear trumpet.
I have all that
to look forward to.
Life is a thief. Sebastian always
said, "Life steals everything."
I want to show you his garden.
Are you sure you should go out,
Mrs. Venable?
Quite sure.
They treat me like an invalid.
You see, last spring I had a tiny
convulsion of a tiny blood vessel.
What did your doctor call it?
A malady of living.
After all, I've buried a husband
and a son. I'm a widow and a...
Funny, there's no word.
Lose your parents, you're an orphan.
Lose your only son and you are...
...nothing.
Foxhill.
Where are they?
I put them in the patio.
They sent them parcel post from
Pensacola. That's why they were late.
Another day and we'd have starved
to death. Come on, doctor.
In your letter,
you said an urgent matter.
I must say, you're handsomer
than your photograph in the paper...
...without that awful paraphernalia
you doctors wear.
Your son's favorite color, white.
Such extraordinary eyes.
So like his. You must...
I almost said, "You must meet
my son Sebastian." Force of habit.
Is he the son who died?
Yes, last July, in Europe.
He must have been young to die.
All poets...
...whatever age they may seem
to others, die young.
- It's unexpected.
- Like the dawn of creation.
It was Sebastian's idea.
Part of his lifelong war
against the herbaceous border.
Not unlike a well-groomed jungle
and, frankly, a little terrifying.
So was creation.
So is creation.
Listen to them buzz, buzz.
What's in there?
This way, before our poor lady
dies of hunger.
The Latin names to the plants
are printed on tags...
...attached to them,
but the print's fading.
Those ones there
are the oldest plants on earth.
Survivors from the age
of the giant fern forest.
And here's my poor lady.
They never get away.
The lady exudes this marvelous
perfume which attracts them.
They plunge into her chalice.
And they never come out.
This operation
you perform is called...?
Lobotomy.
- That's an unusual...
- I hate these flies.
Foxhill!
She loves feeding our wicked lady.
Foxhill's rather a brute.
Such an extravagance, really,
from early fall to late spring...
...lady must be kept under glass...
...and we have to provide her
with flies flown in at great expense.
Foxhill, you do the honors.
- Lady's very hungry today.
- Of course, Mrs. Venable.
I've never seen an insectivorous
plant before. What is it called?
The Venus flytrap.
A devouring organism...
...aptly named
for the goddess of love.
What was your son's work?
I mean, aside from this garden.
As many times as I've had
to answer that question...
...it still shocks me
a little to realize...
...that Sebastian Venable the poet
was quite unknown...
...outside of a small coterie
of friends, including his mother.
- Your son was a poet?
- His life was his occupation.
Yes. Yes, Sebastian was a poet.
That's what I meant
when I said his life was his work.
Because the work of a poet
is the life of a poet. And vice versa.
I mean, you can't separate them.
I mean...
...a poet's life is his work.
And his work is his life,
in a special sense.
- Are you all right?
- Right as rain, however right that is.
This operation of yours,
does it really work?
Yes, yes, it does.
However, it is very experimental.
I was struck by something
you said in the paper.
About the sharp knife in the mind.
That kills the devil in the soul?
I'm afraid I got a bit carried away.
No, what you said
was almost poetic itself.
Mrs. Venable, the work
of a doctor is his life too.
But we need help, particularly
in a field as experimental as mine.
Particularly at a state hospital
like Lions View.
We have very little money,
practically none.
Yes, I know.
Doctor...
...I have a niece by marriage...
...at a place called St. Mary's.
I've heard of it.
It's a custodial home for the insane.
She suffers from something
called dementia praecox.
From dementia praecox?
Which is to say, she's mad
as a hatter, poor child.
Would you like to
see Sebastian's studio?
It's at the end of the jungle
in what used to be the garçonnière.
An old New Orleans convenience.
A place where the young men
could go to be private.
You're not from New Orleans?
No, Chicago. Actually, dementia
praecox is a meaningless phrase...
Chicago. I've always wanted
to see two places before I die.
Hong Kong...
...and Chicago.
Now I shall never see either.
Because I must use every inch and
ounce of what little strength I have...
...in doing just what I'm doing.
The foundation you referred to?
Building a memorial to my son.
You see, Sebastian had
no public name as a poet.
He didn't want one.
He refused to have one.
He abhorred the false values
that come from being publicly known...
...from fame,
from personal exploitation.
He'd say to me, "Violet, Mother,
you're going to live longer than me.
When I'm gone, it will be yours
to do whatever you please with."
Meaning, of course,
his future recognition.
- You're very like him, doctor.
- In what way?
Because you, a doctor, a surgeon...
...are dedicated to your art.
Yes, to your art.
It is an art, what you do.
Using people the way he did.
Grandly, creatively.
Almost like God.
I'm afraid my art is to help.
Not to use, but to be used.
Well, it comes to the same,
doesn't it?
I mean, in the end.
Oh, I don't know what I mean.
There is the atelier,
Sebastian's studio.
Most people's lives...
...what are they
but trails of debris?
Each day more debris, more debris.
Long, long trails of debris...
...with nothing to clean it all up
but, finally, death.
I guess...
...quiet desperation
is the word for most lives.
But ours were different.
Sebastian's and mine.
I know it sounds
hopelessly vain to say...
...but we were a famous couple.
People didn't speak of Sebastian
and his mother...
...or Mrs. Venable and her son.
They said, "Sebastian and Violet.
Violet and Sebastian are at the Lido.
They're at the Ritz."
And every appearance,
every time we appeared...
...attention was centered on us.
Everyone else eclipsed.
My son, Sebastian...
...and I...
...constructed our days.
Each day, we would carve each day
like a piece of sculpture.
We left behind us a trail of days...
...like a gallery of sculpture...
...until suddenly, last summer...
Your son died?
You say that your niece suffers
from dementia praecox.
There must have been
a more exact diagnosis.
Such a pretty name for a disease.
Sounds like a rare flower,
doesn't it?
Night-blooming dementia praecox.
What form does her disturbance take?
Madness.
Obsession, memory.
She lacerates herself with memory.
Memory of what?
Visions, hallucinations.
It all started last summer.
The first I knew, there was a cable
from this clinic in Paris...
...saying, "Your niece is out
of her mind. What shall we do?"
I was almost out of my mind
last summer.
Sebastian had just died, I was ill,
but I did everything I could.
I said, "Send her straight home
with a nurse."
So they put her on the Berengaria...
...locked in her stateroom
like a wild animal.
She was taken straight to St. Mary's.
And now they can't keep her there,
they can't help her...
...or cope with her fits of violence.
Her babbling.
Her dreadful, obscene babbling.
- What kind of babbling?
- Fantastic delusions and babblings...
...of an unspeakable nature.
Mostly taking the form
of hideous attacks...
...on the moral character
of my son, Sebastian.
And now they tell me at St. Mary's...
...the Mother Superior tells me...
...that we must find
another place for her.
And then I read about you...
...about your operation,
and I thought:
"This may be the answer
to all our prayers."
You must realize
the operation I do...
...is only for the unapproachable,
for the hopeless.
If she isn't unapproachable
and hopeless, I don't know who is.
- The things she says.
- What?
- Terrible, obscene things.
- Such as?
Oh, anything.
Such as?
All right, you asked.
This happened recently at St. Mary's.
Catherine accused an elderly gardener
of making love to her.
They questioned the gardener,
an old man.
It was the other way around.
Catherine had made advances to him,
spoken obscenely to him.
When confronted with her lies,
she fought and screamed.
It took four nuns to control her.
Now I'm put on notice that they
won't keep her there after this week.
You see why I said urgent.
Yes, I do. I certainly do.
It's important I see her
as soon as possible.
And help her. If you can't,
I'm at my wits' end.
I can transfer her to Lions View.
She won't be as comfortable...
I understand.
But the important thing
is you, doctor.
You'll be happy to know
that at this very minute...
...my lawyers are working on the
Sebastian Venable Memorial Foundation...
...to subsidize the work
of young people like yourself...
...who are pushing out
the frontiers of art and science...
...but have a financial problem.
Mrs. Venable, loving your niece
as you do, you must know...
...there's great risk
in this operation.
When you enter the brain with a foreign
object, even a needle-thin knife...
...in the hands
of the most skilled surgeon...
...there still is
a great deal of risk.
But it does pacify them,
I've read that.
It quiets them down.
It makes them peaceful.
- Yes, that it does do, but...
- But what?
Well, it will be years before we know
if the benefits...
...of the operation are lasting...
...or maybe just passing
or perhaps...
There's a strong possibility that
the patient will always be limited.
Relieved of acute anxiety,
yes, but limited.
But what a blessing to them, doctor,
to be just peaceful.
To be just suddenly peaceful.
After all that horror...
...after those nightmares...
...just to be able to lift up
their eyes to a sky...
...not black with savage,
devouring birds.
You said a sky filled
with savage, devouring birds?
Did I?
How odd. I hadn't thought
about all that in years.
Now, why should I suddenly...?
Yes, we saw those birds
one summer in the Pacific.
You see, my son
Sebastian was looking for...
- Looking for what?
- Rare, hungry birds.
- That's not what you started to say.
- You're too quick for me.
I was going to say my son
Sebastian was looking for God.
I stopped myself.
I thought you'd think:
"What a pretentious young crackpot."
Which Sebastian was not.
This is something
I've never told anyone before.
Something so terrible.
Forgive me if I sound quite mad,
but it's true all the same.
Sebastian saw the face of God.
I'd like to hear about that.
Yes, yes.
One long ago summer,
sitting right here in this garden...
...Sebastian said,
"Mother, listen to this."
And he read me
Herman Melville's description...
...of the Encantadas,
the Galapagos Islands.
He read me that description
and said we had to go there.
So we did go there that summer...
...on a boat,
a four-masted schooner...
...the sort of boat that Melville
would have sailed on.
We saw the Encantadas.
But on the Encantadas
we saw something...
...that he hadn't written about.
We saw the sea turtles
crawl out of the sea...
...for their annual egg-laying.
Once a year, the female
of the sea turtles...
...crawls out of the sea
onto the blazing sand beach...
...of a volcanic island
to dig a pit in the sand...
...and deposit her eggs there.
It's a long and dreadful thing,
the depositing of the eggs in the sand.
And when it's finished...
...the exhausted female turtle
crawls back to the sea half-dead.
She never sees her offspring.
But we did.
Sebastian knew exactly when
the sea turtle eggs would be hatched.
- We returned in time for it.
- You went back?
In time to witness the hatching
and their desperate flight to the sea.
The narrow beach, the color
of caviar, was all in motion.
The sky was in motion,
full of flesh-eating birds.
And the noise of the birds...
...their savage cries
as they circled...
...over the beach
of the Encantadas...
...while the new sea turtles
scrambled out...
...and started their race to the sea.
- Race to the sea?
- To escape the flesh-eating birds...
...that made the sky almost black.
And I said, "Sebastian, no.
No, it's not like that."
But he made me look.
He made me see that terrible sight.
- What was not like that?
- Life.
I said, "No.
No! That's not true!"
But he said it is.
He said, "Look, Violet.
Look, there on the shore."
And I looked and saw the sand
all alive, all alive...
...as the new-hatched sea turtles
dashed to the sea...
...while the birds hovered
and swooped to attack...
...and hovered and swooped to attack.
They were diving down
on the sea turtles...
...turning them over
to expose their soft undersides...
...tearing their undersides open...
...and rending and eating their flesh.
Sebastian guessed that possibly...
...only a hundredth
of one percent of their number...
...would escape to the sea.
Nature isn't created
in the image of man's compassion.
Nature is cruel!
Sebastian knew it all along,
was born knowing it, but not I.
I said, "No, no, those are
only birds, turtles, not us."
I didn't know then it was us.
That we are all of us trapped
by this devouring creation.
I couldn't, wouldn't face
the horror of the truth...
...even that last day
in the Encantadas...
...when Sebastian left me...
...and spent the whole
blazing, equatorial day...
...in the crow's-nest,
watching that thing on the beach...
...until it was too dark to see.
When he came down the rigging,
he said, "Now I've seen him."
- And he meant God.
- Do you believe he saw God?
He saw the whole thing there
that day on the beach.
But I was like you. I said no.
I refused to believe...
...until suddenly, last summer,
I learned my son was right.
What he had shown me
in the Encantadas was the horrible...
...the inescapable truth.
Violet, honey.
- You gave me a turn.
- Hi, Aunt Vi.
Why are you two here?
We came for Sebastian's
clothes, like you said.
- Remember? Like you said.
- So we just kind of let ourselves in.
- I must have got hold of this letter.
- Caught on your sleeve probably.
That's Mrs. Holly, mother of the
St. Mary's girl, and that's her son.
Apparently, I said
he could have Sebastian's clothes.
You haven't forgotten what you said
at Elaine Tutweiler's?
Since I was going to college...
...I could have Cousin
Sebastian's clothes.
You did say that.
You said
that Son here could have...
I'm accused of generosity.
Now will you please...?
Aunt Violet is generous,
so generous to her family, Mr...
What's your name?
- Dr. Cukrowicz.
- Are you a doctor?
- Violet, you're not ill again?
- No, Grace!
I'm so relieved.
I was afraid you had another of those
strokes of yours. Those seizures.
I've never had a seizure nor a stroke.
We were discussing your daughter.
My poor lamb, my poor little girl.
- Can you help her?
- I'm gonna try to, if I can.
Mama, look here! White silk.
"Made in Rome."
Oh, boy, is this one gonna
pick up lipstick!
Take the clothes.
Don't flaunt them in my face.
Why don't you both let yourselves out?
- Get the rest another time.
- It won't take two seconds to finish.
It's impossible that Sebastian
won't walk through that door again...
...with all those bright people
he used to know.
All laughing, carrying on...
...saying those witty things
that were way over my poor head.
He was such a tease too.
You know...
...he told me that the piece of lace
on this table...
...was made by these blind nuns
in Belgium. Imagine!
- I thought I'd gone through everything.
- Who is that?
- It's the girl.
- Why, that's my poor angel, Catherine.
- I wonder why he put it there.
- Maybe he liked her.
George, take your plunder
and get out of here.
- Okay.
- This must've been taken last spring.
She's wearing her Mardi Gras gown.
Remember how lovely she was?
You loaned her your fur coat.
I remember everything.
I guess it was not exactly
a happy evening.
- What did happen?
- She was, she is a lovely girl.
And I must say, of all my relations...
...my delightful relations,
she was the one most like me.
That's why you've got to save her.
Because madness is the most horrible
doom on this earth.
Every item here has been inventoried
by the insurance people.
They'd be upset
if anything were missing.
- What do you think I am?
- On that subject, my lips are sealed.
Now, both of you, please go.
- It's almost 5:00.
- That's right.
Violet always has,
I mean, used to have...
...her 5:00 daiquiri
here with Sebastian.
Now I have it here alone.
Well, we must fly now.
I do pray you can help my poor Cathy.
Goodbye.
Violet, bye now.
Say thank you, George.
Bye, Aunt Violet.
Thanks for everything.
Aren't they awful?
Sebastian and I used to speculate...
...on how those Neanderthals...
...could've produced a girl
as rare as Catherine.
You would have liked Sebastian
and he would have been charmed by you.
He wasn't a family or a money snob,
but he was a snob.
He was a snob about loveliness
in things...
...about personal charm
and physical grace in people.
We always had a perfect troupe...
...of beautiful people around us
always, whenever we traveled.
- May I sit here?
- Sebastian's seat.
- Oh, well...
- No, no, please.
It's a court jester's chair.
A rare one, 500 years old.
Please, sit on it.
Say something funny.
Make me stop wanting to cry.
I'm afraid I'd make
a miserable jester.
I get concerned when
people stop wanting to cry.
Time for your medicine and daiquiri.
In that order.
Isn't it nice of the drugstore
to keep me alive?
- Thank you.
- Foxhill...
See the Hollys off the premises.
They're apt to remove the silver.
Yes, Mrs. Venable.
He would sit in his chair,
I in mine, at 5:00 every day...
...and we'd have daiquiris
with St. Sebastian brooding above us.
But you stayed here last summer.
I did. I wasn't well.
He took Catherine with him.
- And he died.
- Of a heart attack.
Was she with him?
She was there with him when he died,
and that day she lost her mind.
When will you see her, doctor?
As soon as I can.
What can I tell Dr. Hockstader
about your interest in helping us?
Can't that wait until
you've met my niece...
...and decided if you think
your operation could help her?
Yes, of course it can wait.
Surely there's no connection between...
Aren't we more interested in something
that concerns us personally?
Aren't we, doctor?
I understand.
I can find my way out.
Millions of years ago, dinosaurs fed
on leaves of those trees.
They were vegetarians.
That's why they became extinct.
They were just too gentle
for their size.
Then the carnivores,
the ones that eat flesh...
...the killers inherited the earth.
But then they always do, don't they?
Catherine.
It's Sister Felicity, Catherine.
Please get up. You're to come with me.
Catherine.
I'm not being violent, Sister.
What are you doing, Catherine?
Just smoking a cigarette.
Now, you know we're not allowed
to smoke at St. Mary's.
- Please let me smoke. Please.
- Give it here.
- Don't be such a bully!
- Disobedience has to be paid for.
- I'll pay for it later.
- Now, Catherine.
I'm putting out my hand for it.
- All right, take it!
- You burned me!
- I'm sorry...
- You deliberately burned me.
- You said to...
- You stuck the lit end into my hand.
I'm so sick of being
bossed and bullied.
I'm sick of being...
You saw that.
Saw her deliberately burn me.
- You better put something on that.
- I can't leave.
- Patients classified as violent...
- Sister.
Very well, doctor. I'll wait outside.
Just outside the door.
You're very brave
being in the room alone with me.
- Do you plan to burn me too?
- Oh, much worse.
I'm classified as violent.
I'm apt to attack you
and then accuse you of rape.
- Do you do that sort of thing?
- That's why I'm in isolation.
I molested an elderly gardener
of great virtue.
When he refused my advances,
I denounced him as a lecher.
After that, I was punished.
Was it true?
That I was punished? Yes.
- That you accused him unjustly.
- Of course I accused him unjustly.
After all, I'm insane.
It's the sort of thing
an insane woman would do.
Besides, haven't you noticed
how oddly I've been looking at you?
Have you?
How I've been staring at your eyes.
Your beautiful, blue, frightened eyes.
Why are they so frightened?
Do you need help?
Do you want help from me?
I'm making you nervous.
You have every reason to be.
Because now I'm going
to attack you. Yes, attack.
It won't be for your beauty.
No, it's for these cigarettes.
Let me have one.
Of course. Help yourself.
You are good.
- Who are you?
- I'm a doctor.
- Sent by my aunt?
- Yes.
- As I haven't responded to treatment.
- So they say.
You've been invited to try
your hand at what is a hopeless case.
Is it hopeless? What do you think?
- Where are you from?
- Lions View.
The state asylum.
Where they have the Drum.
What you call the Drum
is not a torture chamber.
It's really a recreation hall.
They'll keep me there forever.
Like an animal in a cage.
- She is merciless, isn't she?
- Who?
Aunt Violet. Why else
do you think I'm here?
Where no one can see me, hear me?
You sound as if you think
she hates you.
Doesn't she?
Do you hate her?
What, hate?
No. I don't understand what hate is...
...or how anyone could hate
and still be sane.
I really do think I am sane...
...despite considerable evidence
to the contrary.
- Your aunt, Mrs. Venable...
- Can no more help herself than I could.
Help herself? How do you mean?
You see, we all loved Sebastian.
Women, men, children, animal,
mineral, vegetable...
Sebastian was a vocation, not a man.
Poor Aunt Vi was hooked
from the beginning.
Loved Sebastian and nobody else.
She gave up everything for Sebastian.
Even her husband.
What was Mr. Venable like?
Mr. Venable was a good man...
...but dull to the point of genius.
That was Sebastian talking.
From him,
it wouldn't have sounded cruel.
When I talk like him or when Aunt Vi
talks like him, we sound heartless.
And we're not really.
Though we do terrible things.
What do you consider terrible?
Aunt Vi let her husband die
because of Sebastian.
Killed him, some people thought.
How, killed him?
Once, Sebastian decided to give up
the torments of this world...
...and become a Buddhist monk.
That was in Tibet.
He shaved his head, was given
a wooden bowl and was happy.
Till Aunt Vi came.
Why? What did she do?
Lived in a hut, even took vows,
or whatever women do.
Anything to be near him,
to get to him, to make him come home.
While there, word came.
Mr. Venable was dying.
He had to see her.
And she chose to stay?
She chose to let her husband
die alone.
If you'd known Sebastian, you'd
understand she had no choice...
...how none of us ever had a choice,
once Sebastian had decided we were...
...to be used.
Used?
You mean he used people?
Yes.
Isn't that what love is?
Using people?
And maybe that's what hate is.
Not being able to use people.
- Go on.
- Go on where?
Anywhere.
To the first memory you come to.
My first memory?
It was once at a Mardi Gras ball.
The Mardi Gras ball? Yes?
My very first memory.
It was last spring.
Before last spring,
I remember nothing. Nothing at all.
It's as if my life began
and ended that night.
Tell me about it.
At the ball...
I was taken there by some boy
who got too drunk to stand.
I wanted to leave.
My coat was in the cloakroom.
They couldn't find the check for it,
so I said, "Let it go"...
...and started out for a taxi.
Then somebody took my arm and said:
"I'll drive you home."
As we left, he took off his coat
and put it around my shoulders...
...and then I looked at him.
I don't think I've ever seen him
before then, really.
He took me home.
But he took me another place first.
Near the Dueling Oaks at the end
of Esplanade Street.
We stopped. I asked what for.
He didn't answer.
Just struck a match
to light a cigarette...
...and I looked at him,
and I knew what for.
I think I got out of the car before
he got out of the car, and we...
...walked through the wet grass
toward the great misty oaks as if...
...as if somebody were...
...calling for help there.
And after that?
I lost him.
He took me home.
Then he said an awful
thing to me. He said:
"We'd better forget it.
My wife's expecting a child, and..."
I just entered the house
and sat there thinking a while.
I called a taxi and rushed
to the Roosevelt Hotel ballroom.
The ball was still going on.
I thought I'd gone back
to pick up my coat. But I hadn't.
I hadn't gone back for that at all.
I'd gone back to make a scene.
I didn't pick up Aunt Violet's
silver fox in the coatroom.
I rushed right into the ballroom,
spotted him on the floor...
...ran up to him and started...
...to beat him in the face
and the chest with my fists till...
...Cousin Sebastian took me away.
Miss Catherine?
She's here. Miss Catherine's here.
In spirit as well as flesh.
And now you want to play a game.
Look at pictures?
Tell you the first thing that comes
into my mind, my poor deranged mind.
All right.
That shadow on the wall.
What does it look like to you?
Like a shadow on a wall.
I thought we were gonna play a game.
All right.
I see forests.
Trees, a girl.
And those trees
are the Dueling Oaks...
...and that tormented figure
is the girl, Catherine, losing her...
...honor.
I'm trying to make you
feel sorry for her.
- I hope I am.
- I am sorry.
I believe you really are.
Tell me about your cousin, Sebastian.
He liked me, so I loved him.
How? I mean, in what way
did you love him?
The only way he'd accept.
- I tried to save him, doctor.
- Save him from what?
Completing a sort of image
he had of himself...
...as a sort of a sacrifice
to a terrible sort of a...
- God?
- Yes.
Sebastian, who was gentle, kind...
...saw something not gentle,
not kind, in the universe.
Something...
- Something terrible in himself.
- What was it? Can you tell me?
- One day at Cabeza de Lobo...
- Where?
That's where we were last summer.
That's where...
That's where Sebastian died?
Yes.
How did he die?
They say a heart attack,
but I don't remember. I really don't.
You see, afterwards,
I was hysterical, taut.
Said things I don't remember.
That's why I'm here.
Because I say things people don't...
...and then I don't even remember.
Try to remember.
You and Sebastian, last summer...
The beach was very white.
Oh, how the sun burned.
It was like the eye of God
watching us.
Burning, burning.
There was no air that day.
The sun had burned up all the air.
Outside it was like inside a furnace.
- Then they came.
- Who came?
From all parts of the beach.
And that awful noise they made.
The noise of musical instruments
all made of tin.
Who is "they"?
And that, that music.
That awful music.
I hear that music!
I still hear it!
It's getting closer and closer!
Sebastian! Help!
- What happened? What happened then?
- I don't remember after that!
Stop that this minute.
Stop that noise.
- Doctor, I must see you at once.
- Get out of here.
Sister, get out and don't
come back until I call you.
I can't remember.
- I can't remember!
- It's all right.
- Don't worry, it's all right.
- But I have to, I want to!
Then you will.
Will you help me?
- If you let me.
- Yes.
I shouldn't have done that.
Why not?
It was a friendly kiss, wasn't it?
Maybe it wasn't.
Maybe now you'll think
that all those...
...stories about the gardener
are true.
Whatever's true, we'll find.
I want you to know that
I can look attractive...
...if I had my hair done and if...
When I'm at Lions View,
may I wear a pretty dress?
If you like.
Just imagine, once again
to be able to do...
...one thing I'd like.
Come out here, son.
I want you to see something.
Take a good long look.
Tell me, what do you see?
Old tires, tin cans,
and a "Drink Nehi" sign.
That's the past you're looking at.
Thanks to a certain young man
from Chicago...
...there'll be a new building
on that lot...
...devoted to psychosurgery, dedicated
to the memory of Sebastian Venable.
I wish I were that optimistic.
I've been working with
the lawyers and accountants.
And we're getting, listen to this...
...in big, round, beautiful figures,
$1 million.
- Just like that, no strings attached?
- No strings attached.
She wants you, and nobody else,
to do the operation on her niece.
You can't blame her for that.
There isn't anybody better.
Something horrible happened
to that girl last summer.
Some dreadful, traumatic experience
of some kind.
What?
I don't know.
I haven't found out yet.
And she refuses to allow herself
to remember.
She's gonna have to be made
Come in.
Excuse me, Dr. Hockstader.
Mrs. Holly and her son are here
to see the new patient.
Have them wait in my office, will you?
- How's Miss Catherine?
- She looks lovely.
She had her hair done this morning.
She's wearing her own clothes.
I've never seen clothes like
that girl's got. From Paris! And...
Thank you, Miss Benson.
I'll be along.
But she's a patient. You can't
let her wear her own clothes.
I put her in the nurses' wing.
I don't want her in the ward.
The nurses' wing?
I know I'm taking a risk...
...but for a while I don't want her
to feel she's a patient.
I want her to feel she's free of
restrictions, free of being watched.
This is very unorthodox.
So is insanity.
That's why we're here.
Seems your whole approach
has little to do with neurosurgery.
- For the time being.
- That's what this new building is for.
- Dedicated to neurosurgery.
- Yes, I know.
Mrs. Venable thinks you're prepared
to go ahead with the operation.
Yes, I know.
Cathy's in there?
George, hold me now.
I'm so nervous, I could jump
clear out of my skin.
Well, don't, Mama.
- Kitten!
- Miss Benson, you can go to lunch now.
- Thank you, doctor.
- My poor baby. My angel.
- In this place.
- It's all right, Mama. I'm just fine.
You look pretty good,
Cathy, considering.
- So do you, George, considering.
- We wanted to see you.
But Violet said no,
not while you were at St. Mary's.
The doctors there didn't want
anybody to see you, so we didn't.
My, that's a pretty dress.
- When did you get that?
- In Paris. Sebastian bought it.
Yeah? I'm wearing one of his suits.
Yes, I recognize it.
Wasn't it sweet of Vi to give George
his wardrobe?
Not that she could've done
anything with it.
It's the thought behind the deed
that matters.
Have you seen Aunt Vi recently?
Yes, we saw her last night.
At her house.
She invited us to a private supper.
She's had this elevator installed.
Cutest thing you ever saw...
We've got business to talk about.
I know, son. You know
how children are. They're critical.
What did Aunt Vi say last night?
That you were
in extremely capable hands.
And I can tell they are capable too.
Mr. Brossard, the new lawyer we got...
Such a nice man too,
a tower of strength...
...in all these months
since Sebastian's been gone.
It nearly killed Violet.
I know, I was there.
You didn't see her the way I did,
grieving like a madwoman.
I mean, like her heart would break.
He was her whole life. She worshipped
the ground beneath his feet.
When she got this letter
from that place with the funny name...
What letter?
From the authorities, telling about
what happened to him at...
What was the name of that place,
honey, where he passed on?
- Cabeza de Lobo.
- That's it!
- Did you see the letter?
- No.
But I guess it told about
how he had this heart attack...
...and how Catherine was
not quite herself, poor baby.
I'm myself now, Mama.
Aren't I, doctor?
Of course you are.
Don't worry a thing about
what people say.
Nobody in the city knows about
what you've been through.
Do they, George? Not a thing.
Nobody even knows you've come back
from Europe.
When they question us
or inquire...
...we just say that you stayed abroad
to study something or other.
- Can we talk to Catherine alone?
- Yes, on a private family matter.
Just some papers gotta be signed.
Some business.
Is that all right?
Don't worry. Since I've been allowed
to smoke, I've become a perfect lamb.
My little girl was
always a perfect lamb.
Thank you.
- Cathy, Sebastian left a will.
- A generous, thoughtful will.
He bequeathed to us,
to you and to me, $50,000 each...
...after taxes are paid.
- Sebastian always was very kind.
- Isn't that the truth?
But there is a problem.
It's very complicated, but
Mr. Brossard, this new lawyer, is...
...trying to get it through probate.
- Only it won't go through probate.
- Why not?
- Aunt Vi won't let it.
Well, you see, it has to do with you.
With your being ill.
- She doesn't trust me with the money?
- 50 grand is chickenfeed to Aunt Vi.
- Then what is it?
- When you went off your rocker...
Shut up, Mama. Cathy's not
that far gone. Are you, Cathy?
- When I went off my rocker...?
- Yeah. You said something.
You made up some crazy story
about Sebastian.
- When she heard whatever it was...
- Last night...
...not a word would she say,
except that you babbled.
That's her word for it. You babbled
some story about Sebastian...
...and how he lived and...
- Died...
...in a place called Cabeza de Lobo.
What you said gave her a real turn.
When doctors decided you were crazy,
she wanted you to stay at St. Mary's.
Or even right here.
This seems such a nice place too.
- With that nice, capable doctor.
- Go on.
Written permission was needed
to keep you here.
So that was the point
of the private supper.
You've gotta understand...
This 100 grand is important to us.
It means George will have all sorts
of advantages now.
Things we couldn't give him, since 1929
killed your father and our nest egg.
Mother, you didn't sign those papers?
- You didn't commit me to Lions View?
- Not yet.
But, Cathy, the way Aunt Vi put it,
there was no choice at all.
Mama's gotta sign.
Besides, honey, it's not like
it was for always.
In no time,
after the little operation...
...you'll be able to...
What little operation?
Oh, Cathy!
There's only one little operation
they perform here.
It's on the brain.
It's called a lobotomy.
You may have heard of it
or read about it. I have.
It's that nice young doctor's
specialty.
In cases of hopeless lunacy...
...he bores holes into the skull
and operates on the brain!
Oh, honey, please don't
talk about it. Please!
- You can't let them!
- Stop. It's not the end of the world!
- Don't sign that paper!
- They say it don't hurt.
- Don't let them!
- No worse than tonsils.
And then, afterwards,
you're all right again.
Miss Catherine.
- Those faces!
- Look, for the love of...
- You get her back to her room.
- What are you doing here?
We've just come from your office.
- What is all that noise? Is it fire?
- What happened?
I don't know. We were having this chat
about your treatment.
All of a sudden my poor baby flew
out of the room and down the hall.
I'm sure it's the right thing,
what you and Violet are doing.
- It is the right thing.
- Come on, Mama.
- We're so grateful to you.
- Come on.
Having you look after her and...
Will you get me Dr. Van Vitch?
- Yes.
- Thank you.
I'm sorry they upset you.
Miss Catherine, don't ever run away.
Where will you cut, doctor?
- I'm not at all sure that I will.
- Where will you cut my brain, doctor?
In front?
Or further back?
I suppose I'm to have my head shaved.
It seems such a waste, seeing as how
I had my hair fixed this morning...
...then to have it all cut off
right after it.
I tell you, it's funny.
And you were the one who was
going to help me. Help me.
Help me!
Don't talk like that.
Why not?
Now I sound insane, don't I?
- Are you trying to?
- No, and I'm not.
You've got to believe me, doctor.
I am not.
Insane is such a meaningless word.
But lobotomy has a precise meaning,
hasn't it?
Are you going to operate? Tell me,
doctor, please, are you going to?
I don't know yet.
Poor doctor.
I bother you, don't I?
Yes, you do.
Well, I'll try not to anymore.
- Three cc, please.
- Yes, doctor.
Must I take off my pretty dress?
Of course not.
I want to help you.
Trust me.
I want to trust you.
It seems to me that
I need help very much.
- His eyes are so blue.
- Who?
The doctor.
Wonder why he isn't blond.
They usually are blond,
with eyes that blue.
- I'm blond.
- Are you?
Funny. We were going to blonds next.
Blonds were next on the menu.
You just relax now.
Let yourself go.
All last summer,
Sebastian was famished for blonds.
Fed up with the dark ones.
Famished for blonds.
The travel brochures he picked up...
...were advertisements of blond
northern countries.
Think he'd already booked us
to Stockholm and Copenhagen.
Fed up with the dark ones,
famished for the light ones.
That's the way he talked about people,
as if they were...
...items on a menu.
That one's delicious-looking.
That one's appetizing.
Or that one is not appetizing.
I think really he was half-starved...
...from living on pills and salads.
You just relax, now.
We'll fly north, little bird.
It's what he called me sometimes.
Little bird.
We'll walk under those radiant,
cold northern lights.
I've never seen the aurora borealis.
Well...
He never saw those northern lights.
Who said, "We're all of us children...
...in a vast kindergarten...
...trying to spell God's name
with the wrong alphabet blocks"?
Thank you.
Mrs. Venable, I do
want to speak with you...
Oh, this forgetfulness,
my greatest failing, doctor.
I have a little gift for you,
this book.
Thank you.
- Poem of Summer.
- By my son, Sebastian Venable.
That volume contains only one poem,
as do the others I have.
Each with the title Poem of Summer
and the date of the summer.
If you like that one,
I'll bring the others.
He wrote one poem a year?
One for each summer
that we traveled together.
The other nine months of the year
were really only a preparation.
Nine months?
The length of a pregnancy, yes.
I gather the poem was hard to deliver.
Even with me. Without me, impossible.
- Doctor, he wrote no poem last summer.
- But he died last summer.
Without me, he died.
That was his last summer's poem.
Mrs. Venable, how exactly
did your son die?
I told you, a heart attack.
Is that what the letter said?
How did Catherine know
I received a letter?
Catherine? She knows very little.
She can't remember.
That's her illness. She was there,
but she can't remember.
- Mrs. Holly told me about it.
- So you've seen her too, have you?
I must say, you have been observing.
There was no letter,
only a death certificate.
- I'd like to see that if...
- Why?
I think it's important. I want to know
what happened the day your son died.
You shall have it tomorrow.
And tomorrow you shall also have
the permission to operate.
And now I'd better go.
I've got lawyers waiting for me.
You'd think giving you a building was
simple. Apparently, I must sign papers.
But I'm used to it.
Sebastian never signed anything.
- He must have suspected...
- Mrs. Venable.
Your son...
What about my son?
What sort of personal life
did he have?
He was chaste.
- You mean he was celibate?
- Yes.
You don't believe me, do you?
- Do you believe that he never...?
- Yes, never.
As strictly as if he'd taken a vow.
This sounds like vanity, doctor...
...but I was actually
the only one in his life...
...that satisfied the demands
he made of people.
Time after time, he'd let people go,
dismiss them...
...because their attitude
toward him was not as...
- As pure?
- As pure as my son demanded.
Would you want to see Catherine?
Is that wise?
It might help me.
But the lawyer.
Surely you've kept the lawyer
waiting before.
Yes, I have.
Such a strong...
...such a persuasive doctor.
She's been under sedation.
She's just coming out of it.
She looks lovely, doesn't she?
Doesn't she?
- Miss Catherine?
- Where are we going?
His eyes...
This one's eyes are so blue...
...such strange, frightened...
I'm sorry. I must have been dreaming.
Hello, Catherine.
I thought... we would have
seen each other before this.
At St. Mary's, they wouldn't
let any of us see you.
Mama was here today.
That was today, wasn't it? I lose
track of time with all these shots.
You look very well, Catherine.
Mama told me how you got her
to agree to commit me here...
...and then let them...
- She seems disturbed, doctor.
Aunt Violet! I am disturbed.
Don't you think I have
every reason to be?
Forcing my mother
into signing a paper...
I've never forced anybody
to do anything.
Oh, yes, you have.
Always.
And now you're holding $100,000...
...under Mother and George's
poor greedy noses...
...to force her to sign a paper
authorizing this doctor to...
Doctor. I see no purpose in my
remaining here listening to this.
I'll wait for you in that sun room.
Doctor, I wanted to speak
to you alone.
Miss Catherine wanted to see you again
before you left.
I didn't want to take your place
last summer.
Please believe that, Aunt Vi.
But Sebastian insisted. He said...
...you weren't well enough to travel
with him, and he couldn't travel alone.
So he insisted that I go along
with him in your place last summer.
And he died last summer.
Aunt Violet, would you like me
to tell you...?
You fell in love with Sebastian,
didn't you?
I tried to give him
what you had always given him:
The tender understanding
and the love you gave...
My son and I had a rare and wonderful
love and trust between us.
A covenant between us...
- I know about the covenant.
- He broke that covenant...
...when he took her, not me,
to travel while he created his poem.
Even when I was with him,
he'd sometimes be frightened.
But I'd know what of.
I'd reach across a table
and touch his hands.
Say not a word, just look,
and touch his hands with mine.
Then, in the morning, the summer poem
would be continued...
...until it was finished.
- I couldn't help him.
- Naturally not, he was mine.
I knew how to help him.
You couldn't.
- I tried.
- I'd force him.
All right, I failed him.
I knew that the day we flew down
to Cabeza de Lobo from...
...where he'd given off
writing his poem.
- Because he had broken...
- Yes, something had broken.
- That string of pearls old mothers...
- Old?
- Hold their sons by!
- Yes, from death.
No! Hold them from life!
You were the stranger, the destroyer.
- We were life.
- You fed on life.
Both of you. Taking!
People were objects for your pleasure.
That's what you taught each other.
- You were superior to mere mortals.
- We needed no one but one another.
Sebastian only needed you
while you were still useful.
- Useful?
- I mean young, able to attract.
She's babbling and lying.
- He left her home because she...
- You stole him!
Lost her attraction!
What would attraction have to do
with a son and mother?
- Is there no way to stop these lies?
- Yes! Have my brain cut.
This was a mistake.
The mistake was my going
with Sebastian.
- When he left her, she had a stroke.
- Not a stroke!
A hysterical stroke.
Sebastian left her home
like a toy he tired of.
And he took me with him
like a new toy. On his last voyage.
- Lies. All lies.
- You see, doctor, we both...
- We were decoys.
- Decoys?
For Sebastian. He used us as bait!
When she was no longer able to lure
the better fish in, he let her go.
Bait? For what?
What were the better fish?
We procured for him.
She'd do it in the smart, fashionable
places they went before last summer.
Sebastian was shy with people.
She wasn't. Neither was I.
But we both did
the same thing for him.
We both made contacts for him.
I can't listen to this obscenity.
Stop her, doctor.
Cut the truth out of my brain,
is that what you want?
You can't. Not even God
can change the truth.
- That we were nothing but a...
- Doctor!
- It's the truth!
- See how she destroys us?
Cut this hideous story
out of her brain!
How much are you willing
to pay for that, Aunt Vi?
Get me away from her. Out of here.
Out of this...
- Nurse, some spirits of ammonia.
- Yes, doctor.
- What happened?
- She fainted.
No. No, she didn't.
Just a little...
...dizziness, that's all.
Dr. Hockstader, will you
help me to my car?
- I don't think that's a good idea.
- Whether it is or not, I'm going home.
Tomorrow, I want that girl
operated on.
That decision belongs to the doctor
in charge, who is also the surgeon.
I don't want to hear from you again
until the operation has been performed.
No! No!
Please, no!
- You trying to ruin this hospital?
- You know better than that.
Can you imagine what would happen
to us if she'd jumped?
She was frightened. She...
Patients are here
because they can't think.
After 24 hours observation...
During which she tried to kill herself,
incited the men's day room to a riot...
- She opened that door by mistake.
- Trying to get away.
There was a riot, and she caused it.
Don't invent excuses for her.
And from that Paris clinic:
Delusions the world
was devouring her...
...that she was being raped by a man
with dueling pistols.
- The Dueling Oaks.
- Here's more of her erotomania.
At St. Mary's, they couldn't
keep her. Why?
Because of her obscenity and violence.
She sexually attacked
a 60-year-old gardener.
It was the other way around.
She tried to burn one of the Sisters
with a cigarette.
She was provoked.
I was there, I saw it.
Provoked? Who would provoke
a disturbed patient?
You'd be surprised.
And to top it, she attempts suicide.
Cogent proof of sanity,
wouldn't you say?
I need time.
When will you want
the operating room tomorrow?
I said I need more time.
I heard you.
Get me Dr. Glen Kilmer
at the Seattle Clinic.
You know I want that building
as much as you do.
I'll hold on.
Give me one more day to see if I can
break through that block to the truth.
This is a medical emergency.
I want to try something.
I want to try something tomorrow,
at Mrs. Venable's.
- Why Mrs. Venable's?
- I don't know.
I feel somehow that in that garden...
...maybe in that jungle,
we might find...
Look, you don't want Mrs. Venable
giving her money...
...to the Seattle Clinic, do you?
And you don't want anybody to be able
to say that we acted hastily...
...or unethically, do you?
Cancel the call.
But be sure you know where
I can find Dr. Kilmer.
Mrs. Venable will be right down.
- The others are here, as you asked.
- Show them into the sun room, please.
Of course, doctor.
Cathy, honey...
Later, Mrs. Holly.
Doctor, I have the things you wanted.
- In the dining room.
- Oh, thank you.
What's going on here?
Sorry to keep you waiting,
Dr. Cukrowicz.
I had to get those papers you wanted.
I mislay everything.
My son always said,
"Mother, if you..."
What are you two doing here?
And where is Dr. Cukrowicz?
Why, I thought you invited us.
Dr. Cukrowicz asked me
to ask them to come.
Of course.
Dr. Hockstader...
...I want you to meet
my sister-in-law, Mrs. Ho...
- Where is Catherine?
- In the sun room.
Could Mrs. Holly and her son
wait for us in the garden?
Of course. Foxhill?
I don't know why everybody
is being so mysterious.
I brought you some of Sebastian's
papers. Odds and ends.
- And this, the thing you wanted.
- Your son's death certificate?
- This must be painful for you.
- If you don't read Spanish, I have...
I read Spanish.
Well, I have a translation.
As you see,
there was no mystery...
...no matter what the girl said
at the time or any other time.
It says the body was somewhat...
...damaged in falling.
Where did he fall?
On the ground. Where else do you fall
when you die in the hot sun...
...in the street
of a godforsaken village?
Did you see his body...?
It was a primitive country.
The coffin came sealed.
Sealed?
Were there any rumors?
There were no rumors.
His heart stopped and he fell.
I'll wait in the garden now.
That is where you want me?
Yes, if you will.
Dr. Hockstader...
...let me show you my son's garden.
It's very unusual.
Like the dawn of creation.
Sebastian's garden.
I can still cry.
Am I dreaming this?
It doesn't seem real.
Would you take off your jacket?
It's time for another injection.
What is it this time?
- Something different.
- The truth serum?
Yes, except there is no such thing.
As truth?
Or the truth serum?
There is truth, all right. Somewhere.
Sit down.
Now you want me to start
counting backwards from 100?
- Do you enjoy counting backwards?
- Oh, I love it. Just love it.
100...
...99, 98, 97...
...96, 95...
I feel it already.
- How funny.
- Close your eyes for a minute.
I want you to give me something.
Name it, it's yours.
I want you to give me
all your resistance.
Resistance? To what?
To the truth.
Truth is the one thing
I have never resisted.
People think they don't resist it,
but they still do.
Sebastian said:
"Truth is at the bottom
of a bottomless well."
Why did...?
Open your eyes.
Why did you try to kill yourself?
Isn't that what everybody wants?
Me out of the way?
Mother and George
would get their money.
You'd get your building.
Aunt Vi...
Go on.
You know what I think
you're trying to do?
I think you're trying
to hypnotize me.
You're looking at me so...
...straight.
You're doing something strange
to me with your eyes. Your eyes...
- Is that what you're doing?
- Is that what you feel I'm doing?
I feel... peculiar.
It doesn't just have to do
with what you gave me.
I'm putting out my hands.
I want you to put your hands into mine
and give me all your resistance.
Pass all the resistance
from your hands into mine.
Here are my hands...
...but there's no resistance in them.
You'll tell the true story?
Yes, I'll try.
Nothing not spoken.
Everything told exactly?
Everything exactly.
Because I have to.
Can I...?
Can I get up?
Yes, of course, but be careful.
You'll feel a little dizzy.
I can't.
Tell me to.
Then I think I could.
Stand up.
Now I can.
- Oh, I'm dizzy. Help me.
- It's all right. You're all right.
Hold me.
I've been so lonely.
Let me.
I suggest you bring her outside,
if you don't mind, doctor.
We'll be right out.
Are you ready?
Hello, Catherine.
Now, Catherine...
...you're going to tell
the true story.
- Where do I start?
- Wherever you think it started.
I think it started...
...the day Sebastian was born
in this house.
- Cathy.
- I don't mind.
Let's start later than that.
Why don't we begin with last summer?
Last summer?
Last summer. How did it begin?
It began...
...after the Dueling Oaks.
- Don't tell about that, Cathy...
- Mrs. Holly, don't interrupt.
After that happened...
...the next morning,
I started writing my diary...
...in the third person singular,
such as:
"She is still living this morning."
Meaning that I was.
"What's next for her? God knows."
I couldn't go out anywhere.
That's true.
She wouldn't leave her room.
Shut up, Mama.
I would write,
"She woke up early this morning.
She had her coffee, dressed...
...went for a brief walk."
- Who did?
- She did.
I did.
From Esplanade
to Canal Street...
...as though being pursued
by a pack of Siberian wolves.
Went through all the stop signs.
Couldn't wait for the green signals.
"Where did she think she was going,
back to the Dueling Oaks?"
Everything...
...chilly and dim.
But that hot...
...ravenous mouth.
He was a very ordinary married man.
And then?
One morning, Cousin Sebastian
came in and said, "Get up."
Well, if you're still alive after
dying, then you're obedient. I got up.
He took me down to a place
where they take passport photos.
He said, "Mother can't go
with me this summer.
You're going with me this summer,
instead of Mother."
- Except that it was her idea, not his.
- Mrs. Venable.
And your cousin?
He helped bring me back to life...
...in Paris, Barcelona, Rome.
All those lovely foreign cities
I'd never seen, we saw together.
And those...
What did he call them?
Those sunshine days...
...where it's always noon,
and we cast no shadows.
- But then...
- But then what?
At Amalfi...
...high above the Mediterranean,
in a garden, I took his arm.
You took his arm. Yes...?
It seemed like such a natural thing
to do, but he pulled away.
How he must have loathed
being touched by her.
I only did it to try and show
my appreciation for his kindness.
I didn't want to...
There was nothing else.
Anyway...
...it was there in Amalfi...
...suddenly, last summer,
that he began to be restless and...
Go on.
He couldn't go on.
He couldn't write his summer poem.
I have his notebook here. See?
Title, Poem of Summer.
And the date of the summer: 1937.
And after that, blank pages,
blank pages. Nothing but nothing.
A poet's vocation rests
on something...
...as fine and thin as a spider's web.
It's all that holds him
out of destruction.
Very few are able to do it alone.
Great help is needed.
I did give it. She didn't.
She's right about that.
I failed him.
I wasn't able to keep
the web from breaking.
I saw it breaking,
I couldn't save it.
Now the truth's coming out. Maybe
she'll admit what really happened.
- What did happen?
- How she killed him.
How she murdered him
at Cabeza de Lobo. Ask her.
What did really happen?
Suddenly, last summer...
...he wasn't young anymore.
We went to Cabeza de Lobo...
...suddenly, he switched
from the evenings to the beach.
Evenings to the beach?
I mean, from the evenings
to the afternoons.
Suddenly, Cousin Sebastian changed
to the afternoons in the beach.
What kind of a beach was it?
Was it a public beach?
Yes, public.
Little statements like that
give her away.
After all I've told you about his
fastidiousness, can you accept...
...that Sebastian would go to some
dirty public beach near a harbor?
Whatever she wants to say,
I want her to say it.
Go on.
I don't want to go on.
Every afternoon, you and your cousin
would go to this free public beach?
It wasn't the free one.
The free one was right next to it.
There was a fence
between the free beach...
...and the beach that we went to
that charged admission.
Did anything happen there
that disturbed you?
- Yes.
- What?
He bought me a bathing suit
I didn't want to wear.
I laughed.
I said, "I can't wear that.
Why, it's a scandal
to the jaybirds."
What do you mean?
Was this suit immodest?
It was a one-piece bathing suit.
Made of white something.
But the water made it transparent.
I told him I didn't want
to swim in it...
...but he just grabbed my hand
and dragged me into the water...
...all the way in...
...and I came out looking naked.
Why did he do that?
Do you know why he did that?
Yes.
- To attract attention.
- Because he thought you were lonely?
Did he think he could shock you
out of your depression?
You know why I was doing it.
I told you.
I was procuring for him.
Sebastian was lonely, doctor.
That empty blue jay notebook
got bigger and bigger.
So big, it was big and empty...
...like that big, empty,
blue sea and sky.
And before long, when the weather
was warmer and the beach so crowded...
...he didn't need me anymore
for that purpose.
The ones from the free beach climbed
over the fence or swam around it.
So now he let me wear
a decent dark suit.
I'd go to a faraway end
of the beach and write post cards...
...and letters and keep up
my third person journal...
...until it was time to meet him
outside the bathhouses on the street.
He would come out... followed.
Who'd follow him?
The hungry young people that climbed
over the fence from the free beach.
He'd pass out tips among them,
as if they'd all...
...shined his shoes
or called taxis for him.
Each day the crowd got bigger...
...noisier, greedier.
At last, we stopped going out there.
And after that? After you stopped
going to the public beach?
Then one day...
...a few days after we'd stopped
going out to the beach...
...it was a blazing white day.
Not a blazing hot blue day,
but a blazing hot white one.
We had a late lunch at a shabby,
lonely restaurant by the sea there.
Sebastian was white as the weather.
He had on a white silk suit,
a white tie, a white Panama.
And he kept touching his face
and his throat here and there...
...with a white silk handkerchief...
...popping little white pills
into his mouth all the time.
I knew he was having a bad time with
his heart and that it frightened him.
"Let's go north," he kept saying.
"I think we've done Cabeza de Lobo.
I think we've done it, don't you?"
I thought we'd done it.
Then there were those children
along the beach...
...which was fenced off with wire
from the restaurant.
Our table was less than a yard away
from the wire fence.
And those children...
There was a band of them.
They looked like a flock
of plucked birds...
...and they came darting up
to the wire fence...
...as if they'd been blown
there by the wind...
...by the hot, white wind
from the sea.
They were all calling out,
"Pan! Pan! Pan!"
They were calling for bread?
They made gobbling noises
with their mouths...
...stuffing their fists
into their mouths and making...
...gobbling noises
with frightful grins.
We were sorry we'd come to the place,
but it was too late to go.
Why was it too late to go?
I told you. Cousin Sebastian
wasn't well. His eyes looked dazed.
But he said, "Don't look
at those little monsters.
Beggars are a social disease
in this country.
If you look at them,
you get sick of the country.
It spoils the whole country for you."
Go on.
I am going on.
The band of children began
to serenade us.
- Began to what?
- Play for us on instruments...
...make music, if you
could call it music.
Their instruments were the instruments
of percussion, know what I mean?
Yes, instruments of percussion,
like drums.
As far as I could make out in
the white blaze of the sand beach...
...the instruments were tin cans
strung together...
...and bits of metal,
other bits of metal...
...that had been flattened out
and made into...
- Into what?
- Cymbals, you know?
- Brass plates hit together.
- That's right.
Tin cans flattened out
and clashed together. Cymbals.
The others had other things.
All sorts of things.
Things that they'd made or picked up
on the beach to make a sort of noise.
A music made out of noise.
Go on.
I am going on.
Nothing could stop me now.
Your Cousin Sebastian, was he
entertained by this concert?
- Terrified of it.
- Terrified, why?
I think he recognized some
of the musicians.
Some of the boys.
Between childhood and older.
Did he complain to the manager
about it?
What manager? God?
You don't understand my cousin.
How do you mean?
He accepted all as how things are...
...and thought nobody had any right
to complain or interfere whatsoever.
Even though he knew what
was awful was awful...
...that what was wrong was wrong.
He thought it unfitting to ever take
any action about anything whatsoever...
...except to go on doing
as something in him directed.
What did this something in him
direct him to do?
He suddenly pushed himself
away from the table and said:
"They've got to stop.
Make them stop. I'm not a well man.
I have a heart condition.
It's making me sick."
That was the first time that
Cousin Sebastian ever attempted...
...to correct a human situation.
I think that
that was his fatal error.
He stalked out of the restaurant after
throwing paper money on the table.
He fled from the place.
I followed.
It was all white outside.
White hot. A blazing white hot, it...
You followed Sebastian out of the
restaurant onto that hot, white street?
Running along the beach...
- You ran along the beach?
- No, no. We didn't.
We didn't move either way.
I rarely made any suggestion,
but this time I did.
What did you suggest?
Sebastian seemed to be paralyzed
near the entrance at the café.
So I said, "Let's go."
I remember I said:
"Down that way is the harbor,
we're likely to find a taxi there.
Or why don't we go back in
and have them call us a taxi?
Oh, let's do! Let's do that.
That's better."
And he said, "Are you mad?
Go back in that filthy place? Never!
That gang of kids shouted vile
things about me to the waiters."
I said, "Well, let's go down
towards the harbor.
Let's not try to climb that hill
in this dreadful heat."
And Cousin Sebastian shouted,
"Please shut up!
Let me handle this situation, will
you? I want to handle this thing."
And he started up the steep street
with a hand stuck in his jacket...
...where I knew he was having
a pain from his palpitations.
But he walked faster
and faster in panic.
The faster he walked...
...the louder and the closer it got.
- Closer what got?
- The music!
- The music again?
The noise of the following band.
They were following.
They were following...
...up the blazing white street.
Up. Straight up. That was the only
way open, so he went that way.
He tried to escape from those streets?
He tried to escape
from those streets...
- He couldn't find a way out?
- He couldn't find a way out.
Did the band of children...?
When he tried to escape...
...from those streets...
...down those little side streets,
between the buildings...
...they came from everywhere.
So the only way was up.
The only way was straight up...
...up those steep, white streets...
...in the sun, that was like a great
white bone of a giant beast...
...that had caught on fire in the sky.
And Sebastian kept
running straight up.
I don't know how he still ran.
He never ran...
...but he ran and he ran and he ran...
...where it was whiter and emptier.
What was emptier?
The light. The sky and the light.
Those steep, white streets and the sun,
and everything blazed white and empty.
Where did those streets lead to?
Nowhere!
He never reached...?
He never reached the end.
They stopped nowhere! Never!
Except, except...
- Except?
- At the...
At the very top of the hill.
Something. A place, a ruin.
Broken stones. Like...
Like what?
Like the entrance...
...to a ruined temple...
...some ancient ruined temple...
...which he entered.
And they...
...overtook him.
There, in that...
And you, Catherine,
what did you do then?
I heard Sebastian scream.
He screamed just once.
Then I...
Help!
And then? Then?
I ran. They let me run.
- They didn't even see me.
- Run where?
Down.
The waiters, police, people...
...ran out of buildings,
back up to where...
...to where Cousin Sebastian...
He was lying naked...
...on the broken stones.
And this you won't believe.
Nobody, nobody could believe it.
It looked as if...
...as if they had devoured him!
As if they had torn or cut...
...parts of him away
with their hands...
...or with knives or those jagged
tin cans they made music with.
As if they'd torn bits of him away...
...and stuffed them
in their own gobbling mouths!
There wasn't a sound anymore.
There was nothing...
...but Sebastian...
...lying on those stones...
...torn and crushed.
Oh, Cathy.
Mrs. Venable.
There you are.
I thought you were still on deck.
And where's your hat?
Oh, dear, you'll get fever.
A whole day up there in the rigging
in the hot sun.
Watching those awful, hungry birds.
I don't know what you see
in such terrible sights.
It's too much for both of us,
my darling.
That horrible sun.
Of course God is cruel.
We didn't need to come to the
Encantadas to find that out, did we?
We've always known about him.
The savage face he shows to people,
and the fierce things he shouts.
It's all we ever see or hear
of him now. Nobody seems to know why.
The difference is...
...we know about him, the others don't.
That's where we're lucky.
Go rest, my darling.
Look out for that fever.
I'm going to see the captain and tell
him to change our course for home.
Oh, Sebastian.
What a lovely summer it's been.
Just the two of us.
Sebastian and Violet.
Violet and Sebastian.
Just the way it's always going to be.
Oh, we are lucky, my darling...
...to have one another
and need no one else, ever.
There's every possibility
that the girl's story is true.
George, tell her she's got
to come home with us.
- Doctor?
- Catherine will be all right.
- Can she come home?
- Don't worry, she will.
- Why don't you take your mother?
- Sure. Come on, Ma.
Miss Catherine?
She's here, doctor.
Miss Catherine's here.