Sunrise
A Song of Two Humans
This song of the Man and his Wife
is of no place and every place:
you might hear it anywhere at any time.
For wherever the sun rises
and sets in the city's turmoil or
under the open sky on the farm
life is much the same:
sometimes bitter, sometimes sweet
Summertime... vacation time
Among the vacationists was
a Woman of the City.
Several weeks had passed since her coming
and still she lingered.
"They used to be like children, carefree...
always happy and laughing..."
"Now he ruins himself for the woman from the city -
Money-lenders strip the farm - "
Money-lenders strip the farm -
and his wife sits alone."
"Tell me!
You are all mine?"
"Sell your farm...
come with me to the City."
"...and my wife?"
"Couldn't she get
"Couldn't she get drowned?
"...then overturn the boat...
it will look like an accident."
"Leave this behind...
come to the City!"
"COME TO THE CITY!"
"...after the boat has capsized,
save yourself with these bulrushes."
"The rushes will hold you up.
Scatter them before you reach the shore
and tell everyone she drowned by accident."
"We're going for a trip across the water.
I may not be back for quite a while."
"Don't be afraid of me!"
"God is giving you,
in the holy blonds of matrimony, a trust.
She is young... and inexperienced.
Guide her and love her..."
"...keep and protect her from all harm."
"Wilt thou LOVE her?"
"Forgive me!"
"Manicure?"
"You'd look grand
with a high polish!"
"Come again!"
"Thank you!
And you must come and see us some time."
"Congratulations! She is the sweetest bride
I've seen this year."
"FARMERS!
If you want to sell your home
and move to the city--- We Pay Cash!"
"Hit the hole...
make the little piggy roll!"
"We'll sail home by moonlight...
another honeymoon."
"...I couldn't give up hope.
I know the tides...
I went around the Point..."