Birchfield County Sheriff Emergency.
- I'm reporting a girl in trouble.
- May I have your name, please?
Listen, a girl's in trouble, okay?
It's the Mill, the bar on Mill Road.
- Sir, I must have your name.
- Listen to me, goddamn it!
Stop!
There's a rape! Three or four guys.
I don't know. There's a whole crowd!
- I will send someone down.
- Send somebody!
Raise your chin.
What kind of contraceptive
do you normally use?
IUD.
- When was your last period?
- Show me your hands, please.
Ten, twelve days.
Bad cramps.
- What's your usual cycle?
- Turn around. Raise your gown.
Twenty-six, twenty-seven days.
Are you gonna examine me?
- Your leg.
- I need some more history first.
Your leg, please.
Before the incident,
when was your last intercourse?
- Turn around, lower your gown.
- A while.
- Can you be more specific?
- Please lower your gown.
- Two weeks.
- Are you sure?
Yeah.
Sarah, have you ever had
a venereal disease?
I'm Carol Honnicut
from the Rape Center.
Is there anyone
you'd like me to call?
Well, I'm here to help...
so if there's anything I can do,
let me know, okay?
Try to relax.
You're tensing. Easy.
Breathe deeply for me.
Easy.
One more. Hold on.
- I'm gonna comb for hairs, Sarah.
- Not yours. Theirs.
Now, let's get you down.
I want to scrape under your nails
in case you scratched one of them.
Sarah, this is Kathryn Murphy.
She'll be the deputy
district attorney for your case.
You can take a shower now,
and a douche.
The ladies room
is down the hall and on your left.
I brought you something to wear.
I hope you don't mind gray.
- You got any mouthwash?
- Sure.
- A lot of alcohol.
- Legally drunk.
- And grass too. What else?
- What difference does that make?
- She was raped by three men.
- I'm not a rape counselor.
I'm a prosecutor,
and I have to make a rape case.
Then go prosecute.
I'll wait
in the supervisor's office.
- Murphy?
- 101.
Thank you.
I heard somebody screaming,
and it was me.
Sarah, this is Detective Duncan.
Dunc. How you doing?
Would you recognize any of the men?
The Mill is still open. We'd like
you to go over there with us...
and see if you could make
a positive ID.
We'd be right there with you.
If you want to get them,
I need your help.
Yeah.
Do you recognize
any of your attackers?
Let's go.
The guy in the yellow T-shirt.
Check the back room.
The one in the vest.
Are there any others?
John, could you take her
out to my car, please?
I'll be there in a minute.
I'm Kathryn Murphy, deputy district
attorney in Birchfield County.
We have a report of a felony
committed on these premises.
- Felony?
- I have a signed search warrant.
This is Detective Duncan.
He's in charge of the investigation.
Want to turn down the television
so we can talk in peace?
Hey, Polito, how are you doing?
Didn't think I was gonna see you
for a couple of years.
The college one wasn't there.
Kurt, Danny and the college one.
My girlfriend Sally was there.
Bob's the college one. Bob.
Did you go to college?
Oh, yeah, you're a lawyer.
Of course you went.
Turn right here.
Listen, maybe you should
just leave me off here.
You know, 'cause...
'cause he's probably asleep.
He likes to get stoned,
listen to music and fall asleep.
You okay?
Yeah.
My eyes hurt.
- Are you married?
- No. Are you?
My ma was married for ten years,
but he left when I was born.
Are you into astrology at all?
No. No, I'm not.
That's too bad.
I could do your chart for you.
- When were you born?
- 1959.
I sure hope I can wake him up.
You want me to come in with you?
Can I ask you a Question?
Does my face look really bad?
He likes to touch my face.
I wish I knew what to say.
What?
I said, I wish I knew what to say.
Want to take a drive?
Get some air. Go out.
I'll be back in a while.
- Hi. It's me.
- Sarah?
It's awful late.
Is something wrong?
No, nothing's wrong.
No special reason.
I just figured I'd say hello.
You lost your job?
How's Amos?
- Gone.
- Already?
Thanks a lot, Sarah.
I wasn't making fun of you, Ma.
Are you calling for some money?
No, I don't need any money.
I was just thinking...
I was thinking maybe I'd drive out.
Maybe I'd come out for a week or so.
You're in trouble, right?
No, I'm not in any trouble, Ma.
I just figured...
I'm going away.
- Where?
- Florida.
That sounds like fun.
Listen, Ma,
you have a good time, okay?
Hey, how's Sadi doing?
She's fine. I just got her
a new flea collar, so...
Will I talk to you soon?
Yeah, real soon.
It's kind of expensive to call.
That's why I don't...
I've got to get up in two hours.
Yeah, all right.
You go back to sleep, Ma.
You take care.
- Bye.
- It's the one in the green sweater.
- The green sweater.
All right.
Back up, boys, just a second.
County sheriff. Your name Bob?
- Put your hands on the car.
- For what?
Because you're under arrest.
Put your hands on the car.
- For what?
- Put your hands on the car!
"You have the right
to remain silent.
If you give up the right
to remain silent...
anything you say, can and will be
used against you in a court of law.
You have a right to an attorney
during Questioning."
Paul, call my dad!
"If you can't afford an attorney,
one will be appointed to you.
You have the right
to make one phone call."
Do you understand the rights
I have just read to you?
- Yes.
- Fine. Join us.
We expect to indict
for first-degree felony.
My client has no prior record.
In a crime like this, there's
a risk of the defendants fleeing.
- Your Honor, my client...
- Release him to his family.
This is a crime of extreme violence.
The victim has safety concerns.
$ 10,000 each.
Could I have
a glass of water, please?
- She's not moving in.
- It's only two days.
That's what you said last time,
and she was here for three months.
Miss.
I ordered this well-done.
It's raw.
I'm sorry.
I'll have it for you in a minute.
Yeah, and I asked for some ketchup.
I'm just going
a little senile today.
Three men accused of raping
a woman at a local bar...
were released today on $ 10,000 bail.
Lawyers for the accused men
expressed confidence...
that the facts of the case
will reveal...
that the young woman
was not actually raped.
Our defense is simple.
There was no rape.
The so-called victim consented
to all of the alleged acts.
She put on a show, pure and simple.
Thank you, Marcia.
The on-again, off-again debate...
between the five candidates
vying for the council seat...
of Daniel Fine
now appears to be on again.
Representatives for the candidates
met four hours behind closed doors...
All right. Bye.
- Who is it?
- Kathryn Murphy.
Why did you let them out on bail?
I didn't let them out.
It's standard procedure.
Until a jury finds you guilty,
you're free if you can post bail.
The guy on the TV made it sound
like I did a live sex show.
That's not the last time
that that's gonna happen.
May I come in?
Oh, yeah. Come on in.
Sadi, shut up.
The bartender at the Dugout
said you were sick.
You went looking for me?
Well, I had to go to the doctor,
and nobody at work knows.
Come on, Sadi.
You want a seat?
Would you like something to drink?
I could really use a drink.
Thank you, no.
Just to smooth out
the edges a little bit, you know?
Listen, what time were you born?
I already told you
I didn't believe in that astrology.
Oh, so what? I do. What time?
- At night, 7:00, August 9.
- Oh. Where?
Portland. Do you always drink
to smooth out the edges?
Sometimes I'll take a hit of pot.
Why? You want some?
Did you have anything to drink
before you went to the Mill?
Or smoke anything?
Half a joint, a couple beers.
You know, nothing heavy.
- And while you were there?
- I don't know.
I mean, I wasn't
falling-down drunk or anything.
- How were you dressed?
- What's that supposed to mean?
It means were you dressed
provocatively?
Showing a lot of cleavage?
See-through blouse?
What difference does it matter?
They tore it off me!
Did how you dress make those guys
think they could have sex with you?
Did you put on a show?
What the hell are you talking about?
You saw me at the hospital!
You think I asked for that?
Is that what you think?
If that's what you think,
you get the fuck out of my house!
Why didn't you tell me
that you had a record?
Fuck you!
I ain't got no record.
You want to tell me about it?
All right.
I was helping my girlfriend move
with a U-Haul.
We were going through Jersey,
and we ran into this cop.
He sees we got a busted tail light,
and he pulls us over.
He starts looking through her desk
and stuff she's got in the back...
and he finds a half gram of coke.
It was her desk.
It wasn't my stuff.
- So why is it still on the books?
- I don't know. You tell me!
I mean, my record
was definitely...
- Expunged?
- Yeah, expunged.
Have you ever made love
to more than one man at a time?
What the fuck
kind of Question is that?
It's the kind of Question
you're gonna be asked on the stand.
You're also gonna be asked if a man
has ever hit you and you liked it.
You're also gonna be asked
about your drug bust...
and how many drinks a day you have
to smooth out the edges.
And how many joints.
And how often
you go to bars alone...
and whether or not you wear
underwear when you go to them...
and which diseases you've caught
and how many abortions you've had.
And I will object
to all those Questions.
And sometimes the judge will
sustain me, but sometimes not.
That ain't fair.
You're a witness, and it's the
defense's job to show the jury...
that you're a rotten witness because
you've got a rotten character.
I got a rotten character?
You ain't gonna defend me
because I'm some low-class bimbo?
I didn't say that.
Will those bastards go to jail?
Is that what you want?
I want those motherfuckers
put away forever!
Sarah said that you were here
with her that night.
Yeah, I was here,
but I didn't see what happened.
But if Sarah says she was raped,
she was raped.
Can you identify any of the men
who assaulted her?
No. I was out there.
There were a bunch of guys
blocking the door...
so I really couldn't see.
It was the end of my shift,
so I left while she was still here.
Do you know any of these guys?
There's a bunch of them
that were real rowdy.
You know, yelling, clapping.
I really just thought
she was partying, you know?
Well, is there anyone
that you can identify?
Like how?
Did you notice anything
different about any of them?
Let's say long hair,
beard, moustache?
Birthmark, bandana, jewelry?
- Scar, tattoo?
- Tattoo, yeah.
- Well, can you describe it?
- A scorpion.
This one guy, he had a scorpion.
How many drinks
would you say she'd had?
I don't know.
She was pretty loaded.
She'd just had this big fight
with Larry...
the guy she lives with...
She just needed
to cool out a little.
What do you know about Larry?
Not much, except he's an asshole.
I mean, he says he's a musician,
but he's just a dealer.
And he rides a motorcycle.
Come on, man, give me a break.
These guys are my bread and butter.
You didn't see anyone else?
Some kid I never seen before played
one of the video machines all night.
- Who was with him?
- Nobody I saw.
I'll tell you what, Jesse. I'm gonna
inform the state liquor authority...
and tell them how
you kept serving up booze...
while a violent felony was being
committed in your back room.
- Ready?
- Thanks, Jesse.
We'll talk.
I need these by 11:00.
See you tomorrow.
Is he free?
Game time. Let's go.
Hang on just a second.
I don't believe this.
I really don't believe this.
Tina!
- Where the hell are the tickets?
- Gave them to me to hold.
- How are you doing on Tobias?
- We'll talk about it at the game.
If Charley calls,
I'll be home after 11:00.
Hey, ref! Cross-checking!
Open your eyes, will ya!
Take him out, Donovan!
Take him out!
- You two, play hockey!
- Did you see that? Thanks.
Thanks. Now, if I take it
to trial, they'll destroy her.
She walked in there alone,
she got drunk, she got stoned.
She came on to them.
She's got a prior for possession.
- That's inadmissible.
- Penalty.
Sure, it's inadmissible,
but they'll ask her about it.
I'll object, the judge will sustain
it, but the jury will hear it.
- She's a sitting duck.
- I read her Q and A.
Gang rape on a pinball machine.
It's an ugly case.
Is it winnable?
We understand
that you love to win...
but I can't let you dismiss
just because you don't have a lock.
A lock? I don't have a case.
Her girlfriend didn't see anything.
The bartender didn't see anything.
The others didn't think
anything special was going on.
Now, I got Polito...
but the minute the defense brings up
that he's on probation...
they'll know that we squeezed him.
What about the guy who reported it?
I have his voice on tape...
but we don't know who he is
or where to look for him.
Well, do you believe she was raped?
Yes, but I can't win it.
But they can't walk.
So make a deal and put them away.
- A deal with what?
- You got enough. Go for rape two.
So, any felony, as long
as it's a violent one... assault...
coercion, reckless endangerment,
menacing...
- I can't do that.
- You said she was raped.
So make a deal
and put them away.
I don't care if they only get
six months, just make a deal.
You understand, Mr. Polito,
that you'll be testifying...
before a grand jury and at a trial?
Yeah, I got that.
And you realize that you'll be
testifying against acquaintances?
Yeah.
Have I or anyone
in the sheriff's department...
or anyone in the district
attorney's office...
offered you any inducement
to testify?
Money, gifts, anything?
Thank you, Mr. Polito.
Well, he's just a taste.
The bar was filled with witnesses.
We know who they are, and we
anticipate that they'll all testify.
Anticipate? A hundred says you'll
have to drag them into court.
Another hundred says they'll be
useless because they were too drunk.
Whatever you say.
Keep in mind that we don't need
corroboration to prove rape.
And we do have medical evidence...
No doubt about penetration...
and physical evidence...
no doubt about force.
- What will you take?
- Rape one.
We were thinking more in the line
of, say, sexual abuse two.
Rape one.
Maybe I could convince the judge
not to give them the maximum.
- I'd rather go to trial.
- Fine.
Oh, by the way, no separate deals.
One goes to trial,
all go to trial.
What would you say
to sexual abuse one?
I'd say rape one.
Kathryn, cut the crap.
This guy Polito looks like shit.
If you had anybody better,
you'd have shown us his tape.
And your complaining witness...
She walked into a bar...
got loaded and stoned and did
everything but yank their dicks.
- No jury will buy her.
- What would you say to rape two...
with a recommendation for one year?
I'd say go to hell.
Are you sure you're in a position
to be Quite so adamant?
- A rape trial...
- Is always a gamble.
I agree, Mr. Henley,
and I know your reputation.
But look at these photographs!
This is what the jury will see,
and they'll see the girl too.
And you can't tell it from these,
but she's tiny.
She's the most defenseless-looking
thing you ever saw.
If we go to trial and you lose,
I'm gonna ask for 15 to 25...
and I'll get it.
- Eighteen months.
- Stop dancing.
What's your best offer?
Two to five, rape two.
With luck, your boys will be out
in nine months. That's a gift.
On one condition. I'll accept that
on behalf of my client...
if the formal charge is changed
to one without the sexual element.
He's a kid of 22.
He's an "A" student.
- He's got a future.
- I can't do that.
He won't plead guilty
to a sexual offense.
Assault? Coercion?
Reckless endangerment?
- Malicious...
- Reckless endangerment.
The theft occurred
about 5:30 a. M...
as the woman and her husband
were entering their house.
Three men accused of raping
a young woman at a local bar...
pleaded guilty today to a reduced
charge of reckless endangerment.
They were sentenced to two
and a half to five years in prison.
Neither the district attorney
nor spokesman for the defense...
would officially comment
on the plea bargain.
No explanation was given for
the reduction in the charges...
from rape to reckless endangerment.
A source close to the defense
hinted that it was because...
the young woman who was
the alleged victim in the case...
would not have made
a strong witness for the state.
Oh, come on! You?
- It was red.
- Red?
- Where do you want these?
- There.
I think this looks raw.
- Oh, shit!
- I'll get it.
Thanks.
Here we go. This is an experiment,
so I want you all to be kind.
Excuse me!
You double-crossing bitch!
You sold me out!
Did you see this?
Is this what you did?
- Excuse us.
- I wouldn't make a good witness?
I'm too fragile.
My past is too Questionable.
I'm a drunk.
I'm a pothead, a drug addict!
I'm some slut that got bounced
around a little bit in a bar, right?
So I didn't get raped, huh?
I never got raped?
- Of course you were raped.
- How come it doesn't say that?
How come it doesn't say,
"Sarah Tobias was raped"?
What the fuck
is reckless endangerment?
It's a felony that carries
the same prison term as rape.
You asked me to put them away,
and that's exactly what I did.
Who the hell are you to decide that
I ain't good enough to be a witness?
I'll bet you if I went to law school
and I didn't live in some dump...
I understand how you feel.
I did my best.
You under...
You don't understand how I feel!
I'm standing there
with my pants down...
and my crotch hung out
for the world to see...
and three guys
are sticking it to me...
and a bunch of other guys
are yelling and clapping...
and you're standing there telling me
that that's the best you can do!
If that's the best you can do,
then your best sucks!
I don't know what you got
for selling me out...
but I sure as shit
hope it's worth it!
Wow. What did you do?
- That looks weird.
- I needed a change.
Hey, it's nothing heavy.
It's just...
I'm not used to it.
Stop. All right? Stop.
When are you gonna get over this?
You'll have to snap out of this
soon, 'cause it's getting boring.
Get out of here.
Fine.
- Be back in a couple hours.
- No!
You get the fuck out
and don't come back.
Shit, you can cut your fucking hair
any way you want.
This is my house,
and I don't want you in it.
- Now, get out.
- Fine. I'm gone.
You caught me.
I'm sorry.
This is gonna sound like crap,
but I seen you somewhere...
You're right. It's crap.
I have seen you. You're a friend
of Johnny Alworth's sister, right?
It was Duck Island. Last
Sunday afternoon, softball game.
Your hair was different.
- Yes. It was longer.
- Look, I live with somebody, okay?
I got it. Sorry.
He's a lucky guy.
You sure you don't
want to go out tonight?
Oh, I got a smile!
Well, it's a start.
Hey, Sexy Sadi, what about it?
I told you,
I live with somebody!
- I don't mind. I'm liberated.
- I do. I mind.
- I do know you, Sexy Sadi.
- You got me mixed up with somebody.
No. You're the girl
from the Mill that night.
I remember Sexy Sadi!
I do know you! Am I right?
Hey, Sexy Sadi!
I know you!
Oh, do I remember you!
Hey, look, lady!
Hey, want to play pinball?
I've always paid my bills!
I'm sick and tired of this!
- There's nothing I can do.
- Come on.
- I'm sorry.
- Come on!
I'm sorry about this.
But I do know
that I did make the payment.
- There's no records?
- The insurance company I paid.
- I just can't find them.
- Well, my husband...
- This is it.
- Come on, babe!
I'll phone you. Thanks.
You can go in now.
Keep it short.
Thanks.
What happened?
- "Want to play pinball?"
- What?
That's what he said.
"You want to play pinball?"
He sees I'm a piece of shit.
Everybody figures
I'm a piece of shit.
Why not?
You told them that. I never
got to tell nobody nothing.
You did all my talking for me.
I don't get it.
I thought you were on my side.
You told me you were on my side.
Why did you do that?
Sorry, Officer, but
it's been one of those days.
My insurance is no good.
I pay all my bills!
- What happens?
- Come on!
I want to tell the officer.
I'm sorry, okay?
- How's your head?
- Oh, great! Just great.
Honey, just wait here.
I'll go get the car.
Excuse me, sir.
I'm sorry to bother you.
What exactly happened?
Exactly, she rammed my truck.
I was minding my own business.
She drove her car into my truck.
- All right?
- Do you know why?
How do I know why she rammed me?
She's nuts!
- Do you know her?
- No, I don't know her.
She's a whore. Last time I saw her,
she was doing a sex show.
- Come on!
- You watched?
You bet your ass I watched.
She put on a great show.
- I thought she was raped.
- Raped?
She fucked a bar full of guys,
then she blamed them.
Listen, lady, she loved it.
She did the show of her life.
- Come on, move over!
- Honey, do you think...
Next time she does another show,
tell her I'll be there to cheer.
I'd like to report
there's a girl in trouble.
Sir, may I have your name?
There's a girl in trouble
at a bar on Mill Road.
Sir, I'm sorry.
I must have your name.
There's three or four guys.
I don't know.
There's a whole crowd.
There's an assault going on.
There's three or four guys.
I don't know.
There's a whole crowd.
Send somebody, okay?
"Or otherwise attempts to persuade
another person to commit a felony."
Please, I know
about criminal solicitation.
But in this case,
it simply doesn't apply.
- It's not the statute's intent.
- Listen again.
"A person is guilty
of criminal solicitation...
if he commands, induces, entreats...
or otherwise attempts to persuade
another person to commit a felony."
You can read it to me
till you're blue in the face.
I am not gonna let you prosecute
a bunch of spectators.
They're not spectators.
They solicited the rape.
Do you really want to ask a jury
to lock up a bunch of people...
for clapping and cheering?
Clapping, cheering,
pushing, goading...
getting the rape going
and keeping it going.
What happens if you lose?
You'll look like an incompetent.
If you win, you'll look
like a vengeful bitch.
Either way, you hurt yourself
and you hurt this office.
Now, drop it. You've got
more important things to do.
No, I haven't.
You haven't got more important
things to do...
than go to trial
with a sure loser?
- What the hell has gotten into you?
- We owe her.
Owe her what?
We put the rapists away.
- I owe her.
- I see.
You want to spend my money to put
a bunch of spectators on trial...
a trial you'll lose,
because you owe her!
You don't get to use this office
to pay your debts.
I am gonna try this case,
and you're not gonna stop me.
I'm not?
Kathryn, you're an ace.
You've got a great future.
Don't put it in jeopardy.
What are you gonna do, fire me?
Go right ahead.
My first case will be a civil suit
against the rapists...
the solicitors,
the bar and the state.
And I will show that Sarah Tobias
wound up in the hospital...
because this office sold her out.
I will subpoena your records,
put you on the stand...
and cross-examine you on every
plea bargain this office ever made.
You go try your case!
You have a good time!
Because win or lose,
you're through!
What are you looking at?
Get back to work!
I'd like to talk to you.
May I come in?
We got nothing to talk about.
- Yes, we...
- Get outta here!
- Who the hell do you think you are?
- I have to talk to you.
- Get out of my house.
- Will you listen to me, please?
I'm listening.
Sarah, I made a mistake.
Before I agreed to the deal...
I should have offered you
the choice of testifying at a trial.
I can offer that to you now.
I found a way for you to go to court
and testify that you were raped.
- The case is over.
- The rape case, sure.
You made sure of that.
I want to prosecute the others.
The ones who cheered and clapped.
- The ones who made it happen.
- So you can make another deal?
No. I'm not gonna make
any more deals.
If I prosecute the others,
the rapists will stay in jail...
for the full five years,
and the rape will go on record.
The deal won't matter
because the rape will go on record.
You really want to do that?
Only if you help me.
I need you to testify.
- I get to tell my story?
- Yes.
You alone now?
Yeah. I kicked him out.
While I was laid up, he came back
to pick up all his stuff, you know?
What's his is his.
What's mine is his.
- Thank God he left me the radio.
- Anything I can do?
Yeah.
What?
No deals.
It's Kathryn Murphy.
Listen, I need your help again.
Hey, come on. Cut it out.
- Are these yours?
- Let's play.
- Go play someplace else now, okay?
- Come on, let's go!
- Come over here.
- Okay, I'm coming.
I thought it was all over.
I'm gonna prosecute the ones
that cheered it on.
You said of the guys
blocking your view...
that they were real rowdy,
yelling and clapping.
Not the guys at the door.
The ones by the pinball machine.
So you knew that
they were yelling about Sarah?
Yeah, but they aren't the kind of
guys you really want to mess with.
You know what I mean?
Listen, I'd like you to come in
and see if you could identify them.
Oh, Jesus! They're gonna be
right there, aren't they?
- Yes.
- I don't know.
Let's make a date for you to come
into to my office and talk about it.
Sally, she's your friend.
Number two.
Seven.
You positive?
Yes.
Number four, definitely.
Do you believe it?
You can go in now. It's down to
the end of the hall to your right.
There's no purpose in meeting again,
because I'm taking them to trial.
Well, good luck to you too.
- Thank you for coming.
- It's okay.
- There's no need for you to come.
- I figured she needs the company.
Would you mind waiting outside?
Would you please hold my calls?
I'll wait outside.
Sally, why don't you have a seat
right down here, okay?
I want to begin by asking you
a few Questions...
about the night of April 18th.
I'd like you to answer them
as simply and honestly as possible.
A few. Maybe three.
I've seen her drink
a lot more than that.
She needed to get loose. She'd just
had this big fight with her old man.
And she goes,
"I'm so pissed at him"...
'cause she's sure
he's running around on her.
You mean sleeping around, right?
Right. Which I bet he is.
So we were sitting in a booth,
and we were just sort of talking...
There were these two
fraternity guys there.
And Sarah looks
at one of them... Bob.
She goes, "He's cute. Who's he?"
So we started joking around.
What do you mean, joking around?
Well, like what would be
the best way to get back at Larry.
Like should she take this guy home
and do it right in front of him.
You said that
she should take Bob home?
No. She said it. She didn't mean it.
She was just joking around.
Well, she'd had a few drinks.
God, she didn't mean it.
- I'll wait for you downstairs.
- Wait a minute.
- I want to talk to you.
- What's going on?
- I warned you... no secrets.
- I didn't keep any secrets.
She told me what you said
in the bar when you met Bob.
Do you remember? Do you?
I said I'd like
to take that guy home...
and fuck his brains out
right in front of Larry.
- It was a joke.
- She can't be a witness for you.
In fact, when the defense finds her,
she'll be a witness for them.
What other surprises
have you got waiting for me?
None.
I'm sorry.
Is Jesse around?
No, it's his day off.
Can I get you a drink?
No, thank you.
- Mr. Joyce?
- Hi.
I'm Deputy District Attorney
Kathryn Murphy.
I'd like to talk about April 18.
- The night of the rape at the Mill.
- I don't know anything.
Yes, you do, Mr. Joyce. Do you
wanna talk about it over here?
- Sorry, I got a class.
- Your class can wait.
You were there.
Your name is on the video machine.
I'm calling you as a witness.
Would you like to sit down
and we can talk about it?
What do you want?
You got the ones who did it.
I'm prosecuting the others...
the ones who cheered them on.
I didn't see a thing.
Yes, you did.
You were in the room all night.
You saw everything.
Those other guys
didn't do anything.
They probably didn't even know
what was going on.
I mean, it was like a show.
Big deal. They watched.
If you asked a thousand people,
999 would watch. It's no crime.
They did more than watch,
and that is a crime.
You want to tell me about it?
Look, if you don't tell me now...
you're gonna have to tell me
on the witness stand.
Why? Why? This isn't my business.
I don't care about this.
Yes, you do.
Birchfield County Emergency.
I'd like to report
this girl in trouble.
Your name, please?
There's a girl in trouble
at the Mill. It's a bar.
- I must have your name.
- There's an assault. It's a rape!
There's three or four...
And arriving at the courthouse
is Kathryn Murphy...
the deputy district attorney
in this precedent-setting case.
With her is Sarah Tobias.
This is our first chance
to see the victim in the case.
Will you put Miss Tobias
on the stand?
- No comment.
- Who else are you putting on?
- Are your friends gonna testify?
- Son of a bitch!
- We hear you made a deal.
No comment.
What were you thinking
when it happened?
Are you deaf, asshole?
No comment!
You'll wait here for the officer.
What are you doing here?
Moral support.
Saw Whitewood having breakfast.
Seemed in a really good mood.
Good luck, Sarah.
Please come in.
Do you swear to tell the truth,
so help you God?
- I do.
- State your name.
- Sarah Tobias.
- Please be seated.
Miss Tobias, on the night
of the rape at the Mill...
Objection!
These men are not on trial
for rape.
Your Honor, it is imperative
that the jury understand...
what was happening to Miss Tobias
before, during and after the rape.
You may continue your line
of Questioning, but be brief.
Thank you, Your Honor.
Miss Tobias, please tell us what
happened that night at the Mill.
Well, my boyfriend...
My boyfriend and I
had kind of a fight.
So I got in my car and drove to see
my girlfriend Sally at the Mill.
I figured she'd be getting off
work, and we could talk.
She works there?
Yeah. She's a waitress,
just like me.
So, anyway, she was on a break.
We were sitting
in this booth, talking...
and this guy Danny
sent over a couple drinks.
She knew him,
so we took the drinks.
He sat down, and...
we started talking.
And he was funny.
You know, he had a line.
So what happened next?
A bunch of guys went
into the back room to play pinball.
So me and Danny went in and started
playing with this guy Bob.
And after I finished my turn,
I went to smoke.
You know, smoke a little pot.
And...
Somebody put money
into the jukebox...
and this song I really liked
came on the jukebox.
So I started to dance.
And then Danny comes up...
and he starts dancing with me...
real close, you know,
tight, close.
And then he kissed me.
I'm sorry, Miss Tobias.
Could you please speak up?
He kissed me.
Did you try to stop him?
No. I let him kiss me,
because I figured...
he was drunk and stoned and that he
would kiss me and leave me alone.
And then he...
put his hand up my shirt
and grabbed at my breast.
I tried to push him away,
but he kept pulling me closer.
And he put his hand
on my throat.
And he's a really strong guy,
you know.
And the next thing I knew...
Please go on, Miss Tobias.
He was squeezing
my throat with his hands...
and he pushed me down
on the pinball machine.
And he ripped my shirt.
He lifted my skirt.
He pulled down my underpants
really, really hard.
I get...
I wanted to move...
but he was holding me down
really hard and he was jamming...
He was kissing me very hard...
and he was jamming his hand
up my crotch.
I heard a bunch
of people yelling...
"Hold her down! Hold her down!"
And then the big guy,
Kurt, held my arms down...
and I could hear them yelling
and clapping and cheering.
And then...
Danny put his hands over
my mouth and over my face.
And I shut my eyes.
He was inside of me.
And then...
And then they switched.
I could hear them saying,
"Frat boy, frat boy."
And then Bob was inside of me...
And there was all this yelling
and clapping and laughing.
And then I heard them
call for Kurt, "needle dick."
And then they switched again...
and Kurt was inside of me.
They were yelling,
"Kurt, Kurt, Kurt."
And there was...
There was all this chanting.
Please continue, Miss Tobias.
What did they chant?
Something, uh...
"Poke that pussy."
The room was full of people
cheering this on?
Yeah. I kicked him.
I kicked him really hard.
And I ran out into the road and...
This guy picked me up
and took me to the hospital.
No further Questions,
Your Honor.
Miss Tobias,
my name is Ben Wainwright.
Now, I know
this isn't easy for you...
so I'm gonna ask you
only a handful of Questions.
You have testified that all the men
present were strangers to you.
You also testified that while you
were on the pinball machine...
that you mostly kept
your eyes closed.
Is that right?
Your eyes were closed?
Yes, sometimes.
Is it fair to say
you can't tell us who applauded...
or who shouted?
- Is that fair?
- L...
Is it possible that
only one person shouted?
No. There were
different voices.
So at least two, then.
Could it have been only two?
No. They overlapped.
Miss Tobias, you testified that
you were assaulted by three men.
Is that right?
Yes.
Okay. Is it possible...
I'm just saying possible...
that the only ones who shouted
were among your assaulters?
No. The voices were coming
from further away.
You had had several drinks.
You had smoked marijuana.
The TV was playing.
The jukebox was playing.
You were in a room full of noisy
video games and pinball machines.
You had your eyes closed,
sometimes.
And you were being assaulted.
Now, given these conditions...
can you truly say
how many voices you heard...
and where those voices
were coming from?
Is it fair to say, then,
that you can't tell us...
who applauded or who shouted?
Is that fair?
Yes, that's fair.
Okay. Thank you.
While you were on
the pinball machine...
did you at any time
cry "help" or "rape"?
No. I tried, but they were
covering my mouth.
They were either kissing me or they
had their hands all over my mouth.
I kept saying no.
Right. No.
L... No. I said no.
Not "rape" or "help" or "police."
But "no."
Right. No.
- Did anybody hear you?
- I don't know.
Did you signal to anybody?
Say, a hand signal?
No. My hands were
pinned down, right?
Signal to anybody
with your eyes?
- Were you struggling?
- Yes!
Anybody see you struggling?
They must have.
Can you in any way prove to us
that someone in that room...
saw you struggling
or heard you say no?
No more Questions.
Miss Tobias, while you were being
gang-raped, what were you thinking?
- Thinking?
- What words came into your head?
Three men were repeatedly raping
you, holding you down...
Your Honor, prosecution...
and their friends cheered.
You lay there naked, struggling,
every part of you in pain.
What words came into your head?
What words?
"No."
No further Questions,
Your Honor.
The witness is excused.
- How you doing?
- Good.
Good.
Did you cut the whole day?
No big deal. How you doing?
I've been better. So how's
everything? What am I missing?
Listen. They're prosecuting
those guys.
The other guys in the bar
who were cheering.
They're making me testify,
so you have nothing to worry about.
I just wanted to tell you
anyway.
Nothing to worry about?
Are you out of your fucking mind?
- You're not even on trial.
- What are you gonna say?
I'm gonna tell them
what happened.
- And what happened?
- Come on, man. You know.
A bunch of guys were cheering
and yelling and stuff.
You, Kurt and Danny.
You raped her.
Who said I raped her?
I'm not in here for rape.
Did you see me rape her, Ken?
What do you think?
You didn't, did you?
Yes, I did, Bob.
Ken, if you say that,
you know what happens to me?
- Nothing's gonna happen!
- No.
Instead of nine months, the parole
board will make it five years.
You don't understand.
They're making me do this.
No. All they can do is call you.
They can't make you say anything.
You don't remember. You were drunk.
You were too confused
to get it straight.
I don't want to lie.
You want to visit me
the next five years?
Hi. I hope you like it black.
I do, thanks.
I meant to tell you...
this week, Leos,
they frighten away friends...
Not now, Sarah, please.
Sorry.
Excuse us, Miss Murphy.
Mr. Joyce has something
to tell you and Miss Tobias.
Mr. Joyce has told me he doesn't
remember the events in Question.
He only told you what he did
because you coerced him.
If you put him on the stand,
he will recant.
He'll take it all back.
Did you have something
to do with this?
I suggest you notify the court and
the defense he won't be testifying.
In fact, it might be less awkward
to move for immediate dismissal.
Wait right here one minute.
Why?
I don't remember. I only told her
what I told her...
'cause she forced me to.
If she makes me take the stand,
I'm gonna recant it all.
Why?
I don't remember anything.
You're full of shit.
Where do you get off telling me
I'm full of shit? I was there.
Right. You were there.
You saw me have a few drinks.
You saw me blow some grass.
You saw me flirt a little bit.
And then you saw me gang-raped,
and you think I had it coming.
You're just like all the others.
Would you look?
My best friend is in prison.
If I do this, they're gonna
keep him for five years.
Right. Your best friend
is some great guy...
and I'm just
this lowlife whore...
that he raped
right in front of you.
You're not like all the others,
you're worse.
That's not true.
I'm not like that.
Okay?
Are you scared?
Yeah.
Me too.
Your Honor, the people call
Kenneth Joyce.
Do you swear to tell
the whole truth, so help you God?
- I do.
- State your name.
Kenneth Joyce.
Be seated, please.
Mr. Joyce, were you in the Mill the night
of the events involving Sarah Tobias?
Yes.
Would you please recount for us
what happened?
Well, it was late, and me and my
friend Bob had been to the game.
Then afterwards, he took me
to this bar he sometimes goes to.
The Mill. We had been there for
a while when this girl walked in.
She was really sexy.
And she was sitting
at the table behind us...
talking to her friend
while this guy Danny...
he was sitting
at the end of the bar.
He saw her come in too, and he sent
the bartender over with drinks.
So I'm washing dishes.
Then I hear Bonnie screaming her
head off, and go, "Oh, great."
So Chip walks out
in cowboy boots...
and goes, "I didn't just kick her
in the head."
- Hey, dude. What's going on?
- I don't know.
He's cute. Who's he?
Oh, Bob something.
Some college guy.
I should take him home and fuck
his brains out in front of Larry.
Yeah, right!
Can I watch?
Behind you.
Blonde girl.
Wants me in a big way.
Jess.
Jesse, come here.
Here we go, ladies.
Compliments of the gentleman
at the end of the bar.
What do you think he'd do?
Evening, ladies.
Danny, this is my friend Sarah.
Thanks for the drinks, Danny.
Well, it was my pleasure, Sarah.
Well, you talking shop?
No. We're talking
modern romances.
Yeah? Well, I'm a romantic.
That makes me
just like you, Sarah.
You are one romantic-looking girl.
Woman.
It's your turn.
- Romantic, huh? Romantic?
- She didn't come with me.
She didn't!
You don't have to
take my word for it.
Just walk in the back
and see for yourself.
- This is the game room.
- Oh, yeah?
Then she got up and followed him
into the game room.
Pretty soon they were playing
pinball and getting really loaded.
- Ooh. I get 100.
- That's a double.
- She's on a roll!
- You better shut up.
Oh, I don't want to
distract you, now, do I?
- Yeah!
- Line it up.
Line it up again.
Pay up now. She can score.
Yeah! Go, go, go, go!
Yeah! You lose.
- No. I'm a winner. I don't lose.
- Check the score.
Look at that.
- Like I said, lucky.
- Lucky, my ass. You wish.
Yeah?
Looks like your hand's
connected to her ass.
What's your problem?
Who is she?
Get her out of here. I hate her.
I don't know.
- You're up.
- All right. Maybe next time.
Hey, knock it off.
- Go for it.
- I'm gonna.
You gonna keep that
all to yourself?
Yeah.
- Didn't your mom teach you manners?
- No.
- Angela, put some music on.
- I don't have any change.
Hey, Angie, I got some change.
You're so funny,
I can't stand it.
That's what everybody tells me.
I like that.
So modest too.
Very modest.
Let's get out of here.
- Look who's bossy.
- I'll even let you drive.
- You know how to drive?
- You know how to walk?
I think you're
the funniest girl here.
You're not as funny as me.
- Let's get out of here.
- No. Oh, I love this song.
- Are you off, honey?
- Yeah. I don't like the show.
God, I hope it's gonna be me.
Young lady.
Have you been drinking tonight?
Me? Oh, no, Officer.
Hey, listen. I gotta go,
'cause I gotta work tomorrow.
- I'm a working thing.
- I'll pay you whatever they pay.
I'm too drunk.
I got to go home.
Mr. Funny Man, I gotta go.
Come on!
Wait a minute.
No, l...
Go, Danny! Stick 'em.
Right!
All right! Yeah!
Come on. Go for it!
Danny's gonna fuck her right there!
Grab her hands, Kurt.
Go for it, Danny!
Come on, big guy!
Smell that new blood, baby.
Come on, she's loving it!
Hey, college boy, you're next!
Fuck it, bro! Yeah!
That's it, man.
Go, go!
Has been effective
shooting that right hand.
Burt has been landing
significant body shots.
If he can keep doing that...
Get the frat boy in there!
Go on!
Come on, move!
Go get her, frat boy!
That's it!
Pump that fucking college ass!
- Go, go!
- Stick it to her!
Don't stop! Hold her down!
Is she ready to come?
I can't see.
Hold her down.
Make her moan!
Make her fucking moan!
Hold her down!
Make her moan!
Hey, Kurt! Come on!
Watch the kid,
you might learn something.
Shut the fuck up, asshole!
Listen to needle dick!
You a faggot?
You let them talk to you
like that? You a faggot?
You pull down your pants,
we'll see silk panties, huh?
You shut the fuck up!
- You got the champion!
- Here comes Kurt!
Go. Fucking get her!
Gonna see his panties!
You're next, huh?
In control.
Burt is trying
to apply the pressure here.
One, two, three, four.
Poke that pussy till it's sore!
Mr. Joyce, do you believe...
that Sarah Tobias
instigated that rape?
No, I don't.
Thank you.
So?
So Ken helped.
Larry, I don't know.
Jesse hurt.
What about Sally?
Bad, huh?
Shit!
You want to go for a drink?
No. I have to
put together my summation.
What are our chances?
50-50 at best.
Good night.
Your Honor, my colleagues have
agreed to a single summation.
No objection, Your Honor.
Ladies and gentlemen...
the state has charged
these three men with a crime.
The state has
supported that charge...
with the testimony
of two witnesses.
Sarah Tobias...
who told you
how three men raped her...
and she told you how she heard
other men...
shouting encouragement
to her attackers.
Did she name these other men?
No. Did she describe
these other men?
No. Could she tell you
what these other men shouted?
No.
Her sworn testimony... her poignant,
heart-rending sworn testimony...
was an appeal to your pity.
And if her story is true,
you should pity her.
But even if her story
is true and you do pity her...
that has nothing to do
with this case.
Because those three men
did not rape her.
Her sworn testimony is nothing...
and you must treat it as nothing.
Now...
if you wish, you can also treat
as nothing...
the testimony of her lover,
Larry...
who told you
what kind of woman she is.
You can treat as nothing
the testimony of the bartender...
Jesse, who told you that she was
so drunk she could barely stand.
And you can treat as nothing the
testimony of her friend, Sally...
who told you what
Miss Tobias's intentions were...
when she first saw our clients.
Our case does not
depend on those witnesses...
just as the People's case
does not depend on Sarah Tobias.
The People's case...
depends on Kenneth Joyce.
If you believe him,
you'll convict those three men...
and if you don't,
you'll acquit them.
Do you believe him?
Why did Kenneth Joyce testify?
Every day, for months,
he said to himself, "I'm guilty."
Finally he was offered a way to
purge that guilt, and he took it.
Kenneth Joyce told you
he watched a rape.
He told you everyone else
in that room watched a rape.
How did he know that?
Did he read their minds?
To solicit a crime, you must first
know it is a crime.
Well, who knew it?
Kenneth Joyce.
Do you think it matters
to Kenneth Joyce who shouted?
In his mind, every person
in that room was guilty.
He told you that.
And Kenneth Joyce...
who is guilty...
who did watch a rape
and do nothing...
will purge himself by bringing down
anyone who was in that room.
And, of course,
at no legal cost to himself...
while those three men
face prison.
Do you believe him?
Well, if you do, convict.
And if you don't...
and I know you don't...
acquit.
Miss Murphy.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Mr. Paulsen has told you
that the testimony...
of Sarah Tobias is nothing.
Sarah Tobias was raped,
but that is nothing.
She was cut and bruised
and terrorized...
but that is nothing.
All of it happened
in front of a howling crowd...
and that is nothing.
Well, it may be nothing
to Mr. Paulsen...
but it is not nothing
to Sarah Tobias.
And I don't believe
it's nothing to you.
Next Mr. Paulsen
tried to convince you...
that Kenneth Joyce was
the only person in that room...
who knew that Sarah Tobias
was being raped.
The only one.
Now, you watched Kenneth Joyce.
How did he strike you?
Did he seem
especially sensitive?
Especially observant?
Did he seem so remarkable
that you said to yourselves...
"Of course. This man would notice
things other people wouldn't."
Do you believe Kenneth Joyce
saw something...
those three men didn't see?
In all the time Sarah was held down
on that pinball machine...
the others didn't know?
Kenneth Joyce confessed to you...
that he watched a rape
and did nothing.
He told you that everyone
in that bar behaved badly.
And he's right.
But no matter
how immoral it may be...
it is not the crime
of criminal solicitation...
to walk away from a rape.
It is not the crime
of criminal solicitation...
to silently watch a rape.
But it is the crime
of criminal solicitation...
to induce or entreat
or encourage...
or persuade another person
to commit a rape.
"Hold her down. Stick it to her.
Make her moan."
These three men
did worse than nothing.
They cheered and they clapped...
and they rooted the others on.
They made sure that Sarah Tobias
was raped...
and raped and raped.
Now...
you tell me...
is that nothing?
- What time is it?
- You just asked me that.
They want Ken Joyce's testimony
read to them again.
I don't get it.
That's the third time for him.
How come they never
ask for mine?
Because they believed you.
Oh, look. I did your chart. You're
gonna like this. This is great.
The tenth house
is really something.
Saturn in the tenth house
is career and ambition.
Mercury ruling the tenth...
public work.
And you had Sun and Pluto
in the tenth.
That's law
and higher understanding.
I mean, I'm telling you...
the tenth house
is really excellent.
You could be president
or something.
What about you?
What's your future?
Oh, I forgot it at home.
Don't you remember it?
Yeah, it's just...
seventh house mostly.
It's like, uh, feelings, faith...
intuition, mystery.
Really useful shit.
Do I have any of that?
Yeah. Yeah, you do.
You got a little bit right there.
See that?
Keep it.
I was going to sign it,
but I figured...
you're really not
into that kind of stuff.
So...
Will you sign it, please?
Thank you.
Likewise.
Still no verdict in the
precedent-setting Tobias trial.
As the jury continues...
The second day, the jury is showing
no Quick verdict.
Many observers predict
the case will...
The jury has been out for two days.
Both sides express confidence...
but one thing is certain,
this will be an historic decision.
They're coming in.
Ladies and gentlemen,
have you reached a verdict?
We have, Your Honor.
Will the defendants
please rise and face the jury?
"We find the defendant
Matthew Haines...
guilty of criminal solicitation.
We find the defendant
Stuart Holloway...
guilty of criminal solicitation.
We find the defendant
Clifford Albrect...
guilty of criminal solicitation."
Sentence will be imposed
two weeks from today...
at 10:00.
This court is adjourned.
What was the deciding factor
in the case?
There were many
deciding factors.
What are your plans?
I'd like to go home
and play with my dog.