Good morning.
Here's the new dress
for Miss Sloper.
Thank you.
Miss Catherine,
it's your new dress.
Oh! Will you take it out of the box,
Maria, and hang it up?
Yes, miss.
Well, that's all, I think.
I'll be at the Harrisons'.
Yes, Doctor.
I may not get
to the clinic today at all.
Good morning, Lavinia.
Good morning, Austin.
Is Catherine starting
another of these things?
Yes. She embroiders
beautifully.
I hope she doesn't let it
become her life's work.
Austin,
yesterday I had the most exciting experience.
I met two people
from Poughkeepsie.
Oh, birth certificates.
They had been members
of my husband's congregation,
and when I told them I was stopping
with my brother, Dr. Sloper,
at 16 Washington Square,
they were so impressed.
It's just made my visit.
Lavinia, would you care
to spend the winter here?
The winter? Oh, gladly.
Good. I thought if you stayed on,
you might help Catherine.
Help her?
But help her how, Austin?
Well, for instance,
at Sister Elizabeth's party this evening.
Perhaps you could persuade Catherine to
join in freely with the young people.
Enjoy herself.
But of course she'll do that.
I hope so.
Six pounds.
That'll be 30 cents.
Could you please
cut off the head?
Yes, miss.
Kitty, kitty, kitty, kitty.
There you are.
Thank you.
Yes, ma'am.
Fresh fish, fresh fish.
Good morning, Father.
Good morning, Catherine.
I've bought a fine fish
for the chowder you like.
That's very thoughtful.
Next time, let the man carry it in for you.
Oh, yes, Father.
Coming.
It's a lovely morning.
Why don't you invite your Aunt Lavinia
or a friend to take luncheon with you,
perhaps go
to one of the park concerts?
I can't, Father.
I have some embroidery I'd like to attend to.
Yes.
Well,
I'll see you this evening.
Yes, Father. Goodbye.
Catherine?
Come in, Aunt Penniman.
Oh, you must hurry, dear.
You were a long time
at that hospital committee.
Too long.
Didn't you like it?
Oh, some of the ladies on the committee
are so foolish they're useless.
They think it ill-bred to know anything
about food or what is done in the kitchen.
Such airs and graces.
Now, when I was young,
we took pride in our housewifery.
My, when I think
of the meals I used to set
before the Reverend Penniman,
rest his soul.
Then you have deceived me, Aunt.
Why, how so?
You led me to believe that you
and he lived on love alone.
Now, dear, you see,
some little witticism like that
would be of interest to the
young people this evening.
It's a very good way
to get started.
What I mean is,
don't go off by yourself tonight,
will you?
Stay with all of us
and enjoy the party.
You have been talking
to Father.
Well, yes, dear.
In a way, I have.
You see,
your father feels...
Father would like me to be composed
and to join in the conversation.
Yes.
I can't, Aunt Lavinia.
Oh, dear, perhaps
you don't try sufficiently.
Oh, I do, I do.
I would do anything
to please him.
There's nothing that means
more to me than that.
I have sat here in my room and made
notes of the things I should say
and how I should say them.
But when I am in company,
it seems that no one
could want to listen to me.
Now, Catherine,
if you will stay by me this evening,
you will see that what I say is not
always of the greatest importance.
But, dear,
that doesn't keep me from talking.
Yes, Aunt.
Now, I'll finish dressing
and meet you downstairs.
Father?
Come in, Catherine.
Good evening, Father.
Do I disturb you?
You are not
a disturbing woman, my dear.
Do you like my dress?
Is it possible this magnificent
person is my daughter?
But you're sumptuous, opulent.
You look as if you had
$80,000 a year.
I thought you would like the color.
Yes.
It's cherry red.
So it is.
I believe
my mother used to wear it.
In her hair ribbons, Austin.
Yes.
But, Catherine,
your mother was fair.
She dominated the color.
Well, I must dress.
I'll try
not to keep you waiting.
Oh, I must pack our silver
punch cups for Aunt Elizabeth.
Now, Austin,
you do think it's entirely proper
for me to go
to Sister Elizabeth's party?
But of course. Why not?
Well, after all,
I'm still in mourning.
Lavinia, I know you'll bear your
sorrow with equal fortitude
whatever the surroundings.
That's right.
After all, I'm just as
grief-stricken no matter where I am.
You're wonderful.
Your Aunt Penniman has
made a conquest.
Yes.
Well, having a nice time,
Catherine?
Delightful,
Aunt Elizabeth.
So is Jefferson.
Well, Austin, who's sick?
Who's dead?
Who've you been
cutting up lately?
Yes, I can see
you're in good shape.
When your gout's troubling you,
you're more respectful to me.
Are you going to get up there
and make that announcement?
Yes, my dear.
Well, go on, go on.
All right, all right.
If he doesn't do it now,
he'll have to make it from under a table.
My good neighbors
and dear friends,
I am about to lose
the loveliest,
the most beautiful daughter,
the very dearest girl,
to a most wonderful young man,
to Arthur Townsend.
I am at once a sad
and a very lucky father.
I'd like you all
to toast my loss
and my gain.
To the happy couple.
Oh, Mama.
Oh, don't look so happy.
I'll be home for all my meals.
Uncle Austin.
Marian, my dear,
great happiness to both of you.
Thank you, sir.
Oh, Cathy, isn't it wonderful?
Isn't this a lovely party?
Come along, Arthur,
let's dance.
Excuse us.
Oh, Quintus,
you're not dancing?
No, ma'am.
You remember Catherine Sloper,
my niece?
Yes, indeed.
May I have the pleasure,
Catherine?
Thank you, Quintus.
Excuse me, Father.
Permit me, Catherine.
Oh, thank you, Father.
Do you suppose there's another Arthur
somewhere in this great city of ours?
Catherine will find a husband.
You think so?
Oh, she has the prospect
of $30,000 a year.
I see that you appreciate her.
I don't mean
it's her only merit,
but you always have a way of alluding
to her as an unmarriageable girl.
My allusions
are as kind as yours, Liz.
Do you suppose Jefferson has
left any of his French brandy?
Let's see.
May I get you some claret cup?
Oh, yes, thank you.
She's gone to the best schools
in the city.
She's had the finest training I
could get her. Music and dancing.
She's sat with me
evenings on end.
I've tried to make conversation with
her and give her some social adeptness.
I've given her freedom
wherever I could.
The result is what you see:
An entirely mediocre
and defenseless creature
with not a shred of poise.
But, Austin, you're so intolerant.
You expect so much.
You remember her mother, Liz?
Her mother,
who had so much grace and gaiety.
This is her child.
Austin, no child could compete with
this image you have of her mother.
You've idealized that poor dead
woman beyond all human recognition.
You are not entitled
to say that.
Only I know what I'd lost
when she died
and what I got in her place.
Catherine,
what are you doing here?
I'm waiting for Quintus Seabury.
He's bringing me some claret cup.
Well, don't wait here, dear.
Make him look for you.
Dancing was the one thing
we disagreed about,
the Reverend and I.
Do you suppose
he's watching over me tonight?
That depends on where he is,
Aunt.
Good evening, Mrs. Penniman.
Oh, good evening.
Good evening!
Catherine, dear,
may I present Mr. Morris Townsend?
How do you do, Miss Sloper?
Mr. Townsend is Arthur's cousin, dear,
and he's just returned from Europe.
How do you do, sir?
Would you have a dance for me,
Miss Sloper?
I believe
she has a waltz left.
Excuse me, dear,
there is Mr. Abeel.
May I?
Yes.
Which one will it be?
Oh.
The fifth?
The fifth? Thank you.
Two R's in Morris.
Miss Sloper,
I consider that you do me a great honor.
You see,
I'm rather choosy, too.
Catherine Sloper.
You know,
we don't have to wait until the fifth.
No?
No.
Miss Sloper,
we must make an arrangement.
I will not kick you
if you will not kick me.
Oh, dear, I'm so clumsy.
No, no,
it's only that I'm wearing Arthur's boots,
and he's a very bad dancer.
Now.
One, two, three, point.
Don't look at your feet.
Where shall I look?
Look at me.
No.
Very good.
And when we were boys,
Arthur was called Porridge Head.
Shall we sit down?
While I've been in Europe,
he's become
a promising young businessman.
And now, Miss Sloper,
I think it's time you said something.
Are you going to remain
in New York now, Mr. Townsend?
What a delightful question.
Well, I haven't been at all
sure what I was going to do.
But right now, I've decided.
Yes, Miss Sloper,
I am going to remain in New York now.
Are you warm?
Let me get you some claret cup.
Oh, no.
Are you a member
of the Temperance League?
Yes, I believe I am.
Oh.
Well, I'm not.
Will you excuse me for a moment?
Oh, Mr. Abeel,
I can't keep this up any longer.
I must rest.
Catherine, dear,
your old auntie is exhausted.
You finish this delightful polka for me,
dear. Mr. Abeel is an accomplished dancer.
I...
It would be a pleasure, Miss Sloper.
Mr. Townsend,
are you looking for my niece?
Yes, she must have been ambushed.
Will you console me?
She'll be back in a moment.
This is the sixth dance in a row.
Now, he just can't keep it up.
You know, I can dance most of these
young whippersnappers off their feet.
Lavinia?
Oh, Austin,
may I present Mr. Morris Townsend?
Mr. Townsend, my brother,
Dr. Sloper.
I've looked forward to meeting you, Doctor.
I'm honored.
Thank you.
Have you had a nice time?
Austin, I've had
a most wonderful evening.
And we had some difficulty
in persuading her to come.
The gentlemen here all owe
you a vote of thanks, Doctor.
Geier will be ready very soon.
Will you tell Catherine?
It's the best part
of the evening, sir.
It really is, Austin.
But you're used to those gay
nights at the parsonage, my dear.
I, alas,
must be an early riser.
Good night, Mr. Townsend.
Good night, sir.
Oh, Catherine, I have bad news.
We're leaving.
Yes, Aunt.
Where is Mr. Abeel?
He's having a nosebleed.
Oh, dear.
Good night, Mr. Townsend.
Good night, Mrs. Penniman.
I wish to apologize, sir.
You should, Miss Sloper.
Had Mr. Abeel kept his health,
I should have invited him out with sabers.
Well, I...
I must get my wrap.
Oh, I've just met your father.
Yes, I saw.
He left before I could ask him
when I might call.
His office hours
are in the morning.
Are you not well,
Mr. Townsend?
I am in the best of health.
I wish to call on you.
Oh.
Good morning, Mr. Townsend.
Good morning.
Miss Sloper is
not at home, sir.
She isn't?
Why, Mr. Townsend.
Good morning, Mrs. Penniman.
Do come in.
I stopped by because Miss
Sloper told me yesterday
she'd be at home this morning.
Is she really out?
Oh, yes.
I think she has taken flight
at your third visit this week.
I wonder why.
Oh,
I cannot betray a confidence.
You must ask her that.
When?
Well...
I know she won't be long.
Thank you, ma'am.
The parsonage
was a veritable beehive,
with our spelling matches,
our taffy pulls...
Oh, and in the winter,
in the winter,
the sleigh rides
over the Poughkeepsie hills.
Mrs. Penniman,
do you suppose Catherine will...
I mean Miss Sloper.
My dear boy,
you may let yourself go when you're with me.
Yes, thank you, but...
She will be home.
Yes, but when?
Mr. Townsend, you remind me so
of the Reverend Penniman.
The same ardency,
the same passionate nature.
How I wish
I might have known him.
Tell me about the doctor,
ma'am. What sort of...
Oh, Catherine, is that you?
Yes, Aunt.
You have a visitor,
young lady.
Good morning.
It is a beautiful morning for me now,
Miss Sloper,
for I was afraid you might
not come back at all.
I would have to come back
sometime. I live here.
I know you do, Miss Sloper.
That is why I'm here.
Mr. Townsend wondered if his flowers
had been delivered in good condition.
Yes, thank you.
They were very fresh.
I mailed you a note this morning.
I shall treasure it,
Miss Sloper,
although I did not send the
flowers in order to be thanked.
I sent them
to give you pleasure.
Thank you.
Oh, I brought that song
I told you I found in Paris.
Pardon me, ma'am, I'll get it.
I will leave you alone
with him.
What will I talk about?
You will not have to do the talking.
My dear child,
he has come a-courting.
Courting me?
Well, certainly not me, miss.
Now, you must
be very gracious to him.
Oh, Mr. Townsend,
you must excuse me.
I have numerous duties
which call me.
I trust
that we shall see you again.
I'm your servant, ma'am.
Oh, Catherine,
you haven't forgotten about this evening?
No, Aunt.
Our girl is off to another
one of her endless parties.
It makes me very unhappy to hear that.
What?
That you are so sought after.
It makes my way harder.
I am not going to a party.
My father and I are dining with
Mr. And Mrs. Hone, that's all.
That's what I like you for.
You're so honest.
Tell me something.
Did you go out this morning
because you thought I might call?
Yes.
Do you not like to see me?
Yes, I like to see you,
Mr. Townsend,
but you have called so
frequently this week that I...
You're tired of me?
Oh, no.
You consider my behavior
improper?
I do not know. I am puzzled.
Good. I like that.
If you're puzzled,
you're thinking of me.
Is that the song?
Yes.
Will you play it for me?
I do not play.
May I?
I assure you I shan't harm it.
Can you hear me
way over there?
You know, on my tenth visit,
you might even sit here.
Mr. Townsend,
you are very bold.
Do you know what it means?
No.
The joys of love,
they last but a short time.
The pains of love
last all your life.
All your life.
It's a lovely song.
You know,
I think of you constantly.
I'm not very good
at this kind of conversation.
Neither am I.
I'm afraid that is our trouble.
I'm not a glib man, Miss Sloper.
I think you talk very well.
Not when I need it most.
Oh, with Mrs. Penniman,
or in my room at home,
I can think of the most
delightful things to say.
Can you understand that?
Yes, I can.
But here with you,
I sound like a fool.
I don't think so.
You don't?
Well, if ever you do think so,
if ever I sound high-blown or false,
put it down to that, will you?
I will try.
And take pity on my situation.
What situation?
Miss Sloper,
I have fallen in love with you.
You have?
Catherine, are you receiving?
Yes, Father.
I have a visitor.
Good morning, my dear.
How do you do, Mr. Townsend?
Good morning, Dr. Sloper.
Is your cousin here with you?
No, I'm on my own.
I hope you don't mind. Delighted.
I've taken the liberty of calling
on a most attractive young lady
and her attractive father.
Oh, we're not that attractive.
Well, I'd like
my sherry and biscuits.
Perhaps Mr. Townsend
might enjoy some with me.
I'd be honored.
That's an excellent bay rum
you're using, Mr. Townsend.
I brought it with me
from France, Doctor.
Permit me
to share it with you.
Thank you. Very kind,
but I could hardly let you do that.
Well, have you been out
this morning, my dear?
Catherine?
Oh, yes. I stopped by to see
Mr. Rougini after breakfast.
Oh, yes, about the lessons.
What did he say?
You need a very true ear
for the harp.
It seems that I have not
a very true ear.
Nonsense. That's impossible.
Your mother's ear was impeccable.
Yes, Father, I know.
She used
to tune her own piano.
Miss Sloper has a great
appreciation for music.
That is a talent in itself.
Is Cook's knee any better,
Maria?
It's a little easier
this morning, Doctor.
I'll be up to see her in a while.
Here, give that to Mr. Townsend.
You're very kind, sir.
Most great doctors are too busy to
see the illness under their noses.
Mr. Townsend, you're full of agreeable
and flattering observations,
both for Catherine and myself.
That is the way
you both strike me, sir.
I told Miss Sloper earlier,
I'm very candid.
Oh, yes, he is. Very candid.
How long do you plan to remain in our city,
Mr. Townsend?
Oh, my stay
is quite indefinite, sir.
Will you dine with us
one evening this week?
Doctor, I should
be delighted.
Shall we say
Thursday at 6:00?
Thank you, sir.
I was there quite a while. Of course,
not as long as I should have liked.
But I think you'll find Paris changed,
Doctor.
I hope not.
I should like it to be exactly as it was.
You see,
Dr. Sloper went there on his wedding trip.
Oh, in that case,
Paris can never change for you, Doctor.
How do you keep busy since your
return to New York, Mr. Townsend?
I'm looking for a position.
Well, your studies abroad should
open many avenues to you.
I engaged in no studies, Mrs. Penniman.
I was merely idling.
You see, sir, I had a small inheritance,
and that was how I used it up.
What sort of position
should you prefer?
You mean, what am I fit for?
Very little, I'm afraid.
I have nothing but my good right arm,
as they say in the melodramas.
Oh, you're too modest.
In addition to your good right arm,
you have a very good mind.
I know nothing of you but what I see,
but I see that you are extremely intelligent.
Oh, yes.
Thank you very much.
You advise me, then, not to despair?
I should be very sorry to admit
that a robust, well-disposed man
need ever despair.
If he doesn't succeed in one thing,
he can try another,
only he should choose
with discretion.
Oh, yes, with discretion.
Were you kindly intending to
propose something for my advantage?
No, I have no particular proposal to make.
But I hear the West is opening up.
Many young men are turning
their eyes in that direction.
I'm afraid I shouldn't
be able to manage that.
You see, I have ties here.
My sister... Oh, yes.
A Mrs. Montgomery, Austin. Liz knows her.
They met at a charity bazaar.
She's widowed.
Now that I'm back, I'm staying with her.
She lives in the Second Avenue.
She's very dependent on me.
Naturally.
Mr. Townsend has five
little nephews and nieces.
He is helping
to bring them up.
Yes, I give them lessons.
I'm a kind of tutor.
Oh, that's very proper.
Family feeling is very proper,
but it's hardly a career.
No, it won't make my fortune.
You mustn't be too much bent
on a fortune.
Mr. Townsend,
I'd looked forward to an evening at home,
but the Hospital Commission is in
session and I am to address them.
I understand perfectly, sir.
Lavinia, I hope you'll excuse me.
Of course, Austin.
Catherine, my dear,
you will extend the honors of
the house to Mr. Townsend.
I'm very grateful
for your interest, sir.
Yes. Yes, indeed.
He doesn't like me.
He doesn't like me at all.
I don't see how you know.
I feel.
I'm very quick to feel.
Perhaps you are mistaken.
You ask him and you'll see.
Then I would rather
not ask him.
How nice.
But you wouldn't
contradict him?
I never contradict him.
Austin,
isn't he a charming young man?
I never dreamed he'd be so
interested in Catherine.
Nor did I. He's so agreeable,
so elegant.
He may find it hard to maintain
so much elegance in this city
without working for it.
But he's looking
for a position most earnestly.
I wonder if he's looking for it here,
Lavinia. What?
Wouldn't the position
of husband
to a defenseless young girl
with a large fortune
suit him to perfection?
How can you entertain
such a suspicion?
Suspicion?
It's a diagnosis, my dear.
But you're not
in your clinic now, Austin.
Why, Morris Townsend would be
a feather in any girl's cap.
You've only to use your eyes,
which are as good as mine.
Better.
Austin, you must help this along and
be thankful that it's come about.
Very well, Lavinia.
While I'm being thankful,
I hope you will not forget
your duties as chaperon.
Good night, my dear.
Good night, Austin.
Catherine,
have you any spirits of camphor in the house?
I have one of my headaches.
Headaches, Aunt?
Oh, I'm sorry.
I never talk about them.
They strike like a thief in the night.
You must permit me to retire.
Of course.
But, Aunt!
I know it's not like me to give in, dear,
but sometimes fortitude is folly.
Good night, dear.
Good night, Mr. Townsend.
Good night.
Poor Mrs. Penniman.
May I offer you your port
in the drawing room?
You see?
Yes?
Your aunt, she's on my side.
She wouldn't let your father abuse me.
My father won't abuse you.
He doesn't know you well enough.
You know,
I would have liked you
to say to me,
"If my father doesn't think well of you,
what does it matter?"
Oh, but it would matter.
I could never say that.
You could do anything
for one whom you love.
My dearest girl,
you must believe
how much I care for you.
You're everything I've ever
yearned for in a woman.
But I am... I am so...
Oh, Catherine,
will you marry me?
Yes.
You make me very happy.
Do you love me?
Yes.
Oh, Catherine.
I love you.
I will cherish you forever.
We must speak to my father.
I will do it tonight.
You must do it tomorrow.
It's sweet of you to want to do it first.
The young man generally does that.
Oh, women have more tact.
They can persuade better.
You'll need
all your powers of persuasion.
Naturally, your father wants a
brilliant marriage for you, Catherine,
and I'm a poor man.
Oh, my father will not care
about that.
He might. He might fear that I'm mercenary.
Mercenary?
Oh, no.
He may say it.
Well, I shall simply say
it isn't so.
You must make a great point of that,
Catherine.
Why?
Because it's from the fact
of your having money
that our difficulties
may come.
Oh, Morris,
are you very sure you love me?
Oh, my own dearest,
how can you doubt it?
Catherine,
since your aunt has left us alone,
it's not proper that I stay any longer.
Yes, Morris.
I'll be back in the morning
to call on your father.
At what time?
At 11:00 sharp.
I will tell him, and please,
Morris, promise me this.
When you speak with Father,
you will be very gentle, very respectful.
Of course.
And there's something
you must promise me.
If your father is against me, you'll
still be faithful, no matter what comes.
Yes, Morris.
No matter what comes.
You know, you're your own mistress.
You're of age.
Oh, I love you.
I will always love you.
My dear girl.
Oh, Father!
Have you waited up for me?
Yes, Father, I...
I have something to tell you.
Have you?
Yes!
Well!
Let us go into the back parlor
and hear it.
Now, my dear, do you suppose
that we might both sit down?
Well, now?
I am engaged to be married.
You do right to tell me.
And whom have you honored
with your choice?
Mr. Morris Townsend.
You have gone fast.
Yes, I think we have.
Mr. Townsend ought to
have waited and told me.
Oh, he means to tell you,
tomorrow morning at 11:00.
It's not quite the same thing,
my dear.
You shouldn't be pleading for him.
He should plead for you.
Yes, Father,
but I think he is a little afraid of you.
Is he?
He fears that
you do not like him.
Well, I hardly know him,
Catherine.
But our liking each other
isn't important.
The only thing that is
important is that he love you.
He does.
He loves me and I love him.
It is a great wonder to me that
Morris has come into my life.
Oh, Father, don't you think
he is the most beautiful man
you've ever seen?
Well, he's very good-looking,
my dear.
Of course, you wouldn't let a
consideration like that sway you unduly.
Oh, no,
but that is what is so wonderful to me,
that he should have everything,
everything a woman could want,
and he wants me.
I'll see him tomorrow.
I knew you would.
And you are so good that you will
be fair and honest with him.
I shall be as fair and honest
with him as he is with you.
Thank you, Father.
That is all we shall need.
Aunt Penniman.
Oh, Catherine.
He proposed to me.
Does your father know?
Yes.
What did he say?
He will see Morris in the morning.
Eureka!
How is your headache now, Aunt?
Headache?
Good morning, my dear.
This is my brother,
Dr. Sloper, Mrs. Montgomery.
Mrs. Montgomery
has been good to come, Austin.
I'm very grateful to you, ma'am.
Oh, I'm glad to come.
She left a busy household just
on the strength of your note.
I should more properly
have gone to you,
but this is one of my mornings
at the clinic.
I dared not take the time off
to make a formal call.
Oh, I quite understand,
Doctor.
Elizabeth... Oh, certainly.
Will you excuse me?
Certainly. I should like to
see my sister while I'm here.
Mrs. Montgomery,
will you come into the study
where we may talk?
Yes, sir.
...understand my situation,
Mrs. Montgomery.
Your brother wishes
to marry my daughter,
so I want you to tell me
something about his character.
What sort of a gentleman
is he?
Well, Doctor, he's intelligent, charming.
He's a wonderful companion.
Yes, I know that.
But is he reliable?
Is he trustworthy? Is he responsible?
Well, if you mean is he financially secure,
he is not, Doctor.
But I'm sure
you must know that.
Yes, he told me that
himself.
That is another thing
about Morris. He's honest.
Is he? Is he then honest in
his feeling for my daughter?
I don't know that, Doctor. I never could
say what goes on in people's hearts.
Could you?
Well, I have to try, ma'am.
He told me that he'd used
up a small inheritance.
Did he handle it well?
Probably you
would not think so, Doctor,
but from his own point of view,
he did a great deal with it.
He saw Europe, he met
many interesting people,
he enlarged his capacities.
Did he help you, ma'am?
No.
Shouldn't he have?
Why, I don't think so.
You are a widow
and you have children.
I think so.
Oh, but if I'd needed it,
I know he would have helped me.
Are you sure?
You want me to complain
about him, sir,
but I have no complaint.
I brought him up
as if he were my child,
and I have accepted
the good and bad in him,
just as I accept them
in my children.
I have made you angry, ma'am.
I apologize.
I think, Doctor,
you expect too much of people.
If you do,
you'll always be disappointed.
I want you
to meet my daughter.
Will you excuse me?
Certainly.
Catherine? Catherine.
Yes, Father?
Will you come
into the study, please?
Yes, Father.
This is she?
No, that is a picture
of my wife.
Oh, she's very beautiful.
Yes, she was very beautiful.
Oh.
Catherine, this is Mrs. Montgomery,
Mr. Townsend's sister.
Miss Sloper.
How do you do?
I am very happy to meet you.
Thank you.
Isn't Morris coming?
His appointment is for 11:00,
Catherine.
Oh, yes.
Are your children well?
Quite well, thank you.
I hope Morris will bring you to
see me and my family very soon.
Yes.
My brother tells me that you have
an aunt visiting you, Miss Sloper.
Yes.
It is delightful to have someone
to whom one can show New York.
Oh, yes, it is.
Does she like our city?
Yes.
Catherine, perhaps you'll offer Mrs.
Montgomery a glass of the Madeira.
Oh, yes, indeed.
Excuse me, ma'am.
She... She is very shy.
Yes, she is.
Perhaps she is less shy
with Morris.
Now, you said they have just fallen in love.
You were right about Catherine.
Were you right
about your brother?
Well, I can only suppose
that Morris is more mature in
his feelings than I had thought.
This time he has not sought
out superficial charms.
Perhaps he's considered the
gentle character underneath.
Are you being honest?
I think I am.
Well, I believe her money
is the prime attraction.
What money?
She's an heiress.
Didn't your brother tell you that?
No, he did not.
She has $10,000 a year
from her mother,
and on my death,
she will have twice as much more.
She...
She will be immensely rich.
Yes, she will, of course.
If she marries a man I don't approve,
I shall leave my part to the clinic.
Yes, but she has
the $10,000 now.
Yes, she has.
That is still
a great deal of money, Doctor.
It is. And consider
how he has behaved with money.
He gratified his every wish.
Did he help you
with the children? No.
He enlarged
his capacities in Europe.
He left his gloves here last night.
The finest chamois.
Look at yours.
Will he help you with this
fortune he hopes to marry?
I would stake my life
he would not.
You must follow
your own dictates, Doctor.
Tell me she is not a
victim of his selfishness.
Tell me I am wrong.
I must go now.
Good day, Doctor.
Good day, ma'am.
Oh, has Mrs. Montgomery left?
I wanted Lavinia to meet her.
Yes, Liz, she has left.
Did you like her, Austin?
Very much.
Oh, good.
You know, Catherine
has just asked Elizabeth
if Marian
might be her maid of honor.
Austin, Catherine is radiant.
I've never
seen her this way before.
Well, she must get over it.
He's worthless.
What?
The man's a fortune hunter.
All he's interested in
is her money.
Are you going
to tell that to Catherine?
No.
Oh, but, Austin...
Catherine.
Mrs. Montgomery has left.
Oh, I took too long.
I wanted to make the tray
especially nice.
It was not your fault, my dear.
We had concluded our talk.
Concluded?
Did Mrs. Montgomery tell you something bad,
Father?
No, Catherine.
I did not impress her
favorably?
Oh, good heavens, Catherine,
don't hold yourself so cheaply.
I was embarrassed.
I won't be another time.
You had better go
to your room, Catherine.
Yes.
Father, tell him about me.
You know me so well,
it will not be immodest in you
to praise me a little.
How is it possible to protect
such a willing victim?
You will kill her
if you deny her this marriage.
You forget I am a doctor.
People don't die of such things.
Be very careful, Austin.
This man may take good care
of Catherine and her money
and make her very happy.
He will. I know he will.
But she's been taken in.
She's in love.
Mr. Townsend
is in the front parlor, sir.
Good morning, Mr. Townsend.
How do you do, sir?
You expected me?
Yes, I did.
You are admirably prompt.
I could hardly be late
for so important an occasion.
Yes.
Catherine told me yesterday what
has been going on between you.
Will you sit down?
Thank you.
I've been walking all morning,
and you know, sir,
I find New York as lovely as any
city in Europe this time of year.
Yes. You must allow me to say,
Mr. Townsend,
that it would have been becoming of you
to give me notice of your intentions
before they had gone so far.
It was only the other day that
Catherine made your acquaintance.
Yes, we've not been slow
to arrive at an understanding.
My interest in Miss Sloper
began the first time I saw her.
Did it not even
precede your first meeting?
I certainly had already heard
she was a delightful girl.
A delightful girl.
That's what you think her?
Otherwise,
I shouldn't be here.
Well, my dear young man,
as Catherine's father,
I hope I've a just appreciation
of her many good qualities,
but I don't mind telling you I've never
quite thought of her in that light.
I don't know what I might think
of her if I were her father.
I speak
from my own point of view.
You speak very well.
Please sit down.
But did you really expect that I would
throw my daughter into your arms?
No, I had an idea
you didn't like me.
What gave you that idea?
The fact that I'm poor.
Well, that has a harsh sound,
but it's about the truth.
You've no profession,
means. Please sit.
No visible resources
or prospects,
and so you are in a category from
which not to choose a son-in-law,
particularly not for my daughter, who is
a weak young woman with a large fortune.
I don't think
Miss Sloper is weak.
Well, even if she were not,
you are still penniless.
Yes, that is my weakness.
And therefore,
you mean I'm mercenary.
No, I don't say that.
You say that.
But that's what you mean.
There are many poor men,
Mr. Townsend,
but they don't go through the streets
proclaiming that they are not thieves,
especially when no one
has accused them.
I simply said
you are in the wrong category.
But your daughter doesn't marry a category.
She marries a man.
A man she's good enough
to say she loves.
A man who offers
nothing in return?
Is it possible to offer more
than the most tender affection
and a lifelong devotion?
A lifelong devotion
is measured after the fact.
Meanwhile, it's usual to offer
a few material securities.
Well, what are yours?
A handsome face and figure
and a very good manner.
Oh, they're excellent as far as they go,
but they don't go far enough.
You think I'm an idler?
It doesn't matter what I think
once I tell you I just don't
think of you as a son-in-law.
You think
I'd squander her money.
I plead guilty to that.
Because I spent my own,
I suppose.
Well, it was just because
it was my own that I spent it.
I've made no debts.
When it was gone, I stopped.
I don't owe
a penny in the world.
Allow me to ask,
what are you living on now?
The remnants of my property.
You left your gloves here
yesterday.
Thank you.
Doctor, don't you care
to gratify your daughter?
Do you enjoy the idea
of making her miserable?
I'm resigned to her thinking
me a tyrant for a few months.
A few months?
For a lifetime, then.
She may as well be miserable
that way as with you.
You are not polite, sir.
You push me to it.
You argue too much.
I have a great deal at stake.
I know, and you have lost it.
It is over.
I wouldn't be too sure
of that, sir.
You are impertinent.
Dr. Sloper, if it were not
for my feeling for Catherine,
I should not have put up with the
indignities you have offered me today.
You have only to leave
my house to escape them.
Good day, Mr. Townsend.
Good day.
Morris, wait!
Morris!
You promised me, Morris.
You promised you would be
respectful when you saw my father.
Catherine.
What is the matter, Father?
Catherine,
you are without dignity.
Why are you angry?
Why are you and Morris quarreling?
Tell me, please.
I will tell you
when we are alone.
Your father does not approve
of me, Catherine.
You want me to give him up?
Yes, I do.
Why?
What has he done?
What did Mrs. Montgomery
tell you?
My sister.
Have you spoken with her?
She paid me a visit this
morning on my invitation.
You see how painful this is
for me, Father.
Surely you will want me
to know your reasons.
He's a selfish idler.
My sister never said that.
No, I say it.
Father, I know he loves me.
I know that he does not.
In heaven's name, Father,
what makes you so sure?
My poor child, I can't tell you.
You must just take my word for it.
Father, I can't. I can't.
I love him.
I have promised to marry him,
to stay by him
no matter what comes.
So, he forearmed himself by getting
a promise like that, did he?
You are beneath contempt.
Don't abuse him, Father.
I think
we shall marry quite soon.
Then it is
no further concern of mine.
I'm sorry.
Dr. Sloper,
we cannot marry
without your approval.
It would bring unhappiness
to all of us.
Do you mean that, sir?
Yes.
Then will you put if off,
Mr. Townsend, for six months?
I would like Catherine
to go to Europe with me.
Europe?
I would like you
very much to go, Catherine.
Why, Father?
Your father thinks
you will forget me, Catherine.
I shall still love him
when I come back.
You are very sure of your love, but,
Catherine, do you dare to test him?
You underestimate him.
I don't think so.
Catherine,
go to Europe.
Go to Europe with your father.
Sloper
is the name.
That way, sir.
I'll be right back.
Good morning, Doctor.
Good morning, ma'am.
Catherine.
I came because I felt sure you
would not deny me the opportunity
of wishing you both
a safe journey.
Thank you very much.
Morris, I'm glad you came.
I have brought Miss Sloper
a small gift, sir.
Mr. Townsend, it is not usual for young
ladies in my daughter's situation
to receive gifts
from gentlemen.
Yes, Doctor, I know,
but this is a very humble gift.
It's only
a little hand warmer.
Father,
I would like to have it.
You must put live charcoals in it,
Catherine.
I give it to you
with all my love.
Morris.
I will be thinking of you,
Catherine.
Good day, ma'am.
Bon voyage, Doctor.
I never expected to hear a sermon
like that in New York City.
Now, when the Reverend Penniman
sermonized on the loaves and the fishes,
they were there,
right before you.
You could
practically smell them.
Look, Mrs. Penniman,
you've lost.
Why is it you always win?
I cheat.
Mrs. Penniman,
had it not been for your invitations,
these past few months
would have been unbearable.
You like this house,
don't you, Morris?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
You know, the Doctor
is a man of fine taste.
It is strange that although
we do not like each other,
we seem
to like the same things.
That can be a bond
between you in time.
I hope so.
But you see,
he's earned all this by his work.
He believes that every
man should do the same.
The trouble is
that some of us cannot.
You miss her,
don't you, Morris?
Very much.
Dinner is served,
Mrs. Penniman.
Yes, Maria.
And the claret
is room temperature.
Thank you, Maria.
I hope I haven't
kept you waiting, Father.
No, my dear.
Wouldn't you prefer
to go inside?
I like this table.
Oh!
Did you used to come here
with my mother?
Yes, Catherine, I did.
Would you like some chocolate?
No, thank you very much.
Oh, there's the Caf Riche.
So it is. What about it?
Aunt Penniman mentioned it
in her last letter.
Lavinia?
She said
that all the best people
of Paris frequent it.
Her winter of loneliness
has given her second sight.
Something for mademoiselle?
No, thank you.
Bien, monsieur.
Have you given him up?
No, Father.
You mean that in all this time,
you have not yielded one inch?
No, Father.
I see no reason
to prolong this trip. Do you?
I thought
you wanted to see England.
I've seen England.
The pilot's gone down the bay.
They are to dock within the hour.
We're almost ready.
Maria, did you
find my gloves?
As soon as I warm the beds,
I'll look again.
Oh, Geier,
we have to be at the pier in half an hour.
I'm harnessed, ma'am.
What an inconvenient hour
to land.
Now, you will be careful to get
the details right, won't you?
They're most important.
Of course.
You will have a closed carriage
at the corner of MacDougal Street
tomorrow evening
as soon as it gets dark.
Tomorrow night at 9:00.
Yes, at 9:00.
Oh, here they are.
Now, tell her everything.
I will.
Tell her I love her.
I will, I will. Now,
you wait in the mews for my signal, Morris.
Giddap.
Oh, Catherine.
Oh, Catherine,
you look so French.
Well,
no matter how fascinating distant places are,
there's always someone at home
one misses, isn't there?
I've caught a chill, Lavinia.
Would you be so kind as to get
me some hot water for a toddy?
Why, of course, Austin.
It's good to be home,
isn't it, Father?
You will feel better now
that we are back.
I wish you had let me try to
take care of you a little.
Here you are, Austin.
Thank you, Lavinia.
Your brandy decanter
is right there.
Well!
Have you taken to drink, Lavinia?
What...
My heart. I thought
it would help my heart.
Yes.
I know I shouldn't ask you, Catherine,
but did you bring me something?
We brought you
a silk parasol.
Just exactly
what I wanted.
Come and show it to me.
Your heart would improve, Lavinia,
if you stopped smoking cigars.
What?
When I come home
to find empty brandy glasses
and detect cigar bands,
I can only think
of one person.
Well, what's happened to Mr. Townsend?
Is he upstairs in my bed?
Oh, Austin, I forgot to tell you.
He did stop by this evening.
This evening?
Was he here this evening, Aunt?
Yes, yes.
So he's made my house his club.
You should be in bed. Now, I'll just see
that everything has been attended to.
What a ridiculous
position to be in.
Well, I suppose you'll be going
off with him any time now.
Yes, if he will have me.
Why not?
You'll be a most
entertaining companion.
I will try to be.
And your gaiety and brilliance
will make up the difference
between the $10,000 a year you will
have and the $30,000 he expects.
He expects nothing.
He does not love me for that.
No? What else, then?
Your grace? Your charm?
Your quick tongue and subtle wit?
He admires me.
Catherine,
I've tried for months not to be unkind,
but now it's time for you
to realize the truth.
How many girls do you think he
might have had in this town?
He finds me pleasing.
Oh, yes, I'm sure he does.
A hundred women are prettier,
a thousand more clever,
but you have one virtue
that outshines them all.
What... What is that?
Your money.
Father!
You have nothing else.
What a terrible thing
to say to me.
I don't expect you
to believe that.
I've known you all your life and
I've yet to see you learn anything.
With one exception, my dear.
You embroider neatly.
Morris.
Morris!
I haven't had
a moment alone with her.
Where is she?
She's upstairs with Austin.
They had a bad crossing
and he's out of mood.
You'd better leave.
I'll tell her everything later.
No, I want to tell her myself.
I'll wait until he's gone to bed.
Oh, no, no. Please go.
If Austin should see you...
He won't. I'll stay right here.
No, no, you don't know.
I'll take her shopping in the morning
and we'll meet you in the square.
Oh, please go.
Morris.
Morris! Morris!
Morris, Morris, I'm so glad...
Catherine, my dearest.
You were waiting.
You were as anxious as I.
Cathy.
Oh, Morris.
Have you been true to me, Catherine?
Oh, yes.
Good. You've not
changed your mind?
No, no.
Have you?
Oh, wait until you hear my plans.
Plans?
Yes.
For our marriage.
Our elopement.
Oh, our elopement.
It's for tomorrow night,
in a country parsonage
up on Murray's Hill.
There is a Reverend Lispinard there who
knows our story, and he'll help us.
Do you hear me, Catherine?
Oh, I love you so.
Oh, tell me what to do.
I have
a closed carriage engaged.
I will come to the corner of the
square tomorrow night at 9:00.
We'll drive to the parsonage,
and after the marriage,
we'll spend the night at an inn up the river.
The next day,
we'll go to Albany on our honeymoon.
Oh, Morris.
My husband.
You like my plan?
Oh! And I've brought you such
a beautiful silk waistcoat.
You must wear it for our wedding.
My dear girl.
I bought you a set of buttons
at Barrere's in Paris.
Buttons?
They are rubies and pearls.
They are quite nice.
Oh, my dear, dear girl.
How happy we shall be.
Morris?
Yes?
Take me tonight.
Tonight?
How can we?
We must.
In another hour,
everyone will be asleep.
We can get away quietly
and no one will know.
But, Catherine, it's only one more day.
Morris, I beg you.
Where would we go?
To the Reverend...
Lispinard?
Yes. He knows about us.
He will not turn us away because
we've come one day early.
I implore you.
Catherine...
If you love me...
Very well, we'll do it.
I'll leave and find a carriage.
Let's see, it's almost 10:30.
I can be back here at 12:30 on
the dot in front of the house.
You must be ready and waiting for me.
Can you do that?
Oh, I can do anything,
my dearest.
You must leave a letter for your father.
A letter?
Yes. Shall I compose it for you?
No.
Well, you must think very
carefully of how to word it.
You must melt his heart.
I will not write him.
Of course you must write him.
We want him to forgive us.
He won't forgive us.
I know it.
I know it now.
I have good reason to.
What reason?
My father doesn't like me.
Well, what an unhappy thing
to say. Of course he does.
No.
He must love you very much,
or he wouldn't be trying so
hard to protect you from me.
No, Morris.
In this one thing, I know I am right.
I couldn't say it
unless I was sure.
I understood it tonight
for the first time in my life.
You can tell when a person
speaks to you as if... As if...
As if what?
As if they despised you.
Despised?
We must be very happy together,
and you must never despise me, Morris.
Oh, Catherine.
We must never ask him for anything
or depend upon him for anything.
We must be very happy and
expect nothing from him, ever.
No.
I will try to be
the best wife in the world.
I know you will.
I will get ready immediately.
Catherine, dear,
he can't dislike you that much.
He's bound to come around.
No, Morris, he will not,
but even if he would, I would not.
I see.
I will try to be punctual,
Morris. I know you like that.
Till 12:30, then.
Hurry, my darling.
Catherine!
What are you doing?
Aunt, I would like it if you
would please go back to bed.
But I want to know
what you're doing.
I am eloping with Morris.
That's impossible.
It's for tomorrow.
Hush.
No, no,
you've got everything wrong.
Now, Morris will be here
tomorrow evening.
No, Aunt, he will be here
in the next two minutes.
Have you seen him?
Yes.
Oh, Catherine!
Will you spend the night with him unwed?
We are going directly
to the Reverend Lispinard
on Murray's Hill.
If he will marry us,
perhaps we may stay with him.
If not, we will drive all night.
I don't care.
Oh, Catherine, how romantic.
Morris is so daring.
I think I heard a carriage.
No.
Now, wouldn't you like me to
dress quickly and come with you?
There's no time, Aunt.
Morris will be here
any instant.
But I think I should.
You must have a chaperon.
Your father would be shocked.
It serves him right.
What?
Father, he finds me so dull.
It will surprise him to have such
a dull girl disgrace his name.
Catherine,
are you quite yourself?
No, it's just
a shutter blowing.
Think of it.
I may never stand in this window again.
I may never see Washington
Square on a windy April night.
Why won't you?
Because I will never be
in this house again.
Nonsense. You and Austin will
be reconciled within the year.
I will never see him again
in my life.
What?
I am leaving tonight instead of tomorrow
because it is one time less I will
ever have to lay eyes on him,
or he on me.
We dislike each other
too much, Aunt.
But good heavens, child,
you're disinheriting yourself.
Yes, completely.
Have you told Morris this?
Of course.
I told him everything.
He is to be my husband.
Oh, you should have waited.
Did... Did he understand?
There he is. Goodbye, Aunt.
I will write to you, Aunt.
Aunt?
Yes, dear?
Why shouldn't
I have told Morris?
Oh, dear girl.
Why were you not
a little more clever?
Clever? About what?
Oh, Catherine.
Why shouldn't I have told him?
Morris would not want to be the cause of
your losing your natural inheritance.
He could
not see you impoverished.
Impoverished?
I have $10,000 a year.
That is a great deal of money.
Not when
one has expected $30,000.
You think
what my father thinks.
Well, you are wrong.
Morris loves me.
I am everything he ever
yearned for in a woman.
Oh, Catherine... I am, I am.
He has told me so.
He thinks I am pretty.
He wants me.
He could not wait for tomorrow night.
He said we must go tonight.
No, I said that, didn't I?
But he agreed. He was willing.
You can see that for yourself.
He was very willing.
Well, then,
perhaps he will come.
Perhaps?
He must come.
He must take me away.
He must love me. He must!
Catherine, please
take hold of yourself.
No, no, Morris must take hold of me.
Morris will love me
for all those who didn't.
Morris, Morris, Morris!
Morris, Morris,
Morris, Morris!
Oh, I'm sorry.
The doctor's office is closed.
Why, I heard he came back
from Europe a week ago.
He did, but he's confined to his bed.
Try Dr. Isaacs in Great Jones Street.
Well, thank you.
Doctor.
You shouldn't be up, sir.
Now stop fluttering about.
Doctor, please go back to bed.
You just
go about your business, Maria.
Yes, sir.
Catherine. I haven't seen you
since our return.
No, Father.
Of course, if he were ill,
he could not write.
Perhaps you should
send him a brief note.
No, Aunt.
But I would gladly deliver it for you.
Stay out of it, Aunt.
Oh, I want to help if I can.
Can you bring him back
from California?
California?
I went to Mrs. Montgomery's
to see him.
You did?
She told me.
He borrowed the passage money
from his cousin Arthur
and left.
You had better go
to your marketing.
Oh, one moment, Maria.
Yes, Doctor?
If you will interrupt your
embroidery for a moment, Catherine,
I think
you both should know this.
I am ill.
It's not just a simple congestion.
There are rales in the lungs.
I shall need
very good nursing.
I shall not recover, but I wish
everything to be done as if I should.
I hate
an ill-conducted sickroom.
Well, maybe you will get well.
Now, in a few days you'll need a
doctor for me. Get Dr. Isaacs.
If the street noises make me restless,
see that tanbark is put down.
Catherine, I don't want your
Aunt Lavinia in my room at all
unless I should
go into a coma.
As for food, don't overload me, Maria.
Keep me on soup, beef broth and gruel.
Yes, sir.
Find a small lamp. Put fresh wicks
in it so that it doesn't smell.
Doctor!
Now, if you'll please make up my bed for me,
I'll be up in a moment.
Yes.
I will help you, Maria.
Will you stay a minute,
Catherine?
I can only assume that your
departure is imminent.
Is it soon?
This week?
No.
Has he asked you to keep
your plans secret from me?
I am not leaving.
Not leaving?
Will you excuse me, Father?
Come here a moment, Catherine.
Here, in the light.
You are flushed.
Your eyes look sick.
You've been weeping.
You have
broken your engagement.
Oh, if you have, I must tell you, Catherine,
that I admire you greatly for it.
I know the effort
that you must have made.
Do you, Father?
But in time, Catherine, the pain will pass.
I cannot begin to tell you
how proud of you I am.
Are you? Oh, deeply.
Most deeply proud.
He deserted me.
What?
Morris deserted me.
Now do you admire me, Father?
Oh, Catherine.
Don't be kind to me.
It doesn't become you.
Catherine, are you blaming me
because I tried to protect you?
Yes.
Someday you'll realize
I've done you a great service.
I can tell you now what you have done.
You have cheated me.
You thought that any handsome, clever man
would be as bored with me as you were.
It was not love that made you protect me,
it was contempt.
Morris Townsend
did not love you, Catherine.
I know that now,
thanks to you.
Better to know it now
than 20 years hence.
Why? I lived with you for 20 years
before I found out you didn't love me.
I don't know that
Morris would have hurt me
or starved me for affection
more than you did.
Since you couldn't love me,
you should have let someone else try.
You have found
a tongue at last, Catherine.
Is it only to say
such terrible things to me?
Yes. This is a field where you
will not compare me to my mother.
Should I have
let him ruin your life?
You'll find some honest,
decent man someday.
You have many fine qualities.
And $30,000 a year.
Yes. That should make it possible
for you to choose with discretion.
If I am to buy a man,
I would prefer buying Morris.
Don't say such things.
You know him to be a scoundrel.
I love him.
Does that humiliate you?
Catherine, promise me
you are done with him.
I won't promise.
Then I must alter my will.
You should.
You should do it immediately.
"I, Austin Sloper,
"surgeon
of 16 Washington Square..."
You had better tell me
how you wish it worded.
I wish to consider
more carefully.
There is nothing to consider.
You want your money used for
purposes you approve, don't you?
If you leave it to the clinic,
it will do what you want it to do.
Catherine, I am ill.
"...do hereby make
my last will and testament..."
I don't want to do it.
I don't want to disinherit
my only child.
I know that you don't.
You'd like to think of me sitting
in dignity in this handsome house,
rich, respected and unloved.
But I may take your money and chase
after Morris and squander it on him.
I don't know what you'll do,
Catherine.
That's right, Father.
You'll never know, will you?
Miss Catherine,
Dr. Isaacs says you'd better come now.
Your father is...
He's very low, miss.
He wants you, miss.
I know he does.
Too late, Maria.
Yes, miss.
Tell Lavinia I'm sorry we missed her.
I will, Aunt Elizabeth.
Oh, and... Come along, Mother.
Arthur's waiting.
All right, dear, I'm coming.
Say goodbye to Aunt Catherine.
Goodbye, Aunt Catherine.
And thank her.
Goodbye, Andrew.
Here, Mother, you take Andrew.
Goodbye, honey.
Sit here at my side.
Now, that's right.
Why don't you come up
this August?
You'd love Newport, and Jefferson and
I have taken a big house this year.
Well, maybe I will.
We've asked you every year
since your father died.
You always say, "Maybe I will,"
and then you never do.
I like the square.
Goodbye, Catherine.
Goodbye, dear.
Goodbye.
Say goodbye.
Goodbye, Andrew.
Goodbye, Aunt Catherine.
Goodbye.
Oh, Miss Catherine,
you've changed into one of your Paris gowns.
You look very handsome in it.
Thank you.
It's such a hot night. Would you mind if
Cook and I took a stroll in the square?
Maria, you are as free
in this house as I am.
When you want a small favor, you need
not blandish me with false compliments.
But, Miss Catherine,
I meant what I said.
It was the coolest dress
I could find.
Yes, miss.
Aunt Penniman, you're home quite early.
Yes, dear, yes.
Did you see your friends
from Poughkeepsie?
No, dear, I did not.
Now, Catherine,
this will come to you as a great surprise.
Good. I like surprises.
Well, then,
I have seen Morris Townsend.
Oh, we met quite by accident.
He's only been home a week.
Oh, Catherine,
he is so handsome.
And he asked so many questions
about you, dear.
He had heard that you hadn't married.
He seemed very interested in that.
He fears that you never understood him,
that you never judged him rightly.
How can you say that to me?
You were in this room
the night he deserted me.
If you would hear him out.
And if you would try to understand
his side of it, Catherine.
He meant it nobly.
Really, he did.
I can hear
that you have been with him.
He has beguiled you again
and you talk like a fool.
I don't care
what you think of me, dear.
I am convinced that you will be
happier after you've seen him.
Save your breath, Aunt Penniman.
I will not see him.
Aunt Penniman, have you dared?
He walked home with me.
He implored me to ask you.
Oh, I only want your happiness,
Catherine.
Go to the door, Aunt,
and tell Mr. Townsend that I am not at home.
Please, Catherine, if you...
I am not at home.
She is not at home,
Morris.
Oh.
I'm sorry.
Did you give her my message?
Yes,
but she is not at home.
I see.
It's been a long time since I stood here.
I know.
Well, I'm sorry.
Good night, Mrs. Penniman.
Goodbye, Morris.
Come in, Morris.
Good evening, Morris.
Good evening, Catherine.
Do I offend you by coming?
You should not have come.
I had to.
I had to see you, Catherine.
May we not sit down?
I think we had better not.
Can't we be friends again?
We aren't enemies.
You don't know how happy it
makes me to hear you say that.
I've never ceased
to think of you.
Morris, if you cannot
be honest with me,
we shall have nothing more
to say to each other.
But it's true, Catherine.
Ever since the night I left,
it's been the desire of my life that
you should understand my motives.
I have had years to think about them,
Morris, and I understand them.
So we have nothing further to discuss.
I will bid you good night.
But I've come all the way from California
to see you, to explain this to you.
It is late for explanations.
No, Catherine,
I would have been back long since,
but I had to beg and borrow
the passage money.
It's been a real struggle
for me to get back here.
Why, between New Orleans and Charleston,
I worked as a hand, a common seaman.
Now that I'm here, you will give
me the chance to vindicate myself.
You must hear me out,
Catherine.
You must.
For the sake of what
we've been to each other.
What is it
you want to explain?
Many things, Catherine.
May we not sit down now?
Catherine, it was because I loved
you that I disappeared that night.
Oh, I know how it looked.
It looked as if I behaved abominably.
But I knew that if I returned that night,
I might have done you great harm.
You know, my dear, no man
who really loves a woman
could ever permit her to give up
a great inheritance just for him.
That's only in storybooks.
My father
did not disinherit me, Morris.
He threatened it to test you.
But I couldn't be sure of that
the night I went away.
No, you could not.
Try to understand me,
Catherine.
Try not to think of what it looked like,
but of what it was.
I had to make a choice.
I chose your welfare rather than my own.
Can you think of it that way?
I will try.
You know
that I've never changed.
I believe your nature is such you
will always care for me a little.
Yes, Morris, that is true.
Then, Catherine, will you forgive
me for the pain I caused you?
I forgave you a long time ago.
Oh, Catherine, my dearest.
We've only waited and now...
Now we're free.
Nothing stands between us,
Catherine.
Do you mean you love me?
I didn't dare to say it.
Why not?
I wasn't sure
you would believe me.
I believed you once, didn't I?
Then, Catherine, let us make the
rest of life happy for each other.
How?
By picking up
where we left off.
By marrying, Catherine.
Would you like that, Morris?
You would make me the proudest
and happiest man in the world.
And I will try and be a good husband to you.
I'm older. I'm wiser now.
And I know that you love me. I need that.
I need it more than anything else.
When would
you like to marry me?
Oh, Catherine.
Then you will.
Let's marry soon, very soon.
Next month.
You are not as impetuous
as you used to be, Morris.
Impetuous?
Why, I would marry you tonight
if I could.
Come with me now.
We can find a carriage in the square.
Do you think the Reverend
Lispinard is still waiting?
We could tell him
we were detained.
Oh, Morris,
I have thought so many times
of that inn up the river.
My own dearest.
Shall we have
the same honeymoon?
You must give me time to pack.
Yes, of course.
My things are at my sister's.
I'll... We'll pick them up on the way.
Why don't you get them now,
Morris, and come back for me?
All right, I will.
We can be at Murray's Hill in an hour.
We can be there by 10:00.
You remember the buttons
I bought for you in Paris?
Buttons?
Wait. I will get them.
I'm home. Really, truly home.
What, Morris, what?
She's magnificent.
Yes.
She's superb.
She has such dignity now.
Well, tell me.
We're going to be married tonight.
Tonight? Oh, Catherine!
My dear girl.
Here they are, Morris.
Your wedding present.
Thank you, my darling.
Oh, Catherine,
they're rubies.
Look, Mrs. Penniman.
I've seen them. They sparkle so.
They suit you, Morris.
Yes, they do.
They're the most beautiful
things I've ever had.
Catherine,
you will have no regrets.
Till 9:00, then.
Oh, Catherine,
we have him back.
I knew it would turn out this way.
You were not so sure as I.
But I have faith
in love like this.
Oh, I hope
I always stay romantic.
And you know, Catherine, you are much
more romantic than you think you are.
Morris sensed that.
Don't bother about that, dear.
I'll do it.
Oh, that beautiful Paris lingerie.
How fortunate that you kept it.
I'm going to pack that for you.
I will sprinkle it with fresh lavender.
Catherine,
wouldn't you like me to come with you?
Oh, come, dear, we must pack.
Catherine,
you haven't time for that.
There's not much left to do.
But you can
finish it afterwards.
I must finish it now,
for I shall never do another.
No?
He came back
with the same lies,
the same silly phrases.
What are you saying?
He has grown greedier
with the years.
The first time,
he only wanted my money.
Now he wants my love, too.
Well, he came to the wrong house,
and he came twice.
I shall see that he never
comes a third time.
Catherine,
do you know what you're doing?
Yes.
Poor Morris.
Can you be so cruel?
Yes, I can be very cruel.
I have been taught by masters.
Right here.
Wait.
I will attend to that.
It's for me. Yes, miss.
Bolt it, Maria.
Bolt it?
Bolt the door, Maria.
Yes, miss.
Good night, Maria.
Good night, miss.