[door closes]
How was my speech?
You were brilliant.
-[Anne] Did I lisp?
- You don't lisp.
I know.
That was what was so troubling about it.
- The thought that I suddenly did.
- No.
Sarah, you must say hello
to the little ones.
No. It is macabre.
[Anne] Please.
[Sarah] No.
I love you, but that I will not do.
-[Anne] If you love me...
- Love has limits.
It should not.
[keys jingling]
[lock turning]
You do not lisp, but you are mad.
Giving me a palace?
I've been wanting to give you something
for quite some time now.
Seemed like the perfect opportunity
with Marlborough winning.
It is a monstrous extravagance,
Mrs. Morley. We are at war.
We won.
It is not over. We must continue.
Oh.
Oh, I did not know that.
[crow cawing]
[classical music playing]
[knocking on door]
[footsteps]
[woman] Take a hunk of bread.
And then Sally will take you to clean up
and then to Her Ladyship.
[woman] This mud stinks.
[Sally] They shit in the streets
round here.
“Political commentary," they call it.
Go through here.
Clean yourself up.
Thank you so much.
-[billiards balls clacking]
-[indistinct chatter]
Lady Marlborough.
I didn't know the new sewer ended in here.
It is I, Abigail.
Dear cousin.
I have a letter from our aunt...
and...
I'm sorry,
I did not mean to present as a...
I fell out of a carriage.
[shrieks]
And a man was pulling his...
Never mind the man.
The letter from our aunt.
[flies buzzing]
Friends of yours?
I'm sorry.
Your name, girl. If we are blood, name it.
I did not?
- Abigail Hill.
-[Sarah] The Somerset Hills?
The one who went mad and burnt
his own house down, himself in it?
Lost all his money at whist.
No one bets on whist.
My uncle was one of a kind.
[Abigail] I apologize for my appearance.
The staff led me here.
A harmless prank of some sort, I suspect.
[Sarah] And you want...
I hoped I might be employed here by you...
as something.
A monster for the children
to play with, perhaps?
Yes, if you like.
[growls]
[chuckles]
[classical music playing]
[bell rings]
[muffled cheering]
[cheering continues]
[cheering stops]
[music fades]
A palace.
You seem angry at my good fortune
and I thought we were friends.
I really doubt you've made that mistake.
I was actually just teasing.
I thought you'd see that.
It will not stand.
Well, it will if I build it
using the finest craftsmen in the land.
I hope it will stand for 100 years
as a symbol
of my husband's gallant victory.
Listen, I applaud
your husband's gallant victory,
but considering the parlous state
of the treasury,
it seems something the queen should've
taken advice from her loyal opposition on.
Oh, but then it would've lost
its delightful surprise element.
Cunt!
[man] Horatio has done it again.
Prime Minister, we need to discuss
who will go to the French
-with the peace treaty proposal.
- We do not need a peace treaty proposal.
We have them on the run.
So they will give in to us.
One battle will not win the war.
I have held my party together,
as we the country landowners
have essentially paid
for this entire war--
And grateful we are, too.
...while city merchants
enrich themselves from it.
And yet I do not see your fat tweedy dead
when I look out upon the battlefield.
We're out of money. My point.
The French are chastened,
but not defeated, Harley.
We must destroy them.
Make them sue for peace
with broken hearts and begging backs.
- How sweet your wife is, Marlborough.
- Sweet and right.
I cannot agree.
We must take it to the queen.
If you'd be kind enough
to arrange a time, Lady Marlborough.
[Sarah] Of course.
[snoring]
[woman coughs]
[exclaims]
I'm ready for the Russian ambassador.
Who did your makeup?
We went for something dramatic.
Do you like it?
You look like a badger.
Oh.
[Sarah] Are you going to cry? Really?
Well, what do you think you look like?
A badger.
Do you really think you can meet
the Russian delegation looking like that?
No.
I will manage it.
Get back to your rooms.
Thank you.
Did you just look at me? Did you?
Look at me! Look at me!
How dare you? Close your eyes!
[Sally] Hello.
Hello.
Mrs. Meg says you are to scrub the floor
until she can see
her toothless, fat face in it.
Sorry.
[gasps]
You might need gloves.
Lye is dangerous. It burns bad.
[exclaims]
[gasping]
[moaning painfully]
[Anne] Sarah!
I'm here.
You! Grab the bandage box off the shelf.
The queen's had an attack of gout. Hurry!
[Cries]
[Sarah] Mrs. Meg, brandy.
[Anne] It hurts.
[Sarah] My dearest, I know.
[moans]
Cousin, the beef.
[Sarah] Tell me a story.
I can't.
Ow!
[Sarah] Gently.
-[Anne] I can't.
-[Sarah] Yes, you can.
Cousin, start wrapping.
Everyone else, leave please.
[whimpering]
[Sarah] How we first met. Tell me that.
The wretched Cheever boy
had me on the ground
and he was holding me
and dropping spittle in my face.
[Sarah] He is still a pig. Then what?
[Anne sniffling]
[Anne] And then I heard footsteps.
Fast footsteps.
Ow, ow!
[birds chirping]
And I saw these pink shoes
running towards me.
And then they disappeared.
And then I heard a crack.
And then he fell off me.
[Anne moans]
And you held my hand and said,
“Hello. I'm Sarah.
You're covered in spittle.
Let's wash you off."
[Anne screams]
[Sarah] Do you remember
how his jaw just hung there?
[Anne laughs] l do.
-[Sarah] You must try to sleep.
-[Anne moans]
[Sarah] You may go.
-[Anne] Don't leave me!
-[Sarah] I won't.
- Are you still there?
- Yes.
[muffled chatter]
[Abigail] For the queen.
The doctor's ordered it immediately.
It's a matter of extreme urgency.
She's sleeping.
Shall I tell the doctor
you imperiled the queen's health
and let you rue the ramifications?
What does "ramific..."
It means he will have you whipped.
[door opens]
What are you doing?
[Abigail] This is peleatis, the herb.
I out some this morning.
It reduces swelling and inflammation.
I thought it may help the queen.
You cannot just walk in here.
Why did the footman let you through?
It's not his fault. I lied to him.
[footman] The prime minister
and Mr. Marlborough.
L just wanted to help her.
She seemed to suffer so much.
Footman.
Take her downstairs.
Tell Mrs. Meg she is to receive
six of the birch. Go.
It's peleatis, the herb.
Anne, you must focus.
[Marlborough] We gather our forces here.
The Austrians mass here.
[Anne] Which country is that again?
[Sarah] Listen. Marlborough.
[Marlborough] This is the town of Lille,
in a valley in France.
We lure them in by sending a small force
to engage them.
They give chase.
We descend in numbers from above.
-[all] Hear, hear!
- Hear, hear! It is an excellent plan.
Queen Anne, do you agree?
The people expect it to be over.
Well, we all want it to be over,
but wishing does not make it so.
We could sue for peace,
but we will not get it.
It does help.
What?
There's something soothing on my legs,
it takes the burn out. What is it?
Oh, herbs, of some sort.
[Abigail] Please, please.
What is going on?
Do her in the barn, if that's what it is,
not in my kitchen.
Her Ladyship says six of the birch
for this one.
[Abigail whimpers]
[screams]
[Cries]
[Sarah] Stop.
Let her go.
Come with me.
[Abigail panting]
So, you are perhaps too kind
for your own good.
It has been said.
Which leads to stupidity.
The queen is soothed somewhat,
so I thank you.
You will get me some more of those herbs
and not overstep again.
My father always spoke highly of you.
I liked your father.
He had charm to burn.
Then I guess he did.
You have fallen far.
When I was 15,
my father lost me in a card game.
You are not serious.
This one here.
[Abigail] He was very upset about it.
Took off into the forest
with nothing but a scullery maid
and a dozen bottles for solace.
[Sarah] And you went?
[Abigail] I wanted to do right
by my father.
The debt was to a balloon-shaped
German man with a thin cock.
Thankfully, I managed to convince him a
woman has her blood in 28 days a month.
[chuckles quietly]
What happened to your hand?
[Abigail] Some of my...
colleagues are immune to my charms.
[classical music playing]
Earl Stratford,
do not come near me whining today
or I will crush your tiny heart to liver.
Madame Tournee. You may have
the tapestry budget you asked for.
Spend one penny more
and I will take your fingernails in lieu.
[Tournee] Merci.
Abigail, get a platter of oysters
sent to the Dutch ambassador.
Yes, Your Ladyship.
[Sarah] Colonel Masham.
Lady Marlborough.
The queen will ride on Wednesday.
Yes, Lady Marlborough.
Would you like a bite of my new maid
before you leave?
[music fades]
[duck quacks]
Must the duck be here?
Fastest duck in the city.
Horatio is a prize worth stealing.
He does not leave my side.
Keep him away from me,
or I will pull his liver out
and eat it with a cornichon.
Charming.
You should know I've canvassed my party.
They're waiting for us
to announce an attempt at peace.
We shall both make our case to the queen.
Yes, where is the queen?
We've been waiting an hour.
-[footman] Lady Sarah Marlborough.
-I'm here.
[Harley] Might I remind you
you're not the queen?
No, she has sent me to speak for her.
She is unwell.
[prime minister] What says she?
That Harley is a fop and a prat and smells
like a 96-year-old French whore's vajuju.
Oh?
Well, I really doubt you're quoting.
She has decided to continue with the war.
She feels another victory in will put us
in a stronger position for a treaty.
Her letters.
[Harley] And how are we going
to pay for this?
The land tax is to be doubled.
This is madness.
The war you will be fighting
will be in our own countryside.
She relies on you and your love of England
to hold the Tories together.
- There are limits.
-[Sarah] The love of your country?
To me, there is no limit on that.
Our last farthing to protect England
if we must.
[Harley] And our last man, too?
Look, the dead pile up,
as do the resentments.
- Or that does not concern you?
-[Sarah] I grieve them all.
In my heart, a scar for each, and I send
my own beloved with them, chest bared.
So do not lecture me on the cost.
[Harley] A treaty would save money
and lives. A win for all Englishmen.
[prime minister] We go to them after one
victory, they know we are scared.
We bury more of them,
they know we have them.
The queen has decided, Harley.
I disagree.
A lot. I'd like an audience with the queen
where I may state my case.
State it to me. I love a comedy.
ls there cake?
[Harley] This is a disgusting distortion
of the system.
You have no place in this.
Your mascara is running.
If you'd like to go fix yourself,
we can continue this later.
[grunts]
[Harley grunts]
[Sarah] You will need to pay
for the repair of that.
We have a war to finance.
Every penny counts.
[prime minister]
Come on, old bean. One more victory.
[duck quacks]
[prime minister] Must you rub it in?
A man's dignity is the one thing
that holds him back from running amok.
Sometimes a lady likes to have some fun.
[prime minister]
We need to be careful, Sarah.
He's a useful ally, but a dangerous enemy.
[Sarah] Borrow anything you want.
Thank you.
And thank you for the job.
I have a thing for the weak.
[footman] Lord Marlborough.
[Marlborough] It is time.
[Sarah] You must be safe.
You must not be foolish and brave.
Be smart and safe, I beg you.
I will.
[Sarah] Stay with me tonight.
[Marlborough] I must sleep with my men.
It is only right.
I had a dream
that this very small Frenchman
covered in blood...
was carrying Marlborough's head around,
feeding it Brie.
He's a great soldier.
He will be fine.
We will prevail.
Of course we will, Mrs. Freeman.
[chuckles]
[coughs]
[Abigail] I'm sorry, Your Majesty.
I think I caught a chill
picking the herbs for your leg.
-[Anne] That was you?
- Abigail.
Let's shoot something.
-[gunshot]
-[bird caws]
[Abigail] It's sad really.
They're so pretty.
Throw.
[Sarah] You're only
doing damage to the sky.
Can I ask you something?
As long as you are aware
that I have a gun.
You fought hard for this war
and your husband is at the front of it.
His life is at risk.
How can you do that?
[Sarah] It is right.
If we don't do it,
they will gather force and be over here
cutting us all into chops within the year.
You are of a sweet disposition
and have suffered blows,
so desire safety and favor above all else.
If he dies?
[Sarah] Did you not sacrifice your cunt
to fatty German to save your father?
Yes.
[Sarah] There's always a price to pay.
I am prepared to pay it.
- Throw.
-[wings flapping]
[gunshot]
[Sarah] Just relax and aim.
When it crosses your eye,
pull the trigger.
Throw.
[Sarah] Perfect.
I will make a killer of you yet.
[Masham] Are you following me?
I said, are you following me?
You seem to be following me, sir,
as I am in front of you.
That was you I saw
on the horse that morning.
I am a servant. Where would I get a horse?
Perhaps you dreamt of me'?
Perhaps it was you, and I should have you
stripped and whipped.
I'm waiting.
Going to ride that one, are we?
She does make my blood hot.
She's Lady Marlborough's new one.
Indeed.
Interesting.
[footsteps]
[Harley] Excuse me. Move. Excuse me.
- Your Majesty. How lovely to see you.
-[festive music playing]
It seems you have allocated
even more money
into the abyss that is this fool's errand.
Oh, uh, yes. We will win.
Sarah's sure we will win.
It's the landholders' tax.
You have no idea the firestorm of rage
you have set loose in the countryside.
- Really? Are they angry?
- Dearest queen.
[Anne] How do you like my stockings?
[Sarah] Festive.
Very. I was just explaining to the queen
the mistake this tax is. The war as well.
We should sue for peace.
Oh, Harley, you are such a bore.
That is for parliament.
A ball is for dancing and eating
those horseradish and venison puffs.
Have you tried them?
I'm having trouble swallowing
at the moment. Your Majesty...
I'd like to enjoy the music now.
Oh, yes. I love this music. I must dance.
[music continues]
Stop it!
- Stop it! Stop!
-[music stops]
- What has happened?
- I would like to go back to my room now.
Stop. Mr. Harley.
I agree I went too far
with the tax for the war.
-[Sarah] What?
- It will stay as it was.
We are your servants, my queen.
Anne.
I'm sorry.
[Sarah] It's okay.
Shall we go fast?
-[Anne cheers]
-[Sarah giggles]
[Anne cheering, distant]
-[cheering gets closer]
-[door slams open]
[Anne and Sarah laugh]
[both giggle]
[Anne panting]
Fuck me.
-[kissing]
-[panting]
Abigail, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
Stolen a book, I see.
Why, one could be stripped
and whipped for that.
My mistress lent it to me.
Shall we go ask her?
- No.
-[muffled laughter]
No.
Come and take the night air with me.
So, you once were a lady,
and now you are nothing.
A bit of scullery scraps.
How very sad.
Well, I'm still the lady I was,
in my heart.
No doubt. It is important
to make new friends, is it not?
Yes.
If that's what's actually happening here,
and not veiled threats
under the guise of civility.
Am I to understand you are smart?
You want something.
To fuck me?
I will leave that to my friend Masham,
who is completely cunt-struck by you.
So, tell me about Lady Marlborough,
Godolphin, the queen.
Anything gaining on?
I love gossip.
It's a failing, I know.
[Abigail sighs] Lady Marlborough
has been good to me.
She saved me.
I will not breach her confidence.
[Harley] Of course. You are in favor.
But favor is a breeze
that shifts direction all the time.
Then in an instant, you're back sleeping
with a bunch of scabrous whores
wondering whose finger's in your ass.
You cannot have too many friends in court.
I need a friend, Abigail.
One with cute ears and wide eyes.
I'm often blindsided
by the distorted situation at court.
As leader of the opposition,
I should not be.
I would merely like to know of any plans
Her Ladyship, Godolphin,
or the queen may have.
I will not betray my mistress's trust.
Oh, look. A wren. How cute.
[Abigail grunts]
You all right?
[panting]
Anyway, think on it.
There's no pressure.
[Sarah] You will have to tell Harley
you've changed your mind about the tax.
[Anne] Are the people really angry
about the land tax?
[Sarah] They'll be angrier
when the French are sodomizing their wives
and planting their fields with garlic.
[Anne] The Tories must not be
rode roughshod over, though.
And more dead if we do it.
[Sarah] It is painful to lose men,
but we cannot be halfhearted in this
or they will see our weakness and take us
and we will lose thousands more.
None for the queen.
What?
You cannot have hot chocolate.
Your stomach, the sugar inflames it.
- Abigail, hand me that cup.
-[Sarah] Do not.
I'm sorry, I do not know what to do.
[Sarah] Fine, give it to her.
Then you can get a bucket and a mop
for the aftermath.
Take me back.
[classical music playing]
You will pronounce the tax in parliament.
I will set the date.
[music fades]
[Abigail] I must tell you something.
[Sarah] Go on.
[Abigail] Mr. Harley came to me
and asked me to betray your confidence
about what goes on between you
and the queen and Godolphin.
[Sarah] I see.
And what will you do?
[Abigail] I'm not going to, obviously.
[Sarah] Not obviously.
You may tell me of his approach
to encourage my trust
and still work both sides of the street.
[Abigail] I am a person of honor,
even if my station is not.
Even if I were the last one left
in this wretched place,
I would remain a lady.
[Sarah laughs]
You're pretty when outraged.
So my secrets are safe with you?
All of them.
[Sarah] Good.
Even your biggest secret.
Abigail.
[gasps]
If you forget to load the pellet,
the gun fires, makes the sound,
but releases no shot.
It is a great jape. Do you agree?
Yes.
Maybe we will think of
a use for it one day.
Sometimes, it is hard to remember
whether you have loaded the pellet or not.
I do fear confusion and accidents.
I'm sure people will be careful.
[gagging]
[breathes deeply]
[Sarah] Beef, 12 guineas.
Cream.
Mrs. Meg, your cream bill is outrageous.
Are you bathing in it
to help your hemorrhoids?
No, Your Ladyship.
[Harley] May I examine?
Of course.
It's perfect, Lady Marlborough, as always.
[page whispering]
The queen. It is rather urgent.
Shall we sign off?
Of course.
[classical music playing]
Aim for the flagstones.
The lawn might break your fall.
[Anne] You do not care.
Mrs. Morley.
- Please!
- No!
[Cries]
[music fades]
[Anne] Stay a while.
No! Take the day off. I command it.
Someone must run things.
I am not food.
You cannot just eat and eat.
[Anne] Yet you are tasty and salty.
[squeals] If I grilled you,
you'd make a delightful meal.
Very well.
I will come and see you this afternoon,
and we can play whist.
[footsteps]
[classical music playing]
[Godolphin] The opposition asks us
-to be halfhearted in this war!
-[loud, indistinct chatter]
- We will not!
-[man] Hear, hear!
We must wear our griefs,
for England is worth our all,
and suffer we must for her!
Mr. Harley,
control your rabble!
I am, therefore, announcing today
-that, at Her Majesty's...
-[music fades]
About time, Mrs. Freeman.
This fucking leg.
It's like a monster attacking me.
Cut it off for me, will you?
[Abigail] I don't think so, Your Majesty.
Why are you here?
Lady Marlborough sent me,
as I am an excellent whist player
and she has been unavoidably detained
with business of state,
but will be here posthaste.
It's my state.
I am the business of state.
Did she actually send me her maid?
[Abigail] Your Majesty,
I wasn't always a maid.
I'm educated, I speak Latin, French.
My family fell on hard times.
- I'm also her cousin.
-lt's all very fascinating.
You shall leave, regardless,
and tell her to come.
They're gorgeous.
They're my babies. Let them out, please.
[Abigail] How many are there?
[Anne] Seventeen.
It's Hildebrand's day today.
[Abigail] Which one is he?
That one there. Shy, but stubborn.
[Abigail] May I?
[Anne] He likes you.
I lost some 17 children.
Some were born as blood,
some without breath...
and some were with me
for a very brief time.
Oh, my dear.
Today is Hildebrand's day.
The day you lost him.
Yes.
Each one that dies,
a little bit of you goes with them.
Would you like to join me?
[Anne] Oh. Lovely cake.
Yum.
[Abigail] You like it?
-[Anne] Delish.
-[Abigail] You do like it.
[Anne] Hello, Sussy.
Happy birthday.
Come on. There's some for you, too.
Don't eat Mummy's foot.
[knocking on door]
What an outfit.
Thank you.
I thought it might be too much.
Have you come to seduce me or rape me?
[Masham] I am a gentleman.
So rape, then.
[Masham] No.
No, you are...
You have intrigued me.
And you, me.
I'm intrigued by what you look like
under all this.
You're handsome.
No wonder you cover it up.
Who are you?
No ordinary maid.
It could be said I have fallen far.
It could be said I aim to catch you.
[Masham] Ow!
I might allow it.
Now good night, sir.
Progress?
Uh... She, uh...
- She bit me.
- Oh.
This wig's ridiculous.
A man must look pretty.
I'm not entirely sure she approves.
Try again in your own way, old boy.
[classical music playing]
[music continues]
[music fades]
[Sarah] Apologies regarding
sending Abigail in my stead.
[Anne] She was perfectly darling.
Hildebrand really took to her.
Is that a rabbit?
Anne, you are too sensitive.
And you are too mean and uncaring,
some days.
Some days, I'm quite lovely, though.
Let's think on them.
[Sarah] Anne.
You're such a child.
[Abigail] I guess all the rapes
were the hardest.
Made me feel at their mercy.
That I was nothing.
You are not nothing. You're a dear person.
Thank you.
You're so beautiful.
Stop it. You mock me.
I do not.
If I were a man, I would ravish you.
- Ravish.
- Enough.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
[music playing, distant]
Oh, look.
[children playing music]
Make them stop.
What?
Stop!
Enough!
Be gone!
I command it!
Leave!
I don't want to hear it!
-[Abigail] Your Majesty?
- Now I must rest.
- Shall I...
- Leave me be!
[classical music playing]
[music continues]
Give me that.
{baby coos]
-[Anne laughing]
Thank you, Your Majesty.
[baby cries]
Where am I?
[page] Your Majesty,
you are in the west hallway.
Don't speak to me like that!
[Cries]
[Abigail] Your Majesty.
- Stupid girl! Where have you been?
-[Abigail] I'm sorry.
[Anne] Take me back.
[music continues]
[sobs]
[music fades]
[Abigail] Perhaps we should dance.
You mock me.
[Abigail] No. I just believe you can.
That it would be cheery.
I would dearly like to dance with you.
[pigeons cooing]
[both] Back.
Together. And click.
[gun cocking]
-[Sarah] Throw.
-[wings flapping]
- [gunshot]
- Back, front, back.
[gun cocks]
[Sarah] Throw.
[[gunshot]
Off with her head and off with her head.
[both laugh]
[pigeons cooing]
-[gun cocks]
-[Sarah] Throw.
[Abigail] Spin, spin, spin, spin.
[Anne laughs]
[gunshot]
[wings flapping]
-[gun cocks]
-[wings flapping]
[gunshot]
[Sarah] It's 12-11.
You're shooting
exceptionally well, Abigail.
[Abigail] You've taught me well.
I hope you haven't found your time
with the queen too tedious.
Oh, not at all.
And if it gives you rest, I'm happy.
- Did you sleep well?
- Like a shot badger.
Excellent.
The queen is...
an extraordinary person...
even if it's not readily apparent.
She's been stalked by tragedy.
She seems quite lovely.
[Sarah] I will not burden you again.
- I'm quite happy to...
- I know you are.
She will be angry if I do not appear soon.
Take your shot.
Throw.
[Abigail] Thirteen.
[Sarah] The queen?
I will be there directly.
The queen... asked for her.
I have sent for some lobsters. I thought
we could race them and then eat them.
- Oh, hello.
I hope you have three.
You sent for Abigail
to try and make me jealous, I think.
Perhaps.
[Anne gasps]
They'll be in with the lobsters.
You scared?
[door opens]
Oh, I think a moat is a bad idea.
It's just-- It's too old-fashioned.
Your lobsters, ma'am.
Where should I put them?
Uh... here.
[exclaims]
Hello. Remember me?
[Abigail] Mr. Harley.
You always unbalance me.
[Harley] So what's been happening?
The queen and Lady Marlborough
are to race lobsters and then eat them.
Do you want to get punched?
The queen is going to announce
the doubling of the landholders' tax
to parliament.
Do you jest?
I don't think she's certain of it, though.
But Lady Marlborough
is providing that certainty.
Yes.
And?
That is all.
Why do I feel that is not all?
I'm trying my best.
I am.
All right, turn off the tears. Thank you.
Have a pleasant evening.
May I speak a moment,
with Her Majesty's pleasure?
May I exhort the chamber
to roar a mighty hurrah for Her Majesty
in her brilliant decision
to not raise the land tax.
-[crowd] Hurrah!
-[Harley] For the doubling
of the tax would have been a disaster,
and the fields would have run with blood
as the countryside rose up
against our city friends,
to add to the piling dead of our sons
already on the field of this war.
Again, to our queen, for her deep wisdom
in knowing where to draw the line
in holding our country together.
For there is no point winning a war abroad
if we are to star': one at home.
-[crowd] Hear, hear!
-[crowd] Hurrah!
[Harley] I apologize for the interruption,
Your Majesty.
The floor is yours, of course.
We look forward to hearing
what you have to say.
[indistinct chatter]
[imitation animal sound]
[clicking]
-[screams]
[Abigail] Men should not
sneak up on women.
You look scared.
[Masham] I'm hurt.
[Abigail shrieks]
-[Masham grunts]
-[Abigail shrieks]
[Abigail] Wait, wait!
Kiss me properly first.
-[Masham grunts]
-[Abigail giggles]
I have just now decided
to marry you, Masham.
I cannot marry a servant.
I can enjoy one, though.
I know it would ruin you to marry me.
I will fix things for us.
Don't you think we are a good match?
I think a very good match.
[Masham screams]
I looked like a fool.
They were all staring, weren't they?
I can tell even if I can't see,
and I heard the word "fat." Fat.
- And ugly.
- Anne.
No one but me would dare, and I did not.
I felt for you. He set you up.
It is our fault.
I didn't know what else to do.
I couldn't go through with it.
It's fine, Anne. It's fine.
He was ready for us.
He probably just assumed
that you've been working on her.
A minor hitch.
We will reset the date.
[Anne] What are you doing?
Oh, Your Majesty.
Lady Marlborough asked me to wait for you,
and I was...
The bed looked so beautiful,
and I was overcome...
with foolishness. I'm sorry.
Well, you may get out now.
Apologies again, Your Majesty.
What happened to your dress?
Wolves.
Her legs.
[Anne] Rub my legs.
[Abigail] Does it hurt a lot?
They're agony.
[moans pleasurably]
Oh, the pain.
Marlborough has written.
He's in position.
The battle will begin any time.
He will prevail.
Of course.
I imagine you will not sleep tonight.
I can stay and sit with you.
I'm all right.
Good morning, Lady Marlborough.
[Sarah] Did you see that book of poetry
from the Dryden fellow?
I... have not.
[Sarah] No.
No.
I don't understand.
Did you take it? My book.
[Abigail] No.
I think you are a pretty little liar
that I have misjudged.
I did not mean for this to happen.
The queen, she's forceful.
[Sarah] You are dismissed from my service.
Go back to Mrs. Meg and tell her
to find you a position in the scullery.
And if she asks why, tell her
“Because I am a disloyal little bitch."
Yes, Your Ladyship.
It has been an honor and privilege--
If you do not go, I will start kicking you
and I will not stop.
[panting]
[muffled crying]
[crying continues]
[sniffling]
You have become close to Abigail.
She's been a dear. Yes.
It is such a shame,
but I've had to dismiss her for theft.
She's a liar and a thief.
Your tongue
seems uncharacteristically still.
I heard you.
She's my servant. She's not dismissed.
I've made her my maid of the bedchamber.
Did you not hear what I said?
Yes, you regard her as a liar and a thief.
- Yes.
- I do not, obviously.
You will dismiss her.
I don't want to.
I like it when she puts her tongue
inside me.
[classical music playing]
[music fades]
It feels so strange to be in this.
It's good for you.
The doctor says it'll leach the toxins.
What if I should fall asleep
and slip under?
Just imagine it's hot chocolate.
- Oh, then I shall die happy.
-[Abigail giggles]
[door opens]
[door closes]
[Sarah] After you left, I thought,
“What a grand idea to take to the mud."
To get whatever poisons
one carries with one out.
[mud sloshing]
[Sarah] Abigail, could you fetch me
some refreshment?
I would like to, of course, but...
I must be at the queen's side
and behest at all times.
It is my role.
Such loyalty.
How delightful it is when one tries to
cultivate a new trait in one's character.
- Do not scratch at her.
-[Sarah scoffs]
Mr. Freeman.
Mr. Morley.
Oh, how handsome you are.
[Anne] How handsome you are, Mr. Freeman.
[Sarah] Oh... But I...
I forgot my glasses.
[Anne and Sarah laugh]
[chuckles]
You will be back in the street.
[Sarah] Do you remember
when we were young,
and we were not allowed out in the snow,
and we opened all the windows
in the ballroom
and sat there
as the snow flurries just wafted in?
And when your governess came in, we were
making a snowman and our hands were blue.
-[Anne] Oh, it was such fun.
-[Abigail] Sounds marvelous.
[Sarah] So many things
we have done together.
[Abigail] I do love ancient history.
Sorry, Abigail, did you say something?
Oh, I was singing.
I cannot get a tune out of my head.
[Sarah] Well, there is
so much room for it.
[Abigail chuckles]
Lady Marlborough, you're such a wit.
Oh, Abigail, you are a dear.
I think I shall retire for the evening.
Shall I prepare your bed, Queen Anne?
Or shall you and I adjourn
to your apartments for some sherry?
[Anne] Oh!
Sherry sounds just the ticket.
Good night, Abigail.
Yes, good night, dear Abigail.
You are enjoying all of this, aren't you?
To be beloved? Of course.
To see you trying to win me.
Why, what is not to love, my dear?
You will stop this ridiculous infatuation.
You have made your point.
Perhaps I was not making a point.
[Abigail] Perhaps because of my past,
perhaps a malformation of my heart.
I blame my father, of course. Cunt.
I must take control of my circumstance.
I will need to act in a way
that meets with the edges of my morality.
And when I end up on the street
selling my asshole to syphilitic soldiers,
steadfast morality will be a
fucking nonsense that will mock me daily.
I'm not quite following.
Shh.
I apologize.
But do "shh" when I'm thinking.
Your hair is so lustrous.
It's something people in court comment on.
- Really?
- Mm-hmm.
I always thought of it
as rather nest-like.
Not at all.
[footman] Lady Marlborough.
I shall make you tea.
- What a lovely idea. Thank you, Abigail.
-[Abigail] Of course.
[Anne] Pat the kids hello.
Of course.
You will give that speech on
the tax increase in parliament next week.
[Anne] I dreamed of the man
on the roadside with one eye.
[Sarah] What man?
We drove through town.
He looked at me in such a way,
it made my blood chill.
So kind.
[Anne] Abigail, do you think the people
are angry?
Anne, she does not know.
We should ask people. Get some people in
from the villages and ask them.
[Sarah] That is not how matters of state
are dealt with.
People are led. They do not lead.
Would you leave Marlborough exposed?
He needs another battalion
ready to join him, and that means money.
Do not shout at me. I am the queen.
Then for once act like one.
[classical music playing]
Is the queen not riding today?
Do not speak to me.
[music continues]
[gags]
[coughs]
[music fades]
[indistinct chatter, laughing]
I have thought on the terms
of our friendship.
I thought it was unconditional love.
I will get you an audience with the queen
if you ask her a favor for me.
- Wench. You--
- Harley, you do not need me as an enemy.
As it turns out,
I am capable of much unpleasantness.
As am I.
[Abigail] You're so tiring,
being like this.
The queen has taken a shine to me,
and I will drip poison into her ear
regarding you
until she is mad with hatred for you.
Or we could have
a mutually advantageous friendship.
Count of three. Yes or no?
Well, if you're so close to the queen,
why not just ask this favor yourself?
[Abigail] I do not want her to ever think
I want anything from her.
- Have you counseled her for our side?
- No.
[Harley] The country's future
hangs in the balance.
Mm-hmm. My thing is what I wish
to talk about.
You do not care?
I thought you were on our side.
[Abigail] I'm on my side.
Always.
Sometimes,
it's a happy coincidence for you.
Like now.
You'll get a chance to save the country.
[moaning]
[grunting]
[Harley] What tremendous luck
to find you in the garden.
[Anne] We were taking the air.
[Harley] You do not like the war,
I know that.
[Anne] No, I do not,
but we must fight for what we fight for.
[Harley] Godolphin and Lady Marlborough
seem to have corralled you
so you do not get to hear
from your loyal opposition.
[Anne] I am briefed appropriately.
[Harley] Were it in person,
I'd believe it.
-[Anne] I am often ill.
-[Harley] True.
Sadly true.
The war with the French will bleed us dry
even if we win.
We are in our strongest position now.
If Marlborough loses this next battle,
we could lose all.
The people hate the war, you realize,
they begin to hate you.
Lady Marlborough has not told you
of the riots in Leeds?
[Anne] No, she has not.
- All I ask is that you search your heart.
- Of course.
Not Lady Marlborough's heart, your own.
I must talk to you of your maid also.
- Abigail?
- I believe that is her name.
It seems Colonel Masham has fallen
for her. He wishes to marry.
[Anne] She's just a maid.
[Harley] lt is irregular and inexplicable,
but being sentimental,
I am moved to help if possible.
What do you mean she's not been seen?
[Masham] She took a horse, Your Majesty.
It did not come back and nor did she.
[Godolphin] I shall send riders.
No.
I think she means to vex me.
Do not send riders.
[Godolphin]
In case she has fallen, though.
She's too good a rider for that.
I know what she is. Do not seek her.
[grunting and groaning]
Where am I?
You're in heaven.
That's God. You'll meet him later.
- I must go.
- I don't think that's happening.
[woman] Lie back.
[inhales sharply]
[woman] Stop infection.
[Anne] Get Lady Marlborough.
Now! Take me to her!
Find her.
Find her!
[Anne] There are wolves out there,
are there not?
[Godolphin] No, Your Majesty.
I don't think so.
Perhaps she's gone to Blenheim,
her palace?
There is no palace yet. It is the woods.
We should check in the trees,
just to be sure.
[Anne] Mr. Harley!
I apologize.
I hope we find her,
and she's not dead in a ditch.
The business of state, however,
cannot stop.
Your Majesty, there has been no word
from the front in two weeks.
There is no doubt
that Marlborough is in trouble.
We need to send a division immediately
to help him.
Costing a fortune, built on your paranoia,
and walking into God knows what.
We need to wait.
I will think on it for a while.
[Godolphin] This cannot wait.
We need to act now.
Is it a bit like going late to your party?
If the party's going well, they did not
need you, and they resent the intrusion.
But if it's going badly,
you cannot save it,
and you tend to regret
ever putting on your nice gown for it.
[Godolphin] It is not like a party.
[Abigail] I'm sorry, Prime Minister,
a passing thought.
I think it is like a party.
- A perfect analogy.
-[Anne] We will wait.
Make sure they have their best dresses on
so they're ready at a moment's notice.
Shift a division to the coast
and have a boat at the ready.
Abigail.
I worry something has befallen her.
It's night. Out there alone.
[Abigail] She's strong.
- And she'll be fine.
- Yes.
She saved me my whole life.
Without her, I'm nothing.
That is not true.
- You are the queen.
-I'm tired.
It hurts. Everything hurts.
Everyone leaves me.
Dies.
Finally her.
If she's not dead, I will cut her throat.
She may be doing this to hurt me,
make me dissolve and dissemble.
I will not.
She will be fine. They will find her.
[Anne] I don't care.
You are a beautiful person.
You glow with loveliness.
We will marry you.
- What?
- Colonel Masham wishes to marry you.
- He does?
- Yes, you've quite captured him.
That is absurd.
I have nothing to offer.
I'm a penniless servant.
It would be career suicide for him.
Your first thought is for him?
Oh, you are a darling.
I care for him.
Not in the way I care for you,
but enough to marry.
I will not lie,
I would like to be a lady again.
Yes, yes, this is right.
While she is gone.
If we wait, she'll return
and yell and stomp about it.
But you must have this. This is my gift
to you, and I demand you take it.
Of course. When--
Let's-- Now.
[classical music playing]
I, Abigail Hill, take thee, Samuel Masham,
to be my lawful wedded husband.
[Masham] I, Samuel Masham, take thee,
Abigail Hill, to be my lawful wedded wife.
[Clapping]
[Abigail] It is most generous.
I am overwhelmed.
Shall we say "gambling debts," Mr. Harley?
Excellent.
[Anne] Oh, and you are to take apartments
in the east wing.
-[Masham] Thank you, Your Majesty.
-[Abigail] Thank you.
[Anne] Oh, it is fun
to be queen sometimes.
[Harley] Hmm. One can only imagine.
[music continues]
[Masham] You're looking the wrong way.
Where could she have gone?
You sent riders looking for her?
[Masham] I have told you before.
She would be sick for several days,
but she would be near recovered by now.
[Masham] She probably went back
to Southampton.
To do what? To plan what? To get ready?
I am as hard as a rock,
and it is our wedding night.
Lie still.
[Masham grunts]
Now that she is gone, I find myself
more concerned than when she was here.
For it is like she could strike
from anywhere at any time,
and I will not see it coming.
[Masham exhales]
I must be calm.
She's gone.
I'm married.
[Masham groans]
But I must be ready.
And yet, how to be ready
when I do not know where my enemy is?
My life is like a maze
I continually think I have gotten out of,
only to find another corner
right in front of me.
[Masham groans]
[music ends]
-[rhythmic creaking]
-[muffled moaning]
Boy, fetch me a carriage.
Mae says no.
I'm leaving. Help me up.
Are you feeling better, then?
[Sarah] ls my horse alive,
or did you eat it?
I sold it.
You still owe me, though.
You can suck for your supper from now on.
I'll take 20%.
You seem posh. Gents will like that.
[Sarah] Have you ever seen
ten gold sovereigns?
[Mae] In my dreams.
[Sarah] Go to Hyde Park fountain
at 9:00 in the morning,
and you will see a man walking a duck.
[Godolphin chuckles]
What happened? Are you all right?
That cunt, Abigail, poisoned me.
Mary Magdalene here found me.
Did they rape you?
No, they didn't.
But gainful employment is on offer
should I need it.
[Godolphin] Abigail did this?
Yes.
How goes the kingdom?
♪ Music ♪
♪ Music for a while ♪
♪ Shall all your cares beguile ♪
♪ Shall all ♪
♪ All, all ♪
♪ Shall all your cares beguile ♪
♪ Wondering ♪
♪ How your pains were eased ♪
♪ Eased ♪
♪ And disdaining to be pleased ♪
♪ From their eternal ♪
- ♪ Eternal ♪
-[soft, indistinct chatter]
[singer] ♪ Eternal bands ♪
♪ Till the snakes ♪
♪ Drop, drop ♪
[music stops]
Lady Marlborough.
Oh, dear.
The servant is dressed in the clothes
of a lady. How... whimsical.
My dear friend and cousin,
how good to see you've returned from--
Hell.
I'm sure you shall pass through it
one day.
[Abigail] You've missed a few things.
My marriage.
It was a simple affair,
but beautifully done.
[scoffs]
Everyone leave.
If you offer me tea,
you will forgive me if I don't accept.
I have searched my heart, and I did not
have trust in it, and that is my shame.
I could not just stand by
and let you destroy me.
You have perhaps taught me that.
But it's over now.
I have won. I am safe.
We do not have to fight anymore.
ls that not grand?
If you just forgive me,
we can be happy together.
[Abigail grunts]
Obviously, you still have some anger
to expiate.
I'll allow it this once.
[Sarah] Congratulations
on your wedded bliss.
[snickers]
[Anne] Your face.
Do I look that bad?
If I were a man,
it'd be quite dashing, a scar like this.
Where have you been, Sarah?
Why did you leave like that?
[Sarah] I went riding.
Some bandits attacked me.
It took me a while to fight them off.
Oh, your poor face.
[Sarah] You should see them.
And you've been well taken care of,
I trust.
Some men were eventually sent to find me,
I hear
I was worried for you. I thought you...
You did not do it to try and hurt me?
I do not play games with you.
[Anne] No, I know, I know.
Look at me.
I will say this once and plainly,
my dearest one.
You must send Abigail away.
From my heart, Mrs. Morley, do it.
I do not want to.
[Sarah] She is a viper.
[footsteps]
You're jealous.
- You will do as I say.
-[knocking]
[footman] The prime minister
and Mr. Harley.
[Sarah] What is it?
[Harley] A thousand pardons, Your Majesty,
but word from the front.
[Sarah] What has happened?
Marlborough is ready.
He has them outflanked.
He needs a garrison to attack the coast.
Let them go to the party now.
Of course, Your Majesty.
[Sarah] What party?
It happened while you were gone.
Thank you, gentlemen.
Keep me informed of progress.
It is good to see you home
and looking so well, Lady Marlborough.
Now, you did very well with the divisions.
[Anne] Yes, I know I did.
However, the two new cabinet positions,
they must stay with the Whigs.
I am the queen.
Do not try to do that thing you do.
Do not try to manage this, as you cannot.
I know that Harley has been in your ear
and Abigail in your bed.
Enough!
You will be as I wish you to be
from now on. Do you understand?
Anne.
[Anne] Don't. No, don't.
No, your face frightens me. Don't!
-[Sarah coughs]
- Good night, Lady Marlborough.
Morning.
What a strange sight you are, my dear.
It is better, though.
[Anne yawns]
I think I'm becoming quite sentimental
as I get older.
[Anne] Didn't think you had the capacity
for sentimentality.
I didn't think so either...
but so much is surprising me lately.
I started looking over some of the many,
many, many letters you've written me.
"I long for your embrace.
I long for the heat from your naked body
on mine."
It's very intense, very explicit.
I thought I'd misplaced some of them
the other day. It was quite a fright.
What if, say, that son of a bitch,
Jonathan Swift, got his hands on them?
In his newspaper the next day.
You would be ruined.
You would never.
You have no idea what I would do
for my country...
and for you.
Ruin me? You would do that?
I will use these letters,
unless you announce the tax rise,
change the cabinet as I wish,
and get rid of Abigail.
[classical music playing]
Do you not wish to know what I've decided?
I wish to know that you are happy,
and that your spirit will lighten
once this is done.
[music continues]
[door opens]
The queen requests the return of your key.
You will return it and vacate court today.
Where is she?
[courtier] You will hand over the key.
The queen will not grant you an audience.
[door closes]
[music fades]
[knocking on door]
[Sarah] Anne?
I handed over my key.
Mrs. Morley, you are angry, I know.
I am sorry.
I went quite mad for a moment.
Just open the door.
- Please, just... Could you just...
-[knocking]
Mrs. Morley, open the door.
I burned the letters. I burned them.
Oh, do what you will.
[Sarah] But I will not come back.
Do you understand?
I will go and be gone.
Abigail has done this.
She does not love you.
[Anne] Because how could anyone?
She wants nothing from me, unlike you.
[Sarah] She wants nothing from you,
and yet somehow she is a lady,
with 2,000 a year,
and Harley sits on your knee most nights.
I wish you could love me as she does.
[Sarah] You wish me to lie to you?
Oh.
“You look like a-- a-- an angel
fell from heaven, Your Majesty."
No.
Sometimes, you look like a badger.
- And you can rely on me to tell you.
- Why?
Because I will not lie! That is love!
[Anne] I have my duties to attend to.
[footsteps]
I have“.
I have, over the last several months,
been unhappy with the government.
[indistinct chatter]
Lord Godolphin has lost my confidence.
Therefore, I am announcing
a new prime minister...
will be Mr. Harley.
Godolphin,
I thank you for your service.
We will sue for peace
with France immediately.
I have spoken!
All depart!
[cheering, murmuring]
Leave that. I like it.
The mirrors stay, too.
Oh, my God.
You actually think you have won.
Haven't I?
We were playing very different games.
All I know is, your carriage awaits,
and my maid is on her way up
with something called a pineapple.
[driver] Go?
Go.
[classical music playing]
Do it again!
[cheering]
[music continues]
-[door opens]
{Abigail giggles]
I'm here.
Will you do my legs, please?
Of course.
Hot towels, now.
Are you drunk?
I've had wine.
Very good wine.
You should have some.
I'll get you some. It would ease you.
No.
I don't understand these papers.
I'm feeling unwell.
Excuse me a moment, please.
[coughs]
[music fades]
Sorry. I am unwell.
Why, lay down.
I'll call the doctor for you, my love.
[Abigail sighs] Thank you, thank you.
[bell rings]
[Anne] Doctor.
[Sarah] What goes on?
[Godolphin] They've brokered a peace
with the French,
giving up too much, of course.
Of course.
Marlborough returns in a week.
Harley will move to have him replaced.
Now that peace with France
has been made...
[crowd cheers]
[Harley] Marlborough's return back
to England is imminent.
I wonder, Your Majesty,
whether it is right
that he is left as head of our forces?
I will rip his mole from his face.
You must stop it, Godolphin.
He is a hero who won the peace for us.
Indeed, but he would have launched us
into a bloody war
that would have ruined us,
so there's that.
It would be easier to pull my strings
if you were back at court.
A new era of peace and prosperity,
a new day,
a door to a new future.
There's metaphors abound.
I'm tired. I will think on it.
Thank you, all.
[Godolphin] Obviously, you have chosen
to keep the particulars of your dismissal
from me.
I shall leave a gap in the conversation
for you to remedy that.
I do not know of women and their feelings,
but I know they nurse their hurts
like wailing newborns.
Godolphin, I feel a surge of desire
to see your nose broken.
Your point?
Your Majesty, may I broach
the matter of Lady Marlborough?
No, you may not.
[Godolphin] A breach in a dear friendship.
Surely this could be healed.
Some wounds do not close.
I have many such.
One just walks around with them,
and sometimes one can feel them
filling with blood.
A letter.
An apology of some sort
that facilitates your return.
There are limits to what one can give.
Perhaps she could write you,
and we could attempt to repair
at least one wound in our queen?
Cannot stop her.
I imagine it'd be pointless,
and I would dash the letter into the fire,
but I cannot stop her.
[classical music playing]
“You... cunt."
“My God,
I miss you.“
Are you sure this is all of the mail?
[Abigail] You seek something?
No, I...
A fabric piece from my cousin in Florence.
I'm sure it will come.
“L dreamt I stabbed you
in the eye."
[music continues]
This cannot be all of it.
- It is, ma'am.
- Don't lean at me!
Shall we request another fabric piece
from your cousin in Florence?
Perhaps it was lost or eaten by mice
on the long journey.
No, I just want to know
that all my mail is here.
[Abigail] Of course.
Footman, go and check again.
Immediately.
Incompetent.
“My dearest...
Mrs. Morley...
I..."
[music ends]
I am in a quandary...
and you are my dearest one.
I do not know whether to speak of it.
What is it?
I'm not sure.
I don't like this.
You'll lodge this unknowable thing
in my brain,
and it will eat me
with horrible possibilities.
[Abigail] It is not horrible, dear Anne.
It is just money.
Money?
I have found in the books...
large sums of money seem to have flowed
to Marlborough,
but are not reflected
in the forces' receipts of expenses.
What?
[Abigail] It is gone.
Shall I request it back on his return?
Quietly, perhaps?
Are you saying that Sarah
diverted money to him?
[Abigail] It does seem so.
Some 7,000.
[Anne] She would not.
- It is just--
- She would not.
I'm, of course, perhaps mistaken
in the bookkeeping.
Sometimes all these numbers are dizzying,
and they're as fickle as humans.
They often do add up
on the second or third attempt.
There's a simple explanation
I'm not seeing.
We shall banish it from our minds.
Shall we take the children for a walk
in the garden?
No, thank you. I need to rest.
You may leave.
Fuck!
Fuck! Fuck! Fuck!
[door opens]
I need to put it back.
Be gone.
[door closes]
Marlborough is at Southampton.
We need a decision.
-[Godolphin] Your Majesty, if I may--
- There was very little mail today.
[Harley] Quite. If I may,
the situation with Marlborough?
He is stealing from me.
[Godolphin] What?
Your Majesty, that is preposterous.
Lady Abigail, privy purse,
is it not true they have stolen from me?
Damaged us?
Yes.
It is all there in black and white.
She must be ruined,
banished from their beloved England.
They are not loyal.
They would hurt us, our country,
the queen.
- Your Majesty, if I may--
- No, you may not!
He will be charged. They will be banished.
I have spoken. Get out!
Ah, the mail is here.
I suddenly feel so tired of England,
my darling.
Perhaps we should go somewhere else.
[sighs]
[rabbit squeals]
[piano melody starts]
- [thud]
-[Anne grunts]
[Abigail] Anne?
Darling Anne?
Let's get you in a chair.
How dare you touch the queen like that!
-[Abigail] I'm sorry.
- I did not ask you to speak.
[panting]
Rub my leg.
[melody builds]
- You should lie down.
- You shall speak when asked to.
[panting]
I feel dizzy.
I need to hold on to something.
[Anne panting]
[melody builds]
[melody distorts]
[melody fades]
[harpsichord playing]
[man] ♪ Turn me loose ♪
♪ From your hands ♪
♪ Let me fly ♪
♪ To distant lands ♪
♪ Over green fields ♪
♪ Trees and mountains ♪
♪ Flowers ♪
♪ And forest fountains ♪
♪ Home along the lanes ♪
♪ Of the skyway ♪
♪ For this dark ♪
♪ And lonely room ♪
♪ Projects a shadow ♪
♪ Cast in gloom ♪
♪ And my eyes are mirrors ♪
♪ Of the world outside ♪
♪ Thinking of the way ♪
♪ That the wind can turn the tide ♪
♪ And these shadows turn ♪
♪ From purple into gray ♪
♪ For just a skyline pigeon ♪
♪ Dreaming of the open ♪
♪ Waiting for the day ♪
♪ That he can spread his wings ♪
♪ And fly away again ♪
♪ Fly away ♪
♪ Skyline pigeon, fly ♪
♪ Towards the dreams ♪
♪ You've left so very far behind ♪
♪ Fly away ♪
♪ Skyline pigeon, fly ♪
♪ Towards the dreams ♪
♪ You've left so very far behind ♪
♪ Just let me wake up in the morning ♪
♪ To the smell of new-mown hay ♪
♪ To laugh and cry ♪
♪ To live and die ♪
♪ In the brightness of my day ♪
♪ I want to hear the pealing bells ♪
♪ Of distant churches sing ♪
♪ But most of all, please free me ♪
♪ From this aching metal ring ♪
♪ And open out this cage ♪
♪ Towards the sun ♪
♪ For just this skyline pigeon ♪
♪ Dreaming of the open ♪
♪ Waiting for the day ♪
♪ He can spread his wings ♪
♪ And fly away again ♪
♪ Fly away ♪
♪ Skyline pigeon, fly ♪
♪ Towards the things ♪
♪ You've left so very far behind ♪
♪ Fly away ♪
♪ Skyline pigeon, fly ♪
♪ Towards the things you've left ♪
♪ So very ♪
♪ So very far ♪
♪ Behind ♪
[ambient nature sounds]
[ambient nature sounds continue]