After weeks of campaigning on the road...
Tony Blair and his family,
finally strolled the few hundred yards
to the polling station,
this election day morning.
Amongst the Labour faithful
up and down the country...
there is an enormous sense
of pride in Mr. Blair's achievements.
And the confidence
that he is about to become
the youngest Prime Minister
this century.
Have you voted yet,
Mr. Crawford?
Yes, Ma'am...
I was there when they opened,
first in line, at 7 o'clock...
I don't mind telling you...
It wasn't for Mr. Blair.
-Your not a moderniser then?
-Certainly not...
We're in danger of losing too much,
that is good about this country, as it is.
There is a growing sense
of excitement...
I envy you, being able to vote.
Not the actually
ticking of the box, although...
it would be nice
to experience that once.
But the sheer joy of being partial.
Yes...
Of course one forgets
that as Sovereign,
you're not entitled to vote.
No...
Still, you won't catch me
feeling sorry for you.
You might not
be allowed to vote, Ma'am...
but it is your government.
Yes...
I suppose that is some consolation.
Good morning.
-Shall I draw the curtains.
-Yes...
So, did you stay up all night?
Yes, Ma'am.
And was it as expected?
Mr. Blair.
By a landslide.
Oh, I see...
They've stopped the traffic, completely...
For Tony Blair's first
day of power, in London.
You got the ceremonial
with tourists, the official...
and you got
a lovely summer's day...
Tony Blair waving to the crowds,
people waving to them there...
I guess most of them
do know it's the...
the Prime Minister waiting...
Lining in the streets there.
The Prime Minister
is on his way, Ma'am.
To be, Robin...
The Prime Minister to be...
I haven't asked him yet.
He's a hard one to read,
isn't he?
Yes... On the one hand his
background is quite establishment...
father a conservative,
educated at Fettis.
Where he was tutored by the same
man as the Prince of Wales.
Well, we'll try not
to hold that against him.
On the other, his manifesto promises
the most radical modernisation...
and shake up of the
constitution in 300 years.
Oh, you mean he is
going to try and modernise us?
I wouldn't let it past him...
he's married to a woman with known
anti-monarchist sympathies...
you may remember her curtsy,
the first time you met.
It could best
be described as... shallow.
I don't measure the depth of a
curtsy, Robin. I leave that to my sister.
The atmosphere at Downing Street
is expected to very informal...
Everyone on first name terms...
at the Prime Minister's insistence.
-What, as in call me Tony?
-Yes, Ma'am.
Oh, I don't like that.
Could we send him a protocol sheet?
Funny, I'm actually rather nervous.
Why? You've met her
often enough before.
I know, but...
never one to one...
and never as Prime Minister.
Well, just remember...
you're a man that's just been
elected by the whole nation.
But she's still...
you know...
The Queen.
When we reach the
audience room...
I will knock. We will not wait to be called...
we shall go straight inside.
Standing by the door,
we bow... from the neck...
I will introduce you...
The Queen will extend her hand...
you go to her...
bow again...
then shake her hand.
A couple of other things...
It's Ma'am as in ham...
not mam as in farm.
And when you're in the presence...
at no point must you
show your back.
-The presence?
-Yes, sir...
That's what it is called, when you're
in Her Majesty's company.
Would you like
to sit down, Mrs. Blair?
How nice to see you
again, Mr. Blair.
And congratulations.
The children must be very proud?
-I hope so.
-You have three, haven't you?
-That's right.
-Oh, how lovely.
Such a blessing... children.
Please, do sit down.
Thank you.
Have they shown you how to
start a nuclear war, yet?
Ah, no...
Oh, first thing we do.
Apparently...
Then we take away your passport,
and spend the rest of the time
sending you around the world.
You obviously know my job,
better than I do...
Well you are my 10th
Prime Minister, Mr. Blair.
My first, of course,
was Winston Churchill
he sat in your chair... in a frock coat...
and top hat.
He was kind enough to give,
a shy young girl like me,
quite an education.
I can imagine...
With time, one has hopefully added
experience to that education.
And a little wisdom...
better enabling us to execute our
constitutional responsibility.
To advise, guide, and warn
the government of the day.
Advise which I...
look forward to receiving.
Yes, we'll save that for
our weekly meetings.
If there's nothing else, I believe we
have some business to attend to.
Of course...
Your Majesty, my party has
won the election...
so I come now to ask your
permission to form a govern...
No, Mr. Blair.
Mr. Blair, I ask the question.
The duty falls upon me
as your Sovereign
to invite you
to become Prime Minister...
and to form a
government in my name.
And if you agree,
the custom is to say yes...
Yes...
Mrs. Blair...
Lovely to see you again.
And congratulations.
You must be very proud.
-Yes...
-And exhausted, I imagine...
Where will you be spending
the summer?
-France.
-Oh, lovely.
-You'll be at Balmoral, right?
-Yes, I can't wait. It's a wonderful place.
You know my great great
grandmother Victoria said of it...
in Balmoral all seems to breed...
freedom and peace and make one
forget the world and its sad turmoils.
Oh, excuse me.
Oh, yes of course...
I'm so sorry, we're going to
have to leave it there.
Not to short was it?
15 minutes...
One doesn't want to be rude.
No, no.
Thank you very much
for coming, now fuck off!
I know,
what was all that about?
God knows...
Diana. Whatever it is it will
be something to do with Diana.
Princess Diana embroiled
in more controversy
as she pulls out
of a meeting with MP's...
Princess Diana moved today
to patch up
her relations with
the former royal nanny...
Princess Diana flew to Milan today
for the memorial service
for the murdered
Italian fashion designer...
Gianni Versace.
Where tonight, another royal
controversy sparkles...
after finding herself embroiled
in her second controversy this week...
I am not a political figure...
Princess Diana sailed out
into the Mediterranean...
in one of Mr. Mohamed
al-Fayed's yachts today...
with his son.
A quarter of a
million pounds, for photographs
which appear
to show the couple embracing...
Once again,
her judgement's under scrutiny...
Robin Janvrin.
What?
I want everyone in, ASAP.
Ma'am?
Ma'am, Mr. Janvrin
is here to see you.
What?
Good evening, Ma'am.
I'm sorry to disturb.
But I just had a call from
our Embassy in Paris.
It's The Princess of Wales.
Why? What's she done now?
I see, em...
Who are we speaking to then?
Right, well keep me updated.
It's Diana, she's been in
a car accident in Paris.
Is it serious?
Apparently... Dodi Fayed is dead.
Let's just recap on the
details of those injuries, Maxine.
Yes Nick, what they're saying is...
that the Princess is in the intensive
care unit of a south-east Paris hospital.
She has a concussion,
a broken arm, and...
What was she doing in Paris? I thought
she was supposed to be in London.
Oh, you know what she's like.
Charles, isn't this awful?
What are you
going to do about the boys?
Let them sleep until we know more.
Yes, that's sensible.
I should go to Paris. I told
my people to start organising a jet.
-What, a private one?
-Yes...
Isn't that precisely the sort of
extravagance they always attack us for?
How else am I supposed to
get to Paris at this time of night?
The airport at Aberdeen
will be closed.
Charles...
Use the royal flight.
They keep one plane on
permanent standby...
in case I should kick the bucket.
No mummy! That's out of the question.
This isn't a matter of state.
What are you talking about?
Diana is no longer a member
of the royal family.
She's not a HRH.
This is a private matter.
She's mother to your grandchildren.
-What is happening now?
-I don't know... I can't hear...
everyone's shouting.
Thank's for coming in.
The Ambassador, from Paris.
Good evening, sir.
Yes?
I have just spoken to
our Ambassador in Paris, Ma'am...
I'm afraid it's not good news...
No!
No,
no, no...
Diana, Princess of Wales,
has died, after a car crash in Paris.
The French government
announced her death
just before
5 o'clock this morning.
What have I got on this week?
You're writing your maiden
conference speeches, Prime Minister.
Well, let's cancel everything else.
This is going to be massive...
I'd better make a statement
in the morning.
Well, you'll be pleased to know I've
already started coming up with ideas.
God, she's only been dead an hour...
Well, would you prefer
I didn't do my job?
They're going go to
go back to sleep.
Try anyway...
My private secretary's
office have...
found a travel agency open
in New York that will...
sell me a flight to Paris, with
an hours stop over in Manchester.
Perhaps now you might
like to consider whether it's
still an extravagance
to bring back the mother...
of the future King of England...
in one of our planes.
Alright...
of course.
John, I don't want the boys
to see the news and get upset...
first thing in the morning,
I want the radio taken
out of the bedroom, and the
television taken out of the nursery.
Yes, Ma'am.
Well, well, well...
Yes.
Are you alright?
Your sister called.
From Tuscany.
Well, I hope you told her to
come back, cut her holiday short.
I did.
I can't imagine she
was pleased...
That's putting it mildly.
-What did she say?
-Something about Diana managing...
to be even more annoying
dead than alive...
Just make sure you never let
the boys hear you talk like that.
Of course...
Something to help you go down.
No, I think I'll write
my diary a little longer.
Fine.
I'm going to bed.
We've heard nothing official from
the Palace yet, we still don't know
when we're gonna get any further
statements from inside the Palace...
Or of course when the royal
family are due back.
That's how she will remain,
in our minds, our hearts...
forever.
OK?
Got it!
Where will you do it?
We'll do it at the church.
On the way in.
Alright, I'll organise it.
Hang on...
I wanna watch this.
This is not the time for
incriminations, but for sadness...
however I would say
that I always believed
the press would
kill her in the end...
but not even I
could imagine they'll take
such a direct hand in her death...
as seems to be the case.
It would appear that every
proprietor and editor...
of every publication
that has paid for intrusive
and exploitative
photographs of her...
has blood on his hands today.
Not the press, mate.
You got the wrong villain.
Tony...
Oh! Got to go...
You about to speak to The Queen?
Yeah...
Ask her if she
greased the breaks.
Now, now...
Hello?
Right, okay...
Is The Prince of Wales
with the boys?
Yes, Ma'am
-And he's going to Paris?
-Yes...
I'm sorry to disturb, Ma'am...
Ma'am...
but I have the Prime Minister for you,
from his constituency.
Lucky you...
Thank you, Robin.
I'll take it in the study.
-Good morning, Your Majesty.
-Prime Minister.
May I say right away,
how very sorry I am...
and that the thoughts
and prayers of my family
are with you
at this terrible time.
And with the Princes,
in particular.
Thank you.
Is it your intention to make
some kind of appearance?
Or statement?
No, no!
Certainly not.
No member of the royal family
will speak publicly about this.
This is a private matter.
We would all appreciate it,
if it could be respected as such.
I see.
I don't suppose anyone has had
time to think about the funeral, yet?
We've spoken with the
Spencer family, and it is their wish...
it is their expressed wish,
that this should be a private funeral.
With a memorial service to follow,
in a month or so.
Right...
And given that Diana was
no longer a member of the royal family...
we have no other choice,
but to respect their wishes.
I see...
you don't feel...
that in view of her high
profile popularity...
it might be an idea to pay
tribute to her life and achievements?
Or even just to her as a mother?
Well, as I said,
it's her family's wish...
And the public, Ma'am?
The British people...
you don't think a private funeral
might be denying them a chance...
A chance to what?
To share in the grief.
This is a family funeral, Mr. Blair,
not a fairground attraction.
I think The Princess has
already paid a high enough price...
for exposure to the
press, don't you?
Now, if there's nothing else,
I must get on.
The children have to be looked after.
Of course...
well, goodbye Your Majes...
Her instinct is to do nothing.
Say nothing...
and give her a private funeral.
Are you surprised?
She hated her guts.
Well, I think it's a mistake...
They screwed up her life, let's
hope they don't screw up her death.
Where can I find a black tie?
Oh, the chaplain called.
He wanted to know,
whether we should make any
changes in the service...
any...
special mention of Diana.
What did you say?
Well, I told him
not to change a thing.
Quite right...
I think the less attention one
draws to it, the better.
-For the boys.
-Yes...
But I think maybe we should find
some company for them...
Some young people.
I'll take them for a long walk,
this afternoon... up Craggie Head.
Yes, but no guns Phillip...
It is Sunday.
And we're going... in fact...
I believe...
to Sedgefield,
the Prime Minister's constituency,
where he is about...
to make a statement...
yes the Prime
Minister coming now,
with his wife Cherie...
He's on. Alastair, he's on.
Come on!
...as her own life...
was often,
sadly touched by tragedy...
she touched the lives,
of so many others in...
in Britain, throughout the world...
with joy...
and with comfort.
The people, everywhere...
not just here in Britain,
everywhere...
they kept faith,
with Princess Diana.
They liked her, they loved her...
they regarded her,
as one of the people...
she was the people's Princess.
And that's how she will...
stay... how she will remain.
In our hearts...
and in our memories...
forever.
A little over the top,
don't you think?
The people of Britain, he said...
kept faith...
with Princess Diana...
they loved her...
she was the people's Princess.
Did we remember the
Royal Standard?
Yes, Sir.
-And flowers?
-Yes, Sir.
Good, 'cause if we leave it
to the rural undertakers...
they'll bring her
back in a wooden crypt.
Hello?
This is Lord Airlie, may I speak
with the Prime Minister, please?
One moment, please.
Lord Airlie...
The Lord Chamberlain
in charge of the funeral...
you're meeting him at the airport.
Lord Airlie.
Good afternoon, Prime Minister,
it's my job to organise
all the ceremonial events.
There is simply no precedent
for the funeral of an ex-HRH.
Perhaps we shall plan
for any contingency.
Yes, I propose a meeting
at 10 o'clock tomorrow morning
at Buckingham Palace...
officials from all three Palaces,
representatives from the
Spencer family,
the emergency services...
would you send some of your people?
Absolutely, of course.
Precedent!?
Where do they find these people?
Prime Minister...
I'm so sorry, Sir.
If there's anything I...
Or my government, can do...
They stood up, as we drove past,
in cafes, in restaurants...
removed their hats,
this was Paris, one of the
busiest cities in the world...
and you could hear a pin drop.
I imagine it will be the same here.
The Palace would still prefer
to see this as a private funeral.
What are your feelings on that?
I...
I think that will...
present us...
with difficulties.
So do I...
My mother,
The Queen...
comes from a generation
of best equipped...
she grew up in the war...
I think...
what we need... what
this country needs...
is a more modern perspective,
if you follow...
Balmoral is...
I think I understand...
An aircraft of the Queen's flight...
brought The Princess'
body home this evening...
where the Prime
Minister, Tony Blair,
had gathered with members
of his government.
A single black hearse crossed the tarmac...
and a Royal Air Force guard
of honour, moved slowly forward.
Has anyone heard from
the Spencer's yet?
Have they made up their minds
when the funeral will be?
Well I don't know.
Nobody tells me anything.
President Clinton was with his wife,
when he heard the news last night.
We liked her very much...
we admired her work for children...
for people with AIDS,
for the cause of ending
the scour of land mines...
On our walk today one of the
ghillies said he'd seen a large stag
up Craggie Head...
He reckoned, 14 pointer.
We haven't had one as big as
that on the estate, for years...
No,
quite...
Anyway...
I thought it might be
a good distraction...
for the boys.
What... stalking?
You don't think that's
a bit soon, do you?
I think anything that gets
them outside, is a good idea.
...she became an
increasingly unhappy figure.
The couple divorced
in August of last year.
It was the love story that
brought crowds into the streets...
they came to see The Queen,
of course, and The Prince...
but most of all,
they came to see Diana.
I'm going to bed.
I'll ring the Lord
Chamberlain's office.
Say we are going to
send representatives
for the meeting tomorrow
morning, 10 o'clock.
Thank you, Stephen.
She gave us so much.
Why couldn't we have
given her a little something...
and left her alone?
It just hurts me so much.
I've never experienced
anything like this. I can't...
I keep waiting to
wake up, like it's a bad dream.
Right, it's 10 o'clock.
Let's get started, shall we?
And thank you all for coming,
at such short notice.
I think we all agree that this is
an extraordinarily sensitive occasion...
which presents us
with tremendous challenges.
Modestically,
constitutionally...
practically,
diplomatically
and procedurally.
Christ...
After 18 years of opposition...
I am proud to stand before you,
as the new Prime Minister
of our country...
Labour, Prime Minister.
I want to set an ambitious
course to modernise this country...
to breed new life
in to old institutions.
To make privileged something for
the many... not the few...
Flippin' heck...
You think the royals are nutters?
You should meet their flunkies...
Two and a half hours of
whether she should be carried
in a hearse or a gun carriage.
Anyway, you got raves in the press.
This lot calls you the
nation's mourner-in-chief
This lot says
you're the only person who's
correctly judged,
the mood of the country.
Even The Mail is impressed.
The people's Princess, mate...
you owe me.
Gordon for you...
Tell him to hang on.
Alastair...
So they've come to their senses?
Is it going to be a public funeral?
Yeah, Saturday...
It's a whopper!
-The Abbey, the works...
-Great.
Has anyone told the queen yet?
I don't know. No doubt
some flunkey will be dispatched.
Grovelling on all fours.
Do you think it's wise for
the boys to go stalking so soon?
Anything that gets them into
the fresh air, is a good thing.
Maybe they shouldn't take their guns?
I mean, if a photographer
were to see them, it might send
out the wrong signal?
If there is
a photographer out there...
he could be
the first kill of the day.
I see Mr. Fayed was buried last night...
At midnight.
No cameras, no fuss.
Very dignified.
Why do they do that?
Why do they bury their bodies
so soon after their death?
Islamic tradition...
something to do with the heat.
It stops the body decomposing
Yes, come in!
Good morning, Ma'am...
-Ma'am.
-Yes, Robin... what can we do for you?
Ma'am.
There was a meeting at the
Palace, this morning...
About the funeral arrangements, yes...
The Lord Chamberlain faxed over
these plans for you to consider.
There is now
general agreement, Ma'am...
that a public funeral,
would be more appropriate.
I see...
And what form will this funeral take?
At the moment they're suggesting...
and of course, these are early days...
basing it on Taye Bridge.
-Taye Bridge?
-What?
But Taye Bridge is
to go down for my funeral.
Indeed, Ma'am.
But it would be
for practical reasons only...
it's the only one which
has been... rehearsed.
The only one that could be
put together, in time...
But I supervised
those plans myself...
Indeed...
And the Lord Chamberlain
was at pains to stress
that the spirit of the occasion
will be quite different,
for example...
the suggestion is that
instead of 400 soldiers...
400 representatives of the Princess'
various charities march behind...
the coffin.
And instead of
foreign heads of state...
and crown heads of Europe...
the guests would include...
a sprinkling of actors
of stage and screen...
fashion designers...
and other... celebrities.
Celebrities?
Was there anything else?
No, Ma'am.
Oh, yes, one other thing...
the police commissioner was
keen that you consider...
the idea of a condolence book.
It would give the growing crowds
something to do...
make marshalling them easier.
Oh, yes, yes of course...
Oh, and the flowers...
What flowers?
The flowers outside
Buckingham Palace... At the moment
they're blocking the path
through the Main Gate...
And will make things difficult
for the changing of the guards.
Oh, fine.
Just move them away.
Actually, the
Lord Chamberlain was
wondering whether we
shouldn't leave the flowers...
and send the guards
through the North Gate
Oh, yes, yes of course.
Yes, that's quite right.
Stephen Lamport on one.
-Who?
-The Prince of Wales' private secretary.
-Balmoral.
-He says it's urgent.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Prime Minister.
The Prince of Wales has asked me
to thank you again
for your kind words yesterday.
Not at all.
The Prince feels that...
you and he...
are both modern men,
of similar mind...
who could work well together,
at this difficult time.
Ah, well...
please thank His Highness
and assure him
he can count on my full support.
At all times.
Was that it?
Yes...
Goodbye.
Bizzare.
-Why is Charles doing this?
-What?
Creeping up to me like this.
Banging on about being modern.
He did it at the airport, when he
asked me to deal with his mother.
Because he knows that if the Queen
continuous to get it wrong over Diana...
then the royals become
public enemy number one.
And he's terrified of
being shot, apparently.
Who, Charles?
His people have already been on
to us... to ask for extra protection.
He probably thinks that if
he seems to be on our side...
then that would leave
The Queen in the firing line.
What... so it's okay for his mother
to take the bullet, and not him...
What a family!
-Wait, where are they?
-They're up at Craggie Head.
I'll come with you.
Do you want me to drive?
No, certainly not.
I thought you were going
to get a new one of these?
What for... it's perfectly alright.
I was thinking last night what Diana
might have done...
had it been me
that died in the tunnel in Paris.
She would certainly
have taken the boys to Paris.
I rather regret
not doing that now.
What, and expose them to the media?
That would have
been a dreadful thing to do.
No, they're much better of here...
it's private, they're protected.
Whatever else you may have thought
of Diana, she was a wonderful mother.
She adored those boys,
and never let them forget it.
Always warm, and physical...
never afraid to show her feelings...
Especially whenever
a photographer was in sight.
She may have encouraged all that,
but still...
that was always the
extraordinary thing about her...
her weaknesses,
and transgressions...
only made the public love her more.
And ours only make them hate us.
Why is that?
Why do they hate us so much?
-Not us, dear...
-What?
Yesterday, when we
brought the coffin back...
there was a noise, a bang,
I don't mind telling you...
I thought it was a gun.
I thought someone
had taken a shot at me.
I think I'm going to walk back.
I don't feel like stalking.
-Oh, are you sure?
-I'll take the dogs.
Walkies? Yes...
Come on...
Do you think...
you'll ever be Queen?
No I don't, no.
Why do you think that?
I like to be a Queen of people's
hearts, in people's hearts.
But I don't see myself as
being Queen of this country.
I don't think many people
would want me to be Queen...
Actually, when
I say many people, I mean
the establishment
that I married into.
Because they've decided...
that I'm a non-starter.
Charles and I
had a talk in the car today.
He was good enough to share with me,
his thoughts on motherhood.
What did he say?
How wonderful Diana was...
That's changing his tune.
...and natural.
They see me as
a threat of some kind.
Oh, for Gods sake!
Maybe he's got a point...
Maybe we are partly to blame...
Oh, I can't watch this.
No, no wait...
please, no... leave it!
We encouraged the match.
We signed of on it, both of us.
You were very
enthusiastic, remember?
She was a nice girl.
Then...
And I was sure he'd give
the other one up...
or at least make sure
his wife toed the line.
Isn't that what everyone does?
Is it?
Well, there were three of us,
in this marriage...
so it was a bit crowded.
I can't bear it any more...
If you're watching,
I'll sleep next door.
Early start tomorrow.
Any luck with your stag?
No, but close... A couple of
hundred yards at one point.
One of the boys
even got a shot off.
We'll get him tomorrow.
See you in the morning.
Not to worry.
Night night.
Charles continued to love a woman
he'd fallen for years before...
The good news is that the
Palace has agreed to video screens
in the Royal Parks...
-And the bad news?
-Crash barriers...
-What about them?
-Well they're now predicting...
more than two million people
in the centre of London.
There aren't enough barriers
to line the route.
So we've gone tapping into
the French for theirs.
And there's something else
I think you should see...
-Can we run that piece again?
-Of course.
You're gonna love this...
I don't like their behaviour...
very disgraceful.
What do you think madam?
I think it's disgusting, that they
have not appeared or said a word...
relating to all this.
-Look, I know all this.
-Wait for it...
Not to have a flag up, I think it's
a disgrace on the whole royal family.
OK, The Queen's not
in residence today...
but where the hell is the flag?
You see what I'm saying
about the establishment?
Don't tell me there isn't a flag flying
at half mast over Buckingham Palace...
To people she was their king and
queen, when them two were together
it was a fairytale come true...
Will someone please save
these people from themselves.
Fine, I'll call Balmoral.
Because as Prime Minister, I really
got nothing better to do.
Come on dogs, come on...
-Is the fire lights alright?
-A bit damp.
Well I brought some stew...
just in case.
I think it's lamb... we could
always have that cold.
No, we'll be alright.
Stay.
Robin had a call from
the Prime Minister,
who expressed his concern...
About what?
About the flag
above Buckingham Palace.
He thinks it should
be flying at half mast.
I hope Robin told him there
isn't a flag above Buckingham Palace.
There's the Royal Standard,
which flies for one reason only...
to denote the presence
of the monarch.
Since you're here,
the flag pole is bare,
which is as it should be.
Isn't it possible, that for some people...
the Royal Standard,
is just a flag...
And that the flag pole being bare,
sends out the wrong signal...
No, that's not the point.
The point is, it's
more than 400 years old.
It hasn't been
lowered for anyone.
Your grandfather didn't get the
flag at half mast, when he died.
If you're mother died tomorrow,
she wouldn't either.
Yes, granny. But sometimes, in a
situation like this, one has to be flexible.
It is just a flag.
What about the Union Jack?
Was Mr. Blair's next suggestion...
-For heavens sake?
-The next thing he'll be suggesting...
you change your name
to Hilda and mine to Hector.
Who does he think he's
talking to?
You're the Sovereign, the
Head of State...
you don't get dictated to.
You've conceded the idea
of a public funeral...
you've opened up the parks,
that's enough.
Shh... the boys...
You wait... In 48 hours,
this will all have calmed down.
Where once it seemed comforting...
for the first time
my parents can see...
what it's been like for me
all these years...
being up against her popularity.
But they're still making the mistake
of thinking that the Diana they knew...
from living and dealing with her...
will eventually be the one
seen by the public... but it won't!
The two Dianas,
the public's and ours, bear no
relation to one another, at all...
I've been thinking,
the flag of St. George's is
at half mast over High Grove?
Yes, sir.
Well, make sure we get a picture
of that in the papers, will you?
I'll get on to the tabloids,
call in a few favours.
What about a statement
of gratitude, to the crowds?
Something heartfelt,
from myself and the boys...
thanking people for all the flowers...
and so on.
Right.
Di was wonderful, because she
stood up to the establishment...
we have no-one doing that now...
she said you're detached,
elitist people...
we are paying million of
pounds to be better than us...
and you gotta get out
there amongst the people...
we have a wonderful new
Prime Minister in England, Tony Blair...
a compassionate young man,
who after 18 years...
of establishment toil and row...
is such a breath of fresh air,
and I feel he will...
do something about this
in England...
Do you think this will
be the first stirrings of...
Of what?
I don't know...
something more interesting...
Maybe this time people will finally have
seen them for what they actually are.
Which is?
A bunch of free loading...
emotionally retarded...
nutters!
-That's just absurd.
-Why?
They have a ludicrous cocoon
of privilege and wealth...
-and they don't pay tax.
-Yes they do.
Not on all their income.
The Queen alone costs us,
what... 30... 40 million a year?
Look... If you wanna have
a serious conversation...
-I do...
-About the constitution.
-We don't have one.
-About ways in which we as a government...
could phase out hereditary
privileges, then fine...
If you're gonna leave
will you take the plates?
But, you know, spare me the
whole off with their heads thing.
Why?
Because it insults your intelligence.
The Queen can not
be expected to change...
It's unimaginable this
country being a republic.
-Certainly in her lifetime.
-Why?
Because no-one would wear it...
No-one wants it.
It's just...
daft.
It's not a mother thing, is it?
What?
Well, if she were alive now...
your mother would
be exactly the same age.
I mean... you always say
how stoical she was...
old-fashioned, uncomplained...
lived through the war...
Oh, come on...
who does that sound like?
I'm gonna go do the washing-up.
That's the stalking party off...
Right...
I'd better have
a look at those papers.
'Show us there's a heart, in the
house of Windsor', says The Sun.
'It's proof the royals are
not like us', The Mirror.
'Time to change the old guard
at Buckingham Palace', Express.
'One can't help wondering
who's advise they're taking...
for it's clearly
the wrong advise'...
I'll try not to take that personally.
People have been yearning
for a change in this country...
good... the result is a quiet
revolution now taking place...
lead by the real modernisers...
the British people.
Revolution?
Who wrote this?
Where does this come from?
Where does it come from?
You just won a
huge landslide majority.
People wanna see a change.
Why, what did you
think it meant?
Hurry up dear,
your tea is getting cold.
Is that it?
Yes Ma'am, just the
letter of condolence...
to the widow of
the Ambassador to Brazil.
Good, thank you.
Tea!
Mr. Janvrin...
The Prime Minister wishes
to speak to Her Majesty.
Ma'am...
Apparently the Prime Minister
is on the phone, for you...
Tell him to call back.
No, no. It's alright.
I'll take it.
Prime Minister...
Good morning, Your Majesty...
sorry to disturb...
but I was just wondering whether
you'd seen any of today's papers?
We've managed to
look at one or two...
In which case my...
next question would be...
whether you felt...
some kind of response,
might be necessary?
No...
I believe a few, over
eager editors...
are doing their best
to sell newspapers...
and it would be a mistake
to dance to their tune...
Under normal circumstances
I would agree.
But...
well, my advise is...
I've been taking the temperature
among people on the streets...
And... well, the
information I'm getting...
is that the mood...
is quite delicate...
So, what would you suggest,
Prime Minister?
Some kind of a statement?
No, Ma'am.
I believe that the
moment for statements,
has passed...
I would suggest flying the flag
at half mast above Buckingham Palace...
and...
coming down to London,
at the earliest opportunity.
It would be a
great comfort to your people...
and would help them
with their grief.
Their...
grief?
If you imagine I am going
to drop everything, and come
down to London, before I
attend to my grandchildren...
who have just lost their mother...
Then you're mistaken!
I doubt there is anyone,
who knows
the British people
more than I do, Mr. Blair...
nor who has greater faith
in their wisdom and judgement.
And it is my belief they will
any moment reject this...
this mood...
which is being tired up
by the press.
In favour of a period of
restrained grief...
and sober private mourning.
That's the way we do
things in this country...
quietly...
with dignity.
That's what the rest of
the world has always admired us for.
If that's your decision, Ma'am...
then of course,
the government will support it...
Let's keep in touch.
Yes.
Let's.
Bloody fool...
and now your tea's gone cold.
Tony...
Robin Janvrin on one.
He was listening in...
Robin.
I understand how
difficult her behaviour must
seem to you.
How unhelpful...
but try to see it
from her perspective.
She's been brought
up to believe...
it's God's will...
she is who she is.
I think we should
leave God out of it.
It's just...
not helpful.
She just won't have seen anything
like this since the abdication...
and I can not emphasise enough
what affect that had on her.
Unexpectedly becoming King
as good as killed her father.
I'm afraid she's in
a state of shock.
This public reaction
has completely thrown her.
Alright...
but first we have to
deal with these terrible headlines.
I'll see what I can do
with the press.
I'm most grateful,
Prime Minister.
Well I can't promise anything...
it's not me they want to see.
Ask Alastair to come and see me.
Yes...
Cancel what I'm doing tonight.
Good morning.
-Your Majesty.
-Morning, Ma'am.
Thomas... where have
they gone today?
Up to Ardverikie Reach, Ma'am.
All that way...
Remind me... that's
the track up north...
That's right, Ma'am... You follow
the track for about a mile...
-and then you come to...
-The river.
-One of the lads will drive you...
-No, no. I'll manage... thank you.
Oh...
Oh! Stupid...
-Hello, Thomas...
-Hello, Ma'am...
I'm afraid I've done
something rather foolish.
I've broken the
prop shaft crossing the river.
-Are you sure, Ma'am?
-Yes, of course I'm sure.
It's the front one, not the rear.
It was a four-wheel drive.
Don't forget... I used to be a
mechanic during the war.
-And, are you alright?
-Yeah yeah, I'm perfectly alright...
-We'll come about straight away.
-Oh, would you...
Thank you very much. I'll wait by the car.
You are kind... bye.
Oh... you're a beauty...
Shoo... go on!
Go on...
go on...
Just been told
there are news crews outside...
waiting for you to
come and speak to the people...
Yes...
What's all that about?
I told The
Queen's private secretary
I'd do what I could,
to help with the press.
Why?
Don't you think she deserves it?
Sitting up there
on her 40000 acres.
Yeah, but allowing her to hang herself,
might not be in our best interest either.
Besides...
I think there's something...
ugly, about the way
everyone started to bully her...
The first thing you
obviously think about, is...
the rest of your family.
And I think...
She wanted me to pass on to
the people here, crowding around her...
How are the boys?
Not so good, tonight.
A lot of slamming doors...
I think they saw the papers.
Oh no...
I'll take them out early
again, tomorrow morning...
Let them take
it out on the stag.
What do you think of the way
the royal family have behaved?
-They've made a serious mistake.
-Pardon?
They've made a serious mistake.
Why, what do you mean?
Well, they should have came...
the family should
have come down...
to Buckingham Palace,
on Sunday afternoon...
all of them...
That girl has been left on her own.
She's on her own up there...
and the place is empty.
Oh please...
Sleeping in the streets and
pulling out their hair...
for someone they never knew...
And they think we're mad.
Have you seen the latest
funeral guest list?
No...
I suggest you keep it that way...
A chorus line of soap stars
and homosexuals...
Apparently Elton John
is going to be singing.
That would be a first
for Westminster Abbey.
Condolence books are now being
signed in our embassies
in every major city
in the world.
And in London alone,
the number has reached 40.
It reminds me of one
of those films.
A few of us in a fort...
hordes of Zulus outside.
So it's vital you hold firm.
Stick to your guns...
you wait...
they will come to
their senses soon...
They have to.
Come on!
Move over cabbage!
Good morning,
it's 6 o'clock on Thursday
the 4th of September.
I'm Penny Smith...
and I'm Matthew Lorenzo...
As the first people
start camping out...
on the route of Princess
Diana's funeral courtage...
questions are being asked
about why the Queen...
hasn't addressed her subjects...
at this time of national grief.
This is what the newspapers
are saying this morning. The Sun...
Where is our Queen?
Where is her flag?
The Express,
show us you care...
picture of a grumpy Queen.
The Mail, let the
flag fly at half mast...
and inside... the Queen should
be here to show her respect.
But the flip side is,
they're more popular now...
than Churchill's chocolate.
Did any of them pick up
on our statement of support?
Well, just the one...
Statements of support,
doesn't sell papers.
Ma'am...
the Prime Minister
for you, Ma'am.
I'm afraid he's rather insisting.
I'll take it in the kitchen.
Good morning,
I'm so sorry to disturb you.
I'm just expecting a
phone call to come through here.
Out!
Oh, there it is...
Thank you.
Good morning, Prime Minister.
Good morning, Ma'am.
You've seen today's headlines?
Yes, I have.
Then I'm sure you'll agree...
the situation has become...
Quite critical.
Ma'am?
A poll that's to be published in
tomorrow's papers...
suggests that
70 percent of people believe
that your actions
have damaged the Monarchy.
And that,
one in four,
are now in favour... of abolishing
the Monarchy all together.
As your Prime Minister...
I believe it is my
constitutional responsibility...
to advise the following...
Is Queen Elizabeth up yet?
Mummy?
One...
fly the flag at half mast
above Buckingham Palace
and all other
royal residences...
two...
leave Balmoral and fly down to London
at the earliest opportunity...
three...
pay respects, in person,
at Diana's coffin...
and four...
make a statement via
live television...
to my people and the world.
Swift prosecution of
these matters might,
he felt...
just might...
avert disaster.
You will have to talk to the
Lord Chamberlain about all this.
Well I have...
And to Robert Fellows, and it
seems they both agree with Mr. Blair.
Oh, I see...
Something's happened...
there's been a change... some...
shift in values.
When you no longer
understand your people, mummy...
maybe it is time to
hand it over to the next generation?
Oh, don't be ridiculous...
Remember the vow you took?
I declare that my whole life,
whether it be long or short...
shall be devoted to your service.
Your whole life.
That is a commitment to God...
as well as your people.
But what if my actions
are damaging the Crown?
Damaging it!?
You're the greatest asset
this institution has...
one of the greatest
it has ever had.
The problem will come
when you leave...
but you mustn't think
about that now...
Certainly not today.
Oh, mummy...
You must show your strength...
reassert your authority.
You sit on the most
powerful throne in Europe.
Head of an unbroken line that
goes back more than a thousand years.
Do you think any of your predecessors
would have dropped everything...
and gone up to London
because a bunch of hysterics...
carrying candles,
needed help with their grief?
As for that...
silly Mr. Blair...
with his Cheshire Cat grin...
Mr. Janvrin on the
phone for you, Sir...
Yes?
What?
I can't hear!
That's madness...
the whole thing!
Bloody madness!
I've just been told...
You've...
decided to follow the Prime
Minister's advise...
I just want to say, I...
admire...
I think it's the right decision.
Let's hope we haven't
left it too late.
Clearly The Queen
has had a change of heart...
she's clearly responding to
the need to feel...
that the royal family
is somehow engaged.
These are flowers that have been
brought to the gates of Balmoral...
so that she can actually see
some token, of what's been
expressed down here in London...
-Fish Fingers... do you want any?
-I'll be right there...
Thank God, for that!
Britain's Queen Elisabeth will
deliver a televised address Friday...
the royal family has been accused
of not showing enough remorse...
over Princess Diana's death...
Where are the boys?
Have they already left?
Yes...
they left for London,
after breakfast, with Charles.
It's not right, you know...
No, but further discussion
is no longer helpful, either.
Oh, well...
I suppose it does give the ghillies time
to find another stag for the boys.
-Now there's has been shot.
-What?
Haven't you heard?
He wandered over to one
of the neighbouring estates...
where one of the
commercial guests got him.
Oh... really?
Which estate?
Here's your box.
There's some policy and
stuff in here that's important.
Have you seen the papers?
No, I thought I'd give
them a miss today...
of course I've seen the papers!
Not bad, eh... Your Majesty
have come down to London...
Who says that?
Tony Blair.
Mr. Father of the nation.
Ma'am...
-Good morning, Ma'am.
-Good morning.
Is it his Lordship,
you've come to see?
No, please don't disturb him...
I've come on another matter...
I hope you don't mind?
There he is...
A beauty, isn't he?
An imperial, Ma'am.
14 pointer.
-He was wounded?
-Yes...
We got our guest in very close...
had him lined up perfect.
And still...
an investment banker, Ma'am...
from London.
I'm afraid the stalkers had to
follow him for miles, to finish him off...
Let's hope he didn't suffer too much.
Please pass my congratulations,
to your guest.
I will, Ma'am...
God bless you, Ma'am.
Thank you.
Ma'am?
Yes, Robin...
I've done a draft,
of your television address.
Thank you.
Was there anything else?
No, Ma'am.
Landing in 15 minutes.
I've got The Queen's speech.
-Shall I give Tony a copy?
-No, let me have a look at it first...
He's next door.
The Queen is getting out of the car...
and is going to talk to people.
It's extremely unusual...
this is almost unprecedented...
I think perhaps the last time
The Queen was among her people...
outside the Palace...
was the day the war in Europe ended.
They sent a copy
of The Queen's speech...
Well, let's get the frost off it first.
I've phoned them
with a couple of suggestions...
to make it sound like it
came from a human being.
Yeah, alright Alastair...
Well at least the old bat has
finally agreed to visit Diana's coffin.
When you get it wrong,
you really get it wrong...
that woman has given her
whole life in service to her people.
50 years doing the job,
she never wanted...
a job she watched kill her father...
she's executed it with honour, dignity,
and as far as I could tell...
without a single blemish,
and now we're all baying for her blood.
All because she's struggling
to lead the world in mourning
for someone who threw everything
she offered back in her face.
And who for the last few years
seemed committed 24/7
to destroying everything
she holds most dear.
Hello... would you like
me to place those for you?
No...
Oh...
These are for you.
For me?
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
There's been a last minute
addition from Downing Street.
They're suggesting adding,
'and as a grandmother'...
here.
Right.
So what I say to you now, as
your Queen, and as a grandmother...
I say from my heart.
You think you can say it?
-Do I have a choice?
-We're ready for you, Your Majesty.
Just to confirm,
this is going out live.
-Fine.
-And you'll be at the front of
the 6 o'clock news...
on all the channels.
Yes.
-Okay, nice and quiet...
-Ten seconds, everyone!
We cross now, live,
to Buckingham Palace...
for the Queen's tribute
to Princess Diana.
Since last Sundays'
dreadful news...
we have seen throughout Britain,
and around the world...
an overwhelming expression
of sadness at Diana's death.
We have all been trying,
in our different ways, to cope...
it is not easy
to express a sense of loss...
since the initial shock,
is often succeeded
by a mixture
of other feelings...
disbelief,
incomprehension, anger...
and concern for
those who remain.
We have all felt those
emotions in these last few days...
so what I say to you now,
as your Queen, and as a grandmother...
I say from my heart.
Heart...
What heart?
She doesn't mean a word of this.
That's not the point.
What she's doing is extraordinary.
That's how to survive.
Listen to you...
A week ago you were the
great moderniser...
making speeches
about the people's Princess.
Now you've gone weak at the knees.
You know... I don't know
why I'm so surprised...
At the end of the day,
all Labour Prime Ministers...
go Ga-Ga for the Queen.
What?
I, for one, believe that there are
lessons to be drawn from her life...
and from the extraordinary,
and moving, reaction to her death.
I share in your determination,
to cherish her memory.
I hope that tomorrow we
can all, wherever we are...
join in expressing our grief,
at Diana's loss...
and gratitude for her
all too short life.
May those who died,
rest in peace...
and may we,
each and everyone of us...
thank God, for someone who
made many, many people, happy.
Diana's coffin, now on the move...
the short distance
from St. James' Palace...
to her home at Kensington
Palace, for the final night...
before her burial tomorrow.
It's incredible...
less than a week.
Who could have imagined,
such scenes?
Diana was the very essence
of compassion, of duty...
of style, of beauty.
A very British girl...
who transcended nationality.
Someone with
a natural nobility...
who was classless, and who
proved in the last year...
that she needed no royal title
to continue to generate...
a particular brand of magic.
I would like to end by,
thanking God...
for the small mercies he's
shown us at this dreadful time...
for taking Diana at
her most beautiful and radiant.
And when she had joy,
in her private life.
Above all, we give thanks
for the life of a woman...
I'm so proud
to be able to call my sister.
The unique, the complexed...
the extraordinary,
and irreplaceable, Diana.
Who's beauty, both internal
and external...
will never be extinguished
from our minds.
-So, off to see your girlfriend?
-Now, now.
You know, I hope she
shows you some respect this time.
It's quite a debt of gratitude,
she owes you.
Mr. Saviour of the Monarchy.
I doubt she'll see it that way...
-Robin... good to see you.
-Prime Minister.
Tony, please.
The Prime Minister,
Your Majesty.
Do sit down.
Thank you.
It's good to see you again.
After what's been...
quite a summer.
I'm referring to your visit
to India... and Pakistan.
Where your comments on
ending historic disagreements...
went down very well.
On the commonwealth heads
of government meeting...
I spoke to the Prime Minister of Malawi...
and he was saying
how much he appreciated your...
tough stands on Nigeria...
I meant to tell you at the time, but...
you were being monopolised, rather...
I imagine those occasions
must be quite difficult.
24 heads of government, each
clamouring for a private audience.
Also we have another
chance to speak, since... that week.
And I wanted to offer my apologies.
Whatever for?
In case you felt manhandled, or...
managed, in any way.
No, not at all.
I don't think I shall ever understand,
what happened this summer.
Well... the circumstances
were exceptional, Ma'am...
And in the end you showed
great personal strength...
courage and humility.
You're confusing humility,
with humiliation.
That's not true.
You didn't read the cards on the
flowers outside the Palace, that Friday.
I actually think history will show,
it was a good week for you.
And an even better one
for you, Mr. Blair.
But there are 52 weeks
in the year, Ma'am...
and 2500 in the time
since you've been Queen.
And when people come
to assess your legacy...
they won't remember those few days.
Oh, really?
You don't think what affection
people once had for...
for this institution...
has been diminished?
No...
not at all.
You're more respected now,
than ever...
I gather some of your closest advisers
were less fulsome in their support.
One or two...
but as a leader, I could never
have added my voice to that chorus.
Because you saw those headlines,
and you thought...
one day that might happen to me.
And it will, Mr. Blair.
Quite suddenly, and without warning.
So... shall we get on
with the business in hand?
Oh, look...
I do love this time of day.
Shall we walk, while there is still light?
You know the clocks go back
next week, it will be dark before five.
-I do hope you're a walker?
-I am...
Good... I always think these meetings
have a far greater chance of success...
if the Prime Minister is a walker.
As a matter of fact, that's
how I think best... on my feet...
I've never been one
for sitting around endlessly...
a good walk and fresh air
sorts everything out.
One in four... you said...
wanted to get rid of me.
For about half an hour.
But then...
you came down to London,
and all that went away.
I've never been hated
like that before.
Then, that
must have been difficult...
Yes...
very.
Nowadays people want glamour,
and tears, the grand performance.
I'm not very good at that,
I never have been...
I prefer to keep
my feelings to myself.
And foolishly I believed that was
what people wanted from their Queen...
not to make a fuss, nor wear one's
heart on one's sleeve...
duty first, self second.
That's how I was brought up...
that's all I've ever known.
You were so young
when you became Queen.
Yes...
Yes, a girl.
But I can see
that the world has changed...
and one must...
modernise.
Well, perhaps that's where I can help.
Don't get ahead of yourself,
Prime Minister, and remember...
I am the one
supposed to be advising you.
Come, dogs!
Tell me, Mr. Blair, what might we expect
from our first parliament?
Er... well, ma'am,
top of the list is education.
We want to reduce classroom sizes.
Yes.
And create a lower teacher-pupil ratio.