Any sign of the police?
No, no sign.
Looks like we're
getting away with it.
Oh, good.
How far is it to
your father's boat?
Two hours, with luck.
Your luck seems to be
very good, touching wood.
Could you tell me now
what happened?
I'd really like to know.
Only if you feel like it.
It's Charlotte Inwood.
She's in a jam.
That doesn't surprise me.
No, this is serious,
Eve, it's deadly serious.
She was all over the place.
I had to help her.
Anybody would have done.
I was in my kitchen.
It was about 5:00.
The doorbell rang. I went
downstairs to see who it was.
Jonnie, you love me.
Say that you love me.
You do love me, don't you?
I think he's dead.
I'm sure he's dead.
I didn't mean it.
Who's dead?
My husband.
We had a terrible
quarrel... About you.
Oh, he was vile.
You know the sort
of things he can say.
He started to hit me.
I grabbed something.
I was out of my mind with fear.
Oh, what am I to do?
Darling, pull yourself together.
He may not be...
The curtains, Jonnie.
Draw the curtains.
I thought I had some Brandy.
Here. Drink this.
He was an abominable man.
Why do women marry
abominable men?
Where was all this?
My bedroom.
Anyone else in the house?
I left the servants
in the country.
I drove up early
to have an hour's rest
before the performance.
Oh, what shall I do?
I can't go on.
I can't.
Has anyone seen you?
No.
I don't think so.
There wasn't a soul
in the street.
I jumped into my car
and came here.
It's parked around the corner.
Oh, Jonnie, what
will they do to me?
Don't tremble like that.
We'll find a way.
We'll see you
all right, darling.
But you must call the theater.
I can't play tonight.
Tell them I'm ill. Heavens,
it'll be true enough.
You must go on tonight.
You've got to.
As if nothing had happened...
Nothing has happened.
You drove straight to the
theater, do you understand?
Straight to the theater.
You haven't been home at all.
Now get that into your head.
But my dress...
There's blood on it.
I must go back and change.
No, you can't do that.
I could go myself.
Oh, darling, could you?
There's no one there.
I'd give you the key.
There's a blue dress like this
in the big cupboard next to
my window in the bedroom.
Here's the key.
Are you sure the
servants aren't back yet?
No, but you must hurry.
Please, Jonnie, please.
This is my only chance.
You will, won't you?
It's a risk. Let me
think a minute. I mean...
You know I want
to help you, but...
Go or don't go.
It's all the same.
I thought you loved me.
It doesn't matter now.
Oh, my dear.
My darling.
I'd do anything for you.
You know that.
I'll be as quick as I can.
It was your maid...
Nellie.
Oh, yes. She was
going to the house
to pick up some shoes
I need for the show.
Did she recognize you?
I don't know.
You ought to get to the theater.
The police are bound to go
there to tell you the bad news.
Give me my belt,
darling, will you?
Oh, Jonnie, what
have I done to you?
If Nellie recognized you,
it won't be safe here.
You ought to go away
for a while.
I don't think that
will do much good.
But they'll come here.
You must go at once.
Oh, my dearest darling,
you have saved me.
We must think of you now.
You've got to hide.
I don't care what happens to me.
Your job is to try
to forget everything.
Let me do the worrying.
I'll find a way.
Then we'll start again,
won't we, you and I?
No more stealth
and cheating and lying.
I must hurry, darling.
But I worry about you.
Well, you mustn't.
You're an actress.
You're playing a part.
No nerves when you're on.
I'll try.
My dress!
I'll get rid of that.
Don't worry.
Don't come down.
We shouldn't be seen together.
Au revoir, my darling.
Au revoir.
And for heaven's sake,
don't worry.
Yes?
May I speak
to miss Eve Gill, please?
Oh, dear, no.
I'm afraid she isn't in.
She said she was
visiting her father,
but I thought she'd be back.
Yes. That's quite right.
She got back last night.
She's had rehearsals
all day today
at the royal academy
of dramatic art...
You know, the R.A.D.A.
Do you know where she is now?
Didn't you hear?
She's at the R.A.D.A.
Rehearsing.
Jonathan Cooper?
Yes.
We're police officers.
May we see you for
a few minutes, please?
Most certainly.
Please come in.
I can't possibly
accede to your request.
I've come to this decision
after giving the matter
my earnest consideration.
Stop me if ever there was
such an ungrateful child!
No, no, darling. Don't run
your words into one another.
...most shamefully.
Is it not in your memory
that we, too, years ago
suffered the follies
and fevers of youth?
If our blood runs cooler
and more temperate,
let us not account it
to ourselves for virtue,
but place it to the credit
of the soothing balm
of the passage of years
that we have fortifications
against the distempers
of juvenility.
You were won't to be
kinder than this.
No, papa, you are cruel.
If all parents
were of your mind,
marriage would be
an impossibility.
And then what would become
of the human race?
Go away. What are
you doing here?
The police are after
me. Do you see them?
You have not,
I hope, forgotten...
They think I killed a man.
Can you hide me on
your father's boat?
Are you so heartless...
They've just gone.
I was under the impression
that this was a class
of intelligent students
trying to master an extremely
difficult and beautiful art.
I haven't the pleasure
of knowing you, young man,
but I shall certainly report
your behavior to sir Kenneth.
Now we will begin rehearsal
again, with the other cast.
This cast seems to think
acting is just fun and games.
I'm terribly sorry.
Oh, Jonathan.
Let's get out of here.
Have you got your car here?
It's parked in front.
I'll show you
to the back entrance
and pick you up there.
Eve, do you hate me
now that you know
about Charlotte and me?
Well, I could never
hate you, Jonathan,
because we're...
We're such old friends,
and... Well, just because.
But I do wish I'd taken lessons
on the second fiddle.
Good old Eve.
Bring him in here.
It's warmer.
Do you think
I behaved like a fool?
On the whole, I think so.
I think your boyfriend
has behaved like a fool.
I have a strong premonition
that I'm going to
behave like a fool.
It's infectious.
Do you mean you're
going to help him?
Well, why not?
He's a friend of
yours, isn't he?
Oh, yes.
I see. More than a friend, eh?
When I'm with him,
I get a feeling in here
that... that's sort of...
Yes, yes, yes. Well, we'll
go into the symptoms later.
Meanwhile, I take it
you're rather keen on him
or still hungry.
I'm in love with him.
You've roped him,
but he's not yet
broken to harness.
Is that it?
I wish Charlotte Inwood was in...
Oh, do you?
I've seen her on the stage.
She'd have made me laugh,
if I hadn't been
strictly on my guard.
She couldn't make me
laugh, off or on the stage.
I can't bear to sit by
and see what she's
doing to Jonathan.
She's like an evil spirit.
Just look at him!
Ruined, and by a woman, hmm?
Now you want me to take
the ruins for a little cruise.
Well, is that it?
Well, I thought
you could take him
across the channel
or to the Irish coast.
Then he could hide out a bit.
Well, the journey
sounds attractive,
but less attractive to help
a suspected murderer to escape,
particularly with my reputation.
There's nothing the
matter with your reputation.
No, indeed. I rather flattered
myself that there was.
As a matter of fact, the customs
people have their eye on me.
I'm suspected
of being a smuggler.
Well, you're not.
Oh, yes, I am.
One cask of Brandy?
That doesn't mean
you're a smuggler.
Two casks.
That was 15 years ago.
Ah, but I've done one or two
other things since
that I didn't tell
you or your mother about.
It can't have been very much.
Oh, of course not,
not very much.
Nothing could appear very much
to a murderer's moll, hmm?
But I never hope
to be appreciated.
Yes, your mother
cured me of that.
That's why I never could be
bothered with your mother.
I appreciate you, father.
You and captain Kidd
are my favorite heroes.
My child, I am not deceived,
and if there's one thing
I cannot bear,
it's insincerity.
Oh, but you've got to help him.
You will help him, won't you?
He's lonely. He hasn't
got any friends but me
and maybe you.
You will help him, won't you?
He hasn't got me...
Yet.
You're just dying
to get into a part of this,
and you know you are.
A part in this
melodramatic play, you mean?
That's the way
you're treating it, Eve...
As though it were a play
you were acting in
at the academy.
Everything seems
a fine acting role
when you're stage-struck,
doesn't it, my dear?
Here you have a plot,
an interesting cast,
even a costume,
little the worse for wear.
Unfortunately, Eve,
in this real and earnest life,
we must face the situation
and all its bearings. Yes.
What do you mean?
Well, miss Charlotte Inwood
appears to be
an expert in garden paths.
I think she's led
your young friend
up the garden path.
I think we should hesitate
before we follow him.
But why?
Well, I don't know
how this bloodstain
got onto this dress,
but I do know that somebody
smeared it on deliberately.
But why should they do that?
Well, miss Inwood
is an actress, a very good one.
She has an eye for
an emotional situation.
Supposing she wanted our
somnolent young friend
to go to her house
and be spotted there.
This sanguinary garment
would provide
a very plausible reason,
a very plausible reason indeed.
So that's why she didn't
change her dress
before she went to his rooms.
I cannot imagine miss Inwood
going to see her young man...
Or your young man,
whosever young man he is...
In this nasty, messy condition.
No. This dress
is a clue, my dear,
a very important clue.
And though it grieves
me, of all people,
to have to say it, Eve,
I think we should
go to the police.
Jonathan. Jonathan!
Jonathan, wake up.
Jonathan, how far do you think
you could trust Charlotte?
Why, I'd trust her with my life.
What do you mean?
This bloodstain didn't happen by
accident. It was put here deliberately.
Don't be ridiculous. You're
trying to turn me against Charlotte,
but you can't. What's
this doing here, anyhow?
It should have been
destroyed hours ago!
You fool!
There goes evidence
that could have helped you.
You're not to say things
against Charlotte.
I'm doing all this for her sake.
You're just jealous of her!
Young man, I'd remind you
you're my daughter's guest.
I'd like better manners
from you.
Oh, I am sorry, Eve.
Please forgive me.
I lost my head for a moment.
I can hardly think.
I'm almost dead
for want of sleep.
I wonder... would it be
too much trouble
if I went to bed?
That is, if commodore Gill
wants to let me stay.
Your room is at the head
of the stairs.
You'll be quite comfortable.
If you want anything
to read in bed,
you'll find some quite good
murder mysteries in there.
I beg your pardon.
Look, Eve...
But he...
At last we are alone
and unobserved.
You know, I'm beginning
to enjoy this.
Father, do you think
she arranged
to put the suspicion
on Jonathan?
Do you think she
deliberately framed him?
The thought had crossed my mind.
That was why
I reluctantly suggested
that our friends the police
ought to be told about it.
But it's too late now.
Our only piece of evidence
has gone up the chimney.
But we must help Jonathan.
He'll do nothing for himself.
He's hopelessly in love
with that woman.
It's up to us.
Yes, but it...
It won't be easy.
It is easy. I'll go to
her and see her myself.
Would that be wise?
I don't care whether
it's wise or not.
I'll tell her we know
about the dress
and how the bloodstain got there
and we know every move
of her game.
I'll make her talk. It'll be
one woman to another.
An impressive situation
at any time.
She'll give herself away.
She won't be able to
help it. You'll see.
I won't see.
I won't be there,
and neither will you.
If we're right in what we think,
she's a desperate woman,
a dangerous woman.
She won't give herself away.
You'd be giving her
another alternative.
She has no alternative.
She might murder you.
Oh, don't be so
melodramatic, father.
Look, my love.
Face facts.
What is the least
that can happen to you
if you tackle
this remarkable lady?
She'll at once pick up
a little pink telephone
and call the police.
She'll then give you in charge
for concealing
a fugitive from justice.
Eventually, you will be
tried at the old Bailey.
Well, if you're lucky,
you might get off with,
now, let me see...
A couple of years,
which you will spend
in Holloway prison,
meditating on the folly of
transmuting melodrama into real life.
Well...
You see, the best thing
you can do, my girl,
is to go back to your academy
and practice
your soul-shaking antics
in surroundings where
they can't do any harm.
After all, this fellow
can't possibly
mean all that to you.
But he does, father.
Move along there, please.
But I'd like to...
Move on, miss.
There's nothing to see.
Hello, father.
I'm... I'm outside
the Inwood house.
Outside? Well,
why not inside?
Oh, don't be ridiculous, father.
The police won't let
anyone near the place.
Really? How very extraordinary.
Well, look, you've
done your best now.
Come back here
and decide what to do
about the man
that came to dinner.
Oh, I feel awful.
I've been listening to the
people in the crowd talking,
and they assume
that you-know-who is guilty
and all the police
have to do is catch him.
It's terrifying.
Yes, but the police may
not think he's guilty.
After all, they work
in secret, you know.
They may have their own ideas
about a certain lady.
I wish I knew what
the police were thinking.
Well, look, why not ask them?
Well, that's easier
said than done.
Oh, just a minute, father.
Father, good-bye, now.
Eve...
I'll see you back at the
office about 2:00, sir.
May I have
a small Brandy, please?
Madam.
Pardon my intrusion,
but is there, by any chance,
any assistance I could be of?
No, thank you.
I don't know how you
pick up all the dirt.
Oh, I get around.
Right from the horse's mouth.
I most solemnly
assure you, madam,
it would be a pleasure
if there was
any assistance I could be of.
Thank you very much.
Oh... If you will
allow me to say so,
you do look depressed.
Yes... the cheering word,
the helping hand...
I'm perfectly all right.
Oh... Oh, good. Good.
Is there anything
I can do?
Look, I don't know your trouble,
but you don't look
very well to me.
A little Brandy
can't do you any harm.
Why not drink it?
My great-aunt died
over a glass of Brandy,
but it was her 15th that day.
Feeling any better?
Yes, thank you.
You left your lunch over there.
Oh, it won't feel lonely.
I'll go back to it in a minute.
Perhaps you're allergic to bars.
Look, would you feel less uneasy
if I sat with you...
Or more uneasy?
Perhaps you're allergic
to strange men, too.
No. I love strange men...
I mean, I'm very fond of them.
Oh... I'll just go
and get my lunch.
The Butler told me.
Never saw such a sight.
They say his head was
bashed in something terrible.
I heard they clocked him so hard
that his false teeth went
right across the room.
I know I'm pretty silly,
but I overheard two
people on the street today
talking about the murder.
They went into a lot of detail.
I felt so sick and giddy
I just had to come in
and have a Brandy.
My father says I tend
to overdramatize everything.
I expect he's right.
I know how you feel, though.
I hate violence, myself.
Doesn't that make it
rather difficult for you?
I mean, I think
we ought to face up
to the ugly side of life.
Now, me, for instance...
I'm an actress.
I ought to face up to
all sorts of experiences,
oughtn't I?
Oh, I don't know.
Supposing I happened
to be a librarian.
A librarian doesn't have
to encounter much violence
except an occasional
encyclopedia falling on his head.
But you're not a librarian,
are you?
No, I'm not.
How do you know?
Well, you just don't look
like a librarian.
You don't look like an actress.
Oh? I thought I did.
Well, I'm only
a beginner, really.
That is, I've only
played one part in public.
Could I have seen you?
I don't think so.
It was in the church hall.
I played the fourth deadly sin.
Were you good?
I was pretty deadly.
What was this
Jonathan Cooper after?
I heard there was
nothing stolen.
Perhaps he did it
for the fun of it.
Poor Charlotte Inwood.
Imagine coming home and finding
your husband horribly dead,
policemen and detectives
all over the house,
and the blood.
Careful. Careful.
Careful.
Remember, you're sensitive
to that sort of thing.
You'll bring on
another fainting fit.
I hear that Charlotte Inwood's
going back into the show
in a couple of days.
Must be dreadful
to sing and dance
and be gay with that
horrible picture
still burning in one's mind.
Oh, it's the old story,
"is not the actor the man
with a heart?" All over again.
I once had a cousin
who had a duodenal ulcer
and an extremely funny face
both at the same time.
Everybody laughed at him
when he was telling
his symptoms.
His name was Jim.
That must have been terrible.
Oh, I don't know.
Jim's quite a common name.
I wonder what Charlotte Inwood
is really like...
Really, I mean.
Oh, hello, Nellie.
That's Charlotte
Inwood's maid.
Hello, Nellie.
I didn't expect to
see you so soon.
How are you bearing
up, ducks, after last night?
Mrs. tippet,
what I've been through...
All those policemen.
Bothering you with
a lot of questions,
I suppose.
Questions? They've been
asking me this,
asking me that all morning long.
I didn't know whether
I was coming or going.
Gin and lemon, please,
Mrs. tippet.
Not too much lemon, dear.
O.K.
Mind you, they never
laid a finger on me,
but, oh, the questions.
Nag, nag, nag.
"How did you know
it was Mr. Cooper?
"How many times
you seen him and where?
And did he give you anything?"
Blimey, he never
gave me nothing.
"And how long you been
miss Inwood's maid?"
Oh, they was gentlemanly
and polite, all right,
but give me the bleeding
Russians any day, dear.
Yes. You got to watch your step
when you're up
against the police.
And if that wasn't enough,
when I came out of the house,
the reporters pounced on me
with their questions,
asking me the low-down.
I just jumped out of my skin
when that photographer's
flash bulb went.
Well, I mean,
fancy taking my picture.
You're quite a
celebrity, you lucky girl.
I'll have to buy
the daily mirror tomorrow.
Of course, I'm not saying a word
to the reporters... not a word.
After all,
who discovered the body?
I'll be a star witness
at that trial,
and my story ought to be
worth something,
and I've no intention
of giving it away.
Isn't she talking too much?
Too much, too loud,
too everything.
How do you feel now?
Oh, I feel a little better,
thank you.
I have to go.
I don't like
leaving you here alone.
Do you feel fit enough
to let me see you home?
I have a car.
Perhaps you'd better
let me drive it for you.
Well, that's very kind of you.
I do still feel a bit wobbly.
To be quite honest,
it isn't really kindness at all.
I mean, I'm afraid
I maneuvered it.
How clever of you.
You've got something
there, Fred.
I'll drink to that on you.
A double gin and lemon, please.
Double?
All right, Nellie, I
hope it chokes you.
You don't miss a trick, do you?
You're always on the make.
My mother's really a dear...
My father, too, of course,
but they shout at one another,
and neither one like to shout.
I can't tell you how
much I appreciate this.
You've been
extraordinarily kind,
and you know nothing
whatsoever about me.
Oh, I don't know, miss Gill.
You were born in South Africa...
The 17th of September,
wasn't it?
You were educated in America,
and now you're studying at the
royal academy of dramatic art.
Your mother and father
don't live together.
You were a very well-behaved
young lady until today,
but you're allergic to murder,
and that drove you to drink.
I hope it's only temporary.
But I don't even know your name.
I only know that you
play the piano.
I'm so sorry.
It was stupid of me.
I forgot.
My name is Smith.
Just ordinary Smith?
A detective?
I hope you don't mind.
Oh, no.
Of course not.
Oh, I'm delighted.
By the way,
I don't suppose
you and your mother
are interested in tea...
With a detective, that is.
Of course...
Especially with a detective.
Would you like to have
tea with us one day?
Oh, I'd love to.
How about this afternoon?
Well, tomorrow, then?
Yes.
Yes. That's fine.
And I could take your place.
You'd never get away with it.
What makes you think
you could be a maid?
But it would only be
for a day or two.
You'd have to be her dresser
down at the theater, too.
You couldn't do that.
That's very highly skilled work.
Well, I could
if you told me how.
It sounds phony to me...
All this trouble
just to get a newspaper story.
Well, we women
reporters have a tough job
competing with the men...
Especially on important
stories like this.
And what paper
are you on, may I ask?
Well, I can't tell you that.
If anything should go wrong
with my plan,
it would be very
embarrassing for the paper.
Oh? And what about my job?
Suppose miss Inwood found out
I was passing you off
as my cousin.
I'm not sure
she won't smell a rat.
I never been away ill for years.
But anyone could go sick,
and I could do it...
Really, I could.
I've...
I've done a bit of acting.
Character acting?
Yes.
I see. All you've got to do
is to put on some
of your old clothes
and make yourself look common
like me.
Let me explain why
it's so important
that I get the
right slant on this.
I think there's a romance
between miss Inwood and
this man named Cooper.
And where did you get this idea?
Do you know what I think?
I think you're snooping
for the police.
Oh, no!
I saw you this morning
sitting on this very
seat with a detective.
Oh, well, that was
Wilfred Smith.
He's an old friend of mine.
I didn't get a thing out of him.
Charlie.
Double gin
and lemon, please.
Not too much lemon, dear.
Same for me.
I can get five times that much
from any newspaper
when the case is over.
Why not get both?
Caught you, have I?
Hope I don't intrude
on some deep conspiracy,
and I hope
you find yourself no worse
for your
distressing experiences.
Haven't I met
your charming friend before?
I know that face.
This is my cousin Doris,
Mr. Fortesque.
Oh, yeah.
Charming. Charming.
Perhaps as dear Nellie didn't
provide me with your surname,
you'll let me call you Doris,
eh? Yeah.
Mrs. Mason,
I can't think what I've done
with my reading glasses.
Have you seen them anywhere?
Could I...
Oh, there you are.
Help me find my glasses,
Eve darling.
I can't see a thing.
I'm Doris Tinsdale.
I'm from Nellie.
Move along there, please.
I'm Doris Tinsdale.
Miss Inwood's expecting me.
Oh, yes.
You're the temporary
Nellie sent along.
Just wait over here a minute.
We'd like to see miss Inwood.
Can I have a few
words with you as well?
By all means. Will you
step this way, please?
I understand you've
been in service
for six years and five months.
Come in.
O.K., yes.
I'll come around
the box office tonight.
What did they say,
Freddie?
More cancellations.
Oh, how stupid people are.
Even if my understudy's legs
are so peculiar,
she's just as good as I am.
She knows darn well
she'd better not be.
That's not the point.
It's you they want to see.
Well, what do you want?
I'm from Nellie.
Madam's expecting me.
The new girl's here, Charlie.
No. No.
This doesn't fit me.
Here. Here. Pull it
up on this side.
The other side, too.
You know that, don't you?
Excuse me, madam.
Read it to me, dear.
"Dear madam,
"this will introduce
my cousin Doris,
who is in every way
a good girl."
Not so loud.
"I hope you'll find her
satisfactory during my illness.
Signed,
Nellie Goode."
This is very nice,
if you can call mourning nice,
but... Isn't there some way
we could let it plunge
a little in front?
I suppose not.
"Signed, Nellie Goode."
If we could only work in
a little color somewhere.
Oh, well.
"Signed, Nellie Goode."
Take off your hat, dear.
There are simply
millions of things to do,
I'm afraid.
You won't mind if
I depend on you a great deal?
Thank you, darling.
Now, get me out of these weeds.
I'm beginning to feel sad,
and I shouldn't feel sad.
It's so depressing.
See who that is.
What's your name?
Doris Tinsdale, madam.
Yes? What is it,
groves?
Divisional detective
inspector Byard
and detective inspector Smith
to see you, madam.
Good heavens!
Hear that, Freddie?
The police again.
Show them up, groves.
Very good, madam.
I thought I told you
to wait downstairs.
Hand me a negligee
from that cupboard over there,
will you, Phyllis?
Now what about this dress
for the theatrical garden party,
miss Inwood?
Black? Oh, yes, of course.
How clever of you
to remember, darling.
Hold that for me, will you?
Freddie.
Yes?
We haven't decided.
Am I going to
the theatrical garden party?
I don't feel an atom like it.
I keep thinking about
those dreadful cancellations.
I don't see why.
They're a compliment to you.
Hand me a comb and mirror
from over there, will you?
But they do cut down
the takings.
I think I could appear tonight
if you insisted.
It would be
a terrible strain
for you, wouldn't it?
Oh, ghastly.
But I can't help feel
for my poor, dear,
loyal public...
Looking towards it for weeks
and then trailing back sadly
with their tickets...
Getting their money returned.
I simply can't bear it.
It would be pretty trying...
Waves of sympathy
coming on the stage,
all the gangways
flooded with tears.
I can hardly bear
the thought myself.
No use trying to stop me.
I'm going on tonight.
Be at the theater
at 6:00 sharp, will you?
Yes, madam.
Take this away.
You go right ahead, dear...
Garden-party dress
and everything.
And why don't we
let ourselves...
Go a trifle just in front, huh?
And thank you so very much.
What do you suppose
the police wants now?
I don't know.
Must you speak to me
with your mouth full?
They've probably come
to look under your bed
for young master Cooper.
What could I tell them
about Cooper?
I know nothing about him.
Tell them just that.
Listen...
That's a good idea.
Elsie darling, come here.
Now, when the policemen
are here,
I want you to wait
in the other room and listen.
When you hear me cough,
you come in and say,
"the doctor's here."
Have you got that?
Yes, madam.
You can stand
just so much of detectives.
After all, they are only
policemen with smaller feet.
In here?
The next door, sir.
What's the matter with Nellie?
Oh, it's her stomach, sir,
if you'll excuse the expression.
The tragedy
and excitement and all
was too much for her.
Highly strung type, eh?
Oh, very, sir.
And I suppose you know,
miss Inwood,
that whatever
Cooper's motive was,
it certainly couldn't
have been robbery.
Of course, darling.
I understand that.
I suppose
he just tried
to make it look like robbery.
What's your name again?
Doris, sir.
You know, Doris,
you're not bad-looking.
Thank you, sir.
You don't treat your
face properly, that's all.
If you fixed your hair up
and used a little make-up,
you'd be quite attractive.
I suppose I shouldn't
have seen him
as often as I did,
but I didn't realize how madly
infatuated he was with me.
I just didn't realize.
You'll never know how much
I blame myself for all this.
When my husband came back
from New York last week
and I told Jonnie
I couldn't see him,
he kept on phoning me.
He wouldn't let me alone.
Oh, maybe if I had
agreed to see him,
he wouldn't have done
this dreadful thing.
When did you last
see Jonathan Cooper?
Let me think.
It must have been a week...
A week before my husband died.
Go on.
What are you waiting for?
Excuse me, madam.
The doctor's
waiting to see you.
Oh, I'm so sorry, darling,
but I will have to
see my doctor.
I'm feeling wretched.
I've been trying to
get him all morning.
You see, I'm going on tonight.
The producer
has insisted so much,
and I don't want
to see him ruined
because of me.
That's all right.
I think we've covered
most of the points.
If there's any more
I can help you with,
you will let me know, won't you?
Thank you.
We'll try not to
trouble you again.
Thank you.
You're so understanding...
And so are you.
Doris,
show the gentlemen out.
It's all right,
thank you.
We can find our own way
downstairs.
Freddie.
Mavis, go down to the kitchen
and get yourself a cup of tea.
I'll ring when I need you.
Yes. Thank you, madam.
Darling, where's Jonathan?
Where is he?
Friends may be hiding him.
He had no friends.
He only had me.
Well, I hope he hasn't made any,
and I hope he hasn't taken
them into his confidence...
For your sake, his
sake, and their sake.
What do you mean?
If the truth comes out,
it would break you.
I can't have that.
What could you do?
You know me.
You know how it is with me.
You make me afraid.
Not I. You don't know
what fear is.
I've been working on
a tough kind of key.
Oh, that would be most lovely.
But of course, you must
be fond of swimming.
But I am very fond of swimming.
Regularly, I have to go out
to find somebody to swim with.
And you don't live
in the country? Oh, dear.
Of course, we miss
the rain so much,
don't we...
All the flowers.
It's so disappointing.
I really must apologize for Eve,
Mr...
Was the name Smith?
Smith, yes.
Smith. The name
seems familiar, somehow.
I can't understand
why that girl is so late.
I mean, she's
usually so punctual.
She takes that from me.
Her father isn't
punctual at all.
I mean, he catches
trains and things,
but always at the last moment.
I'm always there at
least an hour before.
Yes.
I'm sure you are.
I have heard a lot
about you, Mrs. Gill.
Oh, have you?
Yes. Eve's very fond of me.
Have you know her
long, Mr. Smith?
I've got the name right now,
haven't I?
I've known her for about
a day and a half.
Oh. That's not very long.
Where did you meet?
As a matter of fact,
we met in the saloon bar
of a pub.
Well...
How interesting.
Thank you.
Am I intruding?
This is Mr. Smith.
Mr. Smith, this is Eve's father.
We see him now and again.
How do you do, sir?
Very well, indeed.
Thank you.
Do sit down.
Where's Eve?
She should be here by this time.
She asked Mr. Smith to tea.
Oh, good, good, good.
Anyone else coming?
I mean, is there
going to be a party?
I am passionately fond
of parties.
No. There's no one else coming,
and you weren't invited.
Wasn't I?
Oh, an oversight.
Ah, but I forgive you.
Forgiveness, Mr. Smith...
The secret of
a happy married life...
That and good long
stretches of the absence
that makes the heart
grow fonder.
There you are, my dear...
The last but four
of the Mohicans.
Will you forgive me,
Mr. ordinary Smith?
Yes. I've just been
set an example.
Yes, but he says his
name is just plain Smith.
He did?
I'm terribly sorry to be late,
but the rehearsal
went on and on,
and the awful part is I have
to go back almost at once.
It was very decent
of you to have come.
Father! What are you
doing here?
I've been trying
to reach you all day.
Well, I took the boat out.
We had quite a little cruise...
Jonnie and me.
Poor old Jonnie.
I hope his rheumatism is better.
Do play something, Mr. Smith.
Mr. Smith is a pianist, mother.
Well, I think that's
a delightful career.
I often wish I'd kept
up my practicing.
It's not exactly my
career, Mrs. Gill.
But you must play for us.
Make him, mother.
But I haven't even
started my tea yet.
But of course he hasn't.
Eve, you are ridiculous.
But I've got to leave
in a minute.
Please play.
Jonnie's not much
of a sailor, Eve.
He was abominably seasick.
In fact, as soon
as we got ashore,
Jonnie ran away.
Who's Jonnie?
I wish I knew.
He's about 57
different varieties.
I'd say, roughly speaking,
he was a dog of some sort
that strayed in a
couple of nights ago.
Do the police know about him?
No. I'm not worried about him.
I daresay he'll find his way
back to his old
master... or mistress.
I thought for a minute
we might have to ask
for your help, Mr. Smith.
Mr. Smith is
a detective, mother.
Mrs. Mason!
A detective...
How very unusual.
I suppose you have
many fascinating cases.
Must be
very exciting.
Not very, I'm afraid.
Embezzlement, fraud,
petty thefts...
Smuggling?
Yes. Occasionally.
Brandy mostly.
Murder, too, sometimes, father.
Mr. Smith is working
on the Inwood case.
You don't say so.
Yes. I read about
that somewhere.
How did you know?
I saw your photograph
in the paper.
What is the fellow's name...
Clippen... Clippen...
Cooper.
Did he do it, do you think?
Well, he has run away
and remained in hiding.
We are inclined
to accept the obvious
as being obvious.
Oh, it's just like
Sherlock Holmes
and his fiddle...
A stream of beautiful sound,
and then suddenly
out pops the solution.
Oh, I must run!
So must I.
I don't know
what you'll think of me.
I like people
bound up in their work.
You'll make a very good
actress, indeed.
Au revoir, my pet.
Meet me at the stage door.
Can't I drive you
back to the academy?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I do want you to get to know
father... not professionally.
But he's a wonderful character,
and they'd be hurt
if you didn't stay.
When will I see you again?
Well, I really don't...
Ring me tomorrow first thing...
Regent 1-1-1-3.
I know you think I'm
an idiot, but I'm not.
I'm doing darn well.
Yes. You're giving a good show...
A very good show, indeed.
Pity you've no audience.
But you're my audience!
I wish you'd give me a
little applause now and then.
I wonder when poor
Jonathan is going to turn up.
Turn up where?
Wherever miss Charlotte
Inwood happens to be.
But good heavens!
She'll only turn him over.
Yes, and to your nice
new friend Mr. Smith.
Who was that man?
Oh, that was my dad, madam.
I told him about
my temporary job.
He doesn't like it, what
with the murder and all,
you know, madam.
What's it got to do
with him or with you?
My dad says that man on
the run might turn up here,
might even get into
the dressing room,
might even murder me, madam.
It's the scene of the crime
the murderer returns to,
not the theater.
He might be right, my dad.
I'm surprised you're
not a bit afraid yourself.
Slippers.
This theater's the last
place he'd want to be seen in.
Now, stop acting like
a silly schoolgirl.
The only murderer here
is the orchestra leader.
Father, you've got
to keep on the lookout
and head Jonathan off.
Hmm? Right.
Certainly, my dear.
This is desperate.
Go on, go on, go on, go on.
Madam. Madam.
What?
Madam, there's a man.
I think he's gone up
to your dressing room.
What are you talking
about? What man?
I saw him. Don't go
up there. It's dangerous.
You're an imbecile.
You needn't come up.
I'll manage to change myself.
I know, Jonnie,
darling,
but what a terrible
risk you've taken.
I couldn't keep away.
You haven't told me
where you've been.
Some friends looked after me.
What friends, darling?
Oh, never mind that just now.
We've got to work
out a plan of campaign.
But everything is
going on beautifully.
We've both got to
get a cast-iron story,
and we'll both
have to stick to it.
I must change.
You shouldn't have
come here, Jonnie.
You have been
so wonderful up to now.
Don't think that I'm ungrateful.
I'm not.
Truly, I'm not.
I don't know how
I shall ever repay you.
Repay me?
You talk as though
this were just a favor,
something that a "thank
you" can take care of.
Dearest, you mustn't be foolish.
You must go away
at once, back to...
Where you were hiding.
Freddie's going to get
you out of the country
as soon as he can,
and I'll come to see you
when the run of the show's over.
But that may be months...
Maybe a year or more!
Well, you know how it is.
We were playing for capacity
before all this happened.
Now they're hanging
on to the chandeliers.
50 up tonight.
Goodness knows how
they squeeze them in.
Yes. I could only
get standing room.
Well, there you are.
We'll find a lovely place...
South America or somewhere...
And I'll come out to you
as soon as all of
this has blown over.
I'll be glad of the rest
for a week or two.
Palm trees, sunshine.
Lovely.
A week or two?
Well, you don't want me
to give up everything, do you?
Why not?
I have.
Now, Jonnie,
I thought you said
that my happiness
was all that mattered,
and you must admit that
you behaved as if it was...
Taking all the trouble
to protect my reputation,
covering up the accident,
destroying that dreadful dress
with the bloodstain on it.
I didn't destroy it.
You didn't?
Jonnie, you promised.
Don't you realize if
they find the dress...
So long as I have that dress,
I'm the one who decides
how long this show will run...
And everything else.
Do you understand?
Where the devil is miss Inwood?
The orchestra's
started her number.
My socks and
suspenders! Where is she?
Take this.
I'll change downstairs.
Sorry, darling.
A hook broke.
Just a minute, Charlie.
Jonathan Cooper's
in the theater.
The sergeant's seen him.
He says he was sure
to make for your room.
Have you seen him?
Of course not.
What a stupid idea.
I think I'd better take a look
at your dressing
room all the same.
Doris, show sergeant
Loomis where to go.
Freddie, there's something...
Miss Inwood, please.
Doris, what are you
waiting for?
Oh, I feel so queer.
It's my heart.
The doctor told me I
should the stairs easy.
You don't think
he'll try to shoot his way out,
do you, sergeant?
He might be desperate, sergeant.
Don't you think you ought to
go back and get a policeman?
She was glad
he got away, father.
How do you know?
By a look she gave
Freddie Williams.
"Look she gave Freddie Williams."
That won't get you very far.
She'd be more delighted still
if she knew there was
no bloodstained dress.
Oh, yes.
All the same, I wish
we still had that dress.
There's so very little time.
We've got to make
every minute count.
I have to phone Smith tomorrow.
Why don't I invite him
to the theatrical
garden party with me?
I have to sell programs there.
I don't quite follow
you, my dear Holmes.
In order to make him see.
Nobody suspects
our Charlotte yet,
and they've got to.
First, to see
my mother and father
and get it approved by them.
Most parents nowadays
just don't seem to care
what sort of people their
children go around with,
but I'm not like that.
I know I'm very old-fashioned,
but I've got to think of Eve.
What do you do for a living?
Uh, I... I write a bit.
Oh! What, novels and things?
I'm very fond of novels.
You know, I read a
delightful one the other day.
Now, let me see.
What was the title?
It was written by that woman.
I can't remember her name,
but she's written
a number of books.
You must have read some of them.
They're all
about charming people.
She only writes about
the nice sort, you know.
Now, this book I was
telling you, you know,
the one whose title just slipped
my memory for the moment.
Well, it's about a mother,
which is a nice idea, isn't it?
I mean, one reads so much
about the younger generation.
It does seem a brilliant
idea to have a change.
Now, this mother isn't old.
I'm sorry to turn up
so late, Eve,
but I'm stranded
in town for the night.
All the hotels are full.
My flat's uninhabitable.
I told you, it's in the
hands of the decorators.
I know it's a
frightful imposition,
but I wondered
if you could give me
a shakedown somewhere?
Well, of course we can.
Can't we, mother?
Well, it's a little awkward.
Is your father proposing
to stay here, too?
Well, Jonathan could
have my room,
and I could sleep on the settee.
Where shall we put your father?
No. I'll sleep on the settee,
and you can sleep
with your mamma.
I hate to put you
to all this trouble.
Oh, not at all,
Mr...
What is your name?
Jones. Brown. Robinson.
Robinson.
Mr. Robinson, I think
we'll make it bye-byes.
Come along.
A blanket for the commodore,
and we'll all go to bye-byes.
Robinson... I've heard
that name before.
No, it won't do.
Has Eve gone mad,
turning the house into a hotel
in the middle of the night?
Who is this man, anyway?
What is his name?
Well, perhaps we'd
better not mention it.
The fact is, he's a
fugitive from justice.
The whole police
force is on his heels,
and Eve, well, for reasons
of her own, my dear,
doesn't want him to be caught.
He's... He's wanted for murder.
Now you're going too far.
I suppose you think
I believed that
that Mr. Smith
who came here to tea
was a real detective.
And if I hadn't heard
her maid's scared voice
outside the dressing room
door, they'd have got me.
Oh, Eve, darling,
I know I should
never have trusted her.
Oh, darling, you've
been wonderful to me.
I don't deserve it,
but I need you.
I need you more than ever.
Tonight, when I found
what Charlotte was,
all of a sudden I thought
my brain would burst.
After all that I'd done for her!
Everything I did for her
was because I loved her
and she loved me...
I'm so sorry.
Why the umbrella?
Huh? It is a garden
party, isn't it?
Oh, roehampton club, please.
It couldn't be
helped, I'm afraid.
You must blame a
miss Doris Tinsdale.
Who is Doris Tinsdale?
Hmm? Oh, she's Charlotte
Inwood's temporary dresser.
We've been searching
for her all the afternoon.
One of our men at
the theater last night
let her slip through his fingers
without making a statement.
You look very lovely.
You're very sweet to say so.
What has this Doris
Tinsdale person
got to do with the case,
or shouldn't I ask, Mr. Smith?
Oh, Cooper was at
the theater last night,
and we think she saw him.
And don't call me Mr. Smith.
After all, my name is...
Wilfrid.
Not very good, is it?
It suits some people
very nicely.
I rather liked it when you
called me "ordinary" Smith.
Oh, I didn't mean to, really.
Oh, but I liked it. I
liked it very much.
Please go on calling
me that, will you?
Yes, I will.
What were we talking about?
Oh, yes.
I was going to ask you...
Why did Cooper risk
going to the theater?
He must have had
a very strong reason
for wanting to talk
to miss Inwood.
Look, let's not talk shop
on a nice day like this.
Oh, I am sorry.
Do you hate inquisitive people?
Ha ha! Of course
not. I'm one myself.
But seriously, ordinary,
do you think there's anything
between Cooper and miss Inwood?
Seriously,
extraordinary,
I shouldn't be a bit surprised.
What a curious person
she must be...
I mean, going back on the stage
so soon after everything.
The show must go on.
A smiling face,
a breaking heart...
Actors rather like it, I'm told.
But today...
Going right from the
funeral to the garden party...
I must say, I think that's
overdoing things a bit.
A strong sense
of dramatics, hmm?
All that sort of thing.
It's...
So cold and calculating of her.
Is it?
Yes, it is.
If she's that cold
and calculating,
I was wondering...
Maybe she had something to do
with her husband's death.
Were you?
After all,
there must be a lot that
doesn't appear on the surface...
I mean, like wheels
within wheels.
Who knows what goes on
in a woman's mind?
I don't know.
And if I don't know, I...
Well...
Who?
Uh, a woman's mind sometimes...
I was saying
that a woman's mind...
That's right.
Do you really?
I think so, too.
In miss Inwood's case...
What?
I have to report
to the committee tent
to get my programs.
Whether to give it
to the orphans
or to let
the government take it.
I'm putting it to you.
Oh, there's the
committee tent over there.
You do understand that
I won't be able to spend
the whole afternoon
with you, don't you?
Oh, can't I go around with you?
I can sell a mean program.
We bloodhounds have
methods of our own.
But you must go off and amuse
yourself. I can't take you with me.
Every time I'm
beginning to think I know
what color your eyes
are, you disappear.
Can't I come with you?
But it's against the rules.
Now please go away.
I'll pick you up later.
I'll get in trouble.
Step right up.
Yes, madam.
Over here.
Eve, you brute.
Wherever have you been?
You're hours late.
I'm sorry, chubby.
What a day.
Hello, Valerie.
Hello, Eve.
By the way,
this is Wilfrid Smith...
Chubby bannister
and Valerie Maynard.
They're at R.A.D.A. With me.
Well, how do you do,
Mr. Smith?
How do you do?
I'm sure you'd love
to have some ice cream,
and chubby could
show you where it is.
Oh, but I'd adore to.
That's most good of you.
I'll hope you'll remember
me by this little token
of my regard and esteem.
Allow me.
As you know, this fete
is being held
for the aid of the
actors' orphanage.
Now, it's raining outside,
and if you've got time
to spare, come in...
Which programs shall I take?
Take that pile, dear.
Thank you.
You newspaperwomen
work hard at your job,
don't you, miss Gill?
How did you know my name?
I called that number you
gave me in case of emergency.
A Mrs. Gill answered,
and I put two and two together.
Well, what did you need
me for in such a hurry?
Listen, don't you talk
to me like that.
I've come all the way
down here to tell you
miss Inwood's looking for you.
What does she want?
She wants you here, of course,
and what's more, she said
the police want to talk
to a miss Doris Tinsdale.
She wants to know when
I'm going back to my work,
and I told her my stomach
was still out of order.
Well, it's better now...
Much better, thank you.
You want more money, don't you?
Well, look at the risk
I'm running.
I think I'd better go
to miss Inwood
and tell her everything...
And before that detective
finds out
there's no such person as Doris.
Here's 5.00. It's
all I have with me.
Oh, my job's worth
more than that...
At least another 20.
I'll meet you
outside miss Inwood's tent
in half an hour.
Finished already?
You are doing well.
May I use your
phone, miss Coop-jex?
Why, yes. Of course,
my dear. There it is.
Thank you.
Hello.
Is that you, father?
Could you come right away?
With all the money you
can lay your hands on.
At least 20...
At least!
It's Nellie.
The girl I'm understudying.
Yes. Be quick, darling.
No queuing.
No queuing here.
Step right up.
Yes, madam, over here.
Doris, isn't it?
Yes, sir.
Yes, sir. I took
your advice, sir.
I done meself up!
I mean... what do you
think of it?
Where have you been?
Oh, I can explain it,
sir. Only yesterday...
Come along. I'll take
you to miss Inwood.
Come on, hurry.
Roll up, roll up, roll up.
Come and have a good time.
Come on, sir.
You, sir.
Miss Tinsdale
to see you.
Well, this is a pleasure.
Where have you been?
I thought you were dead.
Oh, no, madam.
I wasn't.
As a matter of fact...
You needn't go
into detail, darling.
I hope you're not
going to turn into
one of those explicit
people who always tell you
exactly how they feel
when you ask them.
You did leave me a
trifle suspended, however.
I'm sorry, madam.
I was held up.
Darling!
Whatever happened to
that peculiar figure of yours?
It's a new dress, madam.
Keep it, dear.
What it does for you
is worth thousands.
I bought it at a sale.
Don't confide in me. Just
pour some tea, would you?
By the way, Doris,
did Nellie tell you the
police want to talk to you?
But whatever for, madam?
Oh, I hope they won't
upset my dad.
My dad said...
They're not going to eat
you, darling. It's not important.
Just pull yourself together
and pour the tea.
Rehearsals, rehearsals,
from morning till night.
If we wanted
to misbehave ourselves,
we couldn't find
a minute to do it in.
Yes.
So I understand.
Eve tells me she
kept hard at it all day
and most of the evening.
But Eve hasn't been
near for days.
I thought she was home
with a cold or something.
Maybe she's got a job in a show.
A fortune
in five minutes
and earn no income tax on it...
Excuse me, madam.
I... I've got to sneeze!
Miss Livingstone, I presume?
That's not my name.
Oh, no, no. It's
Nellie Goode, isn't it?
But what does the name matter?
After all, I could
think of lots and lots
of much more
appropriate names for you.
I could think of a few for
you, too. Who are you?
I understand my
daughter has entered
into a somewhat shady
transaction with you.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
Well, you are a
blackmailer, aren't you?
You know, that's a very,
very naughty thing to be.
Don't you say things
like that to me.
Do you know you could be had
up for saying a thing like that?
Now, don't be so peppery.
I like to keep things
on a friendly basis.
One short!
Well, it's all I've got.
You don't want me to
walk home, do you?
I don't care if you crawl home.
It doesn't matter.
I'm not mean.
And you've got till
tomorrow morning.
Oh, father, Freddie Williams,
Charlotte's manager,
spotted me as Doris.
I had to go into
Charlotte's tent.
Well, if there's
one thing I hate,
it's saying, "I told you so."
And the police want
to talk to Doris.
I don't know which way to turn.
I think I'll get a hold of Smith
and tell him the whole story.
Have you got him
to suspect Charlotte yet?
I'm afraid not.
Hmm? But I thought you
had to pick him up at Whitehall.
Didn't you talk to him about it?
Yes, I did...
In a way.
In a way?
Oh, I see.
Some more important topic arose
in the conversation, hmm?
Well, there's one slight
complication, my dear...
Jonathan.
You're not by any chance
thinking of changing
horses in midstream?
Father, is it awful of me?
Not awful, my dear... just
rather a bad bit of timing.
No matter how my
feelings toward him change,
I still can't let
Jonathan down, can I?
Not while he's hiding
in our house.
Call yourself an actress?
There's your big scene,
if you've the pluck to take it.
You have the law on your arm.
All you have to do is to
rush in there and shout,
"stop. That woman
is a murderess."
And then she'll say,
"how dare you!"
And you'll say, "I'll
dare and dare again!
"What about the
bloodstained dress,
eh, miss Charlotte Inwood?"
And then she'll say...
Please. This is serious, father.
Oh, Eve!
There you are.
I couldn't find you anywhere.
Oh, I've been trying to
get rid of my programs.
I've been too busy
talking to Mr. Smith
to sell any of mine.
Do you think I talk too much?
No. Most women
don't talk enough.
I hate shy women.
No one could
ever call me shy.
Who'll pay half a crown
to shoot lovely ducks?
Who'll come over and
shoot some lovely ducks?
It's only half a crown.
It does such good
for the orphans.
Who'll come and shoot
lovely ducks here
for half a crown?
Only half a crown
to shoot lovely ducks!
Eve.
Excuse me.
Look, Eve, hold everything.
I have an idea.
Get Smith into Charlotte's tent
as near the front as you can.
Go on, quickly!
What do you say we go in
and hear Charlotte sing?
Oh, do let's!
The murder makes her
so interesting.
You know, I think
I'll wait outside.
But you promised.
I promised?
In the taxi.
You said the first thing we'd do
would be to go in and
hear Charlotte Inwood.
Don't you remember?
Do you know, I can't remember.
I must have had
some sort of a blackout.
Oh, do let's hurry!
We'll miss her.
Lovely ducks over here.
Only half a crown
to shoot a lovely duck.
You can win a lovely prize!
Heavenly prizes! Only
half a crown to shoot...
Would you like to shoot a duck?
No, no, no.
I hate firearms.
I wonder if I could
buy one of those dolls.
A doll?
Which doll?
Oh, any doll...
That doll.
Yes, I suppose you could,
but you'll have to pay for it.
But how much, please?
Well, it's for the orphans.
I know, but how much?
You are sorry for the
orphans, aren't you?
Of course I am, but how much?
We all are, aren't we?
Well, I suppose...
At least 4.00.
Give me the gun.
Well, half a crown, then.
You know, money first.
Now, shall I put it in for you?
It breaks somewhere here.
I can't...
It's rather... Ha ha!
Perhaps I can manage.
Wait a minute.
I think you'll have
to do it yourself.
I'm not frightfully good.
Be rather careful, won't you?
You know, it goes off.
Got you again, my beauty.
My bird, I think, sir.
Could I have the doll, please?
What did you say?
Good shot, sir.
Well done. I'll
get you your doll.
Here you are, sir.
Now, then, who's going to shoot lovely
ducks? Come and shoot lovely ducks.
Would you like
to shoot lovely ducks?
Yes. I'd like half
a crown's worth, please.
Are you sure that's enough?
Oh, yes, certainly.
I don't need any more.
I very seldom miss.
Oh, got it at last.
Could I have the doll, please?
I'm sorry, sir,
but I'm afraid that's mine.
What did you say?
Nothing at all.
Could I have the doll, please?
Well done. I'll go
and get it for you.
It is really rather nice, I think,
to have won it, don't you?
You did earn it that time.
You know, they're lovely dolls.
They're fully dressed.
Fully.
Thank you very much.
Now who's going to come and
shoot lovely ducks over here
for only half a crown?
We're having such fun over here
shooting ducks
for only half a crown!
Eve!
I'm sorry, ladies and gentlemen.
Doris. Doris!
Miss Tinsdale!
Come and give a hand here.
What are you waiting for?
I'm sorry, sir.
Do you think there's
anything between
Cooper and miss Inwood?
But Eve hasn't been
near for days.
Doris! Miss Tinsdale!
We got away as quickly
as possible, and here we are.
And that's the story
of the short and stormy life
of Doris Tinsdale.
It is in many respects
a sad one,
but, one hopes, not entirely
without usefulness.
The next thing, I suppose,
is to wait for the arrival
of Mr. ordinary Smith
with his posse
to arrest the whole
boiling lot of us.
Well, you think
I should give myself up?
Is that it? Yes,
I should, shouldn't I?
The longer I stay here,
the worse it will be for you.
But I won't give up.
There must be a way
to get at Charlotte.
I've made a nice hot toddy
for you, Mr. Robinson.
There's nothing like it
for a cold, is there?
Thank you.
Isn't it dreadful?
Poor Mr. Robinson hasn't been
able to stir out of his room
since he arrived.
These spring colds
are really frightful.
By the way, Eve,
Mr. Smith is downstairs
and wants to see you.
I think it would be
such a good idea
if I made Mr. Robinson
a nice, hot mustard plaster.
I wonder if he's got
a temperature.
Unfortunately,
I've broken my thermometer,
but you could easily
run round to the chemist's...
How long have you been
miss Inwood's maid?
Let me tell...
Because I think you know
we've been anxious to ask
Doris Tinsdale a few questions.
I can explain.
Did you talk to Jonathan Cooper
at the theater last night?
No.
Did you see him?
Yes.
Where?
On his way to miss
Inwood's dressing room.
He was there when she
went up to change.
I listened at the door
and overheard him
say something about a
bloodstained dress belonging to her.
And then suddenly,
she became afraid.
Do you hear? Afraid.
When you took sergeant
Loomis up to the dressing room,
you presumed Cooper
to be still there?
Well, I...
I didn't know.
You didn't know, but
you had a pretty fair idea.
Why didn't you tell Loomis?
Then you did
a very neat fainting fit,
which probably allowed
Cooper to get clear away.
Don't talk like that.
I can't bear it.
I don't understand it.
How could you behave like that?
But I can explain.
I don't think that's necessary.
In my job, I find a woman
goes to almost any length
to protect her lover.
But it's not like that.
It's not like that at all.
I thought I was
in love with Jonathan,
but I'm not anymore.
But it doesn't mean that
I still won't go on helping him
as I would any innocent man.
It's not for you to decide
whether he's innocent or not.
You can leave that to the law.
The point is, you put
yourself and your father
in a very serious position
by this infernal
amateur meddling.
How I'm going to get
you out of it,
I don't know.
But you do want to get us out?
In spite of the fact
you made such a fool
of me, you mean?
Your acting in the taxi
was extremely clever.
I wasn't acting in the taxi.
I fell in love with someone,
and all my plans
went out the window.
When we were
in the taxi together,
I felt as though I were
on a great golden cloud.
I told father I didn't
want to go on with this.
I wanted to tell you everything.
But he had an idea
about a bloodstained doll,
and I had to put it off.
I wanted to tell you
all about it.
Please believe me.
Would you like to mix a
cocktail yourself, Mr. Smith?
I'm afraid there's no ice,
but I'm sure you can manage.
Good evening, Smith.
Good evening.
Do I hear the muted
clanking of chains?
It's only the plumbing, dear.
It's in a dreadful state.
How did you enjoy the
garden party, Mr. Smith?
It must have been
awful in that rain.
I think I'll take some
Sherry up to Mr. Robinson.
I've quite changed
my mind about him.
He seems such a nice
young man after all.
Eve, dear, you will look
after Mr. Smith, won't you?
Father, I've been
explaining to Mr. Smith
what we're trying to do.
He thinks we ought to stop.
Oh, what a pity.
Just when you and I
were about to save
Mr. Smith so much trouble.
Save me trouble?
Look here, sir.
You don't look like
an irresponsible imbecile.
Why behave like one?
What do you mean
by letting your daughter
get mixed up in
a business like this?
What sort of father
do you think you are?
Unique. Quite unique.
But rather broken-hearted
at this moment.
You see, I have another idea.
A pity to waste ideas, isn't it?
Have you ever been
blackmailed, Mr. Smith?
Well, I have,
only this afternoon,
at least my daughter and I were,
by Nellie Goode.
Yes, most inappropriate name.
I told her so.
She touched us for 24,
and, do you know, I think
it was well-spent?
Though we could ill afford it.
Come to the point, please.
Well, it struck me
that what Nellie could do,
Doris could do.
I mean, suppose she
went to miss Inwood
and said, "look, miss Inwood,
"I've got a certain dress
of yours.
It's ruined,
but it's still worth money."
And suppose miss Inwood
said, "all right.
I'll give you 100 for it."
What then, eh?
And suppose you happened
to be listening.
Well, that's what police do
in blackmail cases, isn't it?
What about it, eh?
What about it?
You needn't be afraid
that Doris couldn't do it.
She could do it all right,
Doris could.
I mean, Eve could.
She's a very good actress,
a very good actress indeed.
I'm sure she is.
By the way,
is there a bloodstained dress?
Well, no, no.
Not exactly.
Look, there was
a bloodstained dress, only...
Couldn't we tell you
all about that after...
I'm getting back to the office.
I'll let you know
about this later.
In the meantime,
what's miss Inwood
doing without her dresser?
You better run along
to the theater
before she starts
getting impatient.
It's all right.
What do you mean...
It's all right?
He's trying to save his face.
Not a bad face, either.
He'll let us do it.
What's the matter with you?
Aren't you pleased?
Come on.
We'd better hurry.
Come to Burton street at once
and bring two men with you.
Post them at either end
of the street.
I'll be waiting at the telephone
booth at the corner. All right?
Hello. Is that Mrs. Gill?
Is the commodore available?
Oh, he's gone out.
Is miss Eve there?
Oh, she's out, too.
One moment. May I speak
to Mr. Robinson, please?
What's the idea, governor?
Just a little
experiment. Plug it in.
O.K.
The Mike's in position.
I'm speaking about
3 foot from it.
Can you hear me?
Tell him the sound's all right.
O.K.
Do you think it'll work?
What a day, darling.
I've never in my whole life
been so glad to see
the end of it.
Yes, madam.
You must be tired, too.
It can't be easy to be a dresser
when you've had no experience.
But you're quite good,
very good, indeed.
Oh, that rain, that rain
at the garden party.
Thank goodness it didn't
rain at the funeral.
That would have been too much.
I hate rainy funerals.
And then somebody sent
up that disgusting doll.
What vermin some vermin are.
Yes, madam.
By the way, did
the police find you?
I haven't seen them yet, madam.
And anyway, I've got
nothing to tell them.
Well, I suppose that's all.
And that horrible Nellie
will be back tomorrow.
We may never see
each other again.
Ships that pass in
the something or other.
I like you. You're so
very sweet and patient.
I don't suppose I'm
easy to get on with.
Oh, but you are, madam.
It's been wonderful
working with you,
and I do love the theater so.
I don't see why. It's
an awful life, really.
Here, darling. A little
something extra for you.
I couldn't, madam, honestly.
Don't be an idiot.
Put it in the bank
or go out and get
drunk or something.
Thank you, madam.
Can I give you a lift somewhere?
If you would drop me,
I'd appreciate it.
All right, come along, then.
Miss Inwood, could I
talk to you in private?
We can talk in the car.
That's private enough.
Oh, no, no, that won't do.
I've got to talk to you now.
What's all this about?
Let's go some place
where nobody can hear us.
Have you gone mad or something?
No, madam.
I want to tell you
about the bloodstained doll.
Well, what about that doll?
Oh, I hate all this, madam.
I'm that nervous.
I'm so afraid of doing
the wrong thing.
You see, I happen to have
a dress that belongs to you
with a big bloodstain
down the front.
By rights, I know I
should go to the police,
but to tell you the
truth, madam, I'm afraid.
My dad would murder me if
I got my name in the papers.
So you see, I've come to you.
I thought maybe you
could tell me what to do.
How much do you want?
The thought of money never
entered my head, madam.
I hope you won't
think that of me.
Only if the dress
were clean like new,
it might be worth,
say, 75 or 100.
I know nothing about
a bloodstained dress.
This sounds to me
remarkably like blackmail.
I think I'd better
call the police.
Yes. Do call the police,
miss Inwood.
We'll talk to them together.
You're not a maid.
No, I'm not.
Why have you been
pretending all this time?
Shall we say we needed evidence?
We? Are you from the police?
Why was the bloodstain
smeared on the dress?
Who are you?
Why were you so frightened
when Jonathan told you he
hadn't destroyed the dress?
I don't know. I don't know
what you're talking about.
You do know!
Yes. Some blood did
splash on my dress.
I was there in the room
when Jonathan killed my husband.
That's not true.
Yes, it is, but I had
nothing to do with it.
Jonathan wanted
my name kept out of it.
He sent me back to his rooms.
He stayed behind to make it
look like robbery.
Then he brought me
a clean dress.
You're lying.
It's the sacred truth.
I swear to you it is.
Listen, whoever you are,
I'll give you anything
if you keep me
out of this. Anything.
My jewelry is worth over
10,000. You can have it all.
And my furs or money.
How much do you want?
I'll give you anything.
Anything.
I'm going in now to break it up.
Bring him in.
I want the two of them together.
You deliberately tried to pin
the whole thing on Jonathan,
didn't you,
assisted by your friend
Mr. Freddie Williams.
It's not true, I tell
you. It's not true.
You won't get away with it.
I warn you, that's all.
I've had such a terrible scene
with a lunatic girl.
First she pretended
to be my dresser.
Then she pretended
to be a detective
and tried to blackmail me.
That's all right,
miss in wood. You stay here.
I'll have a word
with you in a minute.
Oh, good.
They got him.
Jonathan, what have
they done to you?
Why are you arresting him?
Mellish, stand by
miss Inwood there!
Heavens!
That must be Cooper.
Where's miss Inwood?
Cover the alleyway.
We think he used
an emergency door.
Where do those stairs lead to?
Eve! Eve, come back!
Where's the nearest telephone?
Eve!
Hurry up downstairs.
Go on. Hurry.
Get back into the theater.
Have you been told
to keep an eye on me?
In a manner of speaking, yes.
In that case, may I sit down?
No harm in that.
Get me a chair, then.
Surely, Ma'am.
Surely.
Done with the Mike?
Yes.
O.K. I wonder if they caught...
What's the point
of going up to the roof?
He may have doubled back
along the alley.
So they've heard
everything I said, hmm?
Yes.
And it's all in that book?
All in there, in shorthand.
How clever of you.
Things look bad
for me, don't they?
I'm what you'd call
an accessory,
I suppose.
George! Smith wants you
down at the stage
doorkeeper's office.
Thank you, darling.
We'll need more men
to cover all these rooms.
It's not all in there.
What's your name?
Mellish.
Do you like dogs, Mellish?
Yes, Ma'am, I do.
But not all dogs.
If they don't love you,
you don't love them.
That's right, isn't it?
I suppose so.
I had a dog once.
He hated me.
At last he bit me,
and I had him shot.
When I give all my love
and get back treachery
and hatred, it's...
It's as if my mother
had struck me in the face.
Do you understand that, Mellish?
I've heard it takes them
that way sometimes.
Yes. It takes
some of them that way.
Has miss Inwood
gone yet?
No, sir. She's still
in the theater.
I saw him run down the alley.
This is Smith, sir.
We're covering
the whole of the theater
from the roof right down
to the storeroom. Right, sir.
Look, you heard
what miss Inwood said.
You can't have anything
against young Cooper now.
Nothing, except murder.
He killed Charlotte's
husband, all right.
He's killed before.
What? What do you mean?
He got away with it last time
with a plea of self-defense.
He won't this time.
But Eve.
She's alone with him now.
Can't you see, sir?
She's in very great danger.
It all adds up
to a confession,
except she said you killed him.
Anyone in their right mind
could see that she
was telling a lie.
But I don't understand
why Smith arrested you.
What happened?
Somebody phoned and said
the police were on their way.
I made a bolt for it,
and they grabbed me
at the street door.
Funny, that... getting me
out into the street.
I suppose Smith didn't want me
to be caught in your house.
That would have been
awkward for you, wouldn't it?
I don't think they'll look
for us here for a bit.
After a little while,
maybe we can make a dash
through an emergency exit.
Eve. Eve.
Eve, wherever you are,
come away from him.
Come away from him.
He's dangerous.
He's a killer.
Eve. Eve.
He's right, you know.
Charlotte was telling the truth.
What she didn't tell you
was that she goaded me
into doing it.
She set me against him
in every way she could.
She made me think
she was crazy about me,
but she wasn't.
I was to kill her husband
to leave the coast clear
for that Freddie Williams.
I know that now.
She knew the sort of man I was.
She knows I can't control myself
if I get into a rage.
Like a fool, I told her
about that girl I'd killed.
Oh, Jonathan. Jonathan, you
don't know what you're saying.
I can't help it, Eve.
I can't control myself,
even when I was a kid.
I was lucky that last time.
The little fool
threatened me with a gun.
But you don't know
what it's like
to have a thing like
this hanging over you.
Eve, I hated to tell you
that phony story
in your car that time,
but there was no other way.
Charlotte did go on to my flat
after I'd killed her husband.
Her dress was stained a bit,
so I brought her a clean one.
Then when she went
to the theater,
I made a big stain on it
to make you believe me.
I'm telling you the truth now.
Jonathan...
I feel desperately
sorry for you.
Really, I do.
No, you don't.
You're not sorry at all.
You don't care
what happens to me.
Jonathan...
You could give yourself up.
They'd take care of you.
You couldn't do
all these things unless you...
Unless...
They can't do anything
to a sick man,
and that's what you are.
You must be.
No. They're going to hang me.
They'll hang Charlotte,
too, for planning it.
They've never forgiven me
for getting away with it
the first time.
There's nothing wrong
with my mind.
Nobody can prove
that there is, unless...
Unless I do it a third time,
with no reason whatever.
That would be a
clear case of insanity,
wouldn't it?
Wouldn't it?
Jonathan,
Jonathan, I don't
hear a sound now.
I think we can go now.
We'll go out
through the orchestra pit,
and then I'll take you
to my father's boat.
Come along.
Here he is!
Look!
In the orchestra pit!
Mathews, quick!
Down in the orchestra.
They've got to him!
Where?
They found him.
Where was he?
He was in the theater after all.
Call Smith! He was at the
stage door keeper's office.
Drop the iron curtain
and cut him off!
Get out of the way!
Take the curtain up.
Don't touch anything.
Mellish, you'd better
phone up the photographer.
Someone find out
if Byard's here yet,
and tell him what's happened.