Stall, please.
Ladies and gentlemen...
with your kind attention
and permission...
I have the honor
of presenting to you...
one of the most remarkable
men in the world.
- How remarkable?
- He's sweating.
And can you be surprised
at that, gentlemen?
Every day
he commits to memory
50 new facts...
and remembers
every one of them.
Facts from history, from
geography, from newspapers...
from scientific books,
millions and millions of them.
Think of the strain involved
by his prodigious feat.
His feet ain't half as big
as yours, cully.
I'm referring to his
feats of memory.
Test him, please.
Ladies and gentlemen,
ask him your questions...
and he will answer you,
fully and freely.
Mr. Memory.
I also add, ladies and gentlemen,
before retiring...
that Mr. Memory has left his brain
to the British Museum.
Hurray!
A question, please.
Ladies first.
Where's my old man been
since last Saturday?
- On the booze!
- In quod!
Out with his bit!
A serious question, please.
Um, what won the Derby in 1921?
Mr. Jack Jool's Humorist
with Steve Donoghue up.
Won by a length
at odds 6 to 1.
Second and third:
Craig-an-Eran and Lemonora.
- Am I right, sir?
- Right.
What won in 1936?
You come back in 1937,
and I'll tell you, sir.
How far is Winnipeg
from Montreal?
What won the Cup in 1926?
Cup? Waterloo,
football or tea, sir?
Football, silly.
When did Chelsea win it?
63 B.C. in the presence
of the emperor Nero.
- What causes pip in poultry?
- Ssh! Don't make yourself so common.
But our fowls have got it,
haven't they now?
How many races
did Mick the Miller win?
How old is Mae West?
When was Crippen hanged?
Who was the last British
heavyweight champion of the world?
- Henry VIII!
- My old woman!
Bob Fitzsimmons.
He defeated Jim Corbett...
heavyweight champion of America
at Carson City, Nevada...
in October, 1897.
He was then 34 years of age.
Am I right, sir?
How old is Mae West?
I know, sir, but I never
tell a lady's age.
Next, please.
What causes pip in poultry?
- How far is Winnipeg from Montreal?
- Miss Winnie Who, sir?
How far is Winnipeg from Montreal?
Uuh, a gentleman from Canada.
You're welcome, sir.
Winnipeg, the third city of Canada and
the capital of the province of Manitoba.
Distance from Montreal:
1,424 miles.
- Am I right, sir?
- Quite right.
How old's Mae West?
Hey, you!
Gentlemen, gentlemen!
Please, you're not at home!
Hey, you!
What causes pip in...
causes pip in po-po-po...
Hey, come on!
Hey! For God's sake, play something
man and stop this panic!
Well, here we are.
May I come home with you?
What's the idea?
Well, I'd like to.
Why, it's your funeral.
Go on then, there's a bus.
You don't stay here always?
No, I've taken a furnished flat. I'm only
over here from Canada for a few months.
By the way, am I allowed
to know your name?
Smith?
All right.
Do you want to know more about me?
What do you think I do for a living?
Actress?
Not in the way you mean.
- Chorus?
- No.
- I'm sorry.
- I'm a freelance.
- Out for adventure, eh?
- That's right. - This way.
I'm afraid you'll find my sitting room
all upset, I had the decorators in.
- Wait till I'll find the switch.
- Not yet.
Now.
Mr. Hannay.
Would you be so very kind and turn
that mirror with its face to the wall?
You'd be happier if there were
curtains over those windows.
- Yes.
- I'm sorry.
Hello, there's a telephone.
Just a minute.
Mr. Hannay, don't
answer the telephone.
Why not?
Because I think it's for me.
Please don't answer.
Just as you say, miss.
Won't you sit down?
Thanks, If you'd please kick
that footstool over to me?
You needed that.
I did.
Thank you.
I owe you an explanation.
Oh, don't bother about me.
I'm nobody.
We cannot talk here.
All right.
Just a minute.
- Okay?
- Mm-hmm.
- Cigarette?
- No, thank you.
- Our friend again.
- Take no notice.
Would you think me very troublesome
if I asked for something to eat?
- I've had nothing all day.
- Sure.
- You like haddock?
- Yes, please.
I suppose your name
isn't really Smith.
Depends on where I am.
- You may call me Annabella.
- Annabella Smith.
A clergyman's daughter, I'd say.
Hello. Nervy?
Upset by those shots tonight?
I fired those shots.
- You what?
- Yes, to create a diversion.
You see, I had to get away
from that theater quickly.
There were two men there
who wanted to kill me.
Really, you should be more careful
choosing your gentlemen friends.
- No-no-no, you don't understand.
- You don't make it easy for me, do you?
Beautiful, mysterious woman
pursued by gunmen.
Sounds like a spy story.
It's exactly what it is.
Only I prefer the
word agent better.
- "Agent"? For what country?
- Any country that pays me.
- No, what is your country?
- I have no country.
Born in a balloon, rare.
We'll let that go.
Now I suppose you've come over here
to dig up some great big state secret.
No, I am here to save a secret
from being dug up.
Very important secret
for this country.
Not because I love England, but because
it will pay me better that way.
- Thank you.
- You see, the very brilliant agent...
of a certain foreign power...
is on the point of
obtaining a secret
vital to your air defense.
I tracked two of his men
to that music hall.
Unfortunately,
they recognized me.
- That's why they're after me now.
- That was too bad.
You ever heard of a thing
called "persecution mania"?
- You don't believe me?
- Frankly, I don't.
Go and look down
onto the street then.
You win.
- Are they there?
- Yes.
I hoped I'd shaken them off.
Listen, I'm going to tell you something
which is not very healthy to know.
But now that they have
followed me here...
you are in it
as much as I am.
How do you mean?
- Have you ever heard of the 39 Steps?
- No, what's that, a pub?
Never mind.
But what you were laughing at
just now is true.
These men will stick at nothing. I'm
the only person who can stop them.
If they are not stopped, it's only
a matter of days, perhaps hours...
before the secret is
out of the country.
Why don't you phone
the police, or something?
Because they wouldn't believe me
any more than you did.
And if they did, how long do you think
it would take to get them going?
These men act quickly.
You don't know
how clever their chief is.
- Clever and ruthless.
- Who is he? What's his name?
He has a dozen names,
and he can look like
a hundred people.
But one thing he
cannot disguise...
this.
Part of his little
finger is missing.
So, If ever you should meet a man
with no top joint there...
- be very careful, my friend.
- Thanks, I'll make a note of it.
Meanwhile, what are
you going to do?
First, I'll eat my haddock...
and then,
if you are not going to
turn me out into the street...
- have a good night's rest.
- Oh, you're welcome to my bed.
I'll get a shakedown
on the couch.
Anything else I can get you?
- A map of Scotland.
- Why Scotland?
There's a man in Scotland whom I must
visit next if anything is to be done.
Are the 39 Steps in Scotland,
by any chance?
Perhaps I'll tell you tomorrow.
Clear out, Hannay.
They'll get you next.
What you were
laughing at just now...
is true.
These men will stop at nothing.
There's a man in Scotland...
whom I must visit next
if anything is to be done.
It is only a matter of days,
perhaps hours...
before the secret
is out of the country.
The police would not believe me
any more than you did.
I tell you,
these men act quickly.
Quickly.
Oh, good morning, sir. You're up
bright and early this morning.
Could you use a
pound note, brother?
- What's the catch?
- I want to borrow your cap and coat.
Wait a minute, what's this?
What's the big idea?
- I want to make a getaway.
- Do a bunk? - Yes.
What have you been up to?
I'll have to trust you.
There's been a murder committed
up on the first floor.
- By you?
- No, no.
By those two men out there.
I see... Now, I suppose they're
waiting there as good as gold...
- for a copper to come and arrest them.
- It's quite true, listen.
They're spies, foreigners.
They've murdered a woman in my flat,
and now they're waiting for me.
Oh, come off it. Funny jokes
at 5:00 in the morning.
All right, all right.
I'll tell you the truth.
- Are you married?
- Yes, but don't rub it in.
- What's the idea now?
- Well I'm not, you see, I'm a bachelor.
- Oh, are you?
- A married woman lives on the first floor.
- Does she?
- Yes and I've just been paying her a call.
- And now I want to go home.
- Well, what's preventing you?
One of those men is her brother,
the other's her husband.
Now do you see?
Why didn't you tell me before old
fellow? I only wanted to be told.
Trying to keep me with a lot of tales
about murders and foreigners.
Here, put this on. Put on my
little hat. There you are.
Take the pound.
No-no-no, sir, you're welcome to it.
You'd do the same for me one day.
Leave the pony around the corner.
- So long, old sport.
- Good-bye, thank you.
Oi! The empties!
Papers, magazines,
chocolates, cigarettes.
- Highland Express!
- Mind the gap, please!
Quickly! There he is.
Well, for one thing, they're much
prettier than they were 20 years ago.
- More free. Free and easy.
- You're right there.
I can never understand how people used
to put up with the old-fashioned sort.
All bones and no bend.
Well I will say for the old-fashioned
it did last longer.
I don't know.
Mine last about a year.
Here, I'll show you.
Big demand for these now.
- The old-fashioned sort.
- Brrr! My wife.
Now take a look at these.
Our new Streamline Model number one.
What I've been talking to you about.
- Anything go with it?
- I should say so.
This.
Put a pretty girl inside those, and she
needn't be ashamed of herself anywhere.
All right. Bring it back
to me when it's filled.
I will.
Well, watch this.
Edinburgh, Waverley.
Hm, we're getting on.
I hope you'll pardon us for
talking business, sir.
Oh, certainly. Certainly.
- Good day to you.
- Good day, sir.
Good day.
- Um-um, good day.
- Broad-minded old geezer.
I bet he's very good at charades.
- I wonder what won the 2:00 at Windsor.
- I don't know. Let's get a paper.
- Dispatch.
- Hey, son, speaky the English?
Dispatch.
- Hello.
- Well, what won it?
There's been another woman
murdered in a West End flat.
- What?  - "Woman
murdered in West End flat."
Ah, these sex dramas don't
appeal to me. What won?
- Um, Bachelor Bud.
- Good.
- Seven to four odds.
- Ooh! Not so good.
Portland Mansions,
Portland Place.
By the BBC. That's a nice, quiet
place to put someone to sleep.
"Good night, everybody.
Good night."
That's a good one.
What was she like?
One of the usual?
"A well-dressed woman of about 35
with a knife in her back.
The tenant, Richard
Hannay, is missing."
You surprise me.
"At 7:00 this morning, the
charwoman, Elizabeth Briggs... "
Well, if that isn't
the blasted limit.
- What's the matter now?
- Is there no honesty in this world at all?
I ask you.
"The new Bodyline
rubber panty corset.
On sale today. McCutcheon Brothers,
Princess Street. Price: 17 and 9.
Brassiere to match: 4 and 11."
Do you get that?
The Bodyline. 1 and 3
cheaper than our Streamline.
No use going to Aberdeen now.
Might I have a look
at your paper?
Certainly.
- Thank you.
- Quite all right.
There's enough evidence
there to hang any man.
What can I do for you, sir?
Oh... c-can you tell me what
station the train stops at next?
Who you think I'm a railway porter?
Go and find out for yourself.
I can tell a better one
than that first for you.
- You couldn't. That was very funny.
- You liked it, didn't you?
Have you heard the one about
the young lady of Ongar?
- I don't know, I can't remember them all.
- Oh, you must hear that.
- There was a young lady of Ongar.
- Yes, we, uh...
- Taking tea, sir?
- Yes. Thank you.
Darling, how lovely to see you!
Young man having
a free meal in there.
I was desperate. I'm terribly sorry.
I had to do it, look here.
My name's Hannay, they're after me.
I swear I'm innocent.
You've got to help me. I've got
to keep free for the next few days.
Well, have you seen a man pass
in the last few minutes?
This is the man you want, I think.
- When we passed just now. - Forced his way
in here and told me his name was Hannay.
- Is your name Hannay?
- No.
- Are you coming in to tea, sir?
- I'll be right along.
Pull that cord!
Right down with you.
Go on, men. Go to the
other end, would you?
Get on with it.
Hear! Hear! What for did you
pull the communication cord?
To stop the train, you old fool.
It's against all the regulations
to stop the train on a bridge.
But a man jumped down. He's a
murderer, we've got to chase him.
- Which way did he go?
- He must have jumped off here.
I cannot see him.
Are you sure he jumped?
Anyway, I cannot
wait here any longer!
- There he is, getting on the train.
- No, that's a passenger.
- It's he, I tell you!
- Come on with you, then.
- Hannay escapes! Paper!
Paper! Extra special! Paper!
Sensational escape on Forth Bridge!
Paper!
Extra, extra! Paper!
Correct. Height:
about five foot ten.
Small moustache.
Last seen wearing a dark suit...
but he may have obtained
a change of clothing.
- Good day.
- And to you.
- What'll your business be?
- I'm a motor mechanic, looking for a job.
- You'll find no work about here.
- Oh, are there no big houses around here?
Only Sir Andrews, and
he won't be wanting you.
He's had the same
chauffeur for 40 years.
I didn't know there'd
been cars that long.
He was coachman besides
when he was a boy.
Oh, I see.
Oh, what's that?
That's the manse. But the
minister hasn't got a motorcar.
Are there no newcomers?
Aye, there's an Englishman,
a kind of professor.
- Professor?
- He lives in Alt-na-Shellach.
- Where?  - Alt-na-Shellach,
on the other side of the loch.
Oh, would that be
near that village?
It would.
Thanks.
Thanks, I'll try there.
You won't try tonight.
It's 14 miles.
Maybe get a lift in that van?
No.
Going the other way.
I guess you're right.
Um, could you put me up
for the night somehow?
- Free?
- No, I'll pay.
- All right. Can you eat the herring?
- I could eat half a dozen right now.
- Can you sleep in a box bed?
- I can try.
- Two and six.
- Take it now. Thank you.
Go in with the gentleman.
He'll stay with us
till tomorrow morning.
Your daughter?
My wife.
- Will you now come in?
- Thank you.
Here's your bed.
I'll lift these things.
- Could you sleep there, do you think?
- You try and stop me.
You'll be tired.
I'll say I am.
I'm on the tramp,
looking for a job.
Won't you sit down, please
while I go on with our supper?
Oh, thank you.
You've been in these parts long?
No.
I'm from Glasgow.
- Did you ever see it?
- No.
Oh, you should see Sauchiohall
Street with all its fine shops...
and Argyle Street
on a Saturday night...
with the trams
and the lights...
and the cinema palaces
and their crowd.
It's Saturday night tonight.
You certainly don't get
those things out here.
No.
You miss them?
Sometimes.
Well I've never been to Glasgow, but I've
been to Edinburgh and Montreal and London.
I'll tell you all about
London at supper.
- John wouldn't approve of that
I doubt.  - Why not?
He says it's best not
to think of such places
and all the wickedness
that goes on there.
Oh, why not listen now
before he comes back?
What do you want to know?
Well, is it true that all the
ladies paint their toenails?
Some of them.
Do London ladies
look beautiful?
They do. But they wouldn't
if you were beside them.
- You ought not say that.
- What ought he not to say?
I was just saying your wife that I
prefer living in town than the country.
God made the country.
- Is the supper ready, woman?
- Aye.
Do you mind if I have
a look at your paper?
- No, I don't mind.
- Thank you.
- You did not tell me your name.
- Oh, Hammond.
Well, Mr. Hammond, if you'll
put down that paper.
- I'll say a blessing.
- Yes, of course.
Sanctify these bounteous masses
to us miserable sinners.
O Lord, make us
truly thankful...
for them and for all
Thy manifold blessings.
And continually turn our hearts...
from wickedness...
and from worldly things...
unto Thee.
Amen.
I mined, I forgot to lock the barn.
There are cars coming. It'll be
the police, you best be going.
- Thanks, I was having such a grand sleep.
- Hurry, don't let them catch you.
I'm ready. I'll never forget you
for doing this for me.
- Which way do I go?
- I'll show you.
Aye.
I might have known.
Making love behind my back.
- Get out. - Just a minute...
- Aye and you too.
- Get out of my house before I...
- Aye, go. Go.
And leave you like this?
No fair.
- It's your chance of liberty.
- Look here, you don't understand.
OK, You're all wrong about this.
She's only trying to help me.
Aye, to bring shame and
disgrace upon my house.
She was helping me to
escape from the police.
- The police? - Yes the police, they're
after me for murder. They're here.
She was only trying to warn me.
I had to tell her about it last night.
Don't let them in. Say I'm not here.
I'll make it worth your while.
- How much?
- Five pounds.
- Have you got that much?
- Yes.
- Give it to me.
- After they've gone.
Get back into bed.
Shut him in. Hide him.
- No, not there. I do not trust him.
- But he took the money.
He could not resist it. Here.
What is this in the middle of
the night? What do you want?
Have you seen
a stranger about here?
This kind of a stranger,
I want reward...
I was right.
He's asking if there's a
reward if you get catched.
He'll argue about it for a moment
longer before he lets them in.
Now's your time. Oh, your
jacket's terrible light-colored.
I'm a-feared they'll see you.
- You best take this one.
- Is this your husband's coat?
Aye, his Sunday best one, but
never mind. They must not see you.
- What'll happen to you?
- I'll say I couldn't have stopped you.
- He'll not ill treat you?
- No. He'll pray at me, but no more.
- What's your name?
- Margaret.
Good-bye, Margaret.
I'll never forget you for this.
There he goes!
Spread out in a line.
- Is the master in?
- What name should I say, sir?
Well, he wouldn't know my name.
Ask him if he knows Miss Annabella Smith.
- Would you wait here while I inquire?
- Yes. Go on.
We'd better make inquiries here.
Aye, somebody may have seen
him through the windows.
- There's been a couple of motorcars here.
- Aye.
Murderers do not make calls
in motorcars.
- Good day, dear.
- The same to you.
Have you seen any strangers
about this morning?
There's a few callers upstairs now,
but they're no strangers.
You happen to seen any suspicious-looking
bodies outside the windows or...
- calling at the house?
- No, sir.
There hasn't been anybody near
here for the last half hour.
- You're from Annabella Smith?
- Yes.
We're just having a few drinks to
celebrate my daughter Hillary's birthday.
Give me five minutes, to get rid
of these people then we can talk.
- Of course. - Come along in and
meet my wife. Louisa, my dear.
I've another guest for you.
This is Mr...
- I forgot to ask your name.
- Hammond.  - Mr. Hammond.
He's come to see me on business,
all the way from London.
There's a police inspector at the
door sir, he wants to speak to you.
At the door?
All right.
All right, I'll deal with it.
- Take him in, my dear, will you please.
- Come and meet my daughters.
- This is Patricia.
- How do you do?
Mrs. Bailey, Mrs. Hutchins.
Oh, Hilary my dear,
this is Mr. Hammond.
- He just arrived from London.
- How do you do, Mr. Hammond?
Forgive the orgy. We've been to church and
the sermon lasted 3 quarters of an hour.
- Oh, this is Captain and Mrs. Ogilvey.
- How do you do?
- Have a drink, Mr. Hammond? - Thank you.
- This is Derek. Derek Stewart.
And this is Sheriff Watson.
You've got to be polite to him.
He's our Sheriff Substitute.
Scotch for local Beak.
He'll give you six months hard
as soon as look at you.
It's all right. Don't worry,
I've sent them away.
Come and look at the view from
this window, Mr. Hammond.
We're rather proud of it.
By the way Sheriff... when you
going to catch that murderer?
- Murderer? What murderer?
- My dear, haven't you heard?…
Why, the man that stuck a carving knife
into that woman in Portland Place last week.
- He's here in the district.
- Darling, how exciting. Where?
Oh, somewhere about. He's been on the
moors, Bridge of Lochay or somewhere.
Sheriff Ames, why don't you catch him?
Wouldn't like me to be stuck in the back
with a carving knife, would you?
It's no business of mine to catch him.
You catch him, and I'll convict him.
- Is there reward?  - Gracious, it's nearly
1:00. Jim, we must get out of here.
- Professor wants his lunch.
- There's no hurry, my dear.
Still, if you must go, Pat!
- Um, ring for Captain Ogilvey's
car, will you.  - Yes, I will.
Dear, are you coming out?
Come take me in your new car.
- Come again another time.
- Good-bye my darling. We'd love to.
Well, whenever you do catch him you'll find me
at the Sheriff's Court at 10 every morning.
- So, bring him along.
- Good-bye Sheriff.
Louisa, my dear.
If you'll excuse us Mr. Hammond and
I want to have a chat before lunch.
Now, Mr. Hannay.
I suppose it's safe to call
you by your real name now.
What about our mutual
friend, Annabella?
She's been murdered.
"Murdered"?
Oh, the Portland Mansions affair. What our
friends outside are looking for you for.
- I didn't do it.
- Of course you didn't.
But why come all this way to
Scotland to tell me about it?
I believe she was coming to see you
about some Air Ministry secret.
She was killed by a foreign agent
who was interested too.
- She'd tell you what the foreign agent
looked like?  - There wasn't time.
Oh, there was one thing, part of
his little finger was missing.
- Which one?
- This one, I think.
Sure it wasn't...
this one?
- Lunch is ready, dear.
- I'm coming right away.
Well Mr. Hannay.
I'm afraid, I've been guilty of
leading you down the garden path.
Or should it be up?
I never can remember.
It seems to be the wrong
garden, all right.
Well.
- What we gonna do about it?
- That's just the point.
What are we
going to do about it?
You see, I live here
as a respectable citizen,
and you must realize that my whole
existence would be jeopardized...
if it became known that I'm not...
um, what shall we say,
not what I seem.
Oh, Mr. Hannay,
why have you come here?
Why have you forced me
into this difficult position?
I can't lock you up in a room
or anything like that.
You see, there's my wife
and daughters to think of.
I don't know what to think.
Really, I don't.
What makes it doubly important
that I shouldn't let you go is...
That I'm just about to, um...
convey some very vital
information out of the country.
Oh, yes, I've got it.
I'm afraid poor Annabella would
have been too late in any case.
- Well, that's fair.
- Yes.
- What about it?
- What about what?  - About yourself.
- Seems to me there's only one way out.
- And what's that?
Supposing I left you alone...
with this revolver?
Tomorrow's newspapers
would be able to announce…
that the Portland Place murderer
had taken his own life.
I thought you were coming to lunch
directly, dear. We've all been waiting.
- Will Mr. Hammond be staying?
- I don't think so, dear.
Well...
what do you think, Mr. Hannay?
Well, I'm afraid you
leave me no alternative.
I cannot find my hymn book.
Where did you leave it?
In the breast pocket of my overcoat.
It was hanging here.
Johnny...
I'm afraid I gave it to that gentleman
who was staying here that night.
Cigarette cases, yes, but I've never
seen it happen to a hymn book before,
- except on the movies.  - And this
bullet stuck among the hymns, eh?
Well, I'm not surprised, Mr. Hannay.
Some of those hymns are
terrible hard to get through.
I've stuck at them
myself before now, eh.
I'm not complaining, Sheriff.
"Hymns that have helped me. "
Yes, that's a good one,
Mr. Hannay. That's fine.
And to think that I was
drinking his champagne...
only half an hour before.
Well, It's a lesson
to us all, Mr. Hannay.
not to mix with doubtful
company on the Sabbath.
And, um... how did you escape?
Well, if you look through the
window, sir, you'll see.
They put the... well, the
body in the dressing room.
When I came to, I borrowed
this suit in case...
one of his men recognize me
and pinched this car.
Sheriff, I don't want to
hurry you or anything, but…
oughtn't it we take steps?
This is serious, you know.
If it weren't, you don't suppose
I'd put myself in your hands…
- with a murder charge hanging over me.
- Never heed the murder, Mr. Hannay.
I don't doubt you'll
be able to convince…
Scotland Yard of your innocence
as easily as you've convinced me.
All I'll need...
will be a short statement...
- that I can forward to the
proper authority. - Oh good.
I've someone coming over from the
police station next door to take it down.
Thank you, sir.
- Are you wishing to see me, Sheriff?
- Indeed, I am.
Do you think I enjoy playing
for time with a murderer?
- "Murderer?"
- Certainly.
Hannay, you're under arrest...
on the charge of willful murder...
of a woman unknown
in Portland Mansions, London on Tuesday
last. Take him over to the county jail.
Sheriff, you heard my story, you must believe
it it's true, and in every word of it.
Hannay, we are not so daft in Scotland
as some smart Londoners may think.
Do you think I believed your
cock-and-bull story about the prof.?
Why, he's my best friend in the
district. Get me Prof. Jordan.
If the prof. didn't shoot me,
where did that bullet come from?
That's easy. From one of
your pursuers on the moor.
- Isn't that so, Inspector?
- It is so sir, I had a shot at him myself.
I demand that you allow me to telephone to
the High Commissioner for Canada in London.
You better do that from London.
You'll be there soon enough.
It'll save you the cost
of a trunk call.
That's the professor's
car, all right.
Hannay must be inside
spilling the beans.
Hey, stop him!
My God!
How do you do, how do you do?
We're all waiting for you.
Pamela's gone to meet you
at the station. This way. This way.
...leader and standard-bearer himself.
I welcome this opportunity
of discussing with you...
another question vital
to the import of our country...
at this critical
and momentous hour.
But first of all,
as a preliminary to this...
- I shall occupy your time...
- You've occupied our much already!
We've had enough of you!
Ladies and gentlemen, I'm now going
to call upon the speaker of the evening.
Speak up!
There's no need for me
to tell you who he is or...
or to speak of his brilliant record
as a soldier and a statesman.
- Son of Scotland who's crossed…
- Speak out!
...the border and conquered England.
He's now one of the
foremost figures in the...
diplomatic political world
in the great city of London.
I'm, therefore, going to ask him
to tell you something…
- That's about time too. - We all were
waiting. - How important it is...
to this constituency that at
this crucial by-election...
our candidate should be returned
by an adequate majority.
I now ask for Captain Fraser.
Ladies and gentlemen, I apologize
for my hesitation in rising just now...
but to tell you the simple truth I'd
entirely failed while listening to the...
chairman's flattering description
of the next speaker...
to realize he was
talking about me.
As for you, may I say
from the bottom of my heart...
and with the utmost sincerity...
how delighted and relieved
I am to find myself...
in your presence at this moment.
Delighted, uh because
of your friendly reception...
uh, relieved because...
so long as I stand on
this platform I'm...
delivered from the mom...
from the cares and the anxieties...
which must always be the lot
of a man in my position.
When I journeyed up to Scotland
a few days ago...
traveling on the
Highland Express...
over that magnificent structure
the Forth Bridge that...
monument to Scottish engineering
and Scottish muscle...
That is to say, on that journey
I had no idea that in a few days time...
I should find myself addressing an
important political meeting, no idea.
I'd planned a very different
program for myself.
A very different program.
You'd be for the moors
to shoot something.
Yes, or somebody,
I'm a rotten shot.
Anyhow, I little thought
I should be speaking tonight...
in support of that... that-that
brilliant, young statesman.
That-that rising, um...
The-the-the gentleman on my right...
already known among you
as one destined to make...
no uncertain mark in politics.
In other words, your future
member of Parliament...
your candidate, Mr, uh...
McCrocodile.
Doesn't know the
candidate's name.
I know your candidate will
forgive my referring to him...
by the... the friendly nickname
by which he's already known...
in anticipation...
In anticipation, mark you...
at...
Westminster.
Now, ladies and gentlemen, we'll going to
discuss some topic. What shall it be?
- The herring fisheries!
- Unemployment!
- What about the idle rich?
- Idle rich?
That's a bit of an old-fashioned
topic these days…
especially for me, because I'm not
rich and I've never been idle.
I've been pretty busy all my life, and I
expect to be much busier quite soon.
Have you ever worked
with your hand?
Indeed I have and I've known
what it is to feel lonely and helpless…
and have the whole world
against me
and those are things that no man
or woman ought to feel.
And I ask your candidate...
and all those who love
their fellowmen...
to set themselves resolutely to make
this world a happier place to live in.
A world where no nation
plots against nation...
where no neighbor
plots against neighbor...
where there is no persecution
or hunting down...
where everybody gets a square deal
and a sporting chance...
and where people try to help
and not to hinder.
A world from which suspicion
and cruelty and fear...
have been forever banished.
That is the sort of world I want!
Is that the sort of world you want?
Yes!
Fine!
That's all I have to say.
Good night!
I kept them going
as long as I could for you.
Well, you're certainly
a difficult man to follow.
Well, I suppose you think
you've been damn clever.
- Officer, will you tell your prisoner not to
insult me, please. - You, try and stop me.
- You, come along with me.
- Couldn't you realize I was speaking the truth.
In that railway carriage you
must have seen I was genuine.
Well, whether you believe me or not,
will you put a telephone call through…
to the High Commissioner
for Canada in London?
- and tell him an enormously important
secret's… - That'll do now.
An enormously important secret's being taken
out of this country by a foreign agent.
I can't do anything myself because
of this fool of a detective.
Has that penetrated?
Right to the funny bone,
now tell me another one.
Haven't you any sense at all?
Put that call through,
I beg of you and refer them to me!
Will you do this?
No. Good night.
I beg pardon, miss, but we
should like you to come too.
- Whatever for?
- To identify the prisoner formally.
- Will you come to the police station?
- What?
It's only for a few minutes.
All right, if it's absolutely
necessary, let's get it over.
Not you.
- Must I sit next to this man?
- It's only for a short time, miss.
Be as quick as you can.
All right.
Isn't that the police station?
We're running past it. Tell the man.
I'm afraid, you must have
misunderstood me miss.
We're not exactly going
to this police station.
- Where are we going?
- To Inverary.
- Inverary?
- Yes, miss.
This man is to be questioned
by the Sheriff Principal.
- We have orders to take him there direct.
- But you've no orders to take me.
No, miss, but I'm
afraid you must go.
I'll see you're sent back
the earliest possible moment.
- But, how far is it to Inverary?
- Forty miles.
- Will you keep quiet.
- Sorry.
We'll be there in less
than two hours, miss.
- Two hours, do you think I will spend half
of the night with you all? - Looks like it.
Isn't the man going the wrong way?
That's the way down to the south…
Surely that's the
way to Inverary.
There's a bridge fallen
down on that road, miss.
We shall have to go around.
The man knows the way.
Might I see your warrant?
You shut your mouth. You'll see it soon
enough when we get to the station.
Like to have a small
bet with me, Pamela?
All right, I'll have it
with you, Sherlock.
I'll lay you 100 to 1 that
your Sheriff Principal...
has the top joint of his
little finger missing.
What about it?
I win.
Hello, what are we stopping for?
Oh, it's a whole flock of detectives.
Scattered all over the road, damn silly
things. Get out Bugsy and clear them away.
- What about him?
- I'll soon fix that.
There, miss. Now you're
a special constable.
- Just what's the idea, what's you doing
this for?  - As long as you stay, he stays.
Yes, and as long as I go,
you go. Come on.
Stop them! They got away!
Come on, miss, hurry up.
- I won't!
- Won't?
- You're hurting me.
- Shut up.
See if they've gone down that way.
Where the devil
could they have gone?
Help! Help! Help!
Please help!
Let me go!
One yip out of you, and I'll shoot you
first and myself after. I mean that.
There's nobody down
here, I tell you.
Come up here, blast you,
and don't waste any more time.
Spread out and find them.
Must be a mile away by now.
Don't do that.
Oh, do stop whistling.
What are you doing all this for,
you can't possibly escape…
- What chance have you got tied to me?
- Keep that question for your husband.
Meanwhile I'll admit you're
the white man's burden.
I know, and I can't tell you what
comfort that thought gives me.
I say what is the use of this those policemen
will get you as soon as it's daylight.
They may get me,
but they're not policemen.
- And when did you find that out?
- You found that out yourself…
I should never have known
that was the wrong road to Inverary.
They were taking us to their boss,
and God help either you or me…
- if they ever catch us again.
- I see.
You're still sticking to your
penny novelette spy story.
Oh!
There are 20 million women in this island,
and I've gotto be chained to you.
Now look here miss, once more,
I'm telling you the truth.
I told it to you once in the…
train, last week. I tried to tell you
after the election meeting, this evening.
I'm telling it you now
for the third time.
There's a dangerous conspiracy
against this island and...
we're the only people
who can stop it.
Think what you've seen happen
right under your very nose.
The gallant knight to the rescue.
All right...
then I'm just a plain,
common murderer...
who stabbed an innocent, defenseless
woman in the back not four days ago.
How do you come out over that?
I don't know how innocent you may be…
but you're a woman, and you're
defenseless, and you're alone…
on a desolate moor in the dark,
manacled to a murderer...
who'd stop at nothing
to get you off his hands.
If that's the situation you prefer,
have it, my lovely, and welcome.
I'm not afraid of...
For all you know, I may
murder a woman a week.
So listen to a bit of advice.
From now on do every single thing
I tell you to do, and do it quick.
Uh, you big bully.
I like your pluck.
Come on.
- We're going in there.
- What for?
- That's my business.
- But…
Now, remember what I said;
the civil tongue or else.
We're going in there, and you'll going
to back me up in every single thing…
- I say or do. Has that penetrated
the ivory dome? - Only just.
All right, pull yourself together now.
Put your hand in my pocket and…
look as though you're in a hurry.
Come along.
Oh, come away in, then,
come away in, sir.
Oh, the young lady's
terrible wet.
Oh, yes we had an accident
with our car a few miles back.
- You'll be staying the night?
- Yes.
We've just one room left
with one bed in it.
- But you'll not be minding that.
- Oh no-no-no, quite the reverse.
- You're man and wife, I suppose?
- Oh, yes.
Um... yes.
- Have you any luggage?
- No, we left that behind in the car.
Oh, maybe I could lend the
young lady a nightgown.
Will you please to register?
- Um, James, the book.
- Aye, aye.
I'll away up and light the fire for you.
Will you be needing your supper?
Oh, thank you, just send up a large
whiskey and soda and a few sandwiches.
- Oh, and a glass of milk.
- Oh, very well, sir.
Can't write with my left hand,
my dear, but I can shoot with it.
You can guess what's
in this pocket, come on.
Uh, you should sign, darling...
the sooner you get used to writing
your new name, the better.
Off we go. "Mr. and Mrs. Henry Hopkinson,
The Hollyhocks, Hammersmith."
I'll be back in a minute, chaps.
Now deary, off with that wet skirt of yours
and I'll have it dried in the kitchen.
Oh, don't bother it'll… It'll dry
in front of the fire just as well,
thanks all the same.
No doubt the gentleman
will take care of you.
Good night, sir.
Good night, ma'am.
Good night.
- Is he married to her, do you think?
- I do not can, and I do not care.
They are so terrible in love
with each other.
I tell you, I can't stand it any longer.
I'm gonna tell them the whole story.
Want to hang me for a murder
I never committed? Go on.
Long as they hang you, I don't
care if you committed it or not.
Let me go! Do you think I'm going to spend
the whole night with you in this room?
Of course you are. What else
can you do? Come on.
Can I come in, sir?
Come here.
Come in.
Oh... We were just getting
warm before the fire.
I can see that. I thought maybe
you'd like this in your bed, sir.
Oh, thank you very much. You'd like a hot
water bottle, wouldn't you, my sweet?
Say yes, darling.
Yes, darling.
- Very well.
- I say, please don't go.
Why not?
Is anything wrong?
Of course there's nothing wrong…
she wants to tell you something,
that's all. We're a runaway couple.
I canned it all the time.
And they're after you?
You won't give us away,
will you? Please.
Of course we will
not give you up.
And good night to you both.
- You'll no be disturbed.
- But...
Thank God for a bite to eat.
Come along.
There you are.
Now, what's the next item
on the program?
- Get these things off.
- Right. How we gonna set about it?
Anything in that bag of
yours that will help?
A pair of scissors or
hairpin or something?
There's a nail file here.
Do you think that'd help?
Hm, easily. It'll take about
ten years, but we can try.
Now, let's make ourselves
as comfortable as possible.
What about that skirt of yours?
It's still pretty damp, you know.
I don't want to be tied to a pneumonia
case on top of everything else.
- Take it off, I don't mind.
- I should keep it on, thank you.
And that... is that.
My shoes and stockings are soaked
so I think I'll take them off.
It's the first sensible thing
I've heard you say.
- Can I be of any assistance?
- No, thank you.
Sorry.
- Here, hold this.
- Oh, yes.
Half a minute.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
- Would you like your milk now?
- No, thank you, I'll wait a little.
All right.
Cheerio.
That's better.
- Are your feet quite warm again?
- Yes, thanks.
Then, come on.
Now, will you kindly place yourself
on the operating table?
All right, all right, nobody's gonna
hurt you. This is Armistice Day.
- Let's get some rest while we can.
- I'm not going to lie on this bed.
So long as you're chained to me,
you'll lie wherever I lie.
- We're the Siamese twins.
- Oh, don't gloat.
Gloat? Do you think I'm looking forward
to waking up in the morning…
and seeing your face beside me,
unwashed and shiny?
What a sight you'll be.
Give me that nail file.
Let's have a go at this.
Thank you.
There I go again. I wish I could get
that damn tune out of my head.
I wonder where I heard it.
- You sound very sleepy.
- Sleepy? I'll say so.
Do you know when
I last slept in a bed?
Saturday night, whenever that was.
Then I only got a couple of hours.
- What made you wake so soon? Dreams?
- What do you mean "dreams"?
I've always been told
murderers have terrible dreams.
Oh, but only at first.
Got over that a long time ago.
When I first took to crime,
I was quite squeamish about it.
- I was a most sensitive child.
- You surprised me.
Used to wake up in the middle
of the night screaming,
thinking the police were after me.
But one gets hardened.
- How did you start?
- Oh, quite a small way, like most of us.
Pilfering pennies from other
children's lockers at school.
Then a little pocket picking,
then a spot of car pinching...
then smash and grab and
so on to plain burglary.
Killed my first man
when I was 19.
Then in years to come, you'll be able
to take your grandchildren...
to Madame Tussaud's
and point me out.
Which section?
Oh, it's early to say.
I'm still young.
But I'll be there, all right,
in one department or another.
Yes, you'll point me out and say,
"Chicks, if I were to tell you...
how matey I once was with that gentleman,
you'd be s..." What's the matter?
You're... pinching my wrist
with these handcuffs.
Oh, sorry.
Talking of Madame Tussaud's,
that's how it all began.
- What began?
- My career of crime.
All hereditary.
Great Uncle Penruddock.
Who was he?
My good girl, where
were you brought up?
Never heard of my
Great Uncle Penruddock,
Cornish Bluebeard?
Got it all from him.
I thought your family
came from Canada.
No, that's where they went.
After the Penruddock incident.
Yes, he murdered three wives
and got away with it,
but his third mother-in-law got the goods
on him and tried to have him arrested.
Did she succeed? No.
He was too quick for her.
Took her for a walk to Land's End and
shoved her over into the Atlantic Ocean.
He's in Madame Tussaud's, all right,
and there's no doubt about his department.
You must go down and
see him sometime.
Can't mistake him.
Third on the left as you go in.
Red whiskers and a harelip.
And that, lady, is the
sad story of my life.
Poor orphan boy
who never had a chance.
Are you still set on
giving me up to the police?
You're sure everything's
going to be quite all right?
Bound to be.
He can't have much time.
As soon as I've picked up...
you know what,
I'll clear out of the country.
Be careful.
Wire to me.
- Good-bye, my dear.
- Good-bye.
Is that Professor
Jordan's house?
Can I speak to Mrs. Jordan then?
Is that Mrs. Jordan?
Oh, he's gone to London
already, has he?
If you can manage it,
I'd like that whiskey hot.
I-I'll away and get
the hot water.
No, he ducked down the side street,
the police went the wrong way.
The girl handed him over to us,
thinking we were detectives.
We had to take her as well
because he told her everything.
Very good, ma'am. I see.
Yes, ma'am.
Well?
The old man's got the wind up.
He's cleared out already.
Whatever for?
He thought it too dangerous
with Hannay on the loose.
He's warning the whole 39 Steps.
Has he got the...
- you know?
- Yes.
He's picking up our friend at the
London Palladium on the way out.
Here's your toddy.
That'll be half a crown.
- And the phone call?
- Uh, we'll say a schilling.
Is...
- Is this a hotel as well?
- Aye.
- I mean, do you have people
staying here?  - Aye.
- I suppose, you get a few odd people
at this time of year?  - Aye.
- You didn't happen to have anyone
in tonight, did you? - Aye.
They...
They weren't by any chance
a young couple, were they?
James!
Mercy me!
What kind of a silly creature
am I married to?
Do you want to get us all jailed?
- How much did you take for these?
- Half a crown.
Out, the pair of you!
And do not let on to anybody
that you got to drink here after hours.
Ohh!
You old fool, you. You wouldn't have
give away a young couple, would you?
Good morning.
What's the idea?
How did we get out of these?
We didn't at least you didn't.
I slipped out of mine last night and…
came and camped out here.
- Why didn't you run away?
- I did, but just as I was going I...
I discovered that you've
been speaking the truth.
So I decided to stay.
May I ask what earthquake caused
your brain to work at last?
Those two men were in here last night,
I overheard them telephoning.
- What did they say?
- Oh...
A lot of stuff about...
about the 39 Steps.
- The thirty… You really…
- What? - No, go on. Go on.
Someone's going to warn them.
- How can you warn steps?
- Never mind. Go on.
Oh, yes-yes, and there
was another thing.
Someone got scared
and is clearing out and ehm...
Oh, yes-yes, I know,
and is picking up someone
at the London Palladium.
London Palladium?
What the devil?
Is that the professor?
Our friend with the
little finger missing?
What does he want to
go there for?
I feel such a fool,
not having believed you.
Oh, that's all right.
Well, we... we-we-we
we ought to get a move on.
What room are those two men in?
No room, they... they went
as soon as they telephoned.
They what?
Didn't I tell you?
You let them go after hearing
what they said? You...
- You button-headed little idiot.
- Don't talk to me like that!
Four or five precious hours wasted!
Why didn't you wake me up at once?
Even you might have realized that
what they said was important.
Now they call these men off.
Why not let well alone?
Let well alone? My good girl,
I'm accused of murder!
Can't you realize the only way I can
clear myself is to expose these spies?
You still can. The man's
going to the London Palladium.
Really? First or second house?
I'll get there five hours late!
Fine! The show will
just about suit you.
- What's that?
- Crazy Month!
You're quite right, madame.
It's true the Air Ministry
has got a new thing...
quite a lot of people
are interested in.
But they are positive that no
papers are missing about it...
that would be of
any use to a spy.
But I tell you I'm quite
certain about it.
There's a man leaving the country
tonight with something.
Since you phoned to us
from Scotland this morning...
we've made the
minutest inquiries.
- It's obvious I'm wasting my time here.
- Now, just a moment, miss, please.
Um, there's one thing
you haven't told us.
Where's Richard Hannay?
I haven't the faintest idea.
Now, look here, miss,
you can't...
- You're in the telephone book,
aren't you?  - Yes.
Well, if anything crops up,
we'll give you a ring.
That'll be all now.
Thank you.
Tell Archer and Seagrave to get
another taxi and follow that girl.
She'll lead us to
Hannay, all right.
Love is a flower that blooms.
Cover every exit,
and on no account let
anyone leave the building.
Now, you two men go
in the orchestra pit.
Ladies and gentlemen,
we shall now...
sing.
Go on. Move along
there, please.
Go on, sir.
Sorry sir, but no one's allowed
to leave the theater.
What was the great idea, can't a
mate go out and have a drink?
- Ticket, please. - I got a seat withhold
that I'm just looking for, sir…
- can I go through, please?
- Oh, very good.
She's seen him. She's on her way
down to the stalls, perhaps.
May I borrow your opera glasses,
please? Thank you.
Excuse me.
May I take your place, please?
What are you doing here?
Listen, I found him. He's up in that box.
You can't do anything about it.
I've been to Scotland Yard.
Nothing had ever's been stolen from the Air
Ministry, they're absolutely certain about it.
But, you heard those men say
he'd gone and there he is.
Shall we take him now, sir
or wait till the interval?
What you going to do? There's
nothing missing. There's an end to it.
Hear that tune?
It's that damn thing I couldn't
get out of my head.
Now I know where I heard it before,
of course, that music hall.
Annabella's...
Ladies and gentlemen...
with your kind attention
and permission...
I have now the honor
to present to you...
one of the most remarkable
men in the world.
- That same little man.
- Every day he commits to memory...
50 new facts,
and remembers
every one of them.
Facts from history,
from geography...
from newspapers,
from scientific textbooks...
millions and millions of them...
down to the smallest detail.
Test him, ladies and gentlemen.
Ask him any question...
I've got it! I've got it!
Of course there are no papers missing.
All the information's
inside Memory's head.
Mr. Memory.
- But I still don't understand.
- Don't you see?
The details of that Air Ministry
secret were borrowed,
memorized by this little man...
and then replaced before
anyone could find out.
That's why he's here tonight: to take
Memory out of the country after the show.
- But, surely...  - Some gentlemen
here would like to speak to you.
Question, please.
- When's the boat race?
- When did Florence Nightingale die?
- What is the height of the Empire State?…
- Are you Richard Hannay?
- Listen, there's something you ought to know.
- …Hannay, come along quietly.
- Yes, but look here, that man on the stage…
- I don't care. Now you don't wanna cause…
- any trouble, spoil people's entertainment.
- What was the date on General Gordon's death?
- Where's the capital of M...
- What are the 39 Steps?
Come on, answer up!
What are the 39 Steps?
The 39 Steps...
is an organization of spies...
collecting information on behalf
of the foreign office of...
Please! Keep your seats!
Keep your seats, please!
There is no need for alarm,
no cause for alarm.
- Oh, I'm all right, yes.
- Sure you are.
I don't want a chair, no.
No way.
- Well, let me rest here. I'm all right.
- Take it easy. Take it easy now.
Take it easy.
I'm all right.
Get the girls on straightaway!
The girls' introduction right away.
Mr. Memory,
what was the secret formula
you were taking out of the country?
Would it be all right,
me telling you, sir?
It was a big job to learn it...
the biggest job I ever tackled...
- and I don't want to throw it all away.
- It'll be quite all right.
The first feature
of the new engine is...
its greatly increased ratio
of compression...
represented by R minus 1 over R
to the power of gamma...
where R represents the ratio
of compression and gamma...
seen in end elevation.
The axis of the two
lines of cylinders...
angle of 65 degrees.
Dimensions of cylinders
as follows...
This device renders the engine
completely silent.
Am I right, sir?
Quite right, old chap.
Thank you, sir.
Thank you.
I'm glad it's off my mind,
at last.