LIKE IN A MIRROR
FOR Käbi, my wife
- First at the dock! - That felt good.
Dad and Martin put up the nets and Minus and I get the milk.
No, David and Minus are doing the nets and I'm going for a walk with my wife.
Or Karin and I put up the nets and Minus and Martin get the milk.
I don't want to do either. I decide for myself what I do.
-Should we get the milk, Minus? -Why do women always make the decisions?
Let's do what Karin wants! That way we won't lose our dignity.
We would have saved a lot of time if Dad had said that right away!
Should we get dressed before we put up the nets?
What do you think?
It's quite chilly, and my bathrobe is thin.
-If you're cold... - Me? Not at all. You?
You said it was cool. But it really is a bit windy...
We're toughening ourselves up. Virility is more important than health, right?
We've been able to do what Hemingway can do for a long time! Forward march!
- I wonder if there's a thunderstorm? - Not today.
I don't know, look at the clouds.
- Are you afraid of thunderstorms? - And what kind.
- The thunderstorms in Switzerland... - Did you like it there otherwise?
I was homesick. But I wanted to finish the novel first.
-And is it finished now? -Yes, pretty much.
-How's your stomach ulcer? - It's okay. Can you give me something?
We can go to the pharmacy tomorrow. I have a few things to do anyway.
Did you get my last letter? I sent it on Monday.
- I was in Basel with the Waldsteins. - Then you didn't get him.
- And I flew here on Wednesday. - Then you didn't get it.
-Was it something important? - It was about Karin.
I just had to write to you.
Even if it would interrupt your work.
- A cuckoo. Did you hear it? - No.
-Now you have to hear him! -Where?
- You need to wash your ears! - You hear too much!
The illness has made my hearing worse.
Maybe it was the electroshock therapy.
Didn't Dad look grey when he arrived from Switzerland yesterday?
He was tired from the journey. But he didn't look happy.
- Is Marianne coming too? - Martin said that's over.
-Poor Dad, alone again. -I never liked Marianne.
She always acted so arrogantly. Compared to that, Dad seemed so poor.
- She badmouthed his books. - He needs to get good reviews.
-But everyone reads his books! - He doesn't care about sales figures.
He wants to be a poet.
Why are you laughing like that?
You're so big and serious! ''He wants to be a poet.''
Don't look so offended. I love you, little Minus!
- You're so big! - Don't be so silly!
17 years old, and almost three meters tall!
-Where's your girlfriend? - Nobody wants me!
Don't be mad that I laughed at you.
Edgar is the only psychiatrist I trust.
- He was there from the beginning. - And?
We talked for a long time when Karin last month...
came from the hospital.
He cannot promise lasting recovery.
And now?
She seems to be doing unusually well.
Her sleep is somewhat restless.
Heightened hearing. That's all.
-How much does she know? - She knows about her illness.
Except that it is almost incurable.
fast?
Edgar had patients who became completely healthy, so there is hope.
-How are things going with you two? - Good, thanks.
Everyday life goes on as usual.
I give lectures and examine masses of students.
I love Karin, and I am hopelessly attached to her.
No matter what happens...
I have become the anchor of her life.
Perhaps your only security.
I understand.
-Shall we go back to the nets? - Good.
Minus...
Dear...
Beware of me! Stay away from me!
Stop hugging and kissing me.
Don't sunbathe half-naked, you disgust me!
You know exactly what I mean! Women are horrible!
They smell and move, comb their hair and talk!
I feel like a skinned rabbit!
You arm Kleiner.
Pity! I can feel sorry for myself!
What's wrong, my darling? I've never seen you like this before.
Please don't tell Martin or Dad.
Don't be silly!
If only I could talk to Dad just once!
But he's so busy with himself.
He too.
Come on, let's go back.
- And I spilled the milk. - You careless brat!
Damn! I hate hurting my fingers!
Put a bandage on it.
- Hello! - Martin cut himself.
- Put a band-aid on it. - What a fuss.
How lovely: dinner by lantern light and moonlight!
- You're a master chef, Dad! - That smells wonderful.
Smell it, Minus...
You should write cookbooks instead of novels!
So, how do we sit... Karin there, and you there.
Minus there and me here.
How I longed for this moment! I was so homesick.
- After us? -Yes, even after you!
-Are you staying? -At least this month.
- You're leaving again? - To Yugoslavia, as leader.
-Why? - It was an attractive offer.
From a cultural delegation. And since I know the country...
-So, David. Welcome home! - Thanks.
Cheers to your health, Karin. And to yours, Minus!
- And what about the book? - I'll finish that first.
I'll submit the manuscript next week.
- Are you going away long? - I don't know yet.
Maybe I'll stay in Dubrovnik a bit longer after that.
Now I feel like a criminal.
You promised to stay home after Switzerland.
I can't remember that.
Yes, Dad, you promised.
-How unfortunate. -Yes, how unfortunate.
Listen... We wanted to have a nice evening...
and now we are close to tears!
I brought you gifts from Switzerland!
Cooking.
And Martin.
- Thanks, but that wasn't... - Minus.
- Can we open it right away? - Go ahead!
Excuse me, I'll quickly get my tobacco.
- They don't fit over the thumb. - I already have one.
- They're probably from Stockholm. - Still a nice gesture.
-Thank you, David! - Thanks for the lovely gloves!
We also have a surprise for you!
-We'll blindfold you. - Don't look!
- I'll do it, you go first! - I can't see anything at all!
I feel like I'm walking on air. Who thought that up?
Me and Karin.
Just wait...
It's almost like Shakespeare.
complete?
Our play is called "The Artistic Ghost."
Or ''Tomb of Illusions''.
And here we go!
It is midnight in the Chapel of St. Teresa.
This is where we will meet, my fiancée and I.
Here, by this gravestone, where the scent of death hangs.
Someone moved inside! Could it be her?
I will hide so as not to frighten them.
-Who are you? -I am the Castilian princess.
She died in childbirth, at the age of 13.
And my master, with whom I played as a child...
now finds comfort in other women.
Princess, I love you!
But who are you? I can't talk to everyone, even if I'm dead.
Do not be afraid!
I am the master of my own kingdom. It is quite small and very poor.
- I am an artist! - Artist?
Yes, Princess! An artist of the purest kind.
A poet without poems, a painter without paintings...
- Musician. - A musician without sounds.
I despise finished works of art! Banal results of vulgar effort.
My life is my work, and it is dedicated to my love for you!
- Such beautiful, yet unbelievable words. - I beg you, test me!
Listen carefully. I will be leaving you soon.
When the clock strikes two, you shall enter the grave...
and blow out the three candles in it.
Then the door closes...
and you will join me in death.
An easy target, Princess.
For what does life mean to the true artist?
This is how you complete your work of art and crown your love.
This is how you elevate your life...
and shows the skeptics the power of a true artist.
Farewell, my friend.
Doesn't disappoint me.
This is the moment of absolute perfection! I tremble with anticipation.
I dive into oblivion.
Only death will love me from now on.
I go, and nothing can stop me.
- I'm waiting. - You devil, what am I doing?
Sacrifice my life, but for what?
For eternity? For the perfect work of art? For love?
- Have I gone mad? - I'm waiting!
Who will see my sacrifice? Death! Who will measure my love? A ghost!
-Who will thank me? Eternity! -I wait.
My knees are made of clay, I tremble, my insides churn.
- I can't go into eternity like this... - I'm not waiting any longer.
Well, that's life.
Of course I could write a poem about the princess.
Paint a picture or compose an opera...
although this would of course have a more heroic ending.
I enter the realm of oblivion.
Now only death shall love me.
Not bad.
The young roosters announce the dawn!
I'm going to go home and go to bed.
- And that's it. - The author! The author!
You were fantastic!
- And you, excellent. - That made everything negative!
-But I forgot my lines. -Oh, never!
Now cover and wash.
- I'll do it, I'm not tired. - Out of the question!
Yes, I like cleaning, you would do me a favor.
- Well, if that's the case... - So, it's a deal.
I'll start right away.
-Are you going to bed now? -Yes.
- There's hot water in the kitchen. - Oh, good.
- The storm has passed. - I told you.
We had the windows open, now we have mosquitoes in the bedroom.
- Good night, Dad. - Good night, Karin.
Good night everyone!
-Is it okay? -Yes.
- I'll help you. - It's okay.
Can you please help me?
Such black fingers, that's from gardening.
It doesn't go away either.
You have such kind fingers.
But your thumb looks a little stubborn.
- Are you sad, Karin? - Not really.
What are you thinking about?
Sometimes we are so defenseless.
No, I don't know...
Like children abandoned in the wilderness at night.
The owls fly by, watching you with their yellow eyes.
You can hear the clattering and rustling, the coughing and sighing...
All those wet snouts...
The teeth of wolves...
Don't worry, we have each other.
- You look nervous... - I'm not nervous at all.
You say there are no wolves, I don't see any owls and I don't hear anything.
"You're just imagining it."
You have to trust me, Karin. Little Kajsa.
"Little Kajta",,,
That's what you always say. "Little Kajsa."
Am I so small, or has the illness turned me into a child?
Do you find me strange?
- Do you think I'm telling the truth? - I don't know.
- Do you think I love you? - Yes.
- Isn't that enough? - Of course that's enough.
- Stop, or it'll bleed! - It's okay.
Tomorrow I have to do laundry.
Come to bed, Karin.
Papa took Minus' piece as a personal insult.
It hurt him deeply, but he didn't let it show.
And Minus was, of course, upset too.
Shall we turn off the light?
- I don't want to make you sad. - My dear child...
- I'm sorry. - My dearest...
My dear, dear girl.
Lamb, I love you.
You could never hurt me.
You are so sweet and I am so mean.
Good night.
''Panting with anticipation, she came toward him...
cheeks flushed by the strong wind.''
My God!
''They met...
am Strand.''
Hello, little Kajsa. Up already? It's not even four o'clock yet!
-Hello, Dad. -What's going on?
Do you have something on your mind?
I'm putting the finishing touches to the book, not exactly my favorite hobby.
- Read something to me. - Later, when I have the proofs.
"Why aren't you sleeping?" - The birds screamed eerily.
Then I woke up, and then I didn't dare go back to sleep.
Then come.
-Like when I was little. -Now you'll be asleep soon.
''They met on the beach.
It was a clear day.
Autumn was in the air.''
- Dad! - Shh! Karin just fell asleep.
- Come on, let's pull in the nets. - I'm coming.
Last year I could walk on my hands as well as on my feet.
-Now I'm so big and unstable. - I feel the same way.
Do you mean spiritual?
- Are you writing at the moment? - Plays.
- Can I read something? - No.
No offense, but they're not very good.
- Have you written a lot? - 13 plays and 1 opera this summer.
It just flows out of me. Is it the same for you?
No.
What did you think of our play last night?
- Nice. - I thought it was shit.
''Your illness is incurable...
with temporary improvements.
I've suspected it for a long time, but it's still unbearable.
My curiosity fills me with terror.
My urge to record the progression of the disease.
To accurately describe their gradual decay.
To use them.''
Wake up! How much longer do you want to sleep?
Martin, time for a bath! Get up!
-What time is it? - Almost ten.
My goodness, I slept that long?
- You rascal! It's only five. - So what?
I've been up for a long time and have experienced strange things.
- Come here. - No, get up! We're going swimming.
- Dad and Minus are bringing in the nets. - Come here!
You sleep too much, that's why you're always so know-it-all.
My little one, what's wrong with you?
Nothing...
-What is it, Karin? - I have something to confess to you.
Then speak up.
When Dad went out earlier...
I rummaged around in his desk.
I don't know why, I just had this urge.
And?
- I found his diary there. - And?
- There were things in there... -What kind of things?
About me.
-What did he write? - I can't tell you.
Something about your illness?
- Is it really incurable? - Dearest Karin...
Now listen to me!
Listen... Look at me!
Look at me.
I told David that you might have a relapse.
Maybe he misunderstood that.
No one can say that your illness is incurable.
- Word of honor? - Word of honor.
So.
There was more in there.
-Yes? -But I can't tell you that.
- Please... - Impossible!
ask him yourself!
Karin... Little Karin...
Martin?
You still have to be patient with me.
My cravings will surely return soon.
- Don't you think so? -Of course!
- Are you worried about that? - Not at all.
Listen, I'm terribly tired, but...
I think we should go swimming anyway.
It's not cold at all.
Imagine you had a quiet wife...
who gives you children and brings you coffee.
A soft, warm, beautiful woman...
Wouldn't that be nice?
-But I love you. -Yes, of course, but still.
I don't want anyone else!
You always say and do everything right, and yet things still go wrong.
I do it out of love.
Those who truly love never hurt others.
In that case, you don't love me.
Bye, Minus!
Bye!
Please make sure Minus doesn't fall asleep while learning Latin.
-I wanted to learn grammar with him. -Goodbye, my girl.
Don't forget your cognac and bring a white wine.
- Bye, darling. - See you tonight.
Why are you laughing so stupidly?
Hm?
Say something!
There, if you find it so funny!
Which one do you like best?
Don't be a spoilsport, come here and show me!
- That one? Why? - It's so soft.
I think she's pretty, too. But a bit fat, right?
- And such long hair... - She looks pretty uncomplicated.
But what good is that to me?
Do you want to hit me?
That was my fault. Forgive me.
Calm down, Minus. It's okay, don't worry.
I shouldn't have snooped around.
I don't even want it to happen, it just happens.
-Should I quiz you? -If you feel like it.
- I wonder if everyone's locked up like this? -What?
You in your cage, me in mine. All of us.
- I don't feel locked in at all. - Then I'm wrong again.
Constructio adsensum, what does that mean?
Stop it.
This means adapting a grammatical construction to the content.
For example?
The nobility abandoned the republic,,,
they had deserted,
- Isn't that hot! - And I've been up since half past four.
Do you want to smoke one?
If you look at it with your head tilted for a long time, it becomes creepy.
Creepy?
But also tempting.
I don't talk to Dad or Martin about it, they don't understand.
Especially Martin, he's already nervous and has enough worries.
They don't understand, they just think I'm sick.
- Do you think so too? - No!
I thought so.
You are stronger.
I've wanted to talk to you about all of this so often.
You can trust me.
It's hard to hide something you're constantly thinking about.
But I think they won't mind if I tell you.
- ''You''? - Don't pester me with questions.
Enmeder I tell you or not.
- I'm just curious. - You don't mind.
I want to show you something.
Because I can walk through walls.
Every morning I wake up because someone is calling my name.
Then I get up and go into this room.
One day someone called out to me from behind the wallpaper.
I looked in the closet, but no one was there.
But the voice continued to call my name...
So I pressed myself against the wall, and it gave way like leaves.
And then I went in.
You think I'm just making this up, right?
I enter a large room.
It is bright and friendly there.
People walk up and down.
Some explain it to me so that I understand.
It's so beautiful there, and I'm safe.
A light shines on some faces.
Everyone is waiting for him...
but no one is nervous.
They say I can be there too when it happens!
Why are you crying?
It's already good.
No fear.
But... sometimes I feel such terrible longing.
I long for the moment...
when the door opens...
- and everyone turns to him. -To whom? Who is he?
Nobody said exactly.
But I believe it is God who will reveal himself to us.
That he will come through the door and enter the room.
Minus...
It's not easy for me to say this...
-What? - I turn away from Martin.
He calls for me, but I can't help him.
I'm playing something for him.
- Does he notice anything? - I'm not sure.
I have to choose between him and the others.
I've made my decision. I've sacrificed Martin.
- Is this all real? - I don't know.
I feel torn, and sometimes I'm not sure.
I know that I was sick and that the illness was like a dream.
But these aren't dreams, this is real. It must be real!
For me they are not real, not at all.
Cooking,,,
- For me, it's not real. -But yes!
A god comes down from the mountain.
He walks through the dark forest...
Wild animals everywhere, in the silence and the darkness.
This has to be real.
I am not dreaming, and I am telling the truth.
One moment I am in one world, the next in another.
I can't stop it!
Shall we go swimming?
Otherwise I'll go alone.
I am tired.
I'm going to lie down for a bit.
Close the door when you leave.
Don't do that! Get out! Get out!
What should I do?
Well, have you practiced Latin?
Come on, let's continue.
But first let's have some tea.
Minus!
- Will you tell Dad and Martin? -What should I tell them?
Clever, but you're not fooling me. Martin, you would say:
"I need to talk to you about Karin." And then you tell him everything.
-Can't you tell him? -Promise you won't say anything!
-Promise. -No one understands this but you.
-One word, and you've betrayed me. -Promise.
- It looks like rain. - Do you think so?
-What's wrong with you? -What?
You are so quiet, almost hostile.
- Let's not talk about it. - Yes, please!
It's because of Karin.
She found your diary in your desk.
- And read it, of course. - Oh no...
What did it say?
Karin wanted me to ask you.
That her illness is incurable.
And that I have the urge to record its course.
I can't deny my guilt. There are no excuses.
It's always about you and yours.
Your heartlessness is perverse.
''Capture the flow.'' That's so typical!
- You don't understand. - No, I don't.
But I understand one thing very well: you are looking for topics.
The mental illness of one's own daughter. What a brilliant idea!
- I love her, Martin. - You "love" her?
There's no room for emotions in your emptiness. You have no decency.
You can express yourself well and always have the right words at hand.
But there is one thing you have absolutely no idea about: life!
You are a coward!
But there's one thing you can do like no other: make excuses and evasions.
-What do you want from me? - Write your book!
This might bring you what you want: an artistic breakthrough.
Then you didn't sacrifice your daughter in vain. And...
Tell me!
In your novels you always flirt with a god.
But your faith and your doubt are highly implausible.
What is most striking is your ingenuity.
-Do you think I don't know that? -Why do you keep going?
- Why don't you do something respectable? -For example?
Have you written a true word in your life as a writer?
- I don't know. - See?
Your half-lies are so sophisticated that they look like the truth.
- I'll try. - Maybe.
But you never quite make it.
l know.
You are empty, but capable.
And now you want to fill your emptiness with Karin's downfall.
But how does God fit into this picture? This makes him even more inscrutable!
Here's a question: Can you control your deepest thoughts?
Luckily, I'm not very complicated.
My world is very simple. Clear and human.
But you already wished she would die.
Absolutely not!
Only you can think of something like that.
Do you swear you've never thought of it? It would be logical...
Your case is hopeless. And you know you're suffering in vain.
- She could just as well be dead. - You're grotesque.
That's a matter of opinion.
l love her.
I am powerless.
I can only watch helplessly...
how she turns into a poor, tormented creature.
I would like to tell you something.
When I was in Switzerland, I decided to kill myself.
I rented a car and looked for a precipice.
I set off. It was afternoon, and it was already dark in the valley.
I was empty. No fear, no regrets, no expectations.
I drove toward the edge, accelerated, and suddenly the car stopped.
The transmission was broken.
The car skidded and stopped with the front tires over the edge.
I crawled out trembling.
Then I leaned against a rock wall on the other side of the street.
I sat there for hours and yawned because I was so breathless.
Why are you telling me this?
To say that I no longer have a facade to protect.
The truth does not cause catastrophe.
- That has nothing to do with Karin. - I think it does.
I do not understand that.
From this emptiness came something I cannot touch or name.
A love...
for Karin... and Minus.
And for you.
Maybe I'll tell you about it sometime.
I don't dare do it yet. But...
If it is as I hope...
Let's leave that aside for now.
Now comes the rain.
No.
But...
The rain is coming!
Cook!
Karin, are you there?
It's me, Karin.
Can't you hear me, Karin?!
-I'm not feeling well. -We're going home.
-You have to help me. -How?
You have to help me.
- I'm so thirsty. - I'll get you some water.
Good.
What time is it?
five, I think.
I was feeling very bad, but now I'm feeling better.
-Poor Minus! - Karin, my darling...
- I want to talk to Dad. Alone. - Let's go home.
I need to talk to Dad before it starts again. Please!
I go to the farm and call a rescue helicopter.
Please get my medicine bag. I need to give her an injection.
- Dad... - And?
I want to stay in the hospital. I don't want to be treated anymore.
Will I live if you tell them?
I don't know.
You can't live in two worlds. You have to choose.
I can't keep switching from one to the other.
It has to end.
Was?
- The hate. -What kind of hate?
I didn't do it of my own free will.
A voice commanded me.
A voice commanded you to read my diary.
And tell Martin what you read.
It gets worse.
Much worse.
I tried to fight back, but I couldn't get away.
I was forced to do it.
When?
Just now.
Arms Minus!
I just don't understand it!
Try to stay calm, Karin.
And this room with the waiting people...
These good people who are waiting for the door to open...
and God comes to them.
But then the voices come...
I have to do what the voices tell me.
l don't understand it.
Is it really just my illness?
Papa...
It is so terrible to see and understand one's own confusion!
I would like to apologize to you.
I avoided you because I had a guilty conscience.
It makes me sick to think...
how much life I have sacrificed for my ''art''.
When your mother died, my success as a writer became more important to me.
I was secretly happy, even though I loved her in my confused way.
When I got sick, you went to Switzerland.
Because I couldn't bear the fact that you inherited her illness.
I had to finish writing my novel.
Is it any good?
It's like this, Karin...
You draw a magic circle around yourself...
to keep away anything that doesn't fit into his secret games.
When life breaks the circle, the games become puny and silly.
So you draw a new circle and build new protective walls.
Poor little daddy.
Poor little daddy who has to live in reality.
Come on, let's go home.
I have to pack.
-When will the helicopter arrive? - About an hour.
I just want to quickly change and pack.
I'll manage.
The light is so strong.
You have to help Minus with his Latin, Dad.
We still have to bring the keys to the house.
- Aren't you coming back? - No, I'm staying here.
That's the best, I think.
Now we haven't collected any mushrooms at all.
- Will you help me pack, Martin? - Of course.
Minus!
Minus, I want to talk to you!
Come here, Minus!
Your shirts are clean, but not ironed.
- I still have some in town. - Will you help me close it?
The shoes. I'll leave them here.
Put them on and leave the ones you're wearing here.
I'll take them to the shoemaker.
Do you have a headache pill?
- I thought my suitcase was here. - It's in the kitchen.
True.
- Have you seen Karin? - No.
Yes I understand.
I understand.
Yes this is good.
Yes I understand.
I know it won't be long now.
That is a great consolation.
But we waited with joy.
Shh, Martin! They say he'll be here any minute.
We must be ready.
- Come on, let's go into town. - I can't go now.
You're wrong, Karin.
Nothing is happening here.
Karin... No god will come through this door!
He'll appear any minute, so I have to be here!
Dearest Karin, that's not true!
Better leave if you can't keep quiet.
Come on now.
Go on, give me this moment!
Martin, darling...
I'm sorry I was so mean just now.
Will you kneel next to me and fold your hands?
It looks so weird and demonstrative when you sit there on that chair.
I know you don't believe it.
But do it for my sake, Martin.
Cooking,,,
My love!
My love... my love!
Hold her legs tight.
Calm down, Karin.
I was scared.
The door opened...
but the god was a spider.
He came towards me...
and I saw his face.
It was a terrible, stony face.
He climbed up me and tried to penetrate me...
but I resisted.
And the whole time I saw his eyes.
They were cold and quiet.
When he couldn't penetrate me...
he crawled further up my chest...
Over my face and onto the wall.
I have seen God.
Wait at the jetty, we'll be there as soon as possible.
They wait at the jetty.
Papa...
I'm scared, Dad!
As I sat in the wreckage, holding Karin in my arms, reality crumbled.
-Do you understand me? - I understand.
Reality shattered and I fell out.
It's like a dream...
Anything can happen.
Everything!
l know.
I cannot live in this new world.
Yes. But you need something to hold on to.
And what is that supposed to be? A god?
Prove to me that he exists!
- You can't. - Yes, you can.
But you have to listen carefully.
Yes. I have to listen.
I can only give you a glimpse of my own hope.
The knowledge that love exists in the human world.
- A special kind of love? - All kinds, minus.
The highest and the lowest, the silliest and the most sublime.
All kinds of love.
- The longing for love? - Longing and rejection.
Doubt and faith.
Then love is the proof?
I don't know if love is the proof of God or if it is God,
For you, love and God are one and the same?
This thought helps me recover from my emptiness and hopelessness.
Keep talking, Dad!
Suddenly the emptiness turns into fullness...
and hopelessness in life.
It's like a pardon, minus...
of a death sentence.
Dad, if it's as you say...
then Karin is surrounded by God because we love her.
Could this help her?
I think so.
Dad?
- Can I go for a run? - Go ahead. I'm making dinner.
See you in an hour.
Dad talked to me.