- Beautiful! - An ideal family portrait...
Please look into the camera.
Great! How about a smile?
Let's see some happy faces. You too, Mom... Great!
Take care of your hair! There we have it.
- That should be enough, right? - Yes, I think so.
- We're done with the girls. - You were so good!
- Bye! - You were as good as gold...
How about some shots of the parents on the sofa?
Lean forward, you're sliding too far back. That's it!
- I'll try to belittle myself. - Talk to each other.
Marianne, turn your gaze slightly toward us...
Looks like you guys like each other... I see.
Hold that pose! Great...
- That's it. Thank you very much. - Good!
We'll need some portraits later.
So, let's get started, shall we?
To calm nerves, I always start with a standard question.
- I'm not particularly nervous. - Good. The question is:
How would you describe yourself in a few words?
- That's not easy. - Not so difficult, is it?
- I might be misunderstood. - Really?
It may sound conceited when I say that I am highly intelligent, youthful,
successful, sensible, sexy and I care about the world we live in.
I'm educated, well-read, and a good mixer. Let's see...
I am even a good friend to people who are worse off than me.
I'm good at sports. I'm a good husband and a good son.
I have no debt and I pay my taxes.
I respect our government no matter what it does.
I love our royal family. I left the established church.
- Should I continue? - Please.
- I'm a great lover. - Maybe we can skip that question.
And you, Marianne?
Well, what can I say?
I am married to Johan and have two daughters…
- That's all I can think of... - Come on, think more carefully.
- I think Johan is terribly nice... - How kind of you.
- We've been married for 10 years. - We just renewed our contract.
Unlike Johan, I lack the ability to see myself in such glowing terms,
but honestly, I'm glad I can live the life I live.
It's a good life, if you know what I mean.
What else? My goodness, that's difficult...
- She has a beautiful figure. - I try to be serious.
- I have two girls, Karin and Eva. - You already said that.
How about some personal information? Let's start with your age.
- I'm 42, but I don't look it. - I'm 35.
We both come from obscenely middle-class families.
- Johan's father is a doctor. - And my mother is the maternal type.
My father is a lawyer.
It was clear from the beginning that I would also become a lawyer.
I am the youngest of seven children. My mother ran a large household.
- These days she's taking it easy. - Oh, is she?
Curiously, we get along with our parents and see each other often.
There were never any significant frictions.
Let's talk about your jobs.
Mine is a bit unusual.
I am an associate professor at the Institute of Psychotechnology.
Family law is my specialty. I am a member of a large law firm.
Most of my work deals with divorce, but the interesting thing is…
Hold this pose!
Take a photo, I want to capture this expression. Good!
- My goodness, I feel so... - It will pass.
- Tell me, how did you meet? - I'll leave that to Johan.
- Lord, that's interesting! - It wasn't love at first sight.
We both had a large circle of friends and often crossed paths.
We were both politically active for several years
and we did quite a lot of amateur theater as students.
Well, I can't say we made a deeper impression on each other.
Marianne thought I was arrogant.
Johan had a rather public affair with a pop singer…
...which gave him a certain image and made him unbearable.
Marianne war 19.
She was married to a fool whose only salvation was a rich father.
He was very nice and I was totally in love with him.
I also got pregnant early in the relationship.
- But how did it happen that... - that we both joined forces?
That was actually Marianne's idea.
My baby died shortly after birth
and my husband and I divorced, much to our mutual relief.
And Johan's singer had given him notice.
We were both a little hurt and lonely,
So I suggested giving it a try.
We weren't in love at all, but we were both depressed.
And then we realized that we understand each other very well
and we really focused on our studies.
We moved in together, a situation that our mothers actually took calmly.
In fact, they became good friends.
We were accepted as Johan and Marianne.
After six months we got married.
- At that point, we were already in love. - Very much so!
- We were considered the ideal couple. - And that's still the case.
- No complications? - We never had any material worries.
We are in good contact with friends and relatives on both sides.
We have good jobs that we enjoy. We're healthy.
And so on, to an almost vulgar extent. Security, order, loyalty...
We are almost indecently lucky.
Of course we have our differences, just like other people.
But we agree on all the important points.
- Do you never argue? - Marianne does.
Johan is very slow to anger, so I run out of steam.
That all sounds wonderful. All of it.
Just last night someone said
that the very absence of problems is a serious problem.
We are well aware that a life like ours can be dangerous.
What do you mean by dangerous?
The world is going to hell. I claim the right to mind my own business.
Live and let live, that is my motto.
It makes me sick to hear about the latest cure-all.
- I disagree with Johan. - So, what's your opinion?
- I believe in compassion. - Please explain.
If people have learned to care for each other in childhood,
the world would be a different place.
Hold this pose! Please look into the camera.
Listen to this:
“Marianne’s eyes, blue like an old folk song, shine from within.”
When asked how she manages to balance work and household,
she smiles with shy joy
"and replies that she and Johan help each other." - "That's true."
“We understand each other,” she says, “
brightens up as Johan sits down next to her on her heirloom sofa.
“He puts a protective arm around her and she snuggles up to him.”
- Hey! - This is the best!
"So I go and notice that they seem pleased with the prospect."
that they can be alone together again.
Two people who have matured: strong, happy and positive.
“People who never forgot to give love a place of honor.”
- We almost died when we read it. - I wanted to file a complaint.
But our mothers and daughters were simply thrilled with the article.
What really bothers me is that it doesn't say anything about my eyes.
- Isn't there a mysterious glow in them? - They're more like dark pools.
- Actually, very sexy. - Katarina has a crush on you.
- Johan, do you want to run away with me? - A change would do Johan good.
He was so good for 10 years and was never unfaithful.
Are you sure?
I believe everything Johan says.
- Did you hear that, Katarina? - Johan is a better liar than you.
- But I have no imagination. - That's it.
- It makes you a better liar. - Peter spices up his stories.
Sometimes I find it really touching.
I read your article in Technical Times. Even I could understand it.
- Actually, Katarina wrote it. - Are you that smart?
I was in Germany and they wanted an article immediately.
So Katarina wrote it and read it to me on the phone.
- But why was your name on it? - That's not discrimination.
- We work together. - That's admirable.
If you knew the details, you wouldn't say that.
Things are getting a bit dicey between us. Cheers, Katarina, my darling!
Silly...
Do you mind if I speak freely with Johan and Marianne?
- What's wrong, Katarina? - Nothing. Nothing at all.
Only Peter can be so damn clumsy sometimes.
Clumsy is the right word...
I pride myself on being clumsy... and resourceful.
The funny thing is that according to Katarina
I'm nothing more than a spineless jellyfish.
- Jellyfish? Now you're talking. - Let's try to have fun.
Exactly, because we must not forget...
I will now give a thank you speech.
In view of the fabulous magazine article
reminds us that we are in a happy home
that we must not pollute ourselves with emotional garbage.
Cheers, Marianne!
Perhaps I don't envy your domestic happiness...
...but I envy your cooking talent.
No, I really mean it.
I wish Katarina would learn to cook like that.
Katarina is a much better cook.
- Peter says I'm poisoning the food. - It's a running joke in our house.
- Right, it's obviously a joke. - One that's seen better days.
So, let's go into the living room and have some coffee.
So, Johan, what should I do?
I've put my foot in it again.
The girls will clear the table.
- This is all damn touching. - And what?
Your marriage.
Johan and Marianne...
It can move a person to tears.
In fact, you'd really like to stick a pin into the beautiful balloon.
- Would you do that too? - Cheers to you both!
- It's been 10 years, right? - We just had our 10th anniversary.
- No skeletons in the closet? - You never know.
- Both Johan and I like to tidy up. - Can you hear that, Katarina?
This is where you and I have been negligent... We never clean up.
But next week I will call Marianne and make an appointment,
so she can begin our divorce.
By the time Peter sobers up, he will have changed his mind.
Then the computer starts running.
"He says, 'I agree to the divorce.'"
“if Katarina gives up her claim to our assets in Switzerland.”
And my answer is: “But it’s my money, I earned it.”
Then Peter will say that he has multiplied it
and I can have the whole factory.
Then I say, that’s nice of you to give me a factory in Italy –
This becomes riskier with every increase in labor costs.
“- But Katarina, I said... – “Take the whole facility in Sweden.”
The apartment, the country house, the boat, the car,
“The stocks and the premium bonds.” Isn’t that nice?”
I get all taxable items!
Excuse me for talking about such trivial things,
but when Peter starts talking about the fortune, I know how drunk he is.
- And the insults aren't far-fetched. - That's what I've been saying all along.
Katarina is a businesswoman, with equal emphasis on both words.
A businessman...
In addition, she is a brilliant artist
and she has an IQ of I don't know what.
She is also attractive.
It is a model example and is wrapped like a gift.
How I ever had any luck with this monster of perfection is a mystery to me.
I really think we should call a taxi and go home now.
This can’t be pleasant for Johan and Marianne…
No... Johan and Marianne?
These are candy figures decorated with red ribbons.
Just like the marzipan pigs of our childhood.
It is good for their morale,
to look into the bottomless abyss of hell.
August Strindberg
once wrote:
“Is there anything more frightening?”
"as a man and a woman who hate each other?"
What do you think? Maybe child abuse is even worse.
But Katarina and I are children.
Deep down, Katarina is a little girl who cries
because she fell down
and no one comforts her.
And I haven't grown up either.
I cry because Katarina can’t love me,
despite my bad behavior.
There is one thing to be thankful for.
That there is nothing more hellish than this.
That's why we are ready for a divorce.
Provided you listen to reason.
Provided that we simultaneously,
in the presence of the other
and sign all papers in front of trustworthy witnesses.
This way, no one can rip off the other.
- We'll call you this week. - We have a great business lawyer.
Borglund can help you with financial arrangements.
What do you say?
Even if we agree on money matters, you will never let me go.
I am convinced of that.
You think you're so damn indispensable, my dear Katarina?
How did you come up with this idea?
Tell me... Tell us.
You force me to have sex,
because you can't get an erection with other women.
Their need for a guilty conscience knows no bounds.
Now that everything is over with Jan, you're probably panicking.
You're stuck with old Peter.
He has the right patience.
So you think you're the only one, right?
How touching...
They think there are no others.
Let me tell you one thing, Peter...
Please excuse me if I am a bit blunt.
but Peter demands it and he needs to be enlightened.
I'll tell you this, Peter...
You make me so sick...
..in the physical sense...
that I would buy a fuck just to wash you out of my genitals.
“Stay with me, evening is coming quickly”
“The darkness deepens, Lord, stay with me…”
You bastard!
“When other helpers fail and comfort disappears”
“Help the helpless, oh, stay with me.”
Whatever that means...
I hope there are no stains on the carpet.
I don't know anything about liqueur...
Why don't you send me an invoice?
Do what I say!
Would you mind pouring me a cup of coffee?
I'm pretty drunk.
Forgive us. We don't usually behave like this.
But you are our best friends.
You are our only friends.
Forgive me... forgive us.
If you call for a taxi,
I will take my Bacchante home
and we end our little scene.
The finale is usually not suitable for audiences.
- What time is it? - Ten past twelve.
- Thank God we got rid of them. - Yes, things got a little out of control.
Do you think it is possible for a couple to be partners for life?
It is an absurd convention.
The marriage was supposed to be a five-year contract.
- Or subject to annual renewal. - What about us?
No, we are the exception that proves the rule.
- So you think we'll stay together? - What a strange question.
Do you sometimes feel sorry that you can't sleep with anyone else?
- No, right? - Sometimes.
- Well, the devil take me! - It's a purely theoretical longing.
I wonder if there's something wrong with me, I never feel like that.
- I'm happy. - Me too. Now I have it!
Katarina and Peter are going through hell because they don't communicate with each other.
They have to translate everything they mean into a common language.
- I think it's easier than that. - We understand each other immediately.
We speak the same language, that's why we're doing well.
I think it's about money.
If you speak the same language, money doesn't matter.
- You and your languages. - I see this all the time at work.
Sometimes it is as if the couple
talk about bad phone lines.
Sometimes it is like listening to two pre-programmed tape recorders
and sometimes it is the absolute silence of space.
- I don't know what the worst part is. - I don't know...
Suppose the children went to daycare while we worked shifts in a factory?
- It wouldn't matter. - I think so.
If you speak the same language, it doesn't matter where you are.
That's a romantic view.
Do you think our relationship would suffer if we lived that kind of life?
- Yes, I do. Seriously. - It would damage our relationship?
“Regardless of our “language”.
Isn't the danger of alienation in our lives just as great?
Definitely not.
Hard and arduous work places a much greater strain on people.
You are dumber than I thought, and you represent the romantic point of view.
- We'll see. - What? What will we see?
- I don't know, do you? - Are you kidding me?
- Aren't you hungry? - Yes, terrible.
How about beer and sandwiches?
Sounds wonderful.
The art of sweeping things under the carpet
- Good morning. - Good morning.
- Did you sleep well? - Like a marmot and you?
So, I woke up at 5 a.m. and couldn't go back to sleep.
- Why not? - I was very excited.
- Should I feel guilty? - No.
For once, it's not your fault, dear.
I lay there angry, thinking about that miserable Sunday dinner.
We always have dinner with your or my parents on Sundays.
- That's absurd. - It's because of her.
- I'm going to cancel dinner. - Cancel?
-What will your mother say? - Whatever she damn well pleases.
I want to spend Sunday with you and the children.
- Well, if you can manage it...! - I certainly can!
I'm fed up...
- Is it the curse? - That's what you always say!
Even though my period is due on Monday, that might not be the reason I'm nervous.
- What's going on? - Have you ever noticed
that our lives are predetermined and every single second is taken into account?
- But we have our vacation. - It's even better planned.
- Don't you want to wake the girls? - They're sleeping in today.
Karin has a day off school and Eva has a sore throat.
She has to come with us on Sunday so we don't have to complain!
- You wanted to cancel dinner. - I'd rather you did.
Oh no, I don't want to give your mother any excuses!
Why don't you call your mother? She's an early riser.
- Didn't we agree that you would call? - No, dear.
I will support you morally.
All right, I'll do it...
- My goodness, my heart is pounding! - The first sign of the great revolt.
No answer? What a relief!
Hello. Miss Alm? Is my mother here?
Can I speak to her briefly?
By the way, how is your knee?
Oh, it's not better?
Is it worse? That's too bad... What does the doctor say?
He's not likeable, you say? That's a sign of the times.
Hello, mother. How are you?
Isn't that beautiful? Is Dad already gone?
Right, he wanted to go to the countryside.
So you just let him go off on his own?
Oh, Erik is with him. That's good.
I'm sorry, but I have to tell you something...
Exactly, how did you guess?
What reasons do we have?
I just want to spend Sunday with Johan and the girls.
No, we're not going anywhere.
We just don't want to come over for dinner.
I don't think Dad was looking forward to Sunday for a second.
It should be a pleasure and not a chore, right?
Yes, I understand. I understand.
You didn't tell me this news.
To be honest, I'm bored to death.
No, forget it altogether, Mother.
We will be there.
Yes, we can do this. It's okay.
We are looking forward to it.
Bye for now, dear mother.
The revolution was nipped in the bud.
Aunt Elsa is coming
and she was so excited to see us.
- She has a present for you. - And Mrs. Danielsson is cooking.
- And your father really wanted to see us. - Damn!
I still admire your courage. We'll say no another time.
Don't be upset.
- Are you home for dinner? - No, we're meeting at the theater.
Don't you enjoy coming home anymore?
My goodness, aren't we in a good mood today?
I would like to stay in bed for a week,
so we can just hug each other.
- And we would both cry heartily. - This is not the life we chose.
If only I could be sure that we chose it and not our mothers.
They suffer from maternal paranoia.
- Did you want a life like that? - No.
What if we started cheating on each other?
What would you do then?
Kill you, of course.
- Sometimes I wish... - What?
Nothing...
- Wait a second, I'm coming with you. - Why don't you take your own car?
We can go home together after the play.
- What about the girls? - I'll ask Miss Andersson to cook.
She makes fabulous pancakes. I'll wake the girls up.
- But I'm in a hurry. - It'll only take a minute.
As long as I remember, please pay your parking tickets.
- Here's a whole stack. - Yes, sir.
See you tonight at the theater.
Hello? Yes, I speak.
Hello, Mom. The line is bad, I didn't recognize your voice.
I'm fine how are you?
You're worried. Why is that?
Marianne's mother called
and she is worried too, you say.
Good God...
No, Marianne and I are fine.
We are healthy and happy
and overjoyed.
There's nothing wrong, I swear!
Don't worry, dear mother.
Your intuition has led you astray.
Marianne and I are happier than ever.
Marianne's Mother's Case
that you should do something more constructive than gossip.
I'm under time pressure, dear mother.
Yes, see you soon.
As I said, we'll be over on Friday. Say hello to Dad.
Hell and damnation!
Am I disturbing you?
I just had to see what you were up to. There are a lot of rumors circulating.
What is this mysterious stuff?
- Shouldn't you be in Lund? - That's right.
However, the students are demonstrating.
The lectures were cancelled.
- What will that be? - Look.
- What should I do? - Hold this pen.
When I turn off the light, you see a bright spot on the wall.
Try touching it with the pen.
If you're wrong, draw a line there.
The TV camera will record your efforts.
- But it's dark. - There's infrared light.
I'll be watching on the monitor outside.
I'm turning off the light now.
Let's go.
Get to work.
- Are you kidding me? - No, please continue.
But... it keeps moving.
This is not a trick, it is completely silent.
I've had enough of this. Turn on the light.
Well, aren't you angry?
- That was uncomfortable... - Yes, it makes people nervous.
See how you have been wandering around and becoming more and more irritable.
- What does this prove? - That remains to be seen.
- I'd like a cigarette. - Sure. Take a seat.
I quit smoking six days ago. It's terrible.
- Withdrawal symptoms? - Stefan is gone...
My friends avoid me,
but I will try to hold on.
Go on, take one.
That spy Bromeus left some here.
Oh, this is heaven!
- Lord, what bliss! - And?
Right...
I spent the whole day yesterday reading your poems. Very thoughtful.
- They amazed me. - Were they that strange?
That's not it.
Well, I could be wrong...
- Has Marianne read it? - No, she's not interested in poetry.
- She should be interested in you. - She is, but not like this.
Really?
You and I are old friends.
We never had a sexual relationship.
You can give an objective opinion before I try the editors.
- I shouldn't bother. - Are they that bad?
It's not that they're bad...
..if only that were the case.
You mean they're mediocre?
Are you boring, tidy and childish?
That I indulge in spiritual masturbation?
Some of us on our team believed you were destined for greatness.
We admired you.
You left us all behind.
We even envied you.
- Does that influence my poetry? - No.
- You read it while craving nicotine. - That's right...
I plan to show them everything.
Naturally...
I'm waiting for some publishers to tell me they're bad.
- You feel insulted. - You bet!
I'm sorry.
Well, I know someone who likes her...
- Who would that be? - Curious, aren't you?
My dear little Johan...
Don't pay attention to what I said.
It was simply my desire to talk.
Well, I have to go.
I'll leave the poems on your doorstep. Give Marianne my regards.
I will stick by you through thick and thin.
Bye!
See you around 12:30. Bye.
I'm sorry I kept you waiting.
It is usually during this first encounter that we identify the problem.
I want a divorce.
- How long have you been married? - More than 20 years.
- Do you have a job? - No, I'm a housewife.
Why do you want a divorce?
It is a loveless marriage.
- Is that your reason? - Yes.
- Has it always been like this? - Yes, for the entire 20 years.
But now you want to break free.
Yes.
My husband is a responsible man. He is kind and conscientious.
He was an excellent father. We never argued.
We have a beautiful apartment and a house in the countryside.
We are both passionate about music.
We belong to a chamber music society.
- That all sounds ideal. - Yes, doesn't it?
But there is no love between us, there never has been.
Forgive me for asking, but have you met anyone?
No I haven't.
What about your husband?
Not as far as I know.
Won't it be lonely for you?
I think so...
But that's better
than living in a loveless marriage.
Have you informed your husband about this?
Naturally.
15 years ago I told him
I didn't want to live with him.
He asked me to wait
until the children grew up.
Now that they have left their homes,
I can get a divorce.
And what does he say?
He constantly asks me what's wrong with our marriage.
I tell him I can't go on
in a relationship that lacks love.
Then he asks what this love should consist of.
But I can't describe it
something that doesn't exist.
Did you get along well with your children?
I never loved my children.
I know that now...
I used to think I had that. People do.
But I know now
that I never loved her.
Nevertheless, I was a good mother to her.
I did everything I could, although
I never felt anything for her.
I know exactly what you’re thinking:
“She was spoiled and has no sense of humor.”
She has everything she could ever wish for,
but she still complains about love.
There are other qualities:
“Friendship, loyalty, security…”
Something like that, yes.
Let me tell you something.
I have a mental image of myself,
which does not correspond to reality.
Forgive me for a personal question...
Isn't it true that love...
What did you want to ask?
I'm not sure. Forgive me.
I have the ability to love.
But it was all... bottled.
The life I've been living has stifled my potential.
It's time to change that.
The first step is divorce.
My husband and I
block each other in a deadly way.
That sounds scary.
It's scary.
Something strange happens.
My senses, sight, hearing, touch
are starting to let me down.
This table for example
I can see and touch it...
But the sensation
is reduced and dry.
Do you understand?
I think so.
It's the same with everything -
Music, scents, faces and voices.
Everything seems...
puny, grey and undignified.
Now there is something to drink and eat.
Sitting on an empty stomach is fatal.
Do you remember when we participated in the May Day procession?
You were the more ardent believer.
You told me I neglected our home.
That was the winter we all got sick from the Asian flu.
- Back then, we believed in the future. - It's nice to believe in something.
And we had the pleasure of annoying our parents.
- You were a hothead. - So was your father.
Quite a hothead. As a socialist, you were very attractive.
Am I not very attractive now?
But married people lose interest in each other.
We don't have that.
We simply have too much to do and are completely exhausted in the evenings.
That wasn't an accusation, I promise.
- We like each other. - Not like that.
- Oh yes, we do. - Our lives are full of excuses.
It's not my fault that I don't enjoy it as much as I used to.
There's a natural explanation. You shouldn't blame me.
- Don't get upset. - We have a great sex life.
We're not as passionate these days, but it could be worse.
Sex isn't everything.
If you are not satisfied, find a lover
who is more sexually exciting.
- I assure you, I'll do my best! - Right...
You have that look again.
Tell me what you're thinking about.
- You're just getting angry. - No, I'm listening.
Why make sex so complicated?
It's pretty basic stuff.
It has become a sore point.
It's all your mother's fault.
- You're so superficial. - You're a grump!
You blame me for everything.
- You said you'd do your best. - I am!
This is absurd!
Are you calling me a liar?
Then what are you talking about?
Let's leave that and go to bed.
It's typical of you to upset me so
and then yawn and say it's bedtime.
They suffer from unbridled ambition.
We often joke about
but can't our miserable sex life be spared?
Why don't you leave me alone?
First you attack me because I don't try
and later for the effort.
And now look what I did!
Yes, you actually did.
Couldn't you be kind instead?
Well, well... Don't be sad. I'm sorry.
You know, you can talk too much about these things.
I know you shouldn’t keep secrets,
but in this case the rule is wrong.
There are some things you shouldn't snoop into.
We hurt each other endlessly
and the barbs are still there when we go to bed.
It's like lying on a bed of nails.
- What are you laughing about? - The nail bed.
- Laughter is all well and good. - Let's go to bed.
They were incredibly tactless.
I apologize.
Don't I give you enough affection?
Affection takes time.
- Then you're not getting enough. - We're not getting enough, and we're not giving enough either.
That's why I wanted us to go away this summer.
Affection should not be saved for vacation.
You're nice even if you're an idiot.
Luckily, I'm married to you.
You're mediocre, but you have your moments of greatness.
At our age, thousands of brain cells burn out every day.
- Never to be replaced... - You must lose a million!
You're incredibly sweet anyway, even when you swear and make a fuss.
I've almost fallen asleep.
- I'm just checking on the kids. - I'm almost asleep, so don't worry.
Don't you want to set the alarm?
If you want, you can sleep with me now.
Thanks for the offer, but I'm too tired.
Already here? I wasn't expecting you until tomorrow.
What a nice surprise! Are you hungry?
We all went to bed early.
We thought we'd go to bed early. The girls and I were on a diet.
- Would you like some sandwiches? - Sounds good to me.
Or should I fry you some eggs and ham or make you some soup?
No, sandwiches and beer are perfectly sufficient.
By the way, Peter and Katarina will call you on Monday.
What an ordeal they are going through!
They don't seem to be able to agree on their divorce.
I told them they should each get a lawyer, but they don't want to.
Listen, put on your pajamas and I'll bring in a tray.
Sounds good...
I was afraid you would be angry with me.
- Why should I? - I was horrible on the phone.
I called back, but you had pulled the plug.
I was tired last night.
I was with that idiot from the ministry.
These bureaucratic idiots who are responsible for our well-being...
- I still think I behaved badly. - Let's drop the subject.
You never want to stop talking,
but that won't last long, dear.
I just wanted to say that you were right, but so was I.
If you don't want to wear a tuxedo, that's your business.
- But I have a right to my own opinion. - I hate wearing a tuxedo.
It's a ridiculous outfit. I feel like a chimpanzee in disguise.
Let's not start arguing.
Tuxedo or not, I love you.
A tuxedo is hardly necessary for our marriage.
- That's how it seemed to me last night. - I said I was wrong.
When I watch you eat, I get hungry...
I need a sandwich.
I'm so hungry, I feel dizzy.
I've lost almost two kilos this week. Is it noticeable?
However, I can feel it.
But sometimes it seems pointless...
Why should we deny ourselves the good things in life?
Why can't we be fat and happy?
Do you remember Aunt Miriam and Uncle David?
They were tall, fat and cheerful.
They slept holding hands in their double bed.
Happy with each other, just as they were.
Why can’t we be like them,
full of satisfaction?
What's up?
Are you angry?
Something happened?
What's up?
Tell me.
I came here to tell you something.
I went there and fell in love.
It's pretty absurd and probably completely wrong...
I met her at this conference in June.
She was an interpreter.
She studies Slavic studies.
She's not particularly nice to look at.
You might even find them ugly.
I have no idea what this will lead to.
I don't know anything. I'm confused.
On a certain level I am happy
but I feel so guilty towards you and the girls.
We always got along so well.
Things were neither better nor worse
than in most families.
Say something, for heaven's sake.
I don't know what to say.
It was wrong not to tell you sooner,
but I thought I would get over it.
I didn't mean to alarm you.
It's funny...
...that I didn't notice anything.
Everything was as usual.
In fact, even better.
You were so sweet.
I was a stupid, blind fool.
I didn't understand...
- How humiliating. - No, you didn't understand anything.
You have never been particularly attentive.
- What happens next? - I don't know.
Do you want a divorce?
Will you marry her?
Why are you telling me now? What's the rush?
We're going to Paris tomorrow.
I want to escape it all.
I wanted to go there this fall anyway.
Paula has this scholarship...
..and I want to be with her.
I can't do it without her.
So we're leaving tomorrow.
Now that I'm talking to you,
I want to get rid of the whole damn thing.
I am tired and scared.
Nothing could be more ridiculous.
I know exactly what you're thinking.
How can you know that?
I try not to feel guilty, which is quite a burden for me.
Facts are facts, there's nothing you can do about them.
Let's go to bed. I suppose you have to get up early.
I have a meeting at nine.
Then we should get some sleep.
Won't you take your clothes off?
You have spots on your chest.
How tactless of you.
Is my gray suit here or in town?
- It's at the dry cleaners. - What a shame.
Did you want to bring it?
Can't you pick it up?
I won't have time.
I'm busy until 3 p.m.
I can pick it up for you.
I'll also do the packing for you. You're not good at that sort of thing.
- No, thank you. - Don't be silly...
I'm a bit conventional.
I think you have everything you need here.
There are clean shirts and underwear.
Why not travel in a jacket and flannel?
- They give you a youthful look. - Whatever you say...
- How long will you be gone? - That depends.
What do you mean?
I took at least six months of vacation.
I'll probably be away for at least seven or eight months.
I want to make a clean break.
- And if I'm not here? - I don't care at all.
Do you know how long I've wanted to leave?
How long have I been thinking about leaving you?
- Don't tell me! - Four years!
- I can't stand this! - Empty words...
What will you live on?
You have to pay child support.
Don't worry, I'll manage.
You must have assets that I know nothing about.
That's right, Marianne.
- How is that possible? - Listen, damn it!
Even if it's none of your damn business,
I sold the boat
and I took out a loan.
The bank pays you and the girls 1,600 kroner per month.
We'll arrange something else when I get back.
Get advice from your colleagues, I don't care.
Name your price!
I'm taking nothing with me except my books.
I'll just disappear.
I will dematerialize myself.
I will pay whatever I can to support you.
I'm only interested in putting an end to this.
Do you know what annoys me the most?
All this fuss about what is expected of us
and the people we have to accommodate.
What will your mother think?
Shouldn't we invite so-and-so to dinner?
We have to go here, we have to go there...
We have to celebrate Christmas, Easter, birthdays...
Every single damn opportunity!
- My poor darling... - I don't want your pity!
Stop groping me!
It's pure affectation that I keep walking like this.
I can't get to the truth about us.
There is no one truth.
Wherever we turn, it hurts.
Please don't go!
- I beg you. - It's no use.
Postpone your trip. I think we can save our marriage.
We could make a fresh start. You have to give me a chance!
Maybe Paula would understand me.
I should meet her and talk to her...
Let's tackle this together. Give me a chance!
You are presenting me with a fait accompli.
They are forcing me into an unbearable situation.
They think: What will our parents say!
What will our friends think? Jesus, how tongues will wag!
What impact will it have on the girls?
What about the dinner parties?
What will you tell Peter and Katarina? Who cares?
It feels good to be a villain!
That's not what I meant.
Forget it...
I forgot to set the alarm.
- What time do you have to leave? - Please set it for 5:30 a.m.
I have to pack and have a conference at nine.
I've been wanting to get a new alarm clock for a long time.
This one is so loud and not very reliable.
There it is set to 5:30 am.
I'll wake up on my own anyway, so you don't have to worry.
- Tell me about Paula. - Please... What's going on?
- Why are you torturing yourself? - I want to know what she's like.
It is much worse to imagine a faceless threat.
- Do you have a picture of her? - Can't we be spared this torture?
Please help me with this.
Well, you asked for it...
Where's my wallet? I guess it's in my jacket...
Here are two photos.
This was taken two years ago on vacation.
This is her passport photo. It looks good.
She has a beautiful figure.
- And nice breasts, right? - Yes, she does...
- Does she dye her hair? - That's possible.
- She has a beautiful smile. How old is she? - 23.
She had no luck in love.
She was engaged twice
and had many affairs.
- Does that bother you? - Yes, it does...
Her openness is quite uncomfortable.
She insists on telling me details about her erotic past.
I suffer from retrospective jealousy.
She has no illusions
and she doesn't have high hopes for either of us.
She knows I'll come back to you.
This all sounds like a tired old melodrama.
Are you compatible in bed?
Yes, we actually are.
At first everything was wrong.
I wasn't used to it—to being with other women, I mean.
We spoiled each other, you and I, and we lived in our own bubble.
Everything went like clockwork.
- The lack of oxygen suffocated us. - And Paula will revive you?
I have little self-confidence.
I know little about reality, despite all the books I have read,
but this could be an opportunity for you and me to truly live.
Did Paula put such nonsense into your head?
- How naive can one be? - We can do without your taunts.
- Forgive me. - I'm trying...
I'm trying to be honest, and it's not easy!
We've never talked like this before.
Is it any wonder we are naive?
What else can we expect?
You're in a bind.
Come and lie down next to me.
Come...
I want you to sleep with me.
Please?
For old times' sake.
Lie here in my arms
and we both go to sleep together.
I don't think I can sleep.
I'd better go right away.
Close your eyes.
We both need the rest.
Tomorrow will be a busy day.
I'm so damn ashamed.
We'll talk about that later.
At the moment there are only two of us.
We still have a few hours left.
Just you and me...
- Do you want to pack or eat first? - You decide.
- Tea or coffee? - Tea, please.
- What about your mail? - I'll send you my address.
You can forward the letters and pay the bills as usual.
The plumber should come to fix the bathroom.
Should I call him?
I thought you might have forgotten.
I called him dozens of times and I haven't forgotten.
What about your car?
I asked Paula's sister to take care of it.
She needs a car.
I understand.
would you mind
cancel my dentist appointment?
Your father's birthday is on Friday, we want to eat there.
Do you plan to call him?
This is difficult...
Maybe I can write him a letter.
As long as you don't forget.
Dealing with our parents becomes difficult.
- What should I tell the girls? - Say what you want.
- That you left us? - You couldn't have put it better.
I don't expect you to understand me.
I have to go now to avoid the traffic.
Goodbye, Marianne. Take care.
- Maybe I'll be home in a week. - I wish...
We would make a fresh start.
We would throw old, established routines overboard.
We would talk about the past.
We would try to figure out where we went wrong.
You would never hear me blame you.
Johan, it's all so unreal...
I don't know what to do.
You're excluding me.
Any solution would be better than this.
Couldn't you promise me you'd come back? Then at least I'd have something.
You can't leave me without hope.
Even if you don't plan on coming back, tell me you will.
I have to go now.
Fredrik? It's Marianne. Sorry to wake you.
Is Birgit here? No, let her sleep.
So, how are you?
Oh, you're an early riser, aren't you? I won't keep you long.
It's cloudy... That sounds nice.
I need to talk to you about something.
I really need to talk...
You and Birgit are friends of ours.
I have to...
It's all so unreal, Fredrik.
You see...
I'm close to tears
and crying only makes everything worse.
Johan has fallen in love with another woman.
They are leaving for Paris today.
Couldn't you talk to him?
Tell him not to do anything rash.
Have you spoken to him yet?
I understand...
So you both always knew?
You knew, but never told me?
And you call yourselves friends?
How could you be so disloyal?
I don't believe your explanations!
All the times we met
and none of you said a word...
Damned!
What kind of friends are you?
To hell with your explanations!
How many others did you know?
Oh, lots of people...
Well, isn't that nice!
THE VALLEY OF TEARS
Please come in.
My goodness, you're pretty! What a beautiful blouse.
I liked it when I bought it, but it's kind of girly.
It suits you.
I feel nervous standing here like this.
Me too, I was useless all day.
I know it's silly, but I haven't seen you in over six months.
- How come you suddenly...? - Paula is in London.
- Would you like something to drink? - Yes, please.
Ein Whisky, pur.
It soothes the stomach.
Have you ever drunk whiskey?
Aunt Berit takes care of the girls, much to everyone’s delight.
Tomorrow they are going to the countryside.
Well... meeting them might have been unpleasant.
- How are you? - Don't just ask out of politeness.
Please don't forget your birthdays again.
I bought them gifts from you, but that didn't deceive them.
Can't you take her to the movies one day?
It's hard for them not to hear from you.
Nowadays they hardly mention you anymore.
- The way Paula holds you... - If you start ranting, I'll leave.
You yourself said that she is jealous.
Are you such a coward that you can't stand up to her?
I'm sorry.
I know you think it's absurd,
But don't scold me, it won't help.
- Would you like some more whiskey? - Yes, please.
- How are you, Johan? - Pretty much the same as always.
- And you? - I can't complain.
It was stupid of me to suggest that.
We can't talk without hurting each other.
I have an excellent suggestion: Let's have dinner.
- Then we won't run into each other. - An excellent suggestion.
You look terrible with this haircut
and you have gained weight.
You really turn me on.
- What should we do about it? - We'll see after dinner.
- What a delicious wine! - It's just a cheap red wine.
Things are going well for me at the moment.
I was offered a professorship at Cleveland University.
It's a good move both financially and career-wise.
Something is happening
and I would like to emigrate, nothing is keeping me here.
I'm fed up with this dump
and I hate being ripped off with taxes.
So I'll be leaving in the spring if all goes well.
Congratulations.
I talk a lot about myself, but I'm in such a good mood.
Maybe we can talk about our divorce.
If you are going to emigrate, we should do it now.
- As you wish. - I want a divorce.
I might want to remarry, and if you're in the US, that would be complicated.
Do you have someone in mind?
Perhaps.
Come on, tell me more.
- Would you like anything else? - No, thank you. Don't be evasive.
How are you?
Judging by your appearance,
they must be pretty good.
Do you have a lover?
I'll just quickly get the coffee.
Also...
It sounds like you are disappointed.
It's just your imagination.
I think about you all the time.
I wonder if you are okay or if you are lonely and scared.
Every day, several times a day,
I wonder what I did to cause the rift between us.
I know it's childish of me.
What did i do wrong?
Why don't you ask a psychiatrist?
I go to one several times a week.
- Sometimes we even meet privately. - Is he your lover?
We had sex a few times, but it wasn't good.
So let's dedicate ourselves to my soul.
Where did that get you?
Nowhere.
Basically, I'm learning to speak.
I threw your things out of the study and brought mine in.
I felt guilty, but also brave.
At least it led to something.
- What a massive yawn. - Sorry, it's the wine.
Also, I didn't sleep well and was tense.
- If you want to go home... - Don't get so upset.
- You can take a nap if you want. - What a fuss about a yawn.
I would rather listen to stories about your spiritual journey.
There isn't much to tell.
But last night I noticed something strange.
That sounds exciting.
My therapist asked me to write down everything that came to mind.
No matter how irrelevant. Everything...
I haven't written much so far; I'm not used to writing.
It often seems stilted and a little silly.
Why don't you read me what you wrote last night?
Do you really want to hear it?
I'll just quickly go and get my notebook.
I was up until three in the morning writing,
So I looked like a wreck this morning.
It's clear that this would happen the night before our meeting.
You look so pretty... so beautiful, Marianne.
No compliments, please. Instead, show interest in my soul.
Go and sit down...
Take a seat...
Not...
Let me read to you.
One good thing does not have to exclude another.
I think of you all the time,
about having sex with you.
I have longed for you.
But after you left,
I would long for you again.
I love you, don't you realize that?
Sometimes I hate you for what you did to me.
I rejoice in every hour that passes without thinking of you.
I have friends, lovers, children
and a job that I enjoy and am good at.
And yet I am bound to you.
I don't know why.
Maybe I'm a masochist,
or I'm just a one-man woman.
I don't know...
It's all so difficult.
I don't want to live with anyone other than you.
Other men bore me.
I'm not trying to make you feel guilty,
or use emotional blackmail.
I'm just telling you how I feel.
I can't stand it when you sleep with me.
I can't explain it any other way.
It's because you're going to leave
and I will long for you.
I kind of enjoyed having you at a distance.
So let's keep our hands to ourselves.
You'll just leave me devastated.
I... I'm still in love with you.
Why say that if it is not true?
Do you think I didn't miss you?
I have... We were friends.
We had fun together.
If we want to have sex, why shouldn't we do it?
Why are there all these reservations?
Why worry about how you'll feel tomorrow?
No, Johan...
I want you to stop!
I don't want to brood, pine, and cry about you!
If you insist, you can just leave.
I don't want to sleep with you.
Please try to understand this!
I do my best ...
Okay, I'll sit here...
I'm sitting here and you can read to me.
Then I go home, call Paula and tell her that I was at the theater.
Can I have another coffee and a brandy, please?
I feel like a terrible idiot.
I want to hide somewhere and cry.
- We can meet tomorrow instead. - Yes, that might be just as good.
No, it's better if you stay...
I'm busy tomorrow.
Hello...
I like you so much.
I behave like a child.
The situation is under control.
We have overcome the crisis.
I can barely read my own writing.
The beginning is not important...
“Yesterday I was overcome by a carefree cheerfulness.”
For the first time this year, I felt joy in life.
“I’m excited to see what the day will bring.”
And so forth...
Here it is:
“I turned around and looked at the photo of my class at school.”
taken when I was 10.
I seemed to discover something I had missed before.
To my surprise, I have to admit,
I don't know who I am.
Not at all...
I always did what I was told.
As far as I can remember,
I was obedient, balanced, almost gentle.
I have asserted myself as a girl once or twice,
but Mother punished all such violations of the Convention
with exemplary rigor.
My entire upbringing
aimed to make me agreeable.
I was ugly and clumsy.
A fact I was constantly reminded of.
But if I kept my thoughts to myself
and was ingratiating,
my behavior was rewarded.
The actual deception began in puberty.
All my thoughts revolved around sex.
But I never told my parents that,
or anyone for that matter.
Be deceitful and mysterious
has become second nature to me.
My father wanted me to become a lawyer like him.
I said I wanted to be an actress,
or do something else in the theatre world,
but they laughed at me.
Since then I've been pretending.
A deception in my relationships with others.
For men.
The same deception -
a desperate attempt to please.
I never thought about what I wanted.
Only: “What does he want me to think?”
It is not selflessness, as I always believed,
but pure cowardice.
It comes from the fact that I don't know who I am.
Our mistake was that we did not break away from our families.
“and to create something valuable according to our own ideas.”
Oh damn, I fell asleep!
Your words were also very interesting. Forgive me...
Would you rather not read on unless you feel offended?
I'm not offended, but I think you should go home now.
Yes, I'd better go.
Please call, if only for the sake of the children.
- You're always welcome here. - If only Paula wasn't so jealous.
Nevertheless, she has good reasons …
- When will you hear about the USA? - In about a month.
- Let me know how it went. - Of course I'll call you.
We need to be clear about the divorce.
- Do you want to get married again? - I don't know.
I'd rather wait, what do you think?
I don't know what to think...
- You're staying overnight, aren't you? - Yes.
- How are you feeling? - Anxious...
Let us gather our courage.
- Can't you sleep? - No chance.
I'd better go home. Forgive me!
- That's Paula's handwriting. - She wrote to me.
- What's she up to now? - She sent this before she left.
Read it here.
“Dear Marianne, I assure you”
that there are no ulterior motives behind this letter.
I accepted this job in London
to break a vicious cycle of jealousy and mistrust.
I know Johan will visit you as soon as I'm gone.
I can only blame myself for preventing him from seeing all of you.
“If only it were possible to put things right.”
- How typical Paula! - She wants us to be friends.
- She can't stand hostility. - How touching. And you believe her?
“Johan is the gentlest and kindest person I have ever met.”
He lacks self-confidence,
"even though he tries to seem so brave and cheerful."
You can say anything about anyone. In a certain sense, it always fits.
THE ANALPHITIZED
I'm glad we were able to meet here. It saves time.
- It's not exactly comfortable. - But suitable for divorce cases.
Here is the agreement, word for word, as we decided on it.
- Then I don't have to read it. - Always read before signing.
- Don't look so grumpy. - I'm not grumpy.
Here is the list of our common property and its distribution.
This is just a list; no signature is required.
You got Grandma's watch? There must be a mistake.
- But she left it to me. - I don't remember that.
If you're so attached to it, keep it, but it's mine.
You're always right, aren't you? Take the damn watch!
- Check if I haven't duped you. - Your sarcasm is wasted on me.
I have such a bad cold.
How about a glass of fine old brandy?
Yes, I think we should have one now.
Egerman gave me a bottle.
A few grateful Parisian colleagues gave him a whole case. Cheers!
Not bad, right? I like it.
I don't usually like brandy, but this is good.
I already feel better.
It's still hard.
- Get divorced. - It's just paperwork.
We have been living apart for ages and we agree,
but the guilt remains.
It's strange... Johan?
- What? - It's strange.
On the way there, I was determined not to cry.
You said you felt guilty.
Let's go to the couch instead.
Turn off the light, the bright glare is horrible.
How can you work in such a desolate space?
The sofa isn't very comfortable either.
If you put your feet up, it's okay.
- More brandy? - Yes, please.
- Comfortable? - Very.
- Is the whole place empty? - There's a night watchman.
How nice!
- I just think it's nice. - Nothing's nice when you have a cold.
Stop feeling sorry for yourself. You're not going to die. Cheers!
- This just keeps getting better. - Aren't you in a good mood?
Honestly, I'm in love.
- With this David? - No, that's over.
Give me a kiss.
- But I'm sick. - I'll never catch your germs.
Give me a kiss, I want you to.
- Was it what you expected? - Much better.
Now put your hand on my chest.
- Are you seducing me? - That's true.
Right here on the carpet. Right now.
Doesn't that sound funny?
You look suspicious. Afraid of the night watchman?
After all, we're still married.
Come, lie on me.
People should make love on the floor more often.
- Lock the door. - No one will surprise us.
- I'm a bit of a prudish person. - Just in case the security guard comes.
- He could be eavesdropping. - No, he's making his rounds.
Is it advisable to take off your pants when you have this cold?
- You can warm me up. - So your thing doesn't freeze...
Poor baby, you are so unhappy...
It's nice to be kissed by you.
I'm having so much fun...
What if...?
Close your eyes,
or I will feel insecure.
Put your hands on my hips.
That is nice...
What if the guard came in now?
He could join us. We are free.
Let's stay here all night...
...and just drink and make love.
Tomorrow we will file our divorce papers.
A penny for your thoughts.
I won't tell.
- Are you hungry? - I always am.
How about a steak tartare and some beer?
You shouldn't take me out.
I am in Uppsala with my students.
Arm Paula!
In that case, I would like to have dinner with you.
- Where is the bathroom? - Down the hall, on the left.
Let's sign these papers and go out and celebrate.
Pay tribute to a long and happy marriage.
I think I'll take it home.
Why turn around now?
You yourself said that you should read things thoroughly before signing.
Let’s read it from A to Z,
So you see, I didn't cheat you.
- Why are you so upset? - I'm not. Let's get started.
- You look angry to me. - I am, but I'll control myself.
As I always do when I am subjected to your whims.
Can we end this boring discussion?
It's late and tomorrow is a work day.
- Wouldn't you like to have dinner? - No, thank you.
I am grateful for the favors shown to me.
- Speaking of moods... - Now look here, Johan!
It is pointless to even try to discuss this now.
Let's put these in an envelope so you can take them home.
Then you and Paula can go through the wording
to see that I haven't fooled you.
- What's going on? - Nothing.
A minute ago we were good friends.
Don't forget Eva's birthday.
- Do I usually do that? - No, because I always remind you.
Could you pay for her trip to France?
- How much is that? - 2,000 kroner.
That's out of the question!
- Then let your mother pay. - I've already borrowed too much.
I just paid Karin's orthodontist.
- Doesn't she get free dental care? - She refuses to go there.
Eva has to cancel her trip.
It won't hurt her to learn that she can't have it all.
She's so spoiled and has too many bad manners!
- Mother was horrified last week. - Your mother told you that?
Well, Eva is at a difficult age.
Don't let the girls take over.
I have full confidence in her
and for that I am grateful.
I don't care about little things like manners.
I can't afford the trip. Tell her that.
- Tell her yourself. - Why? You have custody.
I just pay huge sums for child support,
lets me down.
You and I were born
with silver spoons in their mouths.
We have wasted our resources,
and leaves us poor, bitter and angry.
As trite as it may sound, it is the truth:
We are emotionally illiterate.
We learned about anatomy and African farming methods.
We memorized mathematical formulas.
We have not been taught anything about reason.
We don't know what motivates people.
This concludes my lecture.
More brandy? Then we can decide on dinner.
I do not agree with you.
By the way, this job was lost in the USA.
- Not that it matters. - What a pity!
Well, I was pretty disappointed.
There were the usual machinations.
First everything was postponed, then the money was missing...
Then they sent someone else. That's life. Cheers!
I'll be 45 this summer.
I can expect to live another 30 years...
Objectively speaking, I'm a burden.
I'm going to spend the next 20 years being a fucking nuisance.
I am an expensive, unproductive unit
that should be eliminated.
And I should be in my prime,
full of useful experiences!
“But the saying goes: ‘Throw out the loser.’”
"Let him go to the dogs."
I'm so damn tired.
I hardly know who I am.
Someone spat on me and now I'm drowning in saliva.
- Am I boring you? - It's funny...
I wanted to have sex with you today to see if I could feel anything.
I felt only lukewarm affection.
I think I can finally free myself.
It took a long time and was very painful,
but I am now free from you and can live my own life.
Allow me to congratulate you.
It's heartless of me to say this when you're going through a difficult time.
but strangely enough, I don't care.
I have taken your feelings into account far too often.
Consideration destroyed our love.
If I hadn’t been distracted by feelings of guilt,
I would have known that everything we did was wrong.
Do you remember the time after Karin was born?
When we couldn't sleep together?
How we blame my two pregnancies.
We have come up with many reasons why our lovemaking didn't bring us joy.
Warning lights flashed all around us,
but we ignored them.
These autopsies are so pointless.
Your idiotic sarcasm is driving me crazy!
Why should you tell me what to think and feel?
Lord, how I hate you!
I often thought, “Lord, how I hate them!”
Especially when we loved each other and I felt your indifference
and when I saw you naked at the bidet afterwards –
I'm washing away the nasty stuff I've deposited inside you.
I thought, "I hate her body, the way she moves."
I should have hit you.
I wanted to crush your hard, white resistance,
but we chatted and talked about how well we get along.
So why do I enjoy sex now?
- I'll do whatever he asks. - Just wait.
If you are married to him, you will do the same thing again.
Their behavior is deeply rooted.
Then look for a new lover who will free you from your disgust.
You are wrong.
There is such a thing as direct tenderness.
Not to mention the sensuality
and physical desire.
For you, all of this is blocked.
Do you think I wasn't sorry when we didn't get along?
I thought, “Is this misery all there is?”
We consoled ourselves with the thought that sex isn't everything.
That we were otherwise happy. What self-deception!
They forget certain things.
Then please enlighten me.
They made money with their genitals.
They became a bargaining chip.
A night full of sex for a night full of peace.
Good behavior got me fucked.
Bad behavior or criticism
forced you to retreat.
You were worse than any whore!
- You would never face the truth. - Some cosmic truth or your truth?
How you made me your doormat!
Am I a replacement for your mother?
All that whining about how I neglected the home.
That's a lie!
You have burdened me with guilt!
You and your parents!
I felt inadequate at work and at home
and I was also a lousy lover.
I was overwhelmed by all the whining and endless demands.
If I used my genitals, was that so strange?
I fought against hopeless odds:
You, my mother, your parents and society!
When I think about what I endured, I could scream!
I tell you: never again!
They sit there and complain about conspiracies.
Serves you damn right!
I hope it gets rammed down your throat
that you are a useless parasite.
- You're absolutely grotesque! - You made me this way!
The difference between us is that I fight against it!
I intend to face reality as it is.
If there is one thing I truly value, it is being alive.
I enjoy overcoming difficulties.
- I'm not asking for any special compensation. - How nice!
Then we don't need to feel sorry for each other.
We become quite human.
It's a pity we ever met
and decided to live together – what a glorious fiasco!
The sooner we sign the papers, the better.
We will divide our worldly goods and go our separate ways.
It was all just a terrible mistake.
I know what you're thinking.
- You don't want a divorce! - That's absurd!
- Then sign the papers. - Okay, I will.
Now be honest... look at me!
You don't want a divorce, do you?
Would that be such a crime?
I admit defeat. Is that what you want to hear?
I'm sick of Paula.
I want to come home.
Don't look at me like that.
I'm a failure. I'm going downhill.
I am afraid and helpless.
My timing is completely wrong...
- If you think that pity helps... - I will give you a clear answer.
I was connected to you in a deeper way than I knew.
I needed our home
and lead a normal life.
I'm tired of being alone.
Loneliness with Paula is worse than being completely alone.
I can't stand it either.
I won't continue... Now you know.
Please send a taxi to Malmrosgatan 45.
Do you want a ride? You really shouldn't drive.
- I'll stay here for a while. - Please don't brood.
That does not concern you!
- I want you to stay. - But I don't want to.
You're tired and drunk. Let me go.
- I don't want you to leave. - Don't be silly.
We've never behaved like this before. Give me the key.
I don't give a shit what you say.
Her orderly mind is shaken.
“What do I do now?”
“Has he gone crazy?”
“Will he hit me?”
Actually, you're quite a troublemaker.
Then why don't you laugh?
You look scared to me.
Let me cancel the taxi...
For what reason?
You only wait about 10 minutes.
Sit down and relax.
- That'll take quite a while. - Good...
- So, what do you want to say? - Nothing.
- I want to look at you. - Go on.
I should have expected that.
I have often warned wives in the divorce process
against spending time alone with their husbands.
And yet I am here.
Shut your mouth!
I'm not afraid, I don't care what you do.
-Shut up, I said! -You crazy man!
Give me the key, I'll go and wash off the blood.
I won't let you out.
- You asshole! - You bitch!
I'll show you!
I could kill you! I could kill you!
Oh, Marianne ...
Listen, are you okay?
I guess I can only blame myself...
Will you give me the key now?
- Should I help you? - No, don't come near me.
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT IN A DARK HOUSE
What fun this is!
I went to the cottage yesterday and turned on the heating
and stocked up on food, just like in the old days.
- When did I last see the place? - Seven years ago.
- And you? - I don't spend much time there.
Henrik doesn't like the sea.
The girls and I go there occasionally,
but they have to live their own lives.
- How is your husband? - Revised.
He suffers from high blood pressure.
- How is your wife? - She's in Italy to recover.
Strange that they're both abroad.
I think that's almost indecent.
That's the beauty.
- The place hasn't changed much. - It's a bit shabby.
It needs renovation, but we can't afford it.
Park the car, otherwise Erik will see it and come right over.
- This could be embarrassing. - I will, darling...
- Won't you do it now? - No, later.
This feels a little strange...
Let's stretch out on the bed...
I'm nervous. It's like the first time.
But that's not it.
It's been almost a year now.
It was the day before my birthday
and today is August 28th.
You seduced me.
Have you ever seen the last act of this play?
It must have looked strange how we sneaked away like that.
- What prompted you to make this decision? - I don't know...
I saw you the second I walked into the theater.
It seemed natural to approach you.
I was terribly pleased.
Something like that l.
“– And you said, ‘Let’s go.’ – And you blushed.”
- No wonder. I had such a hard-on. - You made me pretty hot, too.
We hadn't seen each other for two whole years.
That's right, exactly two years.
And today is our first anniversary.
NO...
It's not our first anniversary.
It's our 20th.
We got married 20 years ago in August.
It's a whole life.
A whole adult life together.
Isn't that strange?
My love! Darling...
It's this miserable old bed...
Our hotel rooms were accordingly impersonal.
It was wrong of us to come here.
- We should have gone to Denmark. - There was no time for that.
- That's fine. - No, it's not.
I'll call Fredrik. He has a vacation home.
- How do we get in? - I assume a neighbor has a key.
It can't hurt to try.
Fredrik? It's me, Johan.
How are you? I've never felt better.
Look, this is a pretty delicate matter. Are you alone?
Could I perhaps borrow your cottage for the weekend?
Exactly, something like that...
Very pretty. Young...?
She's almost too young!
It's a delicate situation.
That's great!
I owe you a favor.
Don't say a word to Birgit now.
Women don't understand these things.
Right... The key is under the stone step.
And... Blonde.
With a great figure...
I'll call you. I really appreciate it.
Thanks. Say hello to Birgit for me. No, delete the last suggestion.
- I found it. - It's beautiful!
Here's the step. It has to be here.
- Let's clear this up. - Good.
What's wrong? You're crying.
You're so touching. I'm silly.
Touching? That's incredible.
It's the truth.
My dear, beloved Johan...
You have become so small.
You look so good like this.
You always looked so tense.
- Are people mean to you? - I don't know.
I'm no longer on the defensive.
Someone said I had become careless and gave in too quickly.
I have accepted my true dimensions
with a certain humility.
It makes me friendly and sad.
And you with your great expectations.
These were my family's expectations.
I really wanted to do them justice.
You wanted to know something about my husband?
Getting married was a mistake.
It was more of a joke.
When did you meet?
A few years ago.
It was a purely sexual matter.
I understand...
Henrik is... How should I say this?
Very convincing in this respect.
He really enjoys sex
and he made me realize that I felt the same way.
I wasn't that excited before.
I remember.
You don't like this topic, do you?
But it cannot be changed.
I was obsessed with this new sensation.
I felt insatiable.
How nice... for you.
I have grown very fond of Henrik
and he liked me very much,
but I caught him with other women.
What do you know?
I was hurt and humiliated, even jealous.
Are you jealous?
We had a violent scene and I told him to go to hell.
- And did he? - Yes.
He said I was too theatrical.
I begged him to come back.
You look absent-minded.
Everything is fine, that's all.
It simply couldn't be better.
- I just can't stand it. - I knew it!
As if I care about your orgasms with that workaholic.
I welcome your emancipation.
You should write a novel.
The women’s rights activists would be happy.
You're ridiculous...
I tell you, I don't give a shit.
It suddenly became so terribly important.
It's just a taste
the wonderful things that life has to offer.
Think of the awareness we have gained.
It's great!
We discovered ourselves.
One faces his insignificance, the other his greatness.
Here we are, badmouthing our spouses.
You are with us in this room.
This is crazy group sex taken to the extreme.
It's like a textbook about life.
It's fabulous, but I can't stand it.
I understand, but I don't think it's a bad thing.
I can't bear to have all my efforts cast under this cold light.
How I struggle with meaninglessness.
I try to cheer myself up and think
that life is what you make of it,
but these are empty words.
I want something to long for.
I don't feel that way.
I understand that.
I'm holding on.
I'm having fun.
I rely on common sense
and my gut feeling.
They work together.
I am happy with my direction.
Time has given me a third partner:
Experience.
They should become politicians.
Maybe you're right...
I like people.
I enjoy negotiations,
Prudence, compromises...
Are you rehearsing your election speech?
- Am I so impossible? - Only when you preach.
I won't say another word.
No more bitter truths?
I promise it.
Promise me you won't mention that orgasmic Superman again.
Promise to curb your terrible prudence.
It will be difficult, but I will try.
Could you possibly...
...use your feminine power sparingly?
I have to.
All right then...
Let's go to bed.
What is it? There, there...
Come, sit here with me.
Yes, yes...
What causes such nightmares?
- Maybe it was something you ate. - Do you think so?
Unless something else happens in your orderly world...
...that you can't reach.
Hold me, I'm shaking.
I think I caught something.
- The girls had a cold... - They'll feel better soon.
Pull up the blanket. That's nice...
What did you dream about?
We crossed a dangerous road.
I wanted you and the girls to hold on to me,
but my hands were gone.
All I had left were stumps
and I slide around in the soft sand.
You're on the road and I can't reach you...
What a terrible dream!
Do we live our lives in confusion?
- All of us. - What do you mean?
Fear, insecurity, lack of wisdom.
Let's slide downhill
and don't know what to do?
Yes, I think so.
Is it late?
Yes,
but we shouldn't say such things.
Johan, did we miss something important?
- All of us? - No, you and me.
Sometimes I can read your mind
and feel such tenderness.
I forget myself without losing myself.
It's a new sensation.
I understand.
It saddens me that I have never loved anyone.
I don't think I was ever loved either.
This worries me.
Now you're acting theatrical.
I know what I feel.
I love you in my selfish way
and I think you love me,
in your fussy, annoying way.
We love each other
like the people here on earth,
but you are so demanding.
Yes that's me.
It's that easy:
Here I am in a dark house somewhere in the world,
with my arms around you
and you are here in my arms.
I lack empathy for my fellow human beings.
I think I lack imagination.
I don't know what my love looks like and I can't describe it.
Most of the time I don't feel it.
Do you think I love you too?
Yes, I do.
If we keep dwelling on it, love will disappear.
Let's stay like this all night.
Oh, let's not...
One leg has fallen asleep, my left arm is dislocated,
I am tired and my back is cold.
Then let’s snuggle up.
Good night, my darling. It was nice talking to you.
- Sleep well. - You too.