What's the problem?
You know what the problem is.
It's great. It's got rhythm.
I don't like it.
I can't focus.
Why can't we use a pop song?
You're not ready for pop.
If you want to know what the problem is,
I'll tell you what the problem is.
The problem is that you don't trust me.
The problem is you think
I'm not ready for pop, when I am.
Raise your voice at me again,
and I'll take a club
and crack your head open.
And then I'll break your arms
and your legs.
And then you really won't be able
to perform to pop.
In fact, you won't be able
to perform to anything.
Not rock, not fox-trot, not Latin,
not anything.
I know damn well
when someone's ready for pop.
I'm sorry.
You know very well
when someone's ready for pop.
What's your name?
Mary.
Mary or Maria?
What do people usually call you?
Mary.
I'm going to call you Maria.
Do you have any siblings?
No.
Maria, you're hurt very badly.
There's a big chance you could die.
If I asked you to pick an actor,
who would it be?
Who's your favorite?
Look, I'll list some names.
If I hit on your favorite, make me a sign.
Brad Pitt.
No?
Johnny Depp.
What? Not Johnny Depp?
We brought in a girl, around 16 years old.
Car accident.
Internal bleeding, broken ribs.
Plays tennis.
Must have played for years.
Her racquet's pretty light.
Did they take her in for surgery?
Yes.
And her family?
Her parents have been notified.
Where are they taking her?
Room 205.
Okay.
She has no brothers or sisters.
Her favorite actor is Jude Law.
Okay.
Brunette? Blonde? Darker?
Brunette, dark brown.
Her head was covered in blood,
but I think dark brown.
- Coffee?
- Yes.
There's some in the kitchen.
Can I use your mug?
Just for today.
Tomorrow I'll bring my own.
What's yours like?
I'm asking in case there's another one
like it and there's a mix-up.
Blue with red writing.
What does it say?
"Los Angeles."
No, there isn't another one like it.
You must stay calm
in this sort of situation,
however difficult this may sound.
Yes.
- Do you have any other children?
- No.
Everything'll be fine. She'll make it.
She seems tough.
She's an athlete. She plays tennis.
That's excellent.
I play tennis too.
An injury set me back a little,
but I've been much better
the last two years.
My wife is a former tennis champion.
I don't want you to worry.
We're doing everything we can.
Your daughter will be fine.
She'll be back on the tennis court
before you know it.
You'll forget all this ever happened.
I'd like a favor.
This is her favorite wristband.
She wore it at every match.
I'd like you to give it to her.
It'll give her strength.
I don't know if she's allowed to wear it.
That won't be a problem.
You can give it to her yourself
when you see her.
Thank you.
Hello, Dad.
You're late.
It's five to ten.
It's ten past ten.
- There was traffic.
- I was worried.
I'm sorry.
I don't mind if you're late.
Just let me know.
I'm sorry.
I'm going to bed. Is there anything else?
It's going to rain tomorrow.
Take a jacket.
All right.
Good night.
Today is a special day.
As you know, we've been searching
for a good-sounding...
suitable name for our group
for a long time.
After much thought, I've decided on...
- "Alps."
- Alps?
Yes, Alps.
Why Alps?
Alps for two important reasons.
First, the name in no way reveals
what it is we do.
The second reason is purely symbolic.
The mountains of the Alps
cannot be replaced by any other mountain.
Anything else would be smaller,
less imposing,
and thus...
a poor substitute.
But what's fantastic is that while
the mountains of the Alps
cannot be replaced,
they could replace any other mountain.
Who could mind seeing,
in place of Mt. Ararat or Mt. McKinley...
one of the Alps?
Would you mind?
I wouldn't mind.
I'll take the name
of the highest mountain, Mont Blanc.
What about us?
You can choose from any
of the smaller mountains.
Do you know them?
Monte Rosa, Dom, Weisshorn, Matterhorn,
Finsteraarhorn, Aletschhorn,
Barre des Écrins,
Gran Paradiso, Piz Bernina, and one more,
Weissmies.
I made you photocopies.
I want the name Matterhorn.
Good.
Why?
It reminds me of my father.
When I was very little,
we took a trip there.
Where?
- To Matterhorn.
- In Switzerland?
At the foot of the mountain.
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon. Just a minute.
- Hello.
- Please sit.
- Thanks.
I brought the list you asked for
and the photograph.
Very good.
- You don't have a closer shot?
- I'm afraid not.
- A captain.
- A merchant navy captain.
He's wearing the insignia of a lieutenant.
It's an old photograph.
I couldn't find a more recent one.
He wore glasses.
I couldn't find them.
But you must.
I'll look for them again.
We can't use any old glasses.
It won't look right.
I'll look again.
His name is Zachos.
That's right.
Anything in common
with that grill bar in Varkiza?
No, no. They just shared the same name.
Did you know him many years?
We were friends around 20 years.
Since college.
Cause of death?
Heart attack.
Favorite food?
Nothing in particular.
He maybe had a slight preference
for pasta.
Served plain?
- With red sauce.
- Napolitaine.
Yes, Napolitaine.
Don't worry.
He often used the word "anyway"
to start a sentence.
Like, he'd say,
"Anyway, it's very windy today."
Or, "Anyway, we'll talk later."
Or, "Anyway, it's very cold today."
I see.
Favorite foreign actor?
Morgan Freeman.
He liked to go to the movies on his own.
He'd go see all his films.
He usually went alone.
Is it too small?
- Yes.
- I think so too.
We'll get it adjusted.
Maybe your hair's too thick?
No, it's not that.
My friend had no hair.
- Is that a problem for you?
- No.
I don't think so. No.
Great.
If he were wearing the glasses,
it would be completely different.
I'll look again. I'll find them.
- You have to.
- I will.
Hello.
Darling, Anna's come to visit.
My best friend.
Come here, sit down.
What a pleasant surprise.
I wasn't expecting you.
- I've missed you.
- Me too.
Would you like something to drink? Tea?
- Tea.
- Lovely.
Here you are.
Thank you.
How are you?
- I'm fine.
- I'm glad.
Hello.
How are you, Anna?
We haven't seen you in ages.
I must say we've missed you.
I'm fine.
The weather's beautiful today, isn't it?
Very.
I'm going to the office.
I have some important business to tend to.
Will you be home late?
Yes. I'll be back late tonight.
Fine. I'll make you your favorite dinner.
Schnitzel with mashed potatoes? Perfect.
I don't know what I'd do without him.
You're very lucky.
- Would you like me to read to you?
- Yes, I'd like that.
From a book or a magazine?
A magazine.
"What's Hot to Wear This Summer
and What's Not."
"Gianfranco Ferré: The King is Naked."
"A Trip to Guatemala:
Exotic and Mysterious."
- "An Interview with Winona Ryder."
- That one.
"'Tell me, how do you start your day?'"
"'If I'm not working, I get up around ten
and make myself a cup of tea.
Then I sit and read the New York Times.
The rest of the morning,
I make a few phone calls
and set up appointments.
When I'm in Los Angeles,
sometimes I take a long walk
around my house
either to revitalize myself,
or during the night, just to relax.'"
I've got a surprise for you.
Close your eyes.
Do you like it?
Isn't it great?
Sorry.
Isn't it great we've become friends?
Would you like me to sit with you
for a while? To talk?
I want you to know
that whatever you tell me,
I won't say a thing to your parents.
It'll stay between us.
Are you pregnant?
Don't be sad.
You're too young to have a baby anyway.
There's lots of time for that
in the future.
For now, you need to concentrate
on your schoolwork and your tennis.
Also you should know if you're pregnant,
you shouldn't be dyeing your hair.
It's really dangerous.
Anyway, your natural color is beautiful.
It's dark brown, isn't it?
What happened?
Nothing.
I couldn't say something
I was supposed to say.
What couldn't you say?
"Grandpa, look, a beautiful mug
for your coffee or tea."
What did the old man do?
He got sad.
And what did you do?
Nothing.
I left.
Don't tell Mont Blanc.
Please.
He won't give me the car accident girl
if you tell him.
You're the king of coaches.
You're the best...
You're the best coach in the world.
I can't not tell him.
I'm sorry.
It's wonderful.
Is it cold?
No. Not at all.
Come out now. It's getting late.
We have to leave.
Just a little longer.
Please, a little longer.
All right.
Cold is a word...
that winter swimmers don't know.
It's so unfair
that you can't eat ice cream
because of your diabetes.
But you hate chocolate anyway.
I would have a different flavor,
like strawberry, which is my favorite.
There's no point talking about it.
The doctor was quite clear about it.
You're right.
How about a walk along the beach?
That's a wonderful idea.
Light fittings fall into three
main categories:
domestic interior, domestic exterior,
and professional.
Then there are various sub-categories,
such as ceiling lamps,
table lamps, wall lamps,
modern chandeliers, classic chandeliers,
track lighting, uplighters,
spotlights, pendant lamps,
and floor lamps.
Repeat them back to me.
Wall lamps, ceiling lamps,
classic chandeliers,
modern chandeliers, uplighters...
floor lamps, table lamps...
And pendant lamps.
...and uplighters.
Again tonight.
This afternoon there's going to be a ball.
What do you dance?
Everything. Blues, tango, waltz.
And Latin?
And Latin.
- That's nice.
- Will you come?
I'll be there.
Ready? And...
Your daughter lost the most important...
the most important match of her life.
I'm very sorry.
My condolences.
But you must remember
that death is not the end.
On the contrary,
it can be a new
and often better beginning.
Your daughter fought hard,
but her opponent was too tough.
She was a truly remarkable person.
We'll all remember her.
I'm sure of it.
And now I have something wonderful
to tell you.
I can substitute for her, if you like.
It will help ease your grief,
until after a while,
it disappears completely.
Two or three two-hour visits
a week would be enough.
The end can be a new and better beginning.
It all depends on you.
The first four visits are free.
"Grandpa, look, a beautiful mug
for your coffee or tea.
Grandma'll be so jealous when she sees it,
but that's okay,
I bought her a present too--
a wallet with pockets
for photographs and coins."
"Grandpa, look, a beautiful mug
for your coffee or tea."
The car accident girl's condition
is improving,
and the doctors say she's out of danger.
They're calling it a miracle.
That's a shame.
Yes, it is.
Again.
"Grandpa, look, a beautiful mug
for your coffee or tea.
Grandma'll be so jealous when she sees it,
but that's okay,
I bought her a present too--
a wallet with pockets
for photographs and coins.
You sure missed out not coming with us.
The view was wonderful
and the room was fantastic."
You won't be paid this month.
I'm going to keep the money.
Again. Clearer.
"Grandpa, look, a beautiful mug
for your coffee or tea."
What happened?
She made a mistake.
Has it happened before?
This was the second time.
Again with the old man.
Yesterday the barber who cut my hair
for the last 12 years died.
He had no family.
I went to the barbershop today,
and he wasn't there.
Only he ever cut my hair, no one else.
He always made sure my sideburns
were exactly the same length.
Both of them.
Are they the same length now?
I don't know.
They're not.
I hadn't been in a while.
If he wasn't there,
I wouldn't book an appointment.
I always arranged to go when he was there.
Are you going to the funeral?
No.
- Why not?
- I don't go to funerals.
How did he die?
Heart attack.
You danced beautifully.
Thank you very much.
And your dance partner was wonderful.
We always dance together.
Have you known each other long?
About five months.
Are you fond of her?
She's very nice.
What time is it?
I didn't know you were such a good dancer.
I used to dance with your mother
all the time.
Everything except Latin.
She hated Latin.
You must always wear your hair up.
And those aren't tennis shoes.
Of course.
What size shoe do you wear?
Thirty-eight or 39. It depends.
It's amazing. They fit me perfectly.
Amazing.
This is her perfume. "Eternity."
It was a gift from her boyfriend.
You'll have to meet him at some point.
I was sure I'd beat her.
I knew it.
Her backhand was pathetic,
and I knew right away
she didn't have a chance.
Would you like some more water?
No, thanks, Dad.
You usually drink lots of water
after a match.
Okay, then, thanks.
Bite your nails a little.
That's enough.
I really like the latest substitution.
The blind woman?
Yes.
She lost her sight in her old age.
She's never told me how.
She's a beautiful woman.
Her colors are intense.
What do you mean, her colors are intense?
Green eyes, honey-colored hair.
A strange combination.
I go to her house in the center of Athens,
a maisonette with a yard.
She doesn't have much furniture.
Less things for her to trip over.
We sit and I pretend to be her husband.
Yes, I know.
And I tell her stories for hours.
She likes them a lot.
Whatever pops into my head.
She asks me to kiss her from time to time.
And we kiss.
Do you like it?
I like it a lot.
I have a good time.
I mean, do you like it when you kiss?
I like it, yes. She's an active woman.
Imagine if you were blind.
You wouldn't be able to do
rhythmic gymnastics.
Get out of here.
Collect your things from home and leave.
Go back to Toronto, go wherever you like,
so long as I never see you again.
Fuck you. You're so controlling,
you make me miserable.
I'm only thinking of your health, idiot.
But I don't care anymore.
Leave and then eat all the cakes
and desserts you like.
I will leave.
Get out of my sight.
I don't want to see you again.
Get out of here.
Collect your things from home and leave.
Go back to Toronto, go wherever you like,
so long as I never see you again.
Fuck you. You're so controlling,
you make me miserable.
I'm only thinking of your health, idiot.
But I don't care anymore.
Leave and then eat all the cakes
and desserts you like.
I will leave.
Get out of my sight.
I don't want to see you again.
I'm sorry. I love you.
I love you too.
I'm only hard on you for your own good.
I know.
If Mont Blanc finds out about this,
there'll be trouble.
We may have to end our arrangement.
He won't find out.
Not from me anyway.
Leave your blouse on. Take off your skirt.
And my tights?
Take them off too.
Try not to talk too loudly.
I should barely be able to hear you.
At some point you'll say:
"Please...
Please, don't you stop.
It feels like heaven."
And that's it.
Please, don't you stop.
It feels like paradise.
"Heaven."
Please...
don't you stop. It feels like heaven.
Please, don't you stop.
It feels like heaven.
He said I'd never get to perform to pop.
Why?
I don't know.
But I can't take it anymore.
What you just tried to do
was very immature.
You're a very good gymnast.
It would be a terrible shame if you died.
I'll talk to him.
Thank you, Monte Rosa.
You know it'll be very difficult
to change his mind.
But there's no harm in trying.
Is there a particular song you want?
I'm between two of them.
I'll do anything you want.
Let her train with a pop song,
and I'll do anything you want.
Anything I want?
Anything you want.
Think about it.
I've thought of something.
- Tell me where.
- Further in.
- Come on. All right?
- Yes.
How could you? With my husband?
You're my best friend.
I hate you both!
Shame on you. Get out of my sight.
You've got a nice body.
So do you.
Are you cold?
No, not at all.
I turned the heat on,
but it takes a while to warm up.
It doesn't matter.
Dad, would you like to dance with me?
Not now. Some other time.
Tonight?
Tonight.
Promise?
I have to go.
Please stay a little longer.
Okay.
Let's not wait for her any longer.
It looks like she isn't coming.
I agree, she's very late.
Who's up first?
Can I go first?
Are you a man or woman?
A man.
I'll give you a little longer.
- I don't know.
- Me either.
I'm Prince.
Who?
Prince.
You can't substitute for Prince.
Why?
Prince isn't dead.
Prince is dead.
Prince is alive.
Sorry.
You missed our meeting yesterday.
I know.
It's just that I had to cover
a colleague's shift. They were busy.
Here.
So you were here.
Your mug is clean.
You didn't drink any coffee all night?
I used it. I hope you don't mind.
No, I don't mind at all.
I couldn't find mine.
Well, it's a shame
you didn't come yesterday.
It was fun.
The little one stood in for Prince.
But Prince isn't dead.
Prince isn't dead?
No.
He isn't dead.
Have you seen anyone drinking from my mug?
The one with red writing
that says "Los Angeles"?
Not that I remember.
Strange.
You can use mine anytime you want.
Thanks a lot. I don't smoke.
You'd be better off if you gave it up.
- Nice shoes.
- Thanks.
Yesterday I saw a movie
about an old soldier,
called for one final mission.
At first he refuses,
but then he gets armored up and goes.
I think I've seen it.
Mom, Dad,
I didn't expect you home so soon.
Vassilis is a friend from school.
We were just dancing.
- Want to go back to my place?
- Sure.
Hello, Dad.
This is Vassilis.
Vassilis, this is my dad.
- Hello.
We're going to my room
to sit and listen to music.
- If you need anything, let me know.
- Okay.
If the music is too loud,
tell me and I'll turn it down.
- All right?
- All right.
It's too loud. Turn it down.
If you're cold,
just say and I'll turn the heating on.
I'm not cold.
Vassilis is younger than I am,
but we're a good match.
In many ways.
We share many common interests.
Music, sport...
We met at the hospital.
He's a track athlete, 110-meter hurdles.
He fell during a race...
jumping over one of the hurdles...
and fractured his wrist.
I helped with his splint.
And I gave him a painkiller.
Also... he's very creative.
He plays the guitar.
He covers songs with his band at school.
He sings and...
Hi.
Who is it, darling?
A friend from school, Mom.
I'm sorry, I can't come out with you
because I've got homework to do,
and then I have to attend
a very important tennis tournament.
I'll see you tomorrow at school.
We're going to do a test.
I'm going to use this object.
If it doesn't change color
and stays white...
then it automatically means
that you are competent and reliable,
and can stay in our group.
If it changes color,
there are two possibilities.
First,
it can turn blue.
If it turns blue,
then it automatically means...
that you are competent...
but unreliable.
Therefore?
There's no therefore.
It doesn't really matter if it turns blue.
It's just something I said.
The second and worst possible outcome...
is for this club
to turn red...
which means automatically...
that you are too unreliable
and too incompetent to stay with us.
Let's see.
It changed.
It turned red.
I'm afraid you'll have to go.
Drink it now, before the ice melts.
It's very good.
Who was Mom's favorite actor?
Robert Redford.
Mine too.
And her favorite singer?
Harry Belafonte.
And yours?
Elvis Presley.
Mine too.
Nice shoes. Thanks.
Yesterday I saw a movie
about an old soldier
called for one final mission.
At first he refuses,
but then he gets armored up and goes.
I think I've seen it.
Mom, Dad,
I didn't expect you home so soon.
Vassilis is a friend from school.
We were just dancing.
Nice shoes. Thanks.
Yesterday I saw a movie
about an old soldier
called for one final mission,
and at first he refuses,
but then he gets armored up and goes.
I think I've seen it.
Mom, Dad,
I didn't expect you home so soon.
Dad, can you bring me some water, please?
Dad?
I'm home.
Can you open the door, please?
I was really good today.
4-2 in the set.
You're the best coach in the world.