DOGTOOTH
Today the new words are the following:
Sea...
motorway...
excursion...
and carbine.
A sea is a leather armchair
with wooden arms
like the one we have
in our living room.
For example:
Don't stand on your feet.
Sit on the sea to have
a quiet chat with me.
A motorway is a very strong wind.
An excursion is a very resistant material...
used to construct floors.
For example:
The chandelier fell violently
onto the floor...
but no damage was caused to it...
because it is made of 100% excursion.
Carbine.
A carbine is a beautiful white bird.
I say we play a game of endurance.
By that I mean we run hot water
from the taps...
place a finger under the water...
and the one who lasts longest wins.
What do you think?
I like it.
- You?
- I like it as well.
Shall we use all the taps or just one?
We'll just use one if you like.
How will we time it?
With a clock or a stopwatch?
No need.
We'll put our fingers in together.
Last one to take their finger out wins.
So we need all three taps running?
We could do it with just one.
If we use three, someone might sneak
their finger out for a moment.
We could use the bathtub.
It's bigger.
What should we call this game?
I don't know...
Do you like the music
or should I put something else on?
No, it's okay.
No need to be shy.
If you don't like it, let me know.
No, I do like it.
What's your favorite song?
I have two.
Have you taken a bath?
Yes.
Did you wash your hair?
Not my hair.
I washed it yesterday.
- Do you feel dizzy?
- No, I'm fine.
Are you done?
Christina is here.
- Hello, Christina.
- Hello.
You've lost weight.
Yes, a little.
Can I stay, or am I disturbing you?
Stay. You're not disturbing me in the least.
What are those things on your headband?
Sparkling stones.
Sparkling?
They shine in the dark,
like little lights.
Without any power?
Sure.
You're lying.
No, I'm not.
Where did you get it?
I made it myself.
Well done.
Thanks.
Do you have a headband?
A brown one.
But I gave it to my little sister.
She gave me a pair of socks
and two big rubber erasers.
Are those the socks?
No, another pair.
They're nice too.
Thanks.
Will you join us for dinner?
No, unfortunately I have to go.
Too bad. We're having burgers.
Burgers are one of my favorite meals.
What are the others?
I like fish soup and cheese pie.
Fish soup and cheese pie are perfect.
- I had fish soup yesterday.
- Lovely.
There's apple in the juice too.
It's very tasty.
Unfortunately, I have to go.
Shall I shoot a video
with all of us?
Go ahead, we don't have
a video with Christina.
Do you mind if we film us all together?
Not at all.
- Dad, can I sit next to Christina?
- Yes, honey.
Christina, can you smile a bit more?
The sizes of the triangle angles
are 36, 77 and 67 degrees.
Side A has a length of 12.8 cm.
Side C has a length of 9.7 cm.
Find the area of the triangle,
the length of side B...
and the type of triangle.
Good luck.
The eyes of a fresh fish are not:
A) Bleary,
B) Big,
C) Red.
Good luck.
If for any reason
we are still awake at 11:00 p.m.,
what kind of procedure do we follow?
Good luck.
- Are you ready?
- Yes.
- Shall I wait for you?
- How do I look?
- Just fine.
Now?
That's fine, too.
I don't think the skirt goes
with this shirt.
- How many do you have?
- 37.
- You'll be caught if you cheat.
- I've got 37. And you?
52.
You might be the one with the most.
No way.
- More salad?
- No.
We're low on iodine
and the antihistamines have expired.
Also, we need more bandages.
I'll give you a list.
- Whatever you like.
- And black tint for your eyebrows.
Didn't I get you some last week?
I used it all. I need more.
I can't use blue.
It would be unnatural.
I'll get you some.
- Do you want lemon?
- No, thanks.
We'll be out of meat soon.
You need to bring more.
Mom, could you pass me the phone? Please.
Thank you.
- Did you count your stickers?
- I have 76.
I have 52.
37.
Girls, you have to try harder.
Your brother is the winner again.
That means he selects tonight's entertainment.
But I have a surprise for you.
Something unprecedented.
The next prize will be
not one sticker, or two,
but ten.
So you must do your best.
You see how important it is.
Yes, absolutely.
The winner tells us
how we spend the evening.
I say video.
We haven't watched one in a long time.
It's a good opportunity.
Dad, may I water the plants too?
Run!
Be careful, slow down.
Here, Dad, there's a dry herb.
This is the problem.
There are more in there.
Dad, there's an airplane!
Can you bring a wet cloth
from the kitchen?
Mom, where do we keep them?
Under the sink, in the cupboard.
Careful, don't bring a clean one.
Look out, maybe it'll fall.
Watch out!
Mom, that was great!
Let me take a look.
I wash it much better than you.
I also clean the tires and floor mats.
And I never forget the air freshener.
Only once.
It smelled nice and I thought
I'd used some...
already...
You rarely remembered it
and often didn't clean the mats
when they had tough stains,
like mud and tar.
I wish you'd see
that I wash it better than you.
You'd have cried if you'd seen that.
He's out at the fence again.
He started throwing rocks at me.
Your brother would never throw stones.
Not yet, I'll tell you when.
Hold on a while.
Now spit it out.
I wish it would fall.
If it falls, I'll get it.
Whoever deserves it will get it.
- Good morning.
- How are you, Christina?
Fine. My leg hurts a little.
When are you coming again?
I'll check the shifts.
Maybe one afternoon next week.
Do you wear the perfume I gave you?
Does it smell good?
It does.
Mr. Petrou called for you.
- Did you water the yucca?
- Two weeks ago.
- Do it every week.
- Yes, sir. Shall I call him?
- No, I'll go.
- Yes, sir.
My belly has been aching
since last night.
Where exactly does it hurt?
On the upper right side.
Could be an inflamed appendix.
The vermiform appendix
is lower down on the right.
- Here?
- No.
- Does it hurt here?
- Yes.
- Avoid eating fruit and vegetables.
- I drank some milk.
It's okay.
You'd better not work out today.
- No medication?
- You don't need any.
Follow my instructions carefully
and you'll get well.
Otherwise your condition will deteriorate.
Get up. Can you play with me?
We have about 20 minutes.
I have a new anesthetic.
Do you want to try it out?
Yes.
The one who wakes up first
will be the winner.
Don't put more on mine.
One, two, three.
It's nearly finished.
It needs floor tiles and lights.
I can't decide which one I prefer.
- I like these.
- I prefer those.
Those are nice too.
- How's your wife?
- Same.
- Do you go out?
- No.
I told you, you should.
Even if she's in a wheelchair.
She's unwell.
And she doesn't like visitors.
I've told her hundreds of times
to invite you for a beer.
I understand.
It's tragic what happened to her.
It requires great psychological strength.
In the picture, she looks energetic.
She was a volleyball champion?
Handball.
These you said?
Yes. The others are nice too.
Hi, honey.
I had a meeting. A meeting, yes.
Did they go out? Or work out?
Why, what's the matter?
Her belly or her stomach?
Yes, it's cold outside.
I'd like my dog back.
Sorry, I can't do that.
He's still on the second stage
of his training.
I'll show you.
First stage, second stage-
where your dog is-
third, fourth, fifth and final stage.
Let me explain.
Dogs are like clay
and our job here is to mold them.
A dog may be energetic,
a fighter, cowardly, or gentle.
All this requires work, patience
and care from us.
Every dog is waiting for us
to show it how it should behave.
Do you understand?
So the issue here
is to decide together
how we want your dog to behave.
Do we want an animal
or do we want a friend?
Do we want a guard
who will respect us as his masters
and do unhesitatingly
whatever we ask of him?
You see?
Sure.
Rex!
1 minute 15 seconds.
2 minutes.
2 minutes 30 seconds.
2 minutes 45 seconds.
3 minutes 15 seconds.
3 minutes 45 seconds.
4 minutes 30 seconds.
5 minutes 15 seconds.
Five minutes 30 seconds.
What do you mean you can't?
I'm sorry.
We're doing this for you,
not for me.
I'm sorry.
Try again but use your tongue.
There's no point otherwise.
Don't tell Dad.
- Do you feel disgusted?
- No.
Then what?
I prefer what we did last time.
Hello.
What are you doing?
Cleaning the carpet to keep germs off it.
- Do you want this headband?
- Yes, very much.
What are you going to give me?
How about this pencil?
It has an eraser on it.
No.
A tape measure?
You press here and it reels in by itself.
No.
Come closer and lick for a while
and the headband is yours.
Are you disgusted?
No.
- Do you want to dance?
- I don't feel like it.
Besides, we don't have time.
We have to go meet Mom.
Mom will be late.
She's talking to herself again in her room.
Are you afraid of Mom talking to herself?
Not at all.
- You are afraid.
- I'm not.
- You are.
- No.
You can't hear her.
She might be talking about you.
Stop it.
If I give you a present,
will you lick me?
- What kind of present?
- A headband.
I already have one.
This one sparkles in the dark.
What do you mean by sparkles?
It lights up.
Where did you get it?
I can't tell you.
Do our parents know
you have a headband like that?
So, it could easily be yours.
What do you want me to lick?
My shoulder.
Can you get some chocolate
if you pass by the shop?
Don't go out of your way.
Any kind.
Me too.
That isn't yours.
Leave me alone.
- Does it still hurt?
- Yes.
You could ask Dad to get in the car
and fetch it for you.
That's what I'd do if I were you.
It's the only way.
Dad!
The eldest threw the airplane
over the fence.
- Where?
- There, on the road.
I'll try.
How did it happen?
What did you tell them?
You did the right thing.
I'll tell them as well.
Yes, it's a good opportunity.
Yes.
The temperature will rise
and the wind will drop.
Five or six degrees.
All right.
No, it's time to put an end to this.
It's exhausting for everyone.
I agree. You're absolutely right.
Yes.
Your brother is dead.
A creature like the one in the garden
tore him apart.
On the one hand,
he made a huge mistake,
venturing out ill-prepared.
On the other hand, he was my son
and I feel sorry for him.
The animal that threatens us is a "cat":
the most dangerous animal there is.
It eats meat,
children's flesh in particular.
After lacerating its victim
with its claws,
it devours them with sharp teeth.
The face and whole body of the victim.
If you stay inside, you are protected.
We have to be ready
in case it invades the house or the garden.
Our dear brother...
we are all very sorry that you failed
to exterminate the cat...
like I did.
We are going to miss you...
even though you made many mistakes.
It's a real pity
that it happened to you
and that I couldn't use my knowledge
to save you.
My brother, I never expected...
that things would turn out this way.
I hoped you'd manage to survive
with the supplies I procured.
But the dangers are many.
I am very sad.
Push three times on the chest.
Forcefully.
One,
two,
three.
Afterwards you close her nose,
open her mouth and blow.
I'm pregnant.
One boy, one girl. Twins.
Two boys?
No, a boy and a girl.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Triplets?
That's a bit much.
You're right, twins.
Turn round, do the same thing.
Okay.
Dive in.
Ready.
One, two, three, go.
In a few months,
your mother will give birth
to two children and a dog.
Some of you might not like this
because they'll be sharing their room,
their clothes, or even their toys.
However,
look on the bright side:
you'll have two more people
to support you,
the family will be bigger.
Let's all applaud your mother
in anticipation of this gift.
I don't want to share my room.
If you behave,
you won't have to share with anyone.
I will.
I don't want to share my room either.
If I see improvements
in your behavior and performance...
I might avoid giving birth.
But if things remain the same,
you give me no choice.
As for the dog,
I don't want to hear a thing.
I'll give birth as soon as possible.
Well done, honey.
I mean well done, everyone.
Dry yourself. Come and pick a prize.
Don't touch it with wet hands
or it won't stick afterwards.
One more thing.
Your performance was worse
than last time.
I need say no more.
Oh, there's an airplane.
It fell in the garden.
No, not that much. It hurts.
This much?
Less.
That's it.
Do you want me to lick you,
then you'll give me a present?
I have nothing to give you.
It doesn't matter.
This is a good spot.
Good morning, Dad.
How many hours did you sleep?
About nine.
I lost you and my spring departed
Filled with sorrow the stars
and the birds cry
Gray is the dusk and gray my soul
And all is sorrowful
because you are lost
Where are you now, my love
Mind the little toe!
Where are you roaming
For all of this time
Where are you now, my love
I search and search for you
Yet I do not find you
Dad!
There are two fish in the pool.
What kind?
Sea bream, I think.
But I'm not sure.
You must come and catch them.
Mom will be happy if I'm right.
Give me a minute and I'll come.
There are three.
They were two a minute ago.
Probably the other one came later.
The most creative years of a man?
Between 30 and 40.
And of a woman?
Between 20 and 30.
A child is ready to leave the house...
When the right dogtooth comes out.
Or the left. No matter.
Only then is your body ready
to face the dangers that lurk.
To leave the house and be safe outside,
we must take the car.
When are we ready to learn to drive?
When the right dogtooth grows again.
Or the left, it doesn't matter.
Mom, what's a pussy?
Where did you hear that word?
I saw it on a video case,
on top of the VCR.
A pussy is a big light.
For example:
The pussy is switched off,
the room plunges into darkness.
Do you want to hear
your grandfather sing?
Yes!
Dad loves us.
Mom loves us.
Do we love them?
Yes, we do.
I love my brothers and sisters...
because they love me as well.
The spring is flooding my house...
the spring is flooding...
my little heart.
My parents are proud of me...
because I'm doing just fine.
I'm doing just fine,
but I will always try harder.
My house, you are beautiful
and I love you...
and I will never...
ever leave you.
I saw you in my dreams the other day.
I was in the woods with your dad.
In the evening we had a fire
and roasted potatoes for dinner.
Suddenly we heard a weird sound
behind a bush.
It was you... and you were a zombie.
Your father threw rocks at you.
So did I.
- But we couldn't hit you.
- What was I?
A zombie.
- Do you know what a zombie is?
- I do.
- Do you have dreams?
Tell me about one you had lately.
Mom fell into the pool.
And then?
Nothing. Just that.
I brought you another present.
Hair gel.
You put it on your hair,
to shape it.
I don't like it.
What do you mean?
I don't like this present.
Anyway I don't believe you.
You told me your headband sparkled
and it wasn't true.
It was! No way doesn't it sparkle.
Maybe you did something wrong.
I don't believe you.
Look.
Look at me.
If you want me to lick you,
I need a better present.
I don't have anything else.
I want these.
I can't give you those.
- I want them.
- It isn't possible.
In that case, get out.
I can't give them to you.
Get out.
I'm not going to lick you again.
And I'll tell my parents
you brought me a sparkling headband.
And that you told me to lick
your keyboard down there.
Do you know what Dad will do
if he finds out I lick your keyboard?
Please, you have to give them
back to me next week.
Mom, what's a zombie?
Where did you hear that word?
I don't remember. Probably Dad.
A zombie is a small yellow flower.
What are you doing here?
I couldn't sleep, Dad.
I felt very tense.
I'm afraid.
As long as you don't go
into the garden alone, you're safe.
Would I let you come to any harm?
Dad, I want to learn to fight.
What was that? I can't hear you.
When will I learn how to fight?
Can you turn your robot off?
I fight so you don't have to.
I want you to use your head
for something else...
other than a punching bag, like me.
Your head doesn't look
like a punching bag.
No.
This is good, thanks.
It looks like a baseball glove.
You're a smart-ass, aren't you?
Mr. Balboa, Mr. Creed on the phone.
There are all types of shark.
Hammer shark...
blue, mako and white shark.
The chances of the imbeciles
getting the right one...
These types of shark aren't found here.
It's very unlikely.
I don't mean that it isn't
the shark we're looking for.
It probably is, Martin.
It's a man-eater!
Its jaws are different
from the bites on the victim.
I want to be sure
and you want to be sure.
We want to be sure, don't we?
Anybody else seen them?
No.
Get me the duct tape.
I want you to call me Bruce.
What's Bruce?
It's a name.
Every time you say Bruce, I'll turn.
I want a name like that too.
Take your pick.
You can have any name you like.
I want you to call me "back".
You can't be called that.
We call our back, back.
Bruce!
It's nice. My wife and I
thought your house would be like this.
Thanks.
Where's the perfume I got you?
In the bathroom.
It's very good perfume.
My wife absolutely insisted
on getting you that one.
We thought of getting you a vase
but we thought it wouldn't match the house,
so we chose perfume.
Do you live here alone?
Yes. My parents are on the fourth floor.
I hope your kids have bad influences
and develop a bad personality.
I wish this with all my heart.
As punishment for the evil
you have caused my family.
She hit my leg with a hammer.
He's lying! It wasn't me.
I came in and saw a cat with a hammer
jumping out the window.
She did it.
You're hallucinating from the pain.
You'll need analgesics and a plaster.
I bet it's broken, Dad.
Did you do what we said?
Did you take precautions?
He didn't have time, Dad.
From what I saw, it was very quick.
Really quick.
You devote less time to the kids.
Don't cry.
The kids might see you crying.
Haven't you combed today?
I have.
I had a tough day.
We have to find someone
to replace Christina.
You can't trust anyone anymore.
Nobody else will enter this house.
I'm considering assigning the task
to the elder one.
Then again he could make
his own mind up.
That's probably better.
Do that again, bitch,
and I'll rip your guts out.
I swear on my daughter's life
that you and your clan
won't last long in this neighborhood.
Mom!
I found two little zombies!
Shall I bring them to you?
Mom!
It's our wedding anniversary.
We'll celebrate by eating cakes
and decorating the house
with balloons and lights.
Sit up a bit.
I think my dogtooth is moving.
You're imagining things.
It isn't moving at all.
- Did you sleep well last night?
- Great.
Dad I'm tired. Can I stop?
Sure, honey, if you can't go on.
Enough.
Dad, will you give me the harpoon gun?
I've told you,
the harpoon gun is dangerous.
I can lick your ear if you want.
Bruce!
I'll go get the dog tomorrow.
The fifth level will be finished
by now for sure.
Either drink the orange juice while it's fresh
or don't drink it at all.