♪ Sweet dreams
are made of this ♪
♪ Who am I to disagree? ♪
♪ I travel the world
and the seven seas ♪
♪ Everybody's looking
for something ♪
♪ Some of them
want to use you ♪
want to get used by you ♪
♪ Some of them
want to abuse you ♪
want to be abused ♪
♪ Hey, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Sweet dreams
are made of this ♪
♪ Who am I to disagree? ♪
♪ I travel the world
and the seven seas ♪
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.MY-SUBS.com ]=-
Come on in.
Yes, he just arrived.
He is wearing beige pants,
brown leather derby lace ups,
a white shirt
with what must be
his initials on it.
B.M.F.?
No, I'm sorry, R.M.F.
No, I'm not short-sighted,
Raymond, it's just that
the R is badly embroidered
and it looks like a B.
No, his shirt's ironed
just fine.
Would you like me
to take a photo
and send it for you to see?
Yes, I told you, it's fine.
Okay. Okay.
Raymond,
the note that you left me
this morning was perfect.
I'm going to water the plants
and then...
I think I might practice
playing the song on the piano.
It's been so long since I last
practiced playing the piano.
Does it hurt anywhere else?
My arm hurts.
Probably broken.
I think you should take me
to the nearest hospital
right away.
I... I should definitely be
examined by a doctor.
It's probably best
they keep me in
for a few days
for observation.
There might be some sort of
internal bleeding
or something.
Don't worry,
they'll check you for
everything at the hospital.
Good morning, darling.
Good morning.
You got in late last night.
Sorry, I was asleep
before 11:00.
It's fine.
I got held up at the office,
that's why I was late.
Hmm.
What happened
to your forehead?
It's nothing.
There was an accident
on the drive home last night,
but it's nothing serious.
What do you mean?
Shouldn't you see a doctor?
I went by the hospital
last night,
but they assured me
it's nothing that, um...
They just gave me
some tranquilizers.
Robert,
you should've called.
You went to the hospital
on your own?
It was nothing.
There's no need to worry.
Raymond sent it yesterday.
He is such a sweet man.
I don't know how
we can ever repay him
after everything
he's done for us.
A genuine smashed
McEnroe racket from 1984.
It must have cost him
a fortune.
Isn't it wonderful, Robert?
Yes, it's wonderful.
Give Raymond a kiss for me.
I'll give him a call, too.
I rang him just now,
but he didn't pick up
and I didn't want
to call again right away,
in case I woke him.
Sure, I'll do that.
Tell him it's the nicest thing
he's ever given us.
I'll tell him.
"Tomorrow, Wednesday,
wake-up time, 0700 hours.
"Outfit, black monk
strap shoes,
"blue suit,
white shirt and tie.
"Lunch, beef burger,
vanilla milkshake.
"Dinner, linguine Bolognese,
potatoes au gratin...
"chocolate mousse
with almonds and berries.
"At 2300 hours,
"drink one glass of whiskey,
"Johnnie Walker Red
on the rocks.
"Read Anna Karenina till 2330.
"No sexual intercourse.
Have a nice day, R."
Hello.
Good morning, Robert.
Good morning, Louise.
Mr. Frischmann wants
to see you in his office.
Three o'clock, in his office.
Uh,
I might need to pass by
the construction site
this afternoon.
I might not make it
back in time.
If I were you,
I wouldn't pass by
the construction site
this afternoon.
Mr. Frischmann wants to
see you in his office at 3:00.
All right,
then, Louise.
Thank you. Bye.
Hi. Can I go in,
or is he busy?
He's just on the phone.
Won't be long.
Have I ever shown you
my son?
No.
He's adorable.
-Isn't he?
-He really is.
Aren't you and Sarah
thinking of having children?
Sarah can't have children.
She has this issue
with her ovaries.
Sorry, I had no idea.
That's all right.
Good afternoon, Robert.
Don't just stand there,
sit down.
Were you waiting long?
No, 15 minutes or so.
Hey,
your hair's nice like that.
Don't get it cut,
let it grow a little longer.
And you've lost more weight,
I think.
Skinny men are the most
ridiculous thing there is.
We've gone over this before,
you must put on a few pounds.
I told you that last time.
-But I have.
-You most certainly have not.
You're even skinnier now.
We'll have to take
another look
at your eating plan
for the week.
Did you read Anna Karenina?
I'm just finishing it off.
There's a few pages left.
Sit.
Will you have something
to drink?
I would love a vodka.
I will be joining you
after all,
for, uh, your trip to Munich.
I reckon I can make it.
They won't need me
at the construction site here
next week anyway.
Sarah might be joining us too.
If you don't mind, that is.
Also, maybe
she told you already,
but she loved the racket.
Said it was the best gift
you've ever given us.
That's great.
You know what?
I didn't pour you a vodka.
I think a whiskey now
would be much better.
Yes, right,
a whiskey is much better.
Raymond,
I'm sorry about yesterday.
Truly sorry.
What did you do today?
I woke up at 7:30, showered,
didn't wash my hair,
and then drank my juice.
-Orange and lemon?
-Orange and lemon.
Did you and Sarah
fuck this morning?
At 8:30,
right after breakfast.
Very good.
I spoke with Sarah
an hour ago.
And yes, she did say
she liked the gift very much.
Yes, she said
it was the nicest thing
you've ever given us.
She liked it
more than Ayrton Senna's
-scorched racing helmet?
-Oh, much more.
-Thank you so much.
-Oh, no, thank you.
You deserve all these things.
It's the least I can do.
Raymond...
sorry again about yesterday.
I don't know what went wrong.
I should have
been hospitalized.
The doctor just couldn't
be trusted, he must...
The doctor who saw you
is excellent,
he's a friend of mine.
And I spoke with him earlier
and he said
that there was really no need
to have you hospitalized
for a scratch
on your forehead.
My back hurts.
Here and here.
Robert, listen.
It doesn't matter.
These things happen.
And anyway...
I'm going to give you
a chance to make it up to me.
We're going to
repeat the crash
two days from now,
and this time
you can do it right.
Same place, same time,
same midnight blue BMW.
Ram into him at a higher speed
and everything will be fine.
I can't crash
any faster, Raymond.
Robert...
in two days,
it'll be happening again,
and you'll see to it
that you're driving faster.
-I don't think I can do that.
-Really now, Robert...
I don't have time for this.
You have two hours
to think it over.
Go to Cheval, sit at the bar.
Ask them
to bring you a drink,
something nonalcoholic
so it doesn't
cloud your judgment.
Then come by my house tonight
and let me know
what you've decided.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening.
What can I get you?
I'd like a double
Johnnie Walker Red
on the rocks, please.
Just kidding.
A Virgin Mary, please.
Right away, sir.
That was quick.
Enjoy.
Hey, Robert.
Sorry, Robert. Vivian and I
were just having
a very interesting
conversation about palm trees,
so I'll be with you
in just a moment.
Uh, so,
tell me about that weevil.
Yes. So...
there's this weevil
that's destroying them.
It's carried on the wind.
So, it has wings?
Or it's very light,
I don't know.
And it only attacks
palm trees.
And so now...
it's illegal to buy or sell
palm trees
in various places
across Europe and Africa.
Which means that you can't
just walk into a nursery
and buy a palm tree,
because they're banned
because of this weevil.
So, now they're bought
and sold on the black market.
And this weevil
only attacks palm trees?
Yes. Only palm trees.
Okay.
That is really amazing.
I'll leave you two
alone now.
Amazing, eh?
-Really amazing.
-Huh.
Right then, Robert.
I'm all ears.
Yes.
Raymond, I've given this
a lot of thought,
and I can't do
what you're asking me to do.
Again. You come in
and sit down there
before you speak.
-Raymond.
-I want you to come in
and sit down there
before you speak. Vivian.
I'll leave you two alone now.
-Raymond, I've thought...
-And, actually,
it was better when you said it
standing up, so...
go out and come back in.
Do it by yourself.
Without Vivian.
Raymond, please.
Raymond, I can't do
what you asked me to do.
I'm sorry.
Anything else you want, yes.
But that one thing,
it's just too frightening.
If I crash any faster...
the other driver
might be killed.
Yes.
I know
what might happen, Robert.
And the driver
of the other vehicle
is fine with losing his life,
he's agreed to it in fact,
so there's really no
need for you
to worry about that. If you...
really don't want to
disappoint me...
that is, Robert.
If you truly love me, I mean.
What you're asking,
it's too much.
I love you, Raymond,
I love you.
But this is too much.
No, no, no.
You don't love me at all.
I can feel it.
This isn't love.
I don't know what it is,
but it's clearly not love.
But, no matter.
I knew this day would come.
It's fine.
Ten years it lasted.
That's not nothing.
The truth is...
I expected you
to tire of it all far sooner.
Can I just
say something?
This doesn't have
anything to do with love.
Right then, Robert,
you're free now.
You can go on your way.
Tonight,
tomorrow, and every day
from now on, you're free to
sleep whenever you like,
fuck whenever you like.
Have however many children
you like.
Wear whatever socks you like.
Raymond, please.
I never denied you anything.
Even when you asked me...
told me not to have
any children.
I wasn't happy about it,
but I didn't say a word.
Ask me for anything else
you want and I'll do it.
But I can't be responsible
for another man's death.
I'm tired, Robert.
You don't have to give me
anything back.
You can stay in the house
you've been living in
and keep the car of course.
Goodbye, Robert.
They took the racket.
What did you say?
Raymond came in
during the night
while we were sleeping
and took the racket.
That's so strange.
Who could have
taken the racket?
The alarm didn't go off.
I'm calling the police.
Raymond knows
the code, darling.
To be precise,
he picked the code
out himself.
You didn't know that.
1962. The year he was born.
And there's more.
The two of us are together
because that's what
he decided.
That night in Cheval,
he picked you out for me.
He saw you
sitting there on your own
and he told me to go over
and flirt with you.
I liked you a lot too...
don't get me wrong,
but he made me do it.
He suggested I make it
seem like an accident,
told me to pretend I'd hurt
my hand to get us talking.
The notes in the flowers
I sent you, he wrote those.
He picked out this house,
these stools,
-he picked out this robe...
-Robert,
you need to be
heading to the office.
I'm not done yet.
There's one last thing.
I never told you this before.
And it's terrible...
what I'm about to tell you,
I know that...
but you need to hear it.
The reason we never
managed to have a child
all these years,
is not because you couldn't.
It's because...
it's because
Raymond was secretly
paying doctors
to mess things up.
Those weren't miscarriages,
Sarah, they were abortions.
The wireless
customer you called
is not available at this time.
Sarah.
The wireless customer
you called is not available...
Okay, safely.
Safely. Safely.
Remember, it's not a race.
All right. Great job.
Kick. Don't forget to kick.
Very good. Very good.
All right.
Yeah, get your kickboard
if you need it.
Robert, I haven't seen you
in so long.
Have you lost weight?
Will, is Sarah around?
Sarah quit. This morning.
Over the phone too.
Ah, she quit.
She did tell me
she was planning to,
but I've had so much work
recently, Will,
you can't imagine
how much work,
and I forgot all about it.
I did ask
if it was health-related,
but she said no.
I just, I hope
it's nothing serious.
No, no, she just
tired herself out lately,
that's all.
I'm sure you'll have
a great time in Munich.
Why don't you stay there
a few extra days?
I'm sure things will be better
when you get back.
When are you flying out?
In a couple of days.
-Robert.
-Where is my wife?
Raymond isn't here right now,
and I'm getting ready
to head out myself.
Then I'll wait for him
to get back. Sarah!
He left for Germany.
Is my wife with him?
Did they go together?
Robert, get out.
Are the three of you
fucking maybe?
Get out of my house
right now
or I will call Raymond
and you will rue the day
that you ever set
foot in here.
I suggest,
you run back home
to your mom and dad,
while you still can.
Because getting fucked
by an old man like Raymond,
you deserve better than that.
Getting fucked by an old man
like Raymond
is, however,
exactly what you deserve.
You're pathetic.
Get out of my sight.
Good evening.
This here is
Ayrton Senna's helmet.
The blue and green
stripes symbolized
speed and aggression,
whereas the yellow all over
symbolized youth.
Mmm.
What was it
the yellow symbolized?
Youth.
These are the shoes
worn by Michael Jordan,
in the game against
the Washington Bullets in '84
when he led the Bulls
to a home win by 16 points.
Hmm. $10,000.
For what?
For everything.
You can't be serious.
That ping pong ball alone
is worth $5,000.
$12,000.
$20,000 at least.
Yes, good morning.
Uh, can I speak
with Mr. Smith please?
It's Robert Fletcher.
Thank you.
Mr. Smith, I would like to
see you if I can.
I'd like to speak with you.
Yes.
No, no, tomorrow's fine.
Should I come by your office?
In the afternoon sometime?
Yes, that's perfect.
Raymond?
Raymond's well.
He's in Germany,
on a business trip.
Sarah, I'm worried.
Please call to let me know
you're okay.
And I have some good news.
I'm meeting with
Edward Smith tomorrow.
You know how much
he wants me to work for him.
He'll go nuts
when I tell him I'm available.
Please, Sarah, come home.
I miss you.
I know you miss me too.
I'm sorry if I upset you.
I love you very much.
Okay. Bye.
Excuse me, do you know
if Mr. Smith will be long?
I'm not sure, Mr. Fletcher.
I don't imagine so.
He's in his office?
No, he's out.
But he knows I'm here,
right?
He's well aware of all
the appointments he has today.
Don't you worry about that.
Is that
cute little boy
your son?
My grandson.
I don't have
any children.
My wife had this issue,
you see,
but she's all better now
and we're thinking
of having one.
That's great.
Hello.
Yes. Of course.
Hmm. Mr. Fletcher,
I just spoke with Mr. Smith.
And?
Unfortunately
something came up
and he won't be
coming by the office today.
But we will be in touch
to arrange a new appointment.
Right.
How about I call you tomorrow?
We'll be in touch.
Are you ready
to order, sir?
Um, I don't know.
I can't decide.
I know I'm not hungry.
That's fine, sir.
How about something to drink?
Yes.
There's a wine list
on the back.
I'll have the...
Could you recommend me
a wine?
White? Red?
Whatever's best.
I mean, whatever you think.
I recommend a white Chardonnay
from New Zealand.
Perfect.
I slipped and hurt my hand.
I guess someone must've
spilled water on the floor.
It's probably just a sprain.
Good morning, Raymond.
Can I have just five minutes
of your time, please?
I'm afraid not.
Raymond, please.
I want to say I'm sorry.
I regret what I did,
it was totally unacceptable,
you have every right
to be angry.
Please forgive me.
I made a mistake.
I... I made a mistake.
I'm already running late.
I think the best thing
for you
is to go home
and calm yourself down.
I don't want to go home.
Good morning, Raymond.
Can I have just five minutes
of your time, please?
I'm afraid not.
Raymond.
Please, I had
a horrible dream
last night
and that's all
I've been seeing
in my sleep lately.
I want to say I'm sorry.
I regret what I did.
It was totally unacceptable
and you have every right
to be angry,
but please forgive me.
I made a mistake.
I'm already running late.
I think it's best you go home
and calm yourself down.
I don't want to go home,
Raymond. Can I come up
-to your office, please?
-No, you cannot.
I want to go up
to your office.
I think I made myself clear
the other day.
What you're doing now
is completely ridiculous.
Just go.
Before you
humiliate yourself
any more
than you already have.
It's for your own good.
Good morning.
Raymond, I'll do
whatever you tell me.
I'll never object
to anything ever again.
I've even started
gaining weight.
You can't imagine
how much I've been eating.
I ate two burgers
and drank two milkshakes
just now
and I finished reading
Anna Karenina.
You were right.
It really was beautiful.
There were two moments
where I cried.
Go fuck yourself, Robert.
Yes, sir.
Two double
Johnnie Walker Reds
on the rocks, please.
-Hi.
-Hi, Rita.
Thank you so much.
No, no,
I wanted to thank you
for everything.
How's the foot?
Are you all right?
Are you hurt?
Just a lil...
a little.
A little?
I missed that step.
I didn't see it.
What step?
There's a step
in the men's bathroom.
Should I get you some ice?
No, don't worry.
It's nothing.
I wouldn't want
to trouble you.
Thank you so much, though.
You're very kind.
That doesn't look
like nothing.
Are you here with anyone?
No, it's just me.
I have this
exact same car.
Really?
What are the chances?
It hurts more now.
Well, hang in there.
We're only five minutes away.
Have I seen you
somewhere before?
Are you at that bar
and restaurant often?
No, that was
my first time there.
Are you an architect
by any chance?
No, I work
at an opticians downtown.
I'm Rita Fanning.
Robert Fletcher.
I know I've got
a lot of nerve,
what with you
taking me to the hospital
yesterday and all, but I have
one more favor to ask.
Sure, what is it?
I want to take you out
for dinner one night.
It's the least I can do
and it would make me
very happy.
-If it's not a chore.
-I'd like that.
It would be my pleasure.
-Really?
-Of course.
Tomorrow evening?
Tomorrow evening.
Rita, it's Robert.
Um, I hope you're okay.
I'm outside your house
right now.
I guess you
forgot about tonight.
Call me when you can.
Have a nice night.
Come in.
Hi, Rita.
Hi.
What happened?
How are you?
I'm a little worse
than you were
that day at the restaurant.
I'm sorry
about the other night.
There's no need to apologize.
What happened?
I was driving home
from work and
I crashed into
another vehicle at
an intersection and...
I don't remember
anything after that.
I woke up and I was here.
What kind of vehicle was it?
A blue BMW I think.
What about the other driver?
The other driver was a man.
I don't know,
after a certain point
I don't remember a thing.
I mean, is he alive?
He's in pretty bad shape
from what I've heard,
but yes, he's alive.
That's fortunate.
I can't believe
this happened to you.
Are you in pain?
My shoulder hurts a little.
And to be honest,
my whole body does.
Would you like me to
call someone for you or
-can I get you anything?
-No, that's fine.
Actually, could you help me
use the bathroom?
Of course.
Thank you.
Gorgeous flowers.
Aren't they?
They're from some
friends of mine.
They actually left
just before you arrived.
I'm so happy to see you.
Hmm.
I brought you a book
to help you pass the time.
Thank you so much.
Have you read it?
Yes.
Just recently, in fact.
It's amazing.
I cried half the time.
I'll bring you
some other book then.
No, leave it with me,
I'll read it again.
No, I'll bring you
another book.
Well, I have to go.
They're expecting me
back at the office.
Uh, I'll come
visit again tomorrow.
Thanks for coming.
Excuse me.
Could you do me
a favor, please?
Sure.
Could you help me
get to the men's room?
I banged my foot
and it really hurts.
Thank you so much.
Easy, easy.
Right here, sir.
I did it. I did it.
I did good.
Vivian...
didn't I tell you
that this young man here
would not disappoint me?
You sure did, Raymond.
♪ I know your eyes
in the morning sun ♪
♪ I feel you touch me
in the pouring rain ♪
♪ And the moment
that you wander far from me ♪
♪ I want to feel you
in my arms again ♪
♪ And you come to me
on a summer's breeze ♪
♪ Keep me warm
in your arms... ♪
♪ Then you softly leave ♪
♪ And it's me
you need to show ♪
♪ How deep is your love?
How deep is your love? ♪
♪ How deep is your love? ♪
♪ I really need to learn ♪
♪ 'Cause we're living
in a world of fools ♪
♪ Breaking us... ♪
Hello.
Yes?
I can't hear you.
That's a difficult
situation for anybody.
I think Daniel just needs
a little bit more time.
Listen, Neil,
give me no excuses.
I know he needs time.
I was first to say
that he needs time,
but there are limits.
Look at him.
Look how he's acting
with that suspect.
As if they just fucked
for the first time
and he doesn't know
how to tell him
that he loves him.
Help him. He's your friend.
Help him snap out of it.
-All right?
-Mm.
Have a good day, sir.
Thank you, sir.
You too.
That suspect was
looking at me funny.
Well, everyone looks at us
funny, Daniel.
We're the police.
No, he was looking at me
real funny.
Didn't he look
a little like Liz?
Around this area, around
this part of his face,
around the chin?
That little punk
looked nothing like Liz. No.
You're thrown by the fact
that Liz is slimmer.
She should have lost
even more weight by now.
Trust me, he looked like her.
If they are still alive,
what are they eating?
Fish, I guess.
Something like that.
Daniel, hear me out.
The weather's already
getting better.
They haven't called off
the search, you know that.
And I genuinely believe,
no matter how much
you think otherwise,
that they're doing
a great job out there.
I heard this morning,
the head of the rescue mission
is hopeful.
It's just a matter of time,
he said,
now that
the boat's been found.
He said that today?
Around two hours ago.
Will you come by
the house tonight?
We'll come by
the house tonight.
We brought chocolate cake
for dessert.
Chocolate will be banned again
in this house,
you know,
once Liz gets back,
so we thought...
Would you like me
to cook your meat
a little more?
That's okay.
It's a little bloody
for my liking
but it's delicious
all the same.
I like mine almost raw...
-but I can cook yours...
-No, no. Sit yourself down.
Sit yourself down.
It's superb.
I had no idea
what a good cook
you are, Daniel.
-Better even than Liz.
-Hmm.
But soon she'll be back
making us that wonderful
roast lamb of hers.
Well, you're
a wonderful cook,
too, Martha.
Not like Liz.
I'll never forget the night
the two of you came over
and everything went
completely wrong.
Remember that baked salmon?
It came out of the oven
almost charred.
Completely dry.
You're wrong about that.
It was wonderful.
It was awful.
And I made chocolate mousse
for dessert.
Completely forgot that
Liz doesn't eat chocolate.
She was so polite about it.
She said something funny.
I can't quite remember
what it was she said.
Do you remember what it was?
Thank you so much.
What for?
For everything.
Both of you. Thank you.
There's no need for that.
Do you mind
if we watched a video?
One of the old ones.
I... I, um...
I don't think
that's a good idea, Daniel.
I think we'll all find that
a little awkward.
Hmm.
Just a little.
-Well--
-A minute, no more.
To remember her by.
I really don't think
we should.
It won't do you any good,
and it'll be pretty strange
for us, too.
And you already
showed us those...
wonderful photos of Liz
on the boat on her travels.
I'd never seen those
photos of her
with those reefs
she discovered.
Real impressive.
Okay.
Are you sure
you don't want
something else to drink?
Oh, no, I'm fine.
I'm fine, too.
Those photos at the reefs
were great, weren't they?
Really great.
-Okay.
-Hmm.
Okay.
Well, we can watch
a little of that video.
Thank you.
Could you turn
the volume down a little?
Sure.
Hello?
Yes?
Who's there?
-Is this
Mr. Daniels?
-Yes.
Did I wake you?
No, no,
you didn't wake me.
I have some good news
for you, sir.
At midnight last night,
we located your wife.
Really?
Oh, God.
Come here.
We were worried about you.
I missed you so much.
I missed you both
so much.
I can't believe I'm back.
That I'm okay.
I heard that
Carol is still missing.
Jonathan is in the next room,
but he's in pretty bad shape.
-Daniel.
-Yes, my love?
I want you to take me home.
Yes, I will.
Be patient.
You've lost weight,
you're still weak.
What did you
all eat out there
for so long?
Fruit.
Animals.
Fish.
How's Jonathan?
Not great, Daniel.
He's lost a lot of blood.
And they told me
his leg's infected
and they said
there's a chance
he'll lose it.
He'll pull through.
I know it.
He's one tough cookie.
They're operating
on him tomorrow morning.
We'll know more
by 12:00 noon,
but no one's optimistic
about his chances.
I heard Liz
is doing well, though.
You can't imagine
how happy I am for her.
I knew
this would happen someday.
I don't know why,
but I just knew.
When we all
get out of
this hospital, Daniel,
I am not letting him
go out
to sea again.
No way. No more research,
no more reefs,
no more diving.
That's it.
That's right.
You put a stop
to it, Sharon.
Have you told
the children yet?
I don't know
what to tell them.
Anything you need,
just give me a call.
Thanks so much.
What was that about?
What's gotten into him?
He's never acted
like that before.
Are you hungry?
I can fix you
something to eat.
There's eggs.
I could make you an omelet.
There's also some leftover
meat from the other night.
I've missed eating
something sweet.
What is that?
Oh, chocolate.
That's what I want.
Mmm.
You sure you're all right?
I'm totally sure.
Thank you.
And when
the weather turned,
they were only
one day away
from heading home.
Liz kept insisting
they drop anchor somewhere
and wait
for the storm to pass,
and the others insisted
that they set out.
Happy to hear
that Liz is back
safe and sound, Daniel.
Thank you, Chief.
All right.
She told me
from a certain point on
everything happened
real fast,
and all she remembers is
trying to swim to shore.
She also said
how strange it was
that even
when her life was in danger,
all she could think about
was the instruments,
the equipment,
her files and notes
on the boat that
had been lost.
Ever the professional.
And so very brave.
Apart from Liz,
one of her colleagues
survived, too,
but he's in
critical condition.
He lost a lot of blood
and I heard
they amputated his leg.
The other three
were all found dead.
That's awful. Look,
let's not dwell
on unpleasant things.
What's important is that Liz
is well and here with us.
Yes.
Really is amazing
she made it.
Are you sure
this outfit is okay?
Of course it is.
Besides,
it's your favorite.
Yes. Yes, it is.
I don't think
these heels
go with it.
I'll try a different pair.
Your shoes don't fit?
Oh, they fit.
They're fine.
I guess my feet
are a little swollen.
They're fine.
It's fine.
They're on.
I think I heard the doorbell.
Can I have a cigarette?
Sure.
I didn't know
you smoked, Liz.
I don't.
I've never smoked.
Can you believe that?
I've never even tried.
I just really felt
like a cigarette.
Should we all go upstairs
to the bedroom?
I think it's best
we don't go up
to the bedroom tonight.
So, what,
we're going to fuck
on the table?
Come on, Daniel,
that would be weird.
Uh,
we'd better be
getting home soon.
Liz, you must be tired
and I have to be up early.
But everything
was wonderful
tonight, though.
I think you're right.
I think we should leave it
for some other time.
Maybe next time.
I'll clean up the plates.
I just can't stand having
food in front of me
when I've finished eating.
I will help.
No, Martha, you sit,
I'll be right back.
No, I want to, please.
Thank you.
Oh, I've had far
too much to eat tonight,
and when I've had
far too much to eat,
I don't sleep well at all.
Neil, I'm going to
tell you a secret.
You are my best friend,
and I want to tell you
a secret.
You are.
Aren't you my best friend?
Of course, Daniel.
That woman isn't Liz.
She's not my wife.
What do you mean?
I mean,
she's not really Liz.
I don't know
what's going on,
what's happened to Liz,
but what I do know
is that she's lying.
She's not really my wife.
Daniel, you've had
a lot to drink tonight.
Just listen to me. Listen.
We were out for a drive
and I told her
to put on my favorite song.
Anyone who's
close to me knows
which song
is my favorite song.
Holiday.
Right.
But when I asked her
to play that song...
that's not what she played.
♪ When there's lightning ♪
♪ You know it always
brings me down ♪
You like that one a lot,
too, though.
Yes, a lot.
But that's not
my favorite song.
Daniel...
you know Liz
has been through
a lot lately.
She found the chocolate cake
that you brought over
in the refrigerator
and ate it.
All of it.
Daniel...
you mustn't forget Liz
was starving for days.
It doesn't surprise me
she had a little chocolate
now that she's back.
I think it's time.
We should be going.
Um, it's pretty late
and I'm really tired.
-Thanks for everything.
-Hmm.
Yeah.
Thank you both so much.
Liz!
I have to leave for work.
I'm late.
Can you believe
that the whole time
I was lost
in the middle of nowhere,
cold and hungry,
all I could think
about wasn't
the hot meals
I was missing,
or the warm blankets
back home.
Or even my dad.
All I could think about...
-was your cock.
-Liz.
We could fuck
with you wearing
your uniform.
Or I could wear it.
No, you wear it.
Ow!
Have you lost your mind?
That hurt.
I'm sorry, darling.
I thought you liked
a little club play
when we fuck.
Tonight,
we honor Liz
who has advanced
our maritime research
with her passion,
her persistence,
her expertise.
And now I have
a little surprise
for you all.
You could at least
try and look happy for Liz.
It's outrageous,
the way you've been behaving.
You haven't said
a single word to her
all evening.
You've been treating her
very badly.
Safe and sound.
The helicopter pilot
that located
and recovered
Liz and Jonathan.
George, I'm tired.
Could you stop talking?
Snap out of it.
George,
open your eyes
and look clearly
at what's going on
around you.
Thank you
all so very much.
We might all be in danger.
The most important
thing to me...
What, are you drunk?
...are the people
that I love.
Jonathan,
you should know that
you're in our prayers.
In all of our prayers.
You'll feel better soon.
I know it.
You'll be home with your kids
in no time.
Are you a doctor?
No, Jonathan,
it's me. Liz.
It's Liz, my love.
Can I have some Kool-Aid?
Water...
no Kool-Aid.
Sharon,
why don't we
step outside and...
leave these two alone
for a minute.
I'm sure they have a lot
to talk about.
Can I ask you something?
Are you sure...
that man dying in there
is really your husband?
Are you sure
that's Jonathan?
If I were you...
I'd try putting a pair
of your real husband's
shoes on him
and see if they fit.
And I'd tell your kids
to quit crying because
that man in there
isn't their father.
It's just some guy
that looks like him.
A lot.
But it's not him. And,
whoever did this, Sharon,
has done a really good job.
Almost perfect...
but not perfect enough.
Their feet are different.
Their feet are bigger
and softer for some reason.
And there's
other things, too.
Lots of things.
Sharon...
she asked me
to fuck her
in my uniform,
then hit me...
hard with my club.
Can you believe that?
She left a mark.
We didn't, obviously.
Fuck, I mean.
You know he's in there
right now. With her.
And they're laughing at us,
Sharon. That's a fact.
They're laughing at us.
They're playing us for fools.
-Good morning.
I'd like to transfer
the... the money I have
in a joint account
I share with my wife
to a personal account, please.
Okay. Can I see
some form of ID?
Here you are.
Thank you.
I see you're
a police officer, huh?
-Yes, ma'am, I am.
-Okay.
And did you
want to transfer
the entire balance?
The entire balance. Yes.
Aren't you going
to eat something?
I'm not hungry.
Please, darling, eat.
Would you like
something else to eat?
I'm not hungry.
Hello? Yes?
Liz?
Liz, is that you?
Speak to me,
please, Liz.
You took my phone,
give it back.
Darling, don't start
that again.
Why would I
take your phone?
Monty probably
knocked it behind
the couch or something.
It'll be here somewhere.
We can look for it
when we're finished eating.
Liz!
Give it.
Listen, I have some news
that'll cheer you up.
It'll bring
your appetite back too.
Daniel, I'm pregnant.
I know it sounds impossible
but the doctor said it's true.
She can't explain it.
She said it might be
psychological,
me never being pregnant.
Are you excited to find out
if it's a boy or girl?
I know I am.
Isn't it wonderful?
I want you out of the house.
What did you say?
I want you out
of my house.
-Why?
-You know why.
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
I know what's going on.
I know you're lying to me.
Leave...
and I promise
no one will ever
come looking for you.
But if you don't,
I will have you arrested
and you'll go to jail.
Don't touch me.
Pack your things
and get out.
Without any fuss. Tonight.
I'm not leaving, Daniel.
This is my home.
Passenger,
show me your hands.
Fuck it.
Turn off the vehicle,
please, miss.
Shut up.
Sorry, Officer.
You ran a red light
and you were speeding, miss.
I'll need you to step out
of your vehicle.
Yeah, you're right. Shut up.
I didn't see the red light.
It's all right.
Step out, please, miss.
Place your hands
on the vehicle.
Spread your legs.
What's that in
your pocket, miss?
It's my cell.
I want you
to take it out slowly
and place it on the vehicle.
Where did you get this phone?
Who gave it to you?
It's my phone.
I bought it.
Don't lie to me.
-What?
-Don't lie to me.
Do you know
a woman named Liz?
What? No.
No, that's my phone.
This phone, miss.
Who gave it to you?
-This is my phone.
-What?
-Are you out of your mind?
-That's my phone.
-Put the phone down, man.
Quiet down, sir.
You've got no right
looking at her phone.
Passenger,
remain in the vehicle.
You'll stop right there
if you know
what's good for you.
-Daniel, take it easy.
-I said, put the fucking...
-Daniel,
what the fuck?
What the fuck!
Bravo Two to headquarters,
shots fired. Subject down.
I'm sorry, it was an accident.
Here, give me your hand.
Daniel, are you shitting me?
What the fuck are you doing?
I'm sorry.
Dr. Evans.
Hi, Neil.
Dr. Evans,
how did it go?
He'll be
on medication
for a few months,
but it's nothing serious.
At least
it doesn't seem serious.
In the simplest
possible terms,
I'd call it a mild form of
persecutory delusion.
I can't say what caused it,
but I think he'll be fine.
He was perfectly cooperative.
It'll take some time,
but he'll get over it
in my opinion.
Can he carry on working?
It would be better
if he took some time off
from the force.
Better for him,
and for everyone here.
And he's not a danger
to himself?
Or to others?
No, he's just
a little confused.
He poses no real danger
to anyone.
So long as he
keeps taking
his medication,
I think he'll be fine.
He really put the fear
in me, Doctor.
It was like a madman.
I got scared.
I thought he was
going to kill
everyone out there.
Me included.
There's nothing
to worry about.
Daniel,
are you going to eat?
Just answer me.
Yes or no?
Why are you
doing this to me?
You'll starve to death.
Is that what you want?
What else can I do?
I don't know
what else to do.
Talk to me, please.
You have to eat something.
I'll make you
whatever you'd like.
Just tell me
what you want,
and I'll make it.
Whatever you want.
Oh...
Sweetheart,
I don't know
what to say.
I feel ashamed
to call that monster
your husband.
I always knew
that there was
something not quite
right with him,
but I always hoped
that maybe...
Don't you dare
speak about Daniel that way.
He's given me everything.
He loves me like no one else,
and all you do is judge him.
Don't you dare
speak badly about him
to me ever again.
You hear me, Dad?
Apologize for what you said.
To me. Now.
Dad, last night
I had a dream.
I was lying on that beach
where they found me.
I don't remember
what I was wearing,
but it was like
I had been there for years.
And you were there.
Daniel was there.
We all were.
Funny thing is,
life in that place
wasn't like it is here.
It took me
a few days to realize,
but that place went by
different rules.
There, dogs were in charge.
People were animals
and animals were people.
I must admit, Dad, the dogs
treated us pretty well.
They gave us food...
and they bandaged our wounds
after licking them,
and they never bit us,
even when we tried
to hurt them.
And every morning
they gave us chocolate to eat.
Because dogs mustn't eat
chocolate, you know.
Lamb, which is
my favorite food
was a rare treat,
and the dogs mostly
kept that for themselves.
For the first few days,
I refused to eat
and I waited
for leftover lamb chop,
but someone else
always got to it first so...
eventually, I just ate
the chocolate
because there was
lots of it around.
And I didn't like it much
but it was better than going
hungry and so...
from then on,
I ate chocolate every day.
And here's the conclusion
I came to.
It's better
to eat something
that's always available
when you're hungry
than to depend on something
that runs out early
every morning.
And I mean every morning.
Daniel isn't perfect,
but he's always been
there for me.
Go up and see him now.
He'll be so happy
to see you.
I have things to do.
I got to go.
Go up.
Just for a minute.
Say hello.
Sorry, I got to go.
Some other time.
Hi.
Oh, hi, my darling.
I just went to the store.
I got some wonderful tomatoes
and some beef tenderloin.
I ran into Tammy and Kate.
Tammy said they're really
missing you at work.
I'm hungry.
Yes, my love.
What can I make for you?
Want the beef fillet
I just bought,
or some spaghetti?
There's some salmon
in the freezer.
Is it fish or meat
you want?
Meat.
Wonderful.
-Sweetheart.
-Hmm?
I want you to chop
one of your fingers off
cook it with cauliflower,
and bring it to me to eat.
Or your thumb maybe,
whatever you think is best.
That's what I want.
Can you do that for me?
-Hi, Daniel.
-Hi, Doctor.
Come on in.
I think we're doing
much better, Daniel.
I think the medication is
starting to take effect.
How are you feeling?
I'm feeling better, Doctor.
That's great.
I just worry sometimes.
What about, Daniel?
I want to tell you something.
But first...
I want you to check no one
is listening in. That...
she's not at the door
or anywhere in the,
in the house.
No one's at
the door, Daniel.
Liz is out.
What's troubling you?
That woman...
who says she's Liz...
chopped off her
finger last night
and served it to me
to eat.
I didn't, of course, eat it.
The cat did.
And early this morning,
I woke up
and came downstairs,
to find her punching herself
in the face and belly.
How have you
been sleeping, Daniel?
Not well, Doctor.
I worry
that she'll hurt me, too,
at some point.
You got to get her
out of here,
I'm telling you.
All in good time, Daniel.
Just be patient, okay?
Trust me.
Okay.
All right, Doctor.
Liz,
have you heard of
doctor-patient
confidentiality?
Yes.
So you
know that
you can tell me
anything, right?
Yes, I know.
Did someone hit you, Liz?
What happened to you?
I know you've
just been through
something terribly tragic.
And I am truly sorry
about the miscarriage.
But you have to
speak out, Liz.
If someone is responsible
for all of this...
well, then you
really should say so.
For your own sake.
He hit me.
Daniel did.
But it wasn't his fault.
I talked back.
And he's on these pills
that make him aggressive
from time to time.
He didn't do it on purpose.
He really was very happy
when I told him
I was pregnant.
And you know Daniel...
he would never hurt anyone.
Please don't tell anyone
about this.
I've already put it
behind me.
You should, too.
I'm sorry.
I'm just so tired and
after everything
that's happened...
I just can't anymore.
So thank you so much.
Have a nice day.
Liz...
Hi, Dad.
I'm just calling to say that
I won't be able to
make it today.
I need to go into the office,
there's...
a meeting I can't miss.
Tell Uncle Stanley
I'm so sad not to see him,
and make sure to take
lots of pictures, okay?
Oh, Dad, I forgot.
We're thinking of going away
for a few days
to get some rest.
I'm going to take
some time off, and...
it'll do Daniel good too.
Calm him down.
So don't come around
for a few days, okay?
I'm not sure
where we're going yet.
You know Daniel,
he never can decide.
But it'll probably be
somewhere remote
with bad reception,
so I'll let you know
where we are
when we get there.
Okay, bye.
It's good to see you're up
and about, my love.
Yesterday, the doctor said
we need to up
your medication a little
and get you outdoors
from time to time.
We can go for a walk,
if you like.
No, I don't feel like it.
Whatever you want.
I'm hungry.
I'll make you something.
I'll bring it to you.
You go up.
I'm not just hungry.
I'm famished.
But don't go serving me
any fingers today.
Your fingers are revolting.
In fact, I didn't even eat it.
I fed it to Monty instead.
I need something filling.
Your entire leg, let's say.
Or...
your liver.
It's full of iron, liver.
Ultra-nutritious.
That's what they say.
And that's what
I need to eat today
because I'm feeling weak.
♪ When there's lightning ♪
♪ You know it always
brings me down ♪
♪ 'Cause it's free
and I see that it's me ♪
♪ Who's lost and never found ♪
♪ I cry out for magic ♪
♪ I feel it dancing
in the light ♪
Step
on the scale, please.
Good.
Stand up straight.
Turn around.
Perfect.
Step off, please.
Very good.
You have 10 minutes this time.
-Fifteen.
-Ten minutes.
Not a moment more.
It's the best I can do.
-Ten minutes is fine.
-Okay, follow me.
Wait here.
Do you have some preference,
whether it's man or woman?
No.
This one got brought in today.
Gunshot wound.
That'll do fine.
Anna, you can come in.
Harold, wait here, please.
Nine minutes,
I'll be waiting outside.
He said 10 minutes.
Anna, this is it.
The moment of truth.
Isn't it wonderful?
As you heard yourself,
there's not much time.
Can you imagine
what the final test might be?
Great.
And do you think
you can do it?
I think I can. Yes.
Actually, I'm sure I can,
Ms. Emily.
I think so too,
my dear, sweet Anna.
Go ahead.
What if you say
the dead boy's name?
What's his name?
Martin Lowe.
Dear Martin Lowe,
take life from these hands.
Open your eyes.
I think he moved.
His leg, it moved.
I did it.
Can I try with
some other corpse?
Focus, my dear.
Touch him, if you like.
That might help.
I don't want to touch him.
What is that
supposed to mean?
I think I'm going to be sick.
Is there...
any special cream
I could put under my nose
for the stench?
The smell is awful.
No, there's no...
special cream.
Just try again.
Just calm down
and try again.
Can you not watch me?
If that's okay.
Dear Martin Lowe,
take life from these hands.
Open your eyes.
Anna, that's enough.
There's no point
pressing on.
Andrew, let's go.
Thank you very much, Anna.
Such a shame.
Ms. Emily, can I try
with some other...?
A woman maybe?
Hey, hey.
Thank you very much, Anna.
Please, get up.
Sadly, no,
it wasn't.
Right.
Yes, we're leaving
the morgue now.
We thought
we'd head back tomorrow,
so we're not driving
through the night.
Yes.
Yes, we think
that's best, too.
Yes, she's right here
beside me.
Yes, she's fine.
We're both fine.
Um...
We have water to last till
tomorrow, it'll be enough.
It's around a half a gallon.
All right.
Thank you. Bye, Aka.
I know
we're going to find her.
I'm kind of relieved
that wasn't her.
I didn't like her face.
No humility.
I knew she wasn't the one
we were looking for.
I just didn't want
to tell you.
I mean it.
I had a dream last night.
I didn't want
to tell you before,
because I didn't want
to upset you
but I can tell you
about it now.
I was in a big,
beautiful rectangular pool.
The pool had a diving board.
Anyway, that's not important.
What's important is
I was stuck
at the bottom of the pool.
My hair was caught
in the filtration pump
and I couldn't reach
the surface,
but for some reason
I could hold my breath
underwater indefinitely.
I was getting desperate.
Convinced I would die
of hunger and thirst
that no one would realize
what had happened
before it was too late.
When suddenly
music started playing
from the pool speakers.
A few seconds later,
two figures launched
themselves into the water.
It was two women.
Synchronized swimmers
in spectacular swimsuits
who had just
started their routine.
They looked a lot alike.
They may well have been twins.
Although I couldn't really
tell you for sure
because it's
one of those sports
where everyone wears
identical things
and they have
identical bodies,
and so they always
look like twins.
During one of their
underwater tricks,
one of the two women
spotted me.
To her credit,
she stopped
the routine immediately,
swam down to me,
drawing a knife
from her swimsuit
and cutting my hair,
setting me free.
That's the woman, Andrew.
That's the woman
we're looking for.
She didn't look
anything like Anna,
so I knew she wasn't the one.
You want some water?
No, thank you.
I'm hungry.
Do you want to go out to eat,
or do you want to get
food here?
I'd rather
not go out.
I'll call the diner
downstairs.
I'll go pick it up.
Hello. I'd like to place
an order for takeout, please.
What do you have available
right now?
Burger.
Grilled cheese sandwich.
No. No fish.
We don't eat fish.
And if you want my advice,
you should never
eat fish either. Not ever.
Uh... Burger for me.
Grilled cheese.
And a grilled cheese, please.
No, nothing to drink.
All right, I'll be there soon.
I'm going to take a shower.
Emily?
-Sorry, Andrew.
-Where were you?
We said we'd leave early.
I got up early and I went
for a drive to clear my head
and then I lost track of time
and I realized I was late,
so I came rushing back.
Emily, I've been waiting here
for an hour now.
I call you, you don't answer.
I was worried.
Well, I'm sorry,
I didn't see my phone.
Did you check out already?
What about the invoice?
I got it.
Is there any water left?
I'm really thirsty.
You know,
if you want to go see
your daughter and
your husband, then just go.
I won't say anything
to anyone, you know that.
I know, Andrew.
But I don't want to see them,
and if I change my mind,
I will let you know.
Let's make a move.
-Hey, buddy.
-Hi, Andrew.
There you are.
-Hi.
-Mmm.
Mmm.
Are you hungry?
We already ate, Omi.
Thank you.
Darling,
look who's here.
-Get up and say hello.
-Please.
He was afraid
you wouldn't make it back
before his bedtime.
You're late.
Oh, no, it's my fault.
I overslept.
Jack,
finish eating your fruit,
and then you can show
Emily your hedgehog.
This new candidate
I'm excited about.
She's exactly
what we're looking for.
Hmm.
Here's her details
and some cash.
I booked you a room
at the same motel
you were at last night.
Uh, that's enough apple
for you, Jack.
You don't want to overeat.
Show me your hedgehog.
Everything all right
with Emily?
She's a good one, I think.
Clever and keen.
I adore her.
Yes, Emily's all right.
A little strange sometimes,
but okay.
I'm quite tired
from the journey,
but still really horny.
Do you want to have sex
with me or Aka?
With you.
It was perfect last time.
Unless you've got
someone else
scheduled for tonight.
It was good, wasn't it?
No.
There's no one else
scheduled in.
We both left tonight open
for you and Emily.
I think Andrew
has fallen for Omi.
-Really?
-Hmm.
Last night
when he was sleeping,
I think he was having
a wet dream.
It was actually
really funny.
He kept saying the words
"belly, together, Omi, feet."
Over and over again.
Well, today's his lucky day
because I just got my period,
so he doesn't have a choice.
I was nine days late.
I thought I was pregnant.
I even picked out names.
That's a shame.
How is everything
going with the boat?
The boat's almost ready.
Omi will show you tomorrow.
Oh, that's wonderful news.
Susan?
Susan.
What's happening?
It seems you fell asleep,
my dear.
I'm sorry, Omi.
I was waiting for Aka,
and she didn't come.
I fell asleep.
No matter.
Tomorrow morning,
you'll be tested,
and if you're clean,
you can sleep
with either one of us.
You should go.
I swear I didn't have sex
with anyone
other than you two.
And whoever said that I did,
and I know who it was,
he's only saying that
because he doesn't like me.
I believe you.
You should go.
Hello, Andrew.
Emily.
Andrew, would you like
to go first?
No, it's fine.
Oh, you're so
beautiful, Emily.
So very beautiful.
Thank you.
You are too, Omi.
Omi was right.
Susan is not contaminated.
This is the largest room
on the boat.
It serves as a waiting area
for those seeking
her blessing.
It's wonderful.
Here's where we'll store
her sculpted bust.
It'll be displayed
only for special occasions
and for limited
periods of time,
especially in the summer,
for obvious reasons.
A young artist will carve
her likeness out of ice,
free of charge, of course.
This is her bedroom.
And those?
Those are guest rooms
for when someone can't make it
back to shore
because of bad weather
and they have to spend
the night or,
when she wants someone
or other to stay with her
-at some point.
-Hmm.
Ah, this is the prayer room
where she'll spend
most of her time.
The boat
is much bigger
than I thought
it would be.
It's fantastic.
And the name
is really wonderful.
Jack doesn't think so.
He says it doesn't
remind him of water,
he says it reminds him
of Santa.
It's time for you
to pack up some water
and be on your way.
We'll be going soon.
That woman over there
keeps staring at me.
-Do you know her?
-No.
Excuse me.
Can I have a moment
of your time?
Sure.
My name
is Rebecca King.
I am 29 years old.
I majored in literature
and now work in
the human resources department
of a multinational company.
But that's not important.
My sister Ruth,
she's a veterinarian.
Her clinic is on
Kenneth Avenue, Number 18.
My sister and I are twins.
I think my sister is the one
that you are looking for.
There's no need to waste
any more of your time.
I swear to you, it's her.
Um, Ms. King, hi.
Allow me to introduce myself.
My name is Mark Ball.
This is my wife,
Stephanie Ball.
We're here
visiting her parents.
Her mother's not very well,
you see.
And we are looking
for something actually,
a nice, spacious,
affordable apartment.
I can't quite understand
what it is
-you want from us.
-Listen. Emily?
Here's Ruth's card.
On the back is my address
and phone number.
If you met her, you'd know
exactly what
I'm talking about.
Thank you.
I think we should call
Omi and Aka.
I don't think
that's necessary.
She's clearly insane.
How did she know my name?
Maybe she heard me
calling out to you earlier.
I don't know.
Andrew, that woman and her
twin sister, obviously,
look a lot like
the woman that I saw
in that dream
that I was telling you about.
Let me just remind you, Emily,
in case you forgot,
that the woman
we're looking for,
her twin sister
is supposed to be dead
and Ms. Rebecca King
was very much alive,
speaking to us, no less
right here in the flesh.
I don't know what you saw
when you were asleep,
but I know what I just saw
wide awake
and it doesn't deserve
any more of our attention.
Sweetie, go say hi to Mom.
Sorry, Joseph. I should've
called sometime to explain.
It's fine.
Are you doing okay?
The little one's
starting to look like you.
Around here.
Mom, look at my new shoes.
-Dad just got them for me.
- -Oh, they're really great.
I have to go now.
Stay a while.
We're going to make an omelet.
You want to eat with us?
I have to go.
I have an appointment.
But some other time maybe.
Please don't go.
I'm begging you.
Come by tonight.
You don't have to stay long.
We can just have
dinner together.
Come even for a bit.
An hour, that's all.
We really miss you.
I'll see.
We eat at 8:30.
Oh, that's a bit late.
Where are you staying?
I have to go.
Vanessa Weber.
She's 29 years old.
She's a waitress.
Twin sister,
died six years ago
in a car accident.
They were not
identical twins,
but I think that still
fulfills the requirement.
Yes, that's not a problem.
Who do you think
Jack's biological father is?
What are you talking about?
Omi, of course.
I don't think so.
They look nothing alike.
Maybe he's yours.
Will you cut the crap?
So, Vanessa...
lives with her father.
He's 67 years old.
Can I ask
what year you were born?
-1955.
And marital status?
Separated.
Any children?
I had two daughters.
Had?
They both died sadly.
Both of them?
One in
an automobile accident
a while back,
the other one three weeks ago.
Heart attack
just out of the blue.
If you...
don't mind my asking
one more question,
and you don't need to answer
if you don't want to...
how old were they
when they died?
One was 26.
The other one was 32.
They were twins.
Yes, we know.
We won't take up
any more of your time.
You stay strong, Mr. Weber.
Thank you for the tea,
and for your cooperation.
They really were
beautiful, Mr. Weber.
Tall, slim.
If you don't mind me asking,
how tall were they?
About 5'9".
Such a shame.
And they look around
130 pounds, too?
Such a shame.
Thank you very much,
Mr. Weber, for your time.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
Do we head back today?
Let's leave tomorrow morning.
I mean, the room's
already been paid for.
Unless you prefer to
head back today
for whatever reason?
No,
tomorrow morning's fine.
Plus,
I'm quite tired.
I think I'm coming down
with something.
I feel like a hot bath
and an early night.
Yes, me too.
I think you have a fever.
I'll swing by the pharmacy
to get a thermometer
and some pills for you.
There's no need.
No, there is. We have to get
your temperature down.
Cover up.
I'll be back in five.
Emily.
You didn't come over
last night.
I'm sorry.
I was working
and we finished late.
What are you doing here?
I just, uh, I came
to get some painkillers.
The little one hurt her foot
in ballet class.
Nothing serious,
but she's in some pain.
What happened
to her foot?
Is it broken? Is it swollen?
It's just a sprain.
Yeah. We iced her right away.
She almost didn't cry.
You would've been so proud.
Come see her tonight,
whenever you're done.
I'll try.
Let me see.
You really do have a fever.
101. But I'm sure
you'll be better by tomorrow.
I spoke to Aka earlier.
They were worried,
but I told them
everything is going just fine.
Here, drink your water.
We don't want you catching
pneumonia now, do we?
Emily, I think you're
making too much of this.
Try to sleep a little.
You need your sleep.
I'll be going
to bed soon, too.
Very tired today myself.
Sorry I'm late.
I couldn't get here
any earlier.
Did she go to bed already?
Yeah, a while ago.
She was really looking forward
to seeing you.
Come in.
I can't stay long.
How's her foot?
It's fine.
Still hurts a little, I think,
but she'll be all better
soon enough.
You hungry?
No.
Would you like a drink?
A cocktail, maybe?
I came up with one myself.
I drink it every night
before I go to bed.
Grand Marnier, whiskey,
and two drops of Angostura.
It's like an Old Fashioned,
only it's not.
I call it Emily's Forehead.
Wait.
Oh, uh...
How's everything
at the office?
Did you get that promotion?
Yeah. Um...
A year ago.
Finally got it.
More money, same hours.
Slightly bigger office.
It's pretty good.
It's all good.
Hey, Em,
did you know, um,
your forehead goes perfectly
with a little salmon?
Shall I bring you some?
I don't eat fish, Joseph.
Right.
So...
are you seeing someone,
is there someone else?
No, there's just me.
And you didn't say
where you're staying.
I have to go.
I'm sorry, okay?
I won't ask
any more questions,
just stay a while longer.
One more drink, hmm?
Something feels
different with...
Was that picture there before?
I haven't touched a thing.
Everything's
just as you left it.
Get in.
Emily,
I want you to know that
there's a chance those
contaminating fluids will be
expelled with your sweat.
It's been known to happen.
I'm hopeful.
I need you to be hopeful, too.
We'll raise the temperature
as high as it will go.
We'll give it our best shot.
How unfortunate.
Still contaminated.
It's such a shame,
all this.
You shouldn't have let him
defile you, Emily.
Here's something from
both of us to tide you over
until you...
decide what to do.
We're going to miss you.
I'm sorry.
There's no need
to apologize to us.
The only person you've hurt
is yourself.
You're the one
that's contaminated.
I disappointed you.
And I don't know
how it happened or why.
Emily,
maybe all this happened
for a reason.
Maybe it's for the best.
Not everyone's cut out
for everything.
Maybe you came into this world
to raise a daughter
and live in a house
with a husband.
-It's fine. It's no bad thing.
-No. No.
It's fine.
I'm very thirsty.
Can I have some water, please?
Take care, Emily.
Be well.
We'll miss you very,
very much.
No. No, no.
I have an idea.
If I sweat some more,
then my body
will cleanse itself
and I won't be
contaminated anymore.
I'm already sweating.
Aka!
Come lick me!
Omi, I'm not
contaminated anymore!
I'm not kidding! Honest!
When we were younger
I was more headstrong,
more mischievous
and Ruth was more quiet
and conscientious.
One night when we were both
at home alone,
our parents had left town
for three days,
I had this idea to have
a couple of girlfriends over.
Once we drank almost every
drop of alcohol in the house,
I convinced them
to go skinny-dipping with me.
Ruth was the only one
that hadn't had
anything to drink.
She said that the pool
had been drained
and that it was cold out.
But I pushed her aside,
took off all my clothes,
ran to the edge of
the empty pool and dove in.
My head hit
the bottom of the pool hard.
All I remember
is the screams of the others
and my blood
going down into the drain
before losing consciousness.
When I came to, I found myself
inside the house.
Ruth was sitting beside me.
I got up.
My back hurt a little.
I went to the bathroom.
I was thirsty.
When I looked at my face
in the mirror, I saw that
there wasn't even a scratch.
And then a few seconds later,
I heard Ruth's voice,
she said,
"You were very lucky.
You could have died."
And after that...
"We need to get
the house cleaned up
"because Mom and Dad
will be home soon."
Of course, we never told them
anything about it
when they got back
and we didn't speak of
what happened that night
ever again.
Can I get you another drink?
No, I'm fine, thanks.
You have to go see her, Emily.
Let's say everything
you're telling me
is the truth.
There's still
one major problem.
I know. I know.
If all the conditions
are to be met,
then I ought to be dead.
That's what you mean, right?
That's what I'm telling you.
I really ought to be dead.
Hey!
Come here. Stay. Stay.
Come here.
Come on.
Hi. What happened?
We were out for a walk and...
two strays attacked her.
She didn't even have time
to react.
Come on back.
How old is she?
Five.
She looks older than five.
I mean six.
Sorry, I'm really shaken up.
And what's her name?
Linda.
Who's a brave girl, Linda?
Who's a brave girl?
This dog is like my family.
She's all I have.
I'm not sure
if you can relate.
If you don't mind my asking,
are you married?
Do you have children?
No.
No children.
Her wound goes deep.
Those dogs that attacked her
must have been vicious.
They really were.
Is she on any medication?
Does she have
any other health issues?
No.
So this is what you use
to weigh the animals?
Yes.
Twice daily with food,
and this is for the pain.
I don't know how to thank you.
I just hope
everything turns out okay.
Go.
What are you doing here?
Have you been following me?
Have you completely
lost your mind?
Emily, I'm sorry about
what happened the other night.
Please, Joseph, just leave.
I never want to see you.
I came here to apologize.
We both had a lot to drink.
I really missed you.
Please, just...
just come say hi
to the little one.
You brought the little one?
Okay, fine.
Let's go.
Hi, darling.
Hi, I'm so happy to see you.
I have some wonderful news.
Do you remember the woman
that I was looking for?
I found her.
Mommy found her.
How's your foot?
My foot?
It's fine.
That's good to hear.
Now, do you know
how much of your body
is actually water?
Around 70% water.
Isn't that amazing?
And what about a potato?
76%.
And a bell pepper
is 93.4% water.
And what about a man's sperm?
Why don't I just tell you?
It's around 90% water.
And that's why...
as your mother,
I'd like to give you
a piece of advice.
And I want you to promise me
that you'll follow it.
I want you to stay as far away
from Daddy as possible.
He's contaminated, sadly.
His sweat, his sperm,
his genitals,
all the water that's inside
of him is contaminated.
And I don't want him
contaminating you, too.
Hello?
Emily?
-Yes?
-Hello.
I heard you met Ruth.
I'm so glad.
Listen, Emily,
I'm calling because
I wanted to give you
some really good news.
Remember that problem of ours?
It's all been sorted out.
Emily, are you still there?
Yes.
How has it been
sorted out exactly?
Emily, welcome.
Did you find it okay?
I hope it wasn't any trouble.
No trouble.
Come in.
Would you like
some tea?
No, thank you.
I'm all ears, Rebecca.
Just two more minutes
and you'll know
exactly how it's all
been sorted out.
At least try
one of the cookies.
They're still warm.
Hi. Remember me?
I came to you the other day
with an injured dog.
-Of course, I remember you.
-Her name was Mary.
I thought it was Linda.
I call her Mary.
My husband calls her Linda.
I'm sorry
to show up unannounced.
I'm just leaving town shortly
and I wanted to give you
a gift before I go
just to thank you for
everything you did for Mary.
She's fine now.
I'm so glad. Thank you.
You really shouldn't have.
Would you like to come in?
I don't know
if you wear scarves
but I picked this one out
because it's silk
and it has various
animals on it,
you know,
like your profession.
I love scarves.
Thank you so much.
I'm going to get that coffee.
It must be ready by now.
Oh, thank you so much.
Will you do me a favor?
Will you just try
this scarf on?
It took me ages
to pick it out.
There were actually
four that I liked
and I'm just curious to see
if I made the right choice.
Wow.
It's beautiful. I love it.
I don't think
it really goes with
what I'm wearing today though.
Oh, I think it goes perfectly.
Do you mind if I just...?
Just to see
how it looks on you.
Okay.
Ah! Ow.
What the heck was that?
There he is.
Ruth, wake up.
Wake up.
Ruth.
Put your hand on him.
Touch him.
Say, "Take life from my hands,
and open your eyes."
Say it, Ruth. Ruth, wake up.
Wake up. Please wake up.
Ruth.
Put your hand on him.
Touch him.
What is his name?
I told you his name.
Touch him.
Say it.
Say his fucking name, Ruth!
♪ Doggy with no leash ♪
♪ I am free and I'm yummy ♪
♪ Moving bodies sucking me ♪
♪ They need that
bit o' honey, mmm ♪
♪ I see them drool ♪
♪ They could fill
a whole pool ♪
♪ Baby, slide me in and out ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm ready
for the new ♪
for the truth ♪
♪ And I always
make it purr ♪
♪ Never fuck with the rubber ♪
♪ So you can call me
your mother ♪
♪ Let me teach you
how to please me ♪
♪ How to do me,
how to squeeze it ♪
♪ I'm so easy
you can tease me ♪
♪ All I need is that
you see me ♪
♪ Do my nails, cut my hair ♪
Hang in there, Ruth.
We'll be there
in two hours, max.
The boat is so beautiful,
you have no idea.
You need water?
You must be so thirsty.
I have water with me.
Hang on.
Ruth?
-Thank you. Thank you.
-You're welcome.
Please rate this subtitle at www.osdb.link/pemqe
Help other users to choose the best subtitles