Subtitles by: FrancisSubs
^.^.^.^.COLORED by.^.^.^.^
® Sud_Arun collections ®
A member of Psagmeno.com
( ORCHESTRAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( ORCHESTRAL MUSIC CONTINUES )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
( SACRED CHORAL MUSIC PLAYING )
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
- Nice watch.
- Thanks.
- What's the water resistance?
- 200 meters.
- And it's got a date display?
- Yes, it does.
I might have gone for a metal strap
instead of a leather strap.
- Really?
- Yes.
I think I'd prefer a metal strap.
I've had this one for years.
It's as good as new.
- What's the water resistance?
- 100 meters.
- How long have you had it?
- Nine years.
A little bored of it, actually.
I've been thinking of getting a new one
for quite a while now.
Okay, this is what we'll do.
We'll go to the place where I bought mine.
If I tell them you're a colleague,
a friend,
they'll definitely give you a discount.
Both the owner and his father have been
patients of mine for some time,
so I know them quite well. Think about it.
( MAN INHALES AND EXHALES SHARPLY )
( DOOR OPENS WITH A LOUD CREAK )
- Hi.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Ah, did you eat?
I just had some apple pie.
Do you mind if I go grab something
to eat before we go? I'm starving.
Sure. No problem.
Are you sure you don't want anything?
Chicken wings or...
No, thanks, I'm fine. Do you have money?
I can give you some.
BOY : No, I've got money, thanks.
I'll be right back.
( INDISTINCT BACKGROUND CHATTER )
- MAN : Did you get a haircut?
- BOY : Do you like it?
MAN : Looks great.
Aren't you going to eat your fries?
- I'm saving them till last.
- Why?
I really like fries.
I always save them for last.
I do that, too.
( BOY GULPING NOISILY )
( ICE CUBES CLINK )
- BOY : Sorry I was late today, Steven.
- It doesn't matter.
BOY : I was over at a friend's house.
He got a new motorcycle.
I wanted to check it out.
He took me for a ride.
That's why I was late.
STEVEN : It's fine.
BOY : He even let me ride it
for a little bit.
STEVEN : I hope you were wearing helmets.
BOY : Yeah, of course we were.
We weren't going very fast anyway.
( POLICE SIREN WAILING )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
I got you a present.
Oh, thank you very much. What is it?
- ( PAPER RUFFLING )
- What is it?
( CHINKING )
It's very nice.
Can I give you a hug?
Thank you very much.
- ( EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES )
- ( DISTANT SIREN WAILING )
- BOY : That's fantastic.
- STEVEN : It's water resistant
- up to 200 meters.
- BOY : Does this come off?
I prefer a leather strap.
STEVEN : It comes off, yes.
You can put on any strap you like.
But metal are more hard-wearing,
that's why I got you the metal strap.
It's more expensive, too.
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
- GIRL : Hey, Dad
- Hmm!
Do you remember Claire,
my friend from school?
- STEVEN : Yes.
- GIRL : It's her birthday
and she's having
a party in two weeks, at her place.
- Most of the class are invited. Can I go?
- STEVEN : We'll see.
BOY : Dad, if Kim goes to the party,
can I go with her?
STEVEN : I don't know, darling.
Your mother and I will discuss it
and we'll see.
I'd say they can go.
Claire is a very nice girl.
She's the girl you met at the mall
with her parents
who asked about becoming a doctor.
She's the one who wants to be
a cardiologist.
Yes, I remember.
WOMAN : How was work today?
( CUTLERY CLANKING )
Fine. How about you?
I've decided to make some changes
at the clinic.
I think I'm gonna get it painted
and buy a new couch.
Look at you all hunched over like that.
How many times do I have to tell you,
you'll strain your back?
Your hair is practically trailing
in your food.
Bob, you promised me you'd get a haircut
and you still haven't done it.
- BOB : I'll get a haircut.
- STEVEN : Tomorrow.
Not tomorrow, Dad. After the party.
WOMAN : I like his hair long.
He has lovely hair.
- KIM : What about mine?
- You have lovely hair, too.
We all have lovely hair.
I bought that dress that you liked.
I'll wear it for you tomorrow.
I can't show it to you now, it needed
alterations. I'm picking it up tomorrow.
- STEVEN : The black one?
- It was the black one you liked,
- wasn't it?
- STEVEN : Yes.
The other one looked great on you, too.
But I think the black one was perfect.
WOMAN : I'm worried it's a little
too short.
I'd like it better if it were
below the knee.
STEVEN : You look amazing,
however long or short the dress is.
Tomorrow I'm gonna bake a lemon cake
and nobody's gonna eat any of it but you.
Not even the kids?
- WOMAN : Not even the kids.
- Poor kids.
Did I tell you Bob announced the other day
that he wants to be an ophthalmologist?
STEVEN : Yes, you did.
Bob would be a coal miner
if you were one, too.
Could you turn on some more light, please?
( CLICK )
( DISTANT CRICKETS CHIRPING )
General anesthetic?
STEVEN : General anesthetic.
( LANDS WITH A THUD )
How's that?
STEVEN : Perfect.
( SHEETS RUFFLING )
( EXHALES SLOWLY )
( EXHALING CONTENTEDLY )
( BREATHING DEEPLY )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( DISTANT CLATTER )
- STEVEN : Martin.
- Yeah.
Look, I've told you, best not to come
to the hospital without calling me first.
I know, you're right. I'm sorry.
I just wanted to thank you again.
And to show you my new strap
I got for my watch.
I, uh, exchanged the, uh, metal strap
for a leather one.
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to put you
in this awkward position.
Good bye.
Martin. Come here.
What kind of strap did you get?
- Brown leather.
- Show me.
- It's very nice.
- You think so?
- Or are you just saying that?
- No, I really like it.
Next time you want to come here,
please call me first. You have my number.
It's for your own good.
I might be with a patient, or in surgery,
or in a meeting.
There's no point in you waiting around
if I can't see you.
It's for your own... Good morning.
Good morning, Steven,
I have those test results.
Shall I leave them on the desk?
Please do. Yeah, I'll take a look at them
- in a minute.
- All right.
We've got the same watch.
Let me introduce you.
This young man, is one of my daughter's
school mates.
I ran into Martin and his parents
at the mall last week.
He told me he's very interested
in medicine.
- He wants to be cardiologist.
- Ah...
I suggested he stop by sometime...
so he can see what being
a doctor's really about.
Martin, this is Matthew.
Great friend of mine.
And an excellent anesthesiologist.
That's great.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Let me know when you're ready.
I've got to go back in now.
We'll talk on the phone to arrange
our next meeting. All right?
Okay. Goodbye.
( KIM PRACTICING THE SCALE )
( INHALES DEEPLY )
( CONTINUES SINGING THE SCALE )
STEVEN : I think your breathing's really
improved over the last three months.
KIM : That's what the choir director said,
too.
STEVEN : Did you tell her
to move you closer to the front?
Yes, I did.
She said she'd see what she can do.
Bob, did you water the plants?
Mum said she would water them.
Your mother works very hard.
That's why we said it would be nice
to help out all that we can.
And we agreed that Kim would take care
of walking the dog.
And you would take care of the plants.
How about I walk the dog
and Kim can do the plants?
You're too young to be wandering
around at night, by yourself.
- Thanks for the brush.
- KIM : You're welcome.
WOMAN : We have to go.
STEVEN : Tell Bob to water the plants now
that the sun has gone down.
I watered them already.
Come on, we're gonna be late.
- Goodnight, darling.
- Goodnight.
( TOY SIREN WAILING )
( KIM MIMICS SIREN )
STEVEN : A full 40 years have passed
since the German cardiologist,
Andreas Gruentzig, performed
the first coronary angioplasty
on September 16th, 1977.
Today, that first patient
is still alive and well.
Doctor Gruentzig, however,
had an unfortunate accident
and met with an untimely end.
In short, he is one of those rare cases
where we can say:
"The operation was a success...
but, unfortunately,
- the doctor didn't make it".
- ( LAUGHTER FROM CROWD )
In the four decades that have passed
since that first coronary angioplasty,
many things have changed.
A new wave of techniques
and scientific breakthroughs have...
I'm going for a cigarette.
I'll be at the bar.
- Okay.
- STEVEN : ...endovascular aortic surgery
and new treatments
for heart failure that include
stem cell therapy, left ventricular
remodeling and, by all indications,
the rapidly expanding use
of mechanical circulatory support.
( BAND MUSIC PLAYING )
GUEST : The guy that made it told me
what was in it.
And now I can't remember now,
but it is very refreshing.
- Would you like one?
- No, thank you.
GUEST : Just try it.
It's really delicious.
You can use this straw.
I haven't touched it.
He hasn't had a drink in three years.
- High GGTs and elevated transaminases.
- GUEST : Oh, good on you
for not drinking.
MATTHEW : Well, I wouldn't say no
to a cocktail if you're offering.
Of course. I'll get you one right away.
- WOMAN : We should go soon.
- STEVEN : Yeah.
- It's early.
- He's got surgery in the morning.
- He needs to get some sleep.
- It's still early.
STEVEN : We've got surgery in the morning.
Fine, okay.
- MATTHEW : How are the kids?
- WOMAN : They're doing very well.
Bob has started piano lessons.
The teacher says he's very talented.
Now we have to get him one
so he can practice at home.
I just haven't gotten around to it yet.
I'm renovating the clinic.
- WOMAN : I'm on the phone all day.
- Our daughter started menstruating
- last week.
- Great.
STEVEN : Yes, she was a little scared
but she's okay now.
- STEVEN : You haven't seen her in ages.
- Not since last summer
at the school choir...
recital.
You and Mary should come
over one night for dinner.
You really shouldn't stay late, either.
Drink that cocktail you've ordered.
Get yourself home.
You've gotta be at the hospital
- in six hours. Time to go, darling?
- STEVEN : Yes.
- MATTHEW : Goodnight.
- STEVEN : Goodnight, Matthew.
( INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING )
- WOMAN : Oh, it was a good night.
- STEVEN : I think so.
( INDISTINCT CHATTER )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
STEVEN : Do you have many friends?
MARTIN : Not that many.
I don't think people can have
a lot of friends.
I mean, it's difficult.
The most important thing in life is
to have good friends, not lots of friends.
That's what my dad used to say.
- Your father was absolutely right.
- Yes, I know.
I have a very good friend
who plays basketball in school.
Sometimes we play it together.
I also consider my mom to be a friend.
MARTIN : I know it might sound strange
but ever since my father died, we...
We-— we've been very close, me and my mom.
We talk about things. Lots of things.
She helps me as much as she can
with a lot of stuff.
I help her too.
I'd like to ask you a favor.
Only if you want to, of course.
I don't want you
to feel pressured or obliged.
STEVEN : It just seemed to me like
a good idea, so I thought I'd ask.
I'd like you to come by my house one day
to meet my wife and children.
I think you'll get along great.
What do you think?
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( DOORBELL RINGS )
ANNA : Good afternoon. You must be Martin.
- MARTIN : That's right. You must be Anna.
- ANNA : That's right.
MARTIN : These flowers are for you.
Your husband told me you like orchids,
but I couldn't find
any fresh cut ones so I brought you roses.
How do you like roses?
Thank you very much, Martin.
I love roses. That's very kind of you.
Come on in.
Steven is waiting for you in the yard.
- STEVEN : This is Bob.
- MARTIN : Very nice to meet you.
STEVEN : And this is Kim.
MARTIN : Very nice to meet you.
I brought you some little gifts.
STEVEN : That's very kind of you.
It's a key ring with a musical note on it
for Kim because I know she likes music.
And one with a smiley face for Bob.
- STEVEN : What do we say, Bob?
- Thanks.
ANNA : How lovely...
Well, we should probably eat.
( KEYCHAIN JINGLES )
- Are you hungry, Martin?
- I'm starving.
MARTIN : How long have you been
in the choir, Kim?
KIM : Two years. Since I was 12.
Do you like singing?
MARTIN : I love it, but I haven't got
a very good voice.
- BOB : How old are you?
- 16.
BOB : Have you got hair
under your arms yet?
- Yes.
- I just got my first period.
- Do you mind if I light a cigarette?
- BOB : You'd better not.
It's all right.
Just go over by the window.
- ( WINDOW SLIDING OPEN )
- ( DOG BARKS OUTSIDE )
- ( BIRDS CHIRPING )
- ( LIGHTER FLICKS )
MARTIN : Can you sing us something?
- KIM : What, now?
- ( MARTIN PUFFS )
Yes. Anything you like.
No. Not right now.
- BOB : She's embarrassed.
- No, I'm not. Just don't feel like it.
When did you start smoking?
MARTIN : About eight months ago.
I was over at a friend's place.
It was a party, actually.
And this girl offered me a cigarette
and I said, "Why not," and lit up.
That was a mistake. I regret it.
But it's too late now. I'm addicted.
BOB : Can you show me
the hair under your arms?
Sure.
You haven't got that much.
Have you seen how hairy my dad is?
No.
BOB : He's got three times more hair
than you do.
- You've got a great body.
- MARTIN : Thanks.
Do you wanna go out for a walk?
It's a nice day.
BOB : I'd rather stay here
and listen to music.
- Is that my MP3 player or yours?
- BOB : Mine, and don't you dare take
this one and lose it, too.
What kind of music do you listen to?
- MARTIN : All kinds.
- I'm into metal and punk. What about you?
MARTIN : I think it's worth listening
to all kinds of music.
Depends on my mood and what I'm doing.
KIM : I'll come for a walk with you
if you want.
We can take the dog with us
if you don't mind.
MARTIN : I'd prefer it if it was just
the two of us.
I get nervous around dogs...
in case they get into a fight
with another dog.
The idea of separating dogs fighting
scares me.
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( KIM SINGING )
♪.. We... We don't have
to worry about nothing ♪
♪.. 'Cause we got the fire ♪
♪.. And we 're burning ♪
♪.. one hell of a somethin' ♪
♪.. They ♪
♪.. They're gonna see us from outer space ♪
♪.. Outer space, light it up ♪
♪.. Like we're the source ♪
♪.. Of the human race, human race ♪
♪.. When the lights started out ♪
♪.. They don't know what they heard ♪
♪.. Strike the match, play it loud ♪
♪.. Giving love to the world ♪
♪.. We'll be raising our hands ♪
♪.. Shining up to the sky ♪
♪.. 'Cause we got the fire, fire, fire ♪
♪.. Yeah, we got the fire, fire, fire ♪
♪.. And we're gonna let it burn ♪
♪.. burn, burn, burn ♪
♪.. We 're gonna let it burn ♪
♪.. We can light it up, up, up ♪
♪.. So they can put it out, out, out ♪
MARTIN : Is this homemade lemonade?
- ANNA : Yes.
- MARTIN : It's amazing.
MARTIN : My mom makes lemonade, too.
She hasn't made it in a while, though.
I'll ask her to make some.
I love lemonade.
ANNA : I'd like to meet your mother.
And we can have a lemonade contest.
She'd like that.
The kids' rooms are amazing.
So big and bright.
You're welcome to spend the night
if you want.
We can easily fit a mattress
on the floor next to Bob's bed.
You two can hang out in the morning
and I'll drop you home tomorrow afternoon.
Thank you very much, but I'd rather not.
I gotta get home tonight.
I don't like leaving my mom by herself.
- STEVEN : Whatever you want.
- ANNA : Where did you two go?
- Just for a walk.
- MARTIN : I love this neighborhood.
So quiet, clean, beautiful.
Where do you live, Martin?
We live in a not-so-nice neighborhood
in a not-so-nice house.
Up... up... uh, up north
- What a charming boy.
- STEVEN : Isn't he?
Yes, very. How did his father die?
STEVEN : Car crash. Driving home.
Smashed into a pole. Killed instantly.
How long have you known him?
STEVEN : Quite some time.
He was a patient of mine years ago.
- Did you go to the funeral?
- I did go, yes.
Why didn't I go with you?
I think I told you about it,
but you were busy or something.
( CLICK )
ANNA : You should tell him
to come round again.
STEVEN : I will.
He'll be great company for Bob.
I thought next time I could take both
of them out somewhere, for a bike ride.
( PHONE BUZZING )
You should get that.
It could be the hospital.
( BUZZING CONTINUES )
- Hello?
- MARTIN : Hello. How are you?
I'm fine, Martin. Is something wrong?
- No, I just called to tell you I had...
- ( DOOR CLOSES )
- A wonderful time today.
- ( CLICK )
I'm very pleased to hear that.
Yes. I thought I should return the favor.
So I'd like to invite you to dinner,
at my house.
My mom will be delighted to see you.
She hasn't seen you in two years.
Not since the hospital.
She'll make meatloaf.
- ( CAR ALARM BEEPS )
- STEVEN : That's very kind of you.
We'll do that someday.
MARTIN : Tomorrow night.
I told her already.
I've asked her to make meatloaf
and lemonade.
I'll be home by 6:30. Around 7:30?
( ENGINE REVVING )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
STEVEN : Did you come by
the hospital today?
MARTIN : No. I was in school.
And then I went to the gym.
Weren't you down at the hospital today?
- STEVEN : I was, but I was really busy.
- ( DISHES CLINKING IN THE KITCHEN )
I just wondered whether you came by
and couldn't find me.
I thought we could all
watch a movie together.
If you don't mind.
I'd like to watch a movie.
I'm sorry, I have to be getting home soon.
I can't be out too late.
I didn't tell my wife I'd be late tonight
and she might get worried.
You could call her.
Anyway, if you feel tired,
you could stop the movie.
You could go home and we could watch
the rest next time you come.
Please, it's my favorite movie.
It's also my father's favorite movie, too.
( LADY ON TV ) Special today is
blueberry waffles.
- Why are you telling me this?
- ( MAN ON TV ) Because I want you
to believe in me.
You're not a god.
You can take my word for it.
This Is 12 years
of Catholic school talking.
I could come back If you're not ready.
- How do you know I'm not a god?
- ( LADY ON TV SCOFFS )
MARTIN : I think I'll go to bed.
I'm sorry I can't watch the rest
of the movie with you.
- Goodnight.
- Goodnight, Martin.
( TV )...groundhog, who, as legend has it,
can predict the coming of an early spring.
So I guess the question we have
to ask ourselves today is...
Have you been married long?
16 years.
( TV CONTINUES PLAYING )
- You have lovely hands.
- Thank you.
Most doctors have beautiful hands.
So white and soft and clean.
- Really?
- MOTHER : Yes.
I remember your hands from back
when I used to visit my husband
at the hospital.
In fact, I even told him about your hands.
And he agreed.
"You're right," he said.
"He has beautiful hands."
Thank you very much.
Do you remember me coming to the hospital?
STEVEN : Of course.
I was a little heavier then
and my hair was brown.
Yes.
I got tired of it.
I dyed it about a month ago.
Did you prefer me with brown hair?
Like it was back then?
I think it's... nicer now.
Yes, I agree.
( TV PLAYING )
Would you like some dessert?
I made a caramel tart.
No, thank you.
Maybe later then.
You did have a lot to eat.
( STEVEN CHUCKLES )
( DISTANT SIREN WAILING )
Can I take a closer look at your hands?
- ( SQUELCHING )
- ( MOANING )
( CLATTER )
Don't worry, he's definitely asleep.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
In any case, he wants this
as much as I do.
- I have to go.
- I'm sorry if I made you feel awkward.
I didn't mean to.
But I won't let you leave
until you've tried my tart.
Please, I'll get you a piece now.
Please, sit down.
I'm sorry, I really have to go. Goodnight.
( DOOR OPENS WITH A CREAK )
( DOOR CLOSES WITH A THUD )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
Good morning.
What are you doing here?
Why aren't you in school?
- My heart aches.
- What do you mean?
I'm in pain. My chest, it hurts.
- MARTIN : My heart. I'm worried.
- There's no need for you to be worried.
I'm worried because it's hereditary.
- You're too young to be worried.
- That's what you said about my father.
He didn't smoke.
He ate a very healthy diet.
He went swimming almost every day.
He should have come out of that surgery
alive but he died.
I smoke. I started smoking recently.
It hurts here.
( INHALES )
I hardly slept at all last night.
My mom was so worried, I slept in her bed.
If I had hair on my chest and belly,
how would you attach these?
We'd shave the hair off first.
How long does it take for the hair
to grow back?
I don't know.
About a month, I suppose.
Your son told me that you've got
lots of hair under your arms.
Three times more than I do.
And that you've got a very hairy back
and a very hairy belly.
I probably do have a little more hair
than you do because I'm older than you.
But soon you'll have more hair, too.
It's all down to hormones.
Can you show me, please?
Can you take off your shirt
and show me, please?
Please.
( INDISTINCT DISTANT CHATTER )
Okay, you do have more hair than I do
but not three times more.
Me and my mom thought it would be nice
if you came by for dinner tonight.
We could watch the rest of the movie.
Does eight sound good for you?
That's very kind of you
but I just can't make it tonight.
I need to be at home.
- Can't you get away for a couple of hours?
- I can't. No.
Some other time.
My mom's gonna be upset.
Can I tell you a secret?
But don't tell her I told you.
I think she... I think she likes you.
I mean, she's attracted to you.
But she says that's not true.
But it is, I'm sure.
And, to be honest, I think you're perfect
for each other.
You'd make a great couple.
She's got a great body.
You've seen it for yourself.
She lost weight
and she has a really great figure.
Your mother is very beautiful,
but the idea
that she and I could ever be together
is ludicrous.
Let me remind you, I'm a married man.
And I love my wife very much and my kids,
and that we are very happy together.
There's nothing wrong with you.
But you really should stop smoking.
Do you promise?
So we're okay?
There is nothing wrong with me?
You couldn't be healthier.
You should really go now
because I'm late for my rounds.
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
MARY : Don't use that knife. Here.
Use this one. It's much sharper.
- There you go, Doctor.
- Thank you, Nurse.
MARY : Oh, and don't forget to slice off
the cheeks. They're delicious.
MATHEW : I can do that.
MARTIN : Where are you?
I called you a hundred times.
Didn't you see my calls?
Yeah, I'm here.
- ( SNAP )
- ( SQUELCH )
What do you mean you can't?
I got you a slice of apple pie.
Just come for a little while.
I can come closer to where you are.
Are you at the hospital?
I can bring you the apple pie.
What's... what's so important?
Is it a... is it an operation?
Are you at the hospital?
MARY : I love the sound of those cooking.
( EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES )
- Where were you?
- STEVEN : I was inside. Making a call.
MATTHEW : The fish is almost ready.
Pass me your plate.
I'll get them.
I need to wash my hands anyway.
MARY : Thank you, my dear.
( SIZZLING )
- STEVEN : Do you need a hand?
- No, that's okay.
I forgot to tell you
I saw that boy yesterday.
Your daughter's school mate.
Martin?
Yes, right, Martin.
Couldn't remember his name.
- Where did you see him?
- MATTHEW : At the hospital.
He was hanging around your car.
Looked like he was waiting for you.
I tried to say hello
but he pretended not to see me.
That's impossible. Can't have been him.
I could be wrong,
but it looked a lot like him.
Take my piece off the grill, will you?
I don't like it overdone.
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( DOOR CLOSES WITH A THUD )
( APPROACHING FOOTSTEPS )
- Hi, Dad.
- Hello, darling.
- Where have you been?
- Choir practice.
- Have you eaten?
- Yes, I ate earlier.
You don't have to take the dog for a walk.
I took her out already.
- I got back a little while ago.
- Okay.
Dad, do you know who I saw today?
- Who, darling?
- Martin.
Martin who?
Martin, that boy who came over here
the other day.
The son of your ex-patient.
He brought me back from choir practice
on his friend's motorcycle.
He's really funny.
I laughed so hard my ribs hurt.
Yes, he is very funny.
Kim, I don't want you riding
on motorcycles without a helmet.
I was wearing a helmet. He gave me his.
- Why didn't you ask him to come in?
- I did but he was in a hurry.
He had to get home.
- Where's Mom?
- She's taking a shower.
Is there something you need?
I'm going up to bed.
Good night, darling.
( FOOTSTEPS LEAVING )
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( PHONE BEEPING )
- ( DRINK TRICKLING )
- ( CUTLERY CLINKING )
- Did you wake Bob?
- I did.
He just likes lying in bed
before getting up. Leave him be.
You want me to squeeze you
some more orange juice?
He'll be late. Have you seen the time?
School bus will be here any minute.
Robert, do you have any idea
what time it is? Get up and get dressed.
I can't get up.
You have ten minutes to get washed,
dressed, and eat your breakfast.
I'm not going to drive you to school,
and neither is your mother.
I can't get up.
Bob, get up and get dressed,
and stop messing around.
Dad, my legs, they're numb.
I can't move them.
I can't stand up.
( WHIRRING )
( ENGINE REVVING )
DOCTOR : Do you know
where you are right now?
BOB : I'm at the hospital,
in the neurology department.
DOCTOR : You are absolutely right.
Can you tell me what day it is today?
- Thursday.
- DOCTOR : Right again.
Now, I'm going to take this pin,
I'm going to touch the soles
of your feet and your toes
and I want you to tell me...
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
- Can you feel this?
- Yeah.
Mm-hm. Yes.
For this one, you're gonna sit up
and look right at me. Okay?
DOCTOR : Good.
Now stick out your tongue...
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( DOOR OPENS )
- What happened?
- Everything's absolutely fine.
Larry gave him a thorough
neurological exam. It's nothing.
You two go home. And we'll talk tonight.
I won't be late.
My schedule today is pretty light. Okay?
Maybe he should get an MRI.
There's no need to bother with all that.
He just got scared, that's all.
He's absolutely fine.
You're absolutely fine, aren't you?
Yeah.
I think maybe there was a test
at school today
that we hadn't prepared for very well.
Yes, he wanted to spend the day
at the hospital with Larry and us.
Let's go.
- Dad.
- Yeah?
Aren't you going to show us
an operating theater?
Another time, darling.
They need me to prep for surgery
right away.
I have to go. I'll see you tonight.
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUSIC RISES TO A CRESCENDO )
BOB : I can't feel my legs.
- ANNA : What?
- BOB : I can't feel my legs!
ANNA : Come on, roll over.
Excuse me, can we get some help here?
He needs some help. Thank you.
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
DOCTOR : MRI, MRA both fine.
Blood work came back good.
Cardiogram, chest X-ray, all clear.
Has he been
under any psychological stress lately?
Exams at school maybe?
- STEVEN : Yes.
- ANNA : He's not stressed. He's fine.
He's a little anxious
but that's just the way he is.
DOCTOR : In my opinion,
he should stay in tomorrow, as well,
just so we can keep an eye on him.
ANNA : What about a PET scan?
I don't think there's any need for that.
What do you think, Larry?
And tomorrow he'll be well enough
to walk all the way home.
DOCTOR : Yes, I don't think
it's necessary at this point.
Let's see how things go tomorrow
and we'll take it from there.
There's nothing to worry about,
in my opinion.
You go home, we'll speak tomorrow,
and I'll be here all day.
And, Anna, great seeing you...
even under these circumstances.
- You, too, Larry.
- Good night.
Goodbye, Larry. And thanks for everything.
Do you want me to let them know
you won't be operating tomorrow?
STEVEN : I said no.
Stop going on about it.
ANNA : That won't be necessary, Matthew.
I'll come by in the morning.
I won't go into the clinic.
I'll bring in those doughnuts
he loves so much.
STEVEN : Yes. I'm sure he'll be thrilled.
( UNNERVING MUSIC PLAYING )
( UNNERVING MUSIC CRESCENDOS )
- Where were you?
- At Claire's.
- Is Dad asleep?
- Yes.
- How's Bob?
- Bob is absolutely fine.
They're just keeping him
in as a precaution.
- How are you feeling?
- I'm fine. How do you mean?
- I mean, are you tired?
- I'm absolutely fine.
- I'm a little tired, that's all.
- Okay.
See you in the morning.
Oh, and while Bob's in the hospital
you'll be responsible
for watering the plants. Okay?
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
ANNA : Did he go to the bathroom?
Did he get up?
He hadn't when I passed by
about an hour ago. He didn't want to.
He didn't want to pee or hadn't gotten up?
- He didn't want to pee.
- Could he get up?
He was asleep.
I didn't want to drag him out of bed.
MARTIN : Good morning, Doctor.
How are you, Mrs. Murphy?
I came by to see Bob.
Kim told me what happened.
Hi, Martin. How nice of you.
Good morning, darling.
Did your friend Martin come to see you?
I'll leave you alone now so you can spend
some time with him, too.
I gotta go anyway.
I'll come by and see him
again some other time.
I offered to help him go to the bathroom
but he didn't want me to.
He wet the bed.
I brought some lemonade
my mom made yesterday.
You should try some.
Let me know what you think.
STEVEN : Thank you very much.
Darling, do you know what's in this box?
- What?
- Cinnamon doughnuts.
Let's go to the cafeteria upstairs.
MARTIN : Come whenever you can.
STEVEN : I don't think I'll have time
today, as you might imagine.
We'll talk some other time.
MARTIN : No, today. To the cafeteria.
Just for ten minutes.
Don't stand me up like last night.
MARTIN : I brought you a present.
You've given me so many presents
and I've not given you anything.
I thought that was rude of me.
Close your eyes.
Close your eyes, please.
It's a Swiss Army knife.
I shouldn't have told you that.
I've just ruined the surprise. I'm sorry.
- Thank you very much, Martin.
- I was dumb.
Martin, I have to get back downstairs.
Okay.
I won't keep you much longer even though
you... you have been devoting,
less and less time to me lately.
I wanted to say one more thing.
I'm really sorry about Bob.
- It's nothing serious.
- No, it is.
That critical moment we both knew
would come someday...
Here it is. That time is now.
- MARTIN : You know what I mean.
- No, I don't.
Listen, Martin, I don't have time
for this.
Okay, I'm gonna explain this very quickly
so that I don't hold you up.
Yes, it's exactly what you think.
Just as you killed a member of my family,
now you gotta kill a member of your family
to balance things out, understand?
I can't tell you who to kill,
of course, that's for you to decide.
But, if you don't do it,
they will all get sick and die.
Bob will die. Kim will die.
Your wife will die.
They will all get sick and die.
One : paralysis of the limbs.
Two : refusal of food
to the point of starvation.
Three : bleeding from the eyes.
Four : death. One, two, three, four.
Don't worry, you won't get sick.
You've just gotta stay calm, that's all.
There, I said it as quickly as I could.
I hope I haven't kept you too long.
Uh, one more thing.
I'll be very quick.
You only have a few days to decide
who to kill. Once stage three kicks in,
you remember what stage three is?
It's bleeding from the eyes,
that's stage three.
Once the bleeding happens, it's only
a matter of hours before they die.
Okay, there. I have nothing more to say.
Unless you've...
Unless you've any questions.
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
- STEVEN : Has he eaten?
- ANNA : No. He's not hungry.
- What do you mean he's not hungry?
- He's not hungry.
( FOOTSTEPS )
Come on, darling. Eat a doughnut.
- BOB : I don't want it, Dad.
- STEVEN : You do.
STEVEN : But you're afraid your mother
and I'll tell you off
for eating doughnuts. Come on, eat it.
You have my permission.
You have our permission.
It's okay for him to eat a doughnut,
isn't it Anna?
- Yes, of course.
- You heard your mother, eat it.
STEVEN : Bob?
( PAPER RUFFLING )
Leave him alone. He doesn't want it.
He'll eat it later.
That's right.
( BOB CHOKING )
That's right. Eat it. Now chew it.
Swallow.
- Leave him alone. He doesn't want it now.
- He's going to eat them right now.
He is completely run down.
That's why he keeps falling over
and crawling around on all fours.
He's going to eat them, all of them.
Five minutes flat,
I want to see that whole box empty.
( MARTIN SPEAKING IN FRENCH )
( ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING )
That means,
"On the bus there are winners and losers."
But it's funny because it sounds like,
"On the bus there are 20 hearts
and 20 asses."
- ( CHUCKLING )
- That is funny.
Are you on your period?
No.
If you're hungry,
we can order something later.
My parents won't be back till late
and they've left me some money.
I'm not hungry.
( ROMANTIC MUSIC PLAYING )
You're the prettiest girl I've ever met.
I have to go, I'm sorry.
Why?
Stay a little longer.
We can listen to some music.
I can't. It's late. I'm sorry.
Are you mad at me because of my dad?
Don't be stupid.
I'm not mad at you at all.
I thought I made myself clear.
I don't feel angry at him.
I feel sorry for him.
I have to go because it's late.
It's as simple as that.
Don't be a drag. I thought you understood.
I'm sorry, Martin. I love you so much.
( DOOR CLOSES WITH A THUD )
( WHEELCHAIR RATTLING ALONG )
ANNA : He stopped eating today.
He refuses to eat.
Some of the tests need to be done again.
DOCTOR : Take a deep breath.
Hold it for a few seconds.
- STEVEN : They haven't detected anything.
- DOCTOR : Okay, good. Breathe.
It's been less than a day
since his last tests
I don't think the results are gonna show
anything different.
To be honest, I think what we have here
is a clear case
of some psychosomatic disorder.
MAN : I'm inclined to agree with Anna.
STEVEN : Well, what do you mean?
Shouldn't we rule out all possible causes
before we resort to the easy option
of a psychosomatic disorder?
DOCTOR : We already have ruled out
everything else.
( WHEELCHAIR ROLLING ALONG )
MAN : I think with psychological
support and psychiatric treatment,
if necessary, he will be just fine.
He'll walk again and he'll eat again.
Of course he will.
( PLASTIC RIPPING )
( MUSIC CONTINUES )
Anna, if Bob was near-sighted
and had a cataract or glaucoma
then your opinion
really would be valuable.
STEVEN : But, thankfully,
Bob's eyesight is perfect.
And I can honestly say
that if he ever needed glasses
you'd be the first person, I'd consult
But right now the boy can't eat
and he's paralyzed in both legs.
So I'm sorry, I'm not remotely interested
in your medical opinion.
( FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE ) Doors opening.
Take your turn.
( WHEEL CHAIR RATTLES )
( FEMALE AUTOMATED VOICE ) Doors closing.
- Please stand clear.
- ( ELEVATOR DOOR CLOSES )
Come on, Bob. Let's go for a walk.
Up you get. There you go.
Okay.
Ready? There we go.
( LANDS WITH A THUD )
Bob?
( STEVEN SIGHS )
- Why don't we play a game?
- What game?
I'll tell you a secret,
something I've never told you before.
Then you'll tell me one and whoever
tells the best secret wins. Okay?
When I was your age,
I'd only just started masturbating.
And I'd only just started ejaculating.
Only a little, barely a drop.
( CLICKS TONGUE ) I was worried that I had
some kind of problem
because at school I'd heard
all sorts of stories.
Then one day, when my father had had
a lot to drink,
and my brothers were out
and he was sleeping in the bedroom,
I crept inside, put my hand on his penis,
and started stroking it
until he ejaculated.
The sheets were covered in sperm.
I got scared and ran out.
I've never told anyone that before.
Now, it's your turn to tell me a secret.
I don't know. I don't have one.
STEVEN : That's impossible.
You have to have one.
No. I don't.
Bob, if all this is just an act,
you should know that if you tell me now,
I won't punish you.
And neither will your mother.
We won't be angry with you, either.
BOB : It's not an act.
But if it is an act and you don't stop
this stupid joke right now,
your punishment won't just be
no TV for two months.
I will take my electric razor,
and I will shave your head
and make you eat your hair.
I mean it, I will literally make you eat
your hair. I'm not kidding
It's not an act.
( CLOCK TICKING )
( STEVEN BREATHING HEAVILY )
- I brought you a clean shirt.
- ( WHISPERS ) Thank you.
Anything to tell me?
Hungry?
Want me to bring you something to eat?
No, thank you.
Maybe you were right.
Maybe it's all psychological.
Everything will be all right, you'll see.
Trust me.
We're in this together.
It's all gonna be fine.
Let's get you something to eat,
get some fresh air, and go up
and see the little one.
♪.. Christmas is here, bringing good cheer ♪
♪.. To young and old ♪
♪.. Meek and the bold ♪
♪.. Ding, dong, ding, dong ♪
♪.. That is their song ♪
♪.. With joyful ring, all caroling ♪
♪.. One seems to hear words of good cheer ♪
♪.. From everywhere, filling the air ♪
♪.. Oh! How they pound ♪
♪.. Raising their sound ♪
♪.. O'er hill and dale ♪
♪.. Telling their tale ♪
♪.. Gaily they ring, while people sing ♪
♪.. Songs of good cheer, Christmas is here ♪
♪.. Sing Merry, merry, merry Christmas ♪
♪.. On, on they send, on without and ♪
♪.. Their joyful tone to every home I
♪.. Hark! How the bells ♪
♪.. Sweet silver bells ♪
♪.. All seem to say, throw cares away ♪
♪.. Christmas is here, bringing good cheer ♪
♪.. To young and old, meek and the bold ♪
♪.. Ding, dong, ding, dong ♪
♪.. That is their song ♪
♪.. With joyful ring, all caroling ♪
♪.. One seems to hear words of good cheer ♪
♪.. From everywhere, filling the air ♪
♪.. Oh! How they pound ♪
♪.. Raising their sound ♪
♪.. O'er hill and dale, telling their tale ♪
♪.. Gaily they ring, while people sing ♪
♪.. Songs of good cheer, Christmas is... ♪
( DRAMATIC MUSIC PLAYING )
( ANNA WEEPS )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( ANNA CONTINUES WEEPING )
Dad, I don't want any fruit.
STEVEN : Just one bite...
for me.
( GAGS, RETCHES )
I can't.
Okay.
( BIRDS CHIRPING )
( CAR ENGINE HUMMING )
( DISTANT DOG BARKING )
- ( SIREN WAILING )
- ( DOOR KNOCKING )
- ( KNOCKING ON DOOR CONTINUES )
- ( STEVEN YELLS ) Open the door!
- ( DOOR KNOCKING )
- I know you're in there!
- Open the door or I will smash it down!
STEVEN : Martin!
( KNOCKING VIOLENTLY )
Open the door or I will smash it down,
and I will fuck you and your mother
just the way you wanted!
STEVEN : If anything happens to my kids
or my wife, you'll die in prison.
( YELLING ) You know that... you'll die
in prison!
ANNA : How old was his father
when he died?
STEVEN : 46.
ANNA : Had you been drinking that day?
STEVEN : He had an arrhythmia, a stroke,
and that was it.
I asked whether you'd been drinking,
not how he died.
How long has this been going on?
How long have you been seeing this boy?
STEVEN : About six months.
- Where were you meeting?
- What does it matter?
ANNA : Where were you meeting him?
At a diner and then we'd drive down
to the river.
He's got issues,
serious psychological issues.
He always did.
I knew he acted weird sometimes
but now he's lost it completely.
He's become dangerous.
We have to take precautions.
Go to the police and take some
precautionary measures.
We're not going to the police.
We're not telling anyone about this.
What's the point?
Had you been drinking when you operated
on his father?
Only a little. That had nothing to do
with the outcome.
A surgeon never kills a patient.
An anesthesiologist can kill a patient
but a surgeon never can.
For example, Matthew has made
mistakes that have led
to the death of a patient,
but I never have.
Bob seemed a little better today.
He was in a better mood
and he was less pale.
( SIREN WAILING )
Why didn't you tell me
you were seeing him?
At first I didn't see him that often.
It was only recently
that we began meeting more regularly.
And I was going to tell you at some point.
I felt sorry for him.
I gave him some money.
His mum's out of work.
( SHOWER SPLUTTERING )
- BOB : Mom, when are we going home?
- ( DOOR SLAMS )
ANNA : Tomorrow, or the day after,
when all of the tests are done
and the doctors say so.
BOB : But you're doctors, too.
( CAR ALARM BEEPS )
BOB : Tell them we can go home.
ANNA : We'll tell them, darling.
KIM : Mom, did Martin come by
while I was sleeping?
ANNA : No.
KIM : Can you turn me on my side, please?
Is Dad here?
No, he'll be here soon.
Want me to get some juice for you?
No. Don't go anywhere. Stay here.
( PHONE RINGING )
Good morning.
How are you?
Aren't you coming by?
Okay.
Just my mom. My father will be here soon.
You're here?
I can't. Are you coming up to see me?
( CHUCKLING ) You really think
that's possible?
KIM : Well, let's see. Okay. Okay.
Yes, I stood up. Can you see me?
Yes, thank you.
Yeah, I'm standing at the window.
Can you see me?
I can't see you.
I'm waving at you.
( EERIE MUSIC INTENSIFYING )
Mom? I want to stand up like Kim.
How come she can get up and I can't?
ANNA : You'll be able to soon, my darling.
ANNA : Kim's older than you,
that's why she can do it.
Soon you'll be strong enough
to stand up, too.
All right. I'm going back to bed.
You, too.
Bye.
Mom, I'm going over to the window.
( THUD )
No!
( GRUNTS )
( DEEP SIGHS )
Who were you talking to?
Martin. He sends his regards.
I don't want you talking
to him ever again.
- Why?
- ANNA : Because I said so.
- Did you hear what I said?
- ( WHISPERS ) Fuck you.
- ANNA : What did you say?
- I didn't say anything.
Yes, you did. What did you say, Kim?
Mom, let go, you're hurting me.
I didn't say anything.
I'm not like your father.
If this is the way you want it,
I'm confiscating your phone,
right here, right now.
That will teach you to be rude
to your mother.
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
- Give me my phone back.
- You can forget it.
Don't be scared, Mom.
Don't get hysterical.
It's not that tragic.
Sometimes your body hurts from not moving
and you can't sleep.
That's all.
The important thing is to make sure
that everything you need is within reach.
That's all.
You'll see.
You won't be able to move either.
But you'll get used to it.
( EERIE MUSIC CONTINUES )
ANNA : I really saw it happen.
- STEVEN : It was just a coincidence.
- ANNA : How can it be a coincidence?
ANNA : How come neither
of them have been able
to get up and walk until now?
- Darling, listen to yourself.
- ANNA : I saw it.
Okay. It just means
things are getting better.
That's all it means.
That Kim is getting better.
Now please go home
and rest awhile, please.
- They're not better. They're worse.
- This afternoon there'll be
an emergency meeting
with the Medical Board.
Larry and I took the initiative to invite
two outstanding specialists
from the Presbyterian University Hospital
of Columbia.
STEVEN : They already flew in
from New York.
I'm meeting them this afternoon
to brief them about the case.
One of them's actually a personal friend
of the director, Doctor Farrington.
You must've heard of him.
He's the best there is when it comes
- to paralytic disorders.
- ANNA : Yeah.
( CHILDREN PLAYING )
( BIRD TWEETING )
( KNOCKING )
( DOOR CREAKS OPENS )
Good afternoon.
( FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING )
Oh, thank you very much.
I'd like to talk to you.
I'm not gonna take up much of your time.
MARTIN : Of course,
I've only got ten minutes
'cause, I've gotta get to class.
So, what's up?
My husband told me
about you and your father.
Oh, he did? Did he also tell you
about my mom?
No.
Sorry, maybe I'm not the one
you should hear it from.
But... ever since your husband killed
my father, he's been flirting with my mom.
Constantly flirting.
To be honest, she's got feelings
for him, too.
She thinks he has very nice hands.
Truth is, he's... he has beautiful hands.
All doctors have clean, nice,
beautiful hands.
So, I told her, I said, "I've no problem
with it if you wanna go ahead."
I mean, he seems like a nice guy,
a very nice guy.
And I don't wanna get in the way of...
of her trying to get her life
back on track.
I'll be gone. I'll be gone in a few years.
I'll get a job.
If my husband made a mistake,
if out of negligence or...
I don't know what... he caused
this tragic thing to happen
I don't understand why I should have
to pay the price...
why my children should have
to pay the price.
( FORK CLANKING )
MARTIN : You know, not long
after my dad died,
someone told me that I eat spaghetti
the exact same way he did.
They said...
what an extraordinary impression
this fact had made on them.
"Look at the boy.
Look how he eats spaghetti.
Exactly the same way his father did.
He sticks his fork in, he twirls it around
and around and around and around, around.
- ( CLANKING )
- ( SQUELCHING )
Then he sticks it in his mouth."
At that time, I thought I was the only one
who ate spaghetti that way.
Me and my dad.
Later, of course, I found out
that everyone eats spaghetti
the exact same way.
Exact same way. Exact same way.
This made me very upset. Very upset.
Maybe even more upset than when
they told me he was dead...
my dad.
I don't know if what is happening is fair,
but... it's the only thing
I can think of that's close to justice.
( FORK CLANKING )
Time's getting on and if I'm late
for class, I'm done for. ( CHUCKLES )
Have a good day.
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
MAN : So, I don't see any reason
for the children to stay in the hospital.
STEVEN : You mean you think
you've done everything you can?
MAN : Yes, Steven, ( believe
we've done everything we can.
STEVEN : I'm sorry, but If I was running
this hospital
I'd feel like a complete failure.
A loser. I wouldn't be able
to sleep at night.
- Goodnight, Anna.
- Goodnight, Ed.
I suggest we sign the release forms
tomorrow and they can go home.
- ( HORNS HONKING )
- ( CARS WHIZZING BY )
ANNA : Were you the anesthesiologist
for Jonathan Lang?
- Oh, thank you. Do you want?
- No, thank you.
Who's Jonathan Lang?
Male, 46 years old, patient
of Steven's, died on the operating table.
Anna, there have been so many patients
over the years, so many operations.
I don't remember him, unfortunately.
I'm sorry.
Can you find me his file in the records
and show it to me, please?
I wanna see his medical history
and the cause of death.
MATTHEW : I don't think that's possible.
I'm sorry, Anna.
I can't just share files
from the hospital.
Why do you need it?
Please.
Look, I can't give you the file,
but I can tell you
a couple of things about the case.
I remember him now. I put him under.
But what do I get in return?
What you didn't get that day we came
for lunch at your house.
When?
Now.
- ANNA : Had Steven been drinking?
- MATTHEW : Yes.
- ANNA : Can it be considered his mistake?
MATTHEW : It wasn't mine, that's for sure.
You know an anesthesiologist is never
to blame for the bad outcome
of an operation.
The surgeon is always responsible.
He'd had two drinks that morning
before we went in to prepare.
Luckily no one else realized.
I was the only one that knew.
But, back then,
that wasn't exactly unusual.
You know that.
( MATTHEW PANTING )
- ( ZIPPER RATTLING )
- ( MATTHEW PANTS FASTER )
( MOANING )
( EXHALES WITH RELIEF )
( HEAVY BREATHING )
Thank you.
Oh, this meat is delicious.
I mean, you were right after all.
The children are much better off here.
I was even thinking we might take them
to the beach house for a few days.
A little fresh air and a change of scenery
might do us all good.
Do you know what I've been craving?
Mashed potato.
Why don't you make some tomorrow?
You have beautiful hands.
I never noticed before.
Everyone's been telling me lately
what beautiful hands you have,
and now I can see for myself.
Nice and clean.
But so what if they're beautiful?
They're lifeless.
Sometimes, Steven,
you're just an incompetent man
who goes on and on saying stupid things
like "Let's do a scan.
Let's do an ultrasound.
Let's wear brown socks.
Let's make mashed potatoes.
Let's go to the beach house."
Excuse me?
Our two children are dying
in the other room but, yes,
I can make you mashed potatoes tomorrow.
- Please don't talk to me that way.
- If you don't like it, why don't you
go and live with Martin's mother.
I bet she'll talk to you better.
You wanted the kids to come home,
and they came home.
- What else do you want me to do?
- Something to put an end to all of this,
that's what I want. Can you do that?
You do realize, Steven, we're
in this situation because of you?
( WHISPERS ) So, what do you suggest?
Tell me.
No, wait. I know, I've got it.
There is a way we can put a stop
to all this.
All we need to do is find the tooth
of a baby crocodile,
the blood of a pigeon
and the pubes of a virgin.
And then we just have to burn them all
before sunset. Let me see.
Do we have any spare teeth lying around?
Teeth? Pubes? No, nothing here!
( CUTLERY CLANKING )
There's nothing in here.
- Let me see. Nothing here! Pubes? Teeth?
- ( GLASS SHATTERING )
Nothing in this box, either.
Where are they?
I'm sure they were here earlier.
I put them here myself.
Who's been moving things around?
Unbelievable!
I don't suppose you've got any pubes
I can have, by any chance?
Oh, I forgot, you don't have any left.
We don't have any of the things we need.
There's no need for us to argue.
Everything's so difficult already.
There's no point in making it worse.
If he was telling the truth,
wouldn't you be sick, too?
Wouldn't you be paralyzed already?
How do you explain that?
Yes, you're right.
Let's wait a little longer
until we're all dead,
and then see what you can do about it.
There's really nothing to worry about.
You need to go to the hospital tomorrow
and pick up more feeding formula
- for the children. We're almost out.
- Okay.
( SWITCH CLICKS )
( OMINOUS MUSIC PLAYING )
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( DOOR CRACKS OPEN )
STEVEN : Good morning.
Good morning.
Did you get any sleep?
What time is it?
STEVEN : Ten past eight.
Get up and come with me for a moment.
( FOOTSTEPS )
( DOOR CREAKS OPEN )
- ( SWITCH CLICKS )
- ( ELECTRICITY HUMMING )
STEVEN : You remember Martin, don't you?
He came by for a play-date.
I told him the kids were feeling
a little unwell, and he'll have
to stay here until they get better.
Anna, go upstairs and make him
some of that lemonade he likes so much.
Would you? I'll stay here
and keep him company.
Please.
( DOOR CLOSES WITH A THUD )
Let me go.
My mother's gonna be worried sick.
Do you think
your mother's proud of you, Martin?
Do you think she's happy
that her beloved son is a murderer?
Murderer?
There is really no need
for such a dramatic, sensational,
old-fashioned word.
But if you insist,
the murderer, both in my father's case
and our current situation, is not me.
- Stop talking.
- Don't you understand
that you're wasting time
and you don't have much time left.
STEVEN : I said stop talking.
Steven, it's gonna be better
once it's done.
Start over, clean slate. Don't you get it?
Sometimes, I think you're naive.
But you can't be naive.
You're a man of science.
You can't be an idiot.
But, if I'd only just met you,
I would seriously question
your depth of judgment.
( WHACK )
( MARTIN GROANS )
I just want... want to show you an example.
- ( TOOTH ROLLS AWAY )
- That's all.
Just one little example
to show you what I mean.
( STEVEN GRUNTS )
- ( GRUNTING )
- ( GROANING )
Should I apologize? No.
( DEEP BREATHING )
Should I, should I stroke your wound?
Actually, that would probably hurt
even more, touching an open wound.
No, there's only one way to make
you and me both feel better.
( RAPID BREATHING )
- ( SQUELCH )
- ( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( GROANING )
Do you understand? It's metaphorical.
My example. It's a metaphor.
I mean, it's... it's symbolic.
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
- ( DOOR SLAMS )
- ( DOG BARKS )
( FOOTSTEPS RUNNING )
Shut the door, Anna.
Now, Martin, you'll know
what it's like to die.
What it's like when your head cracks open
and your brains blow out.
Don't shoot him.
- MARTIN : And then?
- Shut up!
Shoot me. Then what? Answer.
I'll bury you in the yard. And you'll rot.
That's what.
You won't be able to explain it.
You won't understand
how it could have happened.
You'll say, "But I only killed one person.
How come four people are dead?
I only shot one."
So if you're gonna dig a hole in the yard,
better make it a big one.
- ( RIFLE COCKS )
- ANNA : Steven.
( AGGRESSIVE PIANO PLAYING )
( MURMURING )
( BREATHING DEEPLY )
KIM : He didn't kill him.
- BOB : How do you know?
- KIM : I just do.
Anyway, he made the right choice.
Otherwise it would have been like
killing four people with a single shot.
Wouldn't that be tragic?
I'm going to live with Martin.
I want you to know
that I'm really sorry, Bob.
I really love you. We all do.
Dad does, too.
But he's in a really difficult position
and he doesn't have much of a choice.
It's not because he doesn't love you.
They bought me a piano.
Mom told me it'd be here next month.
They didn't tell you
so you wouldn't be scared.
Bob, something terrible
happened yesterday.
I lost the MP3 player that Martin gave me.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
I've lost two MP3 players
in the last ten days.
So, I'd like to ask you a favor.
Can I have your MP3 player
when you're dead?
Please. Please. Please.
( SLIDES WITH A SQUEAK )
( HANDS LAND WITH THUDS )
( CLICKING )
( WATER SPLASHING )
BOB : Dad. Look.
I cut my hair just as you wanted me to.
Good boy. Well done.
I'm sorry I didn't listen to you
and get a haircut right away.
I don't know
what I was thinking all this time.
I would get so hot
and have to comb it all the time.
It was a total hassle.
I should have listened to you
and cut it off sooner.
I'm gonna water the plants now.
No, darling. I watered them this morning.
Tomorrow.
Dad.
I've been thinking about it
and I've decided
I wanna become a cardiologist.
Not an ophthalmologist.
I lied to Mom because I didn't want her
to get upset.
I think I prefer what you do.
It's far more interesting and challenging.
( SOBBING )
( SNIFFLING )
( PEOPLE TALKING INDISTINCTLY )
PRINCIPAL : The boy is very good
at math and physics.
Kim, on the other hand,
apart from her natural aptitude for music,
is very good at literature and history,
areas in which Bob lags behind.
She wrote a brilliant essay
on the tragedy of Iphigenia,
which she read out in class.
She received an A-plus.
What about their behavior in class?
They're both a little restless, I'd say.
Equally so.
I mean, I've had the occasional complaint
from their teachers
about some minor misdemeanors,
but they've never been rude
to any of the staff.
In any case, if they had ever acted out,
we would have told you about it.
Do you especially like one of them
more than the other?
If you had to choose between them,
which would say is the best?
That's a difficult question.
I'm not sure I can give you an answer.
I don't know.
I don't know what to tell you.
( CLICK )
( ANTISEPTIC SWIRLS )
Thank you for bringing them down.
I really wanted to see them.
I really wanted to see you.
MARTIN : Hey, Bob. Hey, Kim.
Bob, aren't you going to come over
and let me give you a hug?
ANNA : Bob?
MARTIN : No?
I understand. It doesn't matter.
You're a man.
The man of the house
now your father isn't home.
You can go back to bed.
Don't trouble yourselves for my sake.
You can take them away.
( LIPS SMACKING )
Anna, if you're gonna do something,
you'd better be fast.
The boy is about to die.
( CRICKETS CHIRPING )
( SQUELCHING )
( DISTANT CLOCK TICKING )
- ( SHEETS RUFFLING )
- ( BED CREAKING )
I believe the most logical thing,
no matter how harsh this may sound,
is to kill a child.
Because we can have another child.
I still can and you can.
And if you can't, we can try IVF,
but I'm sure we can.
KIM : I'm sorry for what I did tonight.
I don't know what I was thinking.
I was only thinking about myself
and no one else.
That was wrong of me.
I was frightened.
I shouldn't have been.
Let me be the one
who atones for your sins, Dad.
Kill me right here in front of your eyes
so that you can be sure that I die,
in case some fate
spares me at the last moment.
Kill me right here in front of you
and leave me with the ultimate joy
of saving my own mother
and beloved brother from certain death.
( OMINOUS MUSIC )
Mom, tell him.
Dad, please.
I would do anything for you.
I would even die for you
and here's my chance to prove it.
They're all asleep. We can go now
and no one will notice.
All you have to do is help me walk again.
KIM : My legs hurt after all this time
and I feel weak.
But it's okay. It doesn't matter.
I knew at some point this would all
be over and you would come.
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
I thought we could take
your friend's motorcycle
and run away together.
But you have to make me well first.
KIM : I'll untie you if you promise
you can make me better
It's not working. You have to try harder.
Kim's not in her bed.
I'm telling you, you have to try harder!
Are you deaf?
Martin. Try harder!
- STEVEN : Where is she?
- MARTIN : She's gone.
( THWACK )
Where is she? What did you do to her?
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
I love you so much, don't forget that.
You gave me life and you, only you,
have the right to take my life away.
That makes perfect sense.
KIM : You are my lords, my masters
and I am just someone
who lives to obey your wishes.
I love you so much.
Remember that when I'm lying in my grave,
unable to tell you that I love you.
I love you more than anything
in the world, you and my brother.
( LIPS SMACKING )
Where have you been?
I went to the hospital.
Got the feeding formula.
Have you checked on him?
Did you give him the sedative?
I let him go.
- What are you talking about?
- He's not downstairs. I let him go.
Why would you do that?
( WHACKS ) Why did you let him go?
Answer me!
Are you a complete idiot?
It's not gonna make any difference,
Steven.
It's not gonna solve anything.
We both know that.
( WATER DRIPPING )
Mom?
Do you remember that day when I was rude
- to you at the hospital?
- ( WATER DRIPS ) Yes.
Did you tell Dad about it?
ANNA : Of course I told him about it, Kim.
I didn't mean it, Mom.
Maybe it was just a side effect
of the drugs or something.
ANNA : Kim, can you please be quiet?
Do your legs hurt? Do they feel numb?
- Does your back hurt? Has it started yet?
- ( WHACKS HARD )
( EERIE MUSIC PLAYING )
( MUSIC GROWS LOUDER )
( INDISTINCT VOICES )
( VIOLIN PLAYING )
Dad! Quick! Bob's dying!
Dad! Bob's dying!
Dad.
Who's your best friend?
I don't know, Bob.
I have three.
Two boys and a girl in my class.
That's great, Bob.
It's good to have a lot of friends.
( FOOTSTEPS ASCENDING )
Bob's eyes are bleeding.
Come to the living room.
- Now?
- Yes.
Now.
Steven, where are the children?
They're already there.
I think I'm gonna wear
that black dress that you like.
Wear whatever you want. Just hurry.
( MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING )
( FOOTSTEPS )
( RIFLE COCKING )
( WHIMPERING )
( SHRILL MUSIC PLAYING )
( FEET THUMPING )
( SHRILL MUSIC RISING )
- ( GUNSHOT )
- ( CLATTER )
( RIFLE LOADING )
- ( GUNSHOT )
- ( THUD )
- ( BULLET LANDS WITH A CLANG )
- ( RIFLE COCKING )
( GUNSHOT )
( "JOHANNES PASSION" PLAYING )
( "JOHANNES PASSION" CONTINUES PLAYING )
Subtitles by: FrancisSubs
^.^.^.^.COLORED by.^.^.^.^
® Sud_Arun collections ®
A member of Psagmeno.com