Fixed & Synced by bozxphd.Enjoy The Flick
I'm really sorry.
Does he wear glasses or contact lens?
Glasses.
You would have to hurry up.
He decided his brown leather
shoes were the best pair to wear.
His back hurt a little, but not
like some other time in the past...
when the pain was intolerable.
He was thinking his wife doesn't
love him at all anymore.
He didn't burst into tear
and he didn't think...
things most people do...
when they realise someone doesn't
love them anymore is cry.
Sir, would you mind take a look
into the camera here for me?
That's ok, thank you.
Have you ever been on your own before?
No, never.
Are you allergic to any food?
No.
Your last relationship last how many years?
Around 12.
Do you remember how long exactly sir?
Eleven years and seven months.
Sexual preference?
Women.
However I had one homosexual experience...
in the past, in college.
Is there bisexual option available?
No sir, this option is no longer
available since about last summer...
due to several operational problems
I'm afraid you have yo decide right now
if you want to be registered as...
homosexual or heterosexual
I think I should be
registered as heterosexual.
Any children sir?
No.
And dog?
My brother, he was here couple of
years ago, but he didn't make it.
You might remember him.
Medium built, 48 years old,
bald patch, blond hair
I'm afraid no sir.
Ok, I like you to write your
name clearly on this form.
In capital letter and sign please.
Very good, thank you very much.
So, you're not allow to use
volley-ball or tennis court.
These are only for the couples.
You can use facility for individual
sports such as squash and golf.
You can stay at hotel for up to 45 days.
You would be staying at the single room.
If everything goes well and you make it,
you would be moved to a double room
I'm afraid you can't keep any
of your personal belongings.
We will provide everything
you need as far as...
garments, accessories,
and shoes are concerned.
You can keep this
Thank you.
Shoe size please
44 and a half
44 or 45? there's no half sizes
If you need a hair cut, call reception
one day ahead, smoking is not allowed.
That you would be able to run for longer
during the hunt without getting tired...
and you breath won't smell when you kiss.
Enjoy your stay.
Excuse me.
If we need to get hair cut, we must call
reception a day before, is that right?
That's right
Great.
His room number was 101.
A tranqulizer gun...
was hanging on the wall above his bed.
On the table were 20 tranquilzer darts...
a black plastic watch, a
pair of sunglasses...
and a cologne for man.
Inside the wardrobe were four
identical grey trousers...
four identical button down
shirts in white and blue...
a belt, socks, underwear, a blazer...
a striped tie and a white bathrobe.
He looked out of window.
The unconscious bodies
of captured loners...
were lying on the wet ground.
"Thank God they wear those water
proof ponchos", he thought.
Room 195.
Two loners, two extra days.
Room 272.
One loner, one extra day.
Hello, I'm the hotel manager, and
this gentleman is my partner.
We like to welcome you.
You're one of the lucky one.
You have one of our supreme room
which means you have a view.
Did you read the lease list
Yes it is.
Very good.
Now the fact you turning into a animal...
if you fail to fall in love with
someone during your stay here...
is not something should
upset you or get you down.
Just think as a animal...
you have a second chance
to find a companion.
But even then you must be careful.
You need to choose a companion
that is similar type animal...
to you.
A wolf and a penguin can
never live together.
Nor a camel and a hippopotamus.
That would be absurd, think about it
I understand this discussion
is a little unpleasant for you.
But it is my duty to prepare you...
psychologically for all possible outcomes.
Now have you thought of what animal
you like to be if end up alone?
Yes, a lobster.
Why a lobster? Because lobster
live for over one hundred years.
Are blue blood like aristocrat...
and stay fertile all their life
I also like the sea very much
I water ski, swim quite
well since I was a teenager
I must congratulate you, the first
thing most people think of is a dog...
which is why the world is full of dogs.
Very few people choose unusual animal...
which is why they are in danger.
A lobster is a excellent choice.
Could you stand for us please?
This is to show you how easy life is...
when there are two of something
rather than just one.
We tend to forget that from time to time.
The handcuff will be removed
the same time tomorrow
I'm sorry bob.
Hope you enjoy staying with us.
Goodbye.
Have a good day.
Good morning.
Room 101, 44 days left.
Breakfast is served.
His first day was one he never forget.
Near his table of breakfast
sat a young women...
with her head tilted back.
Later he would learn...
she often got nose bleed.
Next to her sat her best friend.
He thanked the waiter who
served his coffee...
and thought about his wife for a moment.
A woman who seems to like butter biscuit...
offered one to a man drinking...
a Compari soda for breakfast.
He then looked behind him saw a woman...
who would later find out
was absolutely heartless.
And some others in the couple's area...
whom he may never meet
druing his stay at the hotel.
That morning he was really hungry.
He could eat a whole chicken...
but ate almost nothing.
Hello
I decided to go for a walk
ouside with my new friend.
Let me introduce you.
This is Robert, he stay in the
room next to mine had a lisp.
Please to meet you, I stay in the room 101
I'm on the same floor, 186.
Would you like to join us?
Why not.
One of these days gonna be
me on one of those yachts.
Why those yachts?
The final ordeal before letting you go.
The hardest one
15 days of vacation just a couple
alone, didn't you read the leaflet?
I did.
Did you see John's leg?
No
John, could you show your leg?
Oh yeah.
Room 187, day 2.
Hello everyone.
My mother was left on her own when my
father fell in love with a woman...
who was better at math than she was.
She has postgraduate degree, I think.
While my mother only a graduate
I was 19 at the time.
My mother entered the hotel but didn't
make it and was turning into a wolf
I really miss her
I found out she's been moved to a zoo
I often went there to see her
I give her raw meat
I knew the wolf like raw meat.
But I couldn't figure out which
of the wolves was my mother.
So I used to give a little
bit to each of them.
One day I decided to enter the enclosure
I really missed her and I wanted a hug
I climbed the fence and jumped in.
All the wolves charged
at once and attacked me.
All but two stood motionless
I guess one of those two must be my mother.
The zoo guard got to me quite
quickly and took me to the hospital.
Thankfully I didn't lose my leg
I just had this limp.
Which also is my defining characteristic.
My wife died six days ago.
She was very beautiful
and I love her very much.
She had limp too.
Thank you John, you can return to you seat.
Let's move on to our next
guest, room 104, day 2.
Hello everyone.
This is only my second day here.
But already I feel like a
member of wonderful group.
My defining characteristic is
that I have very beautiful smile.
Something's gotten hold of my heart.
Keeping my soul and my senses apart.
Something's gotten into my life.
Have you ever dance with anybody?
Sorry?
Yes.
What sort of dancing you should do?
Just depends on the music.
Do you need to sit down?
No, no, I'm getting ready to dance.
Can I sit here?
I'm sorry.
Of course.
Let me introduce you to my best friend.
That woman you were talking
to have no feeling whatsoever.
She feels nothing at all
She's the best hunter in hotel.
Silent and very fast.
She's the women record holder
192 captors.
Changing the grey, changing the blue.
Scarlet for me...
it's scarlet for you
if this is the real thing.
Would you like to dance?
Every day yeah.
You touch me and my mind goes astray yeah.
And baby, and Baby.
Something's gotten hold of my heart.
Dragging my soul to a beautiful land.
Something's gotten into my life
I'm sorry, I got the blood on your shirt.
But don't worry, there are many ways
to remove blood stain from clothing.
One way is to wring the clothes to
cold water, then rub in sea salt.
Another way is to srape the stain
with cotton ball dip in ammonia.
The third way is to make flour
mold into a paste like toothpaste.
Especially it the clothes are
delicate or bright color.
But juse never use warm
water on blood, ever.
Ok.
But then you, you, you.
You came my way.
But then you came my way.
And a feeling unknown shook my heart...
make me want you to stay
all of my nights and all of my days
I think I have to rest for a little bit.
My leg hurts
That's ok.
But let me know when you feel
better, and we can dance again.
Keeping my soul and my senses apart.
Something has invaded my light.
Painting my sleep with
the colours so bright.
Changing the gray changing the blue.
Scarlet for me
it's scarlet for you.
Leave the building in orderly fashion.
Do hurry up, and please be carefully
no one should get hurt or injured...
and good luck with the hunt
I wish I didn't have this limp
I used to good at running, but not anymore
I'm sure would be slower than them.
If I were you, I think of some trick
that choose element of surprise...
instead of speed.
You're right.
That's what I would do.
Back when you loved me.
You asked me one morning
while we were talking
"what was life about?"
I turned and told you
for some it's the wine
for some it's the glory
for some it's being rich
but for me it is only you
for some it's the glory
for some it's being rich
but for me it is only you.
Now that your heart has changed.
And you love someone else.
You still wonder what they're saying.
How my own heart beats.
Are there perhaps more
people like me exist.
Dead on the inside.
Alive on the outside.
Room 186.
One loner, one extra day
38 days left, plus one, 39.
Room 180.
The day of your stay remain unchanged.
Room 290.
Four loners, four extra days
154 days left, plus four, 158.
Room 101.
The day of your stay remain unchanged
32 days left.
Breakfast is served.
Man eats alone.
How many darts did you use yesterday?
12.
Please take off your
trousers and sit on the bed.
Can we not do this today?
It's awful
I know, but I'm afraid we have to do it.
And you have no idea how much
it help you psychologically...
in your search for partner.
Man eats with woman
ls your room number 186?
Yes it is
I imagine you know
masturbation is not permitted
in the room or any other
area of the hotel.
Yes.
And yet, it is been brought to my
attention you continue to do it.
Today, you became erect quicker
than other days, that's good.
Please, just a little longer.
Have a good day.
That's awful, just awful.
Are you looking at the photograph
while you masturbating?
Yes.
What does the photograph show?
A naked woman on a horse in the country.
If I were in your shoes I would not be
ogling the naked woman but the horse
I'm sure that horse's once
a weak and cowardly man...
just like you.
Woman walks alone.
Help.
This is not necessary, please...
It was a accident, I just get carry away.
This is not necessary
Please.
Please place your hand on the toaster
This could be a warning
I've been good otherwise, I...
I'm sorry
I'm sorry, please.
Please, please, I'm sorry.
Woman walks with man.
What they do as soon as
you enter the room...
is to wash you body and
your head really well.
How did you know?
My uncle used to know a
waiter who worked here.
The waiter know the procedure.
They are not allow to inside that room.
Nevertheless, they peel off the skin...
which has become soft due
to the watering and soap.
Afterward they remove the heart, the eyes
and other vital organs of the body...
with laser or scalpels.
Then the procedure changes according
to the animal one has choosen.
That makes total sense
I mean I suppose mammals demand
different kind of work than...
fowl, for example
Exactly.
Afterward they throw
remaining body parts of
the carcass outside the
hotel restaurant...
and distribute the blood to
the hospital in the city.
Why is that.
The blood is used for surgery where
there aren't blood donor available.
New guests arrived yesterday
Yes I saw them
I think I saw a woman with limp.
It is just sprained ankle.
She would be walking normally
again after a few days.
That's a shame.
It's a shame indeed.
One night on the coach, he sat next
to woman who like butter biscuit.
He gazed out of the window, not
looking at anything in particular.
Just trying avoid talking to her.
How is Bob?
He is fine.
Give anything to go for a walk
with you and Bob one afternoon.
The dogs are not allow
there's a rule, I'm afraid.
"There are some excuses no one
can't argue with", he thought.
Some excuses without a
doubt better than others.
That was really good one.
These biscuits are for Bob
I want you to give them to him whenever
you want to reward him for something.
Tell him it is from me
Thank you.
Can I come to your room sometime for a chat
I could give you a blow job.
Or you could just fuck me
I always swallow after
fellatio and absolutely
have no problem with anal
sex if that's you thing.
My ex-husband always used to said that
I have the most beautiful size he's
ever see, but let's not talk about him.
My room number is 180, so my
telephone extension is 180.
Hope catch some loners tonight.
Haven't caught any the last few nights.
Hope you catch lots too.
Thank you very much.
If I don't find a suitable partner soon
I'm gonna kill myself by throwing
myself out of one of room.
Out the window
I want you to know that.
My room is on the first floor.
"I hope catch some loners today"...
she said.
"And I hope you catch lots too".
She then told him that if she didn't...
find suitable partner soon.
She was going to kill herself by
jumping from one of room windows
320, maybe.
Or one higher up, 480,
that would be even better.
When she stop talking.
He stare at her blankly,
not knowing what to say.
Him then look out of the
woods, thought once more...
how good his excuse's been.
Not bad, a bit higher.
You thought about what animal you
wanna be if you don't make it?
A lobster
I'm gonna be a parrot if I don't make it.
Why don't you become parrot
too, then we all be together?
You're complete idiot.
Picking one of few animals that can talk...
when you have a speech impediment.
You're lisp even as a animal.
As for you, they will catch you and put you
in a pot of boiling water until you die.
And then crack open you claws
with a tool by prying it,
then suck up what little flesh
you have with their mouth.
You're pathetic, both of you
I'm not gonna be turning into some
animal, I'll come visit you though...
with my patner, then we walking
together in some park of...
where we swimming in the sea
when we're on one of our trip.
Friends.
Room 187 please.
It's not coincidence that targets are
shape like single people and not couples.
Hello.
Hello
You swimsuit is very nice.
Thank you very much
You're welcome.
Do you like to swim breaststroke,
front row, batterfly or backstroke?
I like all sorts equally.
You know I love breaststroke.
Oh really, my friends
often teased me, said...
"stop swimming breaststroke
all the time"...
and they laughed.
Breaststroke is great.
It's excellent exercise for the back.
When swimming breaststroke, men
shouldn't wear swimming shorts...
has really limit movement in the buttocks.
But you know that, didn't you?
I think your nose is bleeding.
Really?
Oh no.
This happen to me all the time.
It's really, really annoying
I know, I have nose bleeding problem too
I saw what you did, must have hurt.
Is it coming out.
No.
Yes.
Can I use the tissue
Can I ask you a question, I
want you to answer me honestly.
What's worse? To die of cold
and hunger in the woods.
To become a animal would be killed
or eaten by some big animal.
Or have nose bleed from time to time.
To become a animal would be killed
or eaten by some big animal.
Exactly.
She isn't suspect you're lying?
No
I'm very happy because
we have a new couple.
They met just two days ago.
But they very much in
love and perfect suited.
They both have same
problem with their noses.
They bleed quite suddenly.
Tomorrow they will be
transfer to a double room...
with larger wardrobe and larger bathroom.
They will remain in the
double room for two weeks...
and then been transferred to the
yacht for the further two weeks.
We wish you every success and hope
you return to the city as a couple
I'm very happy
Me too.
Congratulation.
The course of your relationship
will be monitored closely...
by our stuffs and by me personally.
If you encounter any problems,
any tensions, any arguing...
that you can't resolve yourselves.
You would be asign children.
That usually helps a lot.
Good morning.
Room 101, 7 days left.
Breakfast is served.
You have really nice hair
I know.
Look.
How do you like mine?
I think yours quite dry hair.
Color is ok though.
The most important thing
is that you're not bald.
However when comes to men, bald is
always the possibility you can't avoid
ls your father bald?
No he isn't.
And even if somedays I lose my hair.
There are things I can
do to get my hair back
I can have a hair transplant.
You always can tell someone
had a hair transplant
I know
Nice hair is not something you can get.
It's something you born with.
The fact your father isn't
bald shouldn't put you at ease.
Have you decided what you're
going to do in your last day?
I'm still thinking about it.
Morning ladies.
So, today is your last day.
And as the customary, you can choose...
how you like to spend your last night.
What I always said in this
situation is it would
be wise to do something
you can't do as animal.
For example read a work
of classic literature...
or sing a song you really like.
It would be silly to choose...
for example, a walking the ground...
or have sex intercourse
with another person,
those are things you
can do as animal.
But first, your best friend
is reading something...
she like to read you,
it's really very touching.
We always sat together at school...
and whenever I had a problem...
I told you about it because you
always give the best advice.
When we didn't manage to find...
dance partner at the school prom.
The fact we were together at that
difficult moment give me strength
I'm sorry things come to this
I'm sure if you have a few more days.
You would find someone just like I did,
because you're a adorable person...
and you have very beautiful
hair and very nice breath
I'm always jealous of your hair...
you know that.
You were, are, and always
will be my best friend.
And I'll think of you often, and I'll
always wear those silver earing...
you give me for my birthday
I'll miss you.
And However many new girl
friends I make in a few days...
when I move back into the city
I don't think I'll find another as true...
I like to ask for the ¡Stand By Me¡·...
with River Phoenix, Kiefer Sutherland...
and Richard Dreyfuss, alone.
Excellent choice.
Lovely film.
Please leave a message.
Hello.
You're probably in the bathroom,
that's why you can't hear phone ring.
Nothing like a cold shower in the morning.
Well, I'll call you a little bit
later after you finish your shower.
We'll talk later.
Bye.
One day, as he was playing golf.
He thought that it is
more difficult to pretend
you do have feelings
when you don't...
than to pretend you don't
have feelings when you do.
He also thought that he like her accent
and he always prefer woman with short hair.
So he decided she was the one.
During the hunt, he would followed her.
And as soon as she shot a
loner, he would said to her:
"I wish we have real gun..."
instead of this silly tranquilizer one...
"why don't you kill him
with your bare hands?"
And the moment she put her
hand around loner's throat.
He would said:
"I hope him die right the way".
What happened?
She jumped from the window of room 180.
There are bloods and biscuits everywhere
I hope she die right the way.
On second thought, I hope she
suffers quite a bit before she dies
I just hope her pathetic scream...
can't be heard from my room.
Because I was thinking about having a
lie down and I need peace and quiet
I was playing golf and I'm quite tired.
The last thing I need is some
woman dying slowly and loudly
I can't hear you with all this screaming.
We'll talk some other
time when it's quieter.
Good bye.
One message.
Hello.
You're probably in the bathroom,
that's why you can't hear phone ring.
Nothing like a cold shower in the morning.
Well, I'll call you a little bit
later after you finish your shower.
We'll talk later.
Bye.
Do you mind if I join in.
You like Martini
I think we're a match
Yes, I think so too.
The keys to the double room, please
I wish you the best of the luck, we
all wish you the best of the luck.
Do you normally sleep on the left
side of the bed or the right?
The right, you?
The left, perfect.
Should I shut off the light
or would you like to read?
I like to read, does light bother you?
No
I'm not bothered by light or noise
I'm deep sleeper.
Hello
Hello.
Congratulation
Thank you.
This is our new daughter,
her name is Elizabeth
Elizabeth, give this nice man a
kiss, he is a friend of mine.
The last thing I want right now
is a kiss from silly little girl.
Come on, you know.
Don't cry, you should thank me, Elizabeth.
Now you have a limp and would
be more like your father.
Good morning.
Good morning
I killed your bother
I left him to die very slowly.
He may not be dead yet as now we speak
I was kicking him for ages.
Doesn't matter.
He whined a little the strangest
kind of bark, something like this.
Must have been from pain.
You didn't hear anything?
No.
You really are deep sleeper.
Would you like some coffee?
I love some.
As soon as I wash my
face and brush my teeth
I can't wait to hear that story you
promise to tell me last night...
about that student of yours in the
university, and his awful final project.
It's really very funny story.
His name is Ryess.
R-y-e-s-s, Ryess.
It is not tear, just water,
I just washed my face
I knew you were lying
I can't understand why you did it.
When you know as anyone...
that relationship can
not be built on the lie.
We're going to the hotel manager right now,
and you'll get the punishment you deserve.
What's the punishment for this.
They turn you into animal
no one wants to be
I saw you patner went back that way.
He looked frantic.
Is everything ok?
At first he wanted to kill her in
some horrible and painful way...
like the death she
inflicted on his brother.
He thought about kicking her in
the stomach over and over again.
And then stabbing her in the
same spot in the stomach.
Then he thought there wouldn't be much
point because she's already unconscious...
and wouldn't feel any pain
from the kick or the knife.
You have to shoot me, so they
don't suspect I helped you.
A hotel maid helped him.
He couldn't understand why she did it.
So he decided to turn her into a animal.
He dragged her to the room
with transformation took place.
I asked him many times what sorts
of animal he turn her into.
But he always give me the same answer.
"That's none of your concern".
That night he left the hotel...
once and for all.
He began to run without
knowing where he was heading.
But he was heading to us.
This was the start of his new life.
Back then, he didn't know how
much it hurts to be alone.
How much it hurts when you can not reach
to rub pain relieve ointment on your back.
And you're constantly in pain.
Find him in the woods,
he escaped from hotel.
Are you a doctor by any chance?
No.
That's a pity.
We need a doctor around.
We had one, but they caught
him a couple of months ago
I'm a achitect.
That's ok, so welcome.
You can stay with us for
as long as you like.
You can be a loner until the day
you die, there is no time limit.
Thank you very much.
Anyway, any romantic or sexual relations...
between loners are not permitted.
And any such acts are
punished, is that clear?
Can I have a converstation with someone?
Of course you can, so long as there
is no flirting or anything like that.
That apply to dance nights as well.
We all dance by ourselves.
That's why we only play electronic music.
What happened to you mouth.
He can't speak, he's getting the red kiss.
What's the red kiss?
We slash his lips with razor
and lips of another loner, then
force them to kiss each other.
That was couple of days ago now.
But the cuts are deep,
so they're still in pain.
They were flirting, you know.
Some punishments are worse
than other punishments.
Having your thumb cut is worse
than having you head shaved.
And having a hot boiled
egg under you arm pit...
is worse than having you leg kicked.
The punishment I'm afraid of isn't
the red kiss but another one.
It is called the red intercourse.
I have never seen it happened.
But it's not difficult to
imagine what it is means.
Oh my God, I'm so afraid of it.
Move.
Hide.
That was the first time I saw him.
He was hiding behind a tree close to mine.
He seems quite presentable.
The next day, in the city.
He found out that I was shortsighted too.
That night in my sleep, I dreamed...
we lived in a big house
together in the city...
with large and well lit kitchen.
And I was wearing dark blue trousers...
and tight green blouse.
And he took my clothes off
and fuck me up the ass.
And as he was fucking me, a
thug came into the kitchen...
and took the steak knife
from the second drawer...
and attacked us, stabbing
the knife into our belly...
one by one.
I woke up terrified.
Try harder.
Don't give up, you know you
should've been more careful.
Try harder, or they'll find you...
and you would be turning
into a animal, a weak one.
We must get to move on now.
It's really too dangerous to stay here.
If you manage to free yourself, run
as fast as you can, and come find us.
If you manage to free yourself, but
think you'll die from bleeding.
Go straight to your grave.
Have you dug your own grave?
¡ªYes
¡ªVery good.
That's enough for now
I'm going to go hunting for truffles.
They are delicious and quite rare.
A kilo can fetch a lot of money.
You're going to need a pig
they are impossible to find out otherwise
I know
Don't be long.
Gonna get them back in 50 minutes.
Hello David
Hello Robert.
What you did to that woman is dreadful
She killed my brother
I would've done the same
thing if she killed you.
You, you're like a brother to me.
Oh you're my best friend of the whole world
I don't think I'm your best
friend of the whole world.
You used to spend much time with John.
Oh, who's John?
John, the limping man
Oh yeah
I didn't even remember
his name, or his face.
You're the one I think of
whenever I need a friend.
Nevertheless, did John make it?
They're getting ready for the yacht.
All begin this week.
Everyone said they're going to
make it as perfect suited...
and a child could help them
pass the fighting and arguing.
That's great
You're not thinking coming back?
You know if you told the hotel
manager about your brother.
She probably forgive you.
No, it's really nice to be on your own.
There is no one tying you down.
You listen to music whenever you like,
You masturbate whenever you want.
Go for a walk whenever you like,
have a chat whenever you like
I don't miss companionship at all
I just miss you, because
you're my one true friend.
Are you gonna shoot me?
I'm afraid so, I only have two days left.
What did you said?
I can't understand what you speak
I'm gonna shoot you, I
only have two days left...
and I need more time.
Do you actually believe another
day would make a difference?
Have you seen how ugly you are.
You haven't got a chance.
If I was a woman...
Don't tell anyone I helped you.
If you want to repay me, there is a way.
If you kill a rabbit,
bring it to me to eat.
You promise?
Yes.
Bye
Bye.
- Hello.
You brought what I asked for?
Of course.
The gun is in the pocket
with the electronic keys...
with the numbers of the double rooms.
Try not to lose the keys
I need to return them
I propose we act on Saturday...
after the ball Everyone is tired...
and most employees are
gone on the week-end.
And the shampoo?
I forgot
I'll bring two bottles next time.
Do you know how fantastic you are?
Please make a note for the
shampoo so you don't forget
I need to tell you something.
What?
This is my last mission
I can't do it anymore
I can't stand living in
that horrible mansion...
with that fat dentist.
He keeps asking if I've flossed.
He makes me clean my teeth after every meal
no matter how small it is.
After we're finished setting
up for the big night
you can come and live with us
I'll find another mole
I don't think I'll ever find
someone as efficient as you
but I need to respect your wishes.
Be patient just a few more days...
and don't forget to take
your birth control pill. Ok?
Thank you.
No, thank you.
You were fantastic.
He carefully flayed the
rabbit with sharp knife...
and cut off his head.
He then sliced open its belly...
and stuffed with well washed
red and green peppers...
not too spicy, and a
little garlic and mint.
He then soak it to lemon juice and
leave it a while to marinate the flesh.
Before you skewer it on a stick and
roast over the fire for about an hour.
That's my favourite food.
Rabbit.
Woman, brunette, 50 years old.
Marriage certificate
expired two months ago.
My husband went on a bussiness trip
Ok, may I have a look?
Hands.
No dirt under her nails
or mud under her shoes
9, Belsize road.
So your husband does away
Yes.
Where?
Bath.
Good morning, sir.
Are you here alone?
Good morning, officer.
No, I'm here with my partner.
She's inside one of the
stores shopping right now.
Can I see you certificate please?
My partner keep it in her purse.
You see, I'm losing it all the time
I see, and what store is she shopping in?
Oh, here she is
I'm sorry, darling.
They have such huge variety
pain relieve ointment
I bought you this one, I hope
it's the one you're looking for.
That's wonderful, dear, can
I have my certificate?
Of course, darling, would you
like to see mine, officer?
No, that's ok.
Thank you, sir.
You have a good day.
Thank you, officer, you have a good day
Madam.
Sir.
If I'm walking too slowly, just say it.
And I'll pick up my pace.
This pace is fine.
Maybe you don't squeeze my hand so tightly,
my palms are getting a little sweety.
Better?
Yes, much better.
Are you planning on buying anything else
nice for yourself while we're here?
Yes, contact len solution...
and Packer rollerball
I didn't know you're short-sighted
I'm short-sighted too.
Will you stay a few days?
I'm afraid not, papa.
We're heading back again today
tomorrow I'm going away
on a bussiness trip.
You know how demanding my job is.
Don't ask if I can stay a
few days everytime I come.
Do you all work for the same company?
Yes
Yes.
My daughter said to me
it's a very fine company.
Do you agree?
It's a rather good company
Yes it is.
One of the best, I would say.
The only problem with job is
that I don't have much time...
for my wife and kids.
We have four beautiful children.
Congratulation.
Thank you
Thank you.
But even if we don't have children
I would never dream of leaving my wife.
Even if it just two of us,
on our own, we go on trips.
We go to Portofino in Italy, and
go to Greek island for the summer.
So our relationship would be as
intense as it was at the start
I love my wife so much...
I could die for her.
That's how much I love her.
We first day in the city did great.
That part about holiday destination in
the Mediterranean was really brilliant.
Thank you very much.
When did you become short-sighted?
When I was 16.
You?
When I was 12.
What was maker of your
first pair of glasses?
I don't remember.
Do you have astigmatism too?
Yes.
Would you like me to rub some balm...
on your back?
On the bits you can't reach on you own?
I like that.
Here?
A little lower please.
Yes.
Hello everyone, and good luck.
The room numbers are as follows.
Room 306, the hotel
manager and her partner.
They both have nice voices.
Room 240, couple who both love to ski.
Room 282, couple who both
studied social science.
Name of the yacht Bliss,
couple prone to nose bleed.
You and you take 306.
You and you take 240.
You take 282.
And you two, take the yacht.
Can I go to the yacht?
Ok then, you take the yacht.
And you take 282.
And us three will take the manager room.
We have 40 minutes.
Wake up.
Get up.
Sit down and sit over there.
Put your hands behind your back.
A basketball weights
between 550 and 650 grams.
Did you know that?
No, I didn't know that.
Yes.
The weight is different for
men's and women's game.
That's roughly how much it weights.
Do you know how much volleyball weights?
No, but I like to find out.
Good evening
I have something to tell you.
His nose doesn't really bleed on its own.
He bangs it against the wall or piece
of hard wood, or something like that.
Or he cut it with pen knife
when you're not looking.
You two are not suited.
Shut up.
Dad, tell him to leave, I'm sleepy.
And I'm quite sure that stain
on his T-shirt isn't blood...
but cherry juice or tomato ketchup,
or red water color paint...
or something like that, or beetroot juice.
Do you love her?
With all my heart.
How much do you love her?
On the scale of 1 to 15
14 is a very impressive score.
He love her very much indeed.
Who do you think we should kill?
Who will be able to live
on their own better.
Here is the knife, mom, kill him.
You better get out before you can.
Ok.
That's all I came to said anyway.
You?
If this woman die, do you
think you manage on you own?
Or will you get involve with someone else?
No, I can live alone, she can't
I'm on my own for hours
when she got out the hotel
I like sitting in the room...
relaxes me, calms me
I like it a lot
I can definitely live on my own.
No!
Be quiet.
Take it.
Shoot her.
No.
No, no, no.
Where were you?
I was looking for you
I was masturbating behind
those trees over there.
Why aren't you dancing?
My legs are little sore.
Did you dig your grave.
Not yet
I don't mean to pressure you, or to
ruin the mood, now we're celebrating.
But at some point you have to do it.
Don't expect anyone else to dig your
grave for you or to carry your corpse.
Or throw some dirts over
you, that's about it
tomorrow find a spot you like, well the
ground isn't too rocky to make a start.
Enjoying the rest evening
Thank you.
As soon as his last patient left, I
entered his office and I said to him:
"Honey, the dinner is ready..."
however, I'm not sure I
can eat right now...
one of my front teeth hurts a lot...
"can you take a look, please dear?"
"Yes, sure, no problem", he said.
And the minute he turn his head
I took the drill and I shoved to his chest.
That story sounds really interesting...
but I have to leave
I just remember I left some batteries
next to tree down there...
and the last thing I want is to lose them.
Sorry.
Did you catch rabbits?
No, someone brought them.
Who?
Friend of mine.
Do you want one?
No.
You don't need to accept
rabbits from other people.
If you need more rabbits,
just ask, and I'll bring more.
Catching rabbit is difficult,
but I try to do better.
There is no need for you to
be in debt to the others.
Thank you very much.
The man who brought you
rabbits, is he short-sighted?
I don't know, I don't think so.
Ok.
Is that a sparrow up that tree?
Can't really see that
far, I don't think so.
Are you short-sighted?
No.
You're lying
it's truth.
What does it say here?
YKK
You knew that already.
All zips say the same thing
I'm not short-sighted
I don't understand why
you won't believe me?
I can see you really clearly,
I used to be a pilot.
You wear contact lenses
I don't wear contact lenses,
I'm not short-sighted, I swear.
You're, you think I'm a
idiot and can't tell.
Let me see
I want to see your eyes.
Look up.
Up, up,
Look down now.
Look left.
Look right.
Up again
I'm sorry
I thought you try to fool me
I'm sorry.
For this synchronization exercise,
we have to fully concentrate...
as we both have to press play
at the exactly the same time.
Why don't we just use one headset?
Because that's the whole point.
This is the exercise for us.
We have to be totally synchronize.
Ok
I'm ready
5...
4...
3...
2...
We developed a code that we can
communicate with each other...
even in front of the others without
them knowing what we're saying.
When we turn our heads
to the left, it means...
"I love you more than
anything in the world".
When we turn our heads to
the right, it means...
"Watch out, we're in danger".
We have to be very careful in
the beginning not to mix up.
"I love you more than
anything in the world"...
with "watch out, we're in danger".
When we raise out left arm, it means...
"I want to dance in you arm".
When we make a fist and
put it behind our back.
It means "Let's fuck".
The code grew, and grew
as the time went by.
And within a few weeks, we could
talk about almost anything...
without even opening our mouths.
Stop it.
That's enough, show my
parents some respect.
They're playing you music.
That's ok.
No mother, that's not ok.
Please continue.
Do you want me to play same
piece or something else.
Something else.
Didn't your parents play beautifully?
Yes they did, it's wonderful.
We love each other, and we suit each other.
And that's the reason why we
decide to leave the woods...
and stay together forever in the city
tomorrow, during the hunt,
we're going to disappear...
and everyone would think we been captured.
And then we're going to turn
into dogs or canary something.
I think the first thing I'm going
to do when I get into the city...
is buy a bathrobe.
And then we're going to a pool
with high diving board...
perfect for diving.
And then we do lots of different things
together, serious thing, not silly one...
like go for a walk in the park
or play the guitar together...
It stops there.
There's notes at the back, but
I don't think it's important.
Read the notes.
PORTOFINO: Italy fishing village...
upmarket resort famous for
its picturesque harbour.
POPULATION: 439
BEACHS NEARBY: Paraggi
beach, Camogli, Chiavari...
and Lavagna.
SERIFOS: Greek island located
in the western Cyclades.
Where did you find that?
By the river.
Someone must've dropped it during the hunt.
Give it to me
I'll take care of it.
Can you imagine why I brought
you to such quiet place today?
No.
Because I think it's the
perfect spot for your grave.
Now cover yourself with soit.
Use your hands.
Over your face too.
You wouldn't want your face to
get eaten by dogs, would you?
If you die before me, I'll visit
you as often as I can, I promise
I think we should leave right now.
The three of us coming here...
in stead of two or four is very dangerous.
How didn't we think it early.
Highly likely the doctor will suspect us
I suggest that we leave
the first chance we get.
Right now in the fact.
Don't be afraid.
No one will suspect a thing
I bet you aren't expect the surprise
isn't it wonderful?
Yes it is.
Still I like a few days just
to think it over so that...
I could maybe have the surgery...
when next time come to the city?
What is that to think about?
It's better to see clearly, or
to be short-sighted? Is that it?
That's absurd, you know that.
Anyway, this doctor is the best as is.
And it's very difficult
to get a appointment
I called him months ago to
get him to see you today.
She's blind
Thank you.
Throw down your knife and stand up.
Why did you have to blind me?
You could blind him?
I have no idea what you're talking about.
The drugs are messing with you head.
If I were you, I would try and be a
little braver about the whole thing.
And now get up and give me your knife.
Or I'll hit you and take it by force.
Here I come
I swear I'll kill you.
Let go of my hair.
You're hurting me.
Just think that when someone goes blind.
One of other senses is heightened.
You could also capture a dog in the
woods, and train him to guide you.
Dog can do that, you know?
I'll help you catch a dog myself.
Now calm down, or I'm going
to leave you here...
and I don't think you'll manage to
find meeting of two on your own.
Are you enjoying the view.
Sure.
What happened to your hand?
I was cutting a tree branch with a knife...
and I cut myself by accident.
You look handsome today,
did you get you haircut?
Thank you, no, I didn't get my haircut
I'm going to get my haircut today.
Look what I brought you?
Oh, thank you so much, I'm so
hungry, I'll eat it right away
it's a big flashlight
Oh, I'm sorry.
It's so big, I thought it was a rabbit.
The biggest flashlight I've ever seen.
Are you ready for today.
Of course I am
I want to tell you something,..
But please don't be angry.
Ok, what's wrong?
I can't see anything
I'm blind.
What do you mean?
There is no point to lying to you.
You'll find out soon or later.
Our leader blinded me in the city.
She must've realised I
love you, you love me...
and we're going to run
away to the city together
I'm sorry.
You can't see at all?
No, not at all.
And why you asked for my haircut?
I was just saying that...
so you wouldn't realise I could't see
I'm sorry.
Don't cry, cry will make
our eyes hurt more.
We'll find a way.
What blood type are you?
B
From the first time I saw
her, I knew she was the one.
As she stared in my eyes and smiled.
And her lips were the colour of the roses.
That grew down the river,
all bloody and wild.
Do you like berries? Blue berries?
Black berries?
No, no
Oh.
Can you play the piano?
No.
Plastic cup.
That's right, very good.
Do you speak German?
No
I could teach you German.
It would take a least a year for you be
able to speak the basic not fluently.
So there is no point.
You know, German is one of the most
difficult language in the world to learn.
Because its grammar is very complicated
I brought you something.
Fish.
On the second day, I brought her a flower.
She was more beautiful
than any woman I'd seen.
"And I said," Do you know
where the wild roses grow...
So sweet and scarlet and free?"
Kiwi
That's right, 10 out of 10, then again.
Can I give you a kiss?
I can't thank you enough for all
the activities and games...
to keep me company.
But you know we can't do that anymore.
Would you like to play another
round of touch, guess thing, win.
No, that's enough for today.
In any case, I run out of
things to test you with.
Maybe tomorrow, or one of these days
tomorrow morning?
We'll see.
Bye
Bye.
Good afternoon.
How are you?
Fine
I'm hungry.
You haven't brought me a rabbit for days,..
Or things for me to touch and guess
I've got good news
I had a great idea.
Have you a minute?
What kind of idea?
I raise my left foot
I bring my elbow to my
knee, and tap it twice
I bring my foot to my knee,
and tap it three times.
And I face down, I knee down
I touch my left cheek,
and then lie face up.
You're sure you prepare to do that?
Yes, of course I'm sure
I wouldn't propose otherwise.
When?
Tomorrow.
We should speed up a little
I can't go much faster.
These trousers are too tight, I'm sorry.
It was dark, I couldn't see clearly.
And I didn't have time to try them on
I'm sorry.
Never mind.
There is a bus coming.
It was the hotel coach.
They didn't see us.
Profile.
Fingers.
Elbows.
Would you like me to show you my belly?
No, I remember you belly very well.
Smile.
Can I have a knife and fork please?
Not a butter knife, steak knife.
Second.
Thank you
I'm going to do with the knife.
Do you want me to come with you?
I rather you didn't.
Don't worry.
It's strange at first,
but you get used to it.
And you other senses are heightened.
Touch, for example, and hearing
I know
I won't be long.
Thank you very much
Hope it helped -> bozxphd
www.moviesubtitles.org