HIDDEN AWAY
Hey, you!
Yes, you!
Think I didn't see you?
What's going on?
I'll tell you what's going on.
If I'm not here they
empty out your store.
Give me that!
I'm calling the police.
Don't even move!
But I haven't done anything.
Sure, and how you gonna
pay for this?
With this.
What is it with you?
We're Arabs so we're thieves?
- No, it's not like that...
- No shit it ain't!
Don't be like that,
it's been a misunderstanding.
I do whatever the fuck I want!
Give me that!
You disgust me!
Let's get out of here!
No wonder you got caught.
It's just that...
Don't come to me with excuses.
I don't care, it's just how
you were doing it.
You should learn a few things.
No...
I won't do it again...
Yeah, and you want to be...
an engineer?
You don't even know how to steal.
Go on, eat.
Well, I'm outta here.
Wait for me!
What a creepy party!
Let's put some
alcohol in here...
Let's go in.
- Ibra, they're beating up Sayid!
- Who?
Some brats.
Fuck, let's go!
What's wrong with you, man?
Break it up.
Get out!
What's your problem?
What are you doing defending
the fucking Arabs?
You always have
to start a fight, asshole!
Rafa, where're you going?
But you're coming to
the game tomorrow, right?
Boo!
Asshole!
- You know what?
- What?
Saturday is Rashid's birthday.
Really?
- Yeah.
- Are we gonna have a party?
Jose said that if we behave
he'll let us get in later.
- Where are we going?
- I don't know.
As long as we get
out to party...
Clean up because we'll have
to find you a girl.
- Good night Ibra.
- Good night.
Shit!
So you overslept too?
Nah man, but I wasn't going to
get up
just for two hours of Maths.
What's with this joint, bastard?
You're smoking.
You bitch.
Here, no way you're
beating me today.
Really? You're stoned,
can't even see the buttons.
We begin from below, slowly...
- You're not getting through.
- I'm not? Look.
This is gonna be a goal.
It's gonna be a goal!
You almost
broke my spine, bastard.
Yellow, you're fucked.
What are we doing on Saturday?
Javi didn't tell you?
He got tickets for the new club.
Which one?
The Sound? Cool.
- You know who's going?
- Who?
A girl...
- A friend of yours.
Who?
A really nice girl you know.
You know her really well.
You wanna tell me who's going,
man?
Marta!
- Goal!
- No!
You bastard!
What a goal!
See? You can't beat me!
You're an ass, man.
What are you playing at?
Come in.
This is your home.
Come on.
Give me your rucksack.
Make yourself comfortable.
Who's this?
And what the fuck
do you care? Bigmouth!
Guys... This is Ibra.
Ibra, the guys.
I'm gonna have some water.
Sit down, man.
How long are you staying for?
He'll stay for as long as he
wants!
Like you all!
Get out of my sight!
Bring me some water.
You, get up!
Sit down.
Don't pay any attention.
What are you looking at?
Get outta here!
It's OK.
- What's up?
- Look at them.
What's up?
Where have you been?
- Ask Rafa.
I beat him real bad.
Shut up, it was just a goal.
- What a goal.
- Stop showing off...
and let's see if you do
something
on Saturday's game.
Guess who had an exam
while you were having fun?
- No way!
Yeah, the bitch gave
us a surprise math test.
And this "genius" here
squealed on us and told her...
that we had cheatsheets
and half the class got caught.
What a bastard, man.
They're the bastards, not me.
They all had cheatsheets.
I had
the guts to squeal on them.
We complained so now
it won't count in the course
- You're off the hook then.
- Yeah, we got lucky.
What's up, you?
What are you looking at?
Nothing.
They're hot, don't you think?
Who?
What do you mean, who?
All of them!
Don't worry you little rascal,
Marta is all yours.
Shut up, don't talk bullshit.
No bullshit.
The other day she asked
me for your phone number.
- What are you talking about?
- Yeah.
- And you gave it to her?
- Of course.
So if you don't hit on her
on Saturday, I will.
I saw you checking out Lore
before.
The bitch's freaking hot!
I don't feel like
practicing right now.
But you need it, bastard.
- Me?
- Take a look at this!
- Can you scan that for me?
- Hello.
How come you're so late?
What do you mean so late?
Forget it, go on inside,
you're late.
In Morocco it's an hour
earlier, so...
And in Spain, there's
a lot of superstition...
For example, Ibra,
since you were late...
what kind of superstition
do you have in your country?
In my country?
- Yes.
I don't know.
- Come on, there must be some.
I can't think of any.
- Really?
And what about that
pendant you're wearing?
It seems related
to superstition.
No, it's a friendship charm.
Well, that is also a
form of superstition.
Teacher, how do you
spell "suprestrition?"
It's not "suprestrition."
The coach is an asshole.
If he had to swim all
that he'd kick it.
- You betcha.
- Geez, he made us swim.
Fuck, these keys seem
to be hiding.
Like you with Marta.
Why do you get so nervous
when we talk about that?
It's just...
I'm not in love...
or anything like that, you know?
You're not gonna marry her
or anything.
Look, when I was with Lore,
it's not that I
didn't like her but...
She had great tits.
Yeah, sure, but
at least you knew how to...
Make out?
That's nothing.
You stick in your tongue...
and forget about it.
You could practice
in front of the mirror...
tonight, but really,
it will just flow.
- In front of the mirror?
- Yep, in front of the mirror.
OK.
Gotta go,
they'll kill me if I don't.
- Will you be online later?
- Yeah, sure.
See you later.
Hi cutie! R u going
to the disco 2morrow?
I guess so...
Dinner is ready!
(I'll go... hope 2 c u there!
Kisses ;)
- Don't you hear me? Dinner!
- Fuck, wait a minute!
Rafa, please.
Fuck, mom, you're so annoying...
Yo!
Wait up!
- Wait up!
- What do you want?
I don't know.
I just wanted to apologize.
For what?
For your eye.
It doesn't matter.
And well, I'm sorry
about the game too.
I wish you'd have broken
Javi's nose.
- He's a bigmouth.
- Whatever.
My name's Rafa.
I don't smoke.
Well, I do joints, but very
little.
You should give it a go.
I told you I don't
usually smoke.
Let's see if you can hit it.
- No shit, it's really easy.
- Try.
Who was that at the stands?
My dad.
Yeah, he's like a
fifty-year-old Javi.
He's a dickhead.
Why didn't you leave with him?
Didn't you hear him?
No one can stand him.
And you? Why didn't you
leave with your friends?
I have no friends.
I'm better off alone.
Rafa, it's Guille.
He says you should go now.
Tell him I'm coming.
Look at him. What's up?
And that bike?
What's that?
I didn't want to walk
so I stole the first
thing I found.
Couldn't you
steal anything better?
Man, I didn't go into a store
asking for technical details.
I stole the first thing I saw.
But stealing that, man...
You shut up, dogface!
You don't even have the balls
to steal a lollipop
at the convenience store.
It's a really smooth ride.
You are the faggot who
likes to get it from behind.
So, are you gonna fuck
a girl tonight or what?
Sure I am.
Well, considering how
ugly you are, son of a bitch.
I'm gonna pull it off
as soon as I get there.
You may try,
but you're not getting Lore.
Of course I will. Her pussy
is like this because of me.
What the hell are
you gonna do with Lore?
She'll suck me off.
Sure. I bet you
anything she won't.
I did your mom and
you said I wouldn't.
He's so obsessed with mothers.
Yours drives me crazy.
- Let's go.
- Come on, let's go.
- What about the bike?
- It's yours for ten euros.
But where are we going?
- I told you, to the pharmacy.
- But... What for?
When we go in, do as I told you.
But what do I have to ask?
You just get in and do it.
- But what do I tell them?
- Just do as I told you!
Come on!
- Hello. How may I help you?
- Do you have any Elotinol?
- What?
- Elotinol.
No, it doesn't ring
a bell. Let me see.
No, there's nothing in
here under that name.
Are you sure that's the name?
Yes.
I'm gonna ask...
Who?
Who are you going to ask?
I've made a mistake.
There's work to do!
What do you mean work?
Work, yes, work.
Thanks for ditching me!
You did really well!
I didn't think you
had it in you!
Why?
Do you see all those lazy asses?
None of them got it
right the first time.
You're ready.
- What do you mean I'm ready?
- You'll see.
- Let's go, guys!
- Get the merchandise.
Let's go!
Wait!
What you saw the other day,
stays between you and me.
My brother doesn't like people.
I'm gonna get him outta this
shitty country
as soon as I can.
Where are you gonna take him?
I'm not sure, but
very far away from here.
Come on, let's go.
Those are the highways
out of this misery.
But first, you know
what we gotta do.
Today is really easy going.
It's gonna be a piece of
cake for you.
What?
- Me?
- Of course.
It's really easy.
Come on, stop shivering!
Look.
All clear.
There is your first costumer.
Take this.
And keep your eyes open.
Come on, go!
I'll watch you from here.
Fuck!
You're so clumsy!
It's alright, man.
Give it to me.
You need to do things with care.
See?
Just strength won't do.
There you go.
Just put a thread on it
and you have your charm.
OK guys, pick up the tools
and clean everything up.
And I'll see you
tomorrow at five, alright?
What are you doing
hanging out here?
- Can't we just hang?
- No.
And what are
those sports bags for?
To practice sports, what else?
- Come on, ID.
- We haven't done anything.
You didn't hear me, did you?
We're here for one reason!
We have a game tomorrow.
You're late!
We got stopped by the police.
Get in the pool,
we've already started.
And you know who's
gotta stay to clean up.
- Look who just arrived.
- What?
Look who just arrived.
Look who's there.
Are you gonna fuck her?
See how she's looking at you.
She wants something.
What do you know?
How many have you made out with?
None.
Shut up then!
- Go get her.
- Yeah, he's right.
Don't be a pussy and
get over there.
Come on! Come on!
- Hi.
Come on!
There's quite a crowd here
today.
Yeah.
Come on! Fuck her, Rafa!
Come on!
Look, I just...
I mean...
Look, I gotta go to the bathroom,
I'll be right back.
Alright.
- Man, this is awesome!
- Yeah!
There's loads of girls!
Wait, I gotta go to the
bathroom.
OK.
Come on, let's go.
What's that fucking Arab up to?
What does it matter?
Leave him be.
Of course it matters.
He's all over Lore!
- Never mind.
- Get outta the way!
It's your fault!
Man, what do you want me to do?
She looked at me first!
How do I know she was his girl?
Besides...
whatever we do,
it's always our fault.
If I get my hands on that
motherfucker
I'll smash in his face!
Did the girls get
tired of you already?
Do you smell so bad?
It's Sayd!
Don't go, they'll take you too!
Let go of me!
You're going to hurt them!
They're just kids!
It's not your business!
Come here!
Come on, get up!
Aren't you ashamed?
They're just kids!
Get up!
What were you thinking, Jose?
You know
what happens with the
inspections.
They started hitting them.
And the worst part is that
you end up here.
I tried to defend the kid.
And who defends the ones at
the centre?
They spent the whole night on
their own.
Fasten your seatbelt.
And why did they take Sayd?
I don't know. They must
have alleged reunification.
Reunification my ass!
Sayd doesn't have
anyone in Morocco.
It's just like always, they
find an uncle, grandpa,
someone who'll allegedly
take care of him.
That's all they need.
It's illegal but it's enough.
Will you fasten
your seatbelt, Ibra?
Rafa, you've been like this
the whole week. What's wrong?
Hey, Guille, how nice to see
you.
Come on in.
Guess who's come to see you?
Fuck man, I know I'm not Megan
Fox,
but cheer up a little.
Ignore him, Guille, he's been
like
that since the holidays started.
Take him out to get
some fresh air.
Your mom, she's leaving
me to do the dirty work.
What did you say?
Nothing, just if he
wanted to come to our place.
The girls are coming.
Girls?
- Who are those girls?
- Mom, drop it.
So you picked up a girl?
Yeah, we're leaving.
Come on.
If you want, I can
introduce them to you.
They're really nice girls.
Look, he's on his own.
What are you doing?
Fucking cheater!
Here, take this.
Yo, Rafita, did
your mommy let you go out?
So, what about Marta?
Did you fuck her or what?
Shut up man!
What's with you? Do you suck
his dick or what?
Enough, man!
You wear me out.
Take it easy, kid.
Do you wanna play to relax a
little?
No way.
If you're not gonna play,
go get me some pot
from the Arab.
Seeing you're not
doing anything...
You shouldn't have smoked it
all, idiot.
Don't be a smartass or...
Or what!? Or what!?
What are you gonna do?
I'm gonna punch
this asshole's face in!
Let's go buy some pot
and forget about him.
At least I didn't drop
anything or
I would've cut him up.
- What do you want?
- Pot. You have any?
Wait here.
What do you think about
the fight at the "place?"
- I don't know. You know Javi.
- He's an asshole.
I would've punched him right
there.
He's not worth it.
- How much do you want?
- I don't know, 10 g?
Ibra!
Where were you?
I've been looking for
you the whole week.
Do you know this guy?
Nah, just from
seeing him around.
- You wanna buy or not?
- Relax, man.
- Hey don't touch me!
- Don't what?
Hey, you!
Are your positions clear?
Careful not to lose the ball...
- Ready?
- Come on! Come on!
Look at these idiots, they
must be great swimmers,
they all come on small boats...
Is there a problem?
Fuck! Enough!
Didn't you have
enough yesterday?
- He started it.
- Let's just play.
Shut your trap.
You're an asshole!
Fuck, don't pay any attention.
You should have hit them.
Goal!
Fucking Arab!
Bastard!
That color looks good on your
eye.
You want me to match you the
other one?
Don't let those
shitheads scare you!
You're a dickhead!
Don't you think?
Are you sure your head
is screwed on?
What a goal!
What a goal yours, eh!
Like it wasn't easy,
they had a great goalie.
You take after your father.
You've got a steady hand.
Concentration, that's
the most important thing.
Stop! Stop! Stop!
- Stop, fuck, stop!
- Why?
Nothing, I forgot my cap.
Go in and we'll wait for you.
That's alright, I'll hike.
You're not coming with us?
What for?
We haven't won anything yet.
Come on, go!
You're such a sourpuss.
We'll celebrate without him.
Yo, wait up!
Aren't you coming to the Mac?
Well... I don't
have any dough and...
I could pay...
Well, I gotta help my
mom with some stuff so...
- We could meet tomorrow.
- Whatever.
Hello, good morning.
Do you know if
Ibrahim is around?
Do you know how many Ibrahims
there are
in a centre like this?
He's a boy...
tall... Fifteen or
sixteen years old.
- He's not in.
- Are you sure?
He's not in, are you deaf?
Screw you!
Get inside, I'll be
right with you.
What are you doing here?
Waiting for you.
You don't have any
friends, do you?
What are they doing?
I don't know, some kind
of weird bowling game.
And you don't play?
Nah. Besides you
play in pairs.
And I already told you
I have no friends.
The thing is he's got no balls.
How's your targeting?
I don't know.
Ask your goalie, he should know.
- You coming or what?
- I'm not allowed.
You see any guards?
Come on.
Rafa! Wait!
You got out really fast.
Nah man. As usual.
Yesterday I called your cell a
bunch of times
and you didn't answer.
I told you I had to
help my mom and stuff.
- The whole afternoon?
- Yeah.
Do you have a problem with me?
No, why?
I don't know, you've been
acting weird lately.
I'm just...
tired of always
doing the same stuff.
I see.
The other day Marta asked me
if you wanted to hang out again.
Look, Guille...
I...
well...
I don't like Marta.
Why?
I just don't...
Forget it, man.
Take it easy...
No need to explain.
Thanks.
Doesn't your aunt work
at the bowling alley?
I don't understand why you're
coming.
Because I want to.
What else?
- You don't have any friends.
- What!? Get inside!
- Hello.
If it isn't the tournament's
most sporting player!
- Stop kidding me.
- Introduce your friend to us.
- Elisa, Alicia... Rafa.
- Hello.
You scored the penalty, right?
Relax, man, it's alright.
Did you bring what I asked for?
Yes, here it is.
How long will it take?
Your paperwork?
It shouldn't take longer than
the summer.
Taking into account you've been
in Spain almost three years.
I've been here
longer and you know it.
And you also know that
for them, those don't count.
Here, two copies.
Besides, after what happened
the other day,
I don't know how they'll react.
Did you expect me to
let them take Sayd?
Don't be like that,
it's not my fault.
What happened to Sayd
was a low blow from
the DA's Office.
But you know that they must
notify
by post before they intervene.
- Wait, I don't get it.
- What?
If they're alright here...
Why do they take them back to
their countries where they
don't have anything?
I just don't get it.
Come on, man, you heard Alicia.
Everything's gonna be OK.
Hey, so...
I forgot to ask you something.
How's your targeting?
Come here, bastard!
Good thing you paid
because I'm flat broke.
Eat, you need your strength.
What for?
I remind you,
you're losing, Mr. Precision.
Precision?
Here's precision for you!
Take this.
What for?
Look, they're two pieces.
They have to always be together.
If they ever get separated...
you gotta do whatever it takes
to get them back together.
Or what?
Or nothing, wacko,
it's a metaphor.
- I get off here.
- So...
Do you wanna meet tomorrow
to throw some ball at the pool?
- OK, at five?
- Good.
Bring a pen and a notebook
because
I'm gonna teach you how to play.
Just go home.
Hey, the disappeared one!
Where have you been, bastard?
Around.
I was with Chete the other day,
smoking and stuff...
and he told me you were
with an Arab
at the bowling alley...
really close and shit.
Tell Chete he's a dickhead...
and that I'm fucking
tired of him.
I've been helping my mom
the whole fucking weekend.
You sure you don't like...?
- For sure.
He knows I don't hang with
fucking Arabs.
Ok, if you say so.
We're going to the pool, wanna
come?
Sure.
- Yeah, sure.
- Come on, let's go.
Hello...
have you seen Ibra?
No, I haven't seen him all day.
I was supposed to meet him at
the pool,
but he didn't show up.
I don't know...
Is he looking for Ibra?
- Have you seen him?
- Ibra is not home, he split.
What are you on about?
If you don't believe me
go check for yourself.
His locker is empty.
- What's this?
- Fuck!
- Can we come in?
- Yes.
Come in.
- Hey, Jose.
- Is Alicia in?
Yes, she's in a
meeting in her office.
- Is it gonna take long?
- I think so.
- Well, we'll wait.
- No fucking way!
Alicia, I need your help!
What's going on?
I'm sorry Alicia, I tried
to stop him but...
Gabriel, do you mind
waiting outside, please?
Thank you, and excuse all this.
- They wanna take Ibra.
- What do you mean?
He got this letter last night.
Again?
A reunification?
Ibra doesn't have anyone there!
I know.
Let's calm down.
First things first,
where's Ibra?
Jose?
- He's not here. He left.
- Fuck, Jose!
What the fuck are
night rounds for?
Jose...
call police stations and
hospitals.
Elisa, call the Department of
Interior,
fool them, ask for paperwork,
whatever.
And what do I do?
- You are his friend, right?
- Yes.
Where do you think
he might have gone?
Hey you, stop!
Don't throw it away,
Youssef will kill you!
Rafa, don't go that way!
- Hey, wait up!
- Don't touch me!
What's wrong?
I thought we were friends.
So did I, but friends
don't ditch each other.
I didn't ditch you.
Don't play dumb,
I heard what you told Javi.
I'm sorry.
I didn't know what to say.
- And...
- Leave it!
No man, really...
I'm not like the others.
I care about you.
I'm apologizing, if I didn't
care
I wouldn't be here.
Anyway...
I don't have anywhere to go,
and if Yousef finds me,
he'll kill me.
I know where you can
hide for a few days.
Do you trust me?
Where are you taking that bag?
Practice.
Don't you get a break on that
team?
They're exploiting us.
Ibra?
What are you doing there?
I thought you weren't coming.
What were you doing there, man?
Hiding.
Why?
- In case someone comes.
- I told you nobody would.
- I don't know. What's this?
- Food.
Go on, eat.
- What are you looking at?
- Nothing.
You don't know what
you're in for!
You fucker!
Now what?
Are you going to kiss me?
Fuck, what a scene!
Your asshole must be wider
than your neck.
Apart from being a
loser, he's a pillow biter.
And with a fucking Arab.
This guy could infect you
with anything.
At least do it with someone
of our own species.
Ain't that right, Guille?
Get outta here, I don't
wanna see no faggot shit.
What if I don't wanna leave?
What's gonna happen?
What's gonna happen if
I don't leave,
you fucking moron?
Asshole!
Your friends are a bunch of
retards,
you know that, right?
Guille is my friend.
You could have fooled me!
What's that?
The fair!
- Ibrahim!
- Where is my money?
Ibrahim!
Wait.
I can clean it up at
home if you want.
No one's home,
they're out for dinner.
Come on, don't be stupid,
it's gonna get infected.
Come on, let's go.
My mom got them when I was
four and they're still here.
You're gonna have
to take them off.
Relax, I'm not gonna rape you.
- Does it sting?
- A bit.
Don't worry, that's
because it's healing.
All done.
What's wrong?
They're kicking me out.
That's what's wrong.
That's not sure yet.
And what if it does happen?
Don't get all worked up.
It doesn't have to happen.
Let's go see Alicia.
I'm sure it will be OK.
Are you gonna send
it by courier?
Cash on delivery, of course.
OK.
I'll call you. Bye.
Look who's here!
Ibra, how are you?
- Good.
- Am I glad to see you!
- Are you alright?
- Yes.
Good job, Rafa.
Alicia, I'm gonna
notify the police.
What do you mean the police?
Elisa, we don't need to
call the police.
Don't worry.
Where have you been?
- Around.
- Around?
Don't worry about the letter,
Ibra.
Everything's gonna be alright.
Will you wait for me in the
classroom?
I've gotta finish something,
I'll be right with you.
Look, Alicia...
say what you want, but if we
don't report it,
we're committing a felony.
Don't you realize that
if you call the police,
it's over?
After they take him and before
they extradite him,
we've got time.
That's when we've got to act.
But we can't hide a minor who
received
an extradition warrant.
I'm gonna call.
May I speak with González,
please?
- Rafa?
Do you need anything?
No, I gotta pee and I don't
know where the bathroom is.
- Down the hall on the right.
- OK, thanks.
Yes. Ibrahim has returned.
OK.
That's it.
They're on their way.
And what do we tell the kid now?
Ibra is not here!
- What!?
- He's not here, he split!
Fuck.
- What happened?
- They bought it.
- Really? Don't fuck with me!
- They did!
But how did you do it?
They told me that it was
really late
and that I better go home.
And they believed you
with that face?
Who do you think you are?
And now what?
Where do we go?
I don't know.
But we can't go back
to my friends' place.
I know.
Who is it?
- Hi.
Where have you been?
Around.
Look...
I need a favor.
- Your mom is upstairs.
- What?
And what did you tell her?
Nothing, she just got here.
We need a place
to spend the night.
- And your folks?
- They wouldn't understand.
I have an idea,
but we gotta go now.
- About before...
- Forget it, don't worry.
I don't know if I understand
what you're doing...
but...
I feel bad.
Can I help in any way?
You can tell my mom not to
worry,
that I'm alright.
I don't know, make something up.
It's all I have.
Thanks, man.
We gotta go, man.
Come on.
You wanna sleep indoors or not?
Come on, trust me.
Let's go.
Cut it out, boy!
Hey...
You never told me...
What?
How you got here.
You don't wanna know.
It's fine if you don't
wanna tell me.
No... That's not it.
It's just that remembering...
Forget it.
It doesn't matter.
What was that?
- It's Youssef.
- No way!
- We gotta help him.
- Are you crazy?
He's gonna kill us!
He helped me first, I owe him.
Youssef! Youssef!
- What are you doing here?
- And you?
I don't know whether to kick
your ass or to thank you.
Because of you the police
caught Moha
and discovered the flat!
And what the fuck is
he doing here?
- You can trust him.
- Look at us!
We had to leave with just
the clothes on our backs.
It's almost better this way...
we're leaving right away.
And you should do the same.
If they catch you they'll
kick you out of the country.
I'm fine here.
And how are you gonna do it?
You see that?
It goes to France,
but we gotta hurry, it's about
to leave.
Hey, stop!
The guards!
Come on guys, please!
I just need your help to
get him on there.
Then you can leave if you want.
Please.
Here, take him.
Go, go, it's leaving!
Let's go! Let's go!
Rafa!
Now hand over my brother!
Come on, get in!
Come with me!
He's got his life here,
you don't fit in it!
What are you doing?
Hey... Ibrahim!
Are you stupid?
Why didn't you go?
- Does it sting?
- A bit.
That's because it's healing.