A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release
Stop!
Mister, you got some money for us?
Come on.
Quick.
Quick!
WUJINSHAN (Black Gold Mountain)
Which way to Wujinshan?
You're here.
- Highway 307?
- This is it.
Dahai.
Whose trike is that outside?
I don't know.
No?
Sit down, Dahai.
It's been there two days.
No idea whose it is.
If no one wants it, I'll sell it.
So if the village chief's Audi A6
sat outside his house,
you'd sell that too?
What do you think?
His A6 belongs to everyone in the village.
He sold the state-owned coal mine
so he could afford it.
No wonder the car looks so familiar.
Those shiny wheels are actually mine.
You're smart.
Dahai.
A pity you weren't born earlier.
In the war years,
you'd surely have made general.
Just see what happens.
When I report to Beijing,
the chief and the new boss Jiao
will be hauling sand in prison.
Before you even get to Taiyuan,
the chief's men will catch you.
Why do you think I studied law?
The chief sold off
collectively owned property.
He accepted a bribe.
That'll get him 20 years.
As for your boss Jiao Shengli,
he's rolling in it, right?
I'll accuse him of polluting
and covering up accidents in the mine.
They'll close him down.
Believe it.
If the coal mine had gone to you,
you'd have been no different.
I would have.
Jiao's Maserati is parked in the yard.
Nobody uses it.
Drive it off and sell it.
Then you can buy us all a drink.
I don't want his fucking car.
- Sanming. Got the train ticket?
- Yes.
- Where are you going?
- To see my wife for New Year's.
That's romantic.
The police are here.
Stop eating.
Investigation.
Are all the migrant workers here?
Yes. What's wrong?
A murder in Shibawan.
The migrants have to be checked.
Get them all outside.
Hurry!
Chief.
Village Chief.
When you sold off the coal mine
you promised yearly dividends.
I said that in private.
I don't have time now.
Okay, explain it
to the Discipline Commission.
You've picked
the wrong time for a fight.
You'll be a loser your whole life.
- You won't discuss it?
- You talk too much.
Okay. People from Chongqing.
Over there.
Next.
He's making a run for it!
Damn animal!
What's up, Dahai?
I'm writing to the Discipline Commission
to complain about the chief
and Jiao Shengli.
Miss, a registered letter.
- To whom?
- Beijing. Zhongnanhai. The Commission.
I need the full address.
Zhongnanhai, Beijing.
That's not enough. I need the full address.
What? Everyone knows Zhongnanhai.
That's not enough.
Miss, are you siding
with the village chief?
Does he give you kickbacks?
Or are you Jiao's mistress?
Has he bought you a car?
You're crazy! Go away!
You two must be in league.
There's no justice!
No justice!
No justice.
All aboard! We're leaving, hurry!
Dahai, come on!
What's this for?
Greeting Boss Jiao.
One bag of flour per person.
Boss Jiao has a new private plane.
He's flying back from Hong Kong.
We're a welcoming group.
Everyone gets a bag of flour.
A plane?
Living on this earth isn't enough?
Were you at the coal mine
when the gun was fired?
Yes.
Who was the guy who ran away?
A loader in the coal yard. From Sichuan.
Why did he run? The killings in Shibawan?
He's an escaped prisoner.
Killed someone in his hometown.
He's been hiding here.
He thought they'd come for him.
He panicked and ran.
- Did they catch him?
- Of course.
- What happened in Shibawan?
- Don't you know?
Someone shot three guys yesterday.
Three dead in Shibawan.
- Who did it?
- I don't know.
Early this morning,
a bunch of armed police were in Shibawan.
I see.
Accountant Liu,
are your accounts up to date?
When Boss Jiao got hold of the coal mine
he said 40% of the profits
would go to the village.
How much do the last
14 years' dividends come to?
Listen, back in 2001,
the village committee
signed to sell the coal mine.
Who asked you to sell it?
Was the contract discussed?
We must keep our word.
But Jiao got so rich
he even bought a plane.
He's a hard worker.
Then tell me how much you
and the chief took in bribes.
Stop, please.
Tell me how much you took in bribes.
Open the door.
Devils like you are more evil
than the village chief and Jiao.
- Listen to me -
- Don't talk to me.
Everyone, repeat after me.
Welcome! Welcome!
A warm welcome!
Good.
Here's the plane!
Mr. Jiao, you've reached a new level.
Let's progress together.
Congratulations, ma'am.
Kids, the flowers.
Mr. Jiao, look this way.
A bit closer, please.
- Please say something, sir.
- Later.
How are you, Auntie?
Thanks for coming.
Long time no see.
- Shengli!
- Dahai.
Congratulations.
Thank you, Dahai.
You're a hard man to reach.
There's something I want to discuss.
Can you do me a favor?
Whatever you need, just ask.
Sponsor my journey to Beijing
to file accusations
against you and the village chief.
Sure, come and pick it up later.
Here, in front of all these villagers,
can't you discuss the village economy?
What are you staring at?
Xiao Bai, are you playing golf?
I'm here to compensate you
on behalf of the Shengli Group.
Case closed.
Where's your mother?
- Who are you?
- Don't you remember me?
I'm your uncle from Wujinshan.
Mom went out for food.
She'll be back soon.
Animal.
Where's your dad?
Out hunting “animals.”
On which mountain?
Jiaokou.
Dahai.
You've -
When did you get here?
I've been in town a couple of days.
Let's go inside.
Ganggang. Eat first, then homework.
Of course, Mom.
You're -
Tell me.
A while back,
I introduced you to a woman from Wangcun.
You were well matched.
But you -
Why didn't you date her, as arranged?
You never think about your life.
All you do is make accusations.
Even if your charges stick, you'll grow old.
I'm already old. But I don't care.
Don't be silly.
You're only middle-aged.
The kid's here.
I'm at fault here.
You really are hopeless.
I told you when we were still at school.
There's more to life than getting rich.
You want to be more evil
than Jiao Shengli?
How can you compare me with him?
If not him, then who?
You and he were classmates.
Look what he's made of himself
compared to us here.
You have your own place in Wujinshan.
But my husband and I
don't even have a home of our own.
Enough of this.
If you have time on your hands,
why not open a restaurant?
Or a shop?
To earn money and get married.
Your life belongs to you.
Stop caring what others do.
My dear, wait and see.
I can be more evil
than the village chief or Jiao.
Isn't that Mr. Golf?
- What did you call me?
- Mr. Golf.
Everyone calls you Mr. Golf now.
Didn't you know?
Mr. Golf!
I...
Lin Chong...
unsheathed my sword and, in anger,
slew two of Gao Qiu's henchmen.
Fortunately for me,
Officer Chen gave me a document
which enabled me to come to Mount Liang.
Good morning.
Dahai, good morning.
I want a word with your husband.
Go ahead.
Write.
Write what?
You know how much
the village chief embezzled.
- Write a confession.
- You're being ridiculous.
What are you doing? That's dangerous.
Write it down.
Write!
Write.
Shoot.
Shoot me here.
You're too much of a coward to kill me.
Village Chief. it's Liuliu.
I just started work.
What do you want done?
Okay, don't worry.
I'll do it this afternoon.
Mr. Golf.
- Where's the chief?
- At the temple.
What did you just call me?
Mr. Golf.
Isn't that your foreign name?
Little bastard.
What did you say?
- Dahai.
- Where are you off to?
Fengjie. Going hunting?
Hunting animals.
Stop fooling around.
Calm down.
Let's sit down and talk.
We can sort it out.
Listen, don't be impulsive.
Let's sit down.
Bastard!
Dahai?
How can we fix this?
Just tell me.
Hey.
You got a light?
No.
Motorcycle taxi.
- Where to, buddy?
- The expressway.
Let's go.
Our Mrs. Zhou here
worked hard to raise her children.
Now it's her 70th birthday,
so let's wish her happiness,
good health and a long life.
And now, let's welcome
her second son and his family,
with their birthday greetings.
San'er is here!
The youngest son is back.
You're back.
Brother.
Why are you running off?
Come here.
Mother.
Don't cry.
Where did you come from?
I came by boat.
And before that?
I got your money transfers.
130,000 yuan in all.
That's right.
The most recent one came from Shanxi.
I earned it in Wuhan
and sent it from Shanxi.
I don't want your money.
Your brothers are coming.
Mother's birthday was on the 7th day
of the 11th lunar month.
But we two had to work that day.
We couldn't get home.
Our relatives couldn't get here either.
Since New Year is now
and many people come home,
we decided to celebrate today.
I'll go through it for you both.
For Mother's 70th birthday celebrations
we received gifts of money
totaling 10,270 yuan.
12 tables of guests.
To buy meat, vegetables,
wine and cigarettes,
the total cost
was 6,477 yuan and 33 cents.
I hired a host for 800 yuan.
Taking all expenses into account,
I had to spend 7,485 yuan and 42 cents.
That was the total cost.
What's left is 2,784 yuan and 58 cents.
This money, the way I see it,
should be shared
between us three and Mother.
A quarter each.
I've already divided it
into four equal shares.
- Right, Second Brother?
- Yes.
I don't need a share.
Give mine to Mother.
I bought ten packs of cigarettes.
A good brand.
There are nine left.
So, that makes three each.
As the oldest brother
I have to be impartial.
If you want your share to go to Mother,
give it to her yourself.
People usually worship the gods tomorrow.
I'm worshiping ghosts.
The gods were to blame.
If you have any grievances,
tell heaven about them.
Is Qinqin in Dongguan?
Didn't she come back with you?
She's gone to Zhongshan.
She won't be back.
She tested HIV positive.
AIDS?
Didn't she work in a factory?
Impossible to make a decent living.
Lili has a hair salon in Zhongshan,
so Qinqin went to work there.
She provided “special services.”
That's how she got AIDS.
Bloody...
you slept with her once.
You'd better have a check-up.
Don't talk crap.
Get a check-up, quick. Good luck with it.
What's your wife up to in Tianjin
while you're stuck here?
You should get her checked up.
- Maybe you have HIV.
- What?
You should keep your mouth shut.
You want to die?
Scumbag! Let's settle this right now!
Action? Let's see it, then.
Only 78 minutes to go
till the New Year bell.
Think you can take me?
- Shall we set off a firework?
- Great!
Watch.
Tickets to Guangzhou, 240 yuan.
Wuhan. Anybody for Wuhan?
Want a ticket?
- To Nanning?
- Yes, how many?
Where else?
Yichang.
One each for Guangzhou,
Yichang and Nanning.
Wait for me on the bridge.
I'll bring them.
- Be quick.
- Okay, wait for me.
Ladies and gentlemen...
Chongqing Railway Station reminds you
that during this holiday congestion
it is strictly prohibited
to carry combustible materials
as well as firearms and knives.
Will you go to Guangzhou,
Yichang.
Or Nanning?
You've looked in my bag?
Not sure yet. I'd like to go to Burma.
You can't stay here in the village?
It's boring.
What isn't boring?
Shooting guns isn't boring.
What would you do in Burma?
I'd buy a new fast-loading pistol.
You should buy a cell phone.
Then I could call you.
No way.
Too dangerous.
Can I help you?
Just looking.
Feel free.
- Where's the bathroom?
- Over there.
Can you watch my bag? I'll be right back.
All right.
- Go ahead and start the car.
- Be careful.
Xiaoyan.
- Where are you going?
- To get her immunized.
Time for her shot?
Afraid?
Say no.
- How are things?
- As usual.
Let's have tea sometime.
I'll call you.
Driver, stop here.
Stop.
I can't, till the next rest area.
Stop here.
Traffic jam?
Small delay in Tianmen.
When did you get here?
Just now.
You're frowning.
To get to the station?
I booked a black car.
The driver's waiting.
Driver Wang? it's me.
Car booked for Xiaoyu.
You can come now.
Okay.
Did you tell her?
I started to.
What did you say?
I hinted.
You're delaying again.
She must have understood.
Come to Guangzhou with me.
I've been with you so many years.
Why do I wait?
I accept things the way they are.
But I owe my parents an explanation.
I want a baby.
Let's go to Guangzhou together.
Either you stay with your wife
and we separate,
or you divorce her and we live together.
You have to choose.
Let's go together.
Once you get back to Guangzhou,
I'll give you six months.
We can both think it over,
then make the decision.
Sir, there's a problem with your bag.
Please come to have it checked.
Open the bag.
You can't take this on the train.
- It's a fruit knife.
- It's not permitted.
- Why not?
- Regulations.
What if I eat an apple?
Eat it with the peel.
Give it to me, I'll take it.
Then you can't go.
I'm not going.
Or enter the station.
Forget the knife.
Your ID card?
I'll leave first.
Call me when you get there.
This is your final call for train 934
from Yichang East to Guangzhou East.
Fellow countrymen in Yuanshan village,
come and have a look!
Roll up, roll up!
See the holy snakes. See the beauty.
A marriage is to be.
The holy snakes foretell weal and woe.
Roll up, roll up!
See the holy snakes. See the beauty.
NIGHT-COMER SAUNA
Good evening, sir. Overnight or sauna?
- Are you Xiaoyu?
- Yes.
I'm Zhang Youliang's wife.
Bitch!
Shameless whore! I'll beat you to death!
Did your mother give birth to you
just to seduce my husband?
Number 11, your turn.
Thank you.
- Thank you.
- Don't mention it.
You have been there a long time.
You know the ropes.
If you don't know the ropes here...
you won't earn much.
I'd rather stay here.
When will this airport be finished?
They're working on the runway first.
When that's finished,
most of the workers will leave.
I'll leave too.
Mom...
I saw Dad in Yichang.
I don't want to hear about him.
Incredible! How could this happen?
At 8:38 p.m. yesterday,
the Beijing to Fuzhou train
reached Shangyu, in Wenzhou.
There it' ran in to a stationary train
going from Hangzhou to Fuzhou.
The collision caused the first four carriages
to plunge from the viaduct.
Two carriages from the other train also fell.
The current death toll stands at 35.
Nineteen have been identified.
They include two foreigners.
In all, 210 people were injured.
- Pay the toll.
- What toll?
Transit fee, 10 yuan.
- We work at the airport site.
- You're most liable.
When your trucks pass through our town,
you leave potholes.
From today you have to pay.
- I don't drive the trucks.
- It makes no difference.
You work at the airport?
I'll pay if you give me a receipt.
Receipt?
Receipt.
Take care of this guy.
Stop it, you'll kill him!
Can an animal commit suicide?
For those who think that humans
are the only advanced creatures
on earth -
Xiaoyu, your shift's over.
Did you know animals commit suicide?
So they don't know the saying:
Better to live miserable than die happy.
Animals wouldn't agree.
Good evening, gentlemen.
Sauna or overnight?
Sauna, then give us a room.
Sauna. Two guests for sauna.
Washing clothes?
Yes.
What's your employee number?
I don't have one.
Give me a massage.
Please go to the third floor.
- The masseuses are there.
- I want an untrained person.
Give me a full set. I'll tip you.
Sorry, sir, I'm a receptionist,
not a masseuse.
Receptionist? Then why are you up here?
Sorry.
What do you mean by that?
Nothing.
Don't look down on me.
- You'll be well paid.
- Get out.
Fuck. Stop pretending.
- I'll have you.
- I'm not a masseuse!
Then why are you in a sauna?
- Get out.
- Fuck.
You've had too many pretty boys, eh?
We can afford you.
I'm not a prostitute.
Go home to your wives.
- Now what?
- I'm having you!
- No, you're not!
- I'm not?
- I have money.
- Money can't buy everything!
I have money.
Isn't it good enough?
It's not fucking good enough?
I'll smother you in it!
Not a prostitute?
I'll smother you in money!
Bitch!
I have fucking money!
Fuck!
Fuck you!
Isn't my money good enough?
It's not good enough?
Not a prostitute? Who is, then?
Hello, this is
the 110 emergency call line.
I've killed someone.
Hands off my phone.
Where's the GPS?
You want GPS, buy a fucking BMW.
I'm going to see my buddy in Dongguan.
I don't know the way.
Get a motorcycle taxi and then a train.
A high-speed train?
- Which town in Dongguan is it?
- Humen.
What should I do?
The company rules say:
“No small talk during working hours.”
The accident today was your fault.
Agreed?
The company will pay the medical fees.
You'll pay for the man-hours.
It'll take two weeks for his hand to heal.
For that period your wages will go to him.
You'll work for him.
Ladies and gentlemen,
the next stop will be Dongguan.
Hey, buddy.
He gets my wages while he's off.
So if he's off for 100 days
he gets 100 days' wages from me.
Shit.
That means you work for him.
So I ran away.
Luckily I got paid not long ago
so I'm ahead.
Come and work here.
The factory's recruiting.
Basic pay is 1,200 yuan,
plus meals and a bed.
What do most people get?
About 2,500 yuan.
Training?
One week, without pay.
Anything else going?
You could be a waiter in Changping.
A waiter?
In a nightclub. The johns
are from Hong Kong and Taiwan.
They tip well. But you gotta work nights.
- Is it far?
- Nah. It's another town in Dongguan.
Hello, Mr. Lau.
This guy's from my village.
Please take care of him.
- Your buddy?
- Sure, his name's Xiaohui.
Xiaohui, get in.
Call me if anything comes up.
Nothing will.
- Look after him.
- Sure.
When a guest arrives,
don't call him “sir.”
From now on
he's a “distinguished guest.”
So you say, “Good evening,
distinguished guest. Welcome.”
Now, after me.
Good evening, distinguished guest.
Welcome to The Golden Age.
In Cantonese.
In English.
Show the guest to room 214.
- What are you doing?
- I didn't see anything.
What didn't you see?
I didn't see anything.
It's okay, I'm decent.
New here?
- Name?
- Xiaohui.
- From Hunan?
- How'd you know that?
Easy. I recognize your accent.
I'm from Hunan too.
Come here.
I'm Lianrong.
It means “lotus seed.”
Easy to remember.
Delicious.
We were meant to meet here.
Lots of people are “meant to meet here.”
Give me a hand.
Sir.
I'm in Dongguan.
A painting by Xu Beihong?
Buy it.
Great investment.
Okay, see you in Macao.
We're done.
- Slacking?
- No.
Aren't you slacking?
This room has great Wi-Fi.
Are there many guests?
On and off.
We have a rush around 1:00,
another at 3:00
and another at 5:00.
It's snowing in Shanxi and Inner Mongolia.
It can't be.
Here in Dongguan it's still 75 °F.
Fuck.
At the home of a land-bureau chief
they found
more than 130 Louis Vuitton bags.
Why did he buy so many?
- He's a she.
- A lady needs that many?
As I said, she's a lady.
Let's post a comment.
- What to write?
- WTF.
WTF.
The bags were worth over 2 million yuan.
Anything else?
A mine explosion in Shanxi.
- Dozens dead.
- Post a comment.
- What?
- WTF.
WTF.
What's your handle?
On QQ, I'm Little Bird.
- Is it really little?
- That's going too far.
Just lending a hand.
You're embarrassed.
What's your handle?
I forgot!
They're not dead?
- You have fish?
- I'm going to set them free tomorrow.
Are you a Buddhist?
Yes.
In this line of work,
the Cantonese call us “illicit traders.”
So we need to do lots of good deeds
to be forgiven in our next life.
Do you understand Little Bird?
My handle is Fish Seeks Water.
Welcome. Room 7 is here.
Now for the first lesson
in our Quick Cantonese series.
When you meet the right guy
you'll know what to say in Cantonese.
When two people
are first drawn to each other,
if the boy's bold enough,
he'll say, “I like you.”
There are more girls than boys
in Dongguan,
so ifs quite common for a girl
to approach a boy.
I only know one sentence in Cantonese.
Say it.
I like you very much.
Let's leave Dongguan.
Where will you take me?
As long as you're coming,
anywhere will do.
There's no true love in sex work.
How well do you know me?
I have a daughter.
That day you saw me on the train,
I was going to see her in Guangzhou.
She's three.
I have to raise her.
Leaders' Train Room.
Come in.
I want a conductor, not a nurse.
Won't a nurse be good?
There's your health to consider.
That's enough.
Go look after sick comrades.
- But -
- I'm in excellent health.
Leave now.
Please wait, then.
- Your fruit, distinguished guest.
- Leave it there.
Distinguished guest, may I serve you?
Address me as Chief Leader.
Chief Leader.
That's better. Let's set off.
Where to?
You don't know where we're going?
Wherever you want, we'll go.
Young people nowadays
have no sense of direction.
Any recent innovations?
Come here.
Have fun, buddy.
I have no place to go.
I came here to join you.
Consider it carefully.
Stick with it, no walking out,
or I'd lose face.
I know.
OASIS OF PROSPERITY
- Are you new here?
- I'm a trainee.
Hello. I'm your workshop supervisor.
Welcome to a Fortune 500 company.
Work hard.
Top employees win trips to Taiwan
and visits to our headquarters.
Good luck.
- Where are you from?
- Hunan. And you?
Taiwan.
Hey, Mom.
Didn't I send you money not long ago?
I changed jobs.
We get paid at the end of the month.
I just checked, I'm broke.
Why would I lie?
I'm at the bank now, I just came out.
I don't waste money.
I can't live on nothing.
I'm not a bank robber.
I really don't waste money.
Thought you could skip work?
Chang Ling wants to see you.
- Hu Yunyun?
- Here.
- Your name is Zheng Xiaoyu?
- Yes.
Your ID card?
- You're from Hubei?
- Right.
Are you familiar with our Shengli Group?
From the Internet, I know a bit.
This is Mrs. Jiao.
She currently chairs our company.
Why have you come
all the way to Shanxi for a job?
Do you have relatives here?
No.
You're a bit older
than the other applicants.
What work experience do you have?
I used to work
in a garment factory in Guangzhou.
Guangzhou?
Why did you leave Guangzhou?
I wanted a new environment.
Your name rings a bell.
Is that problem behind you now?
Yes, it is.
In court,
the magistrate changes his mind
He brands me,
Su San, as a murderer
I cannot defend myself
I am forced to confess
My tears flow
Su San! Do you understand your sin?
Do you understand your sin?
A Team Nanban (594mgnav) Release