Leila Hatami
Peyman Moadi
Shahab Hosseini
Sareh Bayat
Sarina Farhadi
Babak Karimi
A. A. Shahbazi
K. Hosseini - Sh.Yazdanbakhsh
And
Merila Zarei
First Assistant Camera: M. Ebrahimian
Gaffer: K. Kalari
Photographer: H. Majidi
First Assistant Director: H. R. Ghorbani
Continuity: M. Naraghi
Make up Designer: M. Mirkiani
Art Director: K. Moghadam
Production Sound Mixer:
M. Sammakbashi
Production Manager: H. Mostafavi
Sound Designer: M. R. Delpak
Sound Editor: R. Narimizadeh
Investor: Pasargad Bank
Executive Producer: N. Eskandarfar
Film Editor: H. Safiyari
Director of Photography: M. Kalari
What you are saying
are not good reasons for a divorce.
- If there is something else let me know.
- Like what?
Like if he is an addict, beats you
or does not give you an allowance.
Nothing like that.
He is a good, decent person.
Then why do you want a divorce?
He won't come with me.
If he does
I'll cancel my request for a divorce.
- Will you come?
- No, I won't.
- Why not, your honour?
- You know why.
No I don't.
Please explain again why.
Let her explain why we should move
abroad in these circumstances.
- You give me one reason to stay.
- I'll give you a thousand.
- Just one.
- My father. I can't leave him.
But you can leave your wife?
- When did I leave you?
- You brought me here.
You filed for a divorce.
When you tell your wife and child
to leave, isn't that leaving them?
Your honour, didn't he just say
leave if you want?
Yes and I'll say it again.
If you don't want to stay
I can't keep you by force.
Keep your voice down.
Calm down.
One day you came to live with me.
Today you don't.
- When you prefer...
- What does "you prefer" mean?
This was something we both started.
Your honour, after 18 months of running
around and expenses, we got our visa.
It has been six months now
and it will expire in 40 days.
Why should we lose this opportunity?
You don't want to lose this opportunity,
then make a suggestion.
You know my situation.
Tell us what to do, your honour.
- His father is his excuse...
- He is not my excuse. He's the reason.
- Let me speak.
- Calm down.
His father has Alzheimer's.
He doesn't even know that he's his son.
- What difference does it make to him?
- Why are you saying that?
Does he even realise you are his son?
I know he is my father.
Your daughter or her future
is not important to you?
Who said anything about our daughter?
Why do you think only you care?
So the children living in this country
don't have a future?
As a mother, I'd rather she didn't
grow up in these circumstances.
What circumstances?
Is she better off here with both her
parents or there without a father?
That's why I want him to come.
I can't leave.
How many times do I have to say it?
He can't come.
So what happens to me?
Nothing. Go back to your life.
If I could
I wouldn't file for a divorce.
Consent has to be mutual.
He just gave his.
Do you agree to a divorce?
If she prefers to leave her family
to go live abroad, yes I do.
He agrees.
What about my daughter?
You have to agree on everything.
How old is your daughter?
11 in two weeks.
She can't leave
without her father's permission.
He won't give permission.
That's between you two.
Please sign here and good day.
Your honour, I came here
for you to solve my problem.
Please sign here.
You too.
- Where should I sign?
- Here.
He can have everything,
I just want my daughter.
Our daughter is attached to me.
She doesn't even want to go with you.
- She doesn't know better.
- Why not?
She is 11 years old.
Please sign here
and don't take the court's time.
- No one knows better except you.
- No, you're the one who knows better.
Your honour, what should I do?
I only have 40 days.
You can't file for a divorce
over every little problem.
A little problem?
My problem is not little.
It is my daughter.
She is his daughter too.
He has rights too.
My finding is that your problem
is a small problem.
Please sign here and good day.
Nader and Simin, A Separation
Producer, Writer, Director
Asghar Farhadi
You said the second floor.
This is the second floor.
Then what's that?
That's the ground floor, that's the first.
This is the second.
The price we gave was for two floors.
But the buyer will pay you.
Only for two floors.
I don't understand what you're saying.
Call the buyer.
This is three floors.
I'll pay for one floor.
Let me pass.
Excuse me, ma'am?
Go tell your dad
they want to leave.
Why don't you tell him?
What did I say?
Didn't we agree?
I'm studying.
Hello.
Hello, ma'am.
I'll be right there.
I don't know how much you know.
The work is taking care of my father.
There is some housework too,
but the main work is giving him
his medication on time,
keeping him away from the stove,
from leaving the house.
Termeh, get your laundry.
You have to be here at 7:30
so I can go to work.
7:30 is too early.
I'll have to leave my house at 5
to get here by then.
Can you make it by 87?
I don't know.
8 is good too.
Ring the upstairs bell.
I'll leave the house keys up here.
- OK?
- Yes.
Can you pay us please?
What's the pay per month?
She'll be right there.
300,000 a month.
That's too little.
No, that's the rate.
Ask around.
The commute is far.
Several bus lines.
It's what I can afford.
If you agree
you can start tomorrow.
Can I let you know tomorrow?
They might need this too.
I don't have change.
You have till the afternoon.
There is someone else I can hire
if you can't come.
OK.
Termeh! Your laundry!
You're not coming?
- Why are you taking your books?
- I want them.
All this for just 2 weeks?
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Which setting does she use?
Should I go ask her?
You want to make me look bad?
- Simin, where're you going?
- I'll be right back.
Just to the corner.
I'll be right back.
I'll come back.
I have an appointment.
Four.
Why four?
Because it has faded.
She must have used it the most.
Four it is.
From now on
we'll set everything on four.
She is really leaving.
She'll be back.
Termeh!
Come stay with your grandfather.
Dad?
Termeh, honey, go to your room.
Dad, get up.
Let go of her hand.
Get up.
I want to take you to the bathroom.
Where are you taking me?
The bathroom
and then to get the paper.
Darling, I said go to your room...
- Where are you taking me?
- Come on.
Don't put your hand there.
I'm taking this CD.
Take whichever you want.
No, just this one.
Bye.
I thought you live there too.
No, I've moved to my mum's.
This is a bit difficult.
No, you can trust him.
Don't worry about these things.
Besides, he won't be around.
He leaves early
and comes back when you leave.
Do bring your daughter.
She'll keep my daughter company
and I'll feel better.
Tell your sister-in-law
your decision.
Where are you going?
What's this?
Oxygen.
What's oxygen?
Get away.
You'll wake him.
I can't hear anything.
What is it doing?
Hello.
Where do you want to go?
- The paper.
- What?
I want the paper.
The paper is in your room.
Come, I'll take you to your room.
I'll take you to your room
and get your meal.
Mummy...
he's peed in his pants.
Sit on the bed.
What's that?
What are you doing here?
Go get your shoes.
You can see the floor's wet.
He'd say when he needed to go...
Take him to the bathroom...
I can't come till 12. I have class.
Call my husband.
Do you have his number?
Write it down.
There's a pen by the phone.
If I bring you some pants
can you change?
Your clothes, can you change them?
Simin?
Can you wash yourself?
Here are your clothes.
Wash yourself and put them on.
I put your towel here.
- OK?
- Yes.
Clean yourself up.
Put your pants in there.
Will you manage?
Your pants.
Take them off.
Wear the ones I gave you.
OK?
Simin...
Hello.
I had a religious question.
I am working in a house.
There is an old man
I am supposed to care for.
I wanted to ask...
Pardon me,
but he has wet his pants.
I wanted to know if I change him,
will it count as a sin?
No one is here.
He's 70 or 80 years old
and he's senile...
The urgency is that the poor guy
has been sitting like this for half an hour.
I can...?
I won't tell dad.
My angel.
Get up.
Open your legs.
OK, now take off your pants.
Card!
Everyone's staring.
Let them.
- How much?
- 37.5.
- Any change?
- He didn't give it.
- You asked?
- It's his tip.
Tip?
Sir, wait one sec.
A tip is for when he pumps the gas.
Go get it.
- Dad!
- Quick!
Wait.
Here.
Keep it.
Really?
Hello.
Hello, Termeh.
- Hello, how are you?
- Fine, thank you.
I'll get my books.
And your test results.
- How are you, Ms Qahraei?
- Fine, thanks, and you?
Fine, thanks.
Sorry we're late.
It's OK.
How's your wife?
- Good, thank you.
- We'll get started.
- Hello, sir.
- Hello.
How are you, Dad?
- Hi, young lady.
- Hello.
Here's the paper.
Did you read the paper for him
or did he read it for you?
Son...
Ali is married.
- Who's Ali?
- Ali.
Yeah, Ali's married.
Termeh, hurry.
His oxygen valve wasn't shut.
He must've opened it.
From tomorrow tighten it a bit more
so he can't open it.
Sorry, but...
I can't come anymore.
Didn't we say every day?
The commute is too much.
I turned someone else away.
It's 4pm.
How can I find someone now
for tomorrow morning?
It's too much work.
Really I can't.
The work is heavy, I can't.
Come to the other room, please.
- Somayeh, where's your scarf?
- It's here.
Maybe you're tired
because it's your first day.
No.
You were here for a few minutes.
You saw.
Somayeh, come get your bag.
Can you please give me that number?
They also do sonograms.
It moved a lot today.
Then it's a boy.
It was kicking in Mummy's tummy.
Because he wants to come out...
To play with me.
Can you write it in here please?
Tell them Qahraei sent you.
They know me.
- Is it a man or a woman?
- A woman.
Call first.
You had to tell me yesterday.
How can I leave him at home
alone tomorrow?
- Where does your mum keep the tea?
- I don't know.
You should've told me
I've to clean him.
Clean him?
He soiled his pants today.
It's not right for me to clean him.
Please pay me for today
so I can go.
He always said
when he had to go.
There are companies you can call
for a male helper.
I can't just let anyone into my home.
Here.
Count it, please.
Sorry, but it's a religious issue.
It's OK.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
Bye.
Goodbye.
Yes?
I wanted to know
if it is OK for me
to give your number to my husband
and tell him I got it out of the paper.
For the housework and your father.
Give him the job description
and if he agrees
tell him to come...
I don't want to tell him
I know you.
I didn't tell him
I was coming here.
Then tell him to call me
or tell him to come here tonight.
It's late for tonight.
I'll come tomorrow.
Just don't give the job to anyone else.
You'll see with him for the money.
That's not a problem.
Tell him to call me.
I will arrange to meet him.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome. Bye.
And thank you.
Mr Lavasani?
Go ahead.
Hello. I am Samadi.
- I called about the job.
- Yes, how are you?
Sorry I'm late.
It's OK.
Where did you work before?
I was a cobbler.
And you're OK with cleaning him?
With what?
Since yesterday
he's been soiling himself.
I'll treat him like my own father.
But you'll be alone with him
and you have to really watch him.
Your wife won't be there?
No, I am single for now.
Excuse me but isn't 300,000
too little for this work?
How much did you have in mind?
Maybe if you could pay 400,000...
I really can't pay that.
I'll come for a few days.
If you like my work,
add something to the 300,000.
- If not don't pay me.
- Here's the address.
I can even start today.
No, there's someone there today.
Start tomorrow and bring an ID.
Like what?
Any legal ID will do.
Pious?
Worshipper.
Barren?
Sandbar.
Desert!
Desert.
Insurrection?
Rebellion.
Doorbell?
- Razieh.
- No!
Her husband.
Yes.
Give the Persian version
of the following words...
- "Maquette"?
- Nemunak.
"Compote"?
Khoshaab.
"Guarantee"?
Tazmin, zemanat
That's Arabic, not Persian.
That's what my teacher said.
Don't give me that.
What's wrong is wrong,
no matter who says what.
- For "guarantee" write...
- She'll deduct points.
That's OK, let her.
Write poshivaneh.
Poshtvaneh.
Hello.
What happened? Your husband
was supposed to come today.
Sorry, he couldn't make it.
What about tomorrow?
I don't know.
If he doesn't, I'll come.
I hope he won't change his mind
everyday.
No, poor guy wanted to come.
Last night, one of his creditors came
with an officer and took him away.
Yes but if something comes up
and he can't make it
I need to know in advance.
No, he will definitely come.
I'll go see the creditor
and beg him
to release him.
Please lock the door behind me.
Goodbye.
Hi.
Don't step on it.
It is dirty.
Go take the garbage out.
Can you?
Yes.
Where will I get you a clean dress?
Take it off!
Mummy...
he's not in his room.
- What?
- He's not in his room.
Go look in the bathroom.
Like that.
Block the ball. OK?
Give me five.
- Grandpa, whose side are you on?
- He's the manager.
Did you see that?
What's wrong?
Sit here.
You OK?
Where've you been?
Poor thing has been waiting
for half an hour.
It's a long commute.
Hello.
Also, take the garbage out
with the bin.
The bags tear and dirty the stairs.
Yesterday I got dizzy.
I dropped the bag and it tore.
I'll mop the stairs.
Go in.
Let us in.
Let me close the door.
- Mrs...
- She's not there?
- What's her kid's name?
- Somayeh.
Don't sit there. It's wet.
Somayeh!
Mrs Khalani!
Knock.
Grandpa!
Mrs Khalani!
Yes.
- Hello, how are you?
- Fine, thanks.
Did you see the lady that works for us?
She was mopping the stairs.
- When?
- Before noon.
- She's not there?
- No. Thanks.
Wait here.
I'll get the keys from the car.
What's wrong?
Dad?
Get his feet.
Dad, get up, look at Termeh.
Dad!
He's breathing.
Don't worry.
Does your arm hurt?
Help me take his shirt off.
Move your arm.
Does it hurt?
Take a step.
Walk.
Let's get the paper, Dad.
Move your leg.
Does it hurt?
Let me see what's happened.
Who did this to you?
I want to see if your legs are OK.
Let me...
Honey, go to your room.
- Has something happened?
- No. Go out.
She's gone, Dad.
Let me see your legs.
Take them off.
Scum!
Honey, did you take money
from the drawer?
No.
OK, go to the kitchen.
I told you to go to the kitchen.
You saw that nothing happened.
Go on... Close the door.
Hello.
Come here.
Mummy, I'm thirsty.
Watch him.
Hello.
Where were you?
Something came up.
I had to go out.
You had no right to go.
- He was asleep.
- So you lock the door and leave?
I was gone briefly.
Briefly? You're lying.
He was dying when I got here!
He always naps at this time so I...
So you do this everyday?
Lock the door and run your errands?
No. I swear to God, today I had to.
- Why did you tie his hand?
- Go wait outside.
Was this our agreement?
I had to go.
I had no choice.
Thanks a lot!
You tie his hand everyday
and go do your own stuff.
Is he OK?
Thanks a lot!
Wait outside, sweetie.
Go check on grandpa.
Why did you go in that room?
Which room?
The one you took the money from.
I took money from that room?
- Don't I pay you?
- I took money?
You didn't take it?
I swear I didn't take any money.
Get out.
Sir, I'm swearing on our martyrs.
You say I took money.
Here, look in my bag.
If I took it, it should be here.
Here, take this.
Give me my bag.
I am swearing on our martyrs
that I didn't go there.
Here's my bag.
What are you doing?
I didn't go there.
I'm swearing on our martyrs
that I didn't step into that room.
- Get out.
- You're saying...
What did I do?
Don't touch me!
I won't touch you.
Get out.
I won't leave
till I get what I deserve!
What you deserve
is for me to kick you out.
Because of her I won't.
Get out! I'm doing you a favour
by throwing you out.
Tell me what's happened to him.
It's my house, I want you out.
Fine but it's not right.
- It displeases God.
- Out!
That's it.
Dad.
Open the door.
It's me. I want to come in...
This is how you watch him?
Open the door.
Go check what's behind you.
Have a look.
Open the door!
It's no use shouting.
This is why I asked you to watch him.
Maybe his leg hurts
and he can't get up.
Grandpa...
Dad, open the door.
Open the door, please.
I'm going to push the door open.
It'll hit you, Dad. Move aside.
Why do you do this to yourself?
Who told you to come in?
- What happened to him?
- Give me the key. Get out!
I didn't steal from you.
You are pissing me off!
I didn't.
- Don't give me that!
- I wouldn't be here now if I had.
Get out.
Pay me for today.
You already took your pay, didn't you?
Since 5:30 this morning
with my daughter... Somayeh!
Sir, wait!
Get out.
I swear I didn't steal.
Get out!
What happened?
Sit.
Mummy, be careful.
Tell her to work with you
on your English.
Bye, Grandpa.
Dad, Termeh said bye.
Careful!
OK.
What is it?
Mum says come in.
Tell her
grandpa's in the car.
She says it's important.
Not divorced yet
and already ignoring us!
I'm busy.
People divorce their wives
to get less busy.
Ma'am, these channels
have too much static.
OK, set the ones you can.
- Come and sit.
- Thank you. Simin...
Hi.
Where's Termeh?
In the car with dad.
Then bring him in too.
No, he is tired.
It's his nap time.
What is it?
Did you have a fight
with that woman?
Did she come see you?
Her sister-in-law called.
Shameless!
What did she do?
Tied the old man to the bed
and locked the door.
Went after her own errands.
If I'd gotten there 10 minutes later
I would've lost him.
Is he OK?
He had fallen off the bed.
I don't know for how long
he was like that.
Where had she gone?
How should I know?
She said you hit her.
I hit her?
- Nonsense.
- Then why is she in the hospital?
Hospital? Why?
You're asking me?
I just pushed her out of the house.
The sister-in-law called
and told me off.
Saying what?
That if she dies,
her blood will be on your hands.
Stuff like that.
- She didn't say what happened?
- I hung up. She started cursing.
That's what you get
for hiring people off the streets.
Don't blame me. I told you
I only know her sister-in-law.
Did she say which hospital?
- Hello.
- Yes?
Hold please.
A woman by the name of Razieh
was brought in tonight.
- What's her family name?
- I don't know. She was admitted earlier.
Why was she brought in?
- They just told us...
- That she was taken to hospital.
I'll call you back. Bye.
Her husband's last name is Samadi.
Razieh Asnaqi?
Is she in her thirties?
She had surgery.
She's in post-op.
Why surgery?
She had a miscarriage.
Is she OK now?
Hello? Hold.
Yes.
Is her family here?
If they are,
they are downstairs.
Thank you.
What did you do to her?
What did I do to her?
Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
Hello, ma'am.
How is she?
Who?
Your wife.
They took her to the ward.
Do you know her?
- I know her.
- My wife.
- They didn't have sandwiches.
- Hello.
Can we see her?
Where do you know her from?
Your sister introduced her to us
for housework.
Thanks a lot!
She was coming
to your house to work?
She came for a few days.
Apparently you couldn't come
so she came in your place.
Come sit and eat something.
You mean
she took care of your father?
Just for a few days.
Two or three days.
Why didn't you tell me this
at the bank?
I thought she would tell you.
Why have you come here now?
To see if we can do something.
Do what?
Help. We were worried.
Did she fall?
Come with me. I'll explain.
I'll explain to you...
Come with me.
I understand your situation.
You kill her child
and now you've come to do what?
I'm really sorry.
I'm sorry
won't be a child to her.
Just tell me one thing.
I'll explain outside.
Wait! Why didn't you tell me that day?
I told you. I thought she...
You live alone in that house.
Let him go.
Calm down.
This is a hospital.
Don't!
Stop!
Why the hell did you come here?
Let me see.
- My own sister?
- I'm sorry.
Forgive me.
Let me see.
Come out here.
I want to talk to you.
Please, I beg you. Hojjat!
Do you want your seat down?
No.
I'll take you home
then I'll get dad and Termeh.
No.
No?
You want to go
to your parents' like this?
It's over.
You're coming home tonight.
I don't want to.
Where are you going?
Hand it in.
Did you hear his complaint?
It was the 13th.
I'm sorry.
I was really upset when I heard.
- I went to the hospital.
- Then you admit it.
Is this the medical examiner's report?
It is the hospital report
that we took
to the medical examiner.
Four and half months, male.
Please explain.
I accept that I was a bit rough.
By rough you mean you pushed her?
No. I tried to get her out of my house.
Be clear.
Your charge is murder.
It was 19 weeks old.
A full human being.
I didn't intend to push her.
I wanted her to leave
so I could close the door.
- You didn't push me?
- Ma'am, please.
If I knew she were pregnant,
I wouldn't even have tried
to get her out of the house.
I just wanted to close the door.
Do you accept his explanation?
He didn't push. He grabbed me here
and threw me and I fell on the stairs.
I didn't throw you.
I wanted to get you out of my house.
Who throws out a pregnant woman?
I didn't know.
Why are you lying?
I found out in the hospital.
Your honour, can't everyone tell
from the body of a woman
that she is pregnant?
Four to five months pregnant.
When would I even see you?
I was already gone or leaving
when she'd come.
When I'd come, she looked like this.
Always with the chador.
How can anyone tell
she was pregnant?
He can claim that he couldn't guess.
I didn't think a pregnant woman
would come for this kind of work.
Your honour, I spoke of my pregnancy
in front of him,
his daughter and her tutor.
They all heard it.
When?
I don't remember.
No, of course you wouldn't remember.
The issue isn't that I knew or not.
Yes.
If it's proven that you knew
the court can request
a prison term of one to three years.
- Well?
- What?
No, I didn't know.
His daughter's tutor can testify.
Can she come in tomorrow?
I don't want her or the school involved.
It's not good for my daughter.
You trash.
You've killed my child.
It's bad for your child?
She matters
but ours was an animal?
Don't insult...
Am I insulting?
He took my pregnant wife...
Quiet or I'll put you in prison.
Please, he's a bit hot-tempered.
Hot-tempered?
I should sue you for working
for a single man we don't even know.
I wanted to help with the bills.
He hasn't worked for months.
The tutor has to come in as a witness.
Call her to come in tomorrow.
Your honour,
I'm here today for one thing.
I lost my child
but it didn't hurt as much
as when he accused me
of being a thief.
We're thieves?
If we stole
we wouldn't come to wipe
your father's arse.
Do you have proof that she stole?
I didn't say she stole.
Money was missing
and it was the same amount
that I pay her.
Is that why you fought?
He accused her of stealing.
Your honour,
my father has Alzheimer's.
She tied his hand to the bed
and left the house.
That day I came home early.
I saw him on the floor
with his hand tied.
I thought he had died.
She came back
and I'm not saying I wasn't angry,
I was.
I told her to leave
and she wouldn't.
Where should I have gone?
He accused me of stealing.
If I hadn't asked for the money and left
he would've thought I had stolen.
Sit down.
- Was your father hurt?
- Yes, he was.
How hurt?
If he had been
he would've filed a complaint.
Yes, he was hurt.
Where are you going?
I'm going to check on my child.
Come back quick.
Close the door.
What's taking so long?
I'm not well.
You go, I'll come.
He says
you locked up his father and left.
What should I say?
Say?
If he complains you'll be charged.
Where's Somayeh?
Over there.
Go.
I'll get her and come.
Let's go.
Yes?
He was sleeping.
I locked the door to keep him in.
Even he would lock the door
and leave me the key.
I saw that he does it so I...
He says you tied him to the bed.
I was afraid he would wake up
and do something to himself.
I was afraid for him.
Why did you leave?
- So you should hit her?
- Quiet!
Who said
you could touch my wife?
Sir, get out.
They don't care about honouir,
I do.
- Don't be offensive.
- Leave the room.
I want to file a complaint
against this woman.
Write your complaint.
Take your father to the medical examiner.
If he's hurt get a report.
What happens to our complaint?
Sign this and leave.
You have to post bail.
What for?
You're charged with murder.
I can't let you leave.
The blood money is forty million.
How am I going to post bail?
I live at my dad's.
He has Alzheimer's.
If you don't you'll go to jail.
My father can't even come here.
He's sick.
Please don't.
I can't go to jail.
I've left him at home to come here.
I can't post bail.
It's not in my hands.
It's the law.
Wait one second.
What should I do with my dad?
I left him at home
and locked the door to come here.
My child will come home from school.
Please.
What are you writing?
Don't waste time.
Go make your call.
I can't go to jail.
I won't go.
Write what you want!
Go get an officer.
What for? Don't.
I'm begging you.
Please don't write it.
My life will be ruined.
Don't waste time.
Go make your call.
Hello, Termeh. I'm stuck here.
They're keeping me tonight.
Don't worry. It's nothing.
But you'll be alone tonight.
Take care of the house.
Take grandpa to the bathroom regularly.
Take care of yourself.
I'll call you tomorrow.
If you hadn't left
dad wouldn't be in jail.
Your dad's not in jail because of me.
He hit a pregnant woman.
She came because you left.
How upset he was that I left.
He knew you weren't really leaving.
Did you tell him?
No, he knew.
Tell me the truth.
You told him?
Get your stuff.
We're going to grandma's.
What about grandpa?
We'll take him too.
I have homework.
I'm not coming.
- You'll be on your own...
- Fine.
You'd better not call.
He doesn't even ask me to stay.
He doesn't refuse to divorce.
After having lived together for 14 years.
Dad!
What are you doing here?
Who're you with?
Didn't you have an exam?
No, it's tomorrow.
Who're you with?
Hello.
Shouldn't you tell us
you're in trouble
SO we can help you?
I didn't want to trouble you.
Silly man.
- Sit.
- No, ma'am, he has a hearing.
Where's grandpa?
He's safe.
What are they saying?
"My child" as if their 18-year old son
was stabbed to death.
Did you speak to them?
You can't even speak to the man.
I told the wife, "You're young.
"You can try next year."
What happened?
- I have to appraise the house.
- OK, go.
Hi.
- I'll be back.
- We'll be here.
Thanks.
- Hi, Mrs Lavasani.
- Hi, how are you?
Good, you?
- Sorry we're troubling you.
- No, what trouble?
Is it true what they're saying?
Yes, unfortunately he pushed her
and she fell and lost her baby.
So what should I tell them?
I don't know what they'll ask.
What if he asks something
to his disadvantage?
I think you should tell the truth.
Please don't stand there.
Where was he?
Mr Lavasani was in the kitchen.
He didn't have a reaction
to your conversation?
If he did I didn't notice.
How did you realise
she was pregnant?
I think she told me.
You asked.
Why should I tell you?
Her daughter was drawing
a man and a woman.
She said
this is my mummy and daddy.
I said your mummy's not that fat.
She said she was pregnant.
So it wasn't from her appearance?
No.
Why are you lying?
You're a woman.
You can't tell if a woman is pregnant?
Even if I could tell
what difference does it make
for Mr Lavasani?
This woman is his daughter's tutor.
They've fixed their story.
Why are you insulting this lady?
No one's talking to you.
When did I have the opportunity
to fix my story?
I was here last night.
One thing is clear.
Now that we are speaking,
that man over there
can hear us, can't he?
I didn't hear you.
My mind is on other things.
Why would I listen to your conversation?
Do I have to swear to God?
Like you believe in God!
No, God is for your type only!
Open that window.
He is an honourable man.
I've been going there for a year
to teach his daughter.
He's not like that.
Why should she hide her pregnancy?
If I knew
I wouldn't have hired her.
Why did you hire her
without her husband's permission?
Thank you.
You may go.
"During the Sassanid period,
people were divided into two classes,
the royalty,
the upper class and the normal people."
The regular class."
What did they ask you?
Whether your dad knew
she was pregnant.
Forgive us for taking your time.
There's nothing to forgive.
Sweetie, how did mummy lose her baby?
She got a tummy ache.
Why?
Did daddy fight with her?
Why should he fight with her?
Maybe because she didn't tell him
she was working in people's homes?
- Did he hit her?
- My mum and dad never fight.
Then why were they fighting
in your drawing that day?
You showed me.
They don't fight anymore.
No?
You're sure?
Yesterday he said
he didn't know she was pregnant.
Now he says he didn't push her.
And you just stand there in silence!
Honestly, didn't you push me?
-I didn't say I...
- Listen...
Don't repeat everything.
How far is the door
from the stairs?
Two metres?
What else can have happened to her?
The corridor in our house...
- Look...
- I am talking!
Don't talk. Just answer.
Quiet!
You've come here to answer.
I've a question for you to answer.
I want to ask him...
Ask me.
If you hadn't done anything wrong,
why'd you come to the hospital
to see what was wrong with her?
I came out of decency.
Where was your decency
when you hit her?
Was anyone there
during the fight?
The neighbours were there.
I'll order questionings.
They're in it too just like the teacher.
He's been insulting me from the start!
Am I lying?
I'll determine who's lying or not.
You be quiet.
Sir, do you realise
his ex-wife has posted his bail?
Oh my God!
Can someone vouch for you?
What do you mean?
A government employee
or business-owner to vouch for you.
- No one.
- Why vouch?
Because she's been accused.
Accused of what?
According to the complaint he filed...
Which he had no right...
She admitted that she tied his father
to the bed and locked him up.
I explained to you why.
Her child just died.
Keep your voice down.
Aren't you ashamed?
You call yourself a man?
I said quiet.
For God's sake, listen to us
for a change.
He is twisting everything.
He beat my wife
and she had a miscarriage.
What could be clearer?
Why are you being unjust?
Listen to us for a change.
If you disturb the peace,
I'll send you to jail for three days.
I've lost everything.
You think I fear jail?
You should fear God.
Mr Izadi, call an officer to arrest him.
Sir, for the sake of the Qoran, don't.
- No, let them come and take me.
- Go out. Be quiet.
Why be quiet?
So they can trample my rights?
Go out.
- Fine, I'm leaving.
- Sir, come out.
Let me get my helmet.
Get out.
I worked for ten years with a cobbler.
They fired me and said
get justice if you can.
I sued and went back and forth
for a year. In the end, nothing.
They said go sit at home.
But this time I won't let it go.
This time it's different.
I have nothing to lose.
The problem is
I can't talk like this guy.
I am hot-tempered.
Don't!
Hojjat?
I don't feel well.
Go sit there.
Let's go!
- What do you want? He's calm.
- I have to take him.
I'm going to talk to the judge.
Stay there and don't move.
Sir...
I beg you...
Please let me speak.
Sir, he's stressed out.
I've been patient for the past two days.
I swear, he's been
in and out of prison the past month.
His creditors put him in prison.
I begged them to let him come out.
I beg you to forgive him.
Sir, look.
Look at these.
Sir, can I ask you
to please forgive him this time?
Sir, everyday he has to take these.
I swear I'm not lying.
Sir, since he was fired,
he's been depressed.
He can't help it.
Sir, you're his elder.
Please forgive him.
Go tell him to find
someone to vouch for you.
God bless you.
Don't leave the building.
No, I'll wait for him
to come back.
Will you ask her?
She'll think
it's because she bailed me out.
So let her...
Dad... please.
OK.
Promise.
Why do you promise?
Dad...
Yes?
You didn't know
Razieh was pregnant?
No.
Why?
Nothing.
So why did you ask?
Last night,
mum said you knew.
Where was she to see
if I knew?
She said when you were told
that Razieh's baby had died,
you didn't say anything.
You didn't ask if she was pregnant.
You didn't get surprised.
At times like this, people usually ask
if she was carrying a child.
It was like you knew.
Your mum wants
to turn you against me.
Will you ask her?
I can't.
Didn't you promise?
I'm sorry.
Which step was she on?
This one.
- This?
- This one.
Take grandpa in.
I'll be right back.
- Are you mad at me?
- No.
You went upstairs?
Yes, I went to see Mrs Kalani.
What for?
I told her they are coming to investigate.
To beware.
Beware of what?
Beware of...
that they are coming to investigate.
Is that not OK?
If she is to tell the truth,
why should she beware?
Termen...
Yes?
Come with me.
- I have homework.
- Leave it for now.
Look, imagine that I am her.
Is this right?
When someone is thrown
they fall straight.
They don't hit here and bounce off
and hit here and then turn
and hit here and fall here.
Right?
If I'd thrown her from there
she should've fallen there on those steps
or she would fall straight on the railing.
She wouldn't fall like this.
Imagine you were thrown.
Follow the direction.
- Then how had she fallen there?
- I don't know.
I'm just saying
she wasn't thrown on these steps.
Come and stand here.
- Why don't you tell them?
- Forget them.
I want you to know.
Go on.
Did he throw you in this direction?
No, towards the lower level.
You look.
This door doesn't allow me to
even if I want to. It's not possible.
Where did you fall down?
- On these stairs.
- Which step?
I think it was this one.
You think
or you're sure?
I'm not sure.
Ma'am, this is where you found her?
I didn't see her fall.
When I got here,
she was on that lower step.
Why don't you say anything?
Go show them how he threw you.
I was so sick
I didn't know what happened to me.
Look, I'll stand in her place.
You in the doorway
and push me as hard as you want.
I'm saying
it's not possible to fall there.
Of course you won't fall.
A pregnant woman falls easily.
Then you come here.
You choose who pushes you.
I'm saying it's not possible.
I'm saying if you push from here,
she won't fall on the stairs.
What stairs? She says
she fell on that step up there.
They all say
they saw her on that one.
Ma'am, did you see her get thrown?
From up there
I couldn't see the door
but I saw the stairs
when she fell.
Can you show me
where you were?
Maybe she got dizzy and fell.
How often did you use these stairs?
Why hadn't she gotten dizzy?
Excuse me.
That morning when I saw her here
I asked her
why there was garbage on the steps.
She said she had gotten dizzy
and dropped the bag.
Right?
- She took the garbage down.
- You told me you got dizzy.
Mrs Kalani, hadn't she mopped
the stairs that day?
The stairs were wet.
Maybe she slipped.
You jerk! You made her slip.
Be respectful!
I'm polite
in front of your family.
You'd better be polite, you shit!
Don't curse.
Take him outside.
Would his neighbours say
anything against him?
If you can prove they're lying...
So you think
they're telling the truth?
To hell with me
for wasting my time here.
Excuse me.
Give us her backpack.
Here it is...
Don't you want your drawing book?
Sweetie, don't be upset
that I am fighting
with your mum and dad...
Let me put it in your bag.
My mummy didn't take your money.
I know.
That's not why I was fighting with her.
Then for what?
I was upset because she left my dad.
She went to the doctor's.
Go on.
Take care.
According to the court's request,
I'll examine him and write what I see.
Well, doctor, you can see
he doesn't talk anymore.
Didn't you say
he has Alzheimer's?
Yes but before this happened,
he would speak a bit.
This is a doctor's office.
Prove that in court.
Does he have any bruising?
Yes, some.
What happened?
I'm not sure the bruising has to do
with when he fell off the bed.
Don't run.
Mum, pull the window down.
They're fighting.
Don't you see this is a girl's school?
I just have one question for this lady.
You're not allowed to stand here.
Take your fight to the police.
I don't want to fight.
I just want to speak to her.
I have nothing to say to you.
I don't know you or her husband.
- Then why did you lie in court?
- What lie?
She knows what lie.
Ms Safaei, call the police.
Don't scare me with the police.
She's not involved.
Then why does she try
to get my daughter to speak?
I did no such thing.
You are a teacher.
Aren't you ashamed?
Why did you ask her
if I hit her mum
and she lost the baby?
I never did.
You pick on a 4-year-old's drawing
and tell her her dad hit her mum
and she lost the baby?
I didn't say that!
Why do you think we beat our wives
and children like animals?
I swear on this Qoran,
we're humans just like you.
I have nothing to lose.
Tell your husband
not to make me do something crazy.
I'll wait by the door.
I'm unemployed.
I'll stand out there all day.
Eventually you'll come out.
Come to the court
and say you lied
or I'll get to the bottom
of what's between you and her husband.
Shame on you.
I've been patient so far.
So why are you defending him?
I told the truth.
- The truth?
- Yes!
Place your hand on this and swear.
Why swear?
What does this have to do with her?
I'm not scared.
What do I have to say?
You said her husband didn't know
my wife was pregnant.
- Yes.
- Swear it.
I swear on this Qoran
that day at their house,
her husband was in the kitchen
and didn't hear what your wife and I said.
OK?
Anything else I should say?
He's crazy.
Call your husband.
Don't go alone.
No, I don't want him to know.
I'm sorry.
Why are you all standing here?
Hello?
Hello, Ms Qahraei.
I had left you a message.
Can you please pick up?
The lady that took care of my dad,
apparently that day you gave her
the number for a gynaecologist.
I wanted to ask you
for that number to call
and see if she went
to see the doctor that week
and what her problem was.
I would appreciate
you calling me back. Thank you.
What do you want to do?
With what?
You want to keep this up?
Everyday a new fight?
Why? What happened?
He went to her school today
and embarrassed her
in front of everyone.
What did he say?
He screamed
"Her dad killed my child."
How can she go back to that school?
Do you know what you are doing?
What I am doing?
He's making threats.
He wouldn't dare!
Termeh, go to your room.
What if he kills your child
on her way to school?
What would you have me do?
Run off abroad with you?
To hell with abroad.
Why can't you talk normally?
This is about Termeh
and the situation you've put her in.
I've put her in?
You have some nerve accusing me!
Who left home?
Who filed for a divorce?
You said
leave whenever you want.
Why did you come back?
I didn't.
I'm here because of her situation.
Her situation's fine.
- You have two choices...
- Don't try to intimidate me.
What intimidation?
Either you clear up the situation...
- No, I know what to do.
- Didn't you hit her?
Didn't she fall?
Didn't her baby die?
Yes! I killed her child.
Why are you so stubborn?
Pay the blood money and end it.
- I won't be forced into paying.
- Why forced?
Put yourself in their place.
- I'm not responsible for their troubles.
- Their child died!
And my dad has been hurt.
He doesn't even speak anymore.
He didn't speak much before.
I was happy
with the few words he spoke.
Is it as bad as losing a baby?
Where were you
to see I caused it?
- Then how did she lose it?
- I don't know.
There might be a chance
that her husband did something
and now she wants to blame me.
Her child said that day
she had gone to the doctor.
Why couldn't she wait two hours
to go to the doctor?
Why did she tie the old man
to his bed and leave?
The examiner said
her child died due to a blow.
How do we know
it was a blow from me?
I won't accept it
till it's been proven to me.
Fine, let me take Termeh.
Shame on you
for putting pressure on me now.
I am worried about her.
Your child wants to live here.
She has to stay here and learn.
Learn what?
Fighting and obstinacy?
To learn not to be a coward like you
who gives in so easily.
He knows who to frighten.
Why doesn't he threaten me?
Yes, I'm a coward.
Your whole life,
instead of solving problems,
you've either run away
or raised your hands and given in.
Just say why you want
to leave this country.
You're afraid to stay.
I was gone one week
and you couldn't manage.
I couldn't manage
and I'm responsible.
Give me Termeh
and you do what you want.
Termeh, sweetie,
you don't have to stay.
Go wherever you like.
You still don't want to come?
"He sells it for twenty a kilo.
"If everyday he sells 270 kilos..."
Write 270.
Then, how much profit
does he make in one day?
How do you solve this?
Did you lie?
What?
About what?
When you said
you didn't know she was pregnant.
Why?
You said that you didn't hear
Ms Qahraei
and Razieh speaking.
Yes.
Then how did you know
that Ms Qahraei gave her the number?
Didn't she say it at the same time?
OK.
If we want to calculate the profit...
Yes, I knew.
Your mum was telling the truth.
When they were talking in the hall,
I heard everything
from the kitchen.
Then why did you say
you didn't?
Do you know what would happen
if I said I knew?
One to three years in prison.
I only thought
of what would happen to you...
who you'd stay with.
I said I didn't know.
If you knew, why did you hit her?
I knew she was pregnant
but at that moment I didn't.
I had forgotten it.
I wasn't paying attention.
So tell them this.
The law doesn't care about this.
Either I knew or I didn't...
Look at me.
If you want me to
I'll tell them.
Hi.
Didn't I say
not to come to the front?
Ms Qahraei!
What are you doing?
Ms Qahraei, wait...
If you pull over
I'll just explain something to you.
Please let me...
Dad!
Who's responsible
for my child's safety now?
Without a witness there's no case.
So without a witness
I should wait for him to kill her
and then come to you?
How should I know
you are telling the truth?
Why should I lie?
Bring my daughter and father here
just to lie?
Is she here now?
Yes, outside.
Ask her yourself.
I'm afraid to leave her at school.
I'm afraid to leave my dad at home.
Is the plaintiff here?
Did you finish writing?
Almost.
You didn't know
his wife was pregnant?
No, I didn't.
When she was speaking to the tutor,
you didn't hear them?
No, I didn't.
You didn't, huh?
What I'm saying is...
The tutor came
and revoked her testimony.
She says you knew.
- She said I knew?
- Yes, she came yesterday.
He threatened her...
Answer me.
Did you hear her or not?
I said no.
How did you know
about the doctor's number?
My daughter told me.
What did she tell you?
That she got the number
from her teacher.
Go tell her to come in.
Now?
And wait outside.
What question?
What does he want to ask?
I don't know.
Give me that.
So what do you have to say?
You haven't asked me anything.
Didn't your dad tell you
what I want to ask you?
No.
What grade are you in school?
Sixth.
The day your tutor came to your house
and asked the lady
about her pregnancy,
were you there?
Not then, I had gone to get my books.
Then how did you know
she got the doctor's number
from your tutor?
She gave her the number later,
when she was leaving.
In front of you?
Yes.
Why didn't you tell
your dad sooner?
What?
That she got the doctor's number
from your tutor.
I didn't think it was important
for my dad to know.
And did you tell your dad
or did he hear it?
That she gave the number?
I told him.
You told him?
Yes.
OK.
What crime did I commit?
Nothing. You're right.
He's not accepting his responsibility.
I admit that he's to blame
but in the end what will happen?
One or two years in court
for a payment plan of the blood money.
But why?
That's what upsets me.
Why do you think
it's for the money?
When did I say such a thing?
You think I am a bum
and my kid died
and I don't understand anything.
I never said anything like that.
Let's see what she's saying.
There's no other way.
Your child won't come back.
My husband won't get hanged.
Her husband didn't do it on purpose.
They're good people
for giving you a solution.
Take the money and settle it.
You can use it in your situation.
Right now we'll decide on an amount
and I'll get my husband's approval.
Now we have to get his approval?
For God's sake leave us alone.
You act like you don't need the money.
Take a look at yourself.
Don't let him go.
Wait a second.
I want to talk to you.
Will you stay?
Mum...
Let me speak to him.
Come sit.
I want to talk to you.
I can hear you.
I went and spoke to her husband today.
Sit down.
I managed
to get him to agree
to take fifteen million
instead of forty million.
Three five-million checks
in exchange for his consent.
How dare you speak to him
about money?
I can't handle the stress
of my child's safety.
You don't get it.
Just now when you were late,
I was worried sick.
Why are you interfering?
I didn't come here to fight.
Oh God,
why can't I make her understand?
Didn't you say it was my fault,
that I introduced her,
that if I hadn't left,
none of this would've happened?
So let me fix it then.
If I pay, it means
I have accepted it was my fault.
But he has consented.
He won't let us be.
- He won't, anyway.
- Why should I bribe him?
Think of it
as my dower money.
If I had to
I would beg and borrow
to get your dower money.
But I don't have the money
to pay for extortion.
Our child is going through adolescence.
She is suffering.
So you understand
the sensitivity of her adolescence.
If she was suffering
she wouldn't have stayed.
Why do you think she stayed?
Did she choose you?
To keep us from separating.
She knows I won't go anywhere
without her.
She is suffering
but she doesn't show it.
Call them now and say
I won't pay
until it's been proved to me
that I am responsible.
I'll sell my car.
Don't sell it for my sake.
It's not for you.
If your child is not worth...
Why are you talking nonsense?
Money's not the issue.
I won't rest till my child's safety
is guaranteed.
You don't have the right
to do anything.
Understand?
If I had done nothing
you would be in prison.
Come to court
and get back the bail.
I don't want to be out
because of it.
Get up, Termeh.
Get up, let's go.
Get up, I tell you.
Mum, please.
I don't want you to stay here.
No, Mum, I won't let you.
Is fifteen million more important
than your child's life?
I won't let you do this.
If your child is not important...
Mum, please listen,
why are you doing this?
You said you would stay.
I was stupid!
Mum, please...
I'll wait in the car.
Go there for a few days
till your exams are finished.
Your grandparents are there.
You'll have more fun.
Didn't you say
it's not serious?
It got serious.
Termen...
Honey...
If you cry I'll cry too.
Why won't you pay them
so she'll come back?
This has nothing to do
with her coming back.
It does.
She had come to stay.
Her stuff was in the car,
I saw it.
If you think I am guilty
go get your mum.
We'll call them and go pay them.
I have doubts.
Didn't he throw you?
Yes.
Did something happen at home?
No. Even before,
my child wasn't moving.
Before he threw you?
You mean
your child had already died?
I don't know. Maybe.
Had something happened?
I'm not sure but...
the night before, I had pain.
- Have you ever lost a baby before?
- No.
I was hit by a car.
You father-in-law
had gone into the street.
I went after him.
He was crossing the street
to come back.
I ran to stop him
but I got hit instead.
The pain started that night.
Does your husband know this?
Why don't you come say this
in court?
My husband will kill me
if he finds out I told you this.
Since yesterday
when he promised his creditors,
he's been waiting.
What do we have to do
with all this?
It's my fault.
Yesterday when he said
you've promised him this money,
I got really scared.
I called a few people.
They say if I have doubts
then it's a sin to take it.
If we don't pay
my husband's innocence must be proved.
I made you swear
not to repeat any of this!
But your husband
won't leave us alone.
I fear for my child.
I'm afraid
that if I take this money
something will happen to my child.
What do you want me to do?
Don't pay this money.
Don't.
Will your husband leave us alone?
Give me that.
Bring some plates.
Don't worry.
Nothing will happen.
When you revoke your complaint,
we'll give you these three checks.
God bless you.
Hojjat, get a pen and paper
so we can write everything down
and sign it.
I want to say something first...
Say a prayer and finish it.
I have already agreed
and will honour my word.
I just want his wife
and my daughter to be here
when I speak.
Where is she?
Thank you.
Please, also call my daughter.
Come in. Your father wants you.
Termeh, come and sit here.
Excuse me, sir.
Look...
I wrote the checks
and [I'll give them to you.
There's no problem.
I need to ask a favour.
Ma'am, you are a devout person.
Swear on the Qoran
that I caused your miscarriage.
Bring a Qoran.
Go get it.
Come quickly
or they'll suspect something.
His creditors are here for the money.
You'll ruin our reputation.
I won't swear.
Didn't you say you went to get his father
and a car hit you?
Why aren't you coming?
She's afraid to swear.
Why?
[... I have doubts.
Oh God...
Azam, go sit with them.
Why are you saying this now?
I swear I told Azam.
Tell me exactly what happened.
The day before, a car hit me.
And that night I had a lot of pain.
- Let's go, it'll be my sin.
- No.
It's a sin. I asked.
What sin? He's consented.
Let's go.
I am scared we'll be punished.
More punished than this?
Look at my situation.
Have mercy on me.
On our child.
I'm afraid of something happening
to our child.
Let's go.
I can't.
Don't hit yourself!
Why did you come here tonight?
Didn't I tell you not to come?
Didn't I say
we don't want your money?
How will I live in this house?
Why did you do this to me?
Come on.
Let's go.
Hello. Come in.
So what's your decision?
Your parents have left it up to you
to decide who you want to live with.
With your father or your mother?
Have you decided?
Yes.
- Have you?
- Yes.
Have you decided or not?
Yes.
And what is it?
Do I have to say it now?
- If you haven't decided...
- Yes, I have.
- If you haven't decided yet...
- I have.
And?
Would you prefer them
to wait outside?
Can they?
Sir, wait outside for a minute.
You too, ma'am.