I've lived here maybe 23 years.
But I feel afraid to call it home.
There's always the feeling
I'll have to leave.
I fought with my dad.
So I packed my bag
and left for Mumbai.
My brother had a job at the dockyard.
His place smelled so bad,
the first night I couldn't sleep.
I was pregnant,
but I didn't tell anyone.
Because I'd recently
found a job at a house.
I had to take care of a lady's kids,
but they were pests.
But the lady... she fed me well.
That year I ate like a queen.
Every family in the village
has at least one person in Mumbai.
In Mumbai,
there is work and money!
Why would anyone
want to move back?
I'd just had my heart broken.
But the city helps you
forget these things.
I didn't realise
how much time had passed.
The city takes time away from you.
That's life.
You better get used to impermanence.
Breathe in.
Breathe out.
Nurse Prabha tells me
<font color="#FFFFFF"you've been making trouble.
What's the matter?
Tell Doctor why you hid
<font color="#FFFFFF"your medication under your pillow?
I will not take it.
Why?
What happened?
She told me
<font color="#FFFFFF"the pills are giving her bad dreams.
I'll give you
<font color="#FFFFFF"a prescription for that.
OK?
Please, Doctor.
I don't want to stay here.
Please let me go home.
- What is it?
<font color="#FFFFFF"- He comes here.
After dinner,
when I'm watching TV.
Who comes?
Jairam, my husband.
He came yesterday as well.
I was watching TV.
Mr. Bachchan was on.
His voice always makes me feel good.
He talks so smoothly.
And then suddenly,
<font color="#FFFFFF"out of nowhere,
there was
<font color="#FFFFFF"that dirty smell of tobacco.
Then I looked up,
and he was sitting there
<font color="#FFFFFF"on that stool.
No.
Not sitting.
He had no legs!
He was only a torso!
Can we please pick a film already?
If it's just another action film,
<font color="#FFFFFF"I'm not coming.
You're a wuss
<font color="#FFFFFF"who only likes romances.
And the new release?
The one with Shane Nigam!
He's so dreamy.
Nurse Prabha,
want to come with us?
Yeah, Nurse Prabha,
<font color="#FFFFFF"you pick the film!
No, you girls go ahead.
Why? Come with us, please!
I told you, she never comes.
I explained your situation
<font color="#FFFFFF"to Dr. Supriya.
Her friend agreed
<font color="#FFFFFF"to take up your case.
He's a big-shot lawyer.
He'll do it for free.
I don't need any help.
Why are you being so stubborn?
Last night the builders
<font color="#FFFFFF"sent a goon over
to threaten me!
He said: "Buzz off
<font color="#FFFFFF"before Ganpati festival or else."
It's too dangerous.
Parvaty,
<font color="#FFFFFF"stay with me for a few days.
Why should I?
Why should I leave my place?
I told him:
"Threaten me all you want,
<font color="#FFFFFF"I won't leave my place!
"Over my dead body!"
I told them like that.
Let's speak to the lawyer.
It can't go on like this.
And the younger one?
How old is he?
1 year old.
So you have 3 children?
Yes.
How old are you?
24.
No! 25.
Yes. 25, definitely.
Nurse?
The girls told me there's a prize?
A prize for... you know?
Vasectomy?
If your husband agrees,
the government will give you a bucket
<font color="#FFFFFF"and 1,000 rupees.
I told my husband, but...
He says it makes them
<font color="#FFFFFF"lose their strength!
Take this every day.
If you want another kid
<font color="#FFFFFF"just stop it for a month.
Oh, no way!
How much for this?
When did you last get your period?
Hey... what u doing?
Boss is driving me mad.
IMA bored...
Wanna C U...
You'll have to wait
until tonight to see me.
But for now...
I'm sending you kisses
through the clouds.
So when it rains,
my kisses will touch your lips.
But oil won't make
<font color="#FFFFFF"my hair grow back any faster!
I like it short.
It's the new style.
Next month I can't come home.
<font color="#FFFFFF"I can't get leave.
Alright, Mama.
<font color="#FFFFFF"I'm going in for surgery.
Of course surgeries
<font color="#FFFFFF"happen at night!
As if a patient's heart will wait!
Dr. Supriya is calling, Mama!
<font color="#FFFFFF"I have to go. Bye.
Prabha?
I'm leaving.
Will you be long?
Go ahead.
<font color="#FFFFFF"I'll see you at home.
Open your mouth.
More.
Are you hiding them
<font color="#FFFFFF"under your tongue?
Good.
Nurse Prabha?
Working late again?
Sorry, Doctor.
<font color="#FFFFFF"I lost track of time.
It's OK.
Hindi is so frustrating.
The word kal means both
<font color="#FFFFFF"yesterday and tomorrow!
Don't make excuses,
<font color="#FFFFFF"how will you improve without hard work?
I wanted to ask a patient
to come back tomorrow in Hindi
but when the time came,
<font color="#FFFFFF"I couldn't say it.
You have to say it like this:
kal wapas ana<font color="#FFFFFF".
kal wapas ana
Again?
You make it sound so simple.
Good evening, Nurse Prabha.
OK then, I'm going.
Nurse?
I have something to show you.
Don't look.
<font color="#FFFFFF"Open it when you get home.
It's a poem.
A poem?
There's a poetry competition
<font color="#FFFFFF"in our monthly journal.
I thought I'd give it a shot.
I didn't know you were a poet.
Nothing like that.
<font color="#FFFFFF"It's just a hobby.
Alright. See you tomorrow.
Who's this?
How did you get out?
You're all wet!
Lost your umbrella again?
It was so windy,
it broke.
You left so early.
<font color="#FFFFFF"What happened?
Nothing happened.
One of my cousins
<font color="#FFFFFF"is visiting Mumbai.
So I just went shopping with her.
A cousin?
Just a cousin.
Sweetie!
Your tummy has become so big.
How many babies
<font color="#FFFFFF"are you hiding inside?
She was loitering
<font color="#FFFFFF"outside Kulkarni's flat.
What was she doing there?
What were you doing, sweetie?
I've asked Dr. Manoj
<font color="#FFFFFF"to have a look at her.
We shouldn't bother him
<font color="#FFFFFF"with such things.
He won't mind.
He's a nice guy.
Isn't he?
Prabha?
Can you cover my rent this month?
The same situation again?
I promise I'll pay you back.
You need to watch
<font color="#FFFFFF"your spending, Anu.
My salary is never enough.
That's why.
OK, but it's the last time.
Don't ask again.
Sorry.
What are you doing, Anu?
<font color="#FFFFFF"Move aside.
This parcel arrived for you.
Thank you.
What is it?
Is it from your mom?
I don't know.
Prabha, it's for you!
Who's it from?
It doesn't say.
Let's open and see.
Awesome!
We had a rice cooker at home,
but nothing like this!
This one looks so international!
Whatever we make will taste super.
But who could've sent it?
Doesn't say.
It's written in English letters.
But it's some other language.
Made in...
Germany.
Doesn't your husband live there?
My dreams are made of
everyday things,
small and scattered,
that I've left behind.
My hope
is just another casket of things
I carry with me wherever I go.
And now,
you are there
in a neighbour's house
like a burning lamp
whose glow I watch
to keep me warm at night.
C U at the same time.
Don't wait 2 close to hospital.
Someone might see you.
See you soon
Have you noticed
any changes in your new roommate?
All the nurses are talking about her.
She's in love with a boy.
That can't be.
She's not like that.
You know, he's Muslim.
Everyone here knows.
I don't have a problem with it.
But she's your roommate,
you better keep an eye on her.
I just thought you should know.
What is this?
Sims' vaginal speculum.
Good.
What about...
this?
Artery forceps.
Artery forceps, correct.
Nurse Anu will show you
placenta from
<font color="#FFFFFF"today morning's delivery.
And I'll demonstrate
<font color="#FFFFFF"our placenta disposal procedure.
Pass it on.
Still bothered by the smell?
You're all nurses,
you have to be stronger.
Listen...
I've been dying to tell you
<font color="#FFFFFF"what happened today.
You know Crystal, right?
The new nurse.
She was giving an old man
<font color="#FFFFFF"a sponge bath...
when suddenly,
she let out a scream!
Why?
She looked down and...
his 'thing' was standing all the way up!
She'd never seen one standing before!
She ran out of the room.
And then?
Then Prabha came in and scolded him,
he got so scared...
I don't think
it'll ever stand up again!
Boss sent me
<font color="#FFFFFF"to pick up his watch.
Mr. Aslam?
Two minutes.
Don't they look great on me?
Anu?
Have you seen many?
Many what?
What Nurse Crystal saw
<font color="#FFFFFF"at the hospital today.
What's up with you?
<font color="#FFFFFF"Are you jealous?
No, I'm just asking.
Why are you acting like a virgin?
Mister?
Your watch.
Your watch is ready.
The balance is 5,000 rupees.
Shobhna said if we pay off the guard,
<font color="#FFFFFF"he won't bother us.
Are you sure?
Don't be such a wuss.
Let's go see.
There's nobody here.
When did he last phone you?
It's been over a year.
Maybe longer...
Nurse?
When people go abroad,
they can lose their minds,
or their memory.
That's how it is.
What will you do now?
I'll tell you what, call him.
- Me, call him?
<font color="#FFFFFF"- Yeah.
If I meet that husband of yours,
I swear,
I'm gonna box his ears.
It's a real shame.
It says here the builder
<font color="#FFFFFF"is suing you for trespassing.
They could begin demolition
<font color="#FFFFFF"any day now.
Are other tenants
<font color="#FFFFFF"in the same situation?
The ones with papers
<font color="#FFFFFF"have been given new flats.
When the cotton mills shut down,
my husband was allowed to stay on.
Then you must have papers!
He never told me
<font color="#FFFFFF"about any papers.
Now that he's dead,
<font color="#FFFFFF"I can't ask him, can I?
Isn't there another solution?
Look Parvati,
the problem is
<font color="#FFFFFF"you don't really have a case.
Because there is no proof
<font color="#FFFFFF"that you have lived there.
But can't you just ask my neighbours?
I've lived there 22 years,
what do I need papers for?
That won't hold up in court.
There, we need papers.
Can't you find any document
<font color="#FFFFFF"with your name on it?
That bastard!
I will kick his ass!
I'll show him.
Who does he think he is?
How dare those builders
<font color="#FFFFFF"cut off my electricity!
It's so damn dark!
These are just old medical reports.
How is your son doing?
It's been a long time.
You had gotten him chocolates too.
Those, he gobbled up.
You used to be so terrified
<font color="#FFFFFF"of the Head Nurse.
That terror, Nurse Lissy.
Don't remind me.
Why not move in with your son?
No, no.
He already lives in a tiny room
<font color="#FFFFFF"with his wife and kid.
I don't want anyone
<font color="#FFFFFF"breathing down my neck.
We're the same, you and I.
We're better off alone.
Evening is my favourite time of day.
In my village,
<font color="#FFFFFF"this was the time
to stop playing football
<font color="#FFFFFF"and go home.
But here,
it feels like
<font color="#FFFFFF"the day has just begun.
I wanted to be an airhostess.
I secretly signed up for the exam.
But I got scared of Dad
<font color="#FFFFFF"and didn't go.
At least this way,
<font color="#FFFFFF"I got to meet you.
Who knows,
<font color="#FFFFFF"we could have met on a flight.
You seem different somehow.
How so?
I sense some change.
What's the matter?
Nothing.
Okay.
Who are you avoiding?
Mother.
Why not answer?
I know exactly why she's calling.
This guy looks like an eggplant.
What about him?
"I have a 50-acre
<font color="#FFFFFF"cardamom plantation in Munnar.
"Two houseboats in Alappuzha.
"I go pigeon hunting
<font color="#FFFFFF"in my free time."
"I'm the right-hand man
<font color="#FFFFFF"of the Sheikh in Dubai.
"All I ask for is 1,001 gold coins.
"and one Mercedes Benz."
"That's not possible.
"But we can offer 50 gold coins
<font color="#FFFFFF"and one Swift car."
"Marry your daughter for so cheap?
<font color="#FFFFFF"Never!"
Anu,
if I used a Hindu name
<font color="#FFFFFF"for a fake matrimony profile,
would your father send it to you?
Even if he did, I'd turn it down.
You sure are hard to please.
I keep thinking he'll come back.
And he'll say that
<font color="#FFFFFF"he wants to live with me,
and be with me.
Hold its legs.
Ready?
One...
two...
three...
Four heartbeats, wow!
She doesn't bite.
Don't be afraid.
- Go ahead and pet her.
<font color="#FFFFFF"- No!
- Touch her, your fear will vanish.
<font color="#FFFFFF"- No.
People who are afraid of cats
were mice in a past life.
- Just touch her.
<font color="#FFFFFF"- No, no.
If we're done, let's go.
Should I take her home?
What was that back there?
What did I do?
Why were you flirting with Dr. Manoj?
You can't do that.
If you behave like a slut,
people won't respect you.
You know what people
<font color="#FFFFFF"are saying about you?
Let it go.
I have something
<font color="#FFFFFF"that will cheer you up.
Nothing can cheer me up.
Fine.
Then I won't tell you.
Tell me!
- Please tell me, Shiaz.
<font color="#FFFFFF"- Never mind.
Come on!
OK, I'll tell you.
Do you have a burqa?
Why would I have a burqa?
Without a burqa, there's no plan.
What plan?
Aunty and Uncle are going
<font color="#FFFFFF"to a wedding tomorrow.
Goodness!
<font color="#FFFFFF"No need to scrunch up your face.
So nobody will be home?
You know my neighbourhood, right?
If anybody sees you like this,
we're screwed.
Anu?
Aren't you hungry?
I've prepared
<font color="#FFFFFF"your favourite fish curry.
It's chilli fish curry.
I'm not hungry.
Anu, I'm...
sorry.
I didn't mean what I said.
I don't know why
<font color="#FFFFFF"I spoke to you like that.
Prabha?
Did you know him from before?
Who?
Your husband.
No. Not at all.
One day,
<font color="#FFFFFF"Father asked me to come back home.
When I got there,
<font color="#FFFFFF"they'd already fixed my marriage.
Didn't you try to
<font color="#FFFFFF"find out more about him?
I did. I tried to meet him.
It must have been romantic.
Not at all!
He had just a few days of leave.
When we tried to talk,
<font color="#FFFFFF"there were always relatives around.
How could you marry a total stranger?
I don't think I could.
You might think you know someone,
but they can also become strangers.
Soon after the wedding,
<font color="#FFFFFF"he left for Germany.
In the early days,
he used to call.
But gradually,
<font color="#FFFFFF"the conversations grew less frequent.
I don't know what happened.
Maybe...
there was nothing left to say.
I think of him
in this faraway country.
I think of him working
<font color="#FFFFFF"alone in this large factory.
It all seems...
so far away.
Nurse?
There's something I have to tell you.
I'm moving back to my village.
What?
There's nothing more I can do,
<font color="#FFFFFF"is there?
What are you saying?
We can do more.
I'm fed up.
I spoke to a guy in the village.
- He'll find me a job.
<font color="#FFFFFF"- Where?
In a hostel.
As a cook.
At least in the village
<font color="#FFFFFF"I have my own home.
But how will you manage?
I'll figure it out.
You see that tower there?
It's the same builders.
They think that by building
<font color="#FFFFFF"their towers taller and taller,
one day they can replace God.
On my way.
<font color="#FFFFFF"Are you home?
Crazy rain here...
I feel like a spy in a movie.
Have you left yet?
Don't come now...
The wedding is cancelled.
Harbour Line is flooded.
<font color="#FFFFFF"Don't b mad :(
Sorry baby.
Attention all passengers,
due to water logging,
all trains are delayed.
Stand by for further updates.
Hello?
Hello, Mama?
How are you feeling?
No, nothing's wrong.
I'm just calling.
Yes, I've eaten.
We built their buildings!
We cleaned their gutters,
<font color="#FFFFFF"cooked their food,
and did all the work
<font color="#FFFFFF"they refused to do themselves.
But when we ask for a home
<font color="#FFFFFF"near theirs, they can't stand it.
We have to unite,
and make them understand
that ours are the hands
<font color="#FFFFFF"that built this city!
- Workers' unity!
<font color="#FFFFFF"- Long live!
All these years
<font color="#FFFFFF"I walked past this place,
but I've never eaten here.
Today I've done it.
I'm going to miss this place.
But it's like this place isn't real.
What do you mean?
You only seem to be real
<font color="#FFFFFF"if you have papers.
You could just vanish into thin air,
and no one would even know.
We would know, Parvaty.
All of us at the hospital,
<font color="#FFFFFF"we'll miss you.
You're a very good lady, Nurse.
I'm gonna do it!
Run, run!
Nurse Prabha!
When did your shift end?
I didn't see you around.
Nurse, I'm off.
Nurse, I made some sweets for you.
Here.
Don't have them now!
I won't be able to face you
<font color="#FFFFFF"if they're awful.
My contract here is ending soon,
and I'm thinking of not renewing it.
You'll be leaving us then?
So what's your plan now?
Can we go somewhere to talk?
Mumbai is nice....
But I never got used to it.
And I have a problem
<font color="#FFFFFF"with the language too.
Hindi isn't hard to learn.
Maybe.
But it's not just that.
I've been here
<font color="#FFFFFF"for so many months now,
but yesterday
<font color="#FFFFFF"I forgot to get off at my stop.
I went all the way
<font color="#FFFFFF"to the end of the line...
by mistake.
Prabha?
I'm...
Before I go I wanted to...
tell you...
I wanted to know...
if I should stay?
I mean...
If there was a reason
<font color="#FFFFFF"for me to stay here...
But Doctor, I'm married.
I know...
But still...
May I go, Doctor?
I'll miss my train.
Some people call this
the city of dreams,
but I don't.
I think it's the city of illusions.
There's an unspoken code
in this city:
even if you live in the gutter,
you're allowed to feel no anger.
People call this,
"The Spirit of Mumbai."
You have to believe the illusion,
or else you'll go mad.
Parvaty, there's no electricity here?
She made us carry her junk
<font color="#FFFFFF"all this way.
Is she planning on
<font color="#FFFFFF"doing operations here?
Parvaty?
Is this still good?
Perfectly good!
Prabha, have a sip.
Close your eyes and gulp it down.
It will make you feel relaxed!
Trust me.
Just try it and see.
How is it?
Your turn!
Drink!
Where on earth have I landed myself!
Stuck in this weird place,
how did I get here?
Should I cry or should I laugh?
Will someone save me?
How much for the mackerel?
50 rupees.
Is it dried?
No, these are fresh!
Of course they're fresh!
Give me a good price.
- How much?
<font color="#FFFFFF"- 100 rupees.
What?
Who are you trying to fool?
Just look at the size of these fish!
Prabha?
Could you ever move back
<font color="#FFFFFF"to your village?
I don't think I could.
I didn't think
<font color="#FFFFFF"you'd come today, Anu.
It was a big help to Parvaty.
I didn't mind.
I like her.
Prabha?
I have something to tell you.
My parents are sending me photos of guys
<font color="#FFFFFF"for marriage proposals.
But I don't want to get married now.
Have you tried talking to them?
As if they would listen!
So what will you do?
I don't know.
Maybe run away.
It's no use, Anu.
You can't escape your fate.
I'm very tired.
I want to rest.
Are you sure?
Aren't you coming with us?
No, Prabha. I want to rest.
Let her be.
<font color="#FFFFFF"She did carry those heavy bags.
Not everyone can hold their liquor.
Prabha!
Come in!
I should get back now.
Will you be long?
Not long.
Save some for later.
Parvaty?
How long will you be gone?
I only need to tell them
I'm here for the job.
I'll be back by 5 o'clock.
Then I think we should leave now.
What nonsense!
- You have a ticket for tomorrow.
<font color="#FFFFFF"- Yes, but...
You came all this way,
<font color="#FFFFFF"of course you should stay!
How did you find this place?
It's like she's been
<font color="#FFFFFF"stuck here forever.
As if she's waiting
<font color="#FFFFFF"for something to happen.
She looks like you!
I like this place.
Seems like another world.
Shiaz?
Do you ever think about the future?
What do you mean?
I mean...
In 10 or 15 years...
what will your life be like?
Am I there with you?
What's come over you?
I don't know.
I never used to think about
<font color="#FFFFFF"stuff like this.
But I feel like
the future is here
<font color="#FFFFFF"and I'm not prepared for it.
Why don't my parents understand
<font color="#FFFFFF"what I want?
Maybe we can talk to them?
We can try to convince them,
<font color="#FFFFFF"maybe they'll agree.
If I tell them,
<font color="#FFFFFF"they'll never let me see you again.
Shiaz,
I feel so scared.
I've been scared
<font color="#FFFFFF"ever since I met you.
I'd ask myself if it was right,
<font color="#FFFFFF"my being with you.
Or if it would've been best
<font color="#FFFFFF"for us to stay apart.
But when I'm with you,
I don't know what it is...
I don't feel afraid at all.
As if this is
<font color="#FFFFFF"the most natural way for us to be.
It all gets too heavy
<font color="#FFFFFF"for me sometimes.
Shiaz?
There's graffiti here in Malayalam.
OUR LOVE
<font color="#FFFFFF"IS LIKE THE ENDLESS SEA
You wrote it, didn't you?
Somebody help!
He's not breathing.
Looks like it's too late.
Pump his stomach!
Flip him over.
Make him sit up.
Step back please!
Move aside! Move aside!
He's dead, no?
He's not one of ours.
He's a goner.
He needs to go to the hospital.
There's no hospital here.
But there's a village doctor.
OK, quickly.
She saved his life.
He was totally dead.
Miss?
He should see a familiar face
<font color="#FFFFFF"when he wakes up.
Come inside.
Some tea?
Don't be shy.
Doctor will be here soon.
Go inside.
Sorry.
I was only cleaning your wound.
It hurts.
It hurts now, but you'll be alright.
What happened to me?
Don't worry.
Just rest.
I feel like I've been resting
<font color="#FFFFFF"for a long time.
How long has it been?
A few hours, maybe.
I don't remember anything.
It's windy.
He'll catch a cold.
<font color="#FFFFFF"Cover him nicely, dear.
What does he do?
There's some kind of
<font color="#FFFFFF"misunderstanding.
Where does your husband work?
He works in Germany.
Then you must not
<font color="#FFFFFF"see each other often.
Pity your holiday got ruined.
Lucky that you were
<font color="#FFFFFF"there for him today.
What did she say?
Nothing.
She thought you were my husband.
Am I?
No.
Why is there sand on me?
They found you in the sea.
In the sea?
What was I doing there?
You don't remember?
You've changed so much
<font color="#FFFFFF"in all these years.
Have I?
Some days I was stuck
<font color="#FFFFFF"in the factory for so long,
I didn't know if it
<font color="#FFFFFF"was day or night.
I would come out
<font color="#FFFFFF"after 3 or 4 days
as if in a daze.
I was blinded by the light.
In the darkness,
<font color="#FFFFFF"you try to imagine light.
But you cannot.
I thought about you.
What did you think about?
Sitting next to you like this.
I wanted to reach out and touch you,
Why haven't you told me this before?
Prabha,
come with me.
It will be different this time.
I promise.
Stop.
I don't want to see you...
ever again.
Are you closing up?
No. You can sit as long as you like.
Sand...
Where is that boy?
Who?
The boy who was with you.
Prabha,
I'm...
sorry.
It's alright.
Just call him.
Who's that?
Anu's boyfriend.
He followed her all this way?
This is Shiaz.
Where are you from?
Vithura.
Sit down.
I was there once.
It's very beautiful there.
It's very beautiful here too.