Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT
NORTHERN GERMANY
SPRING 1917
THIRD YEAR OF WAR
♪ Girl, I love you, I do ♪
♪ But I can't yet marry you ♪
♪ Wait another year
Then it will come… ♪
♪ Have a cup of tea
Sugar and coffee ♪
♪ And a glass of wine
And a glass of wine ♪
♪ Girl, I do love you, I do ♪
♪ But I can't yet marry you ♪
♪ Wait another year
Then it will come true ♪
LA MALMAISON, NORTHERN FRANCE
25 KM TO THE WESTERN FRONT
Show yourself!
18 MONTHS LATER
SUPREME ARMY COMMAND
7 NOVEMBER, 1918
CHAMPAGNE, FRANCE
OCCUPIED TERRITORY
Hey! Dirty Kraut!
Hey! Hello!
Come here!
Fresh baguette!
For you!
Liverwurst, love!
Lots of love!
Oh, my.
You are very beautiful, my love.
Goodbye!
Goodbye, my friends!
Hello, madam.
I'm Kropp.
And you?
Do you want to…
Do you want to come with me?
Not a problem.
COMPIÈGNE, FRANCE
8 NOVEMBER, 1918
Weygand,
what do these gentlemen want?
I don't know.
If you please,
we would like to know the conditions--
We are asking for an armistice.
You have 72 hours
to accept our conditions.
Sign then.
Retreat! Retreat!
So sorry.
I am so sorry. I am so sorry.
DUVAL, GÉRARD
TYPOGRAPHER
Your wife…
I promise… I promise…
I promise…
THE KAISER HAS ABDICATED
Henri.
Taste it.
Were they made today?
I'm sorry, sir. I don't think so.
I'm listening.
This is a disease
of the defeated, not of the victorious.
I don't fear it.
I reject any compromise.
Fair?
You speak of fairness?
Sign it.
Very good.
The war is over.
Look.
It's really good.
Want some?
Piece of garbage…
Stop!
Thief!
Asshole!
God damn!
We'll kill them, these sons of bitches.
It belonged to Lefèvre.
Poor bastard, he saved it for the end.
-He won't need it anymore.
-Thank you, sir.
Here's to you and to Lefèvre.
Well, it's good.
The nightmare is over.
Enemy attack! Enemy attack!
-In position!
- In position!
Fire!
Charge!
Cease fire!
It is 11:00 a.m.!
A light!
Bring me a light! A light please!
Shortly after the start of hostilities
in October 1914,
the Western Front
froze into positional warfare.
By the end of the war in November 1918,
the front line had barely moved.
More than three million soldiers
died here,
often while fighting to gain
only a few hundred meters of ground.
Almost 17 million people
lost their lives in the First World War.
ALL QUIET ON THE WESTERN FRONT