Hi.
Hi. I'm Ani.
No?
You waiting for someone else?
All right. Are you sure?
Okay.
Hello!
- Hi! How are you?
- Hello.
- Hi. I'm Ani.
- Pleased to meet you.
- Very nice to meet you.
- Yes.
- How you doing?
- I'm doing well.
- Yeah?
- Thank you. Oh, quite lovely.
You can sit right there, okay?
Okay.
Do you still talk to your family?
Do they know you do this?
Mm-hmm.
- They do? They're okay with it?
- Yeah.
I'd be okay.
Does your family know
you're here?
- I hope not.
- Yeah?
- Hi. I'm Ani.
- Nice to meet you, Ani.
- Nice to meet you.
- I'm Ricky.
- Ricky?
- Yeah.
Hi. Nice to meet you.
I'll just sit right next to you right here.
- Oh, yeah.
- Very cozy, right?
Pretty serious.
- Yeah.
- A lot of work, but, you know...
- ...that's why I'm here.
- You're a hard worker?
Chill out and come here,
you know?
Yeah, well, we could go
chill out in a private room.
All right, lucky number six.
That's my number.
Thank you. Oh.
Yeah.
- Ani?
- Yeah.
When Robert was here
the other night,
did he ask you for a dance?
Yeah.
And you danced with him?
Okay.
- Okay.
Bitch.
- Yeah!
- Whoo!
He was really weird.
Super weird.
- Like, serial killer weird?
- Like, he would rub...
Yeah, like, he was like
Indian Jeffrey Dahmer,
- and he kept, like, rubbing my leg...
- Oh, no.
...in a circle like that.
What is that?
Is that a butterfly?
- Yeah, it's a butterfly.
- You're so classy.
I know.
I got dollar signs
like a real ho.
No, but you're manifesting
with those.
He said I looked like
his 18-year-old daughter.
And then he bought
five dances from me.
That's fucking disgusting.
Well, at least
he bought the dances.
Yeah.
- You can touch me. It's okay.
- Yeah?
I'll build you a belt.
Yeah, make me a belt.
A money belt?
You don't have cash?
Let's go to the ATM.
You want to go
to the ATM right now?
- Well, I can't spend too much.
- Yeah, okay.
- Let's go to the ATM.
- Great.
Let's go get you some cash.
Seriously, he came out
of the bathroom one time,
and he didn't zip up
his fucking pants.
It's like, if you can't zip up
your fucking pants
after you take a piss,
I don't trust you
with the music.
Dude, he's 40.
He's literally geriatric.
- No, I know. It's like...
- Ani.
I got a kid who wants someone
who speaks Russian.
You know, Jimmy, the girls
and I have been talking,
and if your cousin doesn't
start showing us some respect...
- ...we're not gonna tip out anymore.
- All right. I'll talk to him.
Who are you talking about,
the DJ?
- All right, seriously?
- He's an asshole.
I shared my playlist with him,
and he was very rude
and dismissive.
You're killing me.
Let's go. Come on.
No. No, I'm eating my food.
That's why you have Tupperware.
To keep things fresh.
- She's eating.
- He's a spender.
- Come on. Let's go.
- Come on. What the fuck.
Time is money, baby.
Get a roll on it.
Without pants, without nothing.
And then some...
- Hey, guys.
- Then... One second, bro.
Guys...
- Hello! This is the beautiful Ani.
- Wow.
She's gonna take care of
everything you need tonight.
Ani, make me proud.
Yeah. I'm... Yeah.
(in Russian): You are beautiful.
(in English): Um, I'm, uh, uh,
Ivan, and...
(in Russian): But you can
call me Vanya.
- (in English): Vanya. Okay.
- Yeah.
Nice to meet you, Vanya.
(in Russian): And this is
my best friend...
(in English): Uh, fucking
best friend, Tom.
- Hi. I'm Ani.
- What's up?
You're not bad. Uh, and, uh...
(in Russian): I heard
you speak Russian, right?
(in English): Mm. No, I don't
speak Russian,
but I know Russian.
(in Russian): What do you mean?
(in English): I can speak Russian.
I just prefer not to,
but you can go ahead
and speak Russian.
I'll understand.
Uh, I not understand.
What the fuck?
Um...
- Okay.
- Yeah.
(in Russian): Hello, Ivan.
(speaks Russian)
(in Russian): My name is Ani.
This is how I speak Russian.
Do you still want me
to speak Russian?
Fuck yeah!
(in English): No, it's...
My Russian is terrible.
I can't even roll my R's.
No, no, you-you are not bad, really.
You are not bad in Russian.
Your Russian is great, great.
- Really? Okay.
- Yeah.
Well, I disagree,
but thank you.
Yeah. And, uh,
how do you know Russian?
My grandmother never
learned English, so...
Ah. Uh-huh.
- Yeah.
- But enough about me.
You two are from Russia?
Yeah, I'm from Russia,
uh, but he lives here.
Yeah.
Mm.
Oh, so you're on vacation or...
Mm, yeah, vacation.
I guess you can say that. Yeah.
But I'm speaking, uh...
(in Russian): May I switch to Russian?
- (in English): Yeah? Yeah.
- Oh, yeah. Whatever you want.
Yeah, because my English
sounds terrible.
- At all, yeah.
- No, no, no.
- Your English is really good.
- Yeah.
(in Russian): And that's why
I think we should toast
to our fucking bad accents
with a bottle.
(in English): Yeah. And you want
to go to VIP, maybe?
Yeah, excellent. I want.
Oh.
(in Russian): You work
in a cool place.
(in English): Yeah, it's a cool place.
And the room I'm bringing
you to is really nice.
Mm-hmm.
- Wow. Mm.
- Right in there.
- Mm.
- You're very good, really.
And one more. Yeah.
Thank you.
Where are you going?
No, I'm not going anywhere.
Can you sit on your hands
for me?
- What?
- Sit on your hands.
- Hands under your legs.
- Like...
Mm-hmm.
(in Russian): This is not allowed.
But I like you.
(in English): God bless America.
(in Russian): Here's to having a
hard dick and lots of money.
Um...
I want to ask.
Do you work outside the club?
(in English): Give me your phone.
Yo.
Yo. Yo. Did you pick up milk?
Do you see milk in the fridge?
No.
Then I didn't pick up
the fucking milk.
Wonderful.
Thank you.
Hi. Uh, I'm here
for Mr. Zakharov.
- Ivan?
- Yeah. Mm-hmm.
Hi. Hello. What's up?
- Uh...
- Hi.
Come in. Come in, please.
Mm, so welcome
to my humble abode.
- Hugs.
- Oh, yes.
Hugs.
I can help you.
- Mm.
- Oh. Thank you.
Ooh, you-you look beautiful.
- Awesome.
- Aw. Thank you.
(in Russian): Want something to
drink?
(in English): Uh, yeah,
I'll-I'll take a water.
- Water? Are you sure?
- Mm-hmm.
You can take everything
you want.
Vodka, tequila, whiskey,
whiskey cola.
Coca-Cola, maybe?
No, a water's good.
- Yeah, thank you.
- Uh-huh.
Suit yourself, Ani.
Uh, sparkling or flat water?
Um, either is good.
Oh...
(in Russian): Where's the
fucking water?
Wow.
(in English): Not too shabby.
What is "shabby"?
Oh, I'm-I'm just playing.
I meant,
your home is-is beautiful.
My home is okay, girl.
Um, sparkling.
Thank you.
Bedroom's upstairs.
Let's go.
Okay.
Oh, sorry.
I am waiting for you.
Oh.
I'll hurry up.
They didn't make my bed yet.
(in Russian): Fuck.
Is it so difficult?
Sorry.
(in English): Whoa.
Nice view.
My view's better.
Okay.
So, what are you looking for?
Um, sex.
Yeah, I know.
I mean, like, anything special?
Yeah, special sex.
- Special sex.
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So, like, a little bit
of everything?
A little bit of...
(in Russian): Yes! Sounds
fucking amazing!
(in English): You want to take
your clothes off?
Yeah.
Wow. Okay.
- You want to put this on?
- Hmm?
Or do you want me
to put it on for you?
- Faster.
- Mm-hmm.
Faster, faster.
- Faster. Faster. Faster.
- Mm-hmm.
- Stop. Stop. Stop.
- Okay.
- So you want me to stop?
- Stop, stop, stop!
- I said...
- Okay.
Want you?
Oh, uh, sure.
S-S-S-Sure.
But be careful
with that shit, yeah?
Careful.
And that's for you.
Tip.
- Thank you.
- Yeah.
That's very generous of you.
And I want to say
one more thing.
Yes.
It was really amazing.
Oh, oh, oh.
I love these guys.
You know them?
No.
Oh. You must know them.
So, um, how old are you?
Twenty-one.
How old are you?
Mm, older than you.
(in Russian): How old are you? 25?
(in English): No, I'm-I'm 23.
Oh, wow.
(in Russian): You act like
you are 25.
(in English): Okay.
You're funny.
Yeah, I know.
So, funny? Why?
I don't know.
You're just... you're, like...
You're funny. It's...
Funny cool, right?
- Yeah, of course.
- Yeah.
Really funny cool.
And if you don't
mind me asking,
like, what do you do
to get all of this?
What do you think I do?
Well, what do you think
I think you do?
Oh, fucking English.
Mm. Okay. I can say,
but it's, uh...
it's really big secret.
Okay.
I'm really big drug dealer.
Oh, really?
Why you trust...?
No.
But I'm really big gun dealer.
Mm. Okay.
Come on.
Oh, my God.
Wait, so, like, you made
some app or something?
- Is that...
- Yeah. Yeah. I-I made.
(in Russian): I do have
some cool ideas for apps...
(in English): No, but no, no.
I... No.
Okay.
My father... (speaks Russian)
Yeah?
(in Russian): Long story short...
my dad is Nikolai Zakharov.
(in English): Whoa.
Sorry, I don't know who that is.
Google him.
- Google?
- Yeah.
Um... wait,
what's his name again?
Nikolai Zakharov.
I-I can spell it for you.
N-I-K-O-lai...
No, I-I got it.
- Yeah?
- Thank you.
Yeah, let me see.
"Children."
Yeah. Vanya Zakharov.
It's me.
Oh, shit.
"Oh, shit."
No. No way.
- Yes fucking way.
- Bro.
And I'm seeing him again
tonight, so...
Crazy.
I guess he had fun
or something.
Yeah, we all know
what fun you are, babe.
Uh, you want to mind
your fucking business?
You're making it
our fucking business.
- Calm down, Diamond.
- Chatty bitch.
Gross.
Ginger cunt.
Yeah.
Oh!
Oh.
(in Russian): This is genius.
(in English): Come on, come on,
come on, come on.
Oh, that was crazy.
(in Russian): Little bonus
because you're the best.
(in English): Okay.
(in Russian): Let's go!
By the way,
I'm having a party.
(in English): New Year's party.
(in Russian): And you have to
come.
(in English): It's going to be
banging.
I might have to work
that night.
Oh, no.
You might not work that night.
(in Russian): Fuck.
(in English): Can I bring
someone?
No.
Uh, if it is a boy, no.
I don't want a sausage party.
(in Russian): Fuck.
(in English): No, she's not.
Okay. See you here.
(in Russian): Why don't you
shoot?
(in English): What?
You know, you paid for an hour,
and there's still
like 45 minutes left,
if you want to go again.
No fucking way.
Yes fucking way.
- I fucking told you.
- Girl.
- Right? I know.
- Girl!
And it's fucking insane inside.
- There's an elevator.
- Oh, my God.
- Fucking elevator.
- Wait.
- Never seen anything like it.
- Are my tits off?
No, your tits look amazing.
- Okay.
- They look perfect.
- Wait, are my tits off?
- No.
- Bro.
I know. I told you.
Didn't I tell you?
- Girl.
- It's crazy,
and upstairs is
even more beautiful.
Yo, yo, yo. What's up? Hi.
- Hi.
- Yeah.
Oh.
Oh, uh, Lulu, this is Ivan.
- (speaks Russian)
- Yes, uh, this is Lulu.
(in Russian): Very nice
to meet you.
(in English): Uh, I am so
excited that you are here,
and let's go drink.
- Yes? Yeah, go, go, go, go, go.
- Yeah.
- Want to get some drinks?
- Hell yeah.
(exclaims in Russian)
Are you ready?
And, Ani, your mouth here.
From the titty.
(in Russian): That's the escort
that's fucking Ivan.
- No way!
- I'm telling you!
- She's pretty good, yeah?
- Totally!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Get down.
This is not jungle gym.
Seventeen! Sixteen! Fifteen!
- Yeah!
- Fourteen! Thirteen!
Twelve! Eleven! Ten!
Nine! Eight! Seven! Six!
Five! Four! Three!
Two! One!
Ani, Ani, Ani,
let's go, go, go, go.
Yeah, yeah.
Fireworks after!
(in Russian): Tell me if you see
those Armenians.
I don't see anyone.
By the way, you can't find
blow like this in Moscow.
(in English): Your, uh, looks
great.
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
Mm.
You were right.
- Huh?
- You were right.
This is bangin'.
- Ah, yeah?
- Yeah.
Having fun?
Yes. Are you?
Yeah, yeah. Do exactly that.
(in Russian): I wanted to ask...
Are you available tonight?
(in English): Uh... maybe.
(in Russian): The fuck? Maybe?
(in English): Well, it's New Year's.
Ah.
(in Russian): And what?
(in English): I have
holiday rates.
Ah.
Yeah?
(in Russian): Ivan, we're
leaving. You good?
Dude. What the fuck. I'm busy!
These fucking guys don't know
their place.
- (in English): All good?
- All great.
Yeah.
Oh, fuck.
Good morning.
No. No, dude, not good morning.
It is 5:00 p.m.
(in Russian): Well then,
good evening.
Wait, are you leaving?
(in English): Yeah, don't go.
Don't go yet.
No, dude,
I-I have to go to work.
I have shit to do, okay?
But text me if you want
to see me again. Yeah?
What? No.
Uh...
I have one question.
- You have a question?
- Yeah, man.
Okay. One minute.
One minute, one question.
- Mm...
- Yeah?
(in Russian): I want to
make an offer.
Would you want to be
exclusive with me?
(in English): Like, how
exclusive?
I don't know.
We can hang out with my boys.
(in Russian): Simply be my
girlfriend for the week.
(in English): My horny
Oh. What about...
...ten K of dollars?
Fifteen.
Cash, up front.
Deal.
You know,
I would've done it for ten.
(in Russian): Well, if I were you,
I wouldn't do it for less
than thirty.
Goodbye.
(in English): Damn.
She's fucking hot, man.
Yeah, baby.
- Who's the birthday boy?
- This guy right here.
Happy birthday.
Thank y'all for coming in.
Y'all come back.
- Y'all come see us soon.
- Bye!
Come with me.
Go ahead. Tell him. Tell him.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Tell him, because I don't want to.
- I am gonna fucking tell him.
- What's going on?
- You don't even want to know.
- Hi, Jimmy.
You don't want to fucking know,
Jimmy.
She wants a week off.
- I thought you wanted me to tell him.
- You see the shit that I have to deal with?
I just made the schedule.
Now she wants to pull this bullshit.
Oh. The schedule.
- We just gave you New Year's.
- Oh, Jesus Christ, Jimmy,
once you give me
health insurance,
workers' comp
and a fucking 401K,
then you can tell me
when I work and not work.
Well, none of that's
gonna happen, so...
- Shocker.
- Bye.
I'll be back on Tuesday.
Today is Tuesday.
Correct.
- That's a week.
- No shit.
Thank you.
- You like that?
- No.
(chatter in Russian)
You know, Ani, it's the
champagne glass of my mother.
Of my fucking mother.
And it will be
your champagne glass.
And what we are cheering for?
About my new girlfriend.
- Hell yeah. To Ani.
- Yeah.
(in Russian): To the most
amazing chick.
(in English): Yeah.
- One more. One more.
- Okay.
Instantly. Instantly.
(in Russian): Fuck.
Klara, maybe you want a hit?
Sorry, Ivan. Not today.
Mm-hmm.
(in English): It was really
funny when, uh,
Klara smoked
last time.
My mother, uh, caught her
in the cryo chamber.
(in Russian): What?
Nothing, just keep working.
(in English): You have a cryo
chamber?
Yeah.
Oh, shit.
Yeah, but I'm not allowed
to drive them
because my parents are dicks.
- What's up?
- How are you?
- I'm good.
- Yeah, what's up, man?
- What's up, Ivan?
- Welcome.
You guys can just, like,
eat whatever the fuck you want.
We got ice cream.
There's, like,
whatever the fuck these are.
There's Ring Pops.
Like, literally,
I just fuck around in here.
The boss is old as fuck,
and he's, like, blind and deaf.
He can't even fucking hear us right now,
Helen Keller-ass bitch, like...
Just fucking go crazy.
Okay.
- Yep, yep, yep.
- Up.
(speaks Russian)
Want? Oh, yeah, man,
finish it up.
Bitch, don't die on the job.
You okay?
How many times you guys
have to be told not...
...no smoking dope in here?
- But we're addicted to the reefer, Billy.
- Come on, man.
We're gonna take our break.
Ten minutes, man.
♪ Hi, Mr. Billy ♪
♪ Again we're smoking dope ♪
- ♪ Dope ♪
♪ In your candy shop,
in your candy shop. ♪
Ani!
- What the fuck?
- Oh, shit.
-  What are you doing?
- (in Russian): Don't do that.
- (in English): No, come back.
- Whoa.
- No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- Come back.
It's fucking cold.
- What the fuck?
- What are you doing?
- Come back.
- Can you say hi to my Instagram?
Ani.
Hmm?
Are you happy?
Yes. Very happy.
Yeah, I'm always happy.
No, it's really good lines,
but ladies first.
Ladies first.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, that's...
Can you...
(in Russian): Guys,
the best ketamine I ever tried
was in Vegas!
(in English): Vegas.
It's a great idea.
We are going to fucking Vegas.
Welcome to Vegas!
We're in Vegas, bitch!
- Ah.
- Welcome back, Mr. Zakharov.
Your suite is almost ready.
We didn't know you were coming,
- and the suite was occupied...
- Uh-huh.
...but they're out,
and housekeeping
should be done any minute.
What the fuck, man?
Are you fucking kidding me?
You mean I have to wait?
You mean we have to wait
right now, bro, yes?
Yes?
Tell him,
tell him, tell him, Ivan.
- Yeah, go off, Vanya.
- Come on. Come on.
I am fucking with you, dude.
We will stay here.
- It's nice to come back.
- Very good.
Let's go apeshit
on this fucking casino.
Have a great time.
What the fuck
are you waiting for?
Yeah! Oh!
Can somebody turn on music?
- Can... Tom, Tom.
- Turn on the music!
I got it. I got it.
Try this, try this, try this.
Vanya! I want this one!
- No, no, no. No. No, no, no.
- This one's mine!
- Vanya!
- Go away from my room!
You claim this room,
I claim your sister.
I claim your mom.
If you are ready now,
yeah, we can...
- You ready now?
- Okay, yes, I'm ready now.
You want me to...
Let's play blackjack, for sure.
"We are going in, all in."
- Yeah? Okay.
- Yeah, say it.
- We are going all in.
- Motherfucker.
Twenty-two, all in.
Whatever. Whatever, guys.
- How much money is that?
- What...
But do it with a double dose
because we're gonna go
even harder tonight.
Okay?
(speaks Russian)
(in Russian): Thank you.
(in English): Tom, give me a cigarette.
- Oh.
- One cigarette.
- You know? Fuck you.
- (speaks Russian)
They fucking do this every day.
I am really happy
that we are here,
- and, uh... I don't know.
- Thank you.
Fuck. You're the best, guys.
You are the fucking best.
Vanya. Vanya.
Vanya.
- Vanya, wait, wait, wait.
- What happened?
Well, you know,
it could last longer
and be better
if you just take it easy.
Like, how?
Here. Let me do it.
Ah.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, I think I love you.
Fuck.
I hope you had fun this week.
I hope you had fun
this week.
Oh, I did.
You know, we should
do it again sometime.
Yeah.
For sure.
Mm, but...
I have to go back to Russia
because I promised my father
that I would start working
in his fucking company.
Oh.
Okay, so that's why
you've been splashing out, hmm?
Eh, no, I am always
partying like this.
Mm.
I love it.
Well, I'm gonna miss you.
- What?
Does that, like, sound weird?
No, no.
And will you miss me
or my money blyat?
Or your money blyat.
- Of course.
- Yeah, I like it.
But, mm, if I get married
to an American,
I wouldn't have to go back
to Russia.
- Oh, yeah?
- Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So, who would you marry?
I don't know.
Maybe Crystal.
Or your friend Lulu.
She's so hot.
You.
"You."
It's Vegas.
It's fucking Vegas.
Don't people get married
in Vegas?
Mm... Don't fuck around.
I am not fucking around.
Okay.
Okay, go.
- Go get married.
- Yes.
Yes, let's get married.
Fuck. You asshole.
- Why?
- Don't.
Like, don't fucking tease me
with that shit, okay?
- Stop.
- It ain't cool.
Stop, stop, stop.
- Ani.
- Yeah?
Will you marry me?
- Seriously?
- Seriously.
Mm-hmm.
So you want to get married
to me, Vanya?
You want me to be
your little wifey?
Yeah?
Yes.
I just think that we had
great time together, and, uh...
(in Russian): Shit, I'm nervous.
I'll say it in Russian.
I think
we would have a great time
even if I didn't have money.
(in English): And I will become
American,
and my parents
will suck my dick.
Are you serious?
I am serious.
And I said it twicely.
Three carats.
What about four or five?
Or six?
Do you promise to love, honor
and cherish her
all the days of your life?
I do.
And do you, Anora, take this
handsome gentleman
standing before you
to be your best friend,
your protector, your husband?
Do you promise to love,
honor and cherish him
all the days of your life?
- Say yes.
- Oh, fuck yeah, I do.
It is now my great honor
to now pronounce you
as husband and wife.
You may seal your promises
with a kiss!
My wife!
- It's my wife, man.
- We got married!
It's my wife. She can do it.
It's my wife, man.
Yeah, we got married
five minutes ago, man.
You're an American, Vanya.
- I'm fucking American!
- We're fucking married!
I am American, bitch!
So, this is for real?
Yeah, it's for real.
- What do you mean?
- 'Cause if it is,
I got to stop letting
the high rollers in.
They're stealing my best girls.
Come here.
You're so lucky.
Oh, my God, I know. Thank you.
Yay!
You hit the lotto, bitch.
Aw. Oh, my God.
Are you gonna cry?
Stop. You don't...
You'll come over
for dinner, right?
You know, I've been thinking
about our honeymoon,
and I think we should do it
at Disney World
because that's been,
like, my dream
- since I've been a little girl.
- Stop.
Yeah. You know those suites
where it's, like,
the Disney Princess theme?
- Cinderella.
- Yes, fucking Cinderella.
You know me
so fucking well, babe.
Bye, Ani.
You better visit us, bitch.
Oh, of course I will, Jenny.
- Bye, babe.
- Caught your whale?
Seems I did, didn't I?
I give it two weeks, bitch.
Oh, Diamond. Oh, sweetie.
You know, I really hope you
find your happiness one day.
- I really hope...
- I hope you find a fucking plastic surgeon.
- What the fuck?!
- Okay, Ani. Ani, come on.
Play in my fucking face again, bitch.
See what happens.
- You're a fucking bitch.
- Oh, stay jealous, babe.
Stay jealous, honey.
Jealousy is a disease.
Remember that, Diamond.
I'm just gonna go chill
in my mansion or whatever.
You know, no big deal.
Hey.
(in Russian): This is
impossible!
These are just
rumors.
I was with him two weeks ago.
He isn't married.
With all due respect,
Galina Stepanovna.
These are just rumors.
No... but I'm heading there now.
Garnik. Garnik.
(in English):
Now?
- Yes.
- Now?
(in Russian): Take this. Grab
the Russian and get over there.
What did he do now?
(in English): Die, die, die.
Yeah.
Come on.
(in Russian): Just answer it or
shut it off.
(responds in Russian)
- Vanya.
- Hmm?
(in English): What did, uh...
what did they say when you told
them?
I don't want really
talk about them.
Well, you did tell them, right?
Mm. Sure.
I mean...
(in Russian): This is good news, right?
Parents usually want
their kids to get married.
Yeah,
but my parents are dicks,
you know.
(in English): Uh, whatever. Mm.
(in Russian): No matter what,
I hope they like me...
(in English): You know...
(in Russian): when we meet.
By the way,
when will we meet your parents?
Mm...
Well, if you want
to go to Miami...
My mom lives there with her man.
And you can meet
my sister anytime.
Although I'm sure
she'll try to steal you.
She loves Russian guys.
(repeats sentence in Russian)
(in English): What?
Are you making fun of me?
I'm trying here, asshole.
(in Russian): No, your Russian
is wonderful! Really.
Every single day
you're doing better and better.
You're almost like
a native speaker.
(in English):
Oh, okay.
- You're a liar.
- No, no, no.
Not now. Ani, not now.
(in Russian): I'm playing.
I have a mission.
Give me the controller.
I lost!
- Okay.
(in Russian): "Arguments and
Facts"
ran a photo of him with
some chick
at an NBA game.
And they are saying
she's a prostitute.
It's not funny, man.
Don't you dare laugh.
If it's true,
Toros and I are fucked.
Well, Toros would be fucked
more than me, but still.
Sounds like tabloid bullshit.
Probably.
But listen, if things get crazy,
don't get rough with Ivan.
Actually, don't even touch Ivan,
let me deal with him.
I got you. But what
do you need me for then?
In case his boys are there
and they want to play games.
(in English): Hey. Is Ivan at
the house?
I don't know.
He hasn't left
since I've been here,
but I just started my shift.
Do you know if he got married?
Married?
I have no idea.
I just got here.
Okay, open the gate.
(in Russian): Drive in
and park on the right side.
Right here.
- (in English): Expecting guests?
- No way.
Oh.
(in Russian): Yo, what do you
want?
Ivan, it's Garnik.
I know. What do you want?
Ivan, open the door, please.
- I'm busy. No.
- We have to talk.
Why do I always have
to repeat myself with you?
I'm busy, I have guests.
Ivan, it's important.
We have to talk.
No, we're done.
Get the fuck out of here.
(in English): Who was that?
They're my father's monkeys.
(in Russian): Son of a bitch.
(in English): What the fuck?
(in Russian): Are you fucking
kidding me?
What the fuck are
you doing?
You think you can enter
my house like this?
- (in English): Vanya, what the fuck?
- (in Russian): Slow down, you'll break my leg.
I don't give a fuck.
- (in English): Vanya, should I call 911?
- It's okay. It's okay.
(in Russian): Ivan, your father
sent us.
Right, my father sent you.
Are you kidding me?
Well, not us. Your father sent
Toros and Toros sent us.
So, where's Toros?
He's busy.
But he will be very upset
with you if this is true.
If what is true?
That you got married
to some prostitute.
(in English): What?
(in Russian): Is that her?
- Are you married to her?
- Yes!
Did you lose your fucking mind?
Yes, we married
and we're doing fucking great!
With a signature and paperwork?
Yes. Now get the fuck out
of my house.
You're in big trouble, brother!
You'll be in trouble if
you don't move your fucking leg.
(in English): Vanya, what the
fuck is going on?
(in Russian): We'll wait, I need
to see the marriage license.
Fuck. Are you serious?
Bro, the faster we do it,
the faster we're out of here.
My parents are fucking crazy!
(in English): Okay.
(in Russian): If my parents need
proof, I'll give them proof.
(in English): Uh, where
is the marriage paper?
- Uh, marriage...
- The marriage license?
- License, yeah.
- It's, um...
It's in the desk
in the office. Why?
- Okay. Uh...
- Should I go with you?
Uh, no, no, no. Stay here.
(in Russian): Wait here.
(in English): Hi.
(in Russian): Here.
Choke on it, dude.
(in English): I'm Igor.
You?
Ani.
I'm Vanya's wife.
Congratulations.
(in Russian): What are you
doing?
I've been asked to take a photo
of the license... if it exists.
That's insane.
My parents asked for that?
Toros.
Are you fucking kidding me?
(in English): No.
What the fuck is going on here?
I have no idea.
(in Russian): It's over, go, go,
go, go...
Wait.
- (in English): Is everything okay?
- Yeah, it's okay.
Yeah? What the fuck
is going on?
Yeah, just time
to say goodbye to guys.
(in Russian): Me and my wife
need some privacy.
You look tired, Garnik, go home.
We need to wait to see
what Toros says.
I'm waiting for you
and your fucking Armenian ass
to be out of my house.
(in English):
Sorry.
So sorry.
I'm so sorry. Excuse me.
(in Russian): I'm waiting for
you to be on your fucking way.
Bye, bro!
Ivan...
It's Toros.
(in English): "Stand by."
(speaks Russian)
..."Stand by"?
He texted, "Stand by,"
so we stand by.
- So stand by outside my mansion, motherfuckers.
- Yeah.
(in Russian): What's the problem?
So apparently, it is true.
Yes.
I've seen the marriage license.
Galina Stepanovna,
please don't worry.
Ivan, with all due respect...
your father sent us.
Fucking Toros sent you!
Toros works for me! I pay him!
And you bring some fucking
gopnik into my home.
I promise,
I will fix everything.
Galina Stepanovna.
Yes, Galina Stepanovna.
I'm having your ass fired!
You're dead for this!
Bitch!
(in English): Okay, look, look.
You work for Ivan's family,
so I'm assuming that means
you work for him, right?
So if he's telling you
to take it outside,
fucking take it outside.
Fucking take it outside!
Listen to my wife.
Real talk! (speaks Russian)
- Are you kidding me?
- Everybody, so sorry.
I have to go.
I have an emergency.
Sorry about that.
(in Russian): He says we have
to stay here.
Move, move...
Move. Thank you.
- Wait.
- It's Toros.
- (in English): Hello, Toros.
- Put me on the fucking speaker
so this hooker
can hear me, too.
He just called me a hooker?
(in Russian): You're already
on speaker.
(in English): She's fucking
erotic dancer. Hi, Toros.
What did you do, Ivan?
What did you do?
(in Russian): I don't check in on you
for two weeks
and you go
and marry a prostitute!
Fucking hell!
(in English): I'm not a fucking
prostitute,
you fucking piece of
shit.
Yeah, fucking Armenian
piece of shit.
You Armenian piece of shit!
(in Russian): Do you understand
how shameful this is?
- Toros.
- Your mother was crying, do you hear me?
Toros!
(in English): Your mother,
she never cry in her life.
She was crying on the phone.
- Toros!
- Shame on you!
- Fuck you! Blyat!
- Ivan.
(in Russian): Fucking faggot.
And guess what?
Guess what, you little shit!
And what? Surprise me!
You really did it this time.
What?
Your parents are on their way!
Your parents are on the way.
Can you hear me?
To where?
Here. Where else? Here!
Coming to pick you up
like a naughty school boy,
you hear me?
We're meeting them
tomorrow at noon.
(in English): Vanya,
what the fuck is going on?
(in Russian): They're taking
you back to Russia,
so start packing.
(in English): Ivan, what
the fuck? What does that mean?
Do you understand?
Game over for you. That's it.
Vanya, we are married.
They're gonna
have to accept that.
- Yeah, I know!
- Yes.
Accept that?
That's funny. Sure, yeah.
(in Russian): Ivan, listen to me
carefully.
I'll be there in ten minutes.
You and your whore
are coming with me.
Whore?
(in English): Your mother is a
fucking... (speaks Russian)
- Who the fuck is this guy?
- Hey! I'm gonna be there
in ten minutes, you hear me?
In ten minutes, both of you
are coming with me
down to the city hall.
We're gonna annul
this marriage.
Do you hear me? This marriage
is gonna be annulled!
Oh, I am not going
fucking anywhere.
We are not getting a divorce
because you tell us to!
Go fuck yourself!
You go fuck yourself.
How about that?
Me go fuck myself?
Me fuck myself?
You go fuck yourself and your
fucking mother, motherfucker!
Shut the fuck up!
You don't even know
who the fuck I am.
Stop, stop, stop, stop, stop.
Toros, Toros, uh...
(in Russian): You said my
parents
are on their way to
America?
(in English): Yes, yes. Are you deaf?
They are leaving Russia
in an hour.
Tomorrow noon, we're gonna
go meet them, you hear me?
- What the fuck is going on?
- Come on.
- Come on?
- Come on, come on, come on.
Why do we have to leave
the house?
They can't just fucking
come in here like that.
- Excuse me. Get the fuck away from me, please.
- (in Russian): Toros will be here in ten minutes.
(in English): Garnik,
shut that bitch up, please.
- Where are we going, Ivan?
- Ivan, Ivan...
I don't know where
are we going, but we are going.
Where is he going?
Why do we have to leave,
and why are they staying?
- Ivan...
- That doesn't make any sense.
- Ivan, where are you going?
- We should call the fucking police or something.
(in Russian): In ten minutes,
Toros will be here...
- Vanya.
- Garnik!
Did he say he's leaving?
- Ivan! We...
- Let's go, let's go, let's go!
Okay! I need to get dressed, though!
- (in English): My fucking clothes are upstairs. Fuck!
- (in Russian): No, no. Let's do this, let's wait for Toros.
Garnik, get him.
Garnik, don't let him leave.
- (in Russian): Toros will arrive in ten minutes.
- Vanya, wait. Give me one fucking minute.
Stop, stop. Where are you going?
No. We have no time.
- I have to get dressed, Ivan. I have no fucking pants on.
- Oh, God!
Okay, bye.
- (speaks Russian)
- Did he say bye?
- What the fuck? Are you fucking kidding me?
- (in Russian): Keep her here.
- Did he say bye?
- Ivan!
(in English): Oh, my fucking God!
Garnik!
Ivan, what the fuck?!
Whoa. Uh...
Get the fuck out of my way.
Ivan!
Get the fuck out of
my fucking way, motherfucker.
- But you...
- Do not fucking touch me!
No. No, no, no.
(in Russian): Stop!
Ivan! Ivan!
(in English): ...fucking
touch me!
- Relax. Relax. It's okay.
- You fucking relax.
What is happening?
Somebody talk to me, please!
Don't you touch me,
motherfucker!
- No, just...
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
- Relax. Whoa.
- Motherfucker!
Everything all right?
What?
(in Russian): Fucking
impressive.
- (in English): Okay...
- Stay the fuck back!
No, no. What?
No, no, no, no, no!
Put it. It's-it's bad way.
- Wha... Just sit.
- I fucking dare you.
Take another fucking step,
motherfucker.
No. Just... I don't...
I don't touch you.
No, no, no, no, no, no!
Don't leave.
It's okay.
Uh, just put it... Whoa!
Stop.
Please stop.
Stop, please.
No, no. Stop.
Stop. Stop, please.
Garnik, what are you doing?
Are you killing her?
- Stop it!
- Fuck!
Ivan throwing another one
of his tantrums, huh?
Hold on. It's okay.
If you don't stop...
I will tie you up!
You're not tying me up,
motherfucker!
Get the fuck off me!
You are fucking insane.
Hey. Hey!
Help me! He's attacking me.
What the fuck
are you doing to her, bro?
Get the fuck off me!
Somebody help!
-  Get him off me!
- (in Russian): What do you mean?
You wanted me to keep her here,
so I'm keeping her here.
Yes, but why
are you tying her up?
But she got fucking crazy,
started jumping all around.
- (in English): Help me!
- (in Russian): What else could I do?
(in English): Why are you just
fucking standing there?
(in Russian): Igor, what the
fuck are you doing, man?
She threw the candlestick at me.
Let's tie her legs.
(in English): No, no, no, no!
Please, please, please, please don't.
(in Russian): We are not doing
that, let her go!
(in English): Let me go, you fucking asshole.
Goddamn fucking bastard.
(in Russian): She will run, bro.
I promise.
Where will she run?
We're two grown men here.
Are you out of your mind?
(in English): Okay.
You crazy motherfucker!
You better stay the fuck
away from me!
Stop, stop. Listen.
You are not going anywhere.
Come back. Please come...
(in Russian): She will run away!
Really?
(in English): Hey, stop.
(in Russian): Get her!
(in English): Get the fuck off me!
Put me down, motherfucker!
(in Russian): Fuck!
What the fuck, man?
She's biting, fuck.
(in English): Fucker!
(in Russian): C'mon, tie her legs.
How?
- (in English): You motherfucker! Fuck!
- (in Russian): What do you mean how?
(in English): Fucking motherfucker.
You fucking asshole.
- (in Russian): With fucking what?
- Use that cord!
(in English): No, no. Don't, don't.
I don't even know
what is going on here.
I didn't do anything. Don't tie me.
I'm not gonna run. I promise.
I'm calm. I'm not gonna do anything.
I'm not gonna run away.
- You do not need to tie me.
- (in Russian): Are you fucking kidding, tie her!
(in English): No, you-you motherfucker.
You don't need to tie me.
- Calm down. Listen, listen.
- I am calm. I am calm.
Ivan's father wants this marriage annulled.
You're staying here and getting this annulled.
You heard my boss.
Fuck your boss.
(in Russian): I swear
to fucking God!
Garnik, you stupid fucking idiot!
Oh fuck.
(in English): I just want to
know what is going on.
Someone fucking tell me
what's going on.
I'm not gonna run. Let me go.
(in Russian): Damn, it's broken.
I think she broke my nose.
(in English): Yeah. I'm glad I
broke your fucking nose!
You fucking bitch,
you broke my nose!
Yeah? Next time, I'll kick you
in the fucking balls!
- God, let me go!
- (in Russian): Hold her.
(in English): Garnik,
you fucking idiot, talk to me!
- Fucking untie me, motherfucker!
- Hello? Garnik?
(in Russian): Hold on a minute, Toros.
(in English): You fucking
piece of shit.
- (in Russian): Hold on?
- (in English): Fucking psycho.
(in Russian): C'mon man,
hold on! Fuck.
(in English): I am not fighting.
(in Russian): Garnik, I swear...
If you fucked this up...
Garnik, motherfucker.
(in English): Untie me. I am not fighting.
I'm not gonna run. Just fucking untie me.
No.
Don't let her go.
(in Russian): I swear...
(in English): Oh, you are
so fucked.
You're going to prison.
Where's your ice?
I can't wait until Ivan sees
what you did to me.
Rich people don't have ice?
Ivan did just leave the house.
He did not leave.
He is going to get help.
I-I don't think so.
Garnik!
You fucking asshole.
Yeah, I bet you like this, huh?
Yeah, you like this,
you sick fuck?
I bet you get off on this.
Fucking psycho.
Tor, where are you?
(in Russian): Here, you donkey
fucker.
(in English): Open the gate.
Okay, sir, but Ivan just...
Open the fucking gate!
I am not fighting. Let me go.
No.
You are not going anywhere.
(in Russian): Don't let her go
under any circumstances.
(in English): You two are
fucking dead for this!
I am Ivan's fucking wife!
Vanya?
Oh, are you the Armenian
fuck I was talking to?
What the fuck is happening?
Is this the big fucking boss?
What happened here?
- She happened.
- Hey, mister.
- Can you fucking tell this guy to untie me?
- What?
Yeah, she did this.
- Hello.
- Where is Ivan?
Ivan run away.
- Why the fuck is no one an...
- Run away?
- Excuse me, sir. Hello.
- You didn't stop him?
I-I tried, but then, uh, there was,
uh, ice on the floor.
- I tried to stop him.
- Hello!
- You tried?
- You tried? You don't try, you just grab the guy.
- Somebody fucking listen to me.
What do you mean you tried?
- What do you mean? I'm not a...
- So he's gone?
I'm not allowed to touch
that motherfucker.
- Excuse me! Hello!
- Shut the fuck up!
No, you fucking let me go.
Tell this guy to fucking let me go.
(in Russian): What were you
doing? Why did you let him leave?
(in English): Are you the boss?
You're the fucking boss?
(in Russian): What? He told me
not to touch the guy
and I was dealing with her.
(in English): Fucking... Excuse me.
Oh, fucking motherfuckers.
- Please leave your message...
- He doesn't answer.
- (in Russian): He doesn't pick up.
- (in English): Hey, fuck face.
(in Russian): Of course
he's not going to answer.
(in English): Can you tell this
motherfucker to let me go?
Why is she on top of you, man?
Wh-Wh-What's going on?
I don't know what's going on.
Can you please tell him to untie me?
- (in Russian): Why is she sitting on you?
- I'm holding her!
(in English): Put-put her down, please.
- No, don't do that.
- Yes, fucking put me down.
No, don't do that.
Tell him to fucking
put me down, please.
Put her down.
- Why you holding her like that?
- Ow.
- No, no, no. Be careful, bro.
- Fuck. Fuck!
- Be careful.
- Why...
Hey, now can you tell him
to fucking untie me?
Why did you... Why...
Why did you tie her hands?
- Untie me.
- Look.
- What, you afraid of this little girl?
- Can you tell him to fucking untie me?
- She's an animal.
- She's a fucking little girl! So, she...
- She beat you both up?
- She's not fighting like one.
- I'm gonna get my phone.
- Can you untie her?
- If you untie her, I'm just leaving, bro.
- This is ridiculous, man. Untie her.
- It's embarrassing.
- She will start swinging again. Don't do that.
(in Russian): I can untie her but you won't get
what you need because she's out of control.
(in English): Fuck you.
- She's an animal, bro. Trust me.
- No, these guys are fucking liars. - Okay, listen to me.
Where is your phone? Can you
please give me your phone?
My phone is in the other room. I will go get my
phone if you untie me. I need you to untie me.
- Where? Which other room? Over there? Can-can
you... (in Russian): Go grab her phone, please.
(in English): No, I will get my phone.
I'll get my phone, and I'll call Vanya.
I will untie you.
Give me a minute.
- No! No, don't do that!
- I just need your phone to call Ivan.
- I know, and I will get my phone.
- (in Russian): I'm telling you to get the fucking phone!
- (in English): Let's just calm down for one second.
- Careful.
Calm down for a second.
- Just calm down. And listen to me.
- I am calm. I'm not fucking moving.
Okay, look, we have an emergency here.
It's very important.
Okay, I need you to cooperate.
I'm begging you.
Your guys came in here.
They chased Ivan out
of the fucking house.
They fucking tied me.
They attacked me.
That motherfucker was making me
sit on his fucking lap.
Your guys are fucking crazy.
I-I'm terribly sorry
it went down that way, okay?
I'm terribly sorry.
But now we have to just
call him, okay?
Here. Help me, please.
He's-he's on your phone?
Yeah, it's under "husband."
Okay. Yep.
"Husband."
Here we go.
- Please leave your message...
- It goes to voicemail.
That's a fucking great
husband you have.
First ditches you,
now doesn't answer your calls.
Real marriage my ass, man.
(in Russian): He's flown the coop.
Fucking little piece of shit.
(in English): I don't know what
kind of...
fucked-up family shit
is going on here,
but Ivan and I
are married, okay?
This is a real marriage,
and I'm not getting a divorce.
This is not a real marriage.
This is a real marriage.
Okay, and we're
getting it annulled,
and you have no say in it.
Well, I'm his fucking wife,
so I do think I have a say in it.
Absolutely not.
Listen to what I'm telling you.
You got married illegally,
it's a fraud marriage,
and we're
- getting it annulled A.S.A.P.
- A fraud marriage?
No, we are two consenting
adults who got married legally,
and there is nothing
you can fucking do about it.
No, this is Ivan
just fooling around!
- Would you get over it?
- No, it's not.
- You have no fucking idea.
- Oh, yeah?
When'd you guys meet, huh?
- When did you meet him?
- Strip club.
I am telling you,
you do not know this guy.
I do know him.
You do not know this guy,
I'm telling you.
- Oh, I know my husband. I do.
- No, you don't.
It's classic Ivan. I've been dealing
with his shit since he was...
- ...he was six years old.
- Classic Ivan.
And now his parents
are gonna kill me,
and my fucking family
will never talk to me again.
(in Russian): Little bastard.
And you left the baptism
half way because of this guy.
- Tell me about it.
- Oh my God.
(in English): I love my husband,
and I plan on being with
him forever.
No, don't give me
that bullshit.
Do not give me that bullshit.
You don't love him.
You do not love him,
and he doesn't love you.
You understand?
That's in your head.
I can't wait to have
Ivan's children.
In fact, I think
I'm probably already pregnant.
I-I certainly hope
you're lying,
'cause we're gonna have to
take care of that, too.
- I promise you that.
- Oh, the-the fuck you will.
- Yes, we will.
- And I would like all of you
to fucking untie me
and leave my home,
- or I will be pressing charges.
- Your home?!
- Yeah, my home.
- This isn't Ivan's home.
This is his father's house.
Everything Ivan has
belongs to his father.
You understand?
Ivan has nothing.
You know that bedroom
you've been fucking in?
That's his parents' room.
Do you know
where is Ivan's room?
It's down the hall with fucking
spaceships on the walls.
Do you know why?
- Do you know why?
- Fucking tell me why.
- You're already gonna tell me, so...
- Because he's a fucking child, that's why.
Fucking kid.
You don't understand--
he's shamed his family
by marrying somebody like you.
If you think for a second
this is gonna be allowed,
you're dead wrong.
In fact, if-if you don't
help me fix this,
I'm gonna have you arrested.
Yeah.
- I'm gonna have you arrested.
- Arrested?
Yeah.
- That's fucking hilarious.
- Yep.
- Arrested for what?
- For what?
- Yeah.
- I'll tell you for what.
- Trespassing.
- "Trespassing."
Fraud, cheating.
- Theft.
- Theft?
- Yes, theft.
- Assault.
And I... actually, the picture
is very, very clear here.
A scheming prostitute
married Ivan, cheated...
cheated Ivan to marry her
so she can steal
from his wealthy family.
- That's it.
- Mm-hmm. Definitely.
And I'm sure you already
have criminal record, so...
For sure happened.
Yeah. One, two, three,
you're in jail.
- Easy.
- Yep.
Ivan proposed to me.
He wanted to get married.
He put a fucking ring
on my finger.
- Do you see this shit?
- What ring?
He bought me
a fucking four-carat ring.
Does this look real to you, motherfucker?
Bet you've never seen one
of these before, have you, huh?
(in Russian): Take that ring off
her finger.
- (in English): No. No.
- (in Russian): Take it off.
(in English): This is my fucking
ring Ivan gave me.
- Give me that fucking ring.
- I am not giving you the fucking ring.
- (in Russian): Take that fucking ring off!
- (in English): You touch me,
and I will fucking scream, motherfucker.
Do not come for me.
- Get that fucking ring off of her.
- (speaks Russian)
- Be careful.
- Hold the legs.
(in Russian): Careful, bro!
This is Zakharov's property.
- Fuck you! Fuck you!
- Shut up. Shut up.
Rape!
Hey, hey, don't scream.
Hey, what-what is she saying?
- Rape! Rape!
- Shut up. Shut the fuck up.
Is she saying, "Rape"?
Is she...
What? What? Shut up!
(in Russian): She bites!
Ouch!
(in English): Don't go
near to her.
(in Russian): Shut her mouth!
Somebody is going to call the
police!
- How?
- You got to shut her up!
- How? I need a rag or something!
- Motherfucker!
(in English): Shut the fuck up.
Stop screaming.
Please stop screaming.
Please! Stop! Screaming!
You get us
in front of that judge
first thing in the morning,
or the family cuts ties
with your firm.
Simple as that.
No, no... no trying.
Everything will be okay.
Yeah.
(in Russian): Time to break this
bitch. Let's go.
(in English): You calm now?
You gonna behave?
(in Russian): Careful.
(in English): Trust me, I know.
I know what you're thinking.
You're thinking
this little shit betrayed you.
Well, guess what,
he betrayed me too, okay?
Me too.
You see?
He betrayed all of us.
'Cause he's a spoiled brat
that doesn't want to grow up.
Big-time.
And now we're in this mess
that we have to...
we have to fix it together.
You understand?
But I'm gonna help you.
Okay? I'm gonna help you.
The way I see it, this is
a green card marriage.
Therefore, Ivan owes you
a green card marriage fee.
It's only fair.
So, once this thing
is annulled,
I'm gonna make sure you get
$10,000 fee in cash.
Hmm?
I'm gonna bring this down,
but no screaming, okay?
If you scream,
this goes right back in.
You understand?
Ten K.
It's as good as you're
gonna get here, honey.
What do you say?
I want to talk to Ivan
before agreeing to any of this.
Sure. Of course.
We all want to talk to Ivan.
We want the same thing.
Okay, so let's
fucking find Ivan.
All right, but look at me.
Look at me.
Once we find Ivan--
which we will--
and we get this thing
annulled-- which we will--
you're gonna walk away
with ten K fee
and never, ever
contact Ivan again.
Is that understood?
Fine.
Untie her.
(in Russian): You got their
marriage license and passport?
Excuse me,
I have to get dressed.
Can I have some privacy, please?
Anora Mikheeva?
Ani. It's Ani.
It says Anora.
I know, but I go by Ani.
- Thank you.
- Okay, get in.
(in Russian): So I'm done?
You're with us
until we find him. Get in.
(in English): Wait, why is...
why is he getting back here?
- I'm not sitting next to this fucking psychopath.
- (in Russian): Can I sit in the front?
- (in English): You are the fucking psychopath.
- Yes, get in the front.
- I don't want to fucking sit next to you.
- I'm not getting back there with you.
Un-fucking-believable.
(in Russian): Klara, come here.
It's a bit messier
than usual today.
So this is for you.
No questions.
(in English): So you're
saying he's gonna be there?
I have no fucking idea.
He better be.
Okay, let's go!
I need to go to the hospital...
(speaks Armenian)
No, you're okay.
Don't worry about it.
No, I'm not, bro.
I feel like I have
a concussion or something.
I'm sorry for what...
Let's go! Let's go! Let's go!
...was happening back there.
(in Russian): How could I have imagined...
I don't want your dude
talking to me, okay?
(in Russian): Leave her the fuck alone, man!
(in English): My head is pounding, bro.
- You can't even...
- Shut it, Garnik!
Oh, my God, we're gonna get
into a fucking car accident
- with you driving like that.
- Are you suicidal or something?
- Just shut the fuck up.
- You almost hit that fucking old lady.
- What do you know about driving? What do you know?
- You shut the fuck up.
- (in Russian): Swing by my place and I will
give him something so he'll stop whining.
(in English): You've been bitching and
moaning this entire fucking car ride
about a little fucking scratch on your face.
You're the biggest fucking pussy I ever met.
(in Russian): Just don't eat
all at once.
(in English): What the fuck?
Okay, let's go.
It doesn't matter.
- Let's go.
A little bit faster.
Hurry up.
- Hey, Crystal.
- Hey, Ani.
Hey, have you seen Vanya today?
No, why? Is everything okay?
No? Uh, yeah, everything's fine.
Could you give him a call for me, please?
Okay. What's going on?
I just need you to call him.
- Can you do me a favor and call him?
- Um...
Don't ask too many questions.
Just pick up your phone and call him.
- Okay. Tom? Tom, Ani's here...
- Miss?
- Hey, Tom. - What's up, Ani?
- Have you seen Vanya today?
I have not. No.
Okay, has he, like, texted
or called you at all?
No, not at all. No.
- Okay, could you just call him right now for me?
- Wait. Who are these dudes?
- It's fine. I just...
- Can you call Ivan, please?
- Wait, what's going on? Why would I...
- Just pick up your phone and call him.
I'm not gonna call him.
Who are you?
Doesn't matter who I am.
I just need you to call him.
It does matter. I'm not gonna give
you my fucking phone to call Ivan.
Listen, Ivan is in a lot of trouble.
We need to find him.
Hey, hey, one of you better get
Ivan on the line now.
"On... on the line"?
- "On the line"?
- What the fuck is funny?
- Who the fuck are these guys?
- What the fuck is funny, man?
I'm telling you to call Ivan. What's wrong
with that? Don't complicate your life.
Man, I'm gonna come back there
and just gonna fucking...
I'll complicate your fucking life,
you motherfucker.
- That's not a good idea. That is not a good idea.
- Get the fuck out of here. Get the fuck out of here.
(in Russian): What's up, man?
Tough guy. What do you plan
to do with that?
Break your legs,
if you don't get the fuck out.
(in English): I told you
it's a fucking bad idea.
- Tom.
- So pick up your phone and call him now.
- Whoa, whoa. Fuck off.
- (in Russian): Fucking smash everything.
- What the fuck?
- Fuck, fuck, fuck, fuck...
Tell him to fucking stop!
What the fuck?
- Oh, no.
- Fucking call Ivan now!
- What the fuck, man?
- Okay, okay. Jesus, fuck!
- That's crazy.
- Oh, fuck.
- I am so fucked.
- Put it on speaker.
I am so fucked.
Please leave your message...
- Where's your phone?
- Hold on, man.
Just don't break anything,
all right?
- Call him.
- What the fuck?
- Put it on speaker.
- There you go. There you go.
Just don't break anything, man.
He's not gonna answer the phone.
He's not gonna answer. I know.
- Please leave your message...
- I know it. He's not gonna fucking answer.
Where is his other friend?
Is he with Aleks?
Aleks is working right now.
He can't be with Aleks.
- Where is he working?
- Tatiana's.
- Fuck.
- Let's go.
No. Oh, no.
What the hell?
- Jesus fucking Christ.
- Where are you going?
To the car.
It's five-minute walk.
- No, no, no. I'm not walking down there.
- Let's drive up there.
- It's fucking freezing.
- No, I'm not gonna look for other parking.
Come on, let's go.
- Why don't we drive?
- It's right here. Walk. Chop-chop. Move.
(in Russian): It's fucking cold, man.
Look at me.
Are you doing this on purpose?
What the fuck, bro.
(in English): That took way
fucking longer than five minutes.
Hey.
Table for four?
(in Russian): Is Aleks here?
Aleks?
He should be working here.
- The assistant cook?
- Yes.
- (in English): Let's go.
- No, wait.
- Hold on. You guys cannot go in there.
- No, you're good. You're good.
(in Russian): They know
what they're doing, relax.
- (in English): Oh, my God, Aleks.
- Ani!
- Have you seen Vanya?
- No. What's going on?
We're looking for Vanya.
It's a family emergency.
- Have you seen Ivan?
- What the fuck is going on?
- No.
- (in Russian): I can get fired.
- (in English): You're good. No, you're good.
Don't worry.
Don't worry about it.
- Can you call him, please?
- I haven't seen him.
- Call him? Really?
- Yes, just call him.
- Yes, please call him. Call him.
- Are you an actress?
- I saw you somewhere? Uh?
- I'm not an actress, no.
No? You look good.
(in Russian): Where are you from?
(in English): Give me your phone
one second. One second.
We can't find Vanya anywhere.
Have you talked to him today?
No, I haven't saw him.
He's probably at home.
No, he's not at home, and Tom and Crystal
haven't seen him, either.
Can I have my phone back, please?
Thank you.
- I need Ivan's photo.
- Okay.
You got to have your husband's
photo on your phone.
- No, I am not giving you my phone.
- I need your phone for one second.
- I just need your phone...
- I... No, and you know what?
If you touch me again,
I will fucking scream.
(in Russian): Use Instagram.
(in English): I don't have
Instagram.
I'm an adult, man.
What are you talking about?
You're going to cost me
my job here. Please.
(in Russian): I have it. Here.
- (in English): Guys.
- Oh, okay.
- Ani, what's-what's going on?
- We're looking for...
We're looking for Vanya.
We don't know where he is.
But it's like,
this nigga's fucking insane.
Okay, thank you. Where...
Where are you going?
You think that
he would be with Dasha?
Not unless he's
in Bahamas with her
and her new fuck boy.
Stop the music one second.
Stop the music.
(in Russian): Excuse me, I'm
terribly sorry.
But I need one minute
of your attention.
We are looking for
a missing child, a sick child.
I'm going to show you his photo.
Any information
would be greatly appreciated.
We're the ones fucking paying
and he wants attention?
My apologies,
but the kid is very sick.
Please let us know
if you've seen him.
You didn't see him?
- Give me a cigarette.
- Are you kidding me?
I'm freezing,
and this guy wants cigarettes.
Toros, seriously...
(in English): You'll get cold
if you don't cover your neck.
Why did you bring that?
Why the fuck
did you bring that?
Why? So you could
fucking gag me again?
Motherfucker.
Fuck it. Give me the scarf.
No! No! No!
(in Russian): Swear to God!
(in English): Hey! Hey! This is my car!
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
- No, no, no.
- Man, it's already attached.
- Please.
- It's already attached. I got to take it.
- I got to take it in.
- Don't take my car. Don't do that.
- This is my business situation...
- Hey! Listen to me. Hey! It's your fault!
You were parked in the middle
of the fucking street, okay?
My friend, I was just parking!
There is no sign.
- I'll give you money. How much?
- Listen to me.
- 100, 200, 300? Tell me.
- Listen, down in the yard you're
gonna talk to people, okay?
- Take the money.
- You're gonna talk...
- Fuck you, then. Fuck you.
- What do you mean, fuck me?
- Fuck you.
- What the... I don't give a shit.
- Hey.
- Get the fuck out of my way.
You get out the fucking car!
You fucking asked for this.
I've been on the job
two fucking weeks, bro!
What the fuck are you...
Are you fucking kidding?
Fucking kidding me!
- Oh, my fucking God.
- Jesus Christ!
- Are you fucking...
- It's all because of you.
- Fuck you!
- Get in the car! Come on! Come on!
- You are so fucked.
I have your license plate. If you
get in that car, you're all fucked.
No, no, no, no, no!
What the fuck are you doing?
Fuck you, Russians!
- God.
- Jesus Christ.
You guys are fucking crazy.
We're going to find this fucker
even if it takes
all fucking night.
(in Russian): I swear on my
mother's life...
What the fuck did you just do?
(in English): Come on, give me
something. Like, something.
- Some... Where would you...
- I don't know. I don't know.
Think. Think. Where?
He... Gaming.
He likes video games.
Maybe he'll be at an arcade
or something. I don't know.
(in Russian): Hurry up.
Stay awake, man.
Guys,
anybody see this guy today?
Have you seen Vanya Zakharov?
(responds in Russian)
Guys, see this kid today?
(in English): Oh! Billiard hall.
There-there is
the billiard hall.
Remember five years ago we...
you-you were teaching him
how to play billiard?
We played here,
right here around the corner.
- You remember?
- Five years ago?
I remember.
Come, come.
One second, my friend.
Look at this picture.
Have you seen this guy?
- Ivan, Ivan.
- Is that Vanya?
- Yeah.
Have you seen him today?
- No, not today.
- No.
He does the greatest
parties, though.
Yeah, he's really cool.
(in Armenian): I hate
this bitch so much,
I want to vomit
when I see her face.
(in English): Please leave your message...
Guys, have you seen this guy?
He's missing. He's been missing.
You sure?
(in Russian): Let me ask them.
- Wait, stop.
- Give me a second.
(in English): Guys, have
you seen this... this guy today?
No.
(in Russian): He's probably not
lost, perhaps he is kidnapped.
Yeah sure, kidnapped...
Of course.
(in English): Think, think,
think, think.
And can you keep
calling him, please?
(in Russian): What the fuck?
- (in English): Oh, my God.
- Oh, you got to be...
- ...fucking kidding me!
- Jesus fucking Christ.
You understand that my wife
has to drive this car tomorrow?
Do you?
How am I gonna get rid
of this smell? Huh?
(in Russian): It's better
you go back to Yerevan.
Fucking get rid of you.
Do you want to blow us up?
- I'm careful.
- Fuck off!
Get the fuck out of here!
You care about
Ivan more than me.
Start cleaning!
Who's more important?
Ivan or your dying brother?
(in English): Yeah, I'm not
getting back in there.
(in Russian): Fuck Ivan.
Fuck that little bitch.
(in English): It still fucking
stinks in here.
Fuck, I know. Shit!
Which clubs did you go
with him?
- I don't know. We went to...
- Huh?
I don't know.
We went to a lot of 'em.
Take me to every single one.
Hey, have you seen
this guy today?
Yeah, we cut him off.
He was wasted.
When?
Like 20 minutes ago.
He just left.
Have you guys seen
this guy today?
No?
(in Russian): Did you ask about
Ivan Zakharov?
- He left me an $800 bill.
- Where is he now?
How should I know?
But somebody has to pay me.
- (in English): Okay, bye.
- No, wait. But you know him.
I told him my apologies.
You can tell him one more time.
I'm gonna definitely
make them up to you.
Or up to them, or up to you.
Wh-What can I do?
Wh-What do you want me to do?
He's fine.
(in Russian): Tell his mom
that everything is fine,
he's sitting next to me.
(in English): Is it a real mink?
(in Russian): I'm telling you...
I can't talk anymore. I have to go.
(in English): No.
(in Russian): Please, I'm begging you.
Please stop.
(in English): It looks like real mink.
Of course I do. Why you...
Yeah, it's fucking
real, but it's not mink.
- (in Russian): I'm the godfather of that child.
- (in English): It's fucking Russian sable, okay?
Which is worth
a lot more than mink.
(in Russian): Of course I'm
ashamed.
(in English): No, don't-don't ta...
don't talk about that baby.
Guys, have you seen
this guy today?
- (in Russian): End of the line.
- I just have a question.
Have you seen this kid?
Yeah,
he was here 30 minutes ago.
He was too drunk to enter.
- Do you know where he went?
- Who the fuck knows.
(in English): Your I.D., please.
(in Armenian): What a shitty
godfather you are.
Instead of protecting the child,
you just left him.
Are you fucking with me?
(in Russian): Maybe he's on a bender.
(in Armenian): If you're so
competent, why did you let him leave?
(in Russian): How do you say bender?
(in English): Uh, "bender."
It-it's a bender. Yeah.
(in Armenian): Tor, what does
that have to do with competence?
Fuck this shit.
I didn't sign up for this.
I just want to go home
to Armenia. This sucks.
Bitch!
(in English): I'm so fucked.
So fucked!
You know, he fucked me
much harder than he fucked you.
- Oh, yeah?
- Hundred percent.
Trust me.
If we haven't found him by now,
we are not finding him.
Did I ask you? Did I ask you?
(in Russian): I'm just saying, man.
(in English): Keep your opinion
to yourself.
(in Russian): I'm not going to
talk at all from now on.
(in English): Ani's fucking
billionaire husband
just strolled in,
and he's looking for action.
And I'm gonna give him some.
Vanya?
Vanya.
You know, it's so sad.
That marriage must really be
in the toilet already.
Vanya's here?
'Scuse!
- Have you seen this guy today?
- No.
How about you, sir?
(in Russian): Igor, thank you
for the pills.
(in English): I want what he
had. I want one of those.
Did you fucking hear me?
I said, "I want one of those."
No.
No?
What the fuck? Why?
'Cause I don't deal drugs.
A fucking gopnik who can afford
to live in Brightwater
and doesn't deal drugs?
Yeah, right.
It's my grandmother's apartment
and her drugs.
I don't have any more,
and I'm not gopnik.
Yeah, you're right.
You're a faggot-ass bitch,
is what you are.
Hey, guys, have you seen
this guy today?
No.
(in Russian): What does
faggot-ass bitch mean?
Fucking faggot.
(in English): Yep, what he said.
(in Russian): Go away!
Why are you being rude?
I'm just asking a question.
I don't give a shit.
(in English): And why am I
faggot-ass bitch?
I don't know.
They say you're
just born that way.
You know what, I'm so
sick of your generation, man.
I mean, look at you.
No respect for elder,
no respect for authority,
no goals.
I mean, the only goal you have
just to buy
pair of cool sneakers.
That's all.
I mean, honestly. Come on.
What the fuck
is wrong with you? Huh?
(in Russian): Why don't you just
hear me out?
(in English): No work ethics.
Lazy, stupid.
I don't understand.
I've been working
since I'm 16 years old.
What is wrong with you?
All you do is TikTok,
Instagram, TikTok, Instagram.
That's it.
He's at HQ!
What?
Fucking Headquarters!
Hey.
Hello.
- What's the address?
- West 38th Street.
- Whoo! I fucking love that place.
- You mean fucking Manhattan?
Yeah, it's in
fucking Manhattan.
Oh, my fucking God.
(speaks Russian)
- Hurry up!
- Oh, I need cash.
Toros!
- That's 45 minutes away.
Hurry up.
Beautiful.
You're Vanya, right?
Yeah, that's me.
Anora.
Anora!
It's not Anora. It's Ani.
Tell your friend to hold him
there at any cost.
Even if they have to
physically hold him.
Like, grab him really.
- More? More?
- More, more.
Because you have the best skin
that I ever touch.
- I love you. I love you.
- How do you say...
- In Russian?
- (speaks Russian)
So, don't have a heart attack,
but Vanya's upstairs
in a private with Diamond.
Ani, who the hell
are these guys?
Vanya?
Where is...
He's in one of these rooms?
Yeah.
Shit. Sorry.
- Sorry. Sorry, Daisy.
- Hey, Ani.
Vanya? Oh, shit.
Carla, have you seen Diamond?
I think she's in the pole room.
Hey, what's going...
- What's pole room?
- Fucking pole room.
- Vanya?
- Oh, what the fuck?
Oh, get the fuck off
my fucking husband.
- You fucking mad?
- Yeah, I am about to be fucking mad, bitch.
- Skip out, ho.
- Let's go!
- Oh, you want to fucking go?
- You fucking bitch.
- Yeah, come get some, bitch.
- (in Russian): We're running around all night
and this fucking guy is here getting
his rocks off.
(in English): Nice to see you guys.
(in Russian): We were looking for you all night, you fuck!
- Vanya, we've been fucking looking for you. All night!
- (in English): I've been texting. I've been fucking calling you.
Why haven't you answered
any of my fucking calls?
- You little son of a bitch.
- Why'd you fucking leave me, Vanya?
I tried to run after you. These guys, they fucking
tied my wrists up. They took my ring.
- For what, bro?
- They fucking assaulted me, Vanya.
Okay, get up. Let's go.
You can talk in the car. Get up.
No, I fucking found him,
so I get to fucking talk to him.
- Okay? That was the deal.
- Vanya, our hour's not over.
Oh, get her
the fuck out of here!
Oh, get the fuck out
of my private, bitch!
- Vanya, look at me.
- I am looking at you.
I'm coming back, bitch.
- Fuck you, Diamond.
- This is very important.
Vanya, look at me.
Just listen to me, baby, listen.
These guys, they want us
to get a divorce, okay?
It's not divorce.
- I told you hundred times.
- Back off. Let me...
It's annulment. Annulment.
Vanya, tell them that we're
not gonna get a divorce, okay?
- Tell them that this is a mistake.
- (in Russian): Are my parents here yet?
- (in English): Baby, this is very important.
- Listen to me here.
- No, no, no. We...
- Your parents are coming at 12:00.
I helped you find him,
so let me fucking talk to him.
(in Russian): We still need
to go to the courthouse!
(in English): Vanya, just look at me, okay? Fucking
ignore them. It doesn't fucking matter about her.
It doesn't matter about anything, okay?
Just... I need you to tell them...
Vanya, this is not funny.
I know. It's not.
Vanya, look at me, baby.
Let's stay married, okay?
Yeah. You know these guys?
Yeah, I love them. I love them.
Jesus, Vanya.
We have to talk
about this, okay?
This is very,
very important, all right?
I don't want to talk
about it right now.
Okay, but just-just...
Look what he...
No, no, no, Vanya,
we can't drink right now.
You need to tell them...
Guys, he's fucking drunk.
We can't talk right... No.
We're not fucking done talking.
- I wanted to talk to him.
- Come on.
(in Russian): Here we go!
(in English): Vanya. Vanya.
Vanya, Vanya, we have to keep
talking about this.
Vanya!
Do not fucking touch me! Jesus.
Vanya, we're not...
we have to keep talking.
They're trying to bring us
to get a divorce. We can't...
Do not fucking...
Get the fuck out
of my fucking face.
Jimmy, Ani's here with
three guys causing a scene.
Russian Ani?
- I fucking told you.
- Get the fuck out of my fucking face.
Didn't I? Two weeks.
On the fucking nose!
Wrong one, bitch.
Guys, there's a fucking fight!
- No way!
- Oh, shit!
Oh, my God, I love it.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
(in Russian): Garnik, do
something!
DJ (in English): Yo, yo, yo.
Break it up, break it up.
Take it outside.
Take that shit outside.
There's no fighting at HQ.
Okay, calm down.
- Whoa.
- Man, get the fuck out of here!
- Get the fuck out of here.
- (in Russian): Get in.
(in English): Get back.
Get the fuck out of here.
- You told me Ani's one of our girls.
- Go. Go.
Fucking found you! We found you!
I can't believe you went
running like a fucking baby.
But it's okay.
Your parents are coming.
You're gone.
You're gone, finally.
- Fucking gone.
- Vanya. Vanya.
Do you know
what's happening right now?
Do you fucking know what's
going on right now, Vanya?
- Mm-hmm.
- Get off me, man.
He's fucking wasted. He-he...
I need to talk to him
when he's fucking sober.
I can't talk to him like this.
Talking is done.
Talking is not done. Of course
he's gonna do anything you say.
He's fucking plastered.
- Talking is done. Now we're gonna get
this thing done in three hours.
- No, this wasn't the fucking deal.
Yes, it was.
Oh, slow down.
I'm gonna get sick.
We're gonna get
this thing done.
You're gonna get
your fucking money,
and you're gonna walk away--
that's it.
That was the deal.
Fuck.
What? You know, you must...
You must really hate me, man.
I mean, seriously.
And after all
I've done for you.
You know, everything.
I mean, I bailed you out
how many times?
Huh? How many times?
And you do this to me?
You know, it-it makes me upset.
You know, it's...
You know how...
how embarrassing
that is for me?
Huh?
Are you even listening
to what I'm saying?
He's passed out, abed.
Now we wait.
Okay. He's here. Hey.
Wake up. Wake up.
He's here. Let's go.
Vanya.
(in Russian): Wake up,
brother, come out, please.
(in English): I want to stay in the car.
Vanya, Vanya, look at me.
We need to talk before
you go in there, okay?
(in Russian): Do not get a ticket
and do not get towed.
(in Russian): Keep your phone on.
(in English): Vanya, Vanya, don't say
anything when you go in there, okay?
Vanya, I'm gonna handle this, okay?
I got it.
Handle what?
- Don't talk to him.
- None of your fucking business.
- Let's go.
- Hello, everyone.
- How are you, sir?
- Toros.
- Stop it, stop it, stop it.
- Whoa, whoa. Is he all right there?
- Does he fucking look all right to you?
- He is okay.
He is not fucking all right.
He can barely stand.
How are you?
Fine, thanks. Uh, the judge
is being very kind,
and he bumped us up.
- Good.
- Hello, Ivan.
(in Russian): Ivan, it's Michael
Sharnov, your father's attorney.
- Remember me?
- You don't remember Uncle Michael?
(mutters in Russian)
(in English): He's a little
bit tired. It's okay.
- I see.
- Tired?
And this is the...
The lucky lady?
- Okay. And who is this?
- Him we're gonna need.
(in Russian): Just holding.
(in English): Okay, I don't know
what that means,
and I don't want to know.
Let's go.
Get your I.D.'s ready.
(in Russian): I talked to him
and it's clear he wants this done.
But does he know that
his son is intoxicated?
He's not intoxicated,
he just woke up.
(in English): Toros, please.
Come on, man.
I'm not gonna risk my license
because you can't...
You want to keep working
for Zakharov family or not?
Oh.
Mr. Sharnov.
- Consider yourself very fortunate.
- Your Honor.
We have a light
calendar today, so, um...
...what's your urgent matter?
Your Honor,
we are here to file a complaint
and request for an immediate annulment
of a union that took place under duress.
- Ivan Zakharov and Anora Mikheeva married...
- Duress, my fucking ass.
Whoa!
I'm sorry. I'm sorry, Your Honor,
but this is bullshit. It's bullshit.
- Your Honor, I...
- These men are trying to...
You got to stop. You can't...
You can't talk this way.
Okay. I'm sorry.
They're trying...
- Do not fucking touch me.
- Who's this man in the camel coat?
- Who are you, sir?
- Security, please get this man away from me.
- Mr. Sharnov, is he with you?
- Get the f... Get him away from me.
- Officer, take... take him back to his seat.
- Come on, come on.
Thank you, Officer. I appreciate it.
- Okay, have a seat. Have a seat.
- I'm sorry.
And thank you, Your Honor.
I really appreciate it.
- You're welcome. Keep that tone.
- Okay.
- You're welcome.
- Your Honor, clearly...
my husband is intoxicated right now.
- He is in no place to be making any decisions.
- Uh, Your Honor, objection. She shouldn't be talking.
- Don't listen to her, please.
- Camel coat, sit down.
Down!
- He is clearly intoxicated, Your Honor.
- Why is she talking?
Your Honor, what I have been
trying to explain to you,
we got married legally.
Objection, Your Honor. They're not legally
married, and she shouldn't be talking.
- I shouldn't be talking?
- Camel man, sit down.
My apologies.
Your Honor, I-I apologize. My client
doesn't know what she's saying. I'm sorry.
- And they are trying to force us
to get an annulment...
- I-I am intoxicated.
- Sit quietly or begone. Please.
We got legally married at a legitimate
marriage place in Las Vegas, Nevada.
- Miss, please keep it down. Keep it down.
- It is real. We have a marriage certificate.
- Mr. Sharnov, take charge now.
- We're not gonna be signing--
They got married in Nevada?
- So what?
- (in Russian): We can't get it annulled here.
What?
(in Russian): We can file for one but
if you want this now, you have to go there.
(in English): Mr. Sharnov. Last time.
Are you fucking kidding me?
- (in English): Folks, get out. Okay that's it.
- (in Russian): My stomach hurts.
No, no, no. Officer, get him
off the table before he throws up.
Fuck!
Get him off the table.
Get him out.
- Fuck!
- Everyone out of the court.
- Clear the court, Officer.
- Come on, time to go.
Officer, clear the court, please.
Why did you go to Vegas?
Why not here in New York?
Guys, you don't have to
fucking drag him around.
Why not here in New York?
Can you explain to me?
We got fucking married in Vegas
because that's where he proposed to me.
So now we're gonna go see your parents.
You're gonna explain to them--
- that you went to Vegas without my permission.
- No, we're not fucking going anywhere.
You understand?
Because it wasn't my fault.
- You, too. You're gonna have to tell them that you...
- Oh, no, I am not going fucking anywhere.
- ...you took him to Vegas without my permission.
- I am not going... No, no, no, no.
This is not my fault.
Get in the car. Get in the car.
I'm not getting in the fucking car,
'cause we're fucking done here.
- And I want my fucking ring now, motherfucker.
- (in Russian): You got a ticket?
Vanya, you don't have to get...
Vanya, get out of the car, okay?
You do not have to
listen to these people.
Okay? You don't have to listen to them
because you're an adult, Vanya.
You're an adult, okay?
(in Russian): You had one job
and you get a ticket?
I must have dozed off.
(in Russian): You are an adult.
You are an adult.
I just need to talk with my parents.
(in English): Okay.
Okay. All right.
We'll talk to your parents, okay?
We're gonna talk
to your parents,
and they're gonna understand
because they love you.
- (in Russian): Get in.
- What happened?
They got married in Vegas,
that's what happened.
(in English): They love you, and
they're gonna understand, okay?
Vanya, okay? Right?
- They're gonna understand, right?
- Get in the car.
- (in Russian): What are we going to do now?
- This is a never-ending nightmare...
- (in English): Right, Vanya?
Right?
Get in the car.
I want him clean
and presentable in ten minutes.
And, you, behave.
(in Russian): Once,
this idiot and his friends decided
to swim in Kool-Aid.
Vanya.
Do you know what is it?
It's a juice.
They were stoned
and poured four pounds
of Kool-Aid in the pool.
They destroyed the whole system.
Eighty-seven thousand dollars
in damages.
Hello, Galina Stepanovna.
Where is he?
(in English): Okay.
Showtime.
(in Russian): Nikolai Zakharov,
how was your flight?
Face down, ass up.
I have some bad news.
Go on.
- You're not going to be happy.
- I'm already not happy.
What?
Vanya. Vanya.
(in Russian): What's wrong with
you? Look at me.
Are you drunk?
Damn...
Garnik, he's drunk.
Yes, Galina Stepanovna,
he's not sober,
but it's not our fault.
Mom, I got it,
I'm already embarrassed.
- So, you're embarrassed?
- Yes.
So, you're embarrassed?
You made our family
a national disgrace.
Galina Zakharova,
I'm Anora.
It's so wonderful
to finally meet you.
It's such an honor
to be Ivan's wife
and a part
of your beautiful family.
(in English): Ivan is not
your husband,
and you are not part
of this family.
And your Russian is
embarrassing.
- (in Russian): Is this from the new collection?
- Yes, new collection.
(in English): Uh, ma'am?
Ma'am?
Yes?
Vanya and I, we are in love,
and we would like you
to accept that.
Vanya is not in love with you.
Understand?
And we will not
accept it, okay?
Galina.
(in Russian): Toros has
something to tell you.
(in English): Fuck.
You are all idiots.
Vanya, we cannot get
on the fucking plane right now.
Toros, we will discuss
your future in our company.
Vanya, why are you listening
to your fucking parents?
What the fuck
is wrong with you?
Vanya, we have to talk
right fucking now, okay?
(in Russian): Kolya,
hang up the phone already!
(in English): Vanya, we have to
fucking talk.
No, no, no, no.
Go back to the plane.
(in Russian): I want us refueled
and in the air in ten minutes.
(in English): Vanya, fucking
look at me. Vanya.
Vanya, be a fucking man
and talk to me!
(in Russian): Is it necessary to
take the night butterfly with us?
Yes, both parties
must be present.
(in English): What do you want
me to say?
Can you understand
that now we must go
in the fucking plane
and fly to fucking Vegas?
Get it?
You get it?
So we're getting a divorce?
You...
Of course! Are you stupid?
(in Russian): Ivan, hurry up!
One second.
(in English): And thank you...
...for making my last trip
to America so fun.
Yeah? You had fun?
Yeah.
Let's go.
(in Russian): Where is she?
I don't know, there.
(in English): Board the plane now.
No.
No, I'm not doing that.
You are getting on this plane,
and you are getting divorced.
Yeah, we're gonna get
a fucking divorce,
but, uh, first,
I'm getting a lawyer.
Then I'm gonna sue Ivan
and you,
and I'm gonna walk away
with fucking half
because I didn't sign a prenup.
Do that,
and you'll lose everything.
Any money you may have--
although I doubt
you have much--
will be gone.
Do you have a house?
Do you have a car?
All gone.
Your life and the lives
of your family and friends,
everything will be destroyed.
(quiet chatter in Russian)
(in Russian): You want to talk
about it now?
- Yes.
- Because I don't.
Please show some respect,
I'm hungover.
If we were your age, and if
we had everything we wanted...
Listen, you little shit.
Next week,
you start working.
Understand, little shit?
Why do you need me there?
Maybe it's not the right moment
but I just want to say...
I'm very happy to finally
be able to spend time
with your wonderful family...
Thank you so much
for trusting me and Toros...
Stop it, get out of here.
Are you crazy?
I want to say a couple
of nice things to them.
Better you married a man.
So what if I married a man?
Do you think that can't happen?
Then what kind of freedom
can we talk about?
If I can't
potentially marry a man?
- Galina Stepanovna, I just...
- Listen!
I'm sorry, I just want to
use this moment...
...to say thank you...
Don't interfere!
We are having a family discussion.
So you think it's normal?
Everything that happened
is normal?
How did you end up in Vegas?
(in English): I understand...
and forgive you what you did.
(in Russian): I just bought a ticket
and flew to Vegas! Why can't I do that?
- Who gave you permission?
- Who would forbid me?
(in English): Great.
I'm so grateful
for your forgiveness.
(in Russian): Why can't I just
fly to Vegas?
Because you went to study.
Not to party,
drink and get hungover.
Why make a tragedy out of it?
What do you want from me?
Do you want me to apologize?
Just kill me, mom!
What did I do? I just spent
time with an escort.
I just spent a week with her.
So what's the big deal?
Why are you making this
such a big deal?
This isn't our family's
biggest problem.
Sit!
It's not going to be
a fucking problem.
I breast-fed you!
(in English): I'm fucking glad
to be divorcing your sorry ass.
You are fucking pathetic, man.
Are you seriously?
You're a pathetic motherfucker.
Fucking pathetic.
- Blyat, no.
- See?
(in Russian): You hurt your
mother so much!
I gave you everything.
Kolya,
give me your hand, please.
(in English): I'm just
going to need some signatures.
If I could just
get that back from...
Actually, if I could just
hang on to all...
- Could I just... Thank you.
- Okay, question.
- Okay. Yes, of course.
- What this mean?
We don't need
to worry about that.
- That's for the judge, so...
- Are you sure?
Um... Very sure.
Okay, so we're just gonna need
some signatures here.
So there you go,
and this one will be for...
(in Russian): Come here.
(in English): Sorry, I'm gonna
mispronounce your name.
- Sign.
- So, Anora Mikheeva,
I just need
your signature as well.
Thank you. Oh, oh.
There you are.
Where the red box is.
Sign, please.
And then--
oh, sorry-- just one more.
Um...
Great.
Oh. Oh, um...
May I have my I.D.?
You can.
All right. Let's go. Come on.
(in Russian): This may be
out of line
but I think it'd be appropriate
if Ivan apologizes.
Don't pay attention to him.
He is tired.
He also drank on
an empty stomach on the plane.
He helped us all night.
Listen here...
My son won't apologize
to anyone. Is that clear?
Of course.
(in English): 'Cause your son
is a fucking pussy.
What?
What? What?
Did you not hear what I said?
I said it's 'cause your
son's a fucking pussy.
(in Russian): Let's go.
(in English): And you are
a disgusting hooker.
And your son hates you so much
he married one to piss you off.
That's enough.
Yeah.
Yeah, your family
is fucking trash.
Is this my scarf?
Yeah, you want...
There. Go get your
little scarf, sweetie.
That's-that's enough. Let's go.
Oh, I'm leaving. I'm leaving.
- Okay. Let's go.
- You know what?
(in Russian): What are you
laughing at?
(in English): Why don't you take
your fucking coat, too?
That's enough. Let's go.
- Thank you so much, ma'am.
- You're very welcome. Um...
Goodbye, America.
Okay.
It's for you.
- Present.
- Oh, gosh.
No, I couldn't.
Thank you so...
Wait, is-is this real?
Take them to
McCarran Airport, domestic.
Igor is gonna take you back.
You can stay in
the house tonight,
but you got to be
out of there in the morning.
And he'll pay you
when the bank opens.
Go.
And thank you.
And it is starting to stick,
as well.
We'll show you a live look
at the roads in a little bit,
but officials that we've talked
with today say they are ready
for whatever Mother Nature
brings the next few days.
We got thousands of sanitation brothers and
sisters coming in doing overtime tonight.
If it accumulates, we'll be clearing
snow and ice from the street.
Every highway,
every bike lane in the city.
We'll be out starting
a midnight shift tonight.
On Long Island,
the salt trucks...
Happy birthday to me.
Hmm?
Was today your birthday?
January is
National Blood Donor Month...
No.
...is urging people to donate.
Advocates say the winter months
are a crucial time...
Yesterday was my birthday.
The senior vice
president and chief of staff
at New York Blood Center,
Clarissa Heyward...
Yesterday was
your fucking birthday?
I was 30.
Mm.
Happy fucking birthday,
I guess.
Thank you.
I like Anora.
I mean, I like Anora
more than Ani.
Okay.
Says the fuck head named Igor.
Fucking Igor.
Stupid name.
No, it's a good name.
It means "varrior."
Warrior.
Yeah?
Igor means "hunchback weirdo,"
you fucking piece of shit.
Can you shut the fuck up, please?
"Touche."
- "Touche"?
- "Touche."
Touché?
Touché, motherfucker?
You know, you really should
try learning English
before attempting French.
Okay. Touché.
Yeah.
And your name is better?
No.
But what does it mean?
In America, we don't care
about that kind of stuff.
We don't give meaning to names.
It's... it's not a thing.
So, it means...
..."pomegranate fruit."
"Light."
Yeah, I'm not interested
in conversation, dude.
And "bright."
It's good that you're not
part of this family.
Did I ask for
your fucking opinion?
- No.
- No. Exactly.
I just tried to support you.
S-Support me?
Dude, you fucking assaulted me.
You... Fucking support?
- You... No, you...
- Oh. What?
No.
I didn't assault you.
You didn't...
You don't call that assault?
- No?
- No.
No, you're right. It's fucking
battery, as well as kidnapping
and fucking a million
other felonies, I'm sure.
- Fuck you, dude.
- (in Russian): But, I didn't assault you.
I was trying to calm you down,
so you didn't hurt yourself.
(in English): You fucking pinned
me to the ground.
You tied my fucking hands
behind my back.
You... you fucking gagged me.
Have you seen
the fucking bruises
on my legs and my fucking arms?
You fucking assaulted me,
you psychopath.
First, it's because
you have sensitive skin.
No, it's not.
It's because
you're fucking crazy.
And second,
because you're too crazy.
I mean "crazy, too."
But I can say
you're too crazy, too.
It's not funny, yeah.
Touché.
"Touche."
But, anyway,
you were not in danger
of injury or harm, right?
You know,
if Garnik wasn't there,
you'd have raped me,
guaranteed.
Raped?
No doubt.
Why... why would I
have raped you?
You have rape eyes.
Raped eyes?
Rape eyes.
You heard me.
You sick motherfucker
would've raped me.
Okay, uh, but I didn't want
to raped you.
Oh, yeah?
Why?
What?
What "why?"
Why wouldn't you have raped me?
Because I'm...
not a rapist.
Nope, 'cause you're
a faggot-ass bitch.
Here.
(in Russian): Goodnight.
Hey.
Don't tell Toros.
This car is very you.
Do you like it?
No.
It's my grandmother's.