[ Foreboding music ]
[ Radio announcer
speaking Russian ]
[ American accent ]
Hi. Julie Schofield.
Hello.
That thing does work properly,
does it?
Oh, it works just fine.
I want my words preserved
for posterity.
I won't miss a thing.
-Drink?
-Thanks very much.
No bourbon, I'm afraid.
Scotch.
Scotch would be great.
-Ice?
-Mm-hm.
Yes, of course.
I'm afraid so.
I've always wanted fame.
I've always liked the idea
of my name
going down in history.
Going down as a spy
for Russia?
Fame or infamy--
what does it matter?
I shan't be forgotten.
If my mother
could only see me now.
The last of the few.
It really was only a few?
Oh, there were plenty
of people
waiting to see
which way to jump.
Things only had to go
a little differently and...
well, you know.
But, yes, in practice
we were just a few.
A happy few.
"Band of brothers."
Shakespeare. "Henry V."
Our most patriotic king.
How big a band were you,
this "band of brothers"?
Some things have
to remain secret, even now.
You sure?
Certain, no less.
Background, dear lady,
is all I can give you.
The whole delightful, utterly
despicable English background.
JULIE: Well, I understand
the delightfulness, all right,
but not why you had
to despise it.
How someone of your class
and, well, background...
Should want to kick it
in the teeth?
Precisely.
MAN: You've no idea what...
life in England
in the 1930s was like.
Treason and loyalty,
they're all relative, you know?
Treason to what?
Loyalty to whom?
That's what matters.
♪ I vow to thee, my country
♪ All earthly things above
♪ Entire and
whole and perfect ♪
♪ The service of my love
♪ The love that
asks no question ♪
stands the test ♪
♪ That lays upon the altar
♪ The dearest and the best
♪ The love that never falters
♪ The love
that pays the price ♪
♪ The love that
makes undaunted ♪
♪ The final sacrifice
♪ And there's another country
♪ I've heard of long ago
♪ Most dear to them
that love her ♪
♪ Most great
to them that know ♪
[ Glass shatters ]
♪ We may not
count her armies ♪
see her King ♪
♪ Her fortress is
a faithful heart ♪
-[ Suspenseful music ]
-♪ Her pride is suffering
[ Creaking ]
♪ And soul by soul
and silently ♪
♪ Her shining bounds increase
♪ And her ways
are ways of gentleness ♪
Martineau! Robbins!
♪ And all her paths are peace
They shall grow not old
as we that are left grow old.
Age shall not weary them,
nor the years condemn.
At the going down of the sun,
and in the morning,
we will remember them.
ALL: We will remember them.
[ Bell chiming ]
Want to come and have lunch?
My parents are down.
That's very nice of you. Thanks.
-MAN 1: You were laughing.
-MAN 2: I was not.
-MAN 1: Giggling, then.
-MAN 2: I didn't utter a sound.
You were giggling silently.
I couldn't concentrate at all.
Jaffed.
Even a crusty old Tory like you,
Devenish,
must be able to see that it's
absolutely ludicrous
for 400 boys to line up and blub
for a lot of people
they never even knew.
What do you mean
they didn't know?
Who only died
in a businessman's war
because they were
too damn stupid
to shoot their superior officers
and start a revolution
like the Russians.
They werethe superior officers,
weren't they?
We could all see
who youwere thinking about.
Wharton! Wharton!
A lovely glass of sherry...
Yes, Barclay?
Take these round
to all the houses, please.
I want one on every noticeboard
before lunch.
Yes, Barclay.
What you forget is
all those people died for us.
They died for their class.
You aretheir class.
It's damn silly
to pretend you're not.
You're always
trying to be different.
What's wrong with
being different?
Well, you are.
I mean, you want to be elected
to be a God,
don't you, Devenish?
-Yes.
-They're different.
That's not what I mean.
[ Sighs ]
You wait.
My waistcoats are
going to be the most different
you've ever seen.
Why an intelligent person
like you
should want to be part
of a self-perpetuating
oligarchy--
It's a pity you have
to be a prefect
before you can be elected,
else I'd be wearing one now.
Oh, you'll make it next time.
Menzies will see to that.
Will l? That's the question.
I expect so.
Would you like to do the honors,
Barclay?
Yes, of course.
Well, I must say I think
that's the best service yet.
Yes, yes.
[ Indistinct chatter ]
[ Boys shouting ]
[ Piano playing ]
Boys!
Any of you seen Martineau?
[ Shouting resumes ]
[ Melancholy music ]
[ Bell chimes ]
Bennett, do
pull yourself together.
Funny even as though he
was there.
Not yet.
Any moment now,
the great oak doors of Longford
shall swing open
on their rusty hinges...
That door does need oiling.
[ Chuckles ]
BENNETT:
...and the glorious vision
will step forth here.
He'll stand a moment,
winsomely framed
in the tumescent archway.
Doing what?
Sniffing the wind.
Like a dappled deer.
-[ Laughs ]
-Oh, my God.
And then... then he'll shoot
a tender yet burning,
soft yet passionate glance
across the 300 yards
of sacred turf,
hoping against hope
that I shall be there
to receive it.
Hmm.
And I shall lay my heart
at his feet.
Must have enormous feet
if they'll stretch
from Longford's to here.
-Hello Menzies, want a peek?
-MENZIES: Thank you, no.
You seen Martineau?
No, I'm afraid I only have eyes
for one person
in the entire world.
-Any of you?
-Probably with his parents.
I don't think they came down.
Still, never mind.
Thanks.
No, thank you
for the good-humored restraint
with which you exercise
your power, Menzies.
It's not only not fair,
it's not even sensible.
Come on, Judd!
Our parents spend hundreds
of pounds a year
sending us to this prison
so we can be educated
and we spend the entire time
playing games.
Quite right too.
Games are good for Bolsheviks.
Teach you a bit of team spirit.
You could be quite good
at cricket
if you'd only try.
JUDD: I don't want to try.
I want to be left alone
so I can get on with my work.
[ Indistinct chatter ]
I hope you're not taking those
binos out of house, Bennett.
Then you hope in vain, Fowler.
Farcical's given me permission
to use them for nature study.
Who?
Farcical.
If you mean the Housemaster,
kindly use his proper name.
-You didn't.
-What?
Use his proper name.
His proper name is
Mr. Farquharson.
Are you trying to be clever
or something?
I don't have to try.
I am clever.
I've half a mind to ask Barclay
for permission to beat you.
Well, you've half a mind,
we can all agree on that.
-[ Laughing ]
-[ Yells ] Quiet!
Get changed, everybody.
Anyone late
for the house matches
will be up before Barclay
for six strokes.
ALL: Ooh!
[ Laughing ]
What you have to grasp,
Devenish,
is that Fowler is
precisely what
this school was designed
to produce.
Not empire builders--
dear me, no.
Building empires
needs imagination.
-Empire rulers.
-Oh, do dry up.
Fowler will go straight
from the King's African Rifles
into the Colonial Service--
you'll see.
-He'll end up with an OBE.
-And syphilis.
Bennett, do you mind?
He'll catch it off
a little native girl
who he'll visit after dark
in her steamy primeval hut.
And when he gets back
to his mildewed little wife
in Bexhill-on-the-Sea,
he won't be able
to look her in the face!
So, he'll turn her over
and...
For heaven's sake!
Serves her right
for marrying an imperialist
and an exploiter.
There's nothing wrong
with the Colonial Service...
"It's a perfectly
decent career."
Shut up!
There is nothing decent
about colonialism.
I don't see why you have
to be against everything.
I'm not. I'm for revolution.
All right, everyone!
Umpires for Longford's
versus Chancellors?
Oh, me, please.
Me and Judd.
All right.
I don't want to go and umpire.
Yes, you do. Come along.
[ Scattered applause ]
[ Melancholy music ]
MAN: Umpire!
Umpire, that was a wide.
No, it wasn't.
I couldn't possibly have
reached that.
Course you could.
You just didn't try.
It was practically
outside the white line.
Are you arguing with the umpire?
Because arguing with the umpire
is not school practice.
At least, it might be
in your house
but it certainly isn't in ours.
And since we beat you last week,
you can just shut up!
Play!
How's that!
Out!
[ Scattered applause ]
MAN: I think we should have
rung the muffled peal
after the dedication.
I don't see why we didn't.
MAN 2: Because we're not
good enough yet.
You don't have to be good
to run a muffled peal.
It's muffled.
No one can really tell.
I'll muffle you if
you don't shut up.
[ Indistinct chatter ]
Out! You lot-- go!
Out, all of you.
Spungin, you get a master.
Now!
MAN: Jesus, God! Did you see?
That was Martineau.
[ Indistinct chatter ]
[ Slams door ]
[ Sighs ]
This place.
This place!
These things should be
left to the Gods.
He'd never have done it
if he hadn't been sent
to see the headmaster.
He knew that meant expulsion.
Yes, but once a master had
caught him, Delahay,
it was out of our hands.
Especially as it was
with a man from another house.
The Gods could have
dealt with it.
That's what we're here for.
Prefects handle house matters.
The Gods deal with
everything else.
And masters should mind
their own business.
Even the mighty Gods
can't expel people, Delahay.
Who needs people expelled?
You wouldn't have
let Martineau stay?
DELAHEY: Of course.
But he wouldn't have been able
to sit down for a week
after the Gods had
finished with him.
But if we start expelling
everyone who indulges--
Yes. Well, there we are,
aren't we?
The tone of this whole house
has simply gone to pieces
and you, Delahay,
are mainly responsible.
-Fowler, please.
-Yes. Shut up, Fowler.
But it's precisely attitudes
like that--
Will you shut up!
Now, we're all, I know,
very distressed about
what's happened.
Personally...
[ Sighs ]
well, I've always tried
to make everyone feel
he can come to me at any time,
whatever the problem.
But he must have been desperate.
It probably wouldn't have
made any difference.
But if he'd talked to me,
to you... anyone!
However,
we have to try and overcome
our personal feelings.
And remember
our responsibility to the house.
Hear, hear.
We don't want people rushing off
confessing things,
which, quite frankly, they'd
do better to keep to themselves.
If people have things
to confess,
I think they
should confess them.
A thorough clear out is what
this house needs.
Thing is, I would like there
to be a House here next term
for me to be Head of.
Well, I'm sure it's not nearly
on that scale.
Well, anyway, wouldn't you like
to start with a clean house?
Quite frankly, I doubt if
such a thing
as a clean house exists,
in this school or any other.
What about a special session
of house prayers?
FOWLER: Almighty
and most merciful Father.
ALL: "Almighty
and most merciful Father,
"we have erred and strayed
from thy ways like lost sheep.
"We have followed too much
the devices and desires
of our own hearts."
[ Prayer continues ]
If you ask me, it all comes of
having masters who
aren't old boys.
I see.
Well, an old boy
would have more sense
than to go prowling around
gymnasium changing room.
Everybody knows what
goes on there.
Look, you'd better
watch yourself, Bennett.
Discretion is going to be
the better part of valor
around here.
Wouldn't you say?
May I go and talk to Judd,
please?
If you think you
can get a word in.
[ Prayer continues ]
"Thou shalt not lie with mankind
as with womankind."
"lt is abomination."
"Neither shalt thy lie
with any beast
to defile thyself therewith."
"Neither shall any woman
stand before a beast
to lie down there too."
"lt is confusion."
"Defile not ye yourselves
in any of these things."
-Alone at last!
-Get off.
[ Sighs ]
-I'll get you one day.
-No, you won't.
Yes, I will. Everyone gives in
in the end.
It's Bennett's Law.
-I won't give in.
-Well, you're not normal.
BENNETT: My God,
that was quick. Who did it?
Matron.
Poor Martineau.
The reason everyone gives in
in the end
is they get lonely
doing it on their own.
-They long for company.
-Well, I don't.
Not your sort, anyway.
That's why my mother's marrying
this awful Colonel person.
Arthur.
It couldn't just possibly be
that she loves him?
Out of the question.
He's got one of those
awful little moustaches.
He's ghastly.
Almost as much of a loather
as my father was.
You mean even you
would draw the line?
Don't be revolting.
He's a grown-up.
Of course.
And it's all just
a passing phase.
Exactly. Just like you
being a communist.
Ha, ha.
-Judd...
-Hmm?
-You and your usherette.
-What about her?
Is it really so different?
From what?
Boys.
Well, how would I know?
I've only ever had a girl.
What is it, Wharton?
I don't know what to do
about Spungin's water.
Leave him to pass it
on his own...
and pour it out
and go to bed.
He makes a terrible fuss
if his water's cold.
He said he'd report me
to Barclay.
Then go fill up the jug
with new hot water,
bring it back to the dorm,
cover it with a flannel,
and leave it by Spungin's bed,
all right?
Thanks, Judd.
[ Faucet running ]
-Hurry up, Wharton.
-Yes, Delahay.
God, "Das Kapital"
looks difficult.
Well, I haven't found anything
I couldn't
understand eventually.
And if they taught us
any economics here
instead of Tudors
and bloody Stuarts...
Marx should be a set book
for the sixth.
They shouldn't leave us
to fight our way through it
on our own.
And under the blankets.
[ Sighs ]
Barclay confiscated
another torch last night.
-How many is that?
-Twelve.
Twelve torches taken away
to stop me getting the education
I'm supposed to be here for.
God, if our parents only knew
what actually went on here.
They do know.
The fathers, anyway.
[ Solemn music ]
Bennett, what the hell
are you doing?
Go to bed.
[ Choir sings ]
[ Door slams ]
♪ My kingdom sails
♪ and grows forever
♪ Dear Lord, thy creatures all
♪ Lord, I swear
[ Bell chiming ]
[ Intriguing music plays ]
What's this?
I'm very sorry, Fowler,
I thought l--
Juniors aren't required
to think, Wharton.
They are required
to obey orders
and I told you
to make cup shine.
Yes, Fowler.
Well...
...not bad except
for that smear.
Get it off.
Yes, Fowler.
BENNETT: You know, if you are
going to be
in the south of France,
you might as well look around
for a nice little villa
for August.
Might l?
Why not just
extend the honeymoon?
I could pop down
on the Blue Train
just as soon as school's over.
I see.
I only want to bring one friend.
It won't be too expensive.
I don't think Arthur
would like Judd, darling.
I don't mean Judd, darling.
Anyway, Arthur thinks
everyone under the age of 18
is either a pinko or a pansy,
so it won't make much difference
who I bring, will it?
[ Laughing ]
You know, I'm awfully worried.
You see,
it is an established fact
that people who go around
suspecting vice in others
are highly suspect themselves.
But Arthur's the most normal man
I've ever known!
What better disguise?
Listen, there's still time
to call it off.
Come on, let's stop the car.
You really shouldn't
joke about it, Guy.
Not after that poor boy.
I suppose he
was dreadfully unpopular.
Martineau? No.
Well, I should thought
a boy like that--
Very well, better off dead,
no doubt about it.
Well, I have known
one or two of-- of those.
And they're never very happy,
you know?
Mummy!
Oh, they can be very amusing,
but, uh-- Oh, here we are!
[ Birds singing ]
[ Organ music
plays in distance ]
[ Indistinct chatter ]
[ Laughing ]
If you ask me,
public schools go on too long.
[ Laughs ]
Arthur means the fees.
It's not just the fees.
I mean, look at Guy.
He's not a boy anymore.
He's a young man.
-Aren't you, old chap?
-Rather.
Well then, I think you
should leave
at the end of this term.
Take a job for a year or two.
Go around the world.
You must be mad.
School's just getting
to the good bit.
ARTHUR: I think you need
to find out a bit about life
before you go up
to the varsity.
I second that.
Why not the army?
Why not, indeed? First class.
I mean, one learns
so much about life
in the army.
-Yes.
-Killing people.
Excuse me.
Mummy!
How dare you talk like that?!
How dare you plan
to send me around the world
without even consulting me?
-It's all right, lvy.
-Oh, excuse me.
It was only an idea, darling.
It was just
that Arthur thought--
Arthur!
We only want to do what's
best for you, Guy.
If either of you
seriously thinks
I would leave now,
after 10 years of hard labor
in the salt mines
of prep and public school.
-You want to stay?
-I'm going to be a God, Mummy.
What?
[ Scoffs ]
The school elite.
The creme de la creme.
Oh, yes. Of course.
It's the only thing that's made
the last 10 years endurable--
the thought that one day,
I'm gonna be top
of the whole stinking heap!
Well, if that's how you feel,
darling.
I really must get back
to my wedding.
[ Horn blares ]
[ Gentle piano music ]
Would you care for a drink, sir?
Ah, yes. A glass of sherry,
thank you.
Very good, sir.
[ Chuckles ]
Gosh, you are brave.
Did you think I wouldn't come?
I, um, didn't know.
I hoped you would.
Well...
...here I am.
I, um, hope you're hungry.
I'm ravenous.
I've had nothing to eat but
a bit of caviar and toast
all day long.
-Doesn't sound bad.
-Oh! It's awful.
Listen, l, um...
...I can't call you Harcourt.
-My name is Guy.
-I know.
I found out.
-Mine's James.
-James.
[ Chuckles ]
That's a very nice name.
You know,
I nearly lost my nerve.
[ Laughs ]
I passed a couple of masters
on the way here.
Oh, don't worry about them.
They won't come in here.
They can't afford to.
Listen, then, do you like
smoked salmon?
I love it.
I-- I love...
...I-- I love food and drink
and...
[ Snickers ]
Should we get terribly,
terribly drunk?
-If you like!
-[ Laughs ]
The only thing is, though,
sometimes when I get drunk, l--
I say things I shouldn't.
Still, we ought to have
something to celebrate with,
oughtn't we?
WAITER: Your sherry, sir.
Are you ready to order?
Ah, not yet.
Bring me the wine list,
would you?
Here we are, sir.
We've a nice little hock,
if you care for hock, sir.
No, no, no-- champagne.
I've been drinking it all day
and it doesn't do
to mix one's drinks.
What's the best champagne
you've got?
The Moet, I suppose, sir.
It's been a most
unfortunate affair, of course,
but on the whole,
the school has not
come out of it too badly.
For that, we must be
extremely grateful
to Barclay and Henderson
for the admirable way they've
handled their respective houses
through what could have been
a most serious crisis.
ALL: Hear, hear.
We all know how quickly
scandal can spread.
As a matter of fact,
my father won't have
anyone in the firm from Harrow
because of what he's heard.
Well, I can't imagine him
wanting anyone from Harrow,
anyway.
But we do still have to
make it absolutely clear
to the outside world
this was
a completely isolated incident.
I cannot emphasize
too strongly--
that nothing even remotely
like it
can ever be allowed
to occur again.
All right?
GUY: My real father died
when I was 14.
JAMES: How awful.
It was the Easter hol's.
I was reading one night
in my bed when...
I heard the most
peculiar noise--
a sort of...
a sort of muffled squeaking.
Couldn't think what it was,
at first.
Sounded... trapped or something.
So l-- I went down the passage
and it seemed to be coming
from my parents' room
and there was a light
under the door so...
...I assumed...
none of my business.
Gosh.
Then l-- I distinctly heard
my mother say, "Help."
[ Whispers ]
Help.
It was terribly eerie.
Complete silence
and there it was again. "Help."
I-- I didn't know what to do.
No.
I went down the passage
and I knocked loudly on the door
and I said, "Are you all right?"
And she said,
"Guy, quick, help."
She sounded
absolutely at her last gasp.
So I--I went in.
Listen, are you sure you
really want to hear this?
No. No, not if you don't
want to tell me.
No, no, I do.
My...
my father had--
had a heart attack.
-Right in the middle of--
-No!
Happens all the time,
apparently.
Well, what better way to go
for the man,
but for my mother...
Well... she was trapped.
How absolutely incredible!
It was awful.
My mother kept her eyes closed
the whole time.
Only wish I could've done--
I was--
It was so embarrassing.
God, it must have been.
She never really
looked me in the eye again.
See... I always hated him.
He was...he was vile.
My mother...
Always been very fond
of my mother.
But, well...
things haven't been
quite the same
between us since...
...since then.
Perhaps, that's why
she married again?
Perhaps it is.
Never thought about that.
[ Sighs ]
You know what I'd like
to do sometime?
Ride around Europe
on a bicycle.
With a tent.
Sharing it with someone
you really like.
Hmm.
I've never spent the night
with anyone.
-Have you?
-No.
Must be wonderful.
Have you ever been in love?
No. Have you?
No.
[ Sniffs ]
Must get in.
-[ Whispers ] Goodnight.
-Goodnight.
[ Sighs ]
Fetch!
BOY:
Come here. Come here!
Susie!
Come here!
Sit!
[ Grunts ]
[ Grunts again ]
All right, Bennett,
I've got you this time.
Oh! God, I thought you
were Fowler.
[ Grunting ]
Hmm!
[ Closing window ]
That drainpipe's
a bloody disgrace.
I must have a word
with the Housemaster.
Sh!
Tommy...
May I call you Tommy, Tommy?
If you want.
Oh! I'm in love.
That's not exactly news.
Well, I-- I don't mean in love.
I mean--
I mean in love.
You're drunk.
You know, till now,
it's just been a game but...
...now!
What are you doing here?
I thought you didn't have to
be back till tomorrow?
And why are you
dressed like a God?
Um, practicing for next term.
Well, you'd better be careful
not to get any more food
on that waistcoat then.
-It's grubby already.
-Oh, damn the waistcoat!
I've been waiting for this
ever since my...
Nothing's ever going to
be as good again
till I'm ambassador in Paris.
Don't be so pathetic.
Life is ladders, Tommy,
that's all.
[ Sighs ]
Prep school to here.
First Form to sixth.
Second assistant
junior undersecretary
to ambassador in Paris.
Sir Guy Bennett, KCVO, KCMG.
Contemptible sycophant
in the service
of the bourgeoisie.
What?
It's what Lenin called
the renegade Karl Kautsky.
Did he indeed?
Because he substituted
eclecticism and sophistry
for dialectics.
Oh, well, that is bad.
Groveling about the kings
and queens,
walking backwards!
Kissing hands.
You're utterly imbued
with the spirit of servility,
that's what he'd have said.
You mean he wouldn't have
liked me?
No.
What about James?
Who's James?
Harcourt. His name's James.
Quite frankly,
I don't think he'd have
cared much for the pair of you.
God! First, they take away
my torches.
Then when I take my life--
or at least my bum-- in my hands
and creep here to do some work,
they send me you.
This place is impossible.
-Goodnight.
♪ Who stole my heart away
Huh!
♪ Who makes me dream all day
♪ Dreams I know will
never come true ♪
♪ Seems as though
I'll ever be blue ♪
[ Indistinct chatter ]
All up!
Who's last?
Wharton.
Find Menzies and ask him
to come to me in the garden,
right away.
-Yes, Barclay.
-Go on!
-BOY: How's that!
-[ Scattered applause ]
-Jim, good.
-What is it?
I'm sorry, I've just discovered
something awful.
Mr. Farquharson's thinking
of asking Fowler to stay on.
To be Head of House
instead of you.
What?
You see, the house isn't
going to have
enough prefects next term.
Why not? What do you mean?
It'll only be you and Bennett.
Two's not enough.
-What about Devenish?
-He's leaving.
His parents take a very dim view
of the Martineau business.
They want him to
go to agricultural college
straightaway.
And as Fowler's
a year senior to you
and as Judd refuses
to be a prefect...
Judd!
Unless you can get him
to take a more
responsible attitude,
you're a man short, Jim.
Fat chance!
I'm terribly sorry.
He's your only hope.
[ Scattered applause ]
The answer is no.
I wish you'd reconsider.
I wish you'd let me work.
Look, I wouldn't ask you to do
anything you didn't want to do.
You just have to go through
the motions, that's all.
Prep duty, dorm, roll call.
Nothing, really.
Menzies, have you the makings
of a politician?
I'm only speaking
as one friend to another.
You have! Well, well.
Look, you don't want Fowler
to be Head of House
any more than I do.
He'll make your life
a complete misery.
Too bad.
But I still refuse
to collaborate
with a system of oppression.
Oh, for God's sake!
GUY: Oh, my God!
I can't look.
Are you all right, Bennett?
Shall I get Matron?
No. It was his smile.
It-- it made me dizzy.
Everything beautiful is
slightly lopsided.
There's a hollow
at the base of his throat
that makes me want to
pour honey all over him
and lick it off--
-Bennett!
-Hmm?
Wharton, this washing up
was supposed to
be finished 10 minutes ago.
Bennett, you come with me.
Have you completely lost
your mind?!
Yes, actually.
After all that's happened,
you talk like that
in front of a junior?!
-He doesn't understand.
-Of course he does!
You'd better take a pull
on yourself, Guy.
I'd rather do it with you.
For God's sake, will you stop?
You've got to start showing
a little responsibility.
What on earth are you
talking about?
You don't know
what's going on.
-Devenish may be leaving.
-Well?
Fowler may be going to stay on
as Head of House.
[ Sighs ]
It can't be true...
Unfortunately, it can.
I need your help, Guy.
It's all Judd's fault
for refusing to be a prefect.
I want you to talk to him.
You're much more his friend
than I am.
Shouldn't think
there's a hope in hell.
Well, there must be.
Remember, if Fowler becomes
Head of House,
he certainly won't put you up
for the Gods.
I'm relying on you, Guy.
Prove your worth for once.
Alright, Devenish,
let's have a look.
Not bad.
Not bad at all.
-Bennett.
-Where?
Don't be silly.
Let me see your uniform.
Well, it won't do.
It won't do at all.
What's wrong with it?
Do you call those creases?
Well, I'm not very handy
with the iron, actually.
Do them again.
Do everything again.
I'm not having you
let down the whole house.
Won't be the whole house,
Fowler, I mean...
...the juniors aren't
in the corps.
Nor is Judd.
Don't mention Judd to me.
Judd?
Judd.
Judd, Judd, Judd, Judd, Judd...
The moon shines bright.
On such a night as this...
...when the sweet wind
did gently kiss the trees
and they did make no noise...
..on such a night, Bennett,
methinks,
mounted the Gascoigne walls
and sighed his soul toward
the Longford tents...
...where Harcourt
lay that night.
I can't do it.
I just cannot be a prefect.
Why not?
I do have my reputation,
you know?
[ Scoffs ]
Your what?
I'm a school joke,
I quite realize that.
But I am, don't you think,
a respected joke?
I do at least stick
to my principles.
People appreciate that.
If I abandoned them now...
No. Sorry.
You don't care
what people think.
About me personally, no.
But they'll say
it was all a fake.
No... No.
Say, "That's what we
said all along.
It's all just a form
of showing off."
On the contrary,
they'll see the means
justifying the ends.
What could be more communist
than that?
They'll think it was all a fake.
They'll think all communists
are fake.
That's what they say
about Stalin.
Now, what's that Stalin
got to do with it?
That man is sweating blood
night and day
to drag his country
into the 20th century
and create a whole new concept
of society at the same time.
I can't stand it when
people sneer at him.
-Jokes about the Tsar...
-Quick! Quick!
Thought I might find you here.
It's all right.
I couldn't sleep either.
That bloody dog of Wharton's
gets on my nerves.
I should like to
go walkies myself.
Want to come?
I'm not exactly dressed
for walking, actually.
I was working.
Well...
I won't disturb you.
Would you like my torch?
It is yours.
Thanks.
This drainpipe's
still all right, isn't it?
Afraid I can't tell you.
-Barclay...
-Yes?
Is the Housemaster really
going to ask Fowler to stay on?
Things do get about, don't they?
-Is he?
-I don't know.
To tell you the truth,
I don't actually care anymore.
I've had enough.
I haven't slept for nights
and nights.
Really?
Quite frankly,
I've got to the pitch
where I wonder why we bother.
-Who?
-Any of us.
Why we keep
the whole thing going.
Sometimes I think none of us
really believes in it.
Of course you don't
believe in it.
You're afraid to think
of anything better.
Do you think so?
You know perfectly well
it's all nonsense.
You know it's positively wrong,
but you daren't act
on your knowledge.
You don't accept
the logical consequences.
Is that it?
You're afraid for your status,
your money, your class.
Everything that makes
your life safe and comfortable
and privileged.
You're afraid to live
like an ordinary human being.
Perhaps I am.
Yes.
Leave the window open for me,
won't you?
My God...
...that man's
really cracking up.
Liberals always do
under pressure.
You know...
you're a really hard man, Tommy.
I've no time for him.
He just wants a nice easy life
with a nice easy conscience
and he's got no right to either.
I'm going to bed.
Are you going to join
the fight against Fowler?
I hate him so much,
it's difficult to be objective.
Well, the objective
fact in this case
is that Fowler
is absolutely objectionable.
Please, Tommy.
If you appeal to me
as your friend,
I'll never forgive you.
Menzies tried that.
I didn't mind it from him.
He isn't a friend.
I'll think about it, but...
Oh, God, and I'll be in a rage
all day tomorrow.
Ah. Jacker Pot.
Militarism from 12
to half past four.
Little boys all dressed up
and playing soldiers. God!
Tommy...
if I lose his Jacker Pot...
...would you agree
to become a prefect then?
If you lose his Jacker Pot,
you probably won't be
a prefect yourself.
-Goodnight.
[ Foreboding music ]
[ Sighs ]
Guy?
Careful! Barclay's about.
I know. He nearly saw me.
Thought I'd have a heart attack.
All right, thank you, Wharton.
Now my sash.
Good.
Good luck, Fowler.
Thank you, Wharton.
Fall in!
Battalion! Attention!
Battalion ready
for inspection, sir.
Thank you, sergeant major.
How's your father?
-Very well, thank you, sir.
-Good. Good.
BARCLAY: Why did you do it,
Bennett?
-BENNETT: Do what?
-You lost us the Pot!
Oh, surely not just me,
not all on my own?
You were far and away
the worst-dressed soldier
on the whole parade.
I'm not a soldier,
I'm a schoolboy and so are you.
You're a disgrace to the house.
You're a disgrace
to the entire school.
Oh, I'm hopeless with Brasso.
I can only get
a really good shine
on my nails. Look!
Let me see your belt!
You want me to undress
in front of all these people?
Give it to me!
[ Takes off belt ]
I reckon that's worth
a full six strokes.
[ Sighs ]
All right, Fowler.
You can go ahead.
Thank you.
Come on, Bennett.
I appeal to Barclay
and Delahay.
Of course.
It's my right.
They're our House Gods.
It won't do you any good.
It's still my right.
All right. If you insist.
-If you let him off--
-We won't.
Bennett's appealed
to House Gods.
Gosh.
I wonder what they'll do
to him.
Give him a jolly good beating,
I should think.
Well, um...
I just thought you
ought to know...
that if one stroke
of Fowler's cane
lands on my ass,
I shall go straight
to Mr. Farquharson, and, uh...
give him the names
of all the people I've...
...done it with
over the past three years,
that's all.
Bennett, you can't do this.
Oh, I shall begin at the top.
Well... can l, um... go now?
Bloody little tart!
You never thought it
particularly bloody at the time.
My God, I'll thrash you myself!
It's only a game, Delahay.
There's no need
to get so excited.
I thought sportsmen
were supposed to be good losers.
[ Solemn music ]
I'd never have dared do that.
It's only cheating.
Everyone cheats here
the whole time.
I don't.
I bet you do.
When you've got the chance.
I don't even crib!
[ Sighs ]
I don't mean work,
I mean games.
Sportsmanship.
It's all hypocrisy.
Well, we all know
what goes on
in the scrum when
the ref's not looking.
[ Chuckles ]
Oh, well...
if that's what you mean.
Mmm.
Yes, of course.
It'll be getting light soon.
Mmm.
I must be going.
-[ Organ music]
-[ Choir sings ]
♪ I was glad when they
said unto me ♪
♪ We will go into
the house of the Lord ♪
♪ Our feet shall stand
in thy gates ♪
♪ O Jerusalem
[ Choir continues singing hymn ]
[ Organ music swells ]
[ Scattered applause ]
Come on.
You know,
what I really hate
about cricket...
is it's such a damn good game.
[ Laughs ]
Ah, Judd's Paradox.
Of course,
cricket is a fundamental part
of the capitalist conspiracy,
hmm?
Of course.
One only has
to observe the scene.
There's the proletariat
forced to labor in the field
while the bourgeoisie
indulges in the pleasures
of batting and bowling.
Quite.
I mean, there's every reason
to suppose...
...that the game
ultimately derives
from the wholly
unjustified right
of the medieval lord
to the unpaid labor
of villeins and serfs
at haymaking and harvest.
You know, you're really
beginning to get the idea.
Thanks.
Ah, there he is
at the school shop.
[ Sighs ]
Isn't he awesome, Tommy?
Drawing attention
to yourself again?
He's not even waving back.
[ Scattered applause ]
Course he's not.
You should learn
from his discretion.
Oh, if only I could.
[ Violin plays ]
So I really can't get you
to change your mind?
It's not so much me,
it's my father.
Quite frankly, when he asked me
what I'd be staying on for,
it was damned hard to say.
You might be
on the First Eleven next term?
It's a long time to wait
just on the off chance.
If I was going to be a God,
that would be one thing but...
as it is...
just being an ordinary prefect
doesn't really
make it worthwhile.
Sorry.
JUDD: By the way...
...I've decided that
the greatest happiness
of the greatest number
will best be achieved
if I do agree to be a prefect.
Tommy!
Stop it.
I shall insist on the terms
set forth by Menzies
but with one extra condition--
I shall refuse
to take house prayers.
GUY:
Oh, he won't care about that.
Oh, Tommy, my cup runneth over.
You really are
a hero of the people.
I'm going to award you
the Order of Lenin,
first class with oak leaves.
You know, if I wasn't in love
with James,
I'd be in love with you.
JUDD: Don't be so emotional.
It's a purely rational decision.
GUY: Go on.
Go tell and Menzies
before you change your mind.
-JUDD: All right, all right.
-GUY: He's in the music school.
-GUY: Go on. Hurry!
-JUDD: Going, going.
-Wharton!
-WHARTON: Yes, Bennett?
Do you want to earn yourself
another ice cream?
I wouldn't mind.
If you go to school shop,
you'll find a man
from Longford's there--
Harcourt.
-Do you know him?
-By sight.
Good. Give him this.
Here's sixpence.
Why are you so keen
on Harcourt?
If you really don't know,
I'm certainly not
going to tell you.
Now get along.
-[ Gasps ]
-Oh!
I'll have that,
if you don't mind,
Wharton.
Now, come on!
Give it to me!
All right, Wharton.
Thank you.
Thank you very much.
[ Violin plays ]
Menzies, can I have a word?
Yes, of course. What is it?
I've decided I am willing
to become a prefect--
[ Shouts ]
FOWLER: Menzies!
...but there are one
or two some conditions--
Menzies!
Look at this.
What is it?
I've got him this time.
He can't get away now.
I'm taking this straight
to Barclay.
What on earth's
that all about?
Just one moment, Judd.
We can discuss this later.
Devenish, do you think it would
make any difference
to your attitude,
or your father's attitude,
if you were to tell him you were
going to be in the Gods
next term, instead of Bennett?
I'm sure it would.
Perhaps you should
go and telephone him.
You mean there's a real chance?
[ Solemn music ]
BARCLAY: Wharton!
[ Knocking at the door ]
Tell Bennett to come
to Hall Table.
I can't do it.
What's the matter?
Lost your nerve?
All right, I'll do it.
Come on.
All right, Bennett.
Bend over.
[ Crack ]
[ Sobs ]
I don't understand.
Why didn't you
just use the blackmail again?
Because.
Because what?
Because if I'd
gone to Housemaster...
it'd all come out
about James.
So what?
We'd have both been expelled.
Lucky you.
I couldn't do that.
-I love him.
-Oh, come on, Guy.
Look, I'm not going
to pretend anymore.
I'm sick of pretending!
You think it's all a joke.
Well, it's not.
I am never going
to love women!
Don't be ridiculous!
Martineau knew that
about himself when he was 10.
He told me.
You can't possibly know
a thing like that at 10 or now.
Yes, you can.
Look, it doesn't...
come as any great revelation.
It's... more like admitting
to yourself
something you've
always known.
Owning up to yourself. It's...
It's a great relief...
in some ways.
You can't trust intuitions
like that.
Well, what else is there?
Are you a communist
because you read Karl Marx? No.
You read Karl Marx
because you know
you are a communist.
Well, I'm very sorry for you.
Thanks! If that's
how friends react.
I'm sorry.
You're quite right.
That was patronizing
and unforgivable.
But you couldn't help it,
could you?
Because in your heart of hearts,
like Barclay and Delahay
and Fowler and Menzies,
you still believe...
in spite of your talk
of equality and fraternity,
you still believe...
some people are better
than others
because of the way
they make love.
Well...
[ Sniffs ]
think of that for a lifetime.
Think of the names.
Pansy. Nancy. Fairy. Fruit.
Brown nose.
[ Sniffs ]
Look, um...
This hurts like hell. I'm--
I'm-- I'm gonna walk it off.
Coming?
Good, that's settled then,
Donald.
Thanks.
I mean, well, thanks.
Bennett can't complain.
I've warned him
time and again.
Oh, good. Here they are.
Wonderful news.
Devenish is staying on
after all.
It's most generous of you
to offer, Judd,
but you can keep your principles
untarnished now.
But I've a disappointment
for you, Bennett,
though it can hardly
come as a surprise
after recent events.
I'm afraid I shall be
nominating Devenish
for the Gods next term
instead of you.
You bastard.
You really gave me
no choice, Guy.
Don't you ever call me
by my Christian name again.
Ever.
You were easily bought.
Well, my father was
a God himself
and when I told him...
Oh, yes, your son will be a God,
and your son's son,
even unto the end of school.
Look, we saved the house
from Fowler.
We saved your conscience.
Oh, yes.
All problems solved for life.
No commies and no queers.
Don't let's quarrel.
We've all got to live together
next term.
Let's try and do it
as amicably as possible,
shall we?
[ Bells chiming ]
It isn't the end of the world.
[ Scoffs ]
[ Bells continue chiming ]
Isn't it?
[ Sniffs ]
When people like Menzies
rule the world...
...and you want to be ambassador
in Paris. Hmm.
"Ah, Bennett, yes."
"Nice enough chap."
"Quite amusing, actually."
"We--We had high hopes of him
once but... oh, yes, you heard."
"Not--not quite one of us."
"Bogota, do you think?
No, maybe not."
"Haiti-- isn't that coming up?"
"That's much more his line.
You see, he was never a God."
"Only ever an ordinary prefect."
No need to be even that.
Oh, yes, there is.
If I'm spending
the rest of my life...
hiding my true nature...
I'm taking every comfort that's
going when it is going.
Oh, well, if that's
your attitude.
And, besides,
being absolutely...
objective...
it would dish me
once and for all, wouldn't it?.
You can't have things
both ways, Guy.
Why not?
Ow!
[ Whispers ]
Why not?
Pretend to do one thing,
only really do the other.
Fool the swine.
Play along with them.
Let them think what they like.
Let them despise you,
but all along--
Oh, don't talk dribble.
...and have the last laugh
and be revenged.
That's just sentimental twaddle.
You wouldn't be in the mess
you are now
if you had any discretion
at all.
What better cover
for someone like me than...
total indiscretion?
[ Wistful music ]
Wouldn't it be wonderful
if communism were really true?
It is true.
What? Heaven on earth?
Earth on earth.
The just earth.
GUY:
Of course,
Tommy was killed
in the Spanish Civil War.
Tough as old boots, Tommy was.
Till the bloody fascists
got him.
JULIE: Have you ever wanted
to go back?
No.
Is there nobody
that you'd want to see?
No.
Isn't there anything
you miss at all?
[ Choir sings ]
I...
...I miss the cricket.
[ "I Vow to Thee, My Country"
plays ]