Raise the head.
He no longer has any milk teeth.
I would say he is 12, or 13.
Michelle, the Filipina?
Michelle?
What is your surname?
Surname?
- Sedad.
You have a passport?
A residence permit?
At home, at my boss's house.
Lama Bekoum.
Who is Lama?
Lama, are you pregnant?
Yes.
How pregnant are you?
Seven months.
OK, Caritas is going to see you.
Who is Tigest Ai lo?
The Ethiopian, Tigest Ailo?
Is it you Tigest?
The hearing is open.
Zain Al Hajj.
Remove the handcuffs.
Come closer.
Souad and Selim Al Hajj.
Yes.
The complainant is in detention.
He is present and without handcuffs.
Show me your hands.
Also presents
His lawyer Nadine Al Aalam.
Accused are also present
Selim and Souad Al Hajj,
represented by their lawyer Said Tamer.
Do you know why
Are you here, Souad?
Yes, I know why, your Honor.
Why?
I know my son
to serve his sentence in prison,
but why does he drag us here
Again, I do not know.
We just are "mops”,
anyone can attack us!
You were called as a witness
at Zain's previous trial, is that?
Yes.
And you had testified?
And now you are accused.
Do you know why
Zain was charged?
Zain got into a dirty story
Because of his childishness.
Childish? He was sentenced
5 years in prison!
Childish?
Short...
How old are you Zain?
I do not know,
ask them the question.
Your Honor, Zain was not
declared at birth,
and he has never been registered
the civil status.
And since obviously his parents
do not know
his exact date of birth
Here is the report of the medical examiner
which certifies that
Zain was about 12 years old
at the time of the incident.
So he is almost 12 years old?
Absolutely.
Where do you live Zain?
Roumieh prison for minors.
You were arrested on June 15 and you
have been serving your sentence since.
Do you know why?
Because I planted
a son of a bitch with a knife.
Did you stab someone?
Yes, and it's a son of a bitch.
Oh?
You insist?
Forbidden to laugh in the room!
What's all this pandemonium
What did you provoke?
On the TV and in the media.
Your prison call.
Do you know why you're here?
Yes.
Why?
I want to complain
against my parents.
Why do you want to complain
against your parents?
For giving me birth.
Hello.
I would like two boxes of Tramadol.
You need a prescription.
Who is it for?
My mother.
Why she did not come herself?
She had surgery on her belly.
She broke her back.
This is his doctor
who prescribed him?
Yes.
Why it's not your father
who came?
He is paralyzed.
- You come to see who, Madam?
- My son.
- His name?
- Ibrahim Al Hajj.
- Ibrahim Al Hajj?
- Yes.
Aunt Souad?
This way!
Massoud? It's you?
How are you?
How are you, my dear?
My son Ibrahim is with you?
No, they took him away
in another cell.
She's trying to talk to you!
Tell him "bye".
Say bye to your cousin.
Your brothers are all with you
in cell?
Yes, everyone.
May God protect you.
We increased the price S 15 a mouthful.
Our hands are busted
force to soak and wring.
Our "sock juice" is worth more
only a kilo of meat!
Be proud of you!
Get away!
- We have an exam tomorrow?
- Look at your calendar.
That's for your mother.
And that's for my pretty Sahar.
I miss her.
Licorice and ramen.
Thank you.
Later.
What a bastard, Assaad's father.
Whenever it fills
the water reservoir,
we drown because of
his crappy piping!
This asshole thinks that
it's a gift? This rat hole?
Sahar!
It's not a house!
It's a pigsty!
Get out! You are going to be
Electrocute, mess!
- House of misfortune!
- Go live in the street.
There is plenty of room!
Zain, why the vegetables
are rotten? Did you upset Assaad?
Zain, he gave you the liquorice
and the ramen?
It's not even day, fucking!
Give me a break!
Stand up, idiot!
This juice is best,
forget the rest!
Sahar, come here.
Why is there blood on your pants?
Where's the blood?
Hurry before we are seen.
Do you remember what happened?
Your girlfriend Alia?
When his mother found out,
she locked her up at home
until the day when a big pig
came to take her.
Mom won't want you.
She'll toss you in the street.
- She'll give you to Assaad.
- But Assaad is really nice.
He is a motherfucker!
He offers me ramen and liquorice.
He'll give you shit to eat!
They will give you to Assaad,
they will get rid of you.
We will never see you again.
And he will throw you with the rats,
he will shut you up, cover the windows
Will not let you out.
He will give you a drop of water
every 3 days and old ramen.
You did not see his ear?
A sewer rat bit him.
Here, put this on.
You've finished?
Yes.
Here.
What do I do?
Put it like that,
down in your pants.
Your hair is so lovely!
Who styled it?
Show me.
So, chief, are you finished?
I still have the cans to put away,
but my mother needs Sahar.
Stay again.
I'm happy to have your sister here.
I'll bring her back later.
I'll talk to your mother.
Bye.
Careful, don't leave
those rags just anywhere.
I'll tell you where to hide them.
- You got pig?
- Yes.
You do not throw them
in the trash.
Juice of beet, flavor so sweet!
Tomato so red, use your head!
It's 250.
Thanks bye.
Hold.
May God bless you.
Take two.
What do you want?
- Just show you something.
- Leave me alone.
Come on, just a moment!
Fuck you, bastard.
Leave him, Zain.
Don't piss me off!
Why sign up for school?
Out of the question. Forget it,
and keep working for Assaad.
Why are you complicating things?
It's not better that he goes to learn
two or three words?
Go to your heart,
but do not wake her up.
Let him go to school.
They will send us something to eat
and get dressed, for kids
And what does Assaad say?
I'll talk to him.
In the morning, I will go to school,
and in the afternoon
I will work at home.
Look at Farid,
the neighbor's son, Zahra.
He returns from school
with all kinds of stuff.
They will give us mattresses,
clothes
Shut up!
At least he'll eat there and
bring food to his sisters.
They receive the remains of the hotels
and the most beautiful marriages.
Enjoy it a bit!
Why are you so stubborn?
Inch'Allah we will see Monday.
Inch Allah?
Do you want me to swear on bread?
I said yes.
And if Assaad gets vexed
and puts us out?
Do not worry,
he will not get angry.
We will send him Zain after school
and he will do overtime.
Soap of my balls!
Why are you pouting?
Take it easy.
Bring a gas canister
to Em Habib down the street
Ms. Bahia, I'm done.
- How much is it?
- 13,000.
Do not touch me, fucked!
Where do these chickens come from?
Who brought them?
It's Assaad, he's at home.
Assaad is up there?
Yes.
Mum?
What are Assaad and
his father doing here?
- Do not make a scene.
- Yeah, you'll see.
- What are they doing here?
- Calm down.
They discuss our rent
with your father.
I'd cut off my left hand
they give you the hens
in exchange for Sahar.
Wait, listen to me
You're going to say this son of a bitch
that he did not do anything here.
- You do not understand?
- Go tell him or I do it.
Lower your voice.
I swear by your sisters,
I swear by God.
That there is nothing at all here.
- So why is Sahar made up?
- She imitates me to have fun.
As soon as they finish the juice,
I'm kicking them out.
Listen, don't.
Go tell him that's not going to work.
Go tell him or I will.
I do not want to hear it.
Do you want him to throw us out?
Not a word.
Welcome, dear neighbors!
Abu Assaad, please help yourself.
Thank you.
Have some, Assaad.
Dearie, take your sister
into the other room.
Wipe off that ugly lipstick.
You look like a witch
in this dress.
Sahar.”
Sahar!
Wakes up,
I'll take you somewhere.
- Where's that?
- 1 will tell you later. Arise.
Be ready when I come back.
Do not say anything to anyone.
How much until Cola?
1,000.
And if I put my sister on my lap,
1,000 pounds will do the trick?
Where is your sister?
At home, I'll get her.
No problem, go get her.
I do not want to leave, pity
I do not want to leave,
I beg you.
Mom, I do not want to leave!
I kill you if you dare
put your feet back here.
Where are you taking her,
you bunch of cretins?
To be a maid for
that son of a bitch?
I want to stay with my brother.
It's none of your business.
- Mom, she's just a child.
- Mind your own business.
Step away I said!
Do not be fooled by this.
You, go downstairs.
Zain, if you still try
something, I kill you.
I understood your little game, bastard.
You were going to fuck us
in shit, little junk.
You send it wipe
the shit of this pig!
Kiss my ass, and you go down.
You, go down.
Let her go!
She will not go to Assaad!
Little bastard!
Open the door, little asshole.
I do not want to leave, Mom!
I do not want!
Let me go!
I beg you, Mom,
ll do not want to leave.
Come on, Sahar!
It's enough!
You stay here, 1 tell you!
I want to stay here.
I beg you.
Come down.
Come down! Come down!
Mom, pity, I beg you!
Son of a bitch.
It's enough!
I can not stand this hell anymore.
I do not want to leave, Mom!
Stop!
Y tired of your bullshit!
Get her up, shit!
Another word
and I cut your tongue off!
No!
Sahar!
Let her go!
You are happy?
You're playing the big man?
You're going to pay him dear, rascal!
Let her go!
It was to lift her out of misery.
With me, she was doomed.
She barely has a bed to sleep,
Barely enough to eat and drink.
She does not wash herself.
Never watches TV.
I told myself, "Marry her,
at least she'll sleep in a bed."”
A real bed.
With a blanket.
She can eat as much as she likes.
- You didn't know it would come to this?
- Never!
I never wanted that!
You think I'm proud
that my son stabbed someone?
Have you considered the possibility
that it is not our fault?
I was born this way, raised this way,
how have I done wrong?
If I had the choice, I would be
maybe better than all of you!
- You can not say that.
- Please
Now, people are spitting on me
in the street.
They treat me like an animal.
I never asked for any of this.
1 was told, "If you do not have children,
You are not a man.”
"Your children will be
your backbone."
But they broke my back,
they broke my heart.
Cursed be the day
where I married.
Why I started in this misery?
I'm not him, boy.
We just look alike, that's all.
But that must be a spider there,
not a cockroach.
Isn't that right?
I do not need a spider,
I am Cockroach man.
Why I need of a spider?
That's it.
I am Cockroach man.
What is your relationship?
With Spider-Man?
What is my link?
I'm his cousin.
So you are his cousin?
That's right. His cousin.
- What's your name?
- Zain.
- Hussein?
- Zain!
Zain!
Where are you going, Zain?
To my grandmother's house.
- Speak louder.
- To my grandmother's house!
Your grandmother's house?
Well, she's lucky to have you.
Me, nobody takes care of me.
- My life is...
- Please, the cigarette.
Please.
Stop, sir.
I'm going down here, please.
Wait, sir.
I'd like to get off here,
please.
Eat my corn
you will be my son-in-law
Mr. Cockroach man?
Is the owner here?
Excuse me?
What do you want with him?
I would like to ask him for a job.
What kind of job?
Whatever,
the important thing is that I work.
What's your name?
Zain.
Zain?
And yours?
My name is Tigest.
I could clean the floor
or do the dishes, for example.
I really do not know.
Do you need an employee?
You need someone
to carry your fishing rod?
Where are your parents?
Where are they?
Sir, you would have a juice for 250?
Or something else for 2507
The juice is 1000.
- Anything cheaper?
- No.
Go ahead.
Take it, I tell you.
Do not worry, take it.
It's occupied, ma'am.
There too?
Yes, and that one is out of order.
Tigest?
You have something to eat?
Please.
Zain.
Here's the milk, OK?
You give him one at 11 am,
then another at 2.
I come home at 3 pm
Don't leave the house, alright?
Don't let Yonas cry,
the neighbor is very boring.
Stay with your boyfriend.
I'm coming back, Yoni.
[Ethiopian]
This is your new friend, OK?
Zain is your new friend.
Are you sleepy?
[Ethiopian]
Tell him you do not have the money.
I told him, but he does not want to do
my papers for less than S 1500.
I absolutely have to renew them,
they will expire soon.
Do as you can, but be quick.
Lots of girls are arrested.
Sometimes in the middle of the night.
You stink shit, shit!
Stop!
Take a seat.
Sit down, fuck!
It fell over!
Sleep, sleep
Come on, go to sleep.
But what do you want from here?
Sleep, Yonas my little brother
Sleep, sleep
Come eat corn, honey.
Bye, Harout.
Come in, enter!
Welcome!
Hot, hot, hot!
Blow, blow it out.
Blow, Zain.
How old are you, Zain?
I do not know.
12 years old, I think.
Do you have brothers and sisters?
Many.
- You don't miss them?
- Yes.
The one I miss the most,
it's my sister, Sahar.
- Where is she?
- With her husband.
She's married?
Yes, and there was drums
and a darbouka.
We had a party in the street.
People were throwing
rice and flowers.
Congratulations.
Rahil Eresa.
- Last name?
- Shifaraw.
Do you know why you are in prison?
Why are you handcuffed?
- 1 do not have a residence permit.
- NO papers.
Where were you working?
I worked for a lady for 6 years.
Then you ran away?
She was not nice to you?
She beat you?
No, she was very kind
but I fell in love,
and I got pregnant and I left
You got what?
I got pregnant and I left
Say, you speak Arabic well.
Do you understand everything I say?
- Yes I understand.
- So no need for a translator?
No.
So you're gone
so that Madame does not know.
I was scared of police,
they'd take my son and expels me.
I was scared and
I did not say anything to anyone.
So, you left Yonas with Zain.
When you came home,
he had taken good care of him?
You never thought
that he could hurt her?
I was scared the first two days,
but afterward
I started to trust him.
Did you expect that
Zain do what he did?
Never.
They were like brothers.
But I never blamed Zain
because I know Aspro.
Who is Aspro?
The guy who forged my permit.
Souk Al Ahad
I gave you until today, no?
But I talked to my girlfriend.
Her papers get made for $900.
Get her to make your papers then!
No but why
this price difference?
Stop your blah blah,
do not try to wind me up.
Calm down, that I can
place two words.
I'm trying to help you, here.
Who gave you the name of Tigest?
I did.
Gallop at your girlfriend
who can you do them $ 900.
Do not do the malign.
I beg you,
I could not find the S 1,500.
Look at that!
Does it look fake?
Nobody will entangle you
with these papers.
The woman on this paper
BOOM!
She exploded into a thousand pieces.
She had no one, no family.
Nobody has claimed his body.
You will be able to remove your
beauty mark, Not need for it.
OK, but give me a bit more time.
Darling, I said you can save $1500.
Give me Yonas and
you will have the license for free.
Never say it again
the name of Yonas,
I'd never do that!
Your kid lives like a fugitive
in this country.
The day they discover him,
they will expel you both.
You make him live underground
like a rat.
He does not see the sun,
he will never go to school.
I suggest you give him a family.
You will be able to see
him from time to time.
I know how to hide my son.
How to feed him and take care of him.
I will not stop telling you:
"Your son died before being born."
He does not exist.
Even a bottle of ketchup has a name.
With a production date
and expiry.
I can not hear that anymore!
How much are you short?
'S 500.
- You're short § 500?
I can buy a human being 500 S.
So you don't think
that Aspro is a crook,
ll give you a reduction of S 200.
And I give you 7 more days.
Either you come here with the money,
or with your son,
either I never want to see
your pretty face here again.
You understand?
So take your time,
all the time you need.
Look.
"Hello man.
How are you, buddy? “
"Doing well, my brother"
"1 saw you rolling a joint.”
Me?
"Your mother is a big bitch."”
"What a jerk of piss.”
"Cocksucker thing."
"Stop your bullshit, fool
Bastard!
"Damn, your mother is ugly.”
Close your damn window!
I'm tired of feeling your food!
I'm going to make her eat shit
if she continues to annoy you.
I kill her or what?
What a shit, that bitch
Slut, whore
Are you going to...
[ Ethiopian] is enough,
you need to get my pay!
You know the guy.
It was you who found the job for me.
I'm not the owner,
ll cannot give you the money.
If it was up to me,
I would have given you the money.
I am Tigest, you know me?
You know me?
Come back in the afternoon,
maybe the boss will be there.
No, not in advance.
We are at the beginning of the month.
You are illegal,
I already take a lot of risks.
Please, 1 will do what you want.
Here is the identity card
of the boss.
I stole it for you. And you know
how much she trusts me
It is not serious,
it's for the little one.
You know what will happen to us
if they learn our story?
They will expel you with the little one.
And God knows what they will do with me.
I am only a simple guardian.
They will replace me
in the blink of an eye.
- You do not even want to see his picture?
- I can not.
I beg you, leave.
Before, I worked at a lady's house.
Then, I ran away.
So, she has to pretend
she's my old boss.
And to say that she
doesn't want me anymore.
She does not want you anymore.
She will say that she wants
transfer me to your home.
So you will become my new sponsor.
My boss.
That's Jacqueline.
Who am 1?
I am not Jacqueline but Daad.
I'm going to play Jacqueline's role.
You have to work for me?
But I do not need an employee.
Oh my God, I'm going to throw
myself out of the window.
I can't pay for a maid.
I do not have S 500 to hire her.
Do you see this cockroach?
It already understood.
If 1 ask it,
it can tell me the whole scam.
As with all Lebanese
To resist and to transfer.
Where do you live?
Arax.
Apartment?
Khachik Papikian.
You give me light, Mr. Harout?
Thank you.
Excuse me, are you smoking?
No thanks.
Why don't you want
this girl anymore?
I have children in Canada,
may God bless them.
They want to send me a Filipina.
They are better?
- It's more prestigious.
- It's different.
And you, you agree
to work for him?
I want to sponsor this Filipina.
With everything.
I want to help her.
She is Ethiopian.
I want to give my wife her as a gift.
What is your business?
I have an electronics store.
Whose name is?
Haroutchum
Electric.
The address of your home
where the girl will reside.
Dawra, Bourj Hamoud.
Your phone number?
4,5, 6 Something like this.
Something like that?
This man is Armenian.
You must not take him literally.
Give me your correct number, 09 ...?
- 3,4...
- 5,6...
And then 7?
He pisses us off and then
he offers us a coffee?
Thank you,
we do not want your coffee.
Thanks my God,
he did not call the cops.
He calls the police!
Yes, I am the king of Hachich
What's the matter?
I look different?
Where are you going?
I'm going to call Mom.
And then Souk El Ahad
to look for stuff.
[Ethiopian]
You're not alone, Zain is here.
Everything '.
"Later,” Zain.
Bye.
[ Ethiopian] I can not
send you money this month.
I'm taking English classes.
I'm sorry, Mom.
My boss is so nice to me.
I'm ashamed to ask her for money.
I love you so much, Mom.
Rahil?
Manara?
Yes, ho in.
I have not seen her since yesterday.
I thought she was sick.
She said she was going to the souk
and she did not come back.
She may have gone to Aspro.
Aspro? Who is Aspro?
It has a booth Souk Al Ahad.
Pullovers for only 2000 pounds!
Sir, where is the Aspro shop?
Aspro? It's there.
The real Aspro?
Rahil?
What is your connection with Rahil?
- We are parents.
- Are you parents?
Show me.
It's clear.
On the paternal or maternal side?
This is her son Yonas?
Is not it?
What is Yonas doing with you?
Rahil left yesterday.
She has not come back since.
Give me Yonas.
- No no...
- Why are you scared?
It's my little Yonas!
I know everything about him.
It's a little thug,
like his mother.
Yasser, 2 falafels
for the two rabbits!
You want to eat?
You did not call her?
I do not have a phone.
His cellphone is off.
Thank you, Yasser.
- Come eat inside.
- No thanks.
What do I say to her, if she comes?
Tell her we're waiting for him at home.
- Stay here.
- No no.
Wait here with me
in case she passes by.
Excuse me!
Where can I open this?
Hold this for me.
- That's it.
- Thank you.
You're welcome.
You are hungry?
No.
Bon appétit.
What's your name?
Ibrahim.
- And who is he?
- His name is...
Assaad.
- And you?
- Maysoun.
You stole it
or do you use it to beg?
It's my brother.
He does not look like you.
We are all born black like him.
And...
With time, we get lighter.
How much are these boxes?
It depends on the car.
Let's say a woman drives by
Look at her hand,
if she's wearing a ring...
You say, "May God protect you
"and keep your husband.”
If she does not wear a ring,
you say:
"May God send you a good husband.”
Stop licking your hands,
they are too dirty.
Line-up over here, the Ethiopians
You are pregnant?
[Ethiopian]
You can not say anything!
They'll take it from you.
[Ethiopian]
Yonas, my son, forgive me!
For God's sake, forgive me!
Do you have something
for a baby?
Yes.
How much?
For 250 or one at 1000.
I take the 250.
Taste.
Just this once.
No kidding...
Isn't this better
that a shawarma sandwich?
Do not swallow it whole,
you will get sick!
Heeee!
You swallowed it in full?
Is it good?
Enjoy it, big guy.
No water?
Fuck this shitty country!
She does not ask about her son?
Do not try to find out how he's doing.
In fact, your mother is worse than mine.
After you, Mr. Yonas.
Go ahead.
Ibrahim!
What are you doing there?
I sell these pans.
These shitty pans?
Better than that stupid
wreath you're carrying!
It's for the graveyard, idiot!
On the contrary,
I sell it in two seconds.
They buy me everything.
You want to bet?
We bet a food dish.
I want meat rolls
and Chich Barak. And you?
I would die for a dish of
Chich Barak well hot
My God...
But not just a plate,
3 enormous one
Where does your
food relief come from?
You talked about it last time.
Ah, do you mean the dispensary?
I can come with you?
But no, you're Lebanese,
ll am Syrian.
Where did you find this rabbit?
Mind your own business.
- You old goat.
- Let's go.
Could you move away?
- Or do you want to taste my fist?
- Come on, Ibrahim. Let's go.
Anyhow, I'm leaving this country,
I'm outta here.
Where to?
I leave you the business
and all the rest.
All is for you.
Where are you going?
To Sweden.
There is a neighborhood
full of Syrians there.
Nobody asks where you come from.
They do not harass you,
nothing at all.
I will have my own room.
Nobody can enter without knocking.
Ll choose who can enter.
In addition, children there
die from natural causes.
I want to go with you.
Of course, but you need money.
How much?
About $ 300. Not much.
That's a lot, $ 300.
You know Os
Q-Spar?
Aspro?
Yes, in the souk.
What about him?
This is his number.
He's organizing the trip.
He gave me this paper.
I drew a boat
Next to the number.
It's a boat with pretty lights,
good food.
Assaad can come too?
Does he know how to swim?
I will help him.
I do not know.
You have to ask Ospro.
Aspro, not Ospro.
Aspro.
"Where are you from?"
[Syrian accent]
"Me? From Syria.”
"Where in Syria?”
Alep
- "This is your brother?"
- "Yes, he's my brother."
[Syrian accent]
"1 mean, he's my brother.”
"What is his name?"
"Na wras."
"It's been two days
that he did not eat or drink anything."
"Why is he black like that?"
"My mother drank a lot of coffee
during her pregnancy."
"She drank liters of coffee a day."”
"Where's your card?”
I lost it while walking
by the river.
You were strolling near the river?
Yes, and the papers
fell to the water.
I could not catch them.
How did you come here?
We were at home, in Syria,
when our neighbor
He denounced us, I think.
But I'm sure of nothing,
but I suspect it.
A shell fell on our house.
We started crawling like Rambo.
Rambo, the one who crawls.
Have you crawled?
Yeah, like him, in the trenches.
Well, what do you want?
What you can, but the essential,
it's milk and diapers.
Milk and diapers.
And maybe ramen
and vinegar crisps?
Stand up.
What are you looking at?
What a Lamborghini!
Come here, let me see that.
Rahil hasn't come back?
No...
ll mean, yes! Rahil?
She came back for a while!
For sure...
What is this thing
that you're trailing behind?
It's a nuclear bomb or a rocket?
A brand new water tank.
How much do you want for
this "brand new" water tank?
- 20,000.
- 20,0007
Yasser!
Give this little 30,000
instead of 20.
Yonas...
Why does Yonas look so skinny?
You do not eat?
He looks sick.
My God, you smell like a the dog or what?
I've already talked to Rahil about it.
I told him that a family
good people wants to take Yonas.
They can take care of him, dress
And you can put yourself $ 500
in the pocket.
Sound good?
So?
It looks like you can help people
traveling to Turkey?
Do you want to travel?
I would very much like.
Would you like to travel where?
In Turkey.
I mean in Sweden.
- Turkey, Sweden, what you want.
- Which is nicer?
You choose,
ll can even send you to the moon.
If you can convince Rahil
About the boy.
Okay, kid?
That's it, boss.
Take this and tell Rahil
that Aspro says hello.
Okay?
I'll ask Rahil.
Yes, do it.
Yonas, give me the clothespin.
Do like me, to warm your hands.
My little sister washed the clothes
because my mother was sick.
So she washed the prescription
with clothes?
I give you one card
You'll have the rest when you pay me
the 3000 that are missing.
One card?
Give me two.
No.
Go away!
I see you moving forward,
I am not blind.
Guys, are you coming to help me?
Gulps of Tramadol,
are you into that?
One gulp for 1000
Help me to carry this thing.
Come and help me!
We will agree on the price, brother.
Come on, hurry!
Guys, he has Tramadol!
- I have Tramadol by the gulp.
- Would you have Viagra or Simo?
- Do you have Rivo?
- Farawla, Tradamol?
- Free base?
- I'm in the juice business.
It's Rivo, but in version juice.
You sell us sea water,
little man?
Nothing better than sea water, man!
I have Tramadol by the gulp.
Interested?
1,000 for a swig.
Go on, choose the country of your dreams.
Let's go to Sweden,
it's the most beautiful.
We'll go with that fool Maysoun.
In Sweden,
nobody ever bothers you.
You can even piss from the balcony,
nobody tells you anything!
You pay what you owe him, bitch!
Take your chick and break!
I'm leaving, asshole!
Go heat up your ass,
when it's well-cooked, eat it!
Do not touch the kid, shithead.
Get out!
Go away!
You will break the door!
What are you doing?
Who is the son of a bitch who has changed
the lock and swing my stuff?
Your things are right there.
Who are you?
I have things inside.
Your stuff is at the owner's.
Where's this stupid owner?
Go see where is hiding
your slutty friend.
Otherwise, I call the owner.
Give him a big kiss for me!
Who are you with the other slut?
I am her brother.
What shit bag are you coming from?
Bug off before I go crazy!
I'll call the cops!
You'll see!
If 1 do not break the door.
Where is the owner, brothel?
If you do not mind,
I break you in two!
- Shut up! Shut up!
- Go away!
1. Want. My. Fucking. Money!
Stay here.
Don't move.
Go over there!
Go.
Go back!
Go there!
Go there.
Yes my friend.
Listen
I'm going to send you a little kid.
He looks like a dog now,
make him look human.
OKAY? I have to pass it.
OK.
Why are you sad?
It's nothing.
It's good, we agreed.
Do you have your papers?
Identity card?
I dunno.
At home, maybe.
I need proof of your existence.
An identity card,
an extract of a civil status,
a newspaper where there is your photo
So that I can take you out
from the port of Beirut.
Understand?
No need to worry about Yonas.
I love him, and I will place him
in a good family.
And the people with whom you travel
will take good care of you.
You remember Yasser
who works for me? Go see it...
He'll send you for a haircut.
Then you go home
and what are you bringing back?
- Your papers.
- My papers.
Okay?
Here are one, two, three, four
Here.
But you promised me S 500.
Do you intend to drink and eat for free?
That's $ 100 for your food.
Kiss Me.
Take care of yourself. Go ahead.
It's good, you can go.
I told you that
I will take care of him.
Zain!
How long Have you been there?
None of your business.
Where did you go?
Where? Where? Where?
I fuck you!
Anyhow, I did not come
to see you,
nor to see that asshole there.
- Want my papers.
- Yes! Of course, my dear!
Selim, do you know the best?
Your son wants his papers!
Where are my papers?
Where were you all this time?
None of your business.
Not my business?
Why do you want your papers?
Do you want to work as a smuggler?
My papers, my ID card,
no matter!
Nobody cares about you or us.
Do not play the little man,
you little asshole!
Come, you'll see,
I will give you your papers.
I have all kinds of papers.
You just have to choose.
I have papers
that will make me rot in jail.
I have an eviction notice.
And that's the paper
Most important.
Come.
Look at this paper!
A hospital bill
that breaks my heart.
We are less than nothing, my boy.
Parasites.
You just have to live without papers
If not, I'll swing you through the window
and I'm done with it.
You understand?
Leave or I break your mouth.
Let him go, Selim!
Tell whoever sent you
I never got you papers!
Return from where you come from!
I fuck you and I curse
the day you are born!
Who is in the hospital?
Not a word Selim,
do not say another word!
Who went back to the hospital?
Who is in the hospital?
Make him leave home or I kill him!
- You bastard!
- Who was at the hospital?
- Bummer!
- Who went back to the hospital?
Talk to me.
Who was at the hospital?
What did he do to him,
this son of a bitch?
What did he do to him?
Sahar is gone.
It's finish.
She left?
You will see what it is, to leave.
1 will show you who is what.
- Come back here, little asshole!
- He has a knife!
I'll fuck you,
if you do not come back!
Come back, doggie!
I will kill you with your bare hands!
Take off the handcuffs.
You are the husband of
- Sahar.
How old was she when you married?
- 11 years old
- 11 years old?
A girl of 11 years
is able to marry?
She knows what marriage means?
From what I know
Yes, she can.
I mean she was "ripe" already.
Really?
I did not know she was a tomato
or a potato to be ripe!
Zain, calm down!
I did not know
that she could die from it.
Lots of girls in the neighborhood
get married at this age.
Even my mother-in-law
was married very young.
She's here, still alive.
When did she get pregnant?
2 or 3 months later.
Everything was normal?
At the beginning,
I did not notice anything wrong.
Then she started to bleed
She bled a lot.
And what happened next?
We brought her to hospital
with her parents.
She died At the hospital gate.
We did not manage to get her admitted.
Can I know why
they refused to admit her?
Because she has no papers.
Master, that's enough.
You bombard her with questions.
I made the slave all my life
and you dare to judge me?
By what right do you dare to judge me?
Have you been in my skin?
Did you live what I lived?
No never,
and you will never live it!
Not even in your worst nightmares.
In my place,
you would have hanged yourself!
You imagine having to feed your children
water and sugar,
because you do not have
nothing else to give them.
I am ready to commit 100 crimes
to keep my kids alive!
These are my children.
Nobody has the right to judge me.
Ll am my own judge.
The flesh of my flesh!
You hear me?
The Syrian, Hussein
The Egyptian, Mohammad
Could we have your attention?
We are there, with the priest,
to meet you
To have a good time with you.
To cheer you up a bit.
Come on, let's sing a song.
Zain Al Hajj, take your stuff
and go to the office.
Zain?
Zain!
What are you doing there?
Zain, where is Yonas?
Zain!
Where is my son?
Where is Yonas? Where?
Who did you leave him with?
My son is alone!
His eye
from this side,
is blue, blue, blue.
- His two eyes are blue?
- No. This eye is brown.
And this eye is blue.
You are live on Freedom Forever.
Please lower the volume
on your television set.
I've watched your show
for a while now...
I know you always
tackle social problems...
How are you?
You're sick?
Did you catch cold?
Congratulations,
are you no longer in mourning?
Do not you wear black anymore?
Why do you hate me so much?
Eat them, Zain.
Why do you want me so much?
I can do nothing.
I could not do anything.
She was my daughter,
it's my pain.
Why are you here?
When God takes you something,
He offers you something in return.
What did he offer you, God?
I am pregnant.
You're going to have a brother or a sister.
I feel sick
I hope it's a girl.
It will be called Sahar.
Your words pierce my heart.
When you get out of here, she'll be
walking, playing
I do not want to see you here anymore.
You are without heart.
Leave me alone, I want to go out.
Since the death of my father,
I did not smile
This report on injustices
against children
deeply touched our viewers.
If you'd like to comment
on what you've just watched...
09658856.
Is there an adult
Next to you, Zain?
An officer.
An officer?
Where are you calling us, Zain?
From the prison.
I hear Zain's voice.
From prison?
What prison?
It's him!
Roumieh Prison for Minors.
Zain, why are you calling us?
What can I do for you?
I want to complain
against my parents.
Hey boys!
Zain is on television!
Zain, you're live.
What would you like to say?
I want adults to listen to me.
I want adults who can't
raise kids not to have any.
What am I going to remember?
Of violence,
insults or beatings,
of the chain, the pipe or belt?
The sweetest word I'm told,
it is: "get out, son of a bitch!"
"Bug off, piece of garbage!"
Life is a pile of shit.
It's not worth more than my shoe.
I live in hell here.
I burn like rotting meat.
How are you?
Life is a bitch.
I thought we would become
good people
and appreciated by all.
But God does not want
that for us.
He 'd rather we be washrags for others.
This child that you're carrying
will be like me.
Zain, what do you want from your parents?
I want them to have no more children.
Stronger.
You want them to have no more children.
Yes.
I do not think they will do
still children.
And who is in her belly?
He will be born, no?
We've discovered a depot
where 15 people were sequestered...
Stand on the line.
A little to the right.
No, the left.
I mean your right.
But that's my right.
And that's my left.
Lift the chin.
Look ahead.
Smile.
Smile, Zain.
It's a passport photo,
not a death certificate!