CELINE AND JULIE GO BOATING
Usually, it began like this.
MAGIC
Fill out a card, please.
But the next morning...
Here...
This is yours, Miss.
Thank you, Sir.
No, I won't have coffee.
Not here.
For you this time.
Here, Lil, for your collection.
- This one's from Borneo.
- Java?
- Java good time?
- Sure.
Better than Kilimanjaro before that.
How's that?
Past... future.
Escape from prison, theatrical coup.
The Chariot. New start. Conquest.
It's your lucky day.
- Oh, Death.
- No, it's affirmative.
Movement, change, the end...
becoming radiance, triumph.
Conquest. The Sun.
How useless.
Don't burn yourself.
You do me now.
The Past. The Hanged Man. Below is
above. Your future is behind you.
And you plunge into the depths...
of night.
My future...
Your grandfather the hermit...
protects you.
You don't move. You don't advance.
You advance, but in total immobility.
- Stagnation.
- Triumphal nevertheless.
Despite the stagnation.
So my future is in the present.
Exactly.
That's fine. I like paper.
I like the smell of wax.
- It'll go better tomorrow.
- Let's hope so.
Well, back to our places.
Back to literature.
Sir.
You may smoke... discreetly.
The children are being very noisy.
Is "White Elephant" back?
No, he's on a trip to Australia.
Have "Naive Larks"...
...and "Ladies of Flajolie" gone?
Like "Spiders in the Night.”
"Death with a Blue Ribbon.”
"Before the Mirror"?
"Before the Mirror"... 11th July...
1578.
Madame Michelle, I told you not to
let your cats stray!
Sorry, did I wake you?
I thought it was them after me again.
Don't you think you need a bed?
I must wash... a shower...
I must take a shower.
You had three phone calls
while I slept.
First door on the left.
It's wild.
My last African safari...
...was really wild.
The heat was killing us.
Hunting animals every day
in the savannah.
I had a boa cockstrictor.
A boa constrictor?
Right! A boa cockstrictor
that stuck it to me.
Not dangerous, I put him around
my neck.
When the natives killed the biggest
tiger of all, they said...
...it was the Bengali tiger.
From Bengal, the region of Africa
we were in. Do you know it?
It's a blue and brown bird.
I was the Pigmy emperor's guest.
But Zouba the Giantess was jealous.
She wanted to marry the emperor
who'd given me the tiger-skin.
But since he had given it to me...
Not a bare skin?
Zouba wanted to skin me.
So I ran.
I almost croaked coming back
from the jungle.
I lived through hell.
I lost my hair all over,
plucked clean.
I was scared to death.
I was traumatoed.
- Tomatoed?
- Yes, freaked out.
I was invited to Hong Kong. A cool
place, I'll tell you some day.
A Japanese guy there did
acoopuncture. He did it to me.
After a month...
...my hair grew back, red at first,
then the usual.
Then I came back.
- Who's he?
- That's Grégoire.
Known as Guilou.
A distant cousin from
childhood holidays.
We were lovers, we had our
innocent games.
Playing hospital, etcetera.
On Sundays we'd get married in the
grass behind the presbytery.
Naked as worms, solemn as popes.
Now Guilou's back.
He's written. I'm waiting.
But he wants a white wedding
in church.
What's this relic?
A forgotten forget-me-not.
Isn't it a marguerite?
You're right, it's not a marguerite,
it's a daisy.
It was a daisy.
We'll see to that.
Mind if I use alcohol?
Does it hurt you?
It's all right.
I have a first-aid certificate.
How did that happen?
I thought they were after me,
so I ran.
I fell, I was scared.
But who are they? Scared of what?
I'd been hired to work in a house.
Then two days ago... it was
fine until then...
...two days ago I found in my room...
...a bracelet with a foreign girl's
name on it.
The girl before me, I thought,
so I took it to my master.
When he saw it he turned pale.
I thought he'd hit me.
He locked himself in his study
with his wife.
She cried, he shouted, I listened.
Then the other woman came.
So I went away.
I kept out of the way, poked around,
looked in drawers...
...and in one drawer I found
two passports...
...with foreign names - one was
the name on the bracelet.
But the photos were torn out.
Yesterday, when I wanted to
go on looking...
...drawers and cupboards were locked.
I tried to force a drawer.
They caught me at it.
I ran away and now they're after me.
Who are they?
The master and the two women.
What did you do in the house?
Nanny.
- There were children?
- Of course.
- How many?
- One.
A little girl?
How old?
Young, seven or eight.
Were the women dark or fair?
Dark and fair.
I don't know their relationship,
they were very secretive.
What did he look like? Grim?
Him? Like your fish.
Black.
All done.
Relax.
I'd kill for a Bloody Mary!
My head hurts.
Relax. Lie down.
Take this. Swallow it whole.
What's the address of that house?
But the next morning...
Lil? It's Julie.
No, not very well.
I don't know... I'm not coming in
today... I'd rather...
No, something popped up.
I'd rather rest. I'll be in tomorrow.
See you tomorrow.
What was the address of that house?
But... I told you yesterday.
7 bis, rue du Nadir aux Pommes.
That's it.
Grégoire? Guilou!
Yes, it's Julie.
I'm so happy to hear you.
You sound so close. How odd.
You're in Paris? Since when?
This morning?
I want to see you. Yes, today.
Three o'clock, St. Vincent Square.
Kiss, kiss. See you soon.
To my Julie. The child has
become a man.
It seems people live here.
Nestor! Fancy meeting you.
Guess who.
I recognize those gentle hands...
...the sweetness of this skin,
the pulse of this breathing.
Guilou, you haven't changed a bit.
Do you remember that Monday...
...when I wildly picked 313?
311, because five of them were
dying purple crocuses.
Those days of blind man's bluff,
when I couldn't find you.
I had no dessert.
Yet playing Hot and Cold you found
the farmer's wife hottest.
Josette was always after me,
even in church after Mass.
Has the presbytery lost none of
its charm?
And the young girl...
...none of her innocence?
It's just as I'd imagined.
Nothing's changed.
The cobwebs caressed our bare feet...
...they were silky and soft.
When I pressed you against the hedge
to kiss you, no one could see.
Red mouth smeared... strawberries
crushed in milk...
...sugared kisses, four o'clock,
snacks, heat...
Kisses and rhubarb jam, cigarettes
stolen from Uncle Edouard...
We blew blue smoke rings.
The forget-me-not song...
white sun, brown stomachs...
...the wind howled and we danced
and we loved... ecstasy!
Ecstasy! Perverse and mystic
sodomization.
Homosexual spleen in the barn,
disguised as Alsatians.
Sodom, Gomorrah, teeth grinding,
loins burning...
Hot lava... sleep...
Sleeping, dying of kisses,
sleeping, kisses...
Sleeping, kisses...
Finish me off, my man-eater.
And now, dear friend, go jack off
among the roses.
You have become an unspeakable
monster of vulgarity.
I never want to see you again.
Goodbye forever, forever goodbye.
It's from the man over there.
Go and thank him.
Mademoiselle Julie?
Mademoiselle Julie has gone far away,
I don't think she'll ever come back.
Where to?
Rue du Calvaire, in Montmartre.
- Tonight you're going to get it.
- I'm going to get it?
You'll be surprised.
You go ahead; I'll go on
keeping my trap shut.
Violins!
If this keeps up, I'm leaving.
I'm eating.
Shut up. Let me tell you a story...
...because compared to your
hang-ups mine are as nothing.
I've met this girl.
And I've dropped my boyfriends.
Shut up! Listen! I've met this woman.
An American. A genuine American.
With butterfly sunglasses?
A terrific young woman,
darling of the gossip columns.
I live at her place. Listen!
I'm not joking.
She has a pink swimming pool. I'll
invite you lot to swim some day.
A heart-shaped pool.
She wants to make me her pygma...
Shit! Her pyg...ma...lion.
- Can we sunbathe?
- Naked.
She's super-rich, her name's in
the papers all the time.
She's taking care of me because
she says I've got something.
She's going to make me a great
lady of the dance.
- Introduce me.
- No, I've got first dibs.
Me next, then.
Is she attractive?
You'll think so. I've been with her
for two days.
How old is she? We've got to
picture her.
- What colour hair?
- Red.
Pale, with freckles.
She gave me a massage.
Well, she has a masseur, he did it.
He's slant-eyed.
- Would she do me?
- She might do guys.
I think she must have some big
political figure behind her.
I don't know about politics,
but there's money for sure.
No names, but that reminds me of...
Yes, an American... he was big in
newspapers, she was like him...
...a bit of a recluse...
...except that my lady's
in the public eye.
Like Marilyn was?
What does your bitch do?
My bitch? You're crazy!
You're not coming swimming.
She doesn't want slobs.
I'm sure I know her.
She's not a dyke, you know.
She's just come from America?
Yes, but she's got a pied-à-terre
in France that's an entire house.
Where?
She told me not to tell,
it's a secret.
Your lady's making it all up.
You're really stupid. She's broke.
She lies to get you to bed.
Idiot! I've been to her place, seen
her money, she has servants.
- Don't be so aggressive.
- I'm not. You're just jealous.
Nobody cares about your American.
You will when you see her.
I wonder if there's a word of truth
in your story.
Listen, Alice, it really is
Wonderland. I'm absolutely ecstatic.
- Lucrezia is zero next to her.
- Tell Alice that!
- I'm getting used to it.
- You're so disgusting.
I'm good at making choices.
- I have good taste, too.
- So have I, not like this lot.
When did all this happen?
Two days ago, stupid.
- Two days... it's not true.
- I won't tell you anything, idiot.
- Shut up!
- Don't get me mad!
- What's the time?
- Six-thirty.
I must buy make-up.
Oh, my sister.
'Bye, Miss Swanky.
Mademoiselle, your fare please.
This way.
Did you have a good day?
I don't remember a thing.
I must get made-up.
And now, the astonishing...
...the amazing, awesome...
...the shimmering...
...the staggering, suggestive...
...most scabrous... most scandalous...
...sensational...
...Mandragora!
It's rigged.
It's fake.
It's fake, sweetie.
What were you just telling me?
Is that your dream?
We all have one...
...deep down.
Best kept there these days.
Could you take the kid out tonight?
I'm too busy with my American.
Where?
I don't know, he'd have fun at the
movies. Right, Paulo?
Would you like that, Paulo?
Have you seen my gloves?
Look what you've done.
May I have a tissue, please?
You all right? Your nose...
Yes, but my skin's breaking out.
I'm sick of all this make-up.
It goes with the job.
I'll become a clown, a sad clown...
...replace Old Père Julien.
I'll get after them, really get up
their noses.
They won't know you?
They wouldn't anyway. They come for
my arse, not my mug.
They doze and drink. Did you see
them tonight?
I like the little pricks as long as
they pay. What are you doing?
Is tomorrow's act ready? Quite ready?
How about this?
Yes, it's all right.
But you should add some feathers...
behind.
I have some.
Green? Not up there!
- She really could do it.
- Feathered Myrtille!
- Hello, kids.
- Hello, Monsieur Dédé.
- Céline, I've something to tell you.
- Tell me here, I have no secrets.
It's good news. Come on.
Wait two minutes for me.
I'm fond of you. You're talented,
full of exuberance and promise.
- I've got you on contract.
- And how!
I'm negotiating a deal on it. A loss
for me, but good for your career.
An international tour.
Ankara, Istanbul, Baghdad, Beirut...
- You're making fun of me.
- Not at all.
In places like that, a great
French artist...
...is worth gold, or better yet,
my dear, worth oil.
I'll settle for oil, I mean gold.
You'll see, you'll make some.
Old Dédé told me that he's got
a tour for me.
An international tour to Ankara,
Beirut...
Wow, Beirut!
It can't be true, I won't go...
He says I'm worth oil, no, gold...
I don't know...
Do you think it's a joke?
- Who is this?
- My cousin.
An American cousin.
With a pool?
Of course. Pink, heart-shaped.
Shit, what's got into you?
Nothing! I remember nothing!
It's no use.
I thought I was doing well,
but nothing went right.
You and your circles... you found me,
that's all, you were in shock.
I don't know.
I'm not getting anywhere.
I don't remember anything.
Look, you're just going...
you're going nuts, eh?
Try. Force yourself.
I am, but I'm getting nowhere.
Look, let's start all over again.
Right?
Try to remember from the moment...
I do start again, it doesn't help.
But start from where you happened
to show up at the club.
Where did you find the taxi?
All right, we'll start from zero.
This is going to be very funny.
I was...
You were...
...pushed out of the house...
propelled.
Then I was... all wobbly.
I felt dizzy.
I was pretty mixed up.
Anyway, I managed to get to
the taxi...
...and once in the taxi I took...
...the sweet from my mouth and
put it in my purse.
What sweet?
This one.
What's the matter?
I see it.
See what?
It is a terrible vow. No one has the
right to make anyone swear it.
Perhaps, but as witness I stand
surety for it.
If you try to disregard it
I will stop you.
Do you think so? Pretty things
do us no harm.
If you say so...
Do not say that word.
You chose the wrong day for
trying to seduce Olivier.
Even so...
You pretend to be unaware of the vow.
Don't go in there!
Was it in the right or left
yesterday?
I've forgotten.
You could lose, but you always win.
You know it is forbidden her.
My own realm, my house, my garden...
...my flowers, my travel books...
for me it was enough.
It would have been enough for
the rest of my life.
But they had to take it away.
The master says it is hereditary.
Well, the scent of these plants
doesn't help matters.
Look what I've drawn for you.
Madlyn...
Blood ties must be renewed.
Must I go on till this ghastly
story ends?
My dear friend, what you have begun
you must complete.
Miss Angèle.
I've no idea where they came from.
But it's odd, though.
They mean something to me,
their faces are familiar.
- They come from far away.
- Yes, they must.
From very far, but they don't seem
at all travel-stained.
Where do they come from?
Zanzibar, Mozambique...
When you've finished with your zzzing
and your childishness...
Look who's talking.
I don't know if my mind went blank
or it's hazy dreams.
It's a mishmash.
It's like four petrified images
of puppets.
Yes, puppets... but they shout...
...eat sweets, faint...
...tell stories...
...fade from grey to blue...
and they swoon.
Totter down stairs...
...and to spice the sauce,
a little blood. Wonderful!
- You know what?
- No, not yet. I'd rather not know.
Why? It will be great.
You don't know the best bit.
Hold on to your seat.
You know the lady in white?
She's my sister.
My twin sister. We're as alike as
two peas in a pod.
The one with none-too-clean hands?
I'm broad-shouldered, but I won't
take all the blame.
You know some pretty weird people.
You should talk, sweetie, your lot
aren't so hot, either.
You make do with what you have.
What you have, you have to get.
It's obvious you never had to eat
shit. The day you do, I'll laugh.
To survive in this life...
...you need dough.
Pack it up, honey, don't make my cry.
But the next morning...
What's the address of your house?
7 rue des Pommes?
It's 7 bis...
...rue du Nadir aux Pommes.
I should have brought my saw.
My Poupie!
It can't be, I must be dreaming.
How you've grown!
After all these years.
My little partridge, my bengali,
how glad I am to see you.
Want your elevenses?
You know, that morning when mother
came for me after all those years...
A baker's dozen.
...I had six months being
coddled by you...
...then she told me Uncle had been
kidnapped by a playboy...
...and taken by helicopter to
the Peloponnese.
Your father did well to leave.
God rest his soul.
What's become of your mother,
with her problems and her men?
I couldn't stand her.
I liked my doll uncles, though...
they were so polite.
Do you ever hear from her?
She flits around, sends me a card
every few months.
The last was from Java.
So she is still the same.
Poupie, do you remember?
The little girl from the house
over there.
After you left she was very ill.
After you left she became difficult.
One day everyone left, I never saw
them again, they never came back.
No news of them.
She was my age.
Their nurse scared you, remember?
No one came back?
Never. The shutters have been
closed ever since then.
Perhaps an heir will come one day
and the shutters will be opened...
...and I'll have some company.
I'd like to see my old room.
It's just as it was, with all your
dolls, I haven't touched it.
I must go.
Already?
But now that I've found you,
I'll come for tea, I promise.
- It's been too long.
- See you soon.
It's broken.
It's in pieces.
Do I swallow them all?
Absolutely not.
You have to take them in order.
There are five pieces.
Well, start with the biggest...
...and end with the teeny-weeny one.
In order.
The tissue will ruin it.
If you only knew the memories
that dress brings back to me.
The sea.
The mountains.
Both.
The Borromean Islands?
Yes, in the evening.
The scent of the lemon trees,
the Kursaal orchestra.
- She was so pale, so fragile.
- More than I?
Out of my sight.
Who? What? Is it...
What out of her sight?
The dress or the girl?
Are they the same ones?
They talk so strangely.
It's a period thing, conventions.
Grand tragedy.
Reeking of mothballs.
Let's continue.
Medium big...
- How is your hand?
- Better, but I must be careful.
Every movement brings peril.
Careful, they are fragile.
Miss Angèle, come quickly.
They're doing the same thing
as yesterday.
- They'll do the same tomorrow.
- The same every day?
- All-day screenings?
- Every day.
So they're doing it in perpetuity.
What next?
My turn now.
- What's up?
- Nothing.
Hello, Madlyn.
Did you sleep well?
Today is a big day.
I disapprove of these little games.
Come, be a sport, Mademoiselle.
What a heady scent.
- Well?
- Well what?
Don't keep me in suspense.
Which hand?
Was it the right or left yesterday?
I've forgotten.
You could lose, but you always win.
You know it is forbidden her.
Madlyn, I've told you not to
hide under the pillow.
What do you mean?
I don't understand.
I've told you, the harm you do her.
I do her no harm.
Keep out of this, Olivier.
I know better than you
how to handle her.
I've cared for her for eight months.
Let me decide; I know better
than you what I'm doing.
Please lower your voices,
the child is resting.
I don't know what I should think.
Well, anyway...
Think what you like.
Today, I'm Angèle.
Yesterday it was me.
But it's still her?
I wonder what she's up to.
And him, what's he up to?
Who is he with?
With Camille? With Sophie?
With Camille and Sophie and Angèle.
What do those ladies want from him?
That's what we may learn
in the next episode.
What did you want to say?
Nothing you don't already know,
Camille.
You chose the wrong day for
trying to seduce Olivier.
Is that all?
You pretend to be unaware of the vow
he made when his wife died.
What vow?
My sister spent her time trapping
people with her vows.
Don't insult that day when
you speak of her.
But if I must repeat it all to you...
Know that Natalie made him swear...
...to safeguard the happiness of
their child, by not remarrying.
This is something I've always known.
I was there, I heard her.
"Because I don't want Madlyn to
suffer what I suffered at her age.”
It's a terrible vow.
No one has the right to make anyone
swear it.
Perhaps.
But as witness I stand surety for it.
If you try to disregard it
I will stop you.
I promised Nathalie. Her wish
will be respected.
Let us make a vow.
Despite my vigilance, the key to
the red cupboard is missing.
What key?
Have you seen it?
- Don't hit it off, do they?
- No, something's going on.
I'd say one is a real slut.
For my money it's the blonde.
All that mincing affectation is
an obvious cover-up.
Any pro will tell you that blondes
are poison.
She's too obviously guilty
for her to be guilty really.
Funny thinking.
We'll let the Judgement of Solomon
decide.
The one who ends up
with the dong wins.
Hold on.
He hasn't one!
He's a girlie!
Another one!
Monsieur wouldn't consider
the mountains?
Olivier, a dreadful thing
has happened.
Do not go in there!
Do you think it could be...
Angèle?
But the next morning...
- I'm ill.
- Me, too.
- I want to sleep.
- Me, too. In fact I am sleeping.
- My legs have had it.
- Mine, too. But who's going...
You're smart.
Who's going to go today?
I'm going.
You want to go? You're dying to go,
you're there already.
It's not worth going.
We have to be serious.
Let's leave it to fate.
Have you got a coin?
I'll look in my shoe.
No more money.
Be sure to give me back my change.
I'll eat it.
It's Swiss chocolate.
Heads I win, tails you lose.
Damn!
I'm struck dumb.
Tails. You lost.
How odd...
I'm going to give you...
A little massage?
An emblem.
- What colour?
- Pink.
Mauve.
- Marshmallow.
- A lovely red.
My little tattoo.
What are you doing?
A double number.
It tickles.
Double 33.
Don't cough.
What do I do with it now?
You can go there. Take your bicycle.
Watch out for traffic.
If I never come back, kiss Harold
goodbye for me.
Stop staring at me, you.
Powder your nose, it's shiny.
The day is composed of four parts...
...corresponding to the four seasons
and the four weeks of the month.
Morning, or spring, time of promise.
Noon, or summer, period of growth.
Afternoon, or autumn, period of
realization.
This is Guilou.
Julie? I've thought a good deal.
We're through, since the day
before yesterday.
Is it really Grégoire?
I've decided you wanted it this way.
Let me get a word in edgeways.
That scene in the square... it was
you who wanted it to end badly.
I'm joining the Trappists.
Is this a game? You're pulling my leg.
We will never talk again.
You're talking to me now.
What's on your mind?
If you want us to break up, we will.
We've broken up already.
I just want to tell you that
it's your fault.
What's my fault?
We can only say goodbye.
So, goodbye.
A Trappist!
Oh, shit! Go masturbate among the
daisies like a Gregorian gherkin!
To my Julie. The child has
become a nun.
He's clinging on.
Properties and powers of
baby dinosaurs' eyes.
The favourite food of
the baby dinosaur...
...who was a fastidious gourmet,
was clover.
For maximum efficiency
use the minimum...
...be a little bit clever,
replace it with clover.
Beirut? Mother?
Excuse me.
I interfered...
Céline? She's out.
It is important, I can see...
Of course, you can count on me.
I'll tell her.
What's this? Where's the Mandragora?
Who are you?
Don't get excited, it makes you
twitch. The Mandragora is out.
She gave me the scoop.
Don't worry, I'm show people.
- Who are you, anyway?
- Haven't you heard?
Not heard of the Kamakaze?
Your guy - they're going to leave.
- Do your best. Get a move on.
- Stay cool, it's in the bag.
Excuse the delay. Artists, you know...
The Mandragora is money in the bag.
Naive, I'm so naive.
Red-headed miss, fingers of bliss.
Naive, I 'm so naive.
When I see you, sirs...
...if I want to make you sigh
I light up your eyes.
If! want to do more
I just lay it on.
Bluestocking, that's what I am.
Shady Miss, a touch like a kiss.
When I see you, gadzooks!
I have no heart, not even for a guy.
Life's played tricks on me.
When I pick up a man,
I say right away...
...you'll be all right with me.
But when he's through the door...
...old loves come back once more.
And memory reappears.
Like a dream.
A past that is mine...
...and kills me.
Excuse me, but I...
I always let myself be overcome by...
...irrepressible waves of feeling.
When I was childish...
...they told me I was a real star...
...a shooting star...
...and a gloating star, because...
...I had a big rayon tutu.
They said I was suppleness itself...
...because I could put my legs
around my neck.
And now I want to express my
temperament, my spontaneity.
I'm very lively.
And... I can do... the sweet woman...
...and the headstand woman...
...on my little finger...
...and the snake woman...
Lots of other things.
And you, anyway, what can you do?
Yes, show me what you can do.
You're here, ogling me.
Ogling every inch of me.
Behind refrigerated glasses.
You're not worth a bean.
Bunch of... pimps!
Cosmic... cosmic twilight pimps!
Voyeurs and perverts!
What is all this?
Come and get me.
Come on! I'll show you!
Want some fun, bunch of idiots?
Come on, let's go!
Oh, shit!
Wait! It's a misunderstanding!
It's nothing really.
Wait till I get the hairs off.
Right, both at once.
- Good morning, Miss Angèle.
- Good morning, Madlyn.
But why so violent?
These flowers are so pretty.
I thought I'd told Mademoiselle
Camille...
...that the sweetest scents are
odours harmful to children.
These plants are so pretty.
I thought I'd told Mademoiselle
Camille...
...that the sweetest scents are
odours harmful to children.
Do you think so?
Pretty things do us no harm.
If you say so...
Mademoiselle runs risks.
I'll leave the roses to you,
because of their thorns.
Goodness does not always do good.
Mademoiselle runs risks.
I'll leave the roses to you,
because of their thorns.
Goodness does not always do good.
- Am I disturbing you?
- You never disturb me.
I was thinking...
Today is Madlyn's first birthday
since her mother died.
And as I look so much like
my sister...
What are you saying?
Olivier, give me the key to my trunk.
I do not want to see
those dresses again.
May I please have the key
to the little red chest?
I understand your reluctance,
but perhaps today...
Madlyn would be so happy.
Look at me. Nathalie's dresses
would so become me.
How lucky that we have
the same colouring.
I don't know what I should think.
I thought that today perhaps...
...at last these dresses...
...should be mine.
Mother left them to whichever
one of us married first.
Since my sister's death,
they've been locked away.
They lie languishing in the attic.
Wrapped in mothballs and rose leaves.
Fashions return every twenty years,
I could wear them unaltered.
Think of Madlyn.
How happy she would be.
Did you sleep well?
Today is a big day.
I disapprove of these little games.
Come on, be a sport.
What a heady scent.
It's hotting up.
Madlyn, I've told you not to
hide under the pillow.
What is it, Olivier?
I've told you, the harm you do her.
I do her no harm.
Keep out of this, Olivier.
She won't get him?
Please lower your voices,
the child is resting.
I don't know what I should think.
Think what you like.
See, I told you.
But I don't believe it.
Someone's used my syringe again.
It's unthinkable and could be dangerous.
Madlyn's still asleep,
should we wake her?
He does not want her to be woken.
He has spoken to you about it?
No, I am the one who is troubled.
These frequent naps...
This sleepiness is abnormal.
He claims it is hereditary.
The scent of the plants
certainly doesn't help.
Sophie, look what I've drawn for you.
Did I frighten you?
Isn't my flower pretty?
Do not say that word.
If you only knew the memories
that dress brings back to me.
- The sea, the mountains?
- Both.
The Borromean Islands?
She's not bad, you know.
I know, I've seen it before.
The Kursaal orchestra.
She was so pale, so fragile.
More than I?
Who? What? Is it...
That thing. You know quite well.
Your whims again, Sophie.
Come with me.
I must talk to you.
What do you want to say?
Nothing you don't already know,
dear Camille.
I'm listening.
You chose the wrong day for
trying to seduce Olivier.
Always the same thing. I'm bored.
But if I must repeat it all to you...
...know that Nathalie made him swear...
Stop. I'm having fun, it's funny.
You can tell me later.
Good night.
"Because I don't want Madlyn to
suffer what I suffered at her age.”
It's a terrible vow.
No one has the right to make anyone
swear it.
What a bitch!
Despite my vigilance, the key to
the red cupboard is missing.
What key?
Have you seen it?
Tied around the neck of the bottle
was a label with the words DRINK ME.
She drank it... the liquid
inside it...
...and became tiny.
Mummy!
Help me.
Take care of her.
Don't be afraid, why hide? That was
Camille, it wasn't your mother.
Don't be afraid. Would you like a
sweet? I have one.
It's over.
I'll never be able to... she hates me.
I'll never get her to love me.
I am tired.
Discouraged again.
It's just as it was ten, fourteen
years ago.
When Nathalie and I were young.
She never loved me, either.
But she was so clever.
It was never Nathalie's fault,
it was always mine.
"Why are you so shy, Camille?
Why aren't you more like your sister?
"You must get out. Let's go dancing,
to the theatre, to the country.”
"Come, Camille, come.”
She was the first to say those things.
But I was silent and refused
everything.
Why? Why, they wondered?
But I knew why. I knew what was
hidden behind her kindness...
...her compassion.
Yes, her compassion.
She wanted to destroy me,
to make me disappear.
And she...
What a shock.
I don't see anything now.
Let's put them back in,
see what's next.
Wait, I want a smoke. Interval, right?
No, I'm going on.
You can tell me about it.
Wait, I'm coming, too.
Coming? Hurry.
You are very gloomy.
I don't like seeing you like this.
Your concern touches me, Sophie,
but I have good reason.
- Camille's appearance upset you?
- It does not concern Camille.
I understand.
It's what she has awakened in you.
Don't think of the past, think of
today, the birthday we celebrate.
Look. The doll I bought for Madlyn.
I'm sure she'll like it.
What would we have done without you?
You are a second mother to her.
Everything I've done...
...I've done for you, too, Olivier.
Do not forget that.
And I hoped that you could perhaps...
that we could...
Alas, Sophie.
Madlyn can draw us no closer.
But is it what you wish?
I wanted to be sure.
Nathalie's vow... I respect it
as much as you do.
But you will hear of it no more.
It's not much like I thought.
Not at all.
How is your hand?
Better, but I must be careful.
Every moment brings peril.
Happy birthday, Madlyn!
You know, inspiration is so fragile...
You can't refuse.
Madlyn would be so happy.
- Please, for us.
- You are cruel.
A sonata.
Another sonata.
Classy.
No, I don't know.
I'll begin again.
My injured hand...
You are so beautiful, in that red.
You are known as the greatest catch
in New England.
I must put my glass down.
It's divine. I'm tipsy.
So beautiful, in that blue.
Hold me close.
I lived just for you, my heart
traced your footsteps.
Naughty girl!
The rogue.
A lofty tower, a bewitched prince...
...and a tree with daggers.
And the Blue Bird!
- What blue bird?
- Don't you know that story?
It's very amusing.
An bewitched prince tries to reach
his beloved in her prison tower.
But a wicked witch has hidden knives
and razor blades in the trees.
The bird is wounded...
...and bleeds.
Stop! All that blood.
Blood ties should be renewed.
Must I tell this ghastly story
to its end?
My dear friend, what you have begun
you must complete.
Excuse me, it's time for
the child to rest.
Madlyn, be good.
Don't worry, my dear,
you won't be disturbed.
I rarely have the chance to tell you...
...how satisfied I am with
your services.
I am duly recompensed, sir.
Not in the way I would like.
Madlyn is fortunate...
very fortunate...
I've run out.
I've finished, too.
Madlyn is very fortunate.
- I'm so disappointed.
- Yes, but...
- It's just padding.
- We still don't know who did it.
We've learned nothing more.
What do we do?
It's full of holes.
I don't know, it's like
Gruyere cheese.
We don't know the end. I hate that.
Anyway, we're not going back.
I have an idea.
At the library...
The library?
Take this off, I can't stand it.
The sun's coming up.
A return to sources both natural
and temporal...
It's the beginning.
...of the four basic elements:
Water.
Air.
- You don't think it's polluted?
- I don't think so.
Very gently, it's the most
fragile part.
You can pour it all.
Earth.
Clover.
How much?
Two stalks.
No, two big ones.
The same size.
Fire.
The fire will shoot out from the
four cardinal points...
...and from its conflagration
you will obtain...
...the memory potion...
...called Herbal Wine by
the ancients.
Because of the clover.
P.S. Beware of side-effects.
Take in small doses.
We'll start together.
Can Harold have some?
Just a drop.
He swallowed it.
It's good.
Very good. Some more...
Let's have another, it's a party.
But I feel funny.
I feel fine.
Really fine.
Mademoiselle runs risks.
Compared to the sweets...
Someone's used my syringe again.
It's unthinkable and could be dangerous.
Madlyn's still asleep.
Should we wake her?
He does not want her to be woken.
Your whims again, Sophie.
Help me.
Take care of her.
I knew what was hidden behind
her kindness, her generosity.
She shone all the brighter to the
point of blinding them all.
She knew how to destroy me,
make me disappear...
...stifle me.
I had my own realm.
It was enough. My house, my flowers...
...my picture books, my travel books...
...but they had to take them away.
"Your sister's getting married.”
"Your sister's getting married.
"They'll come to live here,
it's logical, it's family.
"And they love each other.
"They have secrets,
they must be left alone.
"Wouldn't you like to travel, Camille,
see the places you've dreamed of?
"Borneo, Shanghai...
"...Macao, the Sunda Islands?”
With gentle words they drove me out...
...and with so much money...
...I travelled a lot,
around the world twice.
But it was as if another was doing it.
Only at night was it I.
In my dreams.
Always the same dream,
the same house.
My house.
Now she's dead. I'm alive. Free.
And it's my house.
They won't drive me out again.
I'll do anything.
Anything.
The child will have to give in,
don't you think?
And blood ties?
They must be more important
than everything else.
They must be renewed.
They must.
Don't you think so, Angèle?
Why do you never answer, Angèle?
I have to recover, give me some more.
Blood ties must be renewed.
My head aches.
Everything's spinning.
Julie, I see you here... and there...
Why are you behind my back? There.
- Where?
- There.
Harold's tipsy, too.
Madlyn, be a good girl.
Don't worry, my dear,
you won't be disturbed.
Miss Angèle, I rarely have the
chance to tell you...
...how satisfied I am with
your services.
I am duly recompensed, sir.
Not in the way I would like.
Madlyn is so lucky to enjoy
your constant care.
Could Monsieur make propositions...
...that are more precise?
I had thought of taking Madlyn to
the sea. You could come with us.
Impossible! The mere sight of a fish
gives me amnesia.
Monsieur wouldn't consider
the mountains?
A dreadful thing has happened.
Do not go in there!
You are quite mysterious,
my dear friend.
Your concern touches me, my sweet.
But I have reasons for this mystery.
Both our lives depend on it.
Has my coming troubled you?
It's my turn.
Your arrival awoke in me...
...another world that slumbered.
What you've done,
we've done together.
We have given birth to night.
What would I do without you?
I hope...
...that we might still gather...
...the stars of the Thousand
and One Nights.
I couldn't have done what I've done
but for your presence, my sweet.
This monstrous child...
Will you not reproach me for it
some day?
My sweet, nothing could
bring us closer.
My darling.
I wanted to hear you say it.
Our desires will crystallize
together.
- I'm scared.
- Me, too.
- But we have no choice.
- We must do something.
- Let's go.
- We have to save her.
If we never come back,
what would we do?
Happily, we've still got...
...dinosaur eyes and clover.
We must save the kid at all costs.
- I want to get her out.
- We'll get her out.
We'll get her out,
but we can still be scared.
We can sleep, too, even if
we're scared.
I don't want to sleep,
I might dream if I sleep.
Everything's spinning.
I can't sleep.
I laugh when I'm afraid.
Me, too, when I'm sick.
I feel sick to my stomach.
Once upon a time...
Twice upon a time...
Thrice upon a time...
Only this time... it won't be
like that.
Not like the other times.
We'll get her.
Stop the engines.
But the next morning...
We've got here too early.
Time for a smoke.
- Clever.
- Clover.
First round to us.
I can't see straight.
Where?
Don't try to be clover.
Up the stairs!
A real morgue.
We'll run into stuffed ghosts.
What do we do?
You change, I'm going in.
You look like some crazy oyster-bird.
You think you're so clover.
I'll brighten your façade,
make oranges grow on an olive tree.
Miss... Angèle... Terre.
Mys.. tery... Angèle.
What do you mean?
- This woman's a drag queen.
- No, a defrocked nun.
Everything's spinning... my God!
Take a swig from the flask.
Time's spinning, too. I'll be late
for the camomile scene.
Here, take this.
Eye of lynx and wooden head.
I've forgotten my lines.
I thought I'd already told you...
...that the finest scents are
the best perfumes.
I've forgotten.
You could lose, but you always win.
You know it is forbidden her.
Madlyn, I've told you not to
hide under the pillow.
What do you mean? I don't understand.
- The harm you do her.
- I do no harm.
Keep out of this, Olivier.
I know better than you how to handle
her, eight months I've cared for her.
Let me decide. I know better
than you what I'm doing.
May I please have the key
to the red chest?
I don't know what I should think.
It's taking off.
I'm not a bit clover.
I let the silence in.
I mean, I mixed up two scenes.
- We've had it, they'll be on to us.
- They didn't notice.
And you, Miss Terre, have you some
juicy secrets to tell us?
Imagine, my dear.
I glimpsed Camille in the attic
rummaging in her things.
Did she say hello?
I sneezed. She didn't react.
They're up to their necks in this.
Act Two is about to begin.
See if the coast is clear.
Someone's used my syringe again.
It's incomprehensible and
totally shocking...
Is Madlyn still asleep,
should we wake her?
But he, caught between two fires...
Let her sleep.
He has spoken to you?
Has he said something to you?
No, it's me... I'm getting stuck...
these...
...these whiffs of... it's stifling.
Well, the scent of these plants
doesn't help things.
Sophie, look what I've drawn for you.
Excuse me, I didn't mean to
frighten you.
Isn't my flower pretty?
She's the mur... der... ess!
The bitch! Tea without sugar!
I didn't know I was so emotional.
The bastards! They didn't even
offer me champagne.
It's not funny.
Well, I've won our bet.
We'll discuss it when we're
through with this.
I thought I was done for.
Whether it's Sophie or Camille
makes no difference.
We'll continue as planned.
Help me.
Take care of her.
Do not hide under the pillow.
Don't be afraid.
It wasn't your mother,
it was Camille.
Do you want a sweet?
I have one here for you.
Open your mouth.
You'll sleep now.
My house, my garden, my flowers.
My travel books... I'm going to swoon.
It would have been enough...
"Your sister's getting married.
"They'll come to live here, it's
logical. They'll love each other.”
Lily-livered. Drink some potion.
"Wouldn't you like to travel, Camille,
see the places you've dreamed of?
"Shanghai, Macao, the Sunda Islands,
Borneo.”
They gave me gentle words and
money, lots of money.
I went around the world twice.
You're late. I've been waiting
for two minutes.
I had to answer a call of nature,
I'm not made of clover.
Anyway, don't worry, they won't
get us now.
Eye of lynx, we've got it made.
You are known as the greatest catch
in New England.
You're so beautiful, in that red.
You are so pallid, in that black.
I must put my glass down.
It's divine. I'm tipsy.
We're not in a melo any more.
Eeny, meeny, miny, mo!
Oh, great clover, it's your turn!
Excuse me, it's time for
the child's nap.
You'd lost your talisman.
Not that way, follow me.
Put your leg here.
Wait.
Together now.
It doesn't hurt to fall off the moon.
But we failed again.
The dinosaurs took back their eyes.
What shall we play now?
No more playing, ever.
We're going out.
We'll take you boating.
Got a smoke?
You've dropped your squirrel.