[Crowd Murmuring]
[Man Speaking On P.A.
In Portuguese]
[Train Approaching]
My darling...
my heart belongs to you.
No matter what you've done,
I still love you.
I love you.
While you're locked in there
all those years,
I'll be locked up out here,
waiting for you.
[Chattering]
I want to send a letter
to a guy who cheated me.
Mr Zé Amaro, thank you
for what you did to me.
I trusted you,
and you cheated me.
You even took the keys
to my apartment.
- [P.A. Continues]
- DearJesus...
you're the worst thing
to happen to me.
I'm only writing because
your son Josué asked me to.
I told him you're worthless...
andyet, he still
wants to meet you.
Address?
Jesus de Paiva.
Bom Jesus do Norte,
Pernambuco.
[Mutters]
- Dalva...
- Dalva.
- my hot pussy.
- Pussy?
Your body against mine...
rolling around in the motel bed,
our sweat boiling--
Me, I still--
I still feel--
- Infatuated.
- That's it, infatuated!
- I don't know the exact address.
- I need it.
Okay, then write:
Third house after the bakery,
Mimoso, Pernambuco.
- Cansançáo, Bahia.
- Carangola, Minas Gerais.
Town of Relutaba, Ceará.
Muzambinho, Minas Gerais.
- [P.A. Continues]
- [Chattering Continues]
- Hello, Mrs Dora. Okay.
- How are you, Mr Pedrão?
See you tomorrow.
- See you.
- [Man Responds In Portuguese]
"CENTRAL STATION"
[Chattering, Shouting]
[People Chattering]
Irene!
- What? Coming.
- Come on up! Now!
[Irene] This piece of crap
is as old as I am, isn't it?
Yeah.
♪♪ [Singing In Portuguese]
- [Turns TV On, Off]
- Sit down here.
♪♪ [Continues Singing]
Not again, Dora.
I want you to know that
I disapprove of this, okay?
Here, give me a hand.
Read this one.
"I saw your ad
in the personals column,
and your description was
the only one that interested me."
This jerk wrote the same thing
to ten different women.
"I'm tall.
"I have brown eyes,
straight hair...
- [Making Crunching Sound]
- [Laughing] "and an education.
They say I'm good-looking."
- He's as ugly as a worm.
- Education? He can't even write.
- Trash?
- Trash!
"DearJesus, you're the worst
thing to happen to me.
"At least try and
show up for your son.
He still wants to meet you."
She says the boy wants
to meet his father, a drunkard.
In fact, she just
wants the guy back.
Don't tear this one up!
The kid wants to meet his dad
and reunite the family.
- So what?
- You'll ruin it for them.
He's a drunkard
and used to beat her.
So the boy's
to grow up fatherless?
Better than living with a drunk
who'll beat him.
It's decided: trash.
- But isn't it her first letter?
- It'll be an exception!
I've had enough of this.
I'm leaving.
He'll smash her face in.
So? It's not up to you!
It's her face.
Okay, I'll put it in the dra wer.
No, you'll send it tomorrow.
The trash or the drawer.
I'll send it next week
if we decide.
Liar! Those letters stay
in that purgatory for years.
[Laughing]
[Sighs]
I'll send it next week.
Sit down.
Let's get back to work.
You can be a pain
in the ass sometimes.
"They say many people often lose control
during Carnival. I'm one of them.
We both had a good time,
but let's forget it now."
Oh, I like this one.
[Muttering]
You do?
Really? Really? Really?
[Man On P.A.
Speaking Portuguese]
[Newspaper Vendor Shouting]
[Man] I haven't heard
from home for a while.
I don't think
they get my letters.
Our postal service sucks.
You can't trust them.
- Or maybe they've moved.
- You think so?
- One buck, Mr Sérgio.
- See you, Mrs Dora.
- [Portuguese]
- [Footsteps Approaching]
The other day
I sent a letter through you.
- Remember?
- Yes.
- Did you send it?
- No, I'm sending it today.
Oh, good!
I want to tear that one up...
and send another.
- I think I was too hard on him.
- Go ahead.
- Dear Jesus,
- [Repeating]
- your son Josué wants to meet you.
- He wants to visit you
since he "don't" know you.
- Doesn't know.
He doesn't know you
and wants to visit.
I'm on vacation next month
and can come with him.
Then I can see
Moisés and Isaías.
[Continues Repeating]
You know what?
I'm dying to see
that bastard again!
You're experienced.
Tell me, what do I say now?
- How should I know?
- Help me please.
You think about it and come back.
The truth is,
I still like him a lot.
Jesus, I miss you so much.
It's awful to wake up
without you next to me.
- [Noy Pounding Desk With Toy]
- If I had one strand
of black hair left on my head...
I'd leave it for you to tear out.
- That's great.
- [Groans]
Wait for me.
I'm coming back. Love--
- What's your name? Ana!
- Ana.
[Reading Aloud]
Put this in the letter.
There, it's in the letter.
- Shall I send it or not?
- Send it. How much?
Two bucks, minus one
for the unsent letter.
Mom, how do you know
she'll send the letter?
She hasn't even
put it in an envelope.
Don't be rude.
She's helping me.
- Next!
- Goodbye.
- [Horn Honking]
- Give me your hand.
Hey, my top!
Come on, Josué!
[Vehicle Approaching]
[Brakes Screeching]
[People Shouting]
- What happened?
- A woman got run over by a bus.
- Is she dead?
- She's gone to meet her maker.
- Mom!
- Take him away!
[Shouting Continues]
Thank you, ma'am.
I want to send a letter
to my father.
Start writing!
Dad, come to Rio
because Mom's been hurt.
- Got any money?
- Yes.
Show me.
Who do you know in Rio?
- My mother.
- Who else?
Go on, write the letter like I said!
Only if you show me
your money.
Then give me my mother's letter.
I've already sent it.
Now go away.
- Give me the letter!
- I said scram! Get out of here.
Move it, kid. Scram!
[Clattering]
Come on. Beat it!
Get out!
[Security Guards Shouting]
[Train Rumbling]
Beat it!
[Man On P.A.
Speaking Portuguese]
Hey, kid. Wake up.
Want a sandwich?
- Not hungry?
- I've eaten, thanks.
- [Tapping]
- [Man] Special offer!
Today only! All beauty products
one buck! Combs half-price!
Everything's good.
I ha ve so many customers...
I can hardly handle them all.
I'm saving up
to go back to school.
Thief! Nab him!
- Mr Pedrão!
- Go get him!
- [Alarm Nlaring]
- [People Shouting]
- [Thief Shouting]
- [Guard] Don't move!
- Shut up!
- [Thief Pleading]
- Wait, don't shoot! I'll return it!
- [Gunshot]
Good evening, Mrs Dora.
- Evening.
- Lea ving already?
- Hey, son.
- I'm Josué.
Josué, is it?
Let me see your top.
Oh, I see. Your mother toldyou
not to talk to strangers.
She's right.
- But you needn't be afraid of me.
- I'm not.
It's all right, Mr Pedrão.
I kno w the boy.
Then I'd like
to talk to you.
[No Audible Dialog]
Hey there.
My name isJosué
Fontenele de Paiva.
Paiva from my father,
Fontenele from my mother.
How admirable!
That's very good.
Mine is Isadora Teixera.
Would you like to come home
with me, Josué de Paiva?
I told you,
I'm waiting for my mother.
- She won't be coming.
- You're lying!
She won't be coming, son.
She's dead.
Do you have any relatives
here in Rio? An aunt?
Answer me.
[Man Announcing
In Portuguese]
Look. Take this.
If you change your mind,
you just follow me. Okay?
I mean it.
- [Train Door Closing]
- [Door Opening]
Come in.
Where's your husband?
I don't have one.
- And your children?
- No children, no husband,
no family, no dog.
Then I can use the bathroom?
- Go ahead.
- Where is it?
Over there.
[Doorbell Ringing]
[Greets In Portuguese]
It's hot as hell today!
I'll go freshen up in the bathroom.
I have a guest this evening.
- [Toilet Flushing]
- [Mouthing Words]
This isJosué.
Was it good?
See what a demanding
guest he is?
It's just that
his mother's cooking was better.
No, she was
a lousy cook too.
Hey, you should be
a little more grateful,
you brat.
Irene, what kind
of work do you do?
Guess.
You seem like a teacher,
like Dora.
Except that
she's a letter writer.
You're right,
we used to be teachers.
You've no husband either?
- Neither of us.
- So who takes care ofyou?
We look after ourselves.
Your mother lived on her own.
Who took care of her?
- Me, of course!
- [Laughs]
And your father
never showed his face?
He works too much.
He's a carpenter.
He works with wood.
He makes tables, chairs,
doors, tops, houses...
all by himself.
- Wasn't his father a--
- Well, what do you want to be?
I'm going to be a truck driver.
Our fathers
used to drive big trains.
Yeah, and they were
drunkards too.
It sucked.
- [Dishes Clattering]
- [TV, Faint]
[Dora]
You okay, Josué?
[Train Rumbling]
[Clattering Continues]
What are you doing?
You sneaky rat!
Can you read?
You think I won't mail
your mother's letter?
Well, you're wrong, kid.
It's been so hectic,
I haven't had the time yet.
- Give it to me.
I'll take it to my father.
- Are you crazy?
Do you know where he lives?
Thousands of kilometres away,
on another planet!
- I'll get there!
- You'll never get there. Never.
I think the best thing
is if I mail it tomorrow.
I promise I will.
Do you swear you promise?
I swear I promise.
You're not going to lie again?
No.
[Train Rumbling]
- Where are we going?
- You're going to a great place.
- Hello, Mr Pedrão.
- Hello, Mrs Dora.
Hi there, son.
We're late.
[Knocking On Door]
Hello, Pedrão.
Please come in.
Yolanda, this is Mrs Dora.
- [Yolanda] Nice to meet you.
Now, I'm not sure...
what he's toldyou,
but asyou can see,
we treat our children
as if we were one big family.
[Pedrão] They'll all be going to
wealthy families in Europe, the States.
Once you're loaded with dollars,
you won't forget us, right?
- [Pedrão Chuckling]
- [Yolanda] Let A untie
see your tongue no w.
- Aah.
- [Dora] Go on.
- [Yolanda] It's okay to be rude.
That's it. Great!
- [Dora] I'd like more information.
- We'll talk about it.
What's your name again?
- Josué!
- Tell me, Josué,
are you into video games?
- And would you like an ice cream?
- No, thanks.
Then let's go play
with Shirlene.
- [Video Game Playing]
- [Yolanda] This is foryou.
- Pedrão told you how much--
- [Pedrão] $2, 000.
$1,000 for you.
$ 1, 000.
- [Mutters]
- [Counting Money]
[Pedrão]
It's all there.
Bye, Josué.
[Yolanda, Dora
Exchange Goodbyes]
[Door Closes]
Oh, my goodness!
Blessed Virgin, Mother of God!
- We made it to the remote control age!
- Is it in stereo?
But this stupid thing
doesn't work.
Maybe the batteries are dead.
How'd it go with Josué
at theJuvenile Division?
Very well. He'll be in one of the best
children's institutions.
- I talked to the judge.
- Which institution?
The PadreJesuino Vidal
Foundation in Pelotas...
in the state
of Rio Grande do Sul.
But I thought he'd be nearby
so we could see him.
It'll give you a chance
to visit Pelotas. You love to travel.
- This thing doesn't work.
- No, Dora. Like this.
[TV Turns On,
Woman Speaking In Portuguese]
Can I go see him
in theJuvenile Division?
No, I think he must've
already left for Pelotas.
[Channel Changes]
Where did you get the money
to buy that TV?
I sold a gold ring
a while back.
You're lying.
Otherwise, you wouldn't
bother to explain.
Right, Irene, I'm lying!
You kno w everything about my life!
Now let's watch TV.
[Irene] Where didyou get
the money? Tell me the truth.
Please.
A friend at the station
knows people...
who find foreign families
to adopt these children.
- I can't believe you did that!
- He'll be better off.
Better than in
an institution here.
Don't you read the papers?
Those children aren't adopted.
They're killed
and their organs are sold.
It's not that at all.
I went there!
He's too old
to be adopted, Dora.
Damn it, Irene!
I've had enough of you!
Just leave it, all right?
There's a limit
to everything, Dora.
[Door Slams Shut]
[Man Speaking On TV]
[Train Rumbling]
- Hi.
- I was here yesterday.
- Yes.
It occurred to me afterwards
that you might be interested...
in other children.
We don't need
any more right now.
They're lovely children.
Have a look.
Look at this one.
[Muttering]
- [Door Opens]
- [Man] Yolanda. Who is it?
Hold on. I'll have a word
with my partner.
[Man]
Let me sleep, damn it.
[Yolanda] Nut look ho w many.
This one's so cute.
- She's onto something.
- What kind of work is this?
We're not a 24-hour
pharmacy here!
I never said we were.
Yesterday
I went to bed at da wn.
A fteryou got me into
that other big mess--
You're always complaining.
You're a born complainer.
Ifyou're not happy,
you can get out!
Quick!
Josué, wake up! Hurry!
What are you doing here?
Go away!
- Let's go.
- No!
- Liar! Go away.
- Come with me.
- No, you're no good! No!
- Come on. Hush!
- I'll call Yolanda.
- You'll call no one.
[Dora Yells]
[Yolanda] What's going on?
The bitch!
You old co w!
I'll get you!
[Yolanda Screaming]
You'll die, you fucking bitch!
Old bag! Sleaze! Bitch! Cow!
I'll get you! I'm going to kill you!
You goddamn bitch!
You're already dead!
Esperanto Street,
in Cascadura.
[Sighs]
[Chuckles]
I'm sorry.
I've changed my mind.
- Hello? Who is this?
- Guess.
I'm glad you called.
Irene, listen carefully.
If a big guy with a moustache comes
around asking for me, you scram!
And don't you invite him
in for coffee, okay?
Well, actually--
- I don't believe it.
- Yes.
He's there?
If he is,
say something crazy.
Milton, I can't
see you this evening.
I've made plans
to go dancing with a friend.
Say no more.
Where are you, Milton?
At the barracks?
I'm at the bus station,
and I'm in deep shit!
[Nervous Chuckle]
Is that cute little
friend of yours...
on duty with you?
Josué's with me.
I've taken him away.
I always knew
you were a good soldier.
Irene, do me a favour.
Lock up my apartment.
Got that? Lock it up,
and watch out for yourself.
- One last favour.
- What is it?
Could you lend me 200 bucks?
Send them to the Bank of Brazil
in Bom Jesus do Norte.
Here's your ticket.
We'll be off soon.
Take it, kid.
- I'm trying to help.
- I'll go by myself.
- I'm going with you.
- I don't want you along.
Why not?
Because I don't like you.
- Why not?
- Like I said, you're no good.
How will you get there then?
Give me some money for food.
When I get there,
my dad'll pay you back.
- Stupid idiot.
- Give me my mother's letter.
What's the shirt for?
Getting married?
It's for when
I meet my father.
What are you looking at? Go back
to the bus. I've something to buy.
- Is it far still?
- What?
My father's house.
Watch for the road signs.
They'll tell you.
How do they measure
a kilometre?
A kilometre is a kilometre.
1,000 metres.
I know, but how can they be sure?
How do they count them?
They make it up.
[Drinking From Nottle]
Do you think that man
is a father?
- What?
- Do you think that man there
has children?
No.
He doesn't look
like a father.
But this one does.
- [Man On Radio Speaking Portuguese]
- I kno w the type.
Just like my father.
A saint in the house
and a real prick outside.
Someone once said:
"Are you Dildo's daughter?"
That was what they called him:
"Dildo."
- [Radio Continues]
- [Laughing]
Prick! Prick!
- [Giggling]
- I don't like riding the bus.
I prefer taxis.
You shouldn't. You should
always take the bus, not a taxi.
The bus has a defined route
with definite stops...
while a taxi can take any
route and then gets lost.
Why?
That was in a letter
my dad wrote to my mom...
saying he was tired of riding
the same bus every day,
meaning my mother,
and he'd decided
to take a taxi,
meaning another woman.
But my mother took a taxi too.
A space taxi.
She died
when I was your age.
Ahh!
[Cars Rushing Past]
- Get back to your seat.
- I'm Josué.
Fontenele de Paiva. Paiva from my
father. Fontenele from my mother.
Look at that, folks!
The kid's fucking drunk!
- [Passengers Laughing]
- Prick!
- You drunkard!
- Hag!
The old bag's drunk!
Fucking hell! If I were your mother,
I'd let you have it!
But you're not.
You're not related to me!
You'll end up a drunk
like your father.
Just like you!
Why'd you come with me, anyway?
- I wanted to help. Hear that?
I wanted to help you!
[Nus Driver]
Nenemerêcia! Ten minutes.
Excuse me, please.
I'm with my nephew who's meeting
his father in Bom Jesus do Norte.
This is as far as I go, however.
Could you make sure
the boy gets to this address?
I don't know.
It's complicated.
What if something
happens to him?
Wait a minute.
This is for you.
Go on. Please take it.
♪♪ [Radio: Reggae]
- A ticket for Rio.
- Sixty bucks.
[Nus Departing]
You should have
stayed on that bus.
You were right.
You're better off without me.
I'd arranged everything for you.
Why don't you want
to leave me now?
If you want to talk,
I'll be over here.
Where's your backpack?
Where is it, kid?
Don't tell me
you left it on the bus!
[Frustrated Groan]
[Sighs]
[Horn Nlaring]
I've decided not to go to Rio.
Can I get a refund for my ticket?
I can't refund
your money now, ma'am.
The bus to Rio just left.
- Want some?
- No, thanks.
Yes. Thank you.
Here, help me out.
I can't eat all of this.
You don't look well.
It's my heart.
It's suddenly sped up.
With your little finger,
press in time to your heartbeat.
- Like this?
- [Laughing]
"STRENGTH IS IN EVERYTHING,
BUT ONLY GOD IS POWER"
Going to Bom Jesus
to fulfil a vow regarding the boy?
Yeah, talk about a vow!
Where do you live?
Here.
And your wife?
Here we go again!
Why do you always ask that?
I'm married to the road.
I have no family.
So you're like her.
[Engine Shuts Off]
Please excuse me. I've got to unload.
I'll be about 20 minutes.
Give the man a hand, Josué.
[Grunts, Chuckles]
- [Laughing]
- ♪♪ [Radio: Nrazilian]
[Truck Driver]
Nice to see you, Mr Nené!
Long time no see!
Ho w long has it been no w?
[Both Grunting, Chuckling]
[Both Exchange Greetings]
I'll get the other one.
You can stay here.
♪♪ [Continues]
The boys and girls of today...
are being converted
at a young age.
It's just wonderful,
I tell you.
They're a generation
raised in the values of Christ.
I always see them in church no w
wherever I go.
Things ha ve changed.
They'll be living
in a different world...
more in keeping with God's will.
There's a reverend
who's been inspiring them.
[Train Horn Blowing]
- What've you got?
- Let's go eat in the truck.
For Christ's sake, kid.
Put it in my bag! Right now!
- I'll take it back. Go on.
- Why?
If your father knew,
he'd thrash you!
Want to go to jail?
Put that in here and
go wait for me in the truck!
[Truck Driver] I'll try my best to
bring that reverend here in two weeks.
We'll see what he can do
for the youngsters in our parish.
Ma'am! May I see
what's in your bag?
- What?
- You heard me.
Let me see what's in your bag.
She's a friend, Mr Bené.
Well, let's see what's in the bag,
and the matter's sealed.
[Truck Driver]
Nené, even though we're friends...
and we're brothers in faith,
I won't let you humiliate...
a woman I know,
my friend... Joana.
Okay. It's all right.
- I must've been mistaken.
- Thank you.
Don't you want to get anything?
There's nothing
worth buying here.
Don't you ever do that again.
All you had to do was ask. Look what
I got with the money I had left.
I even had enough to buy this.
- [Scoffs]
- What?
- You didn't have any money left.
- I did so.
Here, eat this.
- Liar!
- What?
You didn't buy anything.
You stole even more.
Show some respect.
I could be your mother.
My mother wouldn't steal
or drink like you.
Right. Your father
was the one who drank.
No! He built the house, and he can
make anything out of wood.
Yeah. Your father was a drunkard, boy.
Know what that is, a drunkard?
You're a liar and so ugly
no one will marry you!
You look like a man--
don't even paint your face.
You're not like Irene.
Even with tons of paint
on her face, she didn't marry.
- You should always steal sausage.
- I hate sausage.
- Would you like some?
- No, thanks.
I'm sorry about what happened
back in the store, Mrs--
Dora. But I like "Joana."
- [Chuckling] Dora.
- Have some.
Mr Bené is a good guy,
but he tends to be suspicious.
- [Both Laughing]
- [Engine Starts]
"WITH GOD I FOLLOW MY DESTINY"
The boy wants to be
a trucker when he grows up.
[Chuckling] Then you'll have
to carry a lot of flour.
To buy a truck like this,
you think it's cheap?
This is a small one. I want
a huge one with a turbo engine.
Could you let the kid
get behind the wheel?
Sit over here.
Careful now.
Don't hit the accelerator.
[Chuckling]
- [Tooting Horn]
- [Laughing]
[Tooting Horn]
[Toots]
[Both Chuckling]
It can get cold here
in the Sertão.
- [Shouts]
- [Dora] Coming!
- Where are you from?
- I'm from Vitória de Conquista.
But I left there
a long time ago.
Since I've been on the road,
I feel like I've changed
my life ten times over.
The downside is that
you meet many people,
and then you never
see them again.
You two, for example.
We'll probably never
see each other again.
We don't have
to lose contact.
Dora!
[Josué]
I'm cold!
I'm coming!
Excuse me.
- [urinating]
- [Josué] In Rio,
I had two girlfriends.
[Chuckles]
Did you know that in Rio all women
have sex before marriage?
- [Urinating Stops]
- All of them.
- What'll you have?
- We're just keeping him company.
Not at all.
I insist on treating you.
Make that three portions.
And I'll have water.
- What about you?
- A beer.
And your son?
A Coke.
What do you do, Dora?
I was an elementary
school teacher.
No, she's a letter writer.
She makes money
writing letters for people.
After I retired...
I started doing that
to help make ends meet.
Don't you like table football?
Go and play.
Go play, kid!
[Drinks Neing Set On Table]
No, no, no!
No, I can't have any.
I'm an Evangelist.
I'm sure He's not
watching you up there.
I want to tell you something.
I'm really glad
I missed that bus.
- Really glad.
- [Josué Playing Foosball]
Listen, I'll be back
in just a second.
♪♪ [Radio: "Ho w Great Thou Art"
In Portuguese]
Could I borrow your lipstick?
- It's almost finished. Keep it.
- Thank you.
[Foosball Continues]
[Truck Departing]
[Sighs]
[Sobbing]
[Josué]
Why did César leave?
Don't you have an answer
to that, like you usually do?
He got scared.
He's one of those queer men, isn't he?
No. He isn't.
- Can I tell you something?
- [Truck Approaching]
You look a lot prettier
with lipstick on.
[Parking Nrake Sets]
[Portuguese]
- Good afternoon.
- Afternoon.
You wouldn't be going
to Bom Jesus?
- I am, but it's far.
- It'll cost you ten bucks per person.
♪ Virgin Mary
of the candlelight ♪
♪ Guide me ♪
♪ To the end of my journey ♪
[Together]
♪ Virgin Mary of the candlelight ♪
♪ Guide us to the end
of our journey ♪
♪♪ [Woman Continues Singing]
My mother taught me that.
[Man]
Want some?
- No, thank you.
- Yes, thanks.
Sure. You're a growing boy.
- How many under the belt?
- I'm nine.
At that age,
I could've ate a whole cow.
- Have some, it's good.
- No, got too many under the belt!
Too bad.
[Chuckles]
♪♪ [Pilgrims Singing]
Mom always said Dad would
show me the Sertão one day.
I wonder where she is now?
Do you think they gave her
a decent funeral?
Come on. Come with me.
Put your mother's
handkerchief there.
- Are we going to my father's house?
- Yes.
Are you happy?
What's the matter?
Don't tell me you've
changed your mind now.
I don't want him
to see me all dirty...
like a beggar.
Your father will like you, Josué.
Don't worry.
- The problem is, will you like him?
- I do like him.
Listen.
Your father's not
the person you think he is.
- You don't know him.
- He built our house--
I know!
I know all that by heart.
You'll soon be with your father.
If you like, I can ask if you can
stay with us for a few days.
Do you know where this is?
Go on, Josué.
Ma! There's a boy here.
- [Clucking]
- Anybody there?
- Yes?
- [Exchanging Greetings]
- DoesJesus live here?
- Yes.
- Would you like to see him?
- Yes. Is he home?
He's gone out,
but he'll be back.
- [Chicks Chirping]
- You can wait ifyou like.
- Come in.
- Thank you.
- Afternoon.
- She's here to see your husband.
- Didyou offer her coffee?
- No, thanks.
Could I know why
you want to see my husband?
I'm sorry.
I can only tell him.
Your friends
have been waiting...
to see you.
- Good afternoon. I've come from Rio.
- Afternoon.
I must talk to you in private.
Okay. Maria, Mother,
please excuse us.
Go on, boy!
Get out!
Tell me.
[Softly]
I've brought this boy to you.
His mother died.
He's got no one else
but you now.
What's your relation to him?
We're not related.
Why did you
bring him here then?
Let's just say
we're friends.
Is he a good boy?
Yes. He's a good boy.
This letter is for you.
[Chuckling]
That's not me.
I'm Jessé. The letter's forJesus,
who used to live here.
Wait a second.
Here, this is his new address
in the new settlements.
He won a house in a lottery
and so he sold this one.
But let me tell you.
He drank it away,
house and all.
[Phone Ringing]
- Hello?
- [Dora] Irene!
Dora! Everything okay?
Did you send the money
like I asked?
Yes, the money's already
there in Bom Jesus da Lapa.
Bom Jesus where?
Isn't it "da Lapa"?
[Sighs]
♪♪ [Pilgrims Singing]
I found no truck to get away
from this god-awful pilgrimage.
- Where are we going?
- To hitch a ride on the road.
- We're walking?
- Yeah, walking!
Hell! What did I ever do to God
to deserve this?
- You're my punishment.
- I'm hungry.
You think you're the only one?
What about me?
We've no money, no food,
nothing left! Understand?
- Nothing!
- What's us going to do?
I don't know.
Your parents should
never have had you.
No w it's me who has
to put up with you.
You're a curse!
Oh, hell!
Josué!
Where are you going?
Come back!
- ♪♪ [Singing Continues]
- [Nell Ringing]
Josué!
Come back here!
Josué! Josué!
[Bell Ringing]
Josué!
♪♪ [Singing Continues]
Thank you!
Thank you, Jesus.
Here I am, Lord.
I beg of you,
I'm praying with all my heart...
with all my soul, Jesus.
I'm a Franciscan
from the bottom of my heart.
Oh, Jesus, bless my people!
Nless my pilgrims.
I'm a sinner, Jesus!
For the blood of Christ!
Look at the hardships
I must bear!
I suffer in my flesh,
my bone, my blood,
in my body,
like our Lord, Jesus Christ!
Protect me, Mother!
Nless me, Mother,
for the blood of the Holy Ghost.
[Pilgrims Praying]
[Praying]
Burn, Lord! Burn!
Flood the darkness
with light, Lord!
[Man]
Let us keep a way evil...
and let the light come through!
- Josué!
- Shh.
[Pilgrims Cheering]
[Praying Continues]
[Applause, Cheering
Dies Do wn, Stops]
[Man]
This commerce here...
this madman's fair...
is the fair of the devil
and the merchants of the temple.
This is the carnival of Satan!
He's do wn belo wjumping forjoy!
The evil beast roars with laughter
at the sight of such shamelessness!
- Hallelujah, brother!
- [Portuguese]
[Rock Falls To Ground]
- [Clanging]
- [Laughs]
♪♪ [Singing In Portuguese]
[Conversing In Portuguese]
For a few coins,
I'll tell your fortune.
- I've no more money.
- You pay me what I deserve.
- You only pay if I deserve it.
What a pest!
[Clicking]
Where are you going, Josué?
Sir, how much is a photo
with the saint?
It's three bucks.
- That much?
- That's the price.
Does it include
a message to the saint?
No, only the photo ofyou
and the saint.
Don't want it?
Josué, what are you doing
at this stall?
- Miss! She's a writer.
She'll send the saint a message.
- Can you?
Only one buck.
Letters! Send a letter home,
a message to a saint!
Letters! Only one buck!
[Repeating Sales Pitch]
- How much to send a message?
- One buck.
- One buck?
- Two, if you want us to post it.
- Holy shit!
- If it's okay, wait in line.
[Repeating Sales Pitch]
Is that right?
Shall I start?
Criseldinha,
I've come here from Itabaiana.
Itabaiana.
I walked all the way,
along the road.
I'm fulfilling the vow I made
to come here...
if Benício agreed to marry me.
Thank you, Jesus,
for answering my prayers.
My husband has stopped drinking.
Leontina Emerentina...
I am now the happiest man
in the world.
[Laughing]
[Dora Laughing]
How long has he been away?
Four years.
- You've had no news at all?
- No.
Love to Mother,
Maria Adalgiza Bezerra.
Josefa Maria da Silva
in São Bento do Una.
To my fiancé,
João Pedro da Silva, in São Paulo.
To our father,
José Alves da Silva.
Thank you, babyJesus,
for answering our prayers.
Thank you
for bringing us rain this year.
I came to Bom Jesus and
set off ten coloured rockets...
in your honour.
Sebastiano.
Here you are.
Your letter.
We're rich.
We can even eat.
Let's shake.
I'll shake you up!
[Laughing]
Come on, let's go!
I'll get you this dress
as a present.
- For me?
- Yes, for you.
- How much is it?
- Five bucks.
You'll look much nicer
in that dress.
I'm beat.
No, don't do that.
Should we tear them up first?
No. Give them to me.
I'll do something
with them later.
Will we look
for my dad tomorro w?
Yes. There's a bus
that leaves at lunchtime.
Come, Josué.
You can sleep here.
- Good night, Josué.
- Night, Dora.
Do you always
go to bed like that?
You don't expect me
to sleep naked?
Sleeping naked is much nicer.
Well, take off your clothes
if you like. I don't mind.
What? Are you embarrassed?
[Chuckling]
- I bet you've never
seen a woman naked.
- I've seen loads.
Sure. Your mother.
Not true!
I've seen other women.
Well, you might've seen,
but that's as far as it went.
- I had sex with them.
- Oh, you did?
How did you do it?
It's not something
to discuss with women.
So I've got
a real man in my bed!
How long will it take
to get there?
How long?
"POST OFFICE"
Stay here.
I'll be right back.
Dora! The bus!
[Chicken Clucking]
It's packed.
[Man Speaking
Portuguese]
Could you tell me
where "F" Street is?
[Clattering]
Hey, you!
Where's "F"Street?
That's the new street,
the paved one.
It's that way.
- [Josué] They're all the same.
- Yeah, you're right.
- Did your mom have your dad's photo?
- Yes.
Do you think you can
remember his face?
Sometimes I can remember,
but then it gets blurry.
I forget my father's face too.
Damn photos shouldn't
be there to remind us.
We should be able to forget.
I left home at sixteen,
and never saw my father again.
Except for once, years later,
I saw him in the street.
I froze, then found the courage
to go up to him.
"Remember me?" I said.
"Do you recognize me?"
I could see
he hadn't recognized me.
He didn't recognize
his own daughter.
He said, "How could I have forgotten
such a lovely girl like you?"
I told the rat
I'd made a mistake and left.
I heard he died
soon afterwards.
- You understand?
- What did I do?
You'll soon forget me too.
I don't want to forget you.
Even so, you will.
[Clapping]
[Man On TV, Indistinct]
MrJesus!
[Portuguese]
Jesus doesn't
live here any more.
- Do you kno w where he lives?
- No.
Vanished into the wilderness.
No one's heard from him since.
Thanks.
So he'll never come back?
No.
I don't think so.
I'll wait for him.
It's no use, Josué.
He's not coming back.
- [Sniffling]
- Why don't you come with me?
I'd really like that, kid.
You know that.
I really would.
Let's go.
- The father's vanished.
- [Irene] What are you going to do?
I can't leave the boy here
on his own.
Of course not.
You know him.
He's really a good kid.
Are you coming home with him?
I'm not sure what to do.
What do you mean?
I've made so many mistakes in Rio.
You know that, Irene.
So what are you
going to do?
Listen, I want you to sell
my fridge and my sofa.
- What else have I got?
- The TV?
Yeah, sell the goddamn TV.
What are you going to do?
When I'm settled somewhere,
I'll call you.
Two tickets back to
Bom Jesus, please.
Not till tomorrow morning.
- What about to somewhere else?
- Nothing till tomorrow.
This is the end
of the world here.
- How do I get out of here?
- Tomorrow.
Not till tomorro w.
[Dora]
Okay.
Two tickets for the first
bus tomorro w morning.
- Are you looking for my father?
- Your father?
- Yes, Jesus.
- I was told some strangers
were looking for him.
That's right.
- Do you know him?
- I'm a friend of his.
What a coincidence,
meeting his son.
Not really,
given the size of this place.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Isaías.
Nice to meet you,
Isaías. Dora.
Are you visiting?
Well, I was in the area,
and I remembered
an old friend who lived here.
Then you must come
to the house for a bite.
People don't often
come to visit Dad.
I insist.
You're not going to refuse me.
And who's this?
What's your name?
- Geraldo.
- Geraldo, Mrs Dora, please.
I insist. Come.
Come here, Geraldo.
- Know what a tongue twister is?
- No.
"Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers."
- Now you say it.
- "Peter pecked a pick of paper--"
[Laughs]
What a dope!
This is where me and my brother
moved after Father left.
Moisés!
Guests from far away!
Moisés, this is Mrs Dora,
a friend of Father's. Imagine!
- Hello.
Mrs Dora, how long is it
to get here?
It depends on the way you come.
Moisés is dying to see Rio.
They say it's nice, but full of crooks.
You find crooks everywhere.
We took this land and are
squatting it, Mrs Dora. All of it.
We took this house
after Dad lost the other...
and put in
this carpentry workshop.
Moisés grinds away here
all day long.
He's even better
than Father now.
He can make tables,
chairs, everything.
We even sell things
to the capital.
Go on, Geraldo.
You can get closer.
Hey, the kid
plays pretty well!
No praise.
His head's already big enough!
I play okay.
It's just that they're lousy!
[Laughing]
Give it to her.
She can read it for us.
- What's she got to do with it?
- She's dad's friend.
We can trust her.
Show it to her, please.
Then I'll get it.
All right,
get that damned letter.
This came six months ago,
from Dad to Ana Fontenele.
She was the woman he was with
after Mother died.
Nine years ago, Ana Fontenele
took off to Rio. She was
expecting our little brother.
Dad waited two years
for her to come back.
He stopped working and
started drinking all the time.
He sold the house
to pay his debts.
[Isáias] One day,
I woke up to find Dad gone...
and a half-empty bottle
on the table.
That worried me.
For Dad to leave a bottle
half empty, something serious...
must ha ve happened.
[Moisés] He just vanished,
but it was better for us.
We saved money.
- Our lives impro ved.
- Don't say that, Moisés.
- I will say it!
- You know Father.
- He's an okay guy.
- Okay?
I'm going to ask her to read it.
Yes, ask her.
It's a letter to Ana, not to us.
Dad never cared about us.
But Ana never came back,
so we open it.
You don't mind
reading it to us, do you?
Not at all.
- So?
- It says where he is?
Go on, read it.
"Ana,
"my misfortune.
"It was hard to find
a letter writer to tellyou...
"that I finally understood...
"that you went back and
found our new little house...
"while I'm here in Rio...
"looking foryou.
"I hope I get back
before this letter,
"but if it arrives before me,
"do as I say:
"wait for me.
I'll be coming home too."
The letter arrived
six months ago.
He's been held up.
"I left Moisés and Isaías
to look after things."
- To look after things? That's a joke!
- Shh!
"Ana, I may work in the mines
for a month before coming home,
"but I'll be back.
Please wait.
"Then we'll all be together:
"me, you, Isaías...
"Moisés...
"and Josué.
"...and Josué...
"who I can't wait to meet.
"You're a bad-tempered mule,
"but I'd give all I ha ve
to see you again.
"Forgive me.
"It's you and me, for life.
Jesus."
He'll be back.
No, he won't.
Yes, he will, one day.
Dora.
Did my father really say
he wanted to meet me?
Of course he did.
I know he didn't.
Hey, folks.
Come inside.
I fixed up Dad's bedroom
for you, Mrs Dora.
Thank you.
Tongue twister, boy.
- Again?
- Say five times very quickly:
- "How now brown cow." Now say it.
- "Say five times very quickly--"
- [Both Laughing]
- You dope!
[Dog Narking]
Dora?
[Dora's Voice]
"Josué,
"I haven't sent a letter
to anyone for a while,
"but I'm sending you
this one now.
"You were right.
Your father will come back,
"and he surely is
all you say he is.
"I remember riding
with my father in his train.
"I was just a little girl,
"but he let me blow
the whistle the whole time.
"When you're driving do wn
the road in your big truck,
"remember that I was
the first person...
"to ha ve you put
your hand on the wheel.
"It will be better foryou
to stay with your brothers.
"You deserve much more
than I can give you.
"If you miss me one day,
"look at the picture
we took together.
"I'm telling you this because
I'm afraid you, too, may forget me.
"I long for my father.
"I long for everything.
Dora."
[People Dictating Letters
In Portuguese, Overlapping]
[Dictating Continues]
♪♪ [Man Singing
In Portuguese]
♪♪ [Continues]
♪♪ [Ends]