(light music)
(tense music)
(rapid footsteps approaching)
(heavy breathing)
(tense music crescendo)
(traffic humming)
(church bell rings)
(background chatter)
(sinister music)
(elevator announcements)
(heavy door opens)
(quiet chatter)
(music crescendo)
(ominous beat)
He is with God.
(ominous music)
(dramatic music)
(sobbing)
(metal scrapes)
(light hammering)
(clang)
(sombre music)
The throne of the Holy See
is vacant.
(dramatic music)
Aldo.
(quiet chatter)
Hey, do you think that anybody
would mind
if I took that, as a keepsake?
- Of course, take it.
He would've wanted you to
have it.
Because we used to play quite often in
the evenings.
He said... it helped him
to relax. (chuckles)
And who won?
- Oh, he did.
- (laughs)
He was always eight moves ahead.
Hmm.
Aldo...
I'm sorry.
Hmm.
No, go on. What happened,
do you know?
No. They say a heart attack,
but...
there had been warnings.
I don't know.
I hadn't heard that.
Yeah. He didn't want anyone
to know.
He was afraid that if word
got out
that they would start
circulating rumours
that he was going to resign.
The Curia.
(ominous music)
Yes.
Okay.
I know this is hard for you,
but...
we will have to prepare a detailed statement.
Who discovered
the Holy Father's body?
I did, Your Eminence.
And then what did you do?
I... called the Holy Father's
doctor.
Mm-hmm.
But it was too late.
And what time was this?
Around... 11:30, Eminence.
We would have called you
earlier, but...
Thomas, I'm so sorry.
I know His Holiness had
no colleagues
closer than you and Aldo.
But I asked Janusz to hold off
calling you.
I wanted to ascertain
all the facts.
You know how rumour spreads.
I've prepared a timeline of
His Holiness's last day,
and these are the Holy Father''s
most recent medical records.
And who was the last to have
a scheduled meeting with him?
I believe that may have been me.
Father Wozniak,
I was the last one?
You were, Eminence Tremblay.
Put in all the meetings he had
that day.
It will show how hard he was
working right to the very end.
Well...
it might look like we
were placing
a huge burden on a sick man.
The Papacy is a huge burden,
especially for an older man.
(tense beat)
Well, Dean,
it seems the responsibility for the Conclave
falls upon you.
(sombre music)
(in Italian): Seal the room.
(dramatic music)
(zipping)
(high tempo music)
(gurney clanking)
(straps pulling)
(light switch clicks)
(door closes)
(gurney wheels trundling)
(siren blares)
(quiet, rhythmic clacking)
(lively street sounds)
(in English): Security say they'd like to test
the electronic jammers
one last time, Your Eminence.
Well, then they'd better
be quick.
Is this really necessary, Willi?
Apparently so.
They say eavesdroppers
can use lasers
to read the vibrations
of the glass.
Really? Well, let's hope none of our brothers
suffer from claustrophobia.
And who knows how long we're going to be in here?
Can you reassure me that we
will be finished on time?
They will work through
the night if they have to.
It will be fine, Your Eminence.
It always is.
- Italy, you know.
- I'm sorry to fuss.
Well, Eminence, I'd say this is
a pretty fair vision of hell.
Well, don't be blasphemous, Ray.
Hell arrives tomorrow
when we bring in the cardinals.
Now, how do I pronounce this?
Kahl-koh, Your Eminence.
He's Indian.
Oh, Kahl-koh, thank you.
Archbishop Wozniak has asked if
he might have a word, Eminence.
Well, I don't think that's
possible.
The cardinals will be arriving
in an hour.
What's it about?
- He didn't say.
I... I wouldn't have
brought it up,
it's just he seemed so... upset.
Ray, we're going to be
sequestered from six o'clock.
He should've come to me earlier.
Yes, Your Eminence.
I'll let him know.
No, Ray...
tell him that I will see him
after I've met the cardinals.
The poor fellow will be
worrying about his future.
(whirring, buzzing)
(quiet prayers whispered)
(distant traffic rumbling)
(footsteps echoing)
(distant tannoy announcement)
(ominous music)
(high tempo music)
(helicopter whirring)
(men chattering)
(laughing)
(high tempo music continues)
So, how many is that, Willi?
103, Eminence Lawrence.
I wonder where Tedesco
has got to.
Perhaps he's not coming.
Well, that'd be too much
to hope for.
(chuckling)
We could wait inside,
if you prefer.
No, let's stay out here and get some fresh air
while we can.
Ah.
Father Bellini.
(echoing footsteps)
Aldo.
- Am I the last?
- Not quite. How are you?
Oh, well, you know,
fairly dreadful.
- Have you seen the papers?
- Mm-hmm.
Apparently it's already decided
it's to be me.
And I happen to agree with them.
(scoffs) What if I don't
want it?
No sane man would want
the Papacy.
Some of our colleagues seem to
want it.
What if I know in my heart that
I am not worthy?
You are more worthy than any
of us.
- I'm not.
- Well, then tell your supporters
not to vote for you.
Pass the chalice.
And let it go to him?
I could never live with myself.
(helicopter whirring)
(in Italian): Eminence Tedesco.
(laughter)
Dean Lawrence!
How are you?
I'm well, Goffredo.
(in English): Sorry, my train
was delayed from Venice.
(in Italian): We've missed you.
- Yes.
No doubt.
(in English): But don't worry,
my friends have kept me well informed.
(in Italian): Are you well?
(in English): No one is ever well at our age.
(in Italian): True.
(in English): And you, huh?
How do you feel with your new,
er, responsibility?
(uneasy laugh)
Everything under control?
(in Italian): Yes, I believe so.
Eminence Tedesco, may I?
- No.
(in English): See you later.
(in Italian): You're welcome.
See you later, Eminence.
(plastic rustling)
(in English): Tell you what, that's enormous.
Apparently Pope John the 23rd
was too fat
to fit into the biggest cassock, so they had to
split the seam
at the back
for him to get into it.
(chuckling)
No.
You look tired.
Well, all this is...
a duty I thought I'd never have
to perform.
I thought he would outlive
all of us.
We didn't part well.
I asked for his permission to
resign as Dean,
join an order.
What did he say?
He refused my resignation.
Said some were chosen to
be shepherds
and some to manage
the farm.
Apparently I am a manager.
(laughs softly)
He told me about your
crisis of faith.
But you should know that he had
his own doubts...
towards the end.
Wow, the Pope had doubts
about God?
No.
Never about God.
What he had lost faith in was
the church.
(door creaks opens)
Father Wozniak?
(loud chatter)
In the name of the Father, the Son,
and the Holy Ghost.
- My last confession was...
- Janusz.
four weeks ago.
- Janusz,
I haven't got time
to hear your confession.
There's still so much to do.
Have you been drinking?
What's troubling you? Tell me.
I should have come to you
before,
but I promised not to
say anything.
Promised who?
Cardinal Tremblay.
Janusz, the doors close soon
and you'll have to leave.
Now, if you promised
Cardinal Tremblay,
then perhaps it isn't
right that you're...
The day the Pope died,
the last person to have
an official appointment with him
was Cardinal Tremblay.
- Yes, I know,
it's on the official timeline.
- At that meeting,
the Holy Father dismissed him.
What?
He sacked him!
Why?
For gross misconduct.
And you tell me this now?
We're about to be sequestered,
Janusz.
Forgive me, but it wasn't until
the last few days
when I started to hear
the rumours.
What rumours?
That he may be elected Pope.
Oh, and you see it as your duty
to prevent that, do you?
I... I no longer know what my duty is.
Were you there at this meeting?
No, Your Eminence.
The Holy Father told me about
it afterwards,
when we had supper.
Did he tell you why
he had dismissed
Eminence Tremblay?
Err... no.
He said the reasons would
become clear soon enough.
(dramatic music)
(echoing footsteps)
(doors grind, clang closed)
(shutters clang, trundle)
(shutters clang shut)
(steam hissing)
(terrines boiling)
(quiet chatter)
(cutlery clinking)
(nuns talking)
Dean Lawrence...
an issue.
Oh, dear God.
One of them's died?
- I'm sorry?
Have we lost a cardinal?
No, Your Eminence.
We seem to have acquired one.
I mean it literally.
Another cardinal has just
turned up.
Well, then, we've left someone
off the list.
He was never on our list,
Eminence.
He says he was created
in pectore.
Oh no, then he has to be
an imposter, surely.
Well, that's what I thought,
Eminence.
But Archbishop Mandorff has
spoken to him
and he thinks not.
Er, what's this I'm hearing?
His name is Vincent Benitez,
Your Eminence.
He's the Archbishop of Kabul.
Archbishop of where?
Kabul.
But he's Mexican.
The Holy Father appointed him
last year.
Last year? So, how has this
been kept a secret for so long?
I thought perhaps you would be aware of
his elevation.
No, I'm not. Ray, ask
Eminence Bellini to join us,
maybe he knows something
of this.
- Yes, Eminence.
- Thank you.
He has a letter of appointment from the Pope,
addressed to the
archdiocese of Kabul,
which they kept secret at
the Holy Father's request.
Mm-hmm.
You don't think he could've
forged it?
Well, err, where is he now?
BELLINI: A cardinal in
Afghanistan?
- LAWRENCE: Hmm.
- BELLINI: It's absurd.
How many Catholics are there
in Afghanistan?
LAWRENCE: He was head of
the Catholic mission there
until his elevation.
But how can we possibly ensure
his safety?
Well, presumably that's why
the Holy Father
wanted it kept a secret.
Well, it won't be in
pectore now.
I don't think we have any
choice but to admit him.
Wait, wait. Thomas.
Are we sure...
that the Holy Father
was entirely...
competent...
when he made this appointment?
(stutters)
I believe this man is legally
a cardinal, Aldo, and I...
I think he has a right
to take part in the election.
(loud clanging)
(chatter)
(knife clinks on glass)
Eminences, before we eat,
I'd like to introduce a new
member of our order,
whose existence
was not known to any of us
erm, until only a few hours ago.
This is because our brother
was made a cardinal by the
perfectly legitimate procedure
known as creation in pectore.
Now, the reason why it had to
be done this way
is known only to God and to
the late Holy Father.
But I think we can guess well enough,
as our new brother's ministry
is an extremely dangerous one.
Welcome to our order,
Vincent Benitez,
Cardinal Archbishop of...
Kabul.
(quiet chatter)
(applause)
Eminence, please would you
bless our meal?
Of course.
(chairs scrape)
Bless us, oh Lord,
and these, your gifts,
which we are about to receive from your bounty.
ALL: Amen.
(men chattering)
(in Spanish): Bless all those
who cannot share this meal
with us
and help us, O Lord,
as we wat and drink,
to remember the hungry,
the thirsty,
the sick,
and the lonely,
and the sisters who prepared
this food for us.
Through Christ Our Lord.
Amen.
(in English): Amen.
Please, come.
(loud chatter)
This is your...
(in Italian): Dean!
Goffredo.
Thomas.
(laughs)
Come.
(in English): Take some wine.
(wine pouring)
(in Italian): Thank you.
(in English): You look anxious.
Oh...
(in Italian): And we haven't
even begun yet.
(laughs)
(in English): Our new brother...
(in Italian): Did I hear correctly, Afghanistan?
Yes.
A marvellous testament to
the Universal Church,
So many men of different
cultures, races,
bound together
by their faith in God.
(snorts with laughter)
Hmm?
Look around you.
Notice how everyone gravitates
to their fellow countrymen.
Italians over here.
Spanish speakers there,
Mm-hmm.
English there.
Yes.
French.
(laughs heartily)
(in English):
Divided by language.
(in Italian): When we were boys
and the Tridentine Mass
was still the only true liturgy
of the world,
we would all have been
speaking Latin.
But then your fellow liberals
insisted we get rid of that
"dead" language.
(chuckles)
Without Rome, without
the tradition of Rome...
(in English): Things fall apart.
The centre cannot hold.
(in Italian): So what,
the next pope must be Italian?
Why not?
We haven't had an Italian pope for more
than 40 years. 40 years, Tommaso.
Can you seriously imagine
the alternative?
(cardinals laughing, chatting)
Excuse me, I must circulate
amongst our brothers.
The abyss calls out.
(in English): It was shrewd of him to stay away
from Rome until today.
One outspoken newspaper
interview
could have written Tedesco off.
But instead, he will do well
tomorrow, I think.
LAWRENCE: Which means?
SABBADIN: I would say...
he's worth 15 votes
on the first ballet.
LAWRENCE: And Bellini?
(soft music)
BELLINI: Why do I feel like a
cow being priced by the farmer?
SABBADIN: First ballot...
Between 20 and 25.
But it is tomorrow night that
the real work begins.
Somehow we have to get him
a two thirds majority, hmm?
By real work you mean what, exactly?
LANDOLFI: But Eminence Bellini, those who seek
the Papacy...
I don't "seek" the Papacy. I...
(doors rattle open)
(cardinal clears his throat)
(metal clanging, rolling)
(in Italian): Thank you, Sisters.
(door closes)
(in English): Listen, you don't
have to do anything.
Just leave it to us.
BELLINI: Tell them I stand for a
common-sense approach
to such issues as gays
and divorce.
Tell them I stand for never
returning to the days
of the Latin liturgy,
or families of ten children
because Mama and Papa
didn't know any better.
That was an ugly
and repressive time
and I'm glad that it's over.
Tell them I stand for...
respecting other faiths,
for tolerating other views
within our own church.
And tell them that I believe
women should play more of
a role in the Curia.
Let's, um...
Let's not mention women.
Why?
Brother, I have no intention of
concealing my views
or pretending to be anything
other than I am
in order to sway any of our
number who are undecided.
So...
if you want to canvas
on my behalf,
then make sure that
my message is clear.
I stand for everything that
Tedesco does not.
- Okay.
- If you'll excuse me.
(footsteps receding)
SABBADIN: Alright.
Rocco, you talk to the Americans.
Villanueva, I'll leave
the South Americans to you.
Gianmarco,
you take the Africans.
Aldo doesn't want it.
Any of it.
You know that, don't you?
SABBADIN: Of course, I do.
That's why I support him.
The men who are dangerous
are the ones who do want it.
(beeping)
(door opens)
I'm enjoying all this mystery,
Thomas.
(door closes)
And I suppose you should tell
me what you want to talk about.
Your last meeting with
the Holy Father.
Oh, what about it?
Well, I've been told
it was difficult.
- Was it?
- TREMBLAY: Difficult? No.
Not that I can recall.
Well, I... I'm sorry to have to
ask you this, Joe,
but to be specific,
I was told that the Holy Father
demanded your resignation.
What?
- That's absurd.
- I...
I don't know what we...
who... who told you that?
Archbishop Wozniak.
Why would he say such a thing?
So, there isn't any truth in the allegation?
Oh God, no, of course not. It's absurd.
Hmm.
- You don't think that...
- No, well, I... I had to ask.
I understand, but no.
You... you can ask
Monsignor Morales.
He was at the meeting.
Well, I would,
but at the moment
we happen to be sequestered.
Oh.
Can you think of any reason why
Archbishop Wozniak
would circulate such a story?
No, I can't.
(coffee machine buzzes)
I really... do you want a coffee?
No.
TREMBLAY: (frustrated sigh)
I'm shocked.
He told you this himself?
Yeah.
You don't think...?
Well, what?
The drinking?
I don't like to bring it up, but we both know
his drinking has been getting
much heavier.
And perhaps it's affecting his
judgement, hi-his mind even.
And...
(sighs)
I know my name has
been mentioned as a future Pope.
And if the Archbishop doesn't
approve of that idea,
maybe he's...
I don't know, I... I'm just
trying to make sense of this.
And the poor man.
He was shattered by
the Holy Father's death.
Yes, indeed.
Again, Joe, er, my apologies.
No, not at all.
I completely understand.
(door opens)
Erm...
what did you discuss with
the Holy Father
in that final
meeting?
Forgive me, Thomas.
It was a private conversation,
and very precious.
Those were the last words
I ever exchanged
with the Holy Father.
Yes, of course.
Goodnight, Joe.
Goodnight Thomas.
(footsteps receding)
(door closes, locks)
(dramatic music)
- Decano.
- Ah!
Oh, we're neighbours, Joshua.
Ah, it appears so. (chuckles)
I thought that I should, er...
(door beeps, opens)
do a little more work on
my homily for tomorrow.
Ah, yes, of course. I look forward to it.
(Lawrence chuckles)
I understand the trick
is to offend no one.
(both chuckling)
(key clicks, beeping)
(door opens)
(door closes)
(cardinal chanting through wall)
(toilet flushes)
(soft music)
(packet rumples)
(packet rips)
(clattering)
You're a manager.
Manage.
(dramatic music)
(choral music)
(church bells ring)
BENITEZ: Decano Lawrence?
(echoing, distorted chatter)
(footsteps receding)
(chain clanks)
(choral chanting)
(book opens, pages turn)
(in Italian): Dear Brothers in Christ,
at the moment of great
uncertainty,
in the history of
the Holy Church,
we must think first of
the late Holy Father,
whose brilliant pontificate
was a gift from God,
now we must ask our Lord to
send us a new Holy Father,
through the pastoral solicitude
of the cardinal fathers.
And we must pray to God for
that loving assistance,
and ask Him to guide us
to the right choice.
(in English):
But you know all that.
Let me speak from the heart for
a moment.
St Paul said, 'Be subject to
one another
out of reverence for Christ.'
To work together, and to, er...
to grow together,
we must be tolerant.
No one person or... or faction
seeking to dominate another.
And speaking to the Ephesians,
who were of course a mixture of
Jews and gentiles,
Paul reminds us that God's gift
to the church...
is its variety.
It is this variety, this diversity of
people and views
which gives our church
its strength.
And over the course of
many years
in the service of our
Mother the Church,
let me tell you, there is
one sin,
which I have come to
fear above all others.
Certainty.
(someone clears his throat)
Certainty is the great enemy of unity.
Certainty is the deadly enemy
of tolerance.
Even Christ was not certain
at the end.
(in Italian): My God, My God, why are you
forsaken me?
(in English): He cried out in his agony at the
ninth hour on the cross.
Our faith is a living thing,
precisely because it walks
hand-in-hand with doubt.
If there was only certainty...
and no doubt...
there would be no mystery...
(whispering)
and therefore no need...
for faith.
Let us pray that God will grant
us a Pope who doubts.
And let him grant us a Pope who
sins and asks for forgiveness,
and who carries on.
(sombre music)
(quiet prayers uttered)
(bell tolls)
(ominous music)
Dean Lawrence...
your homily has
caused quite the stir.
I don't think anyone expected
you to...
To say something interesting?
I'll have a transcript made of
the recording.
Mm-hmm.
If, erm, if there's nothing
else...
Eminence.
Yes, erm...
I... I need you to do
something for me.
Monsignor Morales...
I'm sure he's still in Rome.
Could you try and see him?
- Today? I... I...
- Use my authority.
I'd like to know what happened
in the final meeting between
Cardinal Tremblay
and the Holy Father.
What happened?
Specifically, did anything
occur that might
render Tremblay unfit for
the Papacy?
Of course, Your Eminence.
Bless you.
(footsteps receding)
(slap)
(high tempo music)
(security radio chatter)
(in Latin): And I,
Irumbus Cardinal Nakitanda,
I promise, I vow and I swear
so God will help me
and these Holy Gospels of God,
which I touch with my hand.
(cameras clicking)
(tense music)
Out, everyone.
(loud clatter)
(another loud clatter)
(quiet chatter)
(distant choral singing)
(bell tolls)
(quiet chatter)
(distant choral singing)
(lock clicks)
(doors click)
(doors close with heavy bang)
(locks click loudly)
(in Italian): Cardinal brothers,
we will now proceed to
the first ballot.
You will find in front of you
your ballot paper.
On the top half is written,
"I elect as Supreme Pontiff."
Please make sure your
handwriting is legible.
(quiet whispering)
(papers rustling)
(pens scratching on paper)
(paper folds)
(in Latin): I call as my witness Christ the Lord
who will be my judge
that my vote is given to
the one who, before God,
I think should be elected.
(ballot clangs)
(lid clinks)
(somebody coughs)
(in Italian): The first vote
is cast for Cardinal Tedesco.
The second vote is cast for
Cardinal Tedesco.
Cardinal Tremblay.
Cardinale Tremblay.
Cardinale Tedesco.
Cardinale Adeyemi.
Cardinale Lawrence.
Cardinale Bellini.
Cardinale Villanueva.
Cardinale Tremblay.
Cardinale Adeyemi.
Cardinale Tedesco.
Cardinale Bellini.
Cardinale Adeyemi.
And finally, Cardinal Benitez.
The results of
the first ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi,
21 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
18 votes.
Cardinal Bellini,
17 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay,
16 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 5 votes.
Other cardinals assigned
a single vote, 31 votes
(mumbling, chatter)
(dramatic music)
My brother cardinals,
that concludes the first ballot.
No candidate having achieved
the necessary majority
of 72 votes,
we shall adjourn for
the evening,
and resume voting in
the morning.
Thank you.
(ominous music)
(loud knocking on door)
(doors clank open)
(key turns)
(button clicks)
(smoke hisses, billows)
(crowd cheers)
(high tempo music)
(in English): The media have noticed the presence
of a cardinal
who doesn't appear on
the official list, Dean,
Cardinal Benitez.
So, I've taken the liberty of
putting together
a draft statement.
I've also put together some biographical details
for yourself.
The ministries in Veracruz, the Congo,
where he established a hospital
for the female victims
of genocidal sexual violence
during the first and second
wars.
Then Baghdad, and finally, a mission in Kabul.
Right.
There was some question of his resigning
on health grounds,
but apparently the Holy Father
convinced him to continue.
He's certainly served his
ministry
in some terrible places.
- Yes.
- Health grounds.
Look into that, would you, Ray?
It's the kind of thing
the press like to get hold of.
Of course.
And the, erm... other matter.
The...
Yes.
I spoke to Monsignor Morales.
He was emphatic that he knows
of no reason why
Cardinal Tremblay should not
be Pope.
- Thank you.
- However...
will you forgive me if I say...
I did not entirely believe...
the good monsignor?
He was just...
so... emphatic.
My Spanish is quite poor
and I may have accidentally
given him the impression
that you had seen a document
that contradicts that.
And he said you weren't
to worry,
that... and his exact words were,
'El informe ha sido retirado.'
A report? A report about what?
Withdrawn when?
That... I couldn't say, Eminence.
(treacherous music)
Hmm.
(people chattering)
(bell tolls)
(angry exhale)
(dramatic music)
Third place.
Not what we had hoped.
Your sermon didn't exactly
help us and you have five votes.
You have far too little support
to emerge
as a serious candidate.
Well, my position is an
embarrassment to me.
If I find out who my
supporters are,
I'll plead with them to
vote for someone else.
I'll tell them I'll be voting
for Aldo.
Alright.
That leaves 31 votes
available.
We simply have to pick up most
of them.
(squeaking)
(dramatic music)
(sirens blaring)
LAWRENCE:
The Holy Father's turtles.
He was very fond of them.
A gift from Angola.
(water babbling)
I thought I was imagining them.
I love them. They're so clever.
Well, here they keep escaping
and being run over. (chuckles)
We should go back,
the evening curfew.
And your health, how are you
bearing up?
My health is perfect, thank you.
I only meant have you recovered
from your journey?
- I have, indeed.
- Good.
And in the Sistine, you found
someone to vote for?
Yes. I voted for you.
Forgive me, am I not
supposed to say?
No, no, it's not that you...
No, I'm honoured, but...
my dear Vincent,
may I call you Vincent?
I'm not a serious candidate.
My vocation lies in
a different... um...
After the Conclave, I hope to
resign as Dean,
and then leave Rome altogether.
Why?
I've been experiencing
difficulties.
With your faith?
Prayer.
I only mention it to illustrate
my point
that I'm in no way
worthy to be Pope.
Come.
(intercom announcement)
(metal clanging)
(footsteps approaching)
Aldo.
I... I feel wretched that my
...my meagre tally of votes
may have come at your expense.
Hmm.
I had no idea you were
so ambitious.
Well, that's a ridiculous thing
to say.
Is it?
I thought we had your support.
If we liberals are not united,
Tedesco will become Pope.
You have no idea how bad it
became, Thomas.
The way he and his circle
attacked the Holy Father
towards the end.
The smears,
the leaks to the press.
It was savage.
He fought him every single day of his pontificate.
And now that he's dead,
he wants to destroy
his life's work.
If Tedesco becomes Pope,
he will undo 60 years
of progress.
You talk as if you're
the only alternative,
but Adeyemi has
the wind behind him.
- Adeyemi?
- Mm-hmm.
Adeyemi, the man who believes
that homosexuals
should be sent to prison
in this world,
and hell in the next.
Adeyemi's not the answer
to anything.
And you know it.
If you want to defeat Tedesco...
Defeat? This is a Conclave,
Aldo,
it's not a war.
- It is a war!
And you have to commit
to a side.
Save your precious doubts for
your prayers.
You can't seriously believe
that I have the slightest
desire to become Pope.
Come on!
Every cardinal has that desire.
Every cardinal deep down has
already chosen
the name by which he would like
his Papacy to be known.
Well... I haven't.
(scoffs) Deny it if you like,
but search your heart and then
tell me it isn't so.
(footsteps receding)
(soft music)
(groans)
NUN: Oh, oh, Mother, an evil...
(background chatter)
(man and woman shouting
through walls)
(click)
(shouting grows louder)
(door opens)
(door slams loudly)
(footsteps receding)
(door closes)
(tense music)
(quiet chatter)
(papers shuffling)
(in Italian): The results
of the second ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi,
34 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
25 votes.
Cardinal Bellini,
18 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay,
16 votes.
(furnace door closes)
Cardinal Lawrence, 9 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 2 votes.
(chatter, murmuring)
My brothers, in accordance with
the Apostolic Constitution,
we proceed immediately
to the next vote.
Thank you.
(ballot clangs)
(lid clinks)
The results of
the third ballot are...
Cardinal Adeyemi,
52 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
30 votes.
Cardinal Tremblay,
10 votes.
Cardinal Bellini...
(rumbling)
(loud chatter)
Brothers.
Please.
Thank you.
Cardinal Bellini, 9 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 5 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 4 votes.
(siren blaring distantly)
(birds tweeting)
(siren grows louder)
(nuns chattering)
(in English): Well, I take it
something has happened.
There's been an explosion, Your Eminence,
in the Piazza Barberini.
- A bomb?
- It's unclear at the moment.
There are injuries, but no talk
of fatalities.
We must say nothing to
the cardinal
electors about this, Ray.
We are sequestered,
and they must be shielded
from all news
that may influence
their judgement.
- You understand?
- Of course, Your Eminence.
(footsteps receding)
(dark music)
(loud chatter)
This is exactly what I mean.
What am I supposed to tell them in Milan
when they start to discover our
new Pope's social views?
Tell your congregation that
they should celebrate
the first African Pope in
the history of the church.
If Adeyemi was white,
we would be all condemning him
as more reactionary
than Tedesco?
It's only because he's
not white...
It's too late for all that.
It's too late.
(men shouting angrily)
(clattering)
(chair scrapes)
(woman sobs)
(footsteps receding)
What happened?
(clattering, clanging)
(steam hissing)
(sharp rapping on door)
(door opens)
Good afternoon, Sister.
I would like to speak to the nun
who dropped her tray just now.
She's safe with me, I'm dealing
with the situation, Dean.
I'm sure you are, Sister Agnes,
but I must see her myself.
I hardly think a dropped tray should concern
the Dean of the College
of Cardinals.
Even so, I...
The welfare of the sister
is my responsibility.
And this Conclave is mine.
(bird tweets)
(door opens)
(door closes)
Please sit, my child.
My name is Cardinal Lawrence.
How are you feeling?
She's feeling much better.
Could you tell me your name?
Shanumi, her name is Shanumi.
Please, please do sit down.
I... I really think it would
be better
if you let me deal with
the situation.
Would you be so good as to
leave us now, Sister Agnes?
(footsteps receding)
(door opens)
(door closes)
(chair trundles)
Sister Shanumi,
I want you to understand that,
first of all,
you are not in any
kind of trouble.
The fact of the matter is that I have
a responsibility before God
to ensure that the decisions
that we make here
are the right ones.
Now, it's important you tell me
anything that is in your heart
or that is troubling you,
insofar as it relates to
Cardinal Adeyemi.
(bird tweets)
Can you do that for me?
Even if I give you my assurance
it will go no further than
this room.
Would you like me to hear your
confession?
(knocking loudly)
(footsteps approaching)
(door opens)
I'll be ready in a moment, Dean.
(footsteps receding)
(door closes, locks)
(tap running)
(footsteps approaching)
(Adeyemi clears his throat)
Shouldn't we be going?
In a moment.
That sounds ominous.
If this is about the incident
downstairs,
I have no desire to
talk about it.
(sighs)
I am the victim of
a disgraceful plot
to ruin my reputation.
Someone brought that woman here
and staged this melodrama.
She'd never left Nigeria
before,
and suddenly she's here
in the Casa Santa Marta.
With respect, Joshua,
ow she came here
is secondary to the issue
of your relationship with her.
I have no relationship to her!
I hadn't set eyes on her
in 30 years
until she turned up
outside my room last night!
(frustrated sigh)
It was a lapse, Dean.
A lapse.
'Let God grant us a Pope who
sins and asks forgiveness
and carries on.'
- Your words.
- And the child?
The child?
(scoffs)
The child was raised in
a Christian household,
and to this day he has no idea
who his father is,
if, indeed, it is me.
That is the child.
We were very young.
No, no, no, Joshua,
she was very young,
she was 19 years old.
You were 30.
- Thomas.
Thomas.
Listen to me... please.
I sensed the presence of
the Holy Spirit this morning,
I swear it.
I am ready to take this burden.
Do... does a single...
single mistake 30 years ago
disqualify me?
Thomas, please, I was
a different man.
Please, I... I beg you, do... do
not use this to ruin me.
Joshua, that thought's not
worthy of you.
Shanumi will say nothing to
protect her son,
and I am bound
by the vows of the confessional.
(Adeyemi exhales)
So, I still have hope?
No.
There is no hope.
After such a public scene,
there will be rumours,
and you know
what the Curia is like.
Nothing terrifies our colleagues more
than the thought of yet more...
sexual scandals.
I am more sorry than I can say.
You will never be Pope.
(sobs)
You must begin again.
But you are a good man.
(sobbing)
I know you to be a good man,
and you will find a way
to atone.
(sobbing)
ADEYEMI: Will you pray with me?
(sobs)
(sombre music)
Yes, of course.
(sobbing)
(urn clangs)
(tense music)
(in Italian): The results of
the fifth ballot are...
Cardinal Tremblay, 40 votes.
Cardinal Tedesco,
34 votes.
Cardinal Bellini,
13 votes.
Cardinal Lawrence, 11 votes.
Cardinal Adeyemi, 9 votes.
Cardinal Benitez, 6 votes.
(loud murmuring)
My brothers...
My brothers, that concludes
the fifth ballot.
No candidate having achieved
the necessary majority,
we shall resume voting
tomorrow morning.
(clears throat)
(in English): Yes, Ray?
The... incident this morning,
Your Eminence.
I have more information, if...
No, I too must be shielded from
any knowledge
which could act as
an interference
in the process of this Conclave.
Of course, Your Eminence.
Anything else?
Erm...
Oh, Cardinal Benitez...
who has health problems?
He was issued a round-trip
ticket to Geneva
paid for by
the Pope's own account.
I checked his visa application,
the purpose for travel was
given as 'medical treatment'.
Anyway, whatever it was,
it can't have been serious.
The ticket was cancelled,
he never went.
Alright. Thank you.
Forgive me, Your Eminence.
I know you said we should
forget about the matter
of the withdrawn report.
But I... I wondered...
in light of Cardinal Tremblay's
current position...
I... I could see if I could
find out...
No, I'm not a witch-finder.
It's not my job to go hunting
for secrets
in my colleagues' pasts.
Forgive me.
Please, no more investigations,
I...
I think we've heard enough
secrets.
Let God's will be done.
Yes, of course.
Goodnight then, Your Eminence.
(footsteps recede)
(knock on door)
Was this really necessary?
I feel as if I'm at some
American political convention.
Well, it isn't going to
take long.
Our friend here doesn't have sufficient support
amongst our colleagues to be
elected Pope.
It isn't over yet.
Well, I'm afraid,
as far as I'm concerned, it is.
So, now the question arises,
if I can't win,
whom do I advise
my supporters to vote for?
Thomas,
I am no more an enthusiast
for Tremblay than you are.
But... we have to face the fact
that...
(clanging, gate squeaks open)
(footsteps echoing)
(door opens)
(door closes)
We have to face the fact
that he has demonstrated broad
appeal.
Maybe he'll be a unifying force.
- What?
- Is this what we're reduced to,
considering the least
worst option?
But the field has narrowed.
If we don't change our vote,
we will be here for weeks.
And that's exactly what
Tedesco wants.
We've had a Pope who was
in the Hitler Youth
and fought for the Nazis.
We've had Popes accused of
colluding with communists
and fascists.
We've had Popes who have
ignored reports
of most appalling sexual abuse
of children!
Shh. Okay. Shh-shh!
We take the point.
The point is we will never
find a candidate
who doesn't have any kind of
black mark against them.
We're mortal men.
We serve an ideal.
We cannot always be ideal.
Then we're agreed.
We urge all our supporters to
back Tremblay.
Good.
(footsteps receding)
(door opens)
The other night, you were
kind enough
to say that
you had voted for me.
Now, I don't know if you've
continued to do so,
but if you have, then I must
repeat my plea to you to stop.
Why?
Well, firstly, I lack the
spiritual depth
to be Pope.
Secondly,
I couldn't possibly win.
A long, drawn-out Conclave
would be seen by the media
as proof
that the Church is in crisis.
You have come to ask me to vote
for Cardinal Tremblay?
Yes, I have, and to urge your
supporters to do the same.
Cardinal Tremblay already spoke
to me about this.
Oh, well, I'm sure he has.
You want me to vote for a man
you see as ambitious?
I do not want to see Tedesco
as Pope.
He would take our church back
to... to an earlier era.
I'm sorry, but I cannot vote
for a man
unless I deem him
the most worthy to be Pope.
And for me, that is not
Tremblay.
It's you.
I don't want your vote!
Nevertheless... you have it.
(blows softly)
(footsteps recede)
(tense, high tempo music)
Sister Shanumi is on her way
home to Nigeria.
There was a flight to Lagos
this evening,
and I thought it was best for
everyone if she was on it.
How did Sister Shanumi come to
be in Rome?
I received notification from
the office
of the Superioress General that
she would be joining us.
The arrangements were made
in Paris.
You should Rue de Bac,
Your Eminence.
I would, except of course, I am
sequestered for the duration of
the Conclave.
Then you should ask them
afterwards.
Err, the information is of value
to me now.
Sister Agnes, I know that you
were close to the Holy Father.
When I tried to resign as Dean,
he wouldn't let me.
I couldn't understand why at
the time, but...
now I think I do.
I think the Holy Father knew
he was dying,
and for some reason he wanted me
to run this Conclave.
Which is what I'm trying to do.
For him.
(taps on keyboard)
(door opens)
(door closes)
(bird twittering)
(chair trundles)
(mouse clicking)
(dark music)
I would like you to withdraw
your name
from the next ballot.
(laughs)
You are not the right man
to be Pope.
Er, well...
40 of our colleagues
would disagree with you on that.
That's because they don't know
you as I do.
This is sad, Thomas.
I shall pray for you.
I know there was some kind of
report into your activities.
I know the Holy Father raised the matter with you
hours before he died.
And that he dismissed you
from all your posts.
And I know that somehow
you discovered
Adeyemi's surrender to
temptation 30 years ago,
and that you arranged for
the woman involved
to be brought to Rome,
with the express intention
of destroying Adeyemi's chances
of becoming Pope.
I deny that accusation.
Will you deny asking our
Superioress to transfer
one of her sisters to Rome?
- No. I asked her.
- Hmm.
- But not on my own behalf.
- Well, on whose behalf then?
The Holy Father's.
You would libel the Holy Father in his own home?
It isn't libel, it's the truth!
The Holy Father gave me
the name of a sister
and asked me to make a private
request to bring her to Rome.
I have no idea why.
And now you have chosen to...
(sinister music)
You should be careful, Thomas.
Your own ambition has not
gone unnoticed.
This might be seen as a tactic
to blacken the name of a rival.
Well, that's a despicable
accusation.
Is it?
I wonder...
if you really are so
very reluctant
to have the chalice
passed to you.
I shall pretend this
conversation never took place.
(sinister music continues)
(footsteps recede)
But it has taken place!
(sinister beat)
(sinister beat repeated)
(bell chimes)
(intercom announcement)
(Lawrence breathes heavily)
(sinister, high tempo music)
(music grows in intensity)
(snapping)
(ribbon pulling)
(door closes)
(light switch clicks)
(sinister music)
(drawer opens)
(drawer closes)
(clasp clicks)
(pill bottle rattles)
(book flips open)
(mutters)
(intercom announcement repeats)
(slight gasp)
(treacherous music)
(fearful breathing)
(high tempo music)
(treacherous music)
(door rattles)
(high tempo beat)
(sinister music)
(footsteps receding)
(door opens)
(light switch clicks)
(wardrobe doors open)
(deep sigh)
(wardrobe doors close)
(footsteps pacing)
(sobbing)
(sobbing grows louder)
(uninhibited crying)
(treacherous beat)
(rattling)
(click)
(ominous music continues)
LAWRENCE: It's the report on
the activities of Tremblay.
It's an overwhelming prima
facie case that he is guilty
of simony, which, of course,
is an offence stipulated
in the Holy Scriptures...
- I'm aware of what simony is,
thank you.
- He only obtained
all those votes
in the first ballot
because he bought them.
Cardenas, Diene, Figarella,
Baptiste...
And all this in the last twelve months
when he must have
guessed the Holy Father's
pontificate was... was coming
to an end.
How do we know that this money
wasn't used
for completely
legitimate purposes?
Because I have seen their bank
statements.
- Dear God.
- Seems the Holy Father
was spying on all of us.
He didn't trust anyone.
Where did you get this?
You broke the seals.
I felt I didn't have a choice.
I suspected Tremblay
of bringing
that poor woman from
Africa to embarrass Adeyemi.
You must continue with your
candidacy, Aldo.
(papers rustle)
Put them back.
Put them back, or burn them,
or... just... put them back.
I could never become Pope in
these circumstances.
A stolen document, the smearing
of a brother cardinal.
I'd be the
Richard Nixon of Popes.
Then stay clear of this,
leave it to me.
I'm willing to handle
the consequences.
You know who's gonna benefit
most from this?
Tedesco.
The whole basis of his
candidacy
is that the Holy Father
led the church to disaster
by his attempts at reform.
If you reveal this report,
it isn't Tremblay's reputation
that's going to suffer,
it's the Church's.
Accusing the Curia of
institutional corruption...
I thought we were here to serve
God, not the Curia.
Oh, don't be nave!
(sighs)
Put them back.
And have Tremblay as Pope?
We've had worse.
(door opens)
What has he offered you?
Secretary of State?
Five times I cast my vote
for you, Aldo.
But I was wrong.
You lack the courage required
to be Pope.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(shutters whirring)
(beep)
(sighs)
(dark, high tempo music)
SISTER AGNES: I will do that
for you, Your Eminence
Oh.
(lid creaks open)
(lid bangs shut)
How many copies do you require?
Er, 108.
(copier whirring)
(music intensity rises)
You are responsible for this,
I believe.
(chatter)
No, Eminence. You are.
(sudden silence)
This report is entirely
mendacious.
It would never have seen
the light of day
if you had not broken into
the Holy Father's apartment to
remove it!
If the report is mendacious,
then why did the Holy Father
in his last official act as Pope
ask you to resign?
He did no such thing.
(stammers) As Monsignor Morales,
who was at the meeting...
And yet Archbishop Wozniak
insists the Holy Father...
The Holy Father,
may his name be numbered
among the high priests,
was a sick man toward
the end of his life,
as those of us who saw him
regularly can attest.
(laughter)
(in Italian): If I may join
this amiable dialogue.
I want to remind you that
the names of eight cardinals
have been obscured.
I assume the dean can tell us
who they are?
Let them tell us themselves
here and now.
Here and now!
(in English): If Cardinal Tremblay
requested their votes
in return for the money...
(in Italian): No, I won't do that.
(cardinals shouting)
(in English): Let each man examine his
conscience, as I have.
I have no desire to create
bitterness in this Conclave,
and I will be happy to stand
down as Dean.
(loud, clamorous shouting)
(room grows quiet)
(helicopter whirrs outside)
Eminences.
Although we sisters are
supposed to be invisible,
God has nevertheless given us
eyes and ears.
I know what prompted the Dean
of the College
to enter
the Holy Father's rooms.
He was concerned that
the sister from my order
that made that regrettable scene
might have been brought to Rome
with the deliberate intention
of embarrassing a member of
this Conclave.
His suspicions were correct.
She was indeed here at
the specific request
of Cardinal Tremblay.
(stunned silence)
(footsteps receding)
My brothers...
it's true.
But the Holy Father asked me to.
I had no knowledge
who this woman was,
I swear to you.
(in Italian): Judas.
Traitor.
(footsteps receding)
(quiet whispering)
(footsteps approaching)
(in English): It seems that
we're running out of favourites.
You must take over
the supervision
of this election, Aldo.
Oh, no thank you.
(laughs ironically)
You are steering this Conclave.
Exactly where, I do not know.
But that firm hand of yours
has its admirers.
Thomas I've come to ask...
for your forgiveness.
I had the temerity...
to tell you to examine...
your heart,
when all the time it was
my own that...
It's shameful...
to be this age
and still not know yourself.
Ambition, 'The moth of
holiness.'
I'm sorry.
So, perhaps it's time you
decided... upon a name.
As the next most senior member
of this Conclave,
it will fall to me to ask you
how you wish to be known
as Pope.
For better or for worse,
it would seem that Tremblay
is finished.
This is a contest between
Tedesco and you.
You're the only one who can
stop him now.
John.
I would choose John.
(soft music)
(breathing heavily)
(pen scratches)
(urn lid clinks)
(ballot clangs)
(deafening blast)
(shouting)
(rubble crashing)
(dramatic music)
(laboured breathing)
(footsteps approaching)
O'MALLEY: Everyone has been taken back
to the Casa Santa Marta,
Your Eminence.
No one was seriously hurt.
Some cuts, that's all.
Outside in the city,
how bad is it?
Oh, dear God.
At 11:20 this morning,
a car bomb exploded in
the Piazza del Risorgimento.
Shortly afterwards, as people
were fleeing the scene,
an individual with explosives
strapped to his body
detonated himself.
There are reports of further
attacks in Louvain and Munich.
The current death toll stands...
at 52.
(murmuring)
Hundreds have been injured.
(in Italian): Well, then.
Here at last we see the result of
the doctrine of relativism
so beloved by our liberal
brothers!
A relativism that sees all
faiths and passing fancies
accorded equal weight.
So that now, when we look
around us, we see the homeland
of the Holy Roman
Catholic Church
dotted with the mosques
and minarets
of the prophet Muhammad!
(in English): You should be ashamed ashamed.
Ashamed. Ashamed.
We should all be ashamed!
(in Italian): We tolerate Islam in our land,
but they revile us in theirs.
We nourish them
in our homelands.
But they exterminate us.
How long will we persist in
this weakness?
They are literally at our walls
right now.
What we need now is a leader
who understands
that we are facing
a true religious war.
Do not touch me!
Yes, a religious war.
We need a leader who will
put a stop to the drift
that has gone on almost ceaselessly
for the past 50 years.
How long will we have to
persist in this weakness,
how long?
We need a leader...
(in English):...who fights these animals!
(loud chatter)
CARDINAL: Is this the man you
want to lead us?
My brother cardinal...
(room falls silent)
With respect.
What do you know about war?
I carried out my ministry
in the Congo.
In Baghdad, in Kabul.
I've seen the lines of the dead
and wondered,
Christian and Muslim.
Would you say we have to fight?
What is it you think
we're fighting?
Do you think it's those
deluded men
who had carried out these
terrible acts today?
No, my brother.
(in Spanish): The thing you're fighting is here...
inside each and every one of us,
if we give in to hate now,
if we speak of "sides"
instead of speaking
for every man and woman.
This is my first time here, amongst you,
and I suppose it will be my last.
Forgive me, but these last few days
we have shown ourselves to be small petty men,
we have seemed concerned
only with ourselves,
with Rome,
with these elections, with power.
But things are not the Church.
The Church is not tradition.
The Church is not the past.
The Church is what we do next.
(dramatic music)
(dramatic, high tempo music)
(quiet chatter)
(dramatic music continues)
(rain falling)
(in Latin): We pray.
O Father, so that we may guide
and watch over Your Church.
Give to us, Your servants,
the blessings of intelligence,
truth and peace,
so that we may strive to know
Your will,
and serve You
total dedication.
For Christ our Lord.
ALL: Amen.
(breeze blowing softly)
(ballots rustling)
(pens scratching)
(tense, dramatic music)
(quiet whispering)
Bellini.
Lawrence.
Tedesco.
(applause)
(room falls silent)
(dramatic beat)
(in Italian): Do you accept your canonical
election as Supreme Pontiff?
Do you accept your canonical
I accept.
(gasps, sighs)
And by what name do you
wish to be called?
Innocent.
(whispering)
(resounding applause)
(faint choral singing)
Monsignor.
(in English): I'm sorry to interrupt.
Ray...
I think you should gather
up the cardinals' notes.
The sooner we light the stove,
the sooner the world will know
we have a new Pope.
What is it?
It wasn't...
wasn't the outcome I expected.
No, but it's wonderful
all the same.
If it's my position you're
worried about,
I can reassure you I feel
nothing but relief.
Our new Holy Father will make
a much better Pope
than I would ever have done.
I wonder if I could have a word
in private.
I should have told you this
morning when I found out, but...
with everything that...
And I didn't dream
that Cardinal Benitez would
become...
Ray, please, tell me what's
troubling you.
I found out...
Switzerland.
Cardinal Benitez's trip
to Switzerland.
Switzerland, the... the hospital
in Geneva, yes?
It wasn't a hospital.
It was a clinic.
A clinic for what?
(chatter)
(rapping hard on door)
(door opens)
(in Italian): Eminence,
His Holiness won't get robed.
With permission.
(in English): May I speak to you alone?
Of course.
(in Italian): Gentlemen, let's clear the room.
(footsteps receding)
(heavy doors close)
(in English): I was waiting for you to come.
You must tell me about
this treatment
at the clinic in Geneva.
- Must I, Dean?
- Yes, you must.
Within the hour you will be the
most famous man in the world,
so please tell me,
what is your... situation?
My situation, as you put it,
is the same as when I was
ordained a priest,
and when I was made a cardinal.
But the treatment... in Geneva?
There was no treatment.
I considered it.
I prayed for guidance and decided against it.
But what would it have been,
this treatment?
It was called a laparoscopic
hysterectomy.
(footsteps pacing)
(long, deep sigh)
You have to understand,
when I was a child, there was
no way of knowing my situation
was more complicated.
And life in the seminary is...
as you know,
a very modest one.
The truth is...
there simply was no reason
to think
I was physically different
from the other young men.
Then, in my late 30s,
I had a surgery to remove
my appendix.
And that was when the doctors
discovered...
that I had a uterus...
and ovaries.
Some would say
my chromosomes would define
me as being a woman,
and yet I'm also...
as you see me.
It was a very dark time for me.
I felt as if my entire life as a priest
had been lived in
a state of sin.
Of course, I offered my
resignation to the Holy Father.
I flew to Rome and I told him
everything.
He knew?
Yes, he knew.
And he thought it acceptable
for you
to continue as
an ordained minister?
We considered surgery to remove
the female parts of my body,
but the night before I was due
to fly,
I realised I was mistaken.
I was who I had always been.
It seemed to me more of a sin
to change His handiwork than
to leave my body as it was.
So, you are still, erm...
I am what God made me.
And perhaps it is my difference
that will make me more useful.
I think again of your sermon.
I know what it is to exist...
between the world's certainties.
(distant choral music)
(clanging)
(lighter flicks)
(flame flares)
(switch clicks)
(button clicks)
(loud murmuring)
(whoosh)
(footsteps crunching)
(water babbling gently)
(distant choral music)
(uproarious cheering, applause)
(pensive music)
(crowd cheering distantly)
(click, shutters whirring)
(distant talking)
Hmm.
(curtain swishes)
(window handle rattles)
(ambient street sounds)
(nuns chattering)
(window squeaks closed)