CONFIDENCE
Story / Screenplay
Editor / Sound
Production Design / Costume Design
Producer / Cinematographer / Director
What should one know
about the kind of fear
caused by the sound
of aeroplanes and bombs?
One usually feels
a certain anguish and fear
at the droning sound
of aeroplanes
or the ghostly noises
of bombs falling.
By becoming familiar
with the sound of aeroplanes
and with the expectation of bombs
one can be relieved of such fear.
In flight,
a plane makes a loud booming sound
but one can't accurately guess
the number of aeroplanes
merely from the strength of the sound.
Other circumstances
can be misleading.
A low-flying plane can mislead one
into thinking it's a flight formation.
The clouds and wind
can have the same effect.
One can recognize types of aeroplane
by their engine sounds,
but one would need
considerable practice to do so.
Thus, one rarely
has reliable information
about the type of plane flying
when based on simple human hearing,
especially without sufficient practice.
The sound of falling bombs
is unpleasant for most.
Yet what is it really?
Bombs, when released,
accelerate towards the earth,
causing such a sound effect.
We saw a fine match
between the Hungarian
and German Army teams.
A number of Austrian players
are among the German team
playing against
the Hungarian soldiers.
The spirited match
ended in a 2:2 draw.
Let go of me!
You can't go home.
They're searching your flat.
Your husband
had to disappear.
- Why?
- Please don't ask stupid questions.
Have you anywhere to stay tonight?
At the other end of town?
- With whom?
- You can't go home.
You know of your husband's
contacts in the movement, don't you?
- No, I don't know.
- Good. That was a good answer.
From now on you must always answer
everybody like this. Understand?
What if I had come
from the other end of the road?
We were expecting you.
So you won't let the cat out of the bag.
What cat? I can't make head
or tail out of what you're saying.
Anything might give him away.
So where can you go?
I don't know. I don't know.
Nowhere.
Then go to St. Ferenc Hospital
in an hour's time.
21, Széher St. Find Dr. Czakó
in the surgical department.
You're a refugee from Erdély and
have been hiding at a relative's place.
Your little girl
is in the country, for safety.
You're awaiting news
from your husband.
That's why you arrived here today.
Your address: Erdősor Rd.
5, Ujpest.
Your name: Mrs. János Biró,
née Katalin Simó.
You were born in Kolozsvár,
parents deceased. You're 29.
Your husband, János Biró, is 38,
chemical research worker.
- The child's name is Judit.
- Judit?
When you've memorized that, you'" go
downtown. Take a tram at West Station.
Don't ask anyone any questions,
I've drawn you a map.
It's a one-story house,
brick facade, you can't miss it.
- You ring the bell.
- What do I say? Who am I looking for?
- Your husband will open the door.
- My husband?
Yes, János Biró, and you'll say,
"Thank God, the child's all right."
That's the first thing you'll say,
- Do you have any children?
- A little girl. She's 5.
We sent her to my mother's. Judit.
I don't know how she is,
there've been no letters for two weeks.
You say, "Thank God, the
child's all right." Please repeat it.
Thank God the child's all right...
- Will you tell my husband where I am?
- Of course.
You must face reality.
You won't be alone.
- Exercise a little self-control.
- When will I get news of my husband?
- As soon as possible.
- Where he is staying...?
If I'm right, you know how to draw.
-I studied industrial drawing.
- Very good.
Now I'll leave you to study it.
Please give me all the papers
you have on you,
as well as any family photographs.
It wouldn't do to have them
find them on you.
Here you are.
Katalin Simó, I'm Katalin Simó,
not Sikó, not Sivó, but Simó.
Katalin Simó. I was born in 1915,
11 December, in Koloz...
Kolozsvár, my God...
My name is Mrs. János Biró,
née Katalin Simó,
born in Kolozsvár,
11 December 1915.
Excuse me, some clothes.
My name is Mrs. János Biró,
János Biró.
I am Mrs. János Biró,
Mrs. János Biró.
I am Katalin Simó,
born 11 December 1915.
My daughter Judit was born
in February 1938.
My mother's name...
I can't memorize this. Erzsébet Farkas.
My father, György Simó,
Erzsébet Farkas.
Please go down
to the X-ray department at once.
I have to give an explanation
to the people working here.
- Mrs. János Biró?
- Yes.
- Maiden name?
- Katalin Simó.
- Born?
- 11 December 1915 in Kolozsvár.
The child?
Thank God the child is all right.
- Everything is all right?
- Yes. Thank God the child is all right.
Well, you've come at last,
my dear.
My husband has been
waiting for you impatiently.
You must be tired and hungry.
A hot bath will do you good.
What should I call you, dear?
- Katalin.
- My husband should be here soon.
We could all eat together.
This is our room. It used to be their
son's but he's on the front line now.
His fiancée lives in the next street
and often comes over.
She's very inquisitive about their room.
She's a bit of a Nazi sympathizer.
- So don't have long chats with her.
- Yes.
The door opens out onto the courtyard.
This is the bathroom door.
There's another door
where the old people are.
Living room and kitchen
in one and a bathroom.
We could go through there too
but it's better we go via the yard.
This wall is adjacent
with the old people's room.
Honest working people but best
not to talk in front of them either.
By the way, welcome.
I suppose you know
what's most important.
Yes. Mrs. János Biró,
née Katalin Simó, in Kolozsvár,
11 December 1915.
It's just as well
that my real name is Katalin too.
I am sure you must have
some news of my husband.
It's better for both of us if we know
as little as possible about each other.
But I suppose
they must have tom you that.
Did they send
any messages with you?
No.
Then, I'll wait. You cannot leave
the house without my permission.
But I simply must know
what's happened to my husband.
We didn't know a thing this morning.
I must look around the flat,
perhaps he's left a note for me.
I'll only go after dark.
I'll use the back stairs,
through the surgery.
My husband's a doctor.
You're not going anywhere.
I don't know who you are
or why they've sent you here
but I accept your presence as a fact
and you must do the same.
Try and accept the circumstances.
From here to there is yours.
Why don't you unpack?
I shan't bother you if I don't have to.
I'll get some firewood.
May I see your papers?
I just want to see what they're like.
Will you test me?
The water should be
warm enough soon.
- This isn't exactly the Hotel des
Bains! - I was given the suitcase too.
I'm sorry, but we must behave
naturally because of the old folk.
I'll act natural.
Hurry up.
We've been invited for dinner.
Yes.
You're still young.
Three times I've lived through this,
people rendered homeless
because of politics.
Half the country are refugees
while the other half
either chase them or lie low and wait.
Your soup will get cold,
you talk too much.
One should be happy
with what one can.
Be happy that your belly's full,
that the young lady has arrived
and that the child is all right.
I haven't even asked you,
what's her name?
Judit. She's got lovely long hair.
- The main thing is that she's safe.
- Yes, that's the main thing.
I only wish mine was that old,
he'd be out of this horror.
You did guite well!
But you shouldn't go into details.
What details?
I might have said that
the child's hair is blonde and short.
Don't tell anyone anything,
it's none of their business.
Such small details
can lead to great danger.
Every word you utter might offer
essential proof to the informer.
- But they're sheltering us.
- They're not.
They're workers who rent their rooms
to refugees from Erdély for money.
They have nothing to do with us,
but with their neighbours they do.
That semi-Nazi girl
is almost their daughter-in-law.
Everything you do or say must be
with a possible informant in mind.
Don't leave anything lying around,
don't write anything down.
Don't give any details of yourself.
And so on...
You can turn in now.
I'll go out till you're ready.
Did you sleep well?
Did you count all the corners?
I'm sorry.
I waited with the breakfast
till you woke but I'm hungry now.
Did I sleep that long?
Forgive me.
Doesn't matter. You were tired.
How can I get news of my husband?
Maybe he doesn't know where I am.
He'll find you when the time is ripe.
Hurry, my dear.
They're selling potatoes two streets up.
5 kg per person,
there's hardly any left already.
- Where?
- As you go out, on your left.
We discussed it yesterday.
You can't go out without my permission.
And you queue with all the women
of the neighbourhood in this.
- It's only a nurse's cloak.
- Dead right it is.
But you look nothing like a nurse.
The clothes aren't hers,
how did she get them?
Why can't you understand,
everything has significance?
Your face, your hairstyle, your dress.
They tie their scarves differently here.
- What do you mean by all this?
- Nothing.
I'm just warning you
that this could cost us our lives.
This is not the medical school ball.
Tell me, are you sure
you haven't got any papers
or photographs still on you
which might be dangerous,
- a memento which is identifiable?
- No, I have nothing.
Will you please empty your bag?
Your husband?
I know that I mustn't answer now,
so let's say my brother, all right?
Burn it, you should have done
it yesterday when you came here.
And this too.
Please, this is the only photo
I have of my little girl.
Why can't this be our little girl? After
all we have a little girl too. Judit.
Have you got any children?
I beg you, don't burn this picture,
not this one.
- You can burn the other one.
- All right, this is our child.
As for the other one, burn it.
- Give it to me.
- Do you have children?
- Yes, Judit. Thank God she's all right.
- I'm being serious.
At least answer me this one question.
- Thank God the child is all right. -I
want to know if you have any children.
I have.
Please help me
get news of my daughter.
- At least of her! Please.
- Then, you tell me how.
If only my husband were here.
Wake up! Where's your husband?
My husband?
You're my husband, János Biró.
I'm Mrs. János Biró, Katalin Simó.
Don't talk rubbish.
Where's your husband?
Here. I'm Mrs. János Biró.
All right. Go back to sleep!
Good morning.
Why did you do
that horrible thing in the night?
What?
Look, we are both in a dark forest.
That's why I have to know
if I can let you walk behind me.
If I don't trust you,
you can't come with me on patrol.
I'd kill you the moment
I notice the slightest suspicion.
I'll kill you so you can't kill me.
Do you understand?
I keep dreaming about my son.
He comes through the gate
and stands by this door
and I shake in fear
in case someone has seen him here
because then they'll know
that he deserted.
He stands there a while,
looks through the window and leaves.
And then I'm relieved and wake up.
Why do I dream this?
My husband is restless too
in the night, he wakes up.
Then I wake up too. It took me
a while to go back to sleep last night.
The old woman told me you've been
complaining that I'm restless at night,
that I wake up and wake you up too.
What's the good of telling you?
What's that got to do with
the old woman and her neighbours
and via them
God knows who else, how I sleep?
My underwear is in front of you.
Are you going to tell her about it too?
What they're like,
how often I change them?
If I disturb you in your sleep,
perhaps I snore,
though you'd be the first one
to say so, rather than wake me up.
Tell me not to, give me a nudge.
And another thing.
The old woman tells me everything.
She feels that I belong
to them a little by now.
Whatever you say to her,
you can count as a message to me.
I'm sorry.
My wife told me you dream
of your son a lot.
- What did she say?
- The things you dream of, Aunty Irma.
One talks a lot of nonsense...
we were cleaning peas.
- Leave it, I'll chop those logs up.
- I'll have it done in a second.
Come quickly. Can't you
understand? Don't loiter here.
How long has he been there?
Who is he observing?
I've seen him before.
How long has he been watching us?
He was following us a while back,
yet no one was behind us.
This one's popped up
out of the blue...
If I turn around suddenly,
maybe he isn't even there.
I mustn't turn around,
he's not coming.
That's all right. He was simply
waiting for someone, what a joke.
He was just a pedestrian,
you're beginning to see things.
I was thirsty.
Don't I know you
from way back?
I don't know,
I don't remember you.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
Tell me, would you at least
help me get news of my husband?
There's a lieutenant looking for you.
- My husband's not at home.
- I told him but he said he'll wait.
- Pali Szilasi.
- Good day, lieutenant. Mrs. János Biró.
I'm looking for your husband.
I've known him for a long time
but we lost touch a while back.
We live in such an age, lieutenant.
People lose touch.
These are terrible times,
but it'" soon be over.
It can't last much longer now.
- When will your husband be home?
- I don't know.
Your husband's a wonderful man,
I've known him since I was a kid.
- I learnt a lot from him.
- Yes. My husband is very attractive.
You're a lucky woman,
but he is even luckier with you.
That's very kind of you.
The lieutenant has been waiting
for you for a while.
I'm sure he wouldn't say
no to a cup of tea.
The lieutenant is very smart.
Isn't it a bit risky?
This is my safety,
people respect uniform religiously,
and the women go crazy about it.
I don't know where János
has been hiding you.
It takes a war to enable me
to court my best friend's wife.
So far,
I've only seen a photo of you.
- Where?
- János showed me one a long time ago.
I can just imagine
what sort of photo that was.
All photos of me were terrible.
I couldn't have recognized
you by them.
- I think you have to go.
- Yes.
- When will we see you again?
- When he can come.
He's forgotten...
He didn't forget it,
he's the one we've been waiting for.
But you were faultless.
Another exam?
And were you both satisfied?
It must have been entertaining.
Or perhaps
you're afraid of me too?
Where have you been
the last few years?
Or now on 15 October,
or yesterday,
that you don't wonder
about anything or anyone?
I don't know what's in your head,
but as far as I'm concerned
there's no place left for innocence
and naivety in my life.
Our only chance is to be prepared
to face any and every betrayal.
- Is that the way you like it?
- What?
Did you have a quarrel?
Don't cry.
I see you're both so tight-lipped.
That's worse
than shouting at each other.
Are you worried about the little girl?
Everyone is worried.
- Why are you crying?
- Oh, my God, why?
I don't know what's happening to
my child, or where my husband is.
"You're not alone!"
- Do you know this writing?
- Yes, it's my husband's.
"Darling, I'm safe.
I'll come for you soon.
"It hurts me too
that we had to part so suddenly..."
Thank you,
you're a good man after all.
Well, now we must burn this.
Be careful, your husband's
got someone, I know.
No, it's not true...
Come on, quieten down, wake up.
Calm down, you've been
shouting in your sleep.
Would you like some water?
Calm down now.
Lie back and go back to sleep.
Tamás... Tamás...
- There you are.
- Thank you.
That blonde lady next
to the window sent you this.
"It seems
human cowardice has no limits"
- Aren't you feeling well?
- I'm sorry.
Don't you recognize me?
It must be my hair. I dyed it blonde.
But I thought that this way
I won't look so obviously...
It suits you.
You cannot stay anywhere for long.
After a while you have to escape again.
Just one night, could I come
to your place, just for a night.
I can't go on looking for a place.
I don't want to die like a dog.
I'm sorry, but you must have got
me mixed up with someone else.
Of course, I haven't seen you
since I got my nose fixed.
But don't you really recognize me?
I know that my face looks different
with this nose.
Two years ago, I thought
it might save my life.
What's your name?
Bözsi. Don't you remember?
I sat next to the window in form 2.
Bözsi what?!
No, you don't want
to recognize me.
What Bözsi?!
She's guite clever, having her face
changed. Now let's hear her name.
Deutsch? Löblin? Maisler? Wippler?
Ehrlich? Bettelsheim? Sonnenschein?
I'm Bözsi Tóth
and you go and fuck yourself.
You can all go and fuck yourselves.
Base, coward pretenders.
I hope God will treat you
the way you are treating us!
And I hope your children
will despise you!
Why are you crying?
What's happened?
- Where were you?
- I was busy.
Who was that woman
who followed you to the toilet?
She's in hiding
and has nowhere to sleep.
- Do you know her?
- No.
She said she was a schoolfriend
but I can't remember her.
- Are you sure? You've never seen her?
- I don't know.
- And the man who spoke to you?
- Nobody spoke to me at all.
- Why did you start running away?
- I don't know.
They why did you turn around.
Who were you waiting for?
- I didn't know what happened to you.
- You got a scare.
- Yes.
- Why?
From where do you know
that man I was with?
- I don't know him.
- You've never seen him before?
No. I did a Red Cross
nursing course last year.
My husband insisted on it
and there, one sees so many people...
Maybe...
That woman begged me
to put her up for the night.
She could have come here.
There are three beds.
- What did you say to her?
-I don't know. It was dreadful.
- Keep your voice down.
- I told her I couldn't help.
- Good.
- Her life was at stake.
- We can't risk anything now.
- I can't bear this.
- Who do you think I am?
- Ouiet!
You treat me like a child
not to be trusted,
that I don't need to know anything
because I can't understand.
And if I ask too many questions,
you must smack me like a child?!
- Who is it?
- It's me. There's a raid.
They've closed off the whole area.
They're looking for someone.
In the whole street, the gardens too.
Did you see anyone?
Did anyone come here?
Then they're searching in vain.
Go back to bed.
Keep your thoughts on the fact
that we're refugees from Erdély
and nobody can be looking for us.
Our papers are in order and it would
just be an unpleasant formality.
- Did you hear what I said?
- Yes.
- I think I am terribly afraid.
- So am I, it's natural.
But at least
we can be afraid together.
That's it, they've caught him.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I think so.
Thank God!
We've escaped this time.
You're happy
because you've escaped.
I'm sorry.
- Nice.
- The room's brighter this way.
I think the cupboard
was better against that wall.
It was a good sound barrier
between the old folk and us.
We should keep our voices
down in any case.
What are you looking at?
My hair looks awful.
It's beautiful.
Beautiful you say?
Well, what do you know?!
I look dreadful in these clothes. I like
nice clothes. It's a joke, isn't it?
We are both full of complexes.
But I like my complexes.
I feel quite comfortable with them.
What a fool I am!
I am married.
Yes, yes.
I want you too, believe me.
My first lover!
I've got a lover!
Good morning.
How did you sleep?
- And you?
- Very well.
- What did you dream about?
- I can't remember.
You must have been facing the window,
that's why you don't remember.
Breakfast is ready. Shall I bring yours
here, or would you rather come out?
Good morning.
Sit down.
I haven't had breakfast yet either.
I like having my tea standing up.
Do you want to take back
what you've done?
If you don't want to remember
last night you needn't.
Last night was beautiful.
Thank you.
I love stroking your hand.
Is that enough?
No, but I can't explain
why it's not enough.
- Why did you clench your fist?
- No reason. Instinct.
You're a coward.
You're more of a coward than I am.
- I've decided not to kiss you.
- Why?
I don't know, it's just that
I can see myself from the outside.
Who can see you constantly
the way you see yourself?
You can.
Really?
Do I look at you like that? I've come
to love you, do you believe me?
Why should I believe her?
She just wants to be certain
that she's attached me to herself,
to make me give myself up.
Doesn't the fact that
we made love mean anything to you?
- You're going too fast.
- Really? Sorry.
Attention!
Turn away, they're filming us.
Damn it, where's that Pali?
They are filming us.
And action!
- My respects, madam.
- Watch out, they're filming.
Probably for the Wochenschau.
"Happy interlude
on the Hungarian theater of war".
You'd have looked great.
Young lovers defying hard times.
The Gestapo
would have loved that film.
I'd have been a hit as the young
allied officer. You have a letter.
- From who?
- Your wife.
- Are these the ones?
- Get the hell out of here.
Take my arm and don't look back.
Go down the street
and buy something, anything.
I'll meet you at the tram stop.
Go home if I'm not there.
Be sure you're not being followed.
If you are, try to lose them.
There are houses with
passageways by the East Station.
Christmas trees!
Christmas is the feast of love!
Buy your Christmas trees now.
- What would you like?
- Some paper and envelopes.
I was waiting for my husband
by the Christmas tree seller.
Hoffmann. I am so glad
to make your acquaintance too.
We studied chemistry
together in Duisburg.
He disappeared in '33.
I haven't heard of him since,
and suddenly here he is.
Shall we go and sit down somewhere?
- We have a prior engagement.
-I am free all day.
- We can't make it today.
- Do you live nearby?
- No, the other end of town.
- I'd like to see you one evening.
It would be good to have a quiet chat.
I haven't been able to put
two normal words together
ever since this thing started.
One doesn't talk too much
these days.
Would you have thought in '31
that this would come to pass?
At times I think,
"God why have you forsaken us?"
It's laughable isn't it?
I was overwhelmed with joy
when I saw your husband.
There's a woman queuing up
by the bakery, officer.
She has no right to be on the streets.
They had a pharmacy.
Have her taken away. There she is,
a fugitive, in a blue coat.
Leave me alone, call a policeman.
What do you say
to the world we live in.
What have we got to do
with these things?
Let me write down
your address quickly.
Szív utca 5 in the center of town.
- Day after tomorrow, in the evening.
- We'll be expecting you.
- This is Lotte, my wife.
- We've got a daughter, Judit.
Well, see you
the day after tomorrow.
- Let's hurry.
- We should warn that woman.
You expect me not to warn her?
Don't interfere.
It might be provocation.
And let that poor woman
be taken away?!
Get on!
Please go alone now.
I have to see to something here.