He told me the other day...
... there is an elephant in Manzhouli.
It sits there all day long.
Perhaps some people keep
stabbing it with forks.
Or maybe it just enjoys sitting there.
I don't know.
People gather there,
watching it sitting still.
They feed the elephant food.
but it takes no notice.
He told me that before.
What did he say?
You are stepping on my pants.
Same thing.
Give me some water.
What's the smell?
Who opened the freaking window?
I'm closing it now.
It's too late!
Now the apartment is stinky!
A lousy day starts again!
It's the kitchen window.
What?
The smell comes in
through the kitchen window.
No one cleans the garbage down there.
It's much better than your bedroom!
The dumpster smells better
than your nasty room!
Where's my gift card?
No idea.
You used it the other day.
Where is it now?
Check the cupboard.
It's not there.
Well, I don't know.
He stole it.
I didn't.
You gave a 20% off to
customers at the supermarket.
You then spent the kickback
at Internet cafés!
I did not.
What else can you do?
You little piece of crap.
No one wants the same
lecture every morning.
Am I wrong?
Go to your Grandma's. You're gross.
I'd have gone there already
if there's heat in her place.
We don't have heat either!
You are stinking this place out!
Get out.
Carry the bag.
I'm off.
You're not allowed to burn it here.
Then where?
I don't care. Not in this neighborhood!
But these are from the neighborhood.
You deaf?
You can't burn it here!
Burn it right here!
Who do you think you are?
Come down here You piece of crap!
I'm your Daddy.
Get down here!
Get lost.
Till tonight.
No way.
Why?
I'm leaving for work.
Sometimes when you smoke.
your skin peels off.
and blood will remain on the cigarette.
You see?
So?
You didn't give me the water I asked.
I have to leave.
Suit yourself.
You used the gift card for cigarettes.
I didn't.
What did you buy then?
It's not even yours.
You picked it up on the street.
School district housing
is triple the price of normal housing.
Of course it's not necessary.
But our daughter will go
to a less qualified school.
She might be bullied.
I can't watch my kid going to the
terrible high school where I'm working.
So school district housing is the
only option for a better education.
Your feet.
But our money can only afford
a small school district apartment.
Keep it tight.
We can't all move in.
There's not enough space.
That's why we want to
send you to a nursing home.
You always think.
we want to abandon you that way.
Your instep.
Why do I have to stretch in the morning?
Frequent training
makes you a good dancer.
They say I'm good enough.
You can do better.
What for?
Straighten up your back.
The school forbids us to
tutor students outside.
My own student told on me once.
Private schools don't
have these restrictions.
But it offers no
welfare guarantee either.
It's not an iron bowl in the long run.
Hold on.
It's possible to transfer
to a branch school,
but takes a lot of effort.
Our school acquired a private school
and founded this so-called branch school.
The pay is good
but it sounds less decent.
I'm still thinking about it.
Shoulder.
Good.
Good, go on.
I can't keep my dog at nursing homes.
I can't go there.
OK, I understand.
Let Grandpa help me with the stretching.
He's good at it.
Concentrate.
Dad, please be more considerate.
She doesn't even have a
place to do her homework.
She can't always write
on your sewing machine.
This is my apartment.
Dad, please stop.
We didn't mean it that way.
This is not the first
time you brought it up.
We are not forcing you.
I saw your mother.
What happened?
He slashed my bicycle tires.
Why did you bring it here?
My Dad will beat me up if he knows it.
What's your plan?
I don't know.
Let's see what he's up to.
Buy him a new phone?
Why should I? I didn't take it.
The whole mess will be over.
I'm not afraid of him.
I'm equipped.
Good for you.
I took my Dad's gun.
from his curio collection.
He thought I didn't know.
I found it a couple of years ago.
What are you going to do with it?
Wanna try?
You got anything?
What's that? Fried churrio?
My Dad used to interrogate
people with this.
It leaves no marks.
Your bike.
Who's that?
It's me.
I forgot my shoes.
They are in the cabinet.
Somebody else is home?
No.
Why are you back?
I'm picking up my stuff.
Are you leaving?
What?
Or are you staying home?
Those are your shoes?
Yes.
The water is leaking in the toilet!
The toilet is leaking!
What?
The toilet is leaking again.
It's all flooded.
You did it?
It's the third time.
Call someone to fix it.
or use a basin, OK?
Your cake is there.
You stepped on it?
No.
I bought it for you and you crushed it?
No, I didn't.
I walked two freaking miles.
There was no 24-hour bakery store around.
I told you I didn't step on it!
Where's my contract?
Find it and read for me.
You hear me?
He wanted to beat up Yu Shuai.
But ended up kneeling down by the river,
singing a lullaby.
How did you know?
I was on the other side.
Keep rolling.
Do you have it on you?
I didn't take it.
Yes.
but you stole it.
No, I did nothing.
Everyone else's stuff
was right over there.
Why were you there?
You don't play basketball.
You thought you could fool me?
I didn't steal it. I have my own phone.
What did you see?
Stay the hell out of it.
He's useless.
Why not call you Grandpa.
He practices Tai-chi right?
P...Piss off.
I'll come back during the break.
Meet me at the stairs.
Don't let me come to you.
Let's go.
I will pay for the broken desk.
You were right.
I shouldn't have messed with him.
I should've bought him a new one.
Here's the money for the desk.
Our school is going to be demolished.
What?
This is the worst school in town.
They are building up a new neighborhood.
Our school is merging with another one.
This stupid building will be gone.
What about us?
You?
You go wherever you're supposed to go.
And you?
Me?
I'll have a new office
in the new school.
Larger, more comfortable.
You guys will go to the
worst high school in the city.
When you graduate, most of you
will become street food vendors.
Keep the money.
Have some fun at the Internet café.
Why are you so positive
about your future?
Tell that mopping boy to come in.
Vice dean asked for you.
The world is a wasteland.
What?
A quote from this book. I'm moved.
You are... moved?
Did you pay for the desk?
For History class?
Yep.
Why don't you go inside?
Wanna stand for a while.
Do you want to meet me
later this afternoon?
Where?
Monkey park.
I can't. I have other things.
What things?
You don't have anything to do?
Why always go there?
I've got my own business as well.
Like what?
Feeding monkeys?
No.
You shouldn't have messed with Yu Shuai.
He has a brother. Everyone knows that.
His brother can kill you.
That'd be perfect.
What do you want?
I've seen worse. They didn't
force you out of your home yet.
I know the place.
Tolerable food, TV sets.
But you have to smoke secretly.
My old badminton fellow is there.
Why ask? You're bored at home?
I thought your granddaughter
is close to you.
Mister.
Have you seen a big white dog?
It's white, huge, like this big,
and long hair. Have you seen it?
No.
I saw it.
Running north.
North where?
Towards that bridge.
Are you able to look after the kid?
They won't allow me.
My hands tremor sometimes.
Then you are useless to them.
I bet you have to leave anyways.
They won't even pay for your
residential fees if they're not happy.
The police came.
You know what.
it wasn't because of me.
He bought this apartment
because you made him do it.
He had a lousy pay.
What else can he do with that pay?
So he jumped off the building.
I don't care what you think.
It was his own decision. I'm not guilty.
He was paying for your vanity.
You're the one who should've jumped off.
I can't believe I'm
talking to you about this.
Did anyone ask about it?
They'd better not ask.
Or I'll tell them it was
you that pushed him off.
Why do you look so sad?
Because he's dead?
Because I'm heartless?
Or all the problems coming up?
They called his Mom.
She has booked a flight.
She will come to you.
You were his only friend.
Understood?
You gave him the money?
He didn't take it.
He said our school is closing.
How come?
He said we're going to
be street food vendors.
No. He lied to you.
I know.
But I think it makes sense.
What were you doing with Huang Ling?
She said Yu Shuai's
brother could kill us.
You have the balls to come with him?
Tell me your thoughts.
He didn't steal it.
You were not there.
But I know he's not a thief.
But my phone is missing.
Maybe someone else took it.
Maybe your Dad took it.
What did he take from my
family that got him fired?
Did he bribe you?
So you stand up for him?
Be careful.
The school might kick you out as well.
So you can stay home with Daddy.
Fine. I'll buy you a new phone.
Buy your ass!
What about my old files?
Let him buy one. Give him an out.
Shut up. They asked for it.
We did nothing.
How do you want to end this?
You two sing a lullaby on your knees.
Buy me a new phone later.
No way.
You think you're the boss?
No.
Then stay out of his business.
You are nothing.
What are you?
You stupid jackass.
Your mother sells clothes in the
mining area. Everybody knows that.
Did I tell you to leave?
You wanna fight with that damn stick?
You wanna get yourself killed?
Hey.
Who's this?
It's me.
You changed your number?
No.
No. I'll be gone for a while.
You know, some stuff.
Really?
What're you doing today?
I have a busy schedule.
Fine. Just grab a bite.
What's that?
I have a call.
I can't.
I have a business dinner.
Send me the address. I can wait.
You're annoying.
You're right. Life is annoying.
What now?
Someone beat up Yu Shuai at school.
So? You want me to fight back?
Why are you so shameless?
Why?
Have you no shame?!
Don't go over there! OJ! Come!
Go away.
Have you seen a big white dog?
Like this.
Hey, I'm talking to you.
Did you hear me?
Watch your ass!
You shitty punk!
I forgot my homework.
Where's my money?
I put it under the mattress.
I don't know.
It was there this morning.
That's not your money.
It's my money.
No, it's not.
Have you earned a single penny?
That's the lucky money from Grandma.
Ugh.
Where are you going?
(Missing Dog)
Where do they live?
That's enough. Go back inside.
Go back inside.
No one calls the fucking cops!
Now tell me about it.
It was scary.
They didn't even wipe off the blood.
They shared the picture in a group chat.
What should we do?
Why're you crying?
I don't know what to do.
It's none of your business.
Time for class.
Go back to your seats.
You know what happened?
Not the fighting part.
You two are close?
Just fine.
Why did Wei Bu beat up Yu Shuai?
Yu Shuai believed that Li
Kai had stolen his phone.
Wei Bu tried to help him out.
Can't be that simple.
That's all.
You're asking as if you care.
Because it would get me involved.
The boss would ask me about it.
In the end it's always my business.
Students' problems are my problems.
If you stay out of it,
nothing will change.
I know.
But I'll get into trouble.
Things work like that.
If anything happens,
everyone gets into trouble.
But we keep running into troubles.
We have to close down
the school early today.
Last night my Mom...
Mr. Li.
I want Wei Bu's address and phone number.
(Great Circus in Manzhouli)
Granny!
Granny?
I'm cooking.
Where's your Mom?
Grandma passed away.
Oh, I didn't know.
Now you know.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
You only visit her when you need money.
It's your nephew.
Go and check on your Mom.
You're not going anywhere.
Call his father.
Don't leave.
Who's that?
It's me.
Who are you looking for?
You have a big white dog?
Where is it?
It bit my dog.
He saw Pipi?
He said Pipi bit his dog.
But where is Pipi?
It killed my dog
I'm asking about Pipi.
Is this your dog?
Turn off the gas first.
Ask him about Pipi!
Do you have any proof
that my dog killed yours?
Pipi doesn't bite other dogs.
Shut up.
There was a huge white
dog running in the streets.
But it doesn't have to be my dog.
I have a witness.
Who?
An old lady.
She once saw your wife walking that dog.
I have to find it first.
And confirm what you said.
I went to the vet's.
My dog is dead.
How much do you want?
I'm not going to pay the vet's bills.
I'm coming to tell you
that your dog killed mine.
What do you want?
How much money do you want?
How much is it worth?
Your dog must have bitten mine, right?
Did I ask you for any money?
You wanna blackmail me, isn't it?
What are you up to?
Look
I crashed into a car a
few days ago and got out.
That driver didn't get
a single penny from me.
You think you can rip me off now?
My cue is here.
This one?
No, the Aomi one.
Can't tell.
This one?
It's carved with words.
Can I exchange it for some cash?
You can ask the owner.
This one is worth 800 Yuan.
I only want 500.
I'll get it back as soon as I have money.
I can't do that. The owner is not here.
400 Yuan will also do.
Come on. I don't have a say.
- I saw a boy at the counter.
- Shut up.
Hello, auntie.
I heard about it.
You should've told me to
pick you up at the airport
I'll meet you at the police station.
I'm coming.
There was a boy coming for his cue.
He might be the one you're looking for.
Where's the kid?
Let's go to the monkey park.
An ambulance was at the school today?
Yes.
What happened?
No idea.
No idea?
A student called Wei
Bu hit Yu Weipeng's son.
The kid is in the hospital now.
That Wei Bu got himself
into huge trouble.
What are you so happy about?
I'm not.
Don't use my foundation.
I didn't.
Makeup is for grown-ups,
not for you kids.
I did not.
I know you have.
Don't get yourself pregnant
I'm giving you a warning
I have a colleague
who didn't warn her kid in advance.
Then they were in big trouble.
You make me sick.
Stop pretending.
Does shaming me make you happy?
Stop right here.
I saw it.
What?
How did it die?
A dog bit it.
Somebody else's dog?
Yes.
What happened?
Why ask?
I need some money.
You want money from me?
It's borrowing. I will return it.
Why not ask your parents?
I got into some trouble.
I can't call them now.
But I don't have any money.
I sleep on the balcony.
I can't offer you anything.
I know. I just want to borrow some.
Take a look at this cue.
It cost me over 1,000.
You can ask around in any pool room.
You can keep it as a guaranty.
What do I need this for?
This is the best thing I have
I'll buy it back.
I told you I don't have money.
I don't have my pensions.
You have the wrong person.
I do understand.
Try someone else.
Take a look at this.
Just leave.
Hey.
Where's my dog? Did you kill it?
His dog did it?
Let's go to the police!
Or I'll come down to get you!
What are you up to?
I can scratch your car all over
and not give you a damn penny for it.
Come if you dare.
Come on.
I won't stop you!
Do it!
Come on. Do it!
Stop. I didn't hurt your dog.
A truck will kill you both!
I have to go.
I don't need it.
Take it.
You can sell it for some cash.
I can't carry it with me.
Do you know Manzhouli?
Yes
I'm going there.
There's an elephant sitting there.
Why does it matter to you?
It doesn't.
I want to go and see for myself
I'll go with you.
Don't bother.
I didn't tell them you were here.
You're clean.
You don't have to worry.
How's that?
I heard about this two hours ago.
I could've picked you up at the airport.
I want a cigarette.
Have a new one.
It's so tall.
Aren't you cold?
Was it because Li Kai stole the phone?
He didn't steal it.
How do you know?
I just know it.
What's your plan?
I'm going to buy a ticket.
To where?
Manzhouli.
Go back. It's not that serious.
You don't get it.
What do you want me to do?
You want to join me?
Give me a break.
My Mom just asked me about you.
I don't know where she got the news.
What will you do in Manzhouli?
There will be something.
Look around. Everyone's alive.
It's dangerous for me to come here.
I'll be done if they know it.
No one will know.
Why did you hit him?
I didn't know it until today
that my dad was fired
because he took bribes.
What's that got to do with your fight?
I hit him when I heard it.
It's just natural.
I didn't feel anything
I don't care whether Li Kai
stole the phone or not.
I'm his friend.
I did what I have to do
I've no idea why it ended up like this.
So?
I didn't beat him.
He fell down the staircase.
Then why did you escape?
Are you going to Manzhouli with me?
I can do part-time.
I've worked every summer vacation.
All kinds of work.
You can come back if you want.
Let's see what you're capable of.
You can play shuttlecock.
Yes, I can do that.
So you can perform shuttlecock-kicking
in Manzhouli.
People will give you money for that.
You can settle there then.
Are you making fun of me?
No, just stating the fact.
That is sarcasm.
You were right though.
I can only play shuttlecocks.
You've won prizes for that.
Yes.
Meaning you're really good.
Not at all.
Everyone can waste their
time on any meaningless shit.
It even makes you look
like a freaking pro.
So why shuttlecock?
Because other things
make me feel even worse.
You're leaving?
Yep.
What happened?
Nothing.
I just can't go with you. It's not good.
Really.
You don't have to run away.
Just leave.
You play pool?
Entry level.
That asshole.
Cut the bullshit!
Smash it!
This is the cue.
Aomi.
He showed it off in the pool room.
Who knows where he's
stolen the money for this.
Is this yours?
Yes.
Wanna play with me?
Not today.
When are you free?
Dad, what's going on?
Get out!
You deaf?
Is that you, Grandpa?
There's a name on it.
Let's save some time.
Where did you get this?
What are you going to
do when you find him?
He beat up a piece of trash
and that piece of trash is my brother.
What do you think I should do?
A piece of trash brother?
That's right.
A piece of trash.
Yes.
I'm going to the train station.
Keep an eye on him. Don't let him go.
Watch this.
Let him take a look.
Hey old man, watch this.
Grandpa are you there?
Cut the crap!
Don't mess with us.
Piss off.
Where's the puppy?
Come back home Grandpa!
Come here.
He wants a copy for himself.
You two, come to the train station.
I have something else to do.
That's the dean from my brother's school.
What's your brother's name?
Yu Shuai. You know him?
Heard of him.
That's your girlfriend inside?
No. I don't have other things to do.
You have to be careful.
About what?
Don't be good-for-nothing
when you're at my age.
What's the difference
if you're of any use?
You should go inside and punch that dean.
He is the vice dean.
You'd go inside if he were the dean?
There's no difference. I wouldn't dare.
You should let her know that
you came by, and you saw it.
Why's that?
Or you will be just like
this freaking trash can.
(You're screwed)
What's going on?
Group chat.
They have nothing better to do.
The school didn't call the police. Why?
The fight?
Better settle it privately.
Yu's family has a car dealership.
Settling it privately is the best
way out, for Wei Bu or for the school.
His brother is looking for Wei Bu.
That's fine.
Wei Bu hit him.
He has to pay for that.
Nothing serious.
What do people make of
things happening to them?
What do you mean?
I don't think Wei Bu
knew what he was doing.
He surely didn't.
When I was at school,
there was a guy in class.
One day, I saw him with a
stray cat at the riverside.
He found some stones.
And he slowly smashed the cat to death.
And then?
He was often bullied back then.
His grades sucked as well.
Teachers said that he had no future.
But these had nothing to
do with him killing the cat.
He was just happy doing it.
And you were watching as he did it?
Yep.
I wanted to stop him.
That was the right thing to do.
But if I did
I would have something to do with it.
So I just watched.
I have to admit that I enjoyed
watching the whole thing.
Why are you telling me this?
I want you to know.
Daily routines have always been the same
across different ages.
You don't have to be confused.
People will get it over time.
Can I get myself?
Life just won't get better.
It's all about agony.
That agony has begun since you were born.
You think that a new place
will change your fate?
It's bullshit.
New place, new sufferings.
You understand?
No one truly knows about existence.
Where should I go if school is closed?
Find another one.
You're not divorced.
I saw you pick up your kid.
We're separated.
Easy. I was kidding.
What are you worried about?
Nothing
I'm quite at ease at the moment.
It's been there for a while.
Where's the puppy, Grandpa?
It's dead, right?
Is the puppy dead?
It's an old dog.
I can take her to school.
Dad, don't be too sad.
It's no easy thing keeping a pet.
Even harder if it gets sick.
The vets are really expensive.
What have you got yourself into?
It's OK. I can handle it.
It's not that bad.
You can go to the nursing home now.
I just called them.
An army commander lives there.
You two will get along well.
No rush.
Just think about it.
Let's have dinner.
I ate already.
It's a nice cue. Where did you get it?
Come down here you old piece of crap!
Get your butt down here!
Shall we call the police?
Fine.
Thank you both.
Thank you for taking care of this.
Bye.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
Why're you looking at me?
Then where should I look?
Who knows.
I don't like people staring at me.
Come on.
I'll grab a bite.
You just left a restaurant
I didn't eat much.
What are you doing here?
Hanging out with you.
You just came?
I feel relaxed with you.
It's not going to work out between us.
We're not the same kind of people.
It'll get us nowhere no
matter how many times you try.
Then who is your kind?
Not you at least.
We don't understand each other.
Awesome, that sounds really complicated.
Here it is, again.
Your attitude is so annoying.
You make me feel uncomfortable.
I slept with my friend's
wife this morning.
He found out and jumped off the building.
I have to stay away for a while.
Why are you doing this?
Because you refused to see me.
I won't change my mind.
I'm telling you because
it's all your fault.
It's because of you that he's dead.
What's the matter with you?
Ah!
Get out.
Out!
Get the hell out!
Don't move!
Don't freaking move!
A professor boards a fishing boat.
He asks the fisherman
if he understands poetry.
The fisherman says no.
The professor says
"your life is reduced to half".
Then he asks if the
fisherman understands music.
He says no again.
The professor says "then the
other half of your life is gone".
The fisherman asks if the
professor knows how to swim.
The professor says he can't
"then your whole life is gone."
And the professor is
thrown into the water.
Hello?
Have you checked our group chat?
Hurry up.
The message that just came in.
It was already in other
group chats yesterday.
What happened?
Who filmed this?
I don't know
I'm ruined.
Well.
That guy at the restaurant
with the note...
was stalking us?
These clips began to spread yesterday.
Why are people so freaking nosy?
Why are people so evil?
And they're so young!
Somebody will come get you
when you're minding your own business.
Why are you cursing?
Just go.
You ruined me.
I can't transfer to the new school now.
Take your things.
Why did you go back?
How the hell should I know.
Don't talk to me like that.
Fine. I don't care about anyone, OK?
I don't know if my
brother is dead or not.
Either I'm going to
find that little brat
or I'm going to see my
brother at the hospital.
Then why are you here?
Didn't I tell you?
I have to go away for a while.
I'm leaving tonight.
You'd better go now.
Where were we?
What?
You said your friend died because of me.
Yes.
Tell me about it.
About what?
He killed himself because of me.
I don't see any connections.
You rejected me.
So I went to his place
and slept with his wife.
Then he jumped off the building.
So I can't say no to you?
You believe you're somebody, don't you?
You started all this mess.
You're playing innocent or what?
My life is like a dumpster.
Garbage keeps piling up.
They come one after another.
You can never clean it up.
Everybody is the same.
You think you're the only
one that can't take it?
You're always very blunt
when it comes to me.
Because you won't let me go.
It wasn't like this from the beginning.
That's right.
But it didn't last long.
I started to feel uncomfortable.
Yes, you told me that.
That's right.
No one ever feels comfortable.
It's only you.
Do you feel comfortable?
Why do you ask?
You are faking it.
The way you are.
You make that up.
Actually you're no different
than any other women.
You're so dark.
All the same.
Who gives you the right to say that?
I'm watching you, everyday.
See how you present yourself.
Skiing, scuba diving...
all that middle-class stuff.
Look around.
What's the point of faking
a middle-class life?
You don't have to sound bitter
because I don't want to sleep with you.
Yeah, probably
I'm going to Manzhouli
to check out something.
Wanna come with me?
Not interested.
You don't wanna know
what I want to see there?
I'm going to tell you anyway.
The funniest thing I've ever heard.
There's this elephant in a zoo.
It just sits there all day long.
What's fun about that?
The suicide guy told me one week ago.
You're not interested?
I'm not going anywhere with you.
Why are you standing here?
I can leave.
Be my guest. I'm going to the hospital
to check out a dumbass, his crazy mother
and an old wretch.
You're not leaving with me?
Why?
I don't want to leave you alone.
Cut the crap.
Who is it?
You need to do me a favor.
Where are you? We were looking for you.
The shopping mall near the hospital.
Did you see him?
Take you hands off me.
Don't stumble over.
At the entrance.
We're supposed to meet up here.
But he didn't tell me when.
Where's he now?
I'll look over there.
I can't find him.
Let's go upstairs.
Let's check on different spots.
Wei Bu! Where were you?
Wei Bu! Take your hands off me!
Let me go! Wei Bu!
You freaking sold me out!
I only told your parents.
They could help you out.
They're the only ones you can go to.
Did I say not to tell anybody?
Did I or didn't I?
You piece of crap!
Yes, that's right.
What's right?
The way you are.
I tried to help you out,
but you don't give a damn.
No one gives a damn about me.
What do you mean?
I am nothing!
What was your plan then?
Send my Dad to take me away?
Keep me safe in prison?
Yu Cheng went to your place
and smashed a lot of stuff.
They're worried.
They can't help.
You were wrong the whole time.
I stole that cellphone.
He shot a lot of videos on his phone.
He recorded me taking a piss.
You said you hadn't stolen the phone.
Because I lied to you.
I'd rather buy him a new one
than let him keep the video.
You worthless punk.
I'm probably the last
person to see who you are.
There're other videos on his phone.
Like Huang Ling with the
vice dean at a karaoke bar.
You shouldn't have beaten him up.
He's a coward. A little scare will do.
Now it's all screwed up.
You're saying I screwed this up?
Yes you did.
I've told you this.
I'm not scared of anything.
I can do anything.
I'll do fine without you.
Where the hell can you go?
You will freaking rot in here.
(Nursing Home - Visiting Hours)
I want to take a look.
(Great Circus in Manzhouli)
(Sitting Elephant)
There's a Yu Shuai here...
how's he doing?
There's a Yu...
(Surgical Department Zone 1)
Shut up.
What have you done?
Don't yell at me.
Look at him! He's lying there!
Why not call the police?
Arrest that asshole!
I've looked for him all day.
I'm not stupid.
Once you beat him almost deaf!
You and your gang abused him!
Oh crap, not again!
Get out!
Hey kiddo. Throw that shuttlecock over!
Come on!
Hey! You prick!
Screw you.
What did you say? Say it again?
I said screw you! You hear that?
Come over here!
You'll be dead! I'll kill you!
Wait right there, you little brat!
Come over and I'll kill you!
Stop. That's enough.
Let go!
I'll kill you!
Stay right there!
Try me!
Damn you! You piece of trash!
Stay right there if you dare.
Stay right there!
Come back!
It's not worth it.
You're a scumbag!
You're the most disgusting
thing I've ever seen!
Damn you!
Go to hell!
Tickets?
Where to?
Manzhouli
I have tickets to Manzhouli.
I can line up here.
A couple of tour groups
were here earlier.
You won't get a ticket in two hours.
You're home.
That deputy chief tried
to touch me over dinner.
He ain't nothing.
He pretended to be drunk.
What good could he do for me?
That bald good-for-nothing.
I want to tell you something.
He was talking big.
Says he wanted to buy all
the medicine I'm selling.
What for?
I can sell it to anybody.
I want to tell you something.
Where did you come back from?
The vice dean at the school
has been very nice to me.
Really nice.
I feel much more comfortable
with him than at home.
Did he sleep with you?
Why?
Why what?
You've messed up my life.
Every morning I have to pick
up your clothes from the floor.
If they're stained,
I'm the one that does the laundry.
I always smell of delivered food.
It takes time to clean the smell.
Did he screw you?
I enjoy hanging out at his place.
It's clean and tidy.
I don't need to clean it up.
Can you let me finish?
Go ahead.
Somebody leaked a video of us.
But we haven't done anything out of line.
Everybody from school knows it.
You're going to be famous.
What should I do?
What do you want me to do?
To sleep with that baldy
and sign the sales contract?
You're the most selfish and
disgusting person I know.
No,
that person is thousands of miles away.
Go and find him!
You find this apartment dirty?
Send for a cleaner!
Find a cleaner!
I have my own work to do!
You just do some shitty homework?
No time to find a cleaner?
I'll go and sleep with that baldy.
Happy?
Yes! I'm calling him right away!
I'll tell him myself.
My daughter is much younger.
You make me sick.
Same here.
You know nothing about life.
I don't have time to
give you what you like
I'm living this messy life myself.
My life's miserable.
But it's not because of me.
It's always been like this
I'm like this, you're like this.
It's always been like this.
Where're you going?
Who is it?
Where's your daughter?
She's not home. You can talk to me.
You know what's going on?
I just learned.
Well, a good mother you are.
My daughter is a victim.
Victim?
Your husband is her teacher.
Yes, Mr. Teacher. It's your turn.
Calm down. We can talk it through.
Talk? Talk about what?
Like how this 17-year-old little slut
hooked up with my man?
I'm gonna take a look at her.
Only two rooms in this shithole, right?
Open the door!
You can talk to me.
Don't stand in my way!
Get out, you dirty brat!
Who do you think you are?
Coming here for shit like this!
Stop making a scene.
Come out Ling. You'll be fine.
Shut the hell up!
I should bring our son and
let him see who you are.
Now you know shame? I'll kick
the door in if you don't open it!
Why do you have to embarrass everybody?
Embarrass?
I'm the most embarrassed one!
I'm the most embarrassed
one in all of you!
Where are you going?
Manzhouli?
Any rides going there?
Any?
One adult ticket.
One child.
You sold me a fake ticket.
We've never met.
It's a fake ticket. Gimme my money.
Where's the ticket?
Confiscated.
Well then, how do I tell if
this is a blackmail or not?
You're lying.
I bought your ticket a couple hours ago.
There're a million passengers at
the station. You got the wrong guy.
I know the place where you
get your tickets. Not here.
What do you want?
Give me back my money
or I'll call the cops.
Cops? Well...
I'm not the person taking your money
I'm also the victim.
Follow me and let's get your money back.
Why did you sell fake tickets?
Bring the money with you.
Give me your ID.
Why?
Are you stupid?
You don't need an ID to buy a ticket?
Now give me half the ticket fare
and I'll get you a new ticket.
I know it's a fake one.
I want my money back.
You little shit.
Never gotten on a train before, huh?
Running away from home is fun, huh?
You know what? I can kill you.
Stop there.
You're Wei Bu?
No.
That's a fake name.
Watch him and call Yu Cheng now.
He's been looking for him.
Grandpa.
I'm taking you to where
I served as a soldier.
Okay.
Should we tell Mom?
Do you want to?
No.
Lets go then.
My brother is dead.
What are you thinking?
What?
If you're standing on a
tall building's balcony.
what would come up to your mind?
I would think
what else I can do.
What?
What else I can do.
Hello.
Auntie.
I was there this morning.
I was at his apartment.
Right.
I watched him jump off.
Where are you running off to?
Manzhouli.
What for?
To see an elephant.
You don't have any money.
I spent it on a fake ticket.
You have his ID card?
Yes.
Go and buy him a ticket.
Now you've killed someone.
Somebody will get you anyway.
I don't have to do it.
Right.
I don't like my brother.
But my parents do.
Because he's like a little pussy.
It was an accident.
I didn't intend to hurt him.
Accident or not, does it matter?
I don't like him.
But he's still my brother.
I have to deal with this.
If my Dad had caught you,
you'd be half dead by now
and then sent to a juvy.
That'll be a lot of fun.
Why do you help me?
I told you I don't like anybody.
They all suck.
Why let me go?
None of you business.
You'll get the ticket soon. Just leave.
I called the police!
Yu Cheng, let go of him!
Oh, you are that peeing boy!
I repeat, Yu Cheng. Let him go!
I'm not scared of you!
Stay out of this.
I didn't tell anyone. Just the police.
You sent him the location?
What the hell is that?
Go! Yu Shuai is dead. I'm not going!
I'll cover you!
Oh, he wants to cover you.
What's that in your hand?
You little snitch.
Go back to your Mom.
You shouldn't be here.
Come on! Run!
Come on!
He asked for it.
I didn't upload the video.
What video?
The one with Huang
Ling and the vice dean.
You didn't have to end
up the same way I did.
You don't get it.
Get what?
They are afraid of me.
Most people won't feel this
proud throughout their lives.
You made it. They're all afraid of you.
You're a hero.
Go.
You're all going to hell.
All of you!
Come on,
do your homework before you use it!
The world is just disgusting.
The train is cancelled.
The bus can only make
a transfer in Shenyang.
Then we'll find other ways.
Shenyang it is.
Two tickets would do.
I'm going back.
You lied to me, Grandpa.
Where are you going?
HoMy dog is dead.
No more defense against the nursing home.
Don't cry.
Why not?
Because...
No reason.
You can go wherever you want.
Yes, you can.
However, you'll find nothing different.
I learned this when I've
wasted most of my life away.
So I have to sugar-coat it.
"There must be a difference."
Do you understand?
I do.
No, you don't.
You're looking for something else.
Well the best solution is
you're right here
and you look over to the other side.
You believe that it
must be better than this.
But you can't go.
By not going
you learn to live with it here.
Let's go and take a look...