Do you know that adults
are the stupidest creatures on earth?
They think they can just make up stories
to hide secrets.
They're retards.
They said that bad guys killed my dad
for the insurance money.
What an idiot.
I've known all along that my dad was gay.
He died 95 days ago.
I don't know where people go
after they die,
but Liu San-lien
took me to a place...
It's 1:05 p.m. now. The program
you're listening to now is Mommy DoReMi.
I'm your host, Chung Ксиn-ling.
Nobody's home.
There's no use banging the door.
-He must still be sleeping.
-Who?
A shameless guy.
-Someone Sung Cheng-yuan knows.
-So he is Dad's friend.
-Why do you have to talk that way?
-How about you?
Is that how you talk to your mom?
Birds of the same feather flock together.
Still sleeping?
I don't believe that I can't wake you up.
Are you looking for me?
-He made you the beneficiary, didn't he?
-What?
Or did you change the beneficiary
when he was unconscious?
You shameless bastard!
That money was meant for his son.
Tell him your name and who your dad is.
Tell him yourself.
Sung Cheng-Кси.
If you play with your phone again,
I'll break it!
If you're coming in,
please close the door behind you.
Otherwise, just close the door.
He needs to go to high school, college
and then study abroad.
Never mind that you two messed up my life.
Now you're taking his son's money too?
Are you coming in or not, Auntie?
Who...
Who are you calling Auntie?
Are you coming in or not?
You wait here!
Drink this if you're thirsty.
I'll be out in a second.
Take it, Sung Cheng-Кси!
Quick.
I'll be out in a second.
Sung Cheng-yuan's insurance money
was his way of making up to his son.
-Did he make you the beneficiary?
-"Ben"? "Fishery"?
-Can you speak in Mandarin?
-How dare you? Stop playing dumb.
Auntie, you're not busy, but I am!
I don't have time for this.
Let me be straight with you.
If you have any conscience, give it back.
I don't know what Ben or fishery
you are talking about.
All I know is that Sung Cheng-yuan
gave you every penny he had, didn't he?
If you're not the beneficiary,
then who is?
Turn left when you go out.
Get your answer at the temple there.
Quit playing innocent.
You shameless mistress.
Watch your mouth! Do you have any respect?
I'm still a guy.
At least, call me a male lover.
You've got a week
to give me the insurance money.
Or I swear I'll find a congressman
and hold a press conference.
I'll make sure the whole world knows
-that you're a family-wrecking fag.
-Why don't you get the SNG vans to come?
-Right here.
-You pervert. Shame on you!
-Here!
-Don't think I wouldn't dare.
You damn gay!
Hubby, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Hubby.
Hubby, pick up the phone now.
Hubby, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Hubby.
-Tell me, who's the mistress now?
-Hubby, pick up the phone now.
Do you hear this clearly?
Hubby, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Hubby.
Hubby, pick up the phone...
What's on your mind?
Do you want to talk about it?
What kind of sports do you like to do?
Dancing?
Basketball?
Or video games?
I like to beat up people. Can I go now?
Thank you for respecting my opinion.
I'll respect your privacy too.
Unless you have the intention
to hurt yourself or others.
Otherwise, I won't tell your mom
what we've talked about.
How is that possible? She pays you.
Your mom pays me
to help you.
It's not to tell her what we've discussed.
Do you think talking to you
will stop me from beating people up?
You'll only know when you've tried.
How about
we try something else?
Ask me anything you want.
It can be about anything.
Family, friendship,
love, anything.
Anything you want.
Between a mistress and a male lover,
who do you think would win?
MISTRESS
LIU SAN-LIEN
Sung Cheng-Кси!
Are you going to wake up or not?
It must be the name "Liu San-lien"
-that made her a mistress.
-You have to be early.
The alarm has been ringing
for ten minutes.
All right. Have it your way.
Don't say I didn't wake you up
if you're late.
She is the noisiest woman on Earth.
Sung Cheng-Кси!
What the hell did you stick
in the keyhole?
She thinks the whole world owes her.
-Mrs. Sung.
-So she's in a bad mood every day.
The name listed as the beneficiary
is not your son.
What do you mean?
He changed it to that lover's name?
I told you to sue him for adultery.
You didn't want to.
How can I do that?
I have a life to live,
so does Sung Cheng-Кси.
He's the cheater.
The shame is on him.
What does it have to do with your lives?
You are so stupid!
-I don't know--
-He was cheating on me with a man!
Even if the lover was...
I hate meal times the most.
Sung Cheng-Кси.
What do you think I'm saving up for?
It's for you to study abroad
so you can have a better life.
And you got these grades?
Is this how you repay me?
Am I not working hard enough?
You don't have to do anything else.
Just study. Is that so hard?
Tell me. Is that so hard?
Why don't you try it then?
Let's see if you can get good grades.
You're talking back to me.
Do I have tuition?
Don't I need to work to earn money?
Do you know how expensive
the tuition of private schools are?
They charge so much money
but I still have to teach you myself.
I'm going to see the principal tomorrow.
Don't embarrass yourself again.
Embarrass myself?
Say that again.
Who's embarrassing?
It's Hollywood's loss
that she didn't become an actress.
Your grades are the reason
Sung Cheng-yuan didn't want to see you.
Do you know that?
Here we go.
Three, two, one.
I'm giving you everything, Sung Cheng-Кси.
Why can't you simply try harder for me?
Why can't you do something
to make me proud?
-I dare you to say that again.
-She should go
-to Hollywood.
-Sung Cheng-Кси.
I don't deserve this!
Who embarrassed whom?
You entered my room again?
I changed your sheets
and vacuumed the floor.
What if you get rashes again?
Where's my stuff?
What stuff? You throw your stuff around.
Then, blame me when you lose it.
That's my stuff.
Didn't I pay for all of your stuff?
Give it back!
-Give what back?
-The stuff that you can't buy with money.
What kind of society are we living in?
What can't be bought with money?
Dad's letters, his pictures,
and the watch he gave me.
That lousy man.
He didn't even leave you
the insurance money.
-What are you reminiscing about?
-It's still my stuff!
I threw them away.
You are so annoying!
Where are you going?
It's grandpa's birthday dinner tonight.
Don't be late.
Adults who won't admit their mistakes
should be punished.
His name is Chieh.
MISTRESS
Because he's a mistress with a dick,
so he is a...
MALE LOVER
KAO YU-CHIEH
He must be on drugs.
He walks around in his pajamas daily.
Why won't the police
do something about it?
Morning.
Chieh, what are you doing here?
Here.
You haven't had breakfast, right?
Steamed dumplings.
You need to look after yourself too,
not just the patient.
Okay.
Get well soon, folks.
Best of luck to you!
He's definitely on drugs.
Get to the stage.
-The third one.
-Add some lighting.
-Bali
-I heard that he is a director
and actor in a small theater.
-Hey, eat less.
-It must be a shitty one.
I'm serious!
I'm serious too. Stop eating so much
and you'll be the theater version
of Jolin Tsai.
You can do this!
Let's seize the moment.
Let's test the lights.
-On cue.
-He must have stolen
my dad's insurance money with his looks.
Chieh!
-I can't do anything about that.
-There was so much left afterwards...
Stage Director, I'll do my makeup first.
I'll be back before the tech rehearsals.
There were a lot.
It's not just me.
Everyone's worried about you.
There's nothing to worry about.
I'm serious.
Once you feel better,
we'll support you whenever you need it.
I'm doing great. Can't you see that?
Come on, man! I mean it.
I mean it too. Don't worry.
Can't you see? I'm as lively as a wolf.
That's exactly what worries me.
I'd rather you cry about it.
What the hell should I cry about?
I'm fine.
I just need 50,000 dollars
to tide us over for a few days.
I'll pay you back
once the tickets are sold.
People couldn't get a ticket
for our show 17 years ago!
I made it even fancier this time.
Check it out!
The stage, lights...
Just come to the tech rehearsal tonight.
I've got Lin Wen-ju, the queen of theater,
on my crew!
Once people hear about us,
they'd surely...
So
you went to his place?
You didn't go to your friends' place
or internet cafes.
You chose to go there.
Why?
Aren't you the expert here?
Who do you think
would get my dad's insurance money?
The man lover or the mistress?
Knock it off, Sung Cheng-Кси!
Come home and change your clothes.
We'll be late for Grandpa's
birthday party. Cut it out!
Open the door!
Your mom learned her lesson.
Go home with her.
-Let's go.
-I'll jump if you come any closer!
Come down first.
-It's dangerous!
-You think...
I didn't throw your stuff away.
Come home
and I'll give everything back to you.
-I don't want them anymore! Scram!
-Please.
-Get down first!
-Scram!
-Okay. Calm down!
-Calm down.
-Show some manners to your mom!
It's none of your business.
None of my business? This is my home.
-Go and jump off your own balcony.
-Don't say that!
Come on, Auntie! Can't you tell?
I'm trying to help you here.
-Okay, just come here.
-I'm jumping now!
-Sure. Go ahead!
-No!
-Jump! Right now!
-Don't interfere in my family's affairs.
Is that so?
Can you do this somewhere else then?
Let me tell you.
Come down within one second.
And get out within three seconds.
Or I'm calling the cops!
I'll get down when Liu San-lien
gets the hell out.
Are you sure?
I'll get down when Liu San-lien
gets the hell out.
Fine.
Come down here you punk!
Come here!
-Go away!
-No!
I'll discipline my son myself!
-I doubt that you can.
-It's because of your bad influence.
You spent 14 years together.
We spent 40 minutes. You're ridiculous!
Who knows what kind of voodoo spell
you cast on him to come here?
Maybe you've cursed me too.
No wonder I've been feeling unwell!
Damn it, Auntie!
Why don't you take your son
to a temple and pray?
Then, go home to watch Taiwan Mystery.
Be good, okay?
Are you hurt?
I'd rather die than go home.
ICED WATER
Hey, come to see the play.
I wouldn't understand it.
Then, help me sell tickets
and you'll get the commission.
All right.
I'm not thirsty.
Just hold it for me.
I have two suggestions for you.
-One, go home--
-Third suggestion.
Hubby, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Hubby.
Hubby, pick up the...
I'm the wolf of the theater, Chieh.
Who's calling?
Ma'am.
Thanks for your concern,
but I have to be straight with you.
I have never bought any insurance.
Because it's hard
for my sorry life to end.
Save your speech for...
What?
Sung Cheng-yuan's beneficiary?
What does that mean?
Doesn't he know that my dad
changed the beneficiary to him?
So he isn't really such a bad guy?
I'm not hungry.
Eat it if I say so.
That's impossible.
He surely is a bad guy.
Otherwise, why wasn't he sad
when my dad died?
So...
he must be a bad guy.
TA-HEI
Hubby, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Hubby.
Hubby, pick up the phone now.
And he's the type of bad guy
with lousy acting skills.
Bali.
Bali
The magical Bali
That's right. It's Bali.
Shit, it's not the energy drink.
So you're Mr. Sung's kid.
Hey, Chen.
Your profiles are similar.
-I don't know why I'm wearing a sweater.
-It's Bali.
What the hell are they rehearsing?
I arrived this morning...
Happy Holidays.
It was quite the hit 17 years ago.
-Holiday, my ass...
-What do you want?
-The sweater makes it hot.
-Why don't you believe me?
Please help me
to borrow it from the hotel.
I realized something.
I don't want to do it.
You should do it yourself.
I can't speak English.
I don't want to.
-Please.
-No way!
I've seen this before.
What an amazing balcony!
So this stupid play
has something to do with my dad?
You even complained that it was expensive
and want something cheaper.
Good thing I insisted.
Let me change to swimsuit then.
Then I'll put on sunscreen.
I think
I'll find the answer soon.
Does it sound good?
A guitar would sound better.
Do you play the guitar?
No.
Do you want to learn?
-I do.
-Okay.
Then no more car racing from now on.
I will die a horrible death
-if ever I do it again!
-Hey!
Don't talk like that.
All right.
My brother already died.
If I die as well,
I think my mom will go crazy.
All right. No more car racing for me.
Can you teach me how to play the guitar?
I guarantee you'll get paid
for the performance.
You haven't even paid them
for the venue yet.
You're ridiculous.
Stage Director,
have you distributed the notes?
We can finish off
the lighting cues tomorrow.
All right. We'll rehearse
the next half tomorrow.
We can do this!
Let me say this upfront.
If I don't get paid first thing
at the rehearsal tomorrow,
I swear I'm leaving.
Don't say that.
Hey.
Look at your adorable little face.
Chieh.
-Chieh.
-I promise you will get your paycheck.
Okay?
Don't you lose any sleep over something
as shallow as money.
Be good, okay?
I love the theater.
I love you all.
Love is everything.
He's the bad guy.
He's...
Why did you sell your motorbike?
Don't you have my dad's insurance money?
Hey.
Are you picking him up?
What are you doing over there? Come here!
Cut it out and just go home with your mom.
So you don't plan to come home?
Great!
Don't ever come back.
What does that mean?
You're leaving him here?
I'm not taking him!
Sung Cheng-Кси.
Why are you doing this to me?
He's the pervert
who stole your dad's insurance money.
He's our enemy!
What are you doing here?
Why...
Why are you treating me like a foe
and choose to stay with our enemy?
You're just trying to screw me over,
aren't you?
After all I've done for you--
I didn't ask you to do that.
-Come home with me!
-No.
-Then go live with your aunt.
You can't stay with him. He's...
a pervert.
No. I'd rather die.
You keep talking about dying.
I'll die in front of you first.
Please. If you want to die,
go die in your own home.
You...
He is Sung Cheng-yuan's son,
you should at least have a bit of decency.
What?
Wake him up tomorrow morning
at 6 a.m. for school.
That's none of my business!
Take him and do it yourself!
Your lunch box is in the bag.
Don't eat those deep fried junk.
It's too unhealthy.
-How do you think your dad got cancer?
-Hey.
You have to learn how to protect yourself.
If you lay a finger on him, I swear...
Let me tell you. I have no shame.
He's your son.
Take him home and leave me out of it.
I will cut your dick off!
Take him home!
Hey.
Do you want me to call you a cab?
No.
So you're just going to sit here
for the rest of your life?
That's none of your business.
What's this?
Your dad's pajamas.
I don't need them.
It's not manly to act tough.
Don't you miss your dad?
I'm sure Liu San-lien packed my clothes.
Hey.
What do you have against your mom?
That's none of your business.
Then why the hell are you here?
To steal the insurance money.
So it's a mother-and-son conspiracy.
If I get the insurance money,
she'll send me to Canada for school.
Then I can stay away
from her craziness forever.
If you ever disrespect your mom again,
I'll kick your ass.
Then why did you steal my dad?
Your dad is gone.
I'm like your stepdad now.
Or stepmom?
At least I am your elder.
Have some respect when you talk to me.
So did you start it or was it my dad?
How old are you? You don't know shit.
Yes, I don't. That's why
you have to tell me.
I have nothing to say to a punk ass kid.
You must be the one who seduced my dad.
How do you know?
You destroyed my family.
Do you play the guitar?
Your dad taught me how to play.
He even wrote this song.
Put your heart into it.
My heart's with you.
I don't have it anymore.
Treat it as if it were me.
Listen.
I long for the freedom you gave me
My mom asked me who you were.
Your teacher, roommate,
or colleague from the theater.
I prefer to tell the truth.
The truth will break your mom's heart.
That's impossible.
My mom loves me so much.
You're the only son she has now.
Even if I like you, I still love her.
Even if you don't tell her the truth,
we are still ourselves.
Then why can't we tell the truth?
Not letting them be sad or worried
is our responsibility.
I don't understand
why she'd be sad if I love you.
I don't get it either,
but she will definitely be sad.
Listen.
Be good, okay?
Are you hungry? I'll cook you supper.
I want a steak.
No problem.
I bought two steaks yesterday.
And I also want spaghetti with clams.
White wine clam pasta.
And that red soup.
You ordered so many things.
You better finish them all.
And salad!
He's the bad guy.
Right?
Your hair is falling out in chunks.
It's clogging up the drain.
It was already clogged the day I moved in.
Be careful.
Just shave it off and save us the trouble.
Okay.
I'll help you.
It's better for me to be dead.
Come here.
Look at yourself.
Look!
What are you doing?
Let's see who looks better
with a bald head.
Stop it, Chieh!
Are you afraid that you'll lose?
Are you afraid I'll win?
I'm sick. Why should I compete with you?
What's wrong?
Are you afraid of losing?
-Are you afraid of losing?
-Stop messing around, Chieh!
Please stop.
What are you doing here? It's so early.
Your son is in school already.
I know.
I followed him this morning.
I saw him going to school.
Crazy stalker.
No wonder he's so immature.
I wasn't here to supervise.
That was why he was an hour late.
You have to wake him up at 6 a.m. sharp.
It takes me half an hour to wake him up.
I thought I was going to have a stroke.
So what?
I went to bed at 4 a.m.
I have rehearsals later.
Can you leave now?
Where did he sleep last night?
On the sofa.
How could you let him sleep on a sofa?
-Would you rather he slept with me?
-Hey!
At least give him some clean sheets.
Never mind. I'll deal with this tomorrow.
Tomorrow? Get someone
to take him away today, okay?
When he sees these,
he'll stop being mad
and I'll take him home.
Don't touch my stuff.
-Your table is a mess.
-I said don't touch my stuff.
-Your book--
-That's the book he didn't finish reading.
Tell Sung Cheng-Кси
that I put all his stuff here, okay?
These are his workbooks.
I forgot to bring his skin rash medicine.
He must have been itching all night.
Let me tell you. Don't put too much.
It contains steroids.
Just put a light coat and it'll be enough.
Please take your son home
and care for him yourself.
Do you think I want this?
You stole both of my men.
-I didn't steal anyone.
-Yes!
You're so great!
You didn't steal them,
yet you have it all.
Let me tell you though.
I've already confirmed this.
Without the death
and household cancellation certificates,
even if you are the beneficiary,
you won't be able to get the money.
Where's the kitchen?
In that case,
can you get out of my house now?
Listen.
There are organic salad,
soup and whole grain rice.
I've prepared everything.
When Sung Cheng-Кси gets home,
heat it up for him.
Who has time for that?
Heat it up yourself.
Tell him you cooked this.
-Please.
-Who feeds their children these things?
Listen.
You better cooperate with me
on the insurance claim.
I can assure you.
You're not getting a single penny!
I will--
I hate organic salad.
I hate the sound of the vacuum cleaner.
I hate my skin rash cream.
I hate tuition classes.
I hate that everything has
to be put back to where it was.
I hate how she says she's so pitiful.
I hate
that she loves money so much.
Are you sure it's hate?
Hating something
and having no power over something
are two different things.
Bali
The magical Bali
How I long
For your embrace
So this is how it feels
to have no power over something.
You're welcome.
Thank you.
When are you going to go home?
Someday.
You said you'd go home
when you see these things.
Liu San-lien brought a bunch of grass.
Do you want to eat them?
-No.
-I thought so.
Is that what she feeds you every day?
It's healthy.
Then go home. I eat junk food.
-And everything I use is junk.
-Then why wouldn't my dad go home?
Are you angry that your dad moved out?
What a stupid question!
If my dad left me and my mom for a man,
I'd flip out too.
Why did you even ask then? What a retard.
Respect your stepmom.
Dumbass.
Your dad called that being genuine.
You're genuinely dumb.
To be honest, your dad really loved you.
Right. He made you the beneficiary.
Did you read the letter he left for you?
Never mind.
It's too difficult for you.
Let's see when you're a little older.
Don't you know that Liu San-lien
is really pitiful?
I know.
I also know that you
and your dad are pitiful too.
You're the only one who's not.
It seems that way.
Solve 5(2-x)-(x-2)...
What's the answer?
You wouldn't know even if I told you.
You're so good at math.
Do you know how long a million years is?
-A million years is a million years.
-Wrong!
A million years is...
when someone you love tells you
he wants to be a normal person,
then leaves you.
From that day on, every day...
is a million years.
Bitch!
-What are you doing?
-He doesn't love me.
-All right.
-How dare he?
-Who the hell does he think he is!
There are plenty of men out there.
You don't need him.
-His nose and chin are fake!
-All right.
He...
-What's with him?
Many millions of years later,
my dad reappeared.
Because he had decided to just be himself
in the remaining days of his life.
From that day on,
Liu San-lien 2.0 was born.
He complained that my house is dirty.
So he built a protective fort
to prevent me from bothering him.
So he really isn't planning on going home.
-If you don't pick him up, he can't--
-He doesn't even answer my calls.
It's kind of creative actually.
Look at the proportion!
Didn't we also do that when we were kids?
We thought our moms would always be there
so we didn't know any better.
My place is a dump.
He doesn't like it here.
Pick him up tonight.
I'm sure he'll go with you.
What are you doing?
How clean do you want my house to be
before you can leave?
Cheng-Кси is allergic to dust mites,
you have to clean the house every day.
When the sun is out,
take out all the sheets and pillows
and air them.
Why is everything so dirty?
You must turn the dehumidifier on daily.
Why don't I just quit my job
and care for you two maniacs full-time?
Sung Cheng-Кси cannot breathe in
cigarette smoke.
And drinking will mess up your mind.
Stop touching all my stuff, Auntie!
What would it take for you to leave?
I'll bring the blanket dryer tomorrow.
Will I be adopting Sung Cheng-Кси or what?
How can anyone live here?
I'm going to take off my pants
if you don't leave.
What are you doing?
Hubby, pick up the phone.
Pick up the phone, Hubby.
Hubby, pick up the phone now.
Hubby--
Can you leave now?
Listen. Remember to tell Sung Cheng-Кси
to go to therapy tomorrow.
-One hour of it is expensive. The school--
-I'm taking off my pants.
-You're even doing this to a woman!
-I'm taking it off if you don't leave.
-I...
-Mom?
Gosh, you found me.
Never mind me.
Do your thing.
Go do your thing.
Thank you for taking care of Kao Yu-chieh.
His brother passed away
when he was little.
He is basically an only child.
That's why
he's a little immature sometimes.
He still acts like a boy.
Thank you for putting up with him.
No. I...
I just do what I can.
I haven't even asked your name.
My name is Liu San-lien.
The same Chinese character
as the one for lotus.
-I'm not your son's girlfriend though.
-What a coincidence!
I sell flowers in the market.
Those that sell for 100 dollars
used for praying in temples.
When it's in season,
I sell a lot of lotus flowers.
That is quite a coincidence.
My phone number's written on it.
Yes.
Call me if you need anything.
Ma'am.
Your son and I have
a special kind of relationship,
but I am not his girlfriend.
I know.
Take your time.
It's actually better for the woman
to be older.
I'm not one of those old-fashioned folks.
Nowadays, they're always talking
about men who love men
and women who love women.
I used to worry about Chieh
not having a girlfriend.
I feel at ease now that I saw you.
YANG КсиU-YING
Hey.
How many tickets do you want?
-How much is it for one?
-Five hundred dollars.
That's expensive.
Plays are expensive.
-I might have to ask my mom about it.
-How many tickets?
-One.
-Two.
-How many?
-What's that?
-Tickets for a play.
-What's a play?
How many do you want?
-One.
-Two.
So...
you think he's a good guy?
Where do people go after they die?
What do you think?
Can they hear us talk?
Do you want your dad to hear us?
Can I get my mom to have therapy with you?
Do you want your mom to have therapy?
Why?
Because she's really annoying.
Oh gosh. Please use your imagination...
If you don't get him here,
I'll go in myself.
-What's happening?
-Hey!
You gay asshole who stole my husband,
listen carefully!
-Ma'am, we're having a rehearsal!
-Humans shouldn't be so harsh.
The heavens might not tolerate you.
Your brother drowned to death
when he was three, didn't he?
Your mom has only you left.
If you don't want your mom to go crazy,
you have three days to give me
Sung Cheng-yuan's insurance money.
Otherwise, I'll make sure she knows
that her precious son, Chieh,
is a shameless fag.
Why do you love money so much?
Did you marry Dad for his insurance money?
Yes.
I'm just waiting to get
Sung Cheng-yuan's money and his house.
I was waiting for him to die.
I married him for his insurance money.
All I care about is money.
Why are you my mom?
Sung Cheng-Кси!
Yes.
Why is that?
I really want to know too.
Get your ass back to your home right now.
I said get the hell out of here,
do you hear me?
You're so annoying.
Both of you!
Treat every rehearsal as the actual show.
Why are you all fucking standing here?
Sung Cheng-yuan left me
millions of dollars.
Didn't you fucking hear it?
Can you go back
to being professionals now?
Fuck.
Can we do our best
for the premiere tomorrow?
Can we do that?
Stage Director.
Where do we start?
That's 1,099 dollars.
I sacrificed so much for this family.
Is that wrong?
I worked hard to be a good wife and mom.
Then my husband became gay
and my son went to live with the enemy.
What kind of life is this?
What did I do to deserve this?
And I don't even get the insurance money.
Is that fair?
I thought good things
happen to good people.
Is it because I haven't done enough?
Or I'm not a good person?
Okay.
Then I'll be a bad person.
I'll be really bad.
I'll show you how bad I can be.
Have some lemon juice.
I have something for you.
Take it. Open it when you get home.
There are too many people here
at the market.
Chieh's dad gave it to me.
Let me get some flowers for Chieh.
Please take them with you
when you drop by.
I can't take it.
Take it.
It's okay. It's not expensive.
It's just a small gift.
That's why I can't take it.
I'm not your son's girlfriend.
-I know. No rush. I told you--
-I'll never be your son's girlfriend.
No woman ever will.
Because your son doesn't like women.
Your son is a husband-stealing gay man.
He stole my husband.
Please come in.
Hello, Mrs. Sung.
How is Sung Cheng-Кси?
He just left.
What did he say to you?
We're communicating well.
If I also come for therapy,
can you give me a discount?
I'd recommend
-another therapist for you.
-Can I do it now?
-In 30 minutes, I--
-I'll be quick.
They forced me to do it.
Are you fighting with Sung Cheng-yuan?
I wish we could fight.
He hasn't been home for weeks.
He doesn't even answer my calls.
Do you think he's seeing someone else?
When was the last time you guys did it?
That's not it.
He teaches in Taichung.
Cheng-Кси is all grown up.
And we've been married for so long.
That's the root of all problems.
Why do you think your brother-in-law
and I had four kids
despite his playboy lifestyle?
Sung Cheng-yuan is a professor.
He's handsome too.
Did you really think
luck would always be on your side?
Work hard for it.
Don't make him divorce you.
Don't just lie there like a dead fish.
Be more aggressive!
Be more slutty!
If it goes well in bed,
it'll go well everywhere, you know?
You're off work?
Why did you suddenly come home?
Are you busy later today?
No.
Can we talk, please?
Let me find something first.
I miss you.
Cheng-Кси will see us.
He went to tuition class.
Can we please just talk?
How about...
we listen to music and have some wine?
Don't...
San-lien, please don't do this.
I'm moving out.
Look! This bra is sexy.
My sister brought me to buy it.
She said men like this. Look!
San-lien, no.
Or maybe I can get a boob job?
-Look.
-That's not the issue.
What's the issue then?
Tell me. Where did I go wrong?
What can I improve on?
-Teach me. You like hearing me moan.
-It's not your fault, it's mine.
Don't you? I'll moan today.
I like men!
I'm homosexual.
I thought that if I try hard enough,
I could be normal.
-All these years, I really--
-I don't mind.
I forgive you.
We can go and see a doctor.
We'll get you back to normal.
We can work this out together.
I won't tell anyone that you like men.
We can still be
the happy family people envy.
It's not up to others
to define a happy family.
Are you really happy
-being Sung Cheng-yuan's wife?
-I can change.
I can learn.
And then I'll be happy.
You can change and learn too.
I learned a lot from the movies.
I'll surely satisfy you today.
San-lien, don't do this.
I swear you'll like it.
Don't do this!
I'm sorry.
I got
the divorce papers ready.
My parents' house,
this house, my savings...
You can have whatever you want.
He has never been honest with me
from the very start.
He lied to me.
And I was so stupid.
I believed him my entire life.
Good thing I have a son.
Sung Cheng-Кси can be with me.
Otherwise, what do you think I should do?
From the very start, everything was a lie.
I went to his house that day.
You'll see when I'm done.
-Don't cut it!
-I think I look handsome.
I like you with long hair.
Sung Cheng-yuan.
My son needs to grow up properly.
So listen carefully.
Don't tell Sung Cheng-Кси about this.
Sung Cheng-yuan, do you hear me?
Karma will find you. You know that?
I will not agree to the divorce.
Are you okay?
Do you want to rest?
There's no need.
I'm fine.
It's been so long.
I'm way over it.
I mean, he's dead.
Why would I still hold a grudge, right?
I just have one little question.
I thought about it for so long.
I still can't figure out.
Just this one little question.
Can you tell me?
You're a doctor. You're smart.
Can you please tell me?
I'll try my best.
Was all of it a lie?
Was there no love at all?
Not...
even
a little bit?
I thought I told you to scram.
I have something to say to you.
Say it.
Are you going to say it or not?
I read the letter my dad wrote me.
Go home.
Thank you for taking care of my dad.
Mom, come here.
Hurry!
Now!
-Come here right now!
-Stop the bus!
Excuse me!
Sung Cheng-Кси, come on.
Go home with me right now.
It's too dangerous here.
-Sung Cheng-Кси! Why...
-Mom!
Why won't you listen to me?
Come with me!
Call an ambulance!
-Call an ambulance!
-Go away!
Are you okay? I'm sorry!
Sung Cheng-Кси, call an ambulance!
-Call an ambulance!
-My friend's leg is broken!
-Tell them he's dying!
-He's dying!
Good morning!
Guess what I smuggled in for you today?
Steamed dumplings.
I knew you want to eat steamed dumplings.
What do you think?
Some steamed dumplings in exchange
for a little liver transplant surgery.
Don't you think it's a sweet deal?
Your math is way off.
Come on!
Steamed dumplings...
Steamed dumplings.
Deal.
Chieh.
Stop doing silly things.
We don't have any money.
I do.
Where did you get the money from?
Don't tell anyone.
I won the lottery.
It's no use.
Stop wasting money on me.
Do you think I'm doing this for you?
Actually, I'm doing this for myself.
So I want to keep you next to me
for a really long, long time...
I don't care.
I'm going to keep you next to me
for a long, long time.
Why did he borrow money
from those loan sharks?
It's just a theater play.
How much money can it cost?
Or is he gambling?
Or doing drugs?
No, this is too scary.
You have to come home with me today.
Do you hear me?
-Where are you going?
-The theater. It's opening night.
-How can you perform?
-The audience doesn't know the story.
-Your leg!
-I'm going on stage, even if it kills me!
I told your mom about it.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome aboard our flight to Bali.
May I remind you
that there will be no stops
during this flight.
-Now...
-Lights 1.3, get ready.
Let's begin our wonderful
vacation together.
Thank you.
Lights 1.3, go.
Lights 2.1, get ready.
What's that sound?
Never mind. Is Chieh in place?
Lights, go.
What an amazing balcony!
Keep your voice down.
You're in a deluxe villa.
You get what you pay for.
Remember when you complained
about the price?
Good thing I insisted.
Yes.
Good thing you insisted.
-I don't know why he insisted to do this.
-Mom!
Ксиao-li, I think I found a drum.
Congratulations!
Did you hear some noise?
Yes, I think I heard something.
What's that?
Excuse me.
Excuse me, is anybody there?
-Yes?
-I'm sorry.
I want to get my package.
We're closed though.
Can you please help me?
I'm really sorry. It's like this.
Your people delivered it to me today,
but I wasn't home.
But it's something that I need
to use tomorrow morning.
Good thing I ran into you.
Otherwise, I'd be in big trouble.
What are these?
Musical instruments. Listen.
I don't get it.
Here, you can have this.
Wind chimes?
No,
it's heavenly-sounding wind chimes.
Rest a bit, everyone. Come get your drink.
Thank you, Professor Sung.
Is the director here?
-I'm already here.
-Director.
This just got in yesterday.
-Let's try it out!
-Gosh!
-I thought we're doomed.
-It's so nice.
Who's he?
That guy?
He is Professor Sung Cheng-yuan.
He does our music for us.
He also teaches computing
at the university.
He's a really nice guy.
He writes our music for free every time.
Music?
He's so talented.
No eating on the catwalk.
Has no one ever told you that?
Have you been sleeping here
for the last couple of days?
I live in Linkou.
It's a waste of time to go back and forth.
I won't be late if I stay here.
Fuck.
I'll surely sleep well tonight.
Professor Sung.
Can I kiss you?
Bali
The magical Bali
How I long
For your embrace
How long must I wait?
My body is weary
Don't cover my eyes
Take me
To you
I need a normal wife.
And a normal marriage.
Sung Cheng-yuan.
Sung Cheng-yuan!
Step on it and break it.
I wish you prosperity upon this marriage!
Where are the firecrackers?
Who's lighting them?
Light them when the bride arrives. Hurry!
I don't have a lighter. Who's got one?
-Anyone got a lighter?
-Who has got a lighter?
-I do.
-Get the groom.
-The groom has a lighter!
-Get the groom inside!
Go inside!
-Come and get ready!
-Light the firecrackers!
Tina.
Tina, your voice
and your name sounds familiar.
Have we met before?
What?
Hello?
Tina.
Tina, are you still there?
Hello?
Is this Ms. Liu San-lien?
Can you come to the hospital now?
Can you please
come see Sung Cheng-yuan
for the last time?
The lover borrowed a lot of money
from bad guys
to get my dad a liver transplant.
However, one month after the surgery,
my dad coughed up a lot of blood.
I was in class that day.
During the entire class,
my stomach ached...
really badly.
And then they told me
that my dad had died.
Go.
Go talk to him.
No.
Why?
Hatred makes it easier to heal.
Bullshit.
Love makes it easier to heal.
Maybe after the surgery is successful.
After the successful surgery,
I will definitely
talk to him.
After the surgery is successful.
-After the surgery is successful.
-How magical
You should know
-Bali
-The magical Bali
-How I long
-For your embrace
How long must I wait?
-How much longer
My body is weary
-It's so weary
-Take me
-To you
-Bali
-How magical
A shooting star!
-Where?
-There.
Make a wish!
Me too.
Today is the 100th day
since your dad's death.
What did you guys wish for?
He said he wants to be
with my dad forever.
Now,
he can finally say goodbye
to my dad properly.
Hello, doctor.
I won't be seeing you anymore.
My mom said all doctors are scammers,
especially therapists.
You're expensive, yet you're useless.
However, I've been getting along better
with Liu San-lien recently.
Other than infuriating me last week,
we haven't fought
-for a whole month.
-You don't put your exam sheets away.
Don't tell me you'll review them.
You never use the workbooks I bought.
Grow up, will you?
You have to aim high in life.
Stop making me angry all the time, okay?
Grow up.
We stopped contacting Chieh afterwards.
My mom said that distance
is the best gift for all of us.
However...
...she secretly gave
the insurance money to Chieh.
Thank you, Auntie!
Who are you calling Auntie?
Do you want to take your grass back?
-I don't eat grass.
-How rude.
-I wonder what Sung Cheng-yuan saw in you.
-Hey.
Auntie!
-Miss, your fried chicken chop.
-So
the final winner
is fried chicken chop.
What would you like to order?
Two fried chicken chops.
Sure. Just a moment.
How much is it?
That's all
I've got to say.
I want to tell you thank you.
I wish you prosperity.
Yours truly, Sung Cheng-Кси.
The Bali of my dreams
How magical
You should know
What are you laughing at?
You're amazing. Every key is off.
How should I sing it then?
Like this.
Bali
The Bali of my dreams
-That's how I sang it.
-Of course not.
That's exactly how I sang it before.
-As if.
-Bali
-The Bali of my dreams
-You're singing it wrong.
-How should I sing it then?
-Bali
-Do it again.
-You're totally off.
I'm not.
Ba...
-Bali
-You're totally off-key.
Ladies and gentlemen.
Welcome aboard our flight to Bali.
We're currently cruising
at thirty-six thousand feet...