-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
Today, Germany is proud of its economic miracle.
It is also proud to be the home of Goethe and Beethoven.
But Germany is also the country of Hitler, Eichmann
and their many accomplices and followers.
But as the day consists of day and night
The history of every people has its light and dark sides.
I believe that the young generation in Germany is ready
to know the whole story, the whole truth
which, however, is sometimes difficult for her parents to cope with.
Dr. Bauer?
I'm bringing your groceries, Doctor.
Should I clear up?
...is German merchant shipping. But also air freight transport...
Your car will be ready tomorrow from 7 a.m. If you need me earlier, let me know.
Have a nice evening, Doctor.
Doctor?
Doctor
Doctor!
Help! Help, we need help!
We examined the crime scene, but it does not look like an assassination attempt.
It seems that the general had consumed an unfortunate mixture of alcohol and sleeping pills.
- Sleeping pills? How many sleeping pills? - Two or three are missing.
If there were more, one might think the general wanted to kill himself.
One might think he is overwhelmed.
- True. - Examine the apartment thoroughly.
Kreidler?
Federal Criminal Police Office.
- Kreidler? - Good evening, Chief Public Prosecutor.
Your supervisor almost died today.
- An assassination attempt? - No.
One could interpret it as a kind of suicide attempt.
What incident is he in?
He's getting back on his feet.
But the question is whether and for how long can we even afford such an Attorney General?
I mean, a little more pressure and the man would be, his place would be free.
Thank you, Gebhardt.
- You're welcome. Have a nice evening. - I'll have one.
We continue our conversation with Mr. Eichmann on the Jewish question.
I'd be interested to know how the situation with the Jews would have turned out in the best case scenario, in your opinion, Mr. Eichmann?
I tell you quite honestly, Comrade Sassen,
we had exterminated 10.3 million of the 10.3 million Jews,
I would be satisfied and say: "Well, we have destroyed an enemy.
Our task for our blood, our people,
We would then have fulfilled the freedom of the peoples.
I was also to blame for the fact that the elimination of our enemy, which I had conceived,
could not be fully implemented.
I was an inadequate mind.
That is my fault.
In truth, I could and should have done more.
Good afternoon, Attorney General.
I don't want to talk about it. But thank you.
Fritz!
- Mr. Prime Minister, what an honor. - I wanted to visit you.
Oh, that's nice of you. But it's hardly worth mentioning.
You could have called.
Sit down, we need to talk.
Leave us alone for a moment, please?
There are rumors, Fritz.
What kind of rumors?
That you tried to take your own life.
I haven't been able to sleep without chemicals for a long time.
As your employer, I cannot ignore such rumors.
I have a gun.
If I want to kill myself, there are no rumors.
Dr. Bauer! How nice to see you well! I heard about your mishap.
Don't worry, Kreidler, I'm fine.
Are you sure? You look pale. Some fresh air would do you good.
Yes, you are actually right.
Would you like to visit me at my country house? Are you interested in hunting?
Yes, but not on animals.
Was someone in my room?
- Not that I know of. Is something missing again? - The Schneider file.
Please gather all prosecutors.
Now?
I just need the special department heads.
Please.
- Good day. - Good evening, gentlemen. Please.
- Thank you very much. - Dr. Bauer.
Yes, thank you for coming to this late meeting. As you know, I've been unwell for a few days.
Who wants a cigar?
- No thanks. - Thank you.
No thanks, absolutely not.
Gut.
What is the search for Bormann and Mengele doing?
There's nothing new.
- The search for Eichmann? - Unfortunately, I have nothing new to report, Doctor Bauer.
Mr. Kügler, Mr. Vogel, do you have something to report?
- Well, uh - We've been busy with a few other cases over the last few days.
There is no decisive development.
How could it be? You were only unwell for a week.
Yes, what could possibly happen?
if nothing happened in the twelve years after the war?
Well, then thank you.
With all due respect, Dr. Bauer, was that all?
- What do you mean? - Shouldn't the meeting have been held until Monday?
Sorry to disturb your domestic happiness.
I don't think I have to apologize for planning to spend some time with my young children on Friday nights.
And I don't think you have to apologize to me for anything.
While I was away, another file disappeared from my office.
This time it's that of SS commander Schneider, who today works comfortably at Mercedes-Benz.
My own agency is enemy territory
and nothing is moving forward here at all.
- Goodbye. - Goodbye.
Goodbye.
Dr. Bauer?
I have the Schneider file.
- You have them? - Yes. You asked me last week for my assessment of the evidence presented against Schneider.
Why didn't you just say that?
I didn't mean to embarrass you.
That makes you a rare exception, Angermann. Thank you.
Good evening.
Please contact me at Copenhagen. The Tiefenthal family.
- Tiefenthal, good evening. - Hello, Walter. - Hello?
This is Fritz. Am I disturbing you?
Fritz? Hello! How are you? Margot, your brother
- Thank you. Thank you, very good. And you? - Everything's great.
- Hey, here she comes. - Fritz, how beautiful!
Margot, my love.
Am I disturbing you? I just wanted to hear your voice.
Why? What's going on? Have you received death threats again?
No, no. Everything's fine.
I might be able to make it to Copenhagen for your birthday after all.
Oh, that would be nice. We would be delighted.
Should I invite your wife? Then we'd all be together.
Yes, yes, go ahead and invite her if you want. I'd be happy.
Um, I have to get back to work now, Margot.
Goodbye.
Good day.
- Three oranges. - With pleasure.
Nick?
- Where is Nick? - He wanted to go swimming with a girl.
- What's there to grin about? - I think he likes her.
The main thing is that he doesn't bring them with him.
See you in the morning.
Hello! Is there anything left to eat?
What is?
Oh, good morning, Dr. Bauer. I thought you were already in Copenhagen.
I'm going to the airport now. I just brought some work with me.
Why not use these few days to relax?
I would be the first to be able to relax at a family celebration.
- Good morning. - Thank you. - With pleasure.
Oh, this one seems to be private.
Dear Mr. Bauer: I have started to present this letter to you today, so this is done in the hope
that you help me in catching a man wanted for multiple murders.
Dr. Bauer, it's for you.
I have reason to believe that Adolf Eichmann
- Dr. Bauer? - is staying in a suburb of Buenos Aires under a false name.
My daughter Silvia fell in love with Eichmann's eldest son Nick.
In the Argentine newspaper, I could only read that your agency is following the Eichmann case.
Adolf Eichmann
was responsible for the transport of millions of Jews from all over Europe
in large camps where they were murdered.
If you are interested in my information,
I would be very pleased to receive an answer from you
Yours sincerely, Hermann.
Please cancel my flight to Copenhagen and connect me with my sister.
Hello, can you hear me?
- Fritz! - Rosa Luxemburg?
You're pretty daring. What does the Federal Office for the Protection of the Constitution say about this?
- They're probably still investigating who the picture is. Come in. - Thanks.
Sit down.
Thanks.
Brandy?
No thanks.
A man named Lothar Hermann
believes he has discovered Adolf Eichmann in Argentina.
Obersturmbandführer of the SS,
Head of Department IV, B4 in the Reich Security Main Office
responsible for the "resettlement" of the Jews.
The investigation file was created in 1945.
Hmm. And what do you want to do now?
Bring him to trial in Germany.
Well, good.
But I don't know how.
I just don't know how.
- Your holy anger is good. It keeps you young. - No!
My anger is accompanied by powerlessness. And that ages me!
Undoubtedly. What have I achieved?
One can no longer insult Hitler's assassins as traitors, fine. But otherwise? Nothing!
All investigations are stuck.
You know, after '45, I really thought we had defeated evil.
I thought we could now establish a new society:
free, just, brotherly.
But people don't want any visions.
They want to buy a pleasant single-family home and a small car.
They want Adenauer's damned reconciliation!
The restoration has once again defeated the revolution, as has happened so often in Germany.
I can't breathe in here!
You knew it wouldn't be easy.
Eichmann, that would be a blow. He's the central figure.
The organizer of the Final Solution.
All the threads converge with him.
Do you know how many people would lose sleep at night if we put him in the dock in Frankfurt?
I tried to contact Interpol
but they say they are not responsible for political crimes.
There is no investigative authority that is not riddled with National Socialists.
The BKA, the BND and the Federal Office for the Protection of the Constitution.
But you have your prosecutors.
Files are disappearing in my own agency.
Rome wasn't built in a day.
When we fought on the streets for the SPD in the Weimar Republic,
You were in more of a hurry there than here, in your cozy official villa.
I made you Attorney General.
Stick with it, take them to court, but don't feel sorry for yourself.
In a few years, Germany will be able to forgive them and face their past.
If Eichmann escapes,
then I won't have the strength for a few more years, Georg.
I will contact the Mossad.
This is treason.
There should be no doubt about my patriotism.
- If this gets out, you'll go to jail. - That's why no one would know except you.
I don't think that's a wise decision, Fritz.
And what do you think I should answer Lothar Hermann's letter?
You have a visitor. Mr. Gebhardt from the Federal Criminal Police Office.
- Gebhardt. - Yes. Our friend seems to be regaining his strength.
But.
I heard he canceled a trip to see his sister shortly before. Do you know the reason?
It's always the same reason, Gebhardt. He's obsessed.
- Ambition isn't something everyone is born with, unfortunately. - Everything in its own time, Gebhardt.
They are very calm, but our friends who are now abroad are not having such a comfortable time.
Who are you thinking of?
I don't know exactly, that's my problem.
Farmer has a new horse, and I don't know who he has in his sights.
He has submitted a request to Interpol
without being specific, and knowing whether the high-ranking SS officer whose arrest warrant is being sought can be arrested abroad.
Mhm. What did you answer?
- That we are not responsible for political crimes. - Exactly.
He can't do anything, he is completely isolated.
Don't underestimate him.
- What is that? Danish? - Yes. - I can't read that.
It is a report from the immigration police.
Bauer was caught several times with prostitutes in Denmark, with male prostitutes.
- He's gay? - Yes.
Oh.
The Jew is gay?
- If we catch him with some guy, he's finished. - Exactly.
And even a monk has to fuck sometime.
May I?
Please.
- Enjoy your meal, Angermann. - Enjoy your meal.
- It's not so bad today. - Yes, of course.
This case concerns me.
- What's going on? - A 175.
A young medical student named Johann Kraus.
Shortly before completing his studies, he was denounced for his homosexuality
He was sentenced to two and a half years in prison for "unnatural lewdness."
He lost his study permit.
And now he's been caught serving a public need instead of being a prostitute.
He had earned five marks through mutual masturbation.
I'm not sure what sentence I should ask for.
Six months in prison.
Where is the problem?
Six months for mutual masturbation?
You seem personally attacked, Angermann.
Yes, I am too.
Because only through the tightening of Paragraph 175 by the National Socialists did mutual masturbation become a criminal offense.
The Federal Court of Justice has ruled
the law does not embody typical National Socialist worldviews.
Yes.
I have to go again.
- Are you familiar with the Valentin ruling? - No.
Hamburg Regional Court, approximately summer '51.
This might interest you.
Welcome aboard our DC-6 International Airline flight
Please place your large hand luggage safely under the seat in front of you
Is there any news for me?
No, sir. No news.
- Thank you. - Have a nice day.
Thanks.
Thank you.
No!
- Who's there? - Dr. Bauer?
- Yes? - We're supposed to pick you up.
Okay. Come in!
- Good morning. - Hello. One moment, please.
You can take off the mask.
Excuse the security precautions.
Sorry. I don't understand Yiddish.
Harel. You can call me lsser.
Is it true?
My name is Fritz. I wasn't expecting to see you in person.
I didn't mean for us to have no interest in Eichmann.
In the last few months we have carried out two investigations.
This file contains everything we have discovered.
The trail is a dead trail.
A dead lead? That can't be true.
I wish it were different.
The first examination was conducted by one of my men.
But he didn't find anyone similar to Eichmann.
No Eichmann? And who is that?
This is Nick Eichmann's mother, Vera Leibl.
Vera Leibl-Eichmann, Eichmanns Frau!
We conducted a second investigation.
Silvia Hermann entered the house under false pretenses.
She is a brave girl.
Silvia Hermann was in the house?
She confirmed that a man of Eichmann’s age lives there,
and that Nick calls him "Tate".
- Nick calls him "Father." - There you go!
- But Vera Leibl apparently remarried after the war. - What?
- She remarried - I know.
I interviewed her mother in Germany and find her testimony completely unbelievable.
Vera Leibl is said to have remarried after the war
and emigrated to America with the new husband and the three Eichmann sons.
Since then, the mother claims not to have heard from her, yet no one else in the family has allegedly had any contact.
They don't even know whether it's South or North America, you understand?
I don't think she remarried.
- The house owner is Austrian. - Eichmann is Austrian.
Francisco Schmidt.
We checked him. He is definitely not Adolf Eichmann.
And what is that?
The electricity meter is registered under both names.
Electricity meter? Two tenants distribute: "Klement" and "Dagoto." Have you checked the names?
Adolf Eichmann stole from the richest people in Europe.
Do you seriously believe
when he wished to stay in the house for twelve years?
This is our file on Eichmann.
One person claims he works in Nassere's advisory staff in Cairo.
Someone else says he flies back and forth between Africa and Switzerland.
And according to this, he lives in Kiel and breeds rabbits.
They should have checked the two names on the electricity meter: Klement and Dagoto.
I must defend the living Jews of Israel, not the dead.
You can have your letter back.
Unfortunately, we cannot help you.
The Mossad is a small secret service.
I must deploy my people against our Arab enemies.
- You speak German! - Yes.
But not gladly.
If you find a second, independent source,
which clearly states that Eichmann is in Argentina,
I can continue.
- This can't be true! - Silence in the courtroom!
Quiet or I'll clear the hall!
Mr. Prosecutor Angermann, would you please explain to the court how you came to this conclusion,
to demand such an absurd sentence for the defendant Johann Kraus?
I refer to the Valentin judgment of 21 June 51 in Hamburg,
in the district court director Dr. Valentin in a similar case
sentenced two men to three marks each for continued same-sex activity.
Since the defendant earned five marks through mutual masturbation,
I consider my demand for a fine of five marks to be justified.
- Quiet! - Anyone can leave now
In the name of the people, the following judgment is issued:
Five months in prison for homosexual prostitution.
The court also orders
that the convicted person may not have any contact with men under the age of 21 in the future.
The hearing is closed.
I would like to thank you.
- Thank you for what? - I'm a friend of Johann Kraus.
You were there, and you saw for yourself the inhumane sentence I helped to pass on him.
What you did took a lot of courage.
For that
I would like to thank you.
- Why don't you come by sometime? - At the "Kokett"? I don't think
Good morning, Miss Schütt. Has anything unusual happened here during my absence?
Oh yes, a little scandal.
Public prosecutor Angermann demanded a fine of five marks for a 175 cc car at the regional court.
The judge was beside himself. You can imagine.
And
can I.
Mr. Angermann.
- Dr. Bauer, greetings. - Good evening.
I heard about your request for a scandalous sentence.
- Because of the five marks? - A "Heiermann," as they say.
For immoral homosexual prostitution. You're certainly bold!
Chief Public Prosecutor Kreidler considers it a scandal.
And I think it is a scandal that Kreidler is the senior public prosecutor.
- I have something to discuss with you. Could you come to me on Saturday? - Saturday?
It's not official but confidential, so I don't want to discuss it in the office.
My friends are getting a new kitchen on Saturday. Would Sunday be possible?
- Okay. 11 o'clock? - Sure.
Ah, Angermann!
- Good day, Dr. Bauer. - Good day.
- Coffee? - With pleasure.
Please take off your coat.
Yes.
Tchaikovsky.
Pathetic Symphony
My favorite music.
Yes, fine. What's it about, Dr. Bauer?
Your wife will survive, Angermann.
Sorry. She's very Catholic, and today is Sunday.
- How long have you been married? - Two years.
- Children? - No. - Why not?
Why did you want to talk to me?
Read this.
What do you want to do?
I contacted the Mossad.
But they demand a second, independent source that confirms Eichmann in Argentina,
before starting an operation.
Do you know "The Way"?
A right-wing propaganda sheet from Buenos Aires.
I want you to find out whether this name actually represents Adolf Eichmann.
What will the Mossad do if we find a second source?
Kidnap Eichmann and bring him to trial, I think. What do you think?
I think we're committing treason. The BND is our executive branch.
Do you really think the BND doesn't know where these people are hiding?
And the CIA probably knows it too.
- At most, they would warn Eichmann. - I'm not so sure about that.
Even if the BND orders many former Nazis,
he must bow to Adenauer's policies. And Adenauer wants reconciliation with Israel.
Perhaps a major trial against a war criminal like Eichmann would be quite welcome.
Are you serious?
In such a trial, Eichmann would name countless names in connection with the Final Solution,
perhaps even that of State Secretary Hans Globke.
Adenauer may want to correct the image of the Germans, but he won't give up his right hand for that.
Globke controls the Chancellery, the BND, the Federal Office for the Protection of the Constitution and the CDU.
In any case, his name would be mentioned in connection with the deportations,
if only because of his legal commentary on the Nuremberg Race Laws.
Globke is guilty.
And if Globke falls, it threatens the entire Adenauer government.
And if Adenauer has a problem, the USA has a problem.
Nobody from Bonn to Washington wants Eichmann to go to trial.
- But treason can't be the solution. - Damn it, Angermann!
Do you want justice or just a new kitchen?
If we want to do something for our country,
In this case we have to reveal it.
I have to think about it.
Oh, forget it.
I was obviously mistaken.
Go home. Install the new oven.
I hope you bought a German product.
With all due respect, Dr. Bauer.
Do you think you can persuade me to commit treason with this political polemic?
You sound more and more like the one your opponents want you to be
- like a vengeful man! - Oho, oho!
Don't force yourself. You mean like a vengeful Jew!
What are you doing, Angermann?
Allow me to be your friend. Good day.
We have a very young audience today. But please don't hold back, Dr. Bauer.
Open the eyes of these young people!
Please don't go easy on our audience.
I remember that I devoured all of his writings during my studies!
He used to be so optimistic but
Oh!
- The guests will be here soon. - We still have time.
I can't.
No, please. I
I can't now.
I can now...Aren't you listening? I had an argument with the general today.
- What are you afraid of? Losing your job? - No!
Yes too.
My brother would be happy and you would earn more.
Please don't start talking about that now. I don't want to work as a criminal defense attorney!
Whatever you want, as long as we don't have children, it's fine.
- There are even supposed to be prosecutors with children! Imagine! - Yes? Then ask them how they're made.
- Karl. - Good evening, Hans.
The kitchen is wonderful. Thanks again, that was very generous.
You don't need to thank me. Finally fill this house with life.
- That's amazing. - Great, isn't it? It turned out fantastic.
- Well, angel? - Thank you very much! - Satisfied?
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen, and welcome to our discussion at the Kellerclub.
- Hessian Attorney General Dr. Fritz Bauer - Ingrid! Here we go!
meets a young audience to address the questions of their generation.
Right now, right now the discussion begins.
Dr. Bauer; I would like to ask you
What can a German still be proud of today?
- I don't know if I understand your question correctly - Well, people like you have made us think so badly of Germany.
And we are asked to show energy and interest,
to build something, how is that supposed to work?
Sorry, that wasn't my intention.
You know, after the war, when I
When I returned to Germany for the first time, I traveled on the train with a young man.
Karl!
- We were just bragging about politics, he told me about himself - Oh!
Your boss, right?
- Yes. - of his hopes, of the whole of human life
- Charlotte! - I'd love to see that too, angel.
Oh, the general in the basement? That'll be interesting.
Then I thought to myself: "For this generation, it is worth
to return to Germany from exile."
But if you ask me about me,
quite human, then I must tell you
It seems to me
as if the walls were collapsing on me from everywhere.
You have to stop there, and there and there too, because everything is collapsing on me.
But Dr. Bauer, we have a democratic constitution, and we can be proud of it!
Can you see it
I think we Germans
cannot be proud of our forests and our mountains,
because we can't do anything about it.
We cannot be proud of Goethe and Schiller either
and not on Einstein either, because we can't do anything about all that.
We can only be proud of the good things we have done ourselves.
Only today
A young person who means a lot to me told me that I am tough, sometimes hurtful.
It's just as difficult for me as it is for everyone else to always be good.
But I believe that the atmosphere in the Federal Republic of Germany is determined by this
what we all do every day, as fathers, as mothers, as sons.
You can make paragraphs and write articles,
You can have the best constitution. What you need are the people,
who live these democratic things.
What sentimentality. Is this how this person runs his agency?
No one creates democracy
Don't worry, Karl. Old guard, our lord father.
This is the task we all face.
We must not lose courage
Come on, Karl.
Karl?
What are you doing?
Karl, would you please come down immediately?
He is a good informant, and I know that he has contacts with "The Way" in Argentina.
- Is he trustworthy? - In the Third Reich, he was in Hitler's enemy reconnaissance department.
So one of Reinhard Gehlen's men? Is he now working for the BND?
- But maybe also for the other side. - For the Stasi? - It's possible.
But he is a good informant.
In my opinion, he is one thing above all: for sale.
If he works for the Stasi, we'll go to prison.
And if he is a loyal BND man,
he might warn Eichmann.
But if we're lucky, he'll find a second source.
Let's take the risk.
- Good presentation, Dr. Bauer. - Your words moved me deeply.
Yes, yes, thank you.
Great, Dr. Bauer, absolutely great!
Good morning
- What a wonderful performance. - Yes, enough. Thank you.
- Is it your birthday? - No, it came from Prime Minister Zinn with this telegram, here.
And this is your mail.
I'll never appear on television again if that's the case.
Keep the flowers! They're not for me.
- What's going on? - I need information about a journalist,
who writes for "The Way" in Argentina.
His name is Klaus Eichmann and we wonder if Adolf Eichmann is behind it.
You'd like to know, wouldn't you?
That would be a scoop for the vengeful TV prosecutor,
if he could find dear Uncle Eichmann.
- Can you figure it out or not? - Of course. It's just a question of price.
- These are from the last few days. - Because of the TV show.
- They came in the mail today? - Yes. - 9 mm.
As far as I know, you are armed, Mr. Bauer?
Yes that is correct.
What caliber is your gun?
- 9 mm. - Also. Look.
- I'd like to see your weapon. - Do you think he writes threatening letters to himself?
- I never said that, how do you know that? - Why do you want to see my gun?
What exactly was the motivation for your television appearance?
Out.
Out!
- If we're to investigate, you have to cooperate. - Forget the opportunity!
Could I perhaps speak to you privately?
You just misunderstood that, Mr. Attorney General.
I support your cause wherever I can.
Yes.
I have a reliable source,
according to which a person you are looking for is in Kuwait.
The person is Obersturmbandführer Adolf Eichmann.
He's hiding in Kuwait.
That's interesting.
In fact, we have been looking for Adolf Eichmann for a long time.
But as you have already confirmed to me several times,
Neither the BKA nor Interpol is responsible for political criminals.
Correct. Unfortunately.
You should simply file an extradition request, then we can cooperate with the local authorities.
Thank you, Mr. Gebhardt. I'll take care of that.
We must protect our country from its enemies.
Yes, that's probably right.
What happened?
I need some fresh air.
I won't be coming back, Miss Schütt.
- Dr. Bauer, what did Gebhardt say? - It's over, Angermann.
- Get back to business as usual. We've been exposed. - Why?
Gebhardt told me, without being asked, that Eichmann was in Kuwait.
- He knows we're looking for him. - Morlach! This is my fault.
No, that wasn't your fault, we had to try.
But if Gebhardt knows, Eichmann will be long gone.
It's far too dangerous for far too many people.
Maybe it was really naive of me to think we could bring him to trial in Frankfurt.
But that would have been something, Angermann.
Gebhardt!
He had the nerve to tell me that we had to protect our country from its enemies.
The SS-Untersturmführer in the security service! Me!
I fought for the SPD on the streets during the Weimar Republic!
My father fought for our Kaiser in World War I.
Tell me, Angermann. Tell me honestly, am I an enemy of our country?
No, Fritz, you are not.
- Goodbye, Karl. - What will you do now?
Sleep. Sleep for a very long time.
Quitting time!
- Good evening. Thank you very much. - Have a nice evening.
That's not the case with me.
I play my game the way I want!
Incognito, incognito.
Come, play with me.
From today we are
incognito, incognito.
- No one will ever know - A whiskey, please.
What we are and what we were.
Come on, let's take it to the extreme.
As long as we remain incognito.
Herein.
I just wanted to say good evening. You sang beautifully.
Hello, Mr. Angermann. Come in.
- You remember? - Of course!
I just didn't think you'd come by.
I had a lot of work.
You look unhappy, Mr. Prosecutor.
A lost cause.
Is there anything I can do to cheer you up?
Do you know the prices?
But you, Mr. Prosecutor, are family.
It's free for you.
No, please
What are you doing here so late at night?
I don't know, I
I have to go too, unfortunately.
They sang beautifully.
- Hello? - I have news.
What are you doing calling in the middle of the night?
- That's not how it works. - Calm down, calm down!
Prosecutor, what is it?
You want to catch a big fish, right? Listen.
I have news for you. Klaus Eichmann is not the man you're looking for. The last name is a coincidence.
Stop that. I know you betrayed us.
Me? Really? Before you paid me? Are you stupid?
Maybe you'll get paid twice.
Does the name Willem Sassen mean anything to you?
He is Dutch and was an SS war correspondent.
After the war he became Perón's press advisor.
Since the political situation in Argentina is no longer so rosy, he has been having money problems.
Who doesn’t have one?
Sassen lives in Buenos Aires
and has for years
Interviews conducted.
Obviously dear Uncle Eichmann wants
adjust his place in history somewhat.
So he agreed to
Sassen to have his memoirs written.
- You mean these are Adolf Eichmann's memoirs? - Yes, of course.
But that's only part of it,Sassen has to watch hundreds of tapes.
He thinks it will be a big hit.
But since he's in a mess financially, he wants to sell some of it.
In any case, it proves
that Adolf Eichmann is imprisoned in Argentina.
Can one say that you were definitely involved in the decimation of the Jews?
Yes, yes. After all, I transported the Jews.
Without me they wouldn't have come to the executioner.
I am comparable to a commander who attacks a German city with his bomber squadron.
Has he been convicted?
Why are we condemned?
I didn't kill anyone.
Just as the ground crew loaded the bombs, we transported the Jews.
Apart from Morlach, only the Prime Minister knows about our search for Eichmann.
Why should Gebhardt
out of the blue talking about Eichmann?
I don't know it.
They contacted Gebhardt himself because of the death threats.
Maybe he just dropped it, for no reason, pure coincidence.
- Because he knows we're investigating. - Maybe.
Dagoto or Clement?
The Mossad should have checked these names.
Yes, I wonder how Eichmann lives these days. Does he have a job?
Perhaps he, like so many Germans, works for this dubious company in Argentina?
- Capri? - Yes.
Or Mercedes.
Schneider. He works at Mercedes-Benz in Stuttgart.
SS-Schneider.
Angermann, I'm going to get myself killed.
Turn on the fan.
- Yes, please? - Mr. Schneider, we have a visitor for you.
- I didn't note down an appointment. - A Dr. Bauer; the Hessian Attorney General.
Please.
Thanks.
- Good afternoon, Mr. Schneider. - Attorney General.
- Please thank.
How can I help you?
I am investigating your activities with the security service's task forces.
No calls please.
There is a possibility that your case will be closed for the time being.
And how?
You're part of the human resources department here at Daimler, have I understood that correctly?
Yes.
I would like to know whether a Mr. Dagoto or a Mr. Klement
works at Mercedes-Benz in Argentina.
And?
We have our second source.
If Eichmann isn't gone.
Come, play with me,
From today on we are incognito.
Incognito.
No one will ever know
what we are and what we were.
Come on, let’s take it to the extreme,
as long as we remain incognito.
I'm happy to pay.
Really.
I don't expect any favors.
As you wish.
Good morning!
Hello, my angel. Sorry, we worked all night last night.
Thank you. How lovely.
Karl
We're having a baby.
- Good day, Miss Schütt. - Good morning, Doctor.
Please book me a flight to Paris next weekend,
- Return flight a week later. - Will do.
There was an urgent appointment request from Ludwigsburg. The head of the central office, Dr. Schüle, is looking for an appointment with you.
- Is that what I'm putting behind your journey? - Did the student say what he wanted?
It concerns an arrest warrant against a Mr. Eichmann, Adolf.
Case number 6842.
Ask Dr. Schüle how quickly he can get here.
I'll do it.
- Thank you very much. - Thank you.
- Cigar? - With pleasure.
Then tell me.
Does the name Adolf Eichmann mean anything to you?
Secure.
We maintain the investigation file.
I don't mean to offend you, Dr. Bauer, but you have to take action.
A certain Tuviah Friedman, a private investigator from Israel
He's giving me and the entire central office hell.
He is in contact with a Mr. Hermann from Argentina.
He says he knows that Eichmann is hiding in Argentina
and you would know that and do nothing.
Tell Mr. Tuviah Friedman that the Frankfurt public prosecutor's office
carries out her task conscientiously.
And that we know from a reliable source,
that Mr Eichmann is in Kuwait and not in Argentina.
But he shouldn't pursue this any further now, do you understand, Dr. Schüle?
Because if Eichmann is warned in Kuwait, he might disappear forever.
Prepare a press conference, Angermann.
When I come back,
then we announce that we believe we have tracked down Eichmann in Kuwait.
Dr. Bauer, I
Good luck.
What's going on, Angermann?
I'm going to be a father.
Will you accompany me to the airport?
- Gebhardt here. - Yes, Kreidler.
The general seems to be genuinely interested in Eichmann.
This morning he met with Dr. Schüle from the Central Office of the State Justice Administration.
He then told me that they were now looking for Eichmann in Kuwait.
Yes. Some of our compatriots are actually staying in Kuwait.
The general is currently traveling to Paris.
I wonder whether the colleagues from the BND could take a look at Mr Bauer,
with the persistent death threats recently.
Yes, that's a good idea. I'll take care of it. Thanks.
- I know I can't be a good father - Why do you think that?
Don't worry, Mr. Mahler and I have known each other for many years.
We have some skeletons in the closet.
You can say whatever you want here without worry.
There are these rumors about you, Dr. Bauer,
Rumors that say that the Gestapo persecuted you not only as a socialist because of your Jewish origins
It is said that you had special problems with the Danish vice squad.
Yes. There were incidents.
I've had the feeling for some time now that we have similar interests.
I met someone.
- An "easy girl," you understand? - How often were you together?
Once.
What should I tell you, Karl?
You know that you are committing a criminal offense.
The first time, you can still excuse yourself as a client by saying
that one did not know that the lady was not a lady.
But not the second time.
My wife Anna Maria and I have been separated for many years,
She in Copenhagen, me here.
I think it is one of the happiest marriages ever.
If your wife is a good companion, you don't have to be afraid of raising children.
You will be a fantastic father.
I am so grateful for your openness.
But the price we have to pay is very high.
You mustn't see the young man again, Karl, you know that.
- Not? - Yes.
Are you flying further? This way.
- Are you flying on, sir? - Yes. - This way.
- Yes? - The general flies on to Israel.
Yes, wherever Jews fly.
Maybe he turns to the Israeli secret service.
That would be considered treason.
Even.
Dr. Bauer.
- Chaim Cohn. Call me Herman. - Good afternoon.
Come in. Nice to finally meet you.
You already know Isser Harel. This is Zvi Aharoni, who was also born in Germany.
- I'm from the other Frankfurt. - Aha.
By the way, you know that I studied in Frankfurt am Main.
I should visit you sometime. Please sit down.
- Would you like something to drink? - No, I want to get to the point.
I have discovered a second, independent source,
which confirms that Eichmann's code name is Ricardo Klement.
You already said that on the phone.
We need to verify your source.
We've lost months and you want to check the source first?
Eichmann could change his code name and move. How much more time will pass? It's simply unbelievable!
Any second-rate cop could lead this investigation to success!
Dr. Bauer, we understand your excitement.
Zvi is a very capable officer. He is to lead the new investigation.
I know the status of the investigation, which is, of course, as Harel says: if we can trust the second source, then I will lead an operation.
Who is the second source, Dr. Bauer?
I have already risked the safety of the first source,
and it was he who should have had the Hermann family examined.
My second source remains secret. My word will have to suffice.
Ricardo Klement is Adolf Eichmann.
If you do not act now,
I will contact the German authorities.
If they helped, you wouldn't be here.
Do you think so?
We will try our best, Dr. Bauer.
Thanks.
There is one more thing.
If you have Eichmann, I will request his extradition to Israel.
I do not want him to be judged in Israel as if he had murdered 6 million Jews alone.
Eichmann must appear in court in Frankfurt.
We must confront the Germans with their past.
I will support your proposal, Dr. Bauer.
Wonderful, thank you very much.
Schalem.
- And good luck. - I'll do my best.
When I am back in Frankfurt, I will explain to the press,
that I suspect Eichmann is in Kuwait.
Gut.
I have called this press conference
because we learned from the Federal Criminal Police Office,
that the SS Obersturmbandführer Adolf Eichmann, who was responsible for the deportation of the Jews
went into hiding in Kuwait.
An extradition request has been submitted.
Wait, please not all at once.
Next stop: Carretera San Fernando.
Wait, señor.
The German people feel deep satisfaction,
that through reparations for victims of Nazism
and contribution to the development process of Israel
The Germany of today is no longer the Germany of yesterday.
I wish the Chancellor success in his efforts,
To lead Germany on the path to democracy and international cooperation.
- Yes? - We have him.
Thanks.
Extra edition! Extra edition! Adolf Eichmann caught in Argentina!
Extra sheet! Extra sheet!
Adolf Eichmann caught in Argentina!
Dr. Bauer!
Another glass please.
- We did it, Karl! - I can't believe it!
- You could tell me better in a quiet place. - I don't know any more!
- Stupid, Karl! - Stupid!
We are all lined up for morning roll call before the dreaded camp commandant,
and he yells: "Schumacher! Why are you in a concentration camp?"
Schumacher says: "Because I belong to the defeated party."
He didn't know anything about that.
Kurt Schumacher remained in the concentration camp for twelve years.
But I
I have expressed my concern in an open letter
subjected to the Nazis, they printed it in the newspaper:
"The socialist farmer submits." That's where I got out.
I have never forgiven myself for that.
Schumacher did not submit.
One must never bow to tyranny, Karl.
Never.
I have to go upstairs now, I can't take any more.
I'm a man,
with everything included,
what you do,
and even if you laugh at me,
I am just
A sweet little freak of nature.
I am a man, just look at me,
because I don't mind
because this little quirk of nature
leaves a big mark on me.
The song is very reckless. Aren't you afraid at all?
- You remember Johann Krause, Five-Mark-Johann? - Yes, why?
He is the great love of my life.
Augenblick!
They promised me that Johann would come out early.
- I'm sorry. - Stay seated, Prosecutor.
Yes, yes, love is our downfall, isn't it?
This one is also very beautiful.
Yes, hm, hm
Our little secret doesn't have to cost you your job or your family.
I can keep a lot to myself. Incognito
- What do you want? - Is Bauer behind the Eichmann kidnapping?
I don't know what you're talking about.
Good. You can keep the prints. Perhaps your wife would like to see them before
No, no, wait!
I'll give you a week.
Either you accuse Bauer of treason because he, as a German official, collaborated with a foreign intelligence service
or you go to jail.
- Dr. Bauer, what do you say about the Eichmann kidnapping? - We should have succeeded!
Yes. That would have been a great success.
Herein.
- Dr. Bauer, you wanted to speak to me? - Yes, come.
Everything OK?
I haven't seen you all week.
- I had personal obligations. - Aha.
I would like you to accompany me to the Prime Minister.
Zinn negotiated with the German government about Eichmann’s extradition.
Fritz.
- Where has Rosa Luxemburg gone? - You notice everything, too.
This is prosecutor Angermann.
- Very pleased. - Mr. Prime Minister.
- You're welcome. - Thank you.
Congratulations, Fritz. And to you too, Mr. Angermann.
- The other prosecutors must be impressed. - Yes, by the Mossad.
And that’s how it should stay.
Of course, I understand.
- Can I offer you something to drink? Today is a reason to celebrate, isn't it? - No, thanks.
What did the government decide?
Please.
I'm sorry, but the Federal Government will not request extradition.
- Eichmann goes on trial in Israel - Wait a minute.
The Israelis promised me. Chaim Cohn supports the extradition request.
Cohn is just a lawyer, Fritz.
- There's more to this. - Indeed.
Don't you know why Ben-Gurion and Adenauer met in New York?
Israel wants to buy German weapons; they discussed this in New York.
Germany will only supply weapons if Eichmann goes on trial in Jerusalem.
They are very nervous in Bonn, especially Mr. Globke, of course.
Nobody is interested in a crisis in the federal government except the Soviets.
That is why the US will do everything to protect Adenauer’s government.
And the Israelis need German weapons.
Here...
The rejection from the Ministry of Justice.
I told you, George.
If I don't get Eichmann, I won't have the strength to go on.
But you got him, you brought Eichmann down. That's your success.
No! It's Israel's success.
It would have been mine if Eichmann had been tried in a German court
all the Nazis who today lead this republic as war profiteers.
Other opportunities will come.
But not for me anymore.
Where should we go, Dr. Bauer?
Dr. Bauer?
What do you want to do now, Fritz?
What do you want to do?
I think I will resign from office.
You must not do that. You must not do that.
Vogel and Kügler are onto something here.
Have you heard of the Breslau Documents?
These are reports from camp commandant Höss from Auschwitz.
In it he lists SS men and their victims.
Concrete actions, confirmed by the camp commandant, you understand?
We could bring Auschwitz to justice. A cross-section of the entire camp.
But
But I don't believe in it anymore.
They always find a way to stop us.
Stop. Stop!
- Are you getting off here? - Yes. I have to.
I have to get out now.
Don't give up, Fritz. Please.
Karl!
Come along with me.
Herein.
- Chief Public Prosecutor Kreidler. - Should appear.
- Dr. Bauer, you wanted to speak to me? - Yes.
Are you taking over the Angermann case personally?
Secure.
That has to be done.
A prosecutor who goes against our system like this deserves to be treated fairly, don't you think?
Is this a problem for you?
I hear you were very close?
You should note
that he personally reported his indecency with this boy.
Yes, of couse.
He's the sweetheart of your young guard, isn't he?
Are you biased in this affair?
No, Kreidler. Do your job.
Yes.
But be sure:
I will do mine.
As long as I live,
Nobody can stop me from doing that anymore.