Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
Calm down, your escort is right
outside. Sit down.
Sit. I said sit.
She tells us that you are
her niece.
Is that correct? Are you her niece?
Where is your mother?
Do you know?
Look at me!
Do you understand me?
If you are from Budapest,
state the name and street number
of your former place of residence.
There's a pen and paper.
If you prefer not to speak to us,
write it down with your family name,
and we will try and confirm it.
Is it possible the woman outside
is not related to you,
but is simply an ally you made
along the way who is trying to help you?
You bear little resemblance
to one another.
We will not punish her for trying
to help an innocent young woman.
We want to help you get home.
Your true home.
László, I am alive.
Come on! Documents.
Attila tells me that you, too, are alive
and en route to him from Bremerhaven.
Rejoice!
I cried out in ecstasy
to have news of you.
Where are my things?
- What?
- Screw you!
It is not amusing to me!
Stop it! Don't look at me that way,
old man!
- It's right behind you.
- Where is my luggage?
It's tucked there under the mattress!
Now come on!
Hurry, László,
or we'll be last in the queue.
Zsófia is with me, though she is
frail, strange, and quite ill.
We anxiously await
our being repatriated,
but recently, she has not been herself,
which has, in turn, roused unnecessary
suspicions with local officials.
Fortunately, a few Soviet boys
have taken a liking to us.
They pity your poor niece in particular,
who has grown fuller, even lovelier,
since you last set eyes on her.
These lonesome young servicemen
are ostensibly entranced
by such a radiant creature's
commitment to absolute silence.
Excuse me, sorry.
The Soviets have helped us
relocate
to a nearby shelter
for displaced persons in Vas.
They encourage us
to "enjoy our freedoms",
but I am reminded of Goethe.
"None are more hopelessly enslaved
than those
who falsely believe themselves free!"
I make no mistake,
we are not yet free.
Come on already.
You, like myself, must be
envisioning so many terribly awful, awful things,
but it is better that your thoughts
do not get the best of you.
It is neither better nor worse
than you might imagine.
I have kept myself mostly to myself.
More importantly,
I have defended Zsófia
from unwanted advances.
Below is the address
I am told for mail in Vas.
Please write to me at once
when you have received this.
I am certain now
there is nothing left for us here.
Look at that!
- What did I tell you?!
- Yes!
Go to America and I will follow you.
Faithfully, Erzsébet.
For those of you
that don't speak English,
please engage myself
or any of my colleagues
located in the back
so we may inform you
about our language
and orientation programmes,
which are held
in this very room,
425 Lafayette.
Remember that address.
Additionally, classes
and daily meetings are held
where many of you
will be sleeping tonight
over at the Hotel Marseilles,
located on 103rd and Broadway.
Those of you for whom none of
the aforementioned details apply
and who will be immediately
departing for other destinations
in the morning, please see me
about your $25 travel aid.
These vouchers
are redeemable on trains
and participating bus services.
This is Albert B Chandler.
At this time, I would like
to introduce a boy
who will be under
the leadership of Babe Ruth
when Babe takes over his new
job as director of baseball
for the American Legion.
Representing the boys
of the American Legion,
speaking
for every American boy,
ladies and gentlemen,
here is Larry...
It has been some time, sorry.
What's wrong?
- Don't you think I'm beautiful?
- I do.
Which parts of me
do you find most beautiful?
All parts.
Stop it.
I don't find all the parts
of you beautiful.
Fuck her already!
Shut up.
Fuck her.
Can you tell your friend
to be polite?
Shut your mouth!
My legs? Are they too thin?
No.
You are well proportioned.
It is the space above your brow
for me which is the problem.
What did you say?
That is something I do not like.
Your face is ugly.
I know it is.
We have boys, if you prefer.
No, thank you.
Brothers with dark skin,
but handsome.
No, no. Not for me.
- Wait!
Wait! Wait!
- Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
- Hey, thank you. Thank you.
- Thanks.
It was great. It was great.
I'll see you.
- I will see you.
- Great. Wait, wait.
- For the luck. For the luck.
- Thanks.
- Bye, friend.
See you.
Bye.
Take care.
See you.
Perhaps no state or nation
in all the history of man
has been the deciding ground
of so many human issues
as has the state
of Pennsylvania.
Decisions that founded
and assured survival
of a great nation,
that brought into being
important
colonisation movements,
that established freedom
of worship in America,
that founded great religions,
that gave birth to America's
educational system,
that launched
tremendous industrial empires,
that forged the steel sinews
and powered the driving wheels
of today's great civilisation.
Here is where things happen,
where decisions are made,
where industry is making
the greatest strides
of any state or nation
in the world.
Pennsylvania.
Land of decision for America,
for American industry,
and for American families.
Attila.
Cousin.
Erzsébet is alive.
What? What?
What did you say?
I have a letter from her.
Your Erzsébet is alive
and she is with little Zsófia.
Yes?
Thank you. Thank you.
It's a combination of things,
but I would say the most popular
is the cabinetry
which we do ourselves,
custom-to-order.
The lamps, too.
And here it is.
Audrey did the displays.
He's talking like an American
from the television now.
Yes, well,
we don't have a television,
but he's been here
since before I was born,
and still doesn't sound like
any American I've ever met.
Eight years ago,
we tried opening something
similar in Manhattan.
We lasted two months.
We couldn't compete
with the name brands.
Newlyweds,
they come in with a...
an issue
of Better Homes and Gardens
and they say,
"We like that table
next to the perfume ad."
And we say, "Well, we can
make you something like that."
And they say,
"No, sir, we want exactly that."
Yeah. Turns out
we don't like New York at all.
No charm, right, Audrey?
Every little urchin
you come across,
and seller, buyer, delivery boy,
is running a hustle.
I'm from Connecticut myself.
Do you know it?
Of course he doesn't know it,
Audrey. He just got here.
Give me that.
So...
Cleared out a space for you
in the back.
Audrey made you a bed.
It's just there.
A cot and a lamp for now, but...
feel free to take anything
you want from the showroom.
That's all I need.
And for the employee restroom,
you go out the front door,
around the back to where
I parked the car, you remember?
There's a stairway there that
takes you up to our apartment.
If you need anything,
you just knock.
You and your wife
have done more than enough.
You know, we know someone
who could take a look
at your nose.
I thought maybe
no one would notice.
What happened?
If you don't mind my asking.
I jumped from a railcar.
A few moments later, there was
a loud cracking sound and...
I thought someone
had shot me in the head,
but I'd merely run
into the branch of a tree.
No one was shooting at me.
I take something for the pain
but...
I'd like to have it looked at.
Thank you.
We'll give Kenneth a call.
Come. Take a seat at my desk.
I'll fetch some towels.
Is it smaller than you expected?
What?
Oh, the shop.
No.
No, I had no expectation.
Who is Miller?
I'm Miller.
No, you are Molnár.
Not anymore.
- No Miller, no sons.
- Yeah.
The folks here,
they like a family business.
So what do you think?
Of what? The furniture?
No, well, I meant
of everything so far.
Philadelphia.
But, sure,
the pieces on the floor also.
They're not very beautiful.
Well, that's what
you are here for.
Maestro.
Next month,
I can put you on the payroll.
If you want, you can eat with us
upstairs on Sundays.
You have done more than enough.
- Don't mention it.
- I do mention it.
I do mention.
Thank you.
Gentile?
She's Catholic.
We are Catholic.
László, I am alive.
Attila tells me that you, too, are alive
and en route to him from Bremerhaven.
Rejoice!
I cried out in ecstasy
to have news of you...
We welcome donations.
Please help the homeless.
Help the homeless.
Your donations help to provide
shelter, food, clothing...
Please help the homeless.
Help the homeless.
It's your turn now,
William.
Please help the homeless.
I spy with my eye
something blue.
Is it this gentleman's coat?
He's clever.
You're right.
There is a little blue in it.
Listen up!
Kitchen's closed, folks.
Get back early tomorrow.
Wait! Hold on.
I got a kid here.
Sorry, we're fresh out.
Come find me in the morning.
I'll make sure he gets a plate.
You must have a slice of bread.
He's just a little boy.
There are children here.
How many times
do you people want me to say it?
There's nothing left here.
Thank you, sir.
Will he be all right?
There's somewhere else
we can try tonight.
Then let him sleep tomorrow.
I will be here early.
Come to me here.
I will hold a place.
Good night.
No one deserves
to be on our streets.
I don't deserve
to be on our streets again.
Whatever you can spare
from your hearts.
Thank you for listening.
God bless all of you.
Have a pleasant weekend.
Pardon.
- Rabbi Zunz?
- Yes.
Good morning.
My niece and wife...
I have learned the two are stuck
at the Austrian boundary.
Wait not many minutes for me
and we can speak after.
Mikveh Israel can try and help,
but from here, it is very
difficult, as you know.
I will wait for you. Thank you.
- Thank you very much.
- Wait.
On the 29th of November, 1947,
the United Nations General Assembly
passed a resolution
calling for the establishment
of a Jewish state in Eretz Yisrael.
The General Assembly required
the inhabitants of Eretz Yisrael
to take such steps
as were necessary on their part
for the implementation
of that resolution.
This recognition by the United Nations
of the right of the Jewish people
to establish their state is irrevocable.
This right is the natural right
of the Jewish people
to be masters of their own fate,
like all other nations,
in their own sovereign state.
Accordingly we,
members of the people's council,
representatives of the Jewish
community of Eretz Yisrael
and of the Zionist Movement,
are here assembled
on the day of the termination
of the British mandate
over Eretz Yisrael.
And by virtue of our natural
and historic right,
and on the basis of the resolution
of the United Nations General Assembly,
hereby declare the establishment
of a Jewish state in Eretz Yisrael,
to be known as the State of Israel.
I'm not sure what to do
with them, is all.
What do you think
I should pair it with?
Leave it.
How?
Leave it like that.
Looks like a tricycle.
What is that?
It's a bike for kids.
Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers.
Did Peter Piper pick
a peck of pickled peppers?
If Peter Piper picked
a peck of pickled peppers,
where is the peck of pickled
peppers Peter Piper picked?
Hey. Come with me.
We have an important client
inside.
I furnished him a two-storey
office space downtown
on the cheap last year.
He's interested in us doing
some built-in work for him
at a residence.
Can you give a little smile
for him? Huh? Sell it?
Why are you always
such a businessman?
You are selling,
always selling, selling.
Mr Van Buren.
Let me introduce you
to my cousin László.
Please. That's what people
call my father.
Call me Harry.
Well, Harry would like
some shelving units installed
over at his family's property
in Doylestown.
Sorry to interrupt.
I hoped that someone
might follow me out there
to take a look
at my father's study.
My sister and I would like
to surprise him, you see,
by turning it into
a proper library.
How do you mean?
Well, the place
is in complete disarray.
A whole mess
of books and paperwork.
So I guess we'd just like
some tall shelves
and cabinetry installed.
Maybe make him a ladder
with little wheels on it.
You know? Like you'd see
in a real library.
He's a voracious reader.
Yeah, we can make you
something like that.
Let me have Audrey come down
and keep an eye on the place
and I'll pull the van around.
- Fantastic.
- I'll be right back.
They pay you well?
On the last job,
they paid OK.
Took on a lot of pieces, though.
They kept adding to the order.
Even at a discount, it adds up.
His old man got flush
adapting production techniques
to expedite the manufacturing
of cargo ships during the war.
Christ, is this guy
trying to shake us?
Thinks it's a drag race?
Hey, come on, already!
Stay right until you see
the main house.
You can park wherever you like.
I do appreciate
you coming out here
on such short notice, gentlemen.
Father is away
only until next Friday.
I was anxious to pin this down.
Ah, it's no
inconvenience for us, chief.
It's your lucky day, too,
'cause my cousin here
is a licensed architect,
a specialist in renovations.
He even designed a library
back at home before.
Right? A whole city library.
What city is that?
- Budapest.
- I see. Never been.
Don't mind the mess.
I know.
It's terribly dated, isn't it?
I'm thinking shelves
up to the ceiling
and some good reading lamps.
Perhaps some wall fixtures
that extend.
Father always keeps
the curtains drawn.
This to protect the books
from the sunlight.
We are south-facing here.
Sure.
- What's your budget?
- What's your estimate?
Depends on the materials.
Well, make it
of reasonable quality.
Perhaps a nice place
for him to sit and read as well?
A good chair or a bench for him
against the window.
You want for us to replace that?
If there's time, why not?
A branch fell on it during
a nasty storm last summer.
Tropical depression,
I think they called it.
Keep it below $1,000, can you?
My sister and I
are splitting it.
I don't want
any unexpected add-ons.
Don't worry.
We'll come in on budget.
You want all this done
by next Friday, right?
Thursday night, preferably.
I can't be here during the week,
but the staff can let you in.
If anything comes up,
have them ring me at the office.
If it's to be finished
on Thursday,
we need extra hands.
Including materials, glass...
It's $2,000.
♪ East is east and west is west ♪
♪ And the wrong one
I have chose ♪
♪ Let's go where
I'll keep on wearin' ♪
♪ Those frills and flowers
and buttons and bows ♪
♪ Rings and things
♪ Don't bury me in this prairie ♪
♪ Take me where
the cement grows ♪
♪ Let's move down
to some big town ♪
♪ Where they love a gal
by the cut of her clothes ♪
♪ And I'll stand out
in buttons and bows ♪
♪ I'll love you in buckskin
and skirts that I've homespun ♪
♪ But I'll love you longer
stronger where ♪
♪ Your friends don't tote a gun ♪
♪ My bones denounce
the buckboard bounce ♪
♪ And the cactus hurts my toes ♪
- Flip it for the other side.
- ♪ Let's vamoose where gals... ♪♪
OK.
You should have seen him
talking up the prices.
I was ready to settle at 450.
- I was not doing that.
- You were.
I was not. I was telling him
how much it will cost.
No, I... I thought he was going
to blow it for us.
But you held your ground.
And that's what makes you
professional.
I hope it is not only that.
She's so beautiful.
Look at her.
She has that red dress
and it's the same as...
colour as her lips.
Dance with her.
- I don't want to dance.
- Go on.
- I don't... I don't...
- Come on.
I don't want to. No, thank you.
He doesn't want to.
Don't make her...
Don't make her wait.
Dance with her.
It's her favourite song.
We'll do it together,
I'll show you the steps.
Dance with her.
Dance with her, dance with her.
She wants you to.
- It's her favourite song.
- Attila.
It's her favourite song.
Go on. Dance with her. Don't...
She's waiting for you.
- She's waiting for you.
- OK, OK, I'll dance.
All right.
- Don't.
- Yeah!
- Idiot.
- Go on!
Get off.
♪ Someone kind ♪
♪ Who knows you treasure
any simple little pleasure ♪
♪ Like a full-length mink
to cover last year's blouse ♪
♪ It's so nice ♪
♪ To have a man
around the house... ♪
You're awfully skinny,
aren't you?
♪ It's so nice to have
a man around the house ♪
♪ Oh so nice to have
♪ Just a guy... ♪♪
You see?
Like riding a bicycle.
Tricycle.
Family.
A bike for children.
Children!
You missed the toilet.
What?
Better than the carpet,
I suppose.
When do you expect your wife
might join you, Mr Tóth?
There's not room for the both
of you in that storage space.
I wish I knew, Audrey.
Thank you for the dinner.
Attila showed me
magazine pictures.
The projects you did
at your firm.
You're not what I expected
from what I read about you.
I'm not what I expected either.
You know,
I'm sure you could get a job.
A better job.
At a firm here.
I then...
would be working for someone.
It's better than sleeping
in a storage closet.
I'll look for somewhere else
to stay.
Thank you again for the dinner.
Bring the boxes.
Don't drop them.
Here, here, here.
The guy is rich,
he's gonna buy more books.
You be respectful.
The guy likes to read.
He can tell us a bedtime story.
OK.
Slowly, slowly. Slowly.
Slowly.
Don't scratch the floor.
Yes, the long panels.
The shelves can vary in height
to accommodate
the larger volumes
our client had been stacking
on the floor.
So, 45 degrees.
Three, two, one.
Perfect. It will be beautiful.
That's it.
That's good, that's good.
Left, Gordon, left. And steady.
Careful now, left.
One steady movement.
Come on, one steady movement.
Slowly.
Slowly, slowly, slowly.
It's too close to the roof!
Hey, hey, hey, hey!
Oh, no!
- I told you to pull!
- I did what I could.
We have a piece of guttering
to replace now as well.
One, two, three.
Yeah.
OK.
Put it... bring your hand...
It's good. It's good, it's good.
Dance with me.
Dance with me again.
Attila.
Come. Come.
It's a first edition.
They're all first edition.
You're an idiot.
Stop it. Idiot.
What is this?
What is all this?
Who authorised you to come
into my home
and tear everything apart?
- Excuse me. Excuse me, sir.
- Who the hell are you?
This was all
supposed to be a surprise.
Your son Harry told us
not to expect you...
It is a goddamn surprise!
My mother, an ailing woman,
is sitting outside
on the driveway
too frightened to come inside.
We're sorry
to have frightened her.
We brought her here
for some peace and respite,
only to discover a strange Negro
man roaming around our property.
Your son...
asked us to come here
to redo the study
into a library.
A library?
The room...
it's gutted!
Well, we were just putting
everything back in its place.
You've turned it all inside out.
How do you know
its proper place?
We have taken excellent care
of your belongings,
Mr Van Buren.
I...
I don't know what to tell you.
Who are you?
László Tóth.
László's a licensed architect.
He supervised the renovation
and I've done business
with your son before.
I have a furniture shop
down in Kensington.
Miller and Sons.
Mr Van Buren, may I show you
around the space?
The... the work lamps are not
doing the work any justice.
Your Negro man is waiting
for you outside the gate.
I suggest you pack your things
and leave.
Mr Van Buren...
we are finished here.
It's quite all right. Come.
I will confirm this with my son
in the morning.
My mother is sick.
She needs to be inside
so she can sleep!
It's quite all right?!
This is not all right,
this is my home!
Goddamn you!
Wake up.
That's a hell of a way
to greet the day.
What is it?
Harry Lee called.
He says he won't pay.
For... for the materials?
He says we damaged the property
and I'm lucky if he doesn't
take me to court.
Got nothing to say to that?
What are you going
to do about it?
László...
I take you into my home,
into my place of business,
and this is how you thank me?
You run my clients out the door.
You make a pass at my wife.
She told me.
Of course she told me.
What do you expect?
Well, what did I expect?
You couldn't keep your hands to
yourself even when we were kids.
Listen.
I won't tell Erzsi this time.
I know
you've been through a lot.
That's what I told Audrey too.
I'm not going to hurt you.
But I can't help you anymore
either.
You got that?
Erzsébet,
I can be reached by mail
at a new address...
I wait for you. I wait and wait.
Do you need money?
What do you need?
Yours, László.
Good morning, Philadelphia.
It is Thursday
November 7th, 1950.
This could be the first time
since 1930
that the Republican Party
may seize control...
Gordon.
US and United Nations forces
have made significant advances
on the Korean peninsula...
Wake up. Gordon.
Come on.
Wake up.
We gotta go. I let you sleep in.
Time to get up.
Oh. Gordon.
Has Mr László already gone?
I need to speak with him.
Hold on.
Hey, there.
László?
It is for my injury.
Sister Elizabeth
is asking for you.
I will be right there.
Do me a favour and hold off on
that until we punch the clock.
What did she want
to talk to you about?
She asked for my
participation.
Like what?
They want you to help out?
I already help out.
She wants me to attend
the service on Sundays
and collect donations.
And what did you say to her?
I said I would think about it.
That seems fair, no?
I go to somewhere else.
Why don't you ask
for a place to stay,
wherever it is that you do go?
I do not permit my people from
home to see me as a beggar.
Never.
♪ A rose must remain
♪ With the sun and the rain
♪ Or its lovely promise
won't come true
♪ To each his own
♪ And my own is you
♪ What good is a song
♪ If the words don't belong?
♪ And a dream
must be a dream for two
♪ No good alone
♪ To each his own
♪ For me, there's you
♪ If a flame is to grow
♪ There must be a glow
♪ To open each door,
there's a key
There's a son
of a bitch here to see you.
László Tóth, is that you?
I've been looking for you.
No wonder I couldn't find you,
you've grown a beard.
What can I do for you, sir?
I would like to take you
to lunch.
We do not break
for another two hours.
Point out your manager.
Let me educate him.
Have you seen that?
I can assure you
everyone else has.
Flip to page 66.
Where did you study?
Bauhaus in Dessau.
Bauhaus? How marvellous.
Uh, read the caption
below the photograph.
So what do you think?
Looks good.
Damn right it does.
Why didn't you defend yourself
when I came after you all
like a bat out of hell?
I called that American cousin
of yours, um...
- Attila.
- Yes. Yeah, that's right.
First, I apologised,
then I lauded him with praise.
However, he, quite honourably,
redirected me to you.
And I have since
done my homework.
These are yours, yes?
Yes.
All of them?
I'm sorry.
Have... have I upset you?
No.
Not at all.
I did not realise these images
were still available.
Much less of any consequence.
May I keep these?
Of course you may.
They're very artistic.
They're better in real life.
You could've elaborated a little
more on your background.
You didn't...
You didn't do yourself
any favours back there.
It was difficult to interject
amidst all of the shouting.
Yeah.
Yeah, I... I'm ashamed.
Really, I am, I...
I acted a fool.
My...
My mother was dying.
It's not an excuse, but she died
that very weekend at the house.
I'm very sorry
to hear about your mother.
Tell me, why is an accomplished
foreign architect
shovelling coal
here in Philadelphia?
Well, I'm also
doing the construction
for a bowling alley.
But, um...
The Reich rejected myself
and my colleagues
for our type of work.
For it was deemed
not Germanic in character.
Uh, I don't wish to be rude,
but I only have time
for the coffee.
You were not prepared
for what you saw.
That is understandable.
I'm glad
you have come to appreciate it.
I don't just appreciate it,
Mr Tóth. I cherish it.
I hate surprises.
My fat-headed son
should have known better.
But listen, I'm not here
to boast or to grieve.
I've come to pay you the monies
you're owed.
For what it's worth,
it was not my suggestion
you and your partner
should not be paid.
I only found out about that
after the fact.
We damaged some guttering
which we intended to replace,
but it was a misunderstanding.
Forget it. Take the money.
Thank you.
I'd stash that in your
undergarments, if I were you,
or inside of a shoe.
I would like you to come
and see it in the daylight.
I've already seen it.
I'd like you to come
and enjoy it, rather.
- All right.
- Wonderful.
I can have a car come
and pick you up Sunday morning
if you're...
if you're not too busy.
No.
Here.
Write me down your address.
I've found our conversation
persuasive
and intellectually stimulating.
Bye.
It was a pleasure.
Hey, hey, don't move too much.
Going to be some minutes!
One second. Hold this.
Yes, he's inside.
Everybody left.
It's time to go. We're closed.
Don't push!
I know he is in there.
Ain't nobody in there.
My friend would not leave me!
Please.
Ain't nobody in there!
It's time to go.
- No! No.
- We're closed.
Now go on home.
Listen, my friend is in there,
please!
- Oh! My nose!
- I said go home.
Hey, mister, the picture's
over. You can't sleep here.
This demand is for
these derivatives of opium,
- the narcotic drugs...
..useful in medicine
to relieve pain
and to induce sleep.
Used without supervision,
they can become dangerous,
habit-forming drugs.
Once the habit is formed,
the addict...
What? What?
.. must have a continual
supply at all costs.
Lawfully imported drugs
are not available to him.
He must turn
to an illegal source.
Come.
Come with me.
Good kitty. Come with me.
- Just come.
- Excuse me, Mr Tóth.
The Van Buren family
sent me for you.
On the seat there beside you,
there's a pressed dinner jacket.
There you are!
Man of the hour.
What have you done to yourself?
Fell off a beam and...
- Everyone's famished.
- Harry, you remember each other.
Yes, I do. Afternoon.
Daddy, the kitchen's asking if
we could please take our seats.
And this is Harry's twin sister,
Maggie.
Hello, Mr Tóth.
We love the library.
Thank you.
All right, let's eat.
He won't tout
his own accomplishments, but...
Mr Tóth's work is celebrated
throughout much of Western
and Central Europe.
There are many features on him
in architectural journals,
if you follow
that sort of thing.
What was your focus?
Uh, theatres, synagogues,
restorations.
Many projects
but some quite unusual.
Are you married, Mr Tóth?
Yes.
She's still in Europe.
Why's that?
We were separated.
Forcibly.
Where is it you come from,
if you don't mind my asking?
I... I can't place the accent.
The city of Budapest.
Ravaged during the war.
Just terrible.
What was it like, the war?
We hear some stories here
that make one's toes curl.
I would not know where to begin,
Mrs Hoffman.
Do you plan on
returning to Europe, Mr Tóth?
But my wife, she tries to come
now, here, to join me.
But the situation is difficult.
Well, with Roosevelt gone now,
that should make things easier.
He is gone,
but everyone is still frightened
that people like me are a threat
to their national defence.
When you say "people",
you mean Jews?
We're Jewish.
Michelle converted.
As did my Erzsébet.
It required a great
deal of commitment and study,
but...
..few at home
recognised her for it.
A pity the National Socialists
could not see it their way.
But no, not only Jewish.
Foreign people.
I was fortunate to depart
from Bremerhaven when I did.
Truman's order facilitated
the transfer of my group.
Others were not so lucky.
That sounds
very painful, László.
We're terribly sorry for you.
Michael is my friend
and my attorney, in that order.
Michael, is this a process your
firm could help to expedite?
It is not so simple, I'm afraid.
My wife cannot leave my niece
behind because she is...
young, motherless,
and is very sick.
It's just the two of 'em?
I'd be glad to make an enquiry
on your behalf.
There's something called
the Displaced Persons Act
that's recently
gone into effect.
It will allow some
200,000 European persons
admission
for permanent residence.
You can read about it
in the paper now.
Michael's firm represents the
office of the Vice President.
The President?
Of the United States.
Congratulations.
Come see me in our
Philadelphia office on Monday.
Telephone this line,
and my assistant can arrange.
She'll tell you what
we'll need you both to provide.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
I think we'll take
coffee in the study, huh?
Thank you.
I was married once.
She gave me
two beautiful children.
Nevertheless, my mother
Margaret, and the twins
demanded my attention
every minute
of my scarce personal time.
Things became awkward
between my ex-wife and Margaret
so we separated.
Amicably.
Margaret raised me on her own
in Rochester.
It was just the two of us.
Her parents had disowned her
for a child out of wedlock.
She was my only real family,
other than the twins
later on in life, of course.
I tell you,
shortly before their death,
my mother's parents,
I hesitate to call them
my grandparents,
they reached out to Margaret
and me after reading an article
on the reported success
of my first company.
In actual fact,
we weren't doing that well
at the time
and would soon
shutter our doors,
but this was not yet
public knowledge.
I gather you conclude from our
prior interactions I am blunt,
not hyperbolic
or particularly sentimental.
But my mother...
she was defenceless
against their chumminess.
She argued that they could
very well be sick or dying
and... quite likely
needed the money.
I didn't like seeing Margaret,
an ordinarily pragmatic woman,
reduced to such
bromidic assumptions.
Still, I agreed
to meet with them in person,
in part to appease her,
but also to satisfy
the curiosities of my lineage.
Do you know,
it really is very clever.
The way the space surrounds one,
the forced perspective.
I think so, yes.
It reminds me
of a short story I once read.
It's about
a never-ending library.
Are you working on anything
at the moment, Mr Tóth?
A bowling alley.
Pardon me,
I was just in the middle
of telling our friend here
a story.
I'm so sorry. Not at all.
Please excuse me.
You agreed to see them.
We exchanged
pleasantries over the telephone
and I offered to meet with them
at their modest
apartment residence
in a neighbouring town.
I laughed to realise they'd been
so nearby all those years.
On the drive over...
I had time to think.
And I finally arrived
at a figure
I felt comfortable
in offering the two of them,
seeing that they were,
whether I liked it or not,
our only living relatives.
I was received hospitably,
so I swiftly moved to explain
I'd made them out a cheque
for the amount of $25,000.
When I handed it over,
they appeared relieved,
but perhaps a little
disappointed at the figure.
They were courteous
and thanked me all the same.
I was quite uncomfortable.
But before hurrying off,
I asked them a question.
What will you do
with all this money?
They rambled on about miracles
or some such thing.
For a moment, everything
in their immediate line of view
seemed solvable, achievable.
They would finally be all right
and what a thoughtful grandson
I was.
Upon departure,
before I even reached
the edge of their front lawn,
the two of them came
running out after me, shouting.
"You've forgotten
your signature, Harrison."
I summoned the courage
to be frank
and to speak to them as adults.
I had not forgotten, I said,
but was not ultimately compelled
to sign
due to the blunder
of their response.
They took it as such a shock.
I thought for a moment
it might kill them
right there on the front lawn.
But the two of them just wept
and came apart like beggars.
The whole thing was so much more
disturbing than I'd imagined.
And so on condition
that they let Margaret alone
from then on,
I struck them a separate cheque
for $500 and I signed.
That is how much
I loved my mother, Mr Tóth.
We did things for each other.
What could they expect
after the way
they had treated you both?
Yes, yes,
that's exactly how I see it.
Answer me something.
Why architecture?
Is it a test?
No, it is not.
Nothing
is of its own explanation.
Is there a better description
of a cube
than that of its construction?
There was a war on.
And yet
it is my understanding that...
many of the sites of my projects
have survived.
They remain there
still in the city.
When the terrible recollections
of what happened in Europe
cease to humiliate us,
I expect for them to serve
instead as a political stimulus,
sparking the upheavals
that so frequently occur
in the cycles of peoplehood.
I already anticipate a communal
rhetoric of anger and fear.
A whole river of such
frivolities may flow undammed.
But my buildings were devised
to endure such erosion
of the Danube's shoreline.
What a poetic reply.
You must have been
a beloved professor.
I've said it before,
but I find our conversations...
intellectually stimulating.
I agree with you.
Everyone, please.
Take your brandy
and join me outside.
I have a terrific surprise.
Where the hell
are you taking us, Harrison?
It's freezing out here.
Try doing this
in heels, Michael.
Only a little further. Come on.
Bear with us, everyone.
Hold your horses,
we're almost there.
All right.
As many of you know,
this past year
has been somewhat difficult
for Harry, Maggie and myself.
Daddy, it's very cold out here.
Shall we go back inside?
Maggie, please. Quiet.
I've brought you all out here
this evening in the cold
not to glance over my shoulder
at the past,
but to join me in looking
forward toward the future.
As you know,
over this rise is Doylestown.
And so on this site, we plan to
build a centre for the community
in the name
of Margaret Lee Van Buren.
Harrison, that's lovely.
This shall be
a sacred enough space
that perhaps her soul
might inhabit it.
A place for gathering,
reflecting, learning.
And, Mr Tóth, I would like you
to build this for her.
Something boundless,
something new.
This has shocked you, I see.
I'm delighted.
I thought perhaps
you might see it coming.
No. No.
Listen.
It is no coincidence
that fate brought us together
on the eve of my mother's death.
I'm good at reading the signs.
Sir, I do not know
what the commission entails.
We'll talk about the details
at home,
but you'll be well compensated.
And also, you'll be given
a place here on the property
to live and work.
I think that residing here
will allow you the time
and the space
to conceive of it properly.
And your family,
should they arrive,
they're welcome here too.
What do you say?
Well, I-I... uh...
I would like to draw something
and then present it to you.
You'd like to win
the commission.
All right, you can do that.
It's cold, let's return inside.
Come on.
Excuse me.
I am sorry, I am sorry.
A driver brought me here,
I don't recall his name.
- Sorry.
- No, I need to get back. I...
Could someone possibly
contact the man
who dropped me here
this afternoon?
One minute, please.
Mr Tóth. I'm sorry
to have kept you waiting.
Harrison's gone to bed.
He wishes you a good night.
Would you help me
to find the driver?
Listen, I'm terribly sorry
about my father's theatrics.
Must have caught you off guard.
It's quite all right.
He often makes these decisions
without consulting
the rest of us.
I did not take any of it
to heart.
Oh, you should.
You should, you see.
My father would like us
to hire you.
Oh.
Ah.
I don't have any infrastructure
here.
That's why he's asked me
to oversee and assist you
in this endeavour.
I have no idea
of the parameters.
Once I have distilled the
essence of Father's outburst,
I'll try and make
some economic sense of it.
We've quite a full house
this evening,
so I took the liberty
of making up a place for you
in the guest house.
We can have your things sent for
in the morning.
Mr Tóth?
One minute.
Sir?
You rang for me, sir?
Oh, yes, László, come in.
I've had a vision.
[♪ "Eine Kleine Nachtmusik IV" ♪
by Mozart)
I have some sketches.
I... Also something
I have been working on
which might be applicable here,
if you care to look.
In a moment, my eyes are bleary.
Sit down.
Pardon my appearance, I have...
I have carpenters
in the forehead
causing a terrible ringing
in my ears.
You'll have to bear with me.
I can come back.
Shh! Before I lose it.
Dreams slip away.
Yes, I know.
Doylestown, it's beautiful,
but it's not a cultural place,
you know?
- Sure.
- But it could be.
If there were an auditorium,
it could host a...
a theatre festival.
Sure.
And in the off season,
of course,
the local students
could access it.
Yes.
And what do you think
about a gymnasium?
I used to practise wrestling
when I was a teenager.
I have these fond memories
of my mother
accompanying me to matches
in the neighbouring towns.
Perhaps a swimming pool?
I can't swim.
And perhaps it is too expensive?
Don't talk to me about money.
Pennsylvania
has more owner-occupied homes
than any other state.
More small towns
and small cities,
and more people living in small
towns than any other state,
as well as some of the greatest
cities in the world.
All this is why Pennsylvania
is truly a land of decision
for families who want
a wonderful place
to live and work,
and to enjoy the richness
of leisure
with nearby secure employment.
Don't talk to him about money.
I've spoken to our friends at
the Bucks County mayor's office
who are warm to accessing local
and state funding opportunities
on behalf of our project,
if we are willing
to designate a specific...
and meaningful component
of the centre
for Christian congregation.
But it is a community centre
for all people.
What do they want,
a prayer room?
I'm under the impression
they're expecting something
more specific and meaningful
than that for their earmark.
This, and pending their approval
of the overall proposal,
of course.
Excuse me. An auditorium,
a gymnasium, a library.
Father described it more...
more as a reading room
for the public.
A library and a chapel?
That is four builds, Harry.
Four, not one.
It's ambitious.
And I thought you'd like that.
I put in a call to our frequent
contractor, Leslie Woodrow.
We first worked with Leslie
as one of our ship engineering
officers,
but he's supervised several
important construction projects
for us since,
including these offices.
My father is allocating a sum
of $850,000 to the project,
which, to me,
seems very reasonable,
if not exorbitant.
If Leslie agrees
to come on board,
then I'll have him start
a budget for us right away.
This allocation of 850,000
is inclusive of fees
for yourself and Leslie.
Also we've gone ahead
and made arrangements
to start securing you a licence
here in Pennsylvania.
Well, Harry,
let's start digging.
Erzsébet, I have become
acquainted with an influential American attorney
who says he can help you
and Zsófia with your situation.
Is there somewhere
we might find a photograph
of you and Zsófia pictured together?
Anything linking her to you?
I have reached out to colleagues
who sometimes attended parties
at the house.
I am waiting on return.
Whomever comes to mind, write to them
and explain how urgent this is.
Anything tying her to you,
and you to me,
can be of great assistance
to Mr Hoffman.
504, 505, 506,
507, 508.
I have enclosed a list of
items and information requested by his office.
Please fill out what you can
of these documents
and return these originals
to me at once.
Here: some good fortune
may have fallen upon me.
In an unexpected turn of events,
I have been offered an intriguing
opportunity, a second chance.
...three, four,
five, six, seven.
I can feel you nearer to me
now than ever before.
Your love, László.
Level, level.
Higher, higher.
Little higher. Good.
Good, good, good.
The total area
is 2,684 square metres
including a sizeable condensate
system for harvesting rainwater,
below grade.
Narrow openings
you see here and here,
they are skylights that can also
be viewed as demarcations
of units of space on either side
of the entrance hall.
These units are convertible,
multifunctional.
They offer a total occupancy
of 500 persons on each side.
Bespoke systems
for seating and storage
allow for a conference,
gymnasium, auditorium.
These rooms of a more standard
size are pre-cast concrete.
The chapel at the heart
of the building
contrasted by an altarpiece
of marble
from the mountains of Carrara...
I can't see.
..will serve as the institute's
centrepiece.
Harry, what do you
think about the gymnasium
being off to the side like that?
I'm not sure.
I think it looks like
a barracks.
Well, that's perhaps because
you never enlisted, Harry.
I think it's all
a great surprise. Keep going.
Let me demonstrate.
When the sun travels
from east to west,
wooden beams located
at the base of the towers
will unite to form the symbol
of a cross upon the altarpiece,
when they are illuminated.
Extraordinary.
How wonderful.
Maggie, will you call
for some coffee?
I think it's beautiful, Mr Tóth.
Thank you.
Well, what's the height
of those things?
Six or seven metres also?
And did I understand you
correctly,
over 800,000 square feet
of surface area?
Well, if we can afford these
materials at all, Mr Van Buren.
Sylacauga marble
ships out of Talladega County,
and that might be possible
if I manage to swing
a few favours.
With all due respect,
afford the materials?
Sir, concrete
is sturdy and cheap.
Concrete?
It's not very attractive.
Perhaps we could split
the difference on materials.
Fortunately,
the building's aesthetic
is not yours to resolve,
Mr Woodrow.
And Sylacauga marble is white,
like a sheet of paper.
What I have here is blue
and grey with a softer veining.
I prefer the Italian.
It's more suitable.
Well, I'll have to do
some research but...
I know someone talented.
An Italian mason whom I have
commissioned before.
Oh, another detail
before I forget. The name.
I want to make sure
it's visible, yeah.
Sir, is this really
what you imagined?
Am I missing something?
When Harry called,
he described this to me
as a personal project.
If this is what
we ultimately settle on,
something of this scale,
the timeline will need to be
considerably adjusted.
I'd rather be alive
at 18 percent
than dead at the prime rate,
Leslie.
We will not exceed
our allocations.
Your grandmother
loved marble.
I assure you.
Where are we at
with our discussions
with the mayor's office?
- They're waiting on us.
- Good.
Push them along.
- It's good.
- Thank you.
Shit.
M-Morning, Leslie.
Don't tell me
you're just now getting up.
Two minutes and I'm ready.
I'll give you three
if you use it to rinse off.
Three.
I'll wait outside.
Big day.
Big day. Wake up.
The mayor
hasn't got all day, Leslie.
We're fine, Harry.
Will your father be joining us
as well?
No, he's overseas
on business, I'm afraid.
He sends his regards.
This is a project
he's very passionate about.
It's a priority for us.
He asked if he could
telephone you tomorrow
to talk it all through.
At your convenience, of course.
Well, sure.
Sylvia in my office
can set for just about any time
tomorrow afternoon.
Apologies.
Well, this is, um...
different.
Very modern.
- Yes.
- All right.
Walk us through
what you have in mind.
The construction phase alone
will create upwards
of 80 local jobs.
Carpenters, painters,
upwards of 150 upon completion,
at which point the facility will
need to be permanently staffed.
When are you gonna answer
the questions in the box?
Right.
I would also like to address
some of the written concerns
and comments
submitted to us anonymously
ahead of tonight's discussion.
Questions probing
my personal background,
heritage and ideological
persuasion, if you will.
As a foreign person
and a newcomer to Doylestown,
I see a community in need.
And this is my only persuasion
of relevance.
Mr Van Buren, a generous patron
and practising Protestant,
and I will build a place
you will be drawn to congregate
and inspired to worship.
You may rest assured
that we will honour
the traditions of Doylestown.
The Margaret Lee Van Buren
Centre for Creation and Activity
will be its manifestation.
A landmark which proclaims
not only "I am new",
but "I am part
of the new whole".
Please to pass the, um...
How do you call it?
No, the torch.
Right.
Here we have
the chapel interior.
It is suitable for 119 persons.
At dawn.
At sunset.
- At noon.
- Oh, that's clever.
One of the most
basic commodities
of the world today,
and it had its humble
beginnings in a little town
nestled between the green hills
of Pennsylvania.
László!
It has taken some months to obtain
the items which Mr Hoffman requested
since receiving your letter.
Steel.
I was at a loss at first,
but suddenly thought to contact our
upstairs neighbour in Buda, Mrs Horváth!
Perhaps no one factor
has been of greater importance
in the forward march
of American progress
than Pennsylvania steel.
She was able to provide
me with several family photographs
that clearly picture you,
myself, and Zsófia
with her mother
on our wedding day.
Steel.
The poor dear thought us
dead all these years,
so had kept them
on her mantelpiece in memoriam.
Steel for great buildings.
Steel for bridges.
Steel for motor cars.
Zsófia could have only
been nine years of age at the time,
but her face and expression
are unmistakable.
Steel for trains
and for rails.
I have included all but
one
Steel for planes.
in case this letter
does not reach you.
I will keep it near my breast,
our family tree against my heart.
Steel for the guns of
war and the machinery of peace.
László,
does this mean
we might meet again soon?
Steel.
Yours, Erzsébet.
- Right or left?
- On the left.
Could they have walked past us?
My associate in New York
confirmed they made it on.
Is that them over there?
No, that is not them.
Zsófia?
Zsófia. That is... that is her.
Zsófia!
What's happened?
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
What happened?
It might not be permanent.
What happened? Did someone hurt you?
It's osteoporosis from the famine.
I'll dye my hair. I know it's ugly.
Where's Attila?
I did not want him
to be disappointed
if you were delayed
for any reason.
Zsófia, dear.
Zsófia.
Welcome to America.
How wonderful
to finally make
your acquaintance.
There was a period of time there
where we thought
he had made you up.
Isn't it fascinating,
meeting the significant others
of great artists and thinkers?
Thank you for taking care
of my László.
As persons
of unique privilege,
I've always thought
it's our duty
to nurture the defining talents
of our epoch.
I, of course,
am devoid of any such talent.
Truth be told, I...
I am incredibly emulous
of individuals like him.
That mustn't be true,
Mr Van Buren.
You have done very well
for yourself.
Father's digging
for compliments.
Don't indulge him.
- The property is beautiful.
- Isn't it?
Erzsébet...
Pardon me,
am I pronouncing that correctly?
That's fine, just fine.
Feel free to call me Elizabeth
if you prefer it.
And your English is impressive.
Thank you. I attended
university in England.
Oh. Where?
Oxford. To study English.
And I returned home
for communications.
And did you do anything
with that?
Yes. I worked for a
popular national paper at home,
Magyar Nemzet.
Huh.
A journalist. Hmm!
- Cultural?
- Foreign affairs.
Well, perhaps
you can help your husband
sound less like
he shines shoes for a wage.
Haven't you told them anything
about me?
László, how long have you been
here now? Four, five years?
You have no excuse anymore.
I'm sorry. I got
a little carried away there.
Will you please pass that back?
A penny saved.
Sofia, is that right?
Zsófia.
Does she understand English?
- Yes.
Yes. She understands very well.
The woman
behind the man.
László? May I have a word?
Yes, sir?
On Leslie's recommendation,
we've shown your plans
to another architect.
What? Who?
Just somebody we worked with
on the department store
downtown.
These are minor changes.
Places they thought
we might save a penny.
László?
- Leslie is a bastard.
- Yes, he is.
That's what we pay him for.
Ladies...
I'm sorry for the toys.
I remembered you as a little girl.
Look at your mother.
My sister was beautiful, wasn't she?
Even when she was ill,
she was so beautiful.
Are you angry?
Are you angry with me
for not telling you about my condition?
If you want to start a row
with me,
I might as well work out
my English.
Stop it. Your English
is perfectly all right.
It was an unimaginative joke
he told about you shining shoes.
Tomorrow,
I will take you to see someone.
A specialist.
Don't be angry with me.
Do you not want to be with me
anymore?
Stop this nonsense.
Do you think I look older?
We are older.
Can't you say
anything kind to me?
I love you, you cow.
You can touch me.
I don't want to...
I don't want to hurt you,
physically.
You won't.
I had dreams.
Every night,
I dreamt I was with you.
I know what you've done, László.
And it's all right.
What are you talking about?
I know.
- I can't do it.
- I know everything.
I don't want to do it right now.
You see...
I became sick.
Very sick.
I could hardly breathe.
I yearned to be with you
and it made me sick.
I nearly died.
Between life and death,
I began having fantasies
about you.
But I realised...
they were not fantasies at all,
but visions.
I was with you.
All the time, I was with you.
My László,
I know what you've done.
I'm not jealous because
I was with you all the time.
I know everything
that has happened to you.
And I am here now,
And I will never leave you.
Oh, God!
Oh, my God!
My love...
My love, I cannot bear it
anymore!
- I cannot bear it.
- You can.
You can.
We have a new life.
A new language.
We can start again.
Houp-la!
Pardon. Pardon.
Maggie Lee
lent me some hair colour.
That is wonderful, dear.
László, are you there?
Yes, my love.
The model is beautiful, darling.
So beautiful.
Thank you.
We're going into town
this afternoon to see Attila.
Would you like to come?
I have something
this afternoon.
I cannot.
I've missed him.
Just hearing him
mill about in the other room...
It's fantastic.
Perhaps we should
see about some language classes
this afternoon.
You could take the bus in
on your own.
I'm positive it is the last
place you would like to be,
but it will be good for you,
and I can brief the instructor
or whomever
about your situation.
Listening to me babble on
will only get you so far.
Where are you ladies off to?
We're going into town.
Which town?
We have several nearby.
Philadelphia. To visit family.
Ah, the American cousin,
of course.
- So the city, then?
- Yes, yes, the city.
Ah. Us as well.
Well, don't just stand there.
Let us give you
and your auntie a lift.
Thank you.
I have a friend
in New York, a newspaper man.
He's always on the lookout
for new talent.
Should I mention you to him?
It's very kind
of you, Mr Van Buren.
Would that mean I would
have to work out of New York?
Well, perhaps, in the beginning.
But you don't have the job yet,
so let's not get ahead
of ourselves.
Of course not.
I did not mean it
to be presumptuous.
No, no.
In any event,
you could always commute there
with me at the start.
I'm there Monday to Friday.
Yes, that could be fine.
I would have to speak
with László, though.
I can assure you,
when ground breaks,
he will have his hands full.
And besides, I enjoy showing
friends around Manhattan.
You can't have seen much of it
on your way here.
Penn Station Terminal
was very nice.
It is very nice.
It's a pity it's so full
of tramps these days
hassling women and children
with their arms outstretched.
They line up and extend
from the walls
as if integral
to its very foundation
like some haunted wall mural.
Perhaps that is why
I felt so at home.
I'm a former bag lady myself,
who does also enjoy the work
of the Dutch masters.
Earthly Delights.
You heard it just as I intended.
Very clever.
But "integral
to its foundation..."
A mural is decorative.
It has nothing to do
with the foundation.
Touché.
Where did you get your passion
for architecture?
Oh, we've done buildings before,
but I'd hardly
call them artistic.
I don't know. Perhaps it was
because my cellar was full.
Pardon?
I collect books,
butterflies and such,
but above all else,
Portuguese Madeira.
I take it every evening
after supper.
I've done the math,
and if I were to uncork a bottle
seven days a week
for the next 30 years,
the maximum
of my life's expectancy,
I would need no more
than 10,000 bottles, all told.
So once the cellar was full,
it was time to set about
in a new direction.
Out of the cellar
and into the sky.
If you were to drink a bottle
of Madeira every day,
I shouldn't think
you'd last 30 years.
I always keep good company.
That helps.
I wanna be honest and
I want you to be honest too,
then when we get married...
Whatever you need.
I'm very grateful.
Yep, thank you. Yep.
I'm gonna
have to call you back.
How dare you?
How dare I what?
You go behind their back!
You have the meeting
with another goddamn designer!
Who in the hell is James
T Simpson? Who is he?
You want to try
to get me sacked!
I didn't tell him to meet with
anyone. Of course I didn't.
You think I feel like working
with you hating my guts
for the next
two godforsaken years?
Look, Jim Simpson
is a smart guy.
He doesn't want to
interfere at all.
I am not approving
these changes.
Well, I'm afraid
it's not up to you.
The casts are already finished.
We put in that order
- over a month ago.
- What?
This is the first time
you're hearing about it?
Fuck!
No one tells me
a goddamn thing here!
Harrison said he would
talk it over with you.
I'm sorry you found out
this way, I really am.
There. It is mine again.
He cuts three metres
from the top,
I add it to the bottom.
There you go.
We can't afford all this.
I'm already overbudget
this quarter.
You take what you need
from my fee, Leslie.
Come on, what's the difference
between 40 and 50 feet, anyway?
The ceilings
are still plenty high.
Get it approved!
Well, we have a walk-through
next week
and Jim is supposed to be there.
Just hear him out!
You can state your case
to Harrison and Harry Lee.
I won't open my mouth,
I swear it.
Quit talking
and get it approved, Leslie!
For the cantilevered floors,
we plan to use upside-down
T-shaped beams
integrated into concrete slabs
down here.
This will serve both as the
ceiling for the space above
and provide resistance
against compression.
Well, which corridor
are we in now?
We're below ground here.
It's a sort of passageway
between the main unit
and the three mid-sized
modular units
to the south and southeast.
I'm sorry, but I don't see how
any of this acknowledges
my proposed cuts.
I took ten feet off the height
of these damn things
and now we are 30 feet
underground.
You have added a quarter-mile
or so of tunnel!
We excavate the entire
diameter of the tunnel system
- using a full-face method.
- A what?
So that there is something
inside
for the people to discover.
And so that it is one building,
not four!
For its harmony.
You said it yourself,
Mr Van Buren,
you expected it
to be one building.
Well, now it is.
I'm sorry,
but we are not going back inside
until you look us all straight
in the eye
and you tell us where
you are willing to compromise.
Jim, please, tell us again
what it is that you have built.
- Tell us.
- I'll tell you what I've built.
I've built a shopping centre
in New Hope,
a hotel in Stamford,
Connecticut...
Now, Jim, let me remind everyone
that László has offered to
personally offset these costs.
I'm sorry, but you have asked me
to come here
to tell you what it is
that we do not need.
Plain and simple, the one thing
we do not need is this guy.
You two. Jim.
I'm sorry, but this whole thing
is just bizarre.
- You must all see...
- Now, look.
I really think you two
might see eye to eye
if you just spent a little more
time getting to know each other.
Jim! Listen to me.
Come. Listen to me.
Come. Come here.
I'm listening.
Everything that is...
ugly...
cruel...
stupid...
but most importantly, ugly...
everything... is your fault.
- Jim! That's enough!
- You want to push me?
I think it's time you went home.
Thank you for your insight.
I'm sorry.
He hit me.
I trust you.
I trust you, all right?
Ah...
It went well,
other than that, I think.
- Very well.
- Sorry.
- Very well indeed.
- Sorry, I...
- He's an idiot, though.
- Come on.
- I go home.
- Yeah.
Harrison,
you sure about this guy?
Look, I know
Jim lost his temper,
but he had a few points
back there, didn't he?
Look, my office
is fielding complaints
about plans for this place
on a daily basis, more or less.
Jim's a Protestant.
Gives folks peace of mind.
People are worried
it's gonna ruin the hillside.
We'll do something. A little
event for the community.
Get them on side.
And don't worry,
Jim will stay on.
Yeah, does Jim know that?
I think he thinks he's fired.
I'll have Leslie telephone him
tomorrow.
And he can advise from afar.
Better for morale that way.
Mayor Kinney!
Thank you, everyone,
for being here today.
Girls, come in for this picture.
Here.
I'm proud of you.
Make love to me tonight.
- All right.
- Right. Everybody ready?
Yes, yes. Feeling lucky.
On the count of three.
Three, two, one!
That's a motor grader.
We used to do it with horses.
Makes a flat surface to pour on.
Take a lot of horses to do
what that thing can do, William.
If you want, in the morning,
we can take you down there
if you're curious.
What do you say we get you
in one of them machines?
Sure.
Big day, Mr Tóth.
Yes. Yes, it is.
Excuse us, gentlemen.
Leslie mentioned during
our meeting with Jim last week
that you're planning on putting
your fee back into the project.
Seems a bit irresponsible,
doesn't it,
given your situation?
Will it even last you
to the end of your commitment?
I will figure something out.
Have you discussed it
with your wife?
She will be supportive.
Suit yourself. I wouldn't do it.
I know Leslie
certainly wouldn't do it.
I didn't want you to think
you'd be setting
any sort of precedent.
I expect nothing
from either of you.
How does that work?
The company paying themselves
a fee to finance?
Do you not think
I deserve to be paid
for the time and energy
I devote to the project?
Might I make a suggestion?
You might.
Your niece has made
several of our guests
very uncomfortable.
Perhaps you should
have a talk with her.
About what?
Don't get me wrong, she's...
she's very lovely to look at,
I know.
As much as we all dream
of having a little birdy
that keeps her trap shut,
comes off
like a rude affectation.
And I've tried to connect.
Make conversation.
It goes nowhere.
Oh, it runs in the family.
I would like us to be friends.
Huh!
Great.
This is not friendly, Harry.
I didn't say I'd like
to slip my prick into her.
Forget it.
I had too much to drink.
I need a nap.
László?
We tolerate you.
Rub-a-dub-dub,
three maids in a tub.
Who do you think were there?
Butcher, the baker,
the candlestick maker.
It's invigorating, isn't it?
Do you fancy a stroll?
I swear it.
They looked exactly
like that popular painting.
You know the one. Ooh!
Oh, stop it!
Daddy kept apologising
to our hostess.
For context...
for context, her husband
was one of Van Buren
Manufacturer's
most important private clients.
Daddy tried
to explain everything
that had made us late
that evening,
as she prepared
what appeared to be
a delightful-looking trifle.
- Was it awful?
- Yes.
I kid you not,
cow tallow and fruit pie.
No!
And Daddy
has such a sweet tooth.
I didn't know how to warn him
in front of everyone.
- I was starving.
- He took a bite this big.
I was starving!
He began gagging
like a housecat.
And all he could say
to explain was...
"Dear, I'm allergic."
"I'm allergic."
To which our concerned hostess
replied,
"Oh, goodness,
allergic to what?"
And he said, "To that."
"I am allergic
to whatever that is."
Oh, Daddy.
Let's go.
Bring the chair, please.
Zsófia.
You all right?
It has been a lovely day.
It certainly has been.
Pity the wind's
picked up a little.
Erszi. It's time for us to go.
You won't join us for dinner
at the house?
Uh, we start early tomorrow.
Thank you for the event.
- Does he ever take a break?
- Never!
Goodbye, Mr Van Buren.
All right, stay warm.
What's the rush?
We will talk at the house.
László, can you slow down?
Can you slow down?
I am forfeiting
the remainder of my fee
due to some expenses unforeseen.
Oh, so that's what the son
kept alluding to.
Yes. He's a snake.
Don't go near him, Zsófia.
All right,
so what will that mean for us?
- I will figure something out.
- We will figure something out.
I suppose we can make do
on my salary.
Your salary?
Mr Van Buren's helped me
with a job interview
in New York City.
I'm sure once they meet me,
they won't be able to resist me.
Thank you
for the supper, Mrs Tóth.
I thought we might
have our own little party
to celebrate
all of your hard work.
You've come so far,
the both of you.
Oh, it's not mine, really.
That's not what László tells me.
He says he couldn't have done it
without you.
So do you have a missus at home,
Gordon?
Augusta passed away in '43.
She was sick and died of a damn
tooth infection, of all things.
Very sorry to hear that.
I'm terribly sorry
for your loss.
He's all right. He was too young
then to remember much.
And I was gone two years
in Arizona
before they shipped us all off
to Naples, Italy.
92nd Infantry Division.
They wouldn't let me back home
all that time, not once.
Augusta's sister looked
after him until I got back.
Kept me alive, though,
knowing he was waiting for me.
Kept me good and alive,
thank goodness.
Zsófia's mother passed.
Losing a mother,
it's an unfathomable loss.
To lose one's birth mother
is to lose the very foundation
on which we stand.
The mind may not know its loss,
but the heart does.
I remember her.
That's because I've told you
so much about her.
You were too small.
No, I remember Augusta.
I just wanted
to make it easier on you.
What are you doing?
I'm just looking at you.
What do you think?
It's unusual, even for you.
- Think so?
- Hmm.
Many of the rooms
are quite small,
yet the ceilings are high.
Yes.
Inside, you must look upwards.
So which part of it
are we paying for?
The height of the ceiling.
The glass above.
I like it.
I'm so happy you approve.
The service is in here?
For the overflow.
Because of the holiday?
The community's growing.
What?
Erzsébet? Erzsébet?
What is happening?
It's too much.
- What is too much?
- The pain. It's too much.
I need Zsófia.
She has my medication.
Zsófia!
Zsófia.
Oh, my God!
Get it. Go to her. Go to her.
Give it to her.
Take it.
I have everyone
here with me now, yes.
I see. Well, if there's
anything more we can do.
We're terribly sorry
for the news.
On tenterhooks at this end,
so give me a ring here
when you have something.
A big section came undone.
He didn't know which one
for certain.
And it took seven freight cars
along with it.
Goddamn it, Leslie! How the hell
do you find these people?
Transpo company is our own, Dad.
What?
We sent our own guys
to Charleston.
The rail cars were ours too.
It was cheaper,
given all the back and forth.
It's well over
a hundred shipments, Harrison.
You don't utter another word
to that rail company
till Michael can advise.
I'm hoping to have
some answers for you soon, sir.
Can we see what can be salvaged?
How far is it?
The accident put two brakemen
in the hospital.
It's a real mess out there.
Send flowers to them, to
the families for Christ's sake.
Oh, wait, don't!
That looks guilty.
I'll call Michael.
What do you want me to do
in the meantime?
- With what?
- Well, our crew.
Let them go.
- You can't, sir, you cannot...
- Yes, I can!
Yes. Yes, I can!
People are gonna
write about this.
I'm staring down the barrel
of the next two goddamn years
of my life.
What if one of them dies?
What if they both die?
Who pays for it?
Are you gonna pay for it?
László,
in the interest of transparency,
before I came to retrieve you,
I'd already advised Mr Van Buren
- to cut his losses...
- Shut up, Leslie!
Sir. Sir, please.
Don't beg! It's unbecoming!
You're welcome to stay here
until you find your footing
elsewhere.
I have a mess to clean up.
I'm sorry, Gordon.
Don't apologise to me.
I will give you some money
while you look for something.
I'll be fine.
You have a kid. I will give you
something and you will take it.
Listen...
you got any, uh...
any hop on you?
None at all. I'm off it.
Good.
Good. That's...
That's good to hear.
Fuck.
Fuck!
Damn it all to hell!
Stop it!
You're acting like a child.
It's over!
You're making me
a mess to clean up.
It's over!
You have to march over there
right now
and get him excited again.
Keep him engaged.
You know
how these rich fellows are.
For him, it's like... it's like
refurbishing a kitchen.
Two people are in the hospital.
He does not want to proceed.
That's not your fault!
It's over.
Over.
Finished!
Fuck!
Good evening, New York,
and happy holidays
from ABC News.
November 23rd, 1958,
marks an important milestone
in the fight against the East.
This morning,
the first full-range firing
of an intercontinental
ballistic missile, or ICBM,
was conducted
by the United States.
All right.
Yes. I'll make a note of it.
Morning.
I'm looking for Rudolph Heywood
and Associates.
Pardon me, sir, but who is it
you're looking for?
László Tóth. He draws there.
Could I ask you to spell that?
- Yeah, it's, uh, L-A-S-L-O...
- Oh. Yes. I see him.
The draughtsmen
are right upstairs.
All righty. Thank you, ma'am.
The Macy's
Thanksgiving Day Parade
is just around the corner,
and anticipation is building
for this annual spectacle.
On the political front,
New York...
László?
Michael.
We have some news.
As do I.
How exciting.
What is it, László?
Please. Go ahead, Zsófia.
We are making Aliyah.
- What?
- We are going to Jerusalem.
I heard you.
Binyamin has family there.
My older brothers relocated
with their families in 1950.
They became citizens.
Life is difficult there.
Have you thought this through?
It is our obligation.
To whom?
Our repatriation
is our liberation.
Oh, please...
Where will you live?
Hmm?
Where will you work?
We can stay with my brother's
family when we first arrive.
I was planning to help
with the baby.
My brother's wife can help,
also.
I know.
I am Jewish. My child is Jewish.
We must go home now.
Does it somehow make us
less Jewish that we are here?
Are we not Jewish?
I see.
Perhaps Binyamin did not
recognise me to begin with.
He does.
I'm sorry.
No, I'm sorry.
It's wonderful news.
Mm-hm.
We reacted badly
out of self-interest.
It is simply that...
we are going to miss you.
Well, we would like you to come.
Dear, we have jobs here.
You could have a better job
in Israel.
I like my job.
A women's column.
It's beneath you.
I write for a paper
and I'm paid for it.
How many women my age
could make the same claim?
What's your news, László?
Harrison asked me back.
Michael
came by the office today.
Insurance monies came through.
They plan to forego the library
to compensate
for legal expenses, but...
they want to complete
the project.
I don't like that man.
You scarcely knew him.
He dropped you
as quickly as he took you on.
He's in Roma on business.
He would like me to join him
to select the marble
for the altarpiece in Carrara.
I told you, for him,
it's like doing a kitchen.
Darling?
Everyone is leaving me.
- No, it isn't true.
- Isn't it?
- No.
- No, it isn't.
Uncle László is leaving you
only for a short time.
For some days.
And I will visit and so will
you. We will find a way.
I can make arrangements
to have you dropped
and picked up at the newspaper.
No. It's not just this trip.
You'll be in Doylestown again
now.
I'll be fine on my own.
I will make arrangements.
Promise you won't let it
drive you mad.
I promise.
It's time to go!
You'll be late!
Yes, yes. Yes, one minute.
I must say, Mr Tóth,
you look a mess.
I would expect your Elizabeth
to be taking better care of you.
The years have been difficult.
For us all.
Hm.
Where the hell is he?
I'm sure he'll be...
be along any minute.
He lives in the mountains.
It takes time.
This is why I never do business
with Italians.
They're the spics of Europe.
Hello, László, my friend!
He's right here now.
Hello, Orazio.
- Finally, darling.
- Che bello.
- Mr Van Buren.
- Orazio.
I will take a coffee
and we can go.
Hey...
What happened to his hand?
Dangerous work.
You are tough, Mr László,
you know?
I've worn the wrong
shoes for this little trek.
Do you mind if I take your arm?
Step where I step,
you will be all right.
There aren't many people I
see anymore from before the war.
I'm not surprised to see you, though.
Some people, you just knew
somehow they would be all right.
Because you are stubborn.
And so am I.
I will never leave this place.
Because you are stubborn.
And so am I.
I will never leave this place.
I have left only once in 20 years
to go to Giulino, Azzano,
to beat the corpse of Mussolini
with my own hands.
Those of us here, my colleagues,
we are anarchists.
We were part of the Resistance.
No one knows the quarries like us.
We fought and captured
many members
of the National Republican Army.
We trapped them in these caves.
And we dropped
these very same stones on them.
It is beautiful, no?
It is beautiful.
Exactly as you described,
László.
Extraordinary.
The channelling here
will be done in one month.
If you like it, we can have it fixed
and ready for you in April.
I'm so happy to see you again.
I am happy to see you,
old friend.
Such a life down the years.
And we are still here.
We like it.
This is magic. Thank you.
László, László,
there will be
a big party tonight.
I remember how much
you love a party.
Yeah.
♪ You are my destiny
♪ You are too hard to me
♪ You are my happiness...
I remember that.
Hey! Come, come.
This is my great old friend.
Good evening.
♪ You share my loneliness ♪
♪ You're more than life to me ♪
♪ That's what you are ♪
♪ Heaven ♪
♪ And heaven alone can take ♪
♪ Your love from me ♪
♪ Would I be fool
to ever leave you, dear? ♪
♪ And a fool I'd ever be ♪
♪ You are my destiny ♪
♪ You share my reverie ♪
♪ You're more than life to me ♪
♪ That's what you are ♪
♪ Heaven ♪
♪ And heaven alone can take ♪
♪ Your love from me ♪
♪ But I'd be a fool
to ever leave you, dear ♪
♪ And a fool I'd never be ♪
Mr Tóth?
It's time we return
to our quarters.
Orazio has very kindly
offered us
a place to sleep for the night.
Mr Tóth?
What have you done to yourself?
It's a shame seeing how...
your people treat themselves.
If you resent your persecution,
why then do you make of yourself
such an easy target?
Hmm?
If you act as a loafer,
living off hand-outs...
a societal leech,
how can you...
how can you rightfully expect
a different result?
You... you have
so much potential.
But you squander it.
Get it out. Let it out.
Let it out. It's all right.
It's all right.
Who do you think you are?
You think you're special?
You think you...
...you just float directly above
all those you encounter
because you're beautiful, huh?
Because you're educated?
You're just a tramp.
You're a lady of the night.
You're just a lady of the night.
♪ That's what you are ♪♪
You were in quite a state
last night.
Orazio carried you to bed.
It's a four-hour train
to the airport in Fiumicino.
So you'll have time for a rest.
I hope your stomach is not
too sensitive on aeroplanes.
My dearest Zsófia! Mazel tov!
She is so beautiful.
Your spitting image!
Don't be mad,
but your Uncle László insisted
I enclose a few banknotes
for you and Binyamin.
We hope he won't be offended,
and that it's not too difficult
to change these
into the local currency.
Here, I am so alone.
Perhaps more alone
than I have ever been.
Your uncle closed a door to me.
The man I married is inside,
but the lock's combination
I cannot decipher...
Your uncle no longer attends synagogue.
He prefers to roam obsessively
through the corridors
of his construction in Doylestown.
There, at last, much progress
has been made,
yet he seems no more content
than on the day the Institute
first broke ground.
I suppose that inside,
he worships at the altar
of only himself.
Tell me how you are.
How you really are.
All our love and warmth
to the three of you.
Erzsébet.
You see this, above us?
Measure the same distance
of three or perhaps four inches
between flats,
and place each modular section
apart by that same distance.
Then what do we do
with the gaps?
We insert a thick sheet of glass
between the panels
to let the light in from above.
Give me some time to think about
it and I'll come back to you.
Twenty-two.
- Twenty-three.
- What's going on here?
Twenty-four.
Twenty-five.
Twenty-six.
Twenty-seven.
Twenty-eight.
Twenty-nine.
Thirty.
- Thirty-one
- Stop it right now!
- Thirty-two.
- Stop it! Stop it right now!
What is your name, huh?
Are you stupid? You want
to pull this whole thing down?
Want to get them all killed?
Your childish show-boating
puts everyone else here at risk!
Do you hear me?
Are you thick? Are you lame?
Gordon, can you get him
to stop shouting at everyone?
I will.
You report to the subcontractor.
You tell him
that you've been let go.
- Get out of here!
- Hey!
What's wrong with you, László?
You kicked that boy.
Stay out of it, Gordon.
- What's wrong with you?
- Stay out of it.
Stay out of it,
or you can go with him!
You shout at me again
and you'll be sorry.
You too! You go!
Go! Get out of here.
Get out of here.
You think
I am playing games with you?
Let's go. Let's go.
I only just arrived.
- Mr Tóth.
- Oh, God.
Mr Tóth, we need to talk about
these May-June cost reports.
Not today, Jimmy, not today.
You can't keep
walking away from me
every time I step into a room.
This is not a room, Jim.
Honey, did I introduce you
to Jim Simpson?
Jim is the boss's lapdog
and architectural consultant
extraordinaire!
Jim designed a hotel
in Stamford.
László, that's enough.
Come on, Jimmy, there
must be an unpaid parking meter
around here somewhere, huh?
Be vigilant!
Keep your eyes peeled!
What is it, huh?
It was unnecessary
how you treated that boy is all.
Their safety is my priority.
It is not what you said
to that young man, it is how.
Gordon?
Don't even get me started.
Do you want to wait around
for another few years
for another lawsuit
to resolve itself?
Hmm? I am sick of it.
Sick! Do you hear me?
I finish this
or we are finished.
Speak for yourself.
I am not finished.
Living with you is impossible.
You've become
a selfish old bastard
right before my very eyes.
Don't say something
you'll regret in the morning.
Do you want to kill us?
I'd get out of the car and march
all the way back to Manhattan
if I could,
you egotistic scoundrel!
There is no reason
for me to be here.
I'm here for you. I could do
my ridiculous job anywhere!
Do you think
I went to university
to write about lipsticks?
Shame on you!
We came here
because it was our only option!
- Attila was here...
- Who you refuse to see!
Ask him about that! Ask him.
Did he tell you he kicked me
to the street like a dog?
Did he?
His bitch, bitch wife accused me
of making a pass at her.
- You would never do that.
- I did not do that.
Then why would she say
such a thing?
Because
they do not want us here.
Of course Attila wants us here.
- Not Attila.
- Then who do you mean?
The people here.
They do not want us here.
Audrey, Attila's Catholic wife,
does not want us here!
She does not want us here!
We are nothing.
We are worse than nothing.
You poor man.
My poor husband.
Oh, dear.
What has been robbed of you?
- Zsófia!
- Shh.
- She's not here, darling.
She's not here.
- Zsó...
- Sorry I upset you. Please.
Get me my pills.
It's too much.
I'm in pain! I'm close to death!
Darling?
There is only a pill
cut in halves.
Do you have more in your purse?
I can't.
Darling.
Take this, please.
Do you have more in your purse?
No?
This is too much.
What will I do?
The pain.
This is too much, László.
Shh.
Darling,
I have found something.
Darling, come on.
Shh. Shh.
It's what they gave me
on the boat for my broken face.
It'll help you feel better.
Just listen to my voice, dear.
That's it.
Just listen to my voice.
Listen to my voice.
There you go.
There you go. Shh.
Listen to my voice.
Good, my dear.
There you go.
Good.
Listen to my voice, darling.
Do... do you have more?
I love you.
Keep going.
Yes.
I love you.
Harder.
More.
Toilet.
Yes, dear.
Yes.
Up. Come, my dear.
Oh. Yeah.
Come on.
Come...
Oh. All right?
I'll wait outside.
OK? You tell me
when you need me.
Darling?
Have you finished?
Darling, can I come in?
Darling? Erzsébet?
Help. Help me. Help.
I need a gurney,
a stretcher! Anything! Anything!
Help me.
Help, my wife is dying.
She'll be all right.
OK, OK, OK.
- My wife is dying.
- She'll be all right.
Quickly, quickly, quickly!
My wife, she's dying.
Last night, I met God.
He granted me permission
to call Him by His name.
It's not the first time
we have met.
What did you do to me,
my László?
It was an accident.
Do you remember everything
you confessed to me
at home in our bed?
You needn't be ashamed,
my darling.
The harm done unto us
was done only
to our physical bodies.
You were right.
This place is rotten.
The landscape, the food we eat,
this whole country is rotten.
I'm going to Israel
to be with Zsófia and her child.
I want to become
the grandmother to her
that she will otherwise
never encounter.
Come home with me.
I will follow you.
I follow you until I die.
Mrs Tóth.
You're standing.
How lovely to see.
- Do you need a hand?
- I'm all right, thank you.
Is Mr Tóth here as well?
- Just me, I'm afraid.
- Oh.
To what do we owe the pleasure?
Is your father in?
Sure. We were just
sitting down for dinner.
No trouble at all, I'm happy to
wait until you're all finished.
Don't be silly. I'll ask
the kitchen to fix you a plate.
You're kind, Maggie. Thank you.
Follow me.
You can finally meet my fiancé.
Are you sure
you don't need a hand?
Fine.
Mrs Tóth.
You're up on your feet.
Please, sit.
Where's László?
He's caught a flu.
He's recovering at home.
Well, that explains it.
Jim Simpson mentioned he hadn't
been on site since last Friday.
- Shame.
- Yes.
A terrible shame.
It's going around.
Please. Sit down.
I'm fine to stand.
Fine to stand?
Is something wrong, Mrs Tóth?
Yes.
Something is wrong.
I have come tonight
to tell you something
that is going to be
very difficult to hear.
For you people, too.
I don't know you, but it will
be difficult for you to hear.
If this
is a professional matter,
then perhaps you and I should
talk in the other room.
Your father is a rapist.
Excuse me?
Whatever this is
supposed to be, I don't like it.
I'm calling your husband
to come and fetch you.
Your father is an evil rapist.
Daddy,
what is she talking about?
Look at him.
He cannot say anything.
Did something happen
between you and Mrs Tóth?
- It wasn't me.
- That's enough!
You come in here making vague,
laughable accusations.
I want you out of our house
this instant.
Tell them
what you did to my husband.
Tell them what you did.
Your husband is sick.
He's alcoholic. Drug-addicted.
I don't know why he wishes
to hurt me, to humiliate me.
I have offered him
nothing but kindness.
He's a sick, senile old dog
and when dogs get sick, they...
they often bite the hand
of those who fed them,
until someone mercifully
puts them down.
Now, if you will excuse me...
I think I've endured enough
abuse for one evening.
You can tell your husband
he is off the payroll
now and forever as well.
I will not excuse you!
- Get out!
- No!
Harry!
Harry, let her go!
You are not excused,
Harrison Van Buren!
- Shame!
- Out!
Shame on you!
Mrs Tóth, I'm sorry.
Mrs Tóth.
Here.
- I'm fine.
- Sorry. I'm so sorry.
Can you help me to my car?
Yes. Sure.
Taxi is waiting
for me at the front.
I'm so sorry for the
bizarre interruption, gentlemen.
Harry, Harry, we're leaving.
No! No, don't leave. Please.
Harry, your father's gone to bed
anyhow.
What have you done?
Father?
It's over now.
Father! She's gone.
Dad?
Where the hell has he gone?
Call for him outside.
Dad?
Dad!
Harrison!
He must have left the house,
I can't find him anywhere.
Daddy!
Harrison!
Mr Van Buren!
Father!
Dad!
Daddy!
Shine a bit more light
on this side here.
Harrison!
Van Buren!
You see anything?
There's a door there.
It's locked!
Can't get inside!
Give us the telephone
number for a groundskeeper.
What is this place?
It's the condensate
return system
and the drain pumps.
Harrison!
Think we've got something
over here, Lieutenant.
Turn that music down!
They look beautiful
like this, don't you think?
Excuse us, sir.
Good evening.
My uncle is, above all,
a principled artist.
His lifelong ambition
was not only to define an epoch,
but to transcend all time.
In his memoirs, he described
his designs as machines
with no superfluous parts.
That, at their best,
at his best,
possessed an immoveable core,
a hard core of beauty.
A way of directing their
inhabitants' perception
into the world as it is.
The inherent laws
of concrete things
such as mountains
and rock define them.
They indicate nothing.
They tell nothing.
They simply are.
Born in 1911 in a small fishing
village in Austria-Hungary,
László Tóth looked out
upon the Adriatic Sea.
He was a boy with eyes
wide open, full of yearning.
New borders would eventually
rip this expanse of sea
away from him,
but never did he stop
to try and fill its void.
Forty years later, he survived
the camp at Buchenwald,
as did his late wife,
and myself, in Dachau.
His first American masterpiece,
the Van Buren Institute
outside of Philadelphia,
remained unfinished until 1973.
The building referenced
his time at Buchenwald,
as well as the deeply felt
absence of his wife,
my aunt, Erzsébet.
For this project,
he re-imagined the camp's
claustrophobic interior cells
with precisely
the same dimensions
as his own place
of imprisonment,
save for one
electrifying exception.
When visitors looked
20 metres upwards,
the dramatic heights
of the glass roof above them
invited free thought,
freedom of identity.
He further re-imagined
Buchenwald
and his wife's venue
of imprisonment, Dachau,
on the same grounds,
connected by a myriad
of secret corridors,
re-writing their history,
transcending space and time,
so that he and Erzsébet
would never be apart again.
Uncle...
you and Aunt Erzsébet
once spoke for me.
I speak for you now,
and am honoured.
"Don't let anyone fool you,
Zsófia," he would say to me
as a struggling young mother
raising my daughter
during our first years
in Jerusalem.
"No matter what the others
try and tell you,
it is the destination,
not the journey."
Thank you.
♪ One for you, one for me ♪
♪ Please don't go away ♪
♪ I'm ready and I'm able ♪
- ♪ Please don't go away ♪
- ♪ Don't go ♪
♪ Till morning comes around ♪
♪ Please don't go away
while wine is on the table ♪
- ♪ Please don't go away ♪
- ♪ Don't go ♪
♪ Just lay your body down ♪
♪ Now I don't know
what I would do ♪
♪ If you got up to leave ♪
♪ My jealous heart
beats deep inside ♪
♪ And not here on my sleeve ♪
♪ 'Cause I could show
a girl like you ♪
♪ Such loving and affection ♪
♪ I don't want
to make no speech ♪
♪ This here ain't no election ♪
♪ Please don't go away ♪
♪ Honey, change your mind
and stay ♪
♪ Hot love's on the way ♪
♪ Honey, let me hear you say ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah, yeah ♪
♪ One for you, one for me ♪
♪ One for you, one for me ♪♪