Are you Henry?
Yes.
A girl named Mary called on the pay phone.
Said she's at her parents'
and you're invited to dinner.
Oh, yeah?
Thank you very much.
You're late, Henry.
I didn't know if you
wanted me to come or not.
Where have you been?
You never come around anymore.
Dinner's almost ready.
Come on in.
Hello there.
Hello.
I'm very pleased to meet you.
Sit down.
It's Henry, isn't it?
Yes.
Mary tells me you're a very nice fellow.
What do you do?
Oh, I'm on vacation now.
What did you do?
Well, I-I work at Lapelle's factory.
I'm...
I'm a printer.
Hen-Henry's very clever at printing.
Yes, he sounds very clever.
I thought I heard a stranger.
We've got chicken tonight.
Strangest damn things. They're man-made.
Little damn things... smaller than my fist.
They're new!
I'm Bill.
Hello. I'm Henry.
Henry's at Lapelle's factory.
Oh, printing's your business, huh?
Plumbing's mine. Thirty years.
I've seen this neighborhood
change from pastures...
to the hellhole it is now.
I put every damn pipe in this neighborhood.
- Dad!
- Bill!
People think pipes grow in their home.
Well, they sure as hell don't.
Look at my knees!
Bill, please.
- Are you hungry?
- Bill.
The-The girls have heard this before...
but 14 years ago...
I had an operation on my arm here.
Doctors said I wouldn't be able to use it.
"Well, what the hell
do they know?" I said.
And I rubbed it
for a half hour every day...
and I got so as I could move it a little.
And then I got so as
I could turn a faucet.
And pretty soon, I had my arm back again.
Now I can't feel a damn thing in it.
All numb.
I-I... I-I'm afraid to cut it, you know?
Mary usually does the carving, but...
maybe tonight you'll do it, Henry.
All right with you?
Of course.
I'd be happy to.
Do I just, uh...
just cut them up like regular chickens?
Sure, just cut 'em up
like regular chickens.
She'll be all right in a minute.
Excuse me.
Well, Henry, what do you know?
Oh, uh...
I don't know much of anything.
Henry, may I speak to you a minute?
Over here.
Did you and Mary have sexual intercourse?
Uh... Why?
Did you?
Why are you asking me this question?
I have a very good reason.
And now I want you to tell me.
Oh, I-I'm very...
I love Mary.
Henry, I asked you if you and Mary
had sexual intercourse.
Well, I don't... I don't think
that's any of your business.
Henry!
I'm sorry.
You're in very bad trouble
if you won't cooperate.
Well, uh, I...
Mary!
Mother!
Answer me!
I'm too nervous.
There's a baby. It's at the hospital.
Mom!
And you're the father.
But that's impossible. It's only been...
Mother,
they're still not sure it is a baby.
It's premature, but there's a baby.
After the two of you are married,
which should be very soon...
you can pick the baby up.
Oh.
Ahh.
Mom, he's got a nosebleed.
Oh.
I'll get ice.
You don't mind, do you, Henry?
I-I mean about getting married.
Oh, no.
This dinner's getting mighty cold.
Was there any mail?
No.
Shut up!
I can't stand it! I'm going home!
What are you talking about?
I can't even sleep. I'm losing my mind.
You're on vacation now.
You can take care of it for a night.
Well, you'll come back tomorrow?
All I need is a decent night's sleep!
Why don't you just stay home?
I'll do what I want to do.
And you better take real good care
of things while I'm gone!
Oh, you are sick.
Move over.
Move... Move over.
Move over!
I locked myself out of my apartment.
And it's so late.
Where's your wife?
She must've gone back
to her parents' again.
I'm not sure.
Can I spend the night here?
# In heaven #
# Everything is fine #
# You've got your good things #
# And I've got mine #
# In heaven #
# Everything is fine #
# You've got your good things #
# And you've got mine #
# In heaven #
# Everything #
# Is #
# Fine ##
Okay, Paul!
Hiya, sonny. What do you got there?
Counter, Paul!
It's okay.
Subtitles by TUO PADRE