What is it you're drawing, Celestine?
A bear.
And what's this?
It's a mouse.
They're friends.
Um, you're wrong there.
Am not!
Are so!
-Yes!
-No!
Am mouse and a bear? It's just not possible!
Shush!
Good. So, which story should I tell you tonight?
The one about the big evil bear?
Yes, the big evil bear!
In winter, the big evil bear sleeps.
And, when he wakes up...
When he wakes up, he's hungry!
Exactly!
And when he's hungry...
He'll eat anything?
Absolutely anything!
Tires! Melons! Lamps! Cars! Houses!
And when he's hungry, he drinks...
Um, I mean eats,
Absolutely anything!
And, what is the big evil bear's favourite food?
A little mouse?
A little mouse? ONE little mouse?
Ten!
A hundred!
Thousands of little mice!
Wrapped.
On bread.
In a pan.
Boiled.
Even raw!
Completely raw?
Most of all, completely raw!
And still living,
with a little coat and a backpack still on,
this is what he likes the most.
Completely raw.
And still breathing.
But, but, are you sure that he is this evil?
Do you know the story of a little mouse who didn't
believe in the stories about the big evil bear?
Everyone told her: ,,Beware of the bear!''
But would she listen?
That little... that stupid little...
Cretin!
Oh, pardon me...
That, that...That dirty little...
That naughty child!
She didn't believe that bears are evil,
she said things like:
oh, the big evil bear,
it's just a story that the Gray told us
while drinking her eternal cup of tea.
But she was wrong!
Because one day,
a beautiful d....
Did you draw this, Celestine?
Believe me, children,
it's only in fairytales that the bears are friends with mice!
*mumble, mumble, mumble...*
What is she saying?
I don't know.
What did you say?
I said that that i didn't know.
I'm trying to listen here!
You can't understand her!
Of course I can!
No you can't!
Oh, I can't?
Even when we understand her, you don't understand anything.
Repeat that!
SILENCE!
Come here, little birdie.
*?$&%#/
Celestine!
Is it clear, can we go out?
Wait...
Let's go.
Oh, look, he's lost his first tooth.
Oooh, poor darling.
And not a trace of sugar.
It's like a pearl.
Oh, don't cry now, my darling,
it's not that bad. I'll put the tooth on your nightstand,
and the tooth fairy will come.
The tooth fairy?
What tooth fairy?
The nice little mouse tooth fairy.
She'll fly by when you'll sleep
and take your tooth.
She'll replace it with a nice golden coin.
By the value of... ?
A biiiig coin! Your first! The beginning of your great fortune.
If you learn to invest it, that is.
But... I've never heard of this mouse tooth fairy before.
It's because you've never lost a tooth before!
It doesn't matter. Firstly, if it's a mouse from a fairy tale
she can't possibly exist.
No? Why do the teeth dissappear from nightstands then?
Well, you best go to sleep now. Then the fairy will come to collect your tooth
and replace it with a coin.
How much will she give me?
Um... One pound.
Two.
Oh this is great! That's my son.
Come on, darling, now go to bed.
A MOUSE!
A mouse? Where?
There, by the toys!
I'll catch it!
She's under here!
Where is she?
There!
Hey! My tooth!
That's my money! Give it back!
Dirty beast!
Less noise, George, the little one is sleeping!
George! The trash!
Ernest, Ernest, my name is Ernest,
i have no idea what he's singing here, sorry
...because I'm hungry, I'm hungry,
I'll eat anything, I'll eat anything
It doesn't have to be healthy.
I'm giving this up, i cant translate songs.
Give some spare change in my hat.
I assure you that if you give me some change,
you'll feel better.
And me too.
You have five days to pay the fine.
I'M HUNGRY!
Noooo!
Don't eat me!
But I'm hungry.
What's your name?
Ernest.
I'm Celestine.
Take me seriously, Ernest!
You can't eat me.
Bears eat mice only in fairytales.
Don't tell me you beilive in fairytales, Ernest. You are not an idiot.
Yes, well, but I'm hungry!
You're hungry, you're hungry...
You think eating a little mouse like me will make you full?
Look at me, Ernest, I'm nothing but skin and bones.
And it's very bad for you health to eat from dumpsters.
You woudn't beilive how many diseases are there.
Flu, tifus, colera, hepatitis...
Do you want to catch every disease in existence?
Well... No, Celestine, but...
Let's see. Very cold and moist... Red eyes...
Thin fur... Are your ears sore?
And teeth?
Oh my... You have a dental disease.
What?
I'm sick?
Not yet.
But it'll come.
Listen, Ernest.
I know a place where you can regain your health by eating anything you want.
Marshmallows?
Marshmallows, toffees, nougat, cakes, lollipops... Allright?
Allright.
It's here.
You won't be hungry after this, Ernest.
No, wait!
Here you go. Bon apetit.
Celestine!
Thanks!
No problem.
Watch where you're going!
You made me drop my money!
I'm sory madam, I'm in a hurry!
It's not open yet.
They told us to wait here.
You stink of garbage.
Hurry up, or the big evil bear will get you!
How many teeth did you find?
Seven.
Not bad. I found twelve.
Twelve?
I usualy find more, it's way below my best score.
And you, Celestine?
How many did you find?
...well...
Please wait there.
This will hurt.
Step forward.
Here you go, madam, twelve teeth.
Very good.
I can do even better, you know.
Yes, yes... Next!
Seven? Only?
Yes, but three incisors. And look at the quality.
Incisor? I need one, this one is much too short.
Thank you!
We'll try this one...
Repeat after me: The big bad bear is our biggest burden.
Wa wig wed wear if far wiweft wurden.
It doesn't fit...
And now?
Wa fig fet fear iw of biweft buften.
Allow me.
Try.
The wig wad wear...
Stop!
And now?
The big bad bear is our biggest burden.
Here we go.
The length, my darling, the length.
What?
Only one tooth?
One single tooth in the whole night?
Well yes, but I was thrown in the bin...
Oh yes? And how did you escape?
Well, there was a bear...
A what?
No, no, nothing...
Can we see what you carry around in that bag?
Well, we can see how you spend your time, Celestine.
You draw. Instead of working.
You will never become a dentist if you continue like this, Celestine.
But, but, I don't want to be a dentist...
Oh, I see what's going on here.
I'm afraid, Celestine, that you have lost a too many points...
What you need is a boost of motivation.
Come with me.
You see, Celestine, our kind is nothing like the bear kind.
Our strength does not lie in
our weight, muscles, claws or scary teeth.
No, we are delicate, quiet, refined beings.
Our whole civilisation,
everything we've ever made possible over the centuries,
we owe all that to what?
To what, Celestine?
To what?
To our incisors.
That's right!
They are the very basis for our exsistance.
Thanks to them, we were able to build the biggest cities,
remove the biggest obsticles,
and construct the most complex machinery!
We have the biggest mills in the world!
And all this thanks to our cute, precious, delicate, perfect, sharp front teeth.
But, Celestine, what happens if a rodent looses an incisor?
He dies.
It is an unescapable fate.
He can't chew or talk, he dies,
killed by hunger
and loneliness.
What is the best replacement for a lost tooth?
The bear's tooth.
That's correct. Bears' teeth are very hard.
And the easiest teeth to collect are those which little idiotic bears
leave under their pillows.
Well, Celestine...
You will return to the surface and search for other teeth
in these little idiots' bedrooms.
But, Celestine, you may not return here
until you've collected fifty teeth.
Fifty teeth, Celestine!
Good luck, Celestine!
Well, are you coming or not?
Yes, I'm coming!
Hello, hello children!
How are you?
Fine, thanks!
I would like a cupcake please!
I would like some boiled sweets!
I want some marshmallows!
A lemon cake please, daddy.
Coming right up!
Wait a minute!
Come here you punk!
You are not allowed to eat sugar! I told you a hundred times!
But daddy, why?
Don't daddy me! You are not allowed to eat even the smallest piece of sugar!
Do you want your teeth to rot and fall on the floor?
You'll end in your mother's shop there,
with completely rotten teeth?
Is that what you want?
Go now, we'll talk about this in the evening.
Hello, sir! How are you today?
I'm very well, thank you.
I need a tooth, so I'll be able to eat nougat again.
But of course,
which one do you need?
Actually, it's a first molar...
I have exactly what you need.
It's a first molar of top quality.
Try it on!
I'll take it! It's perfect! Thank you, maam.
Here you go, sweetie.
And you, my little, what will you have?
Sugar canes?
Cotton candy?
Sprinkles?
Do you have any marshmallows?
Marshmallows? But of course!
Oh, but I've run out...
No, no, no! Don't cry! I still have them in storage!
Wait here, I'll be back right away.
What are you doing here?
Thief! Thief!
What have you done? I'm calling the police!
My marshmallows!
They are mine!
Police! Help! Police!
There's a thief!
He'd eaten all of my candy!
Here he is! It's him! He's here!
What's going on here?
Firstly you beg for money and now you're stealing?
But how did you get in there?
A little mouse told me...
A little mouse? What?
I was hungry and it smelled nice in there.
Well, we're taking you with us.
My marshmallows! My marshmallows! They are mine!
What a shameful display. I have no respect for this sort of people.
Ernest, Ernest! Do you want me to free you?
And if I do...
will you do me a little favour?
What about a big favour?
Will you do me a big favour if I free you?
An enormous favour?
The biggest favour in the world?
Yes. The biggest favour in the world.
Would you like more peas, darling?
No, I want some candy.
Come on. Don't start that again.
We told you a hundred times that you can't have any candy.
But why?
You see, my boy, it's the buisiness.
I sell candy, which makes the teeth rot...
... and I sell replacement teeth.
And when you grow up, you'll inherit those two shops.
You'll be able to make a great fortune, my boy.
But only if you'll have a perfect smile for your clients.
And like my father said:
It's simple, Leon.
A beautiful smile is nothing but healthy teeth.
To become rich,
you have to make other people's teeth rot,
not your own. Do you understand?
Yeah..
Well, there's a lot to do tomorow, so let's go to sleep.
I have to replace all of my stock...
Well I'm lucky... Nothing like this would happen to my shop.
Who in the world would get the idea to steal teeth...
It's here, Ernest. Hurry!
This is it.
Stop it! You're making too much noise!
Stop! You'll wake up the whole neighbourhood!
Here we go.
Wait!
Where are those teeth?
They're not here, they are probably in storage...
And that's here, right?
Yes, that's it.
Now, let's see...
No, what are you doing?!
Stop it!
Here you go, it's opened.
Are you mad?
What? I opened it.
Ernest, I won't be able to carry that on my own...
Noo, I'm tired...
But you promised...
Allright, but that's all I'm doing.
Wait, I'll check if the coast is clear.
It's allright, you can come... Ernest?
Wait!
Bears have to go to sleep early.
Especially in winter.
Celestine! I forbid you to return before you...
Celestine...
This is unbelieveable!
This is fabulous!
Just look at this!
How did you manage to...
It's great, this! I'm so proud of you!
Everyone! Long live Celestine!
Long live Celestine!
A big evil bear!
Ernest?
Celestine? You know that....
...that...
...That was you wasn't it?
You brought him here!
She was the one that never believed in big evil bears!
Everyone told her to beware of...
This way!
Jump!
There! They are there!
This way!
There is the exit!
Left! Turn left!
Look!
I'm sure that I'd locked the door...
A mouse!
In my husband's truck!
What are you doing, Ernest? Why did you steal the truck? Are you mad?
I was asleep, it's not my fault.
So it's my fault?
Yes, you made me climb down with you!
I couldn't carry that bag by myself!
You told me you'd show me the exit!
But you told me you remebered where it was!
I said that?
Ernest! Pull over! You can't escape!
Stop this instant!
I have a better idea.
Don't think you'll escape!
You might want to look there.
Ernest! I will never let go of this car!
Well, do as you please, but I'm turning right there.
Here we are.
Well, goodbye now.
What do you mean?
I'm going home.
And me?
You? I don't know.
I'm going to my home, and you're going to yours.
But, Ernest, I don't have a home.
You saw them chasing me...
Celestine, we are over.
It happens.
You saved me from the police,
and in exchange I promised you the biggest favour in the world.
But Ernest...
Well, goodbye now.
But the situation has changed, Ernest!
I don't want any mice in my house.
Ernest, can you please listen to me?
No. I don't want a mouse living in my house.
You take one in, and a thousand come to follow.
I know what you are like. Goodbye!
But Ernest...
I told you to leave!
But Ernest, you have to understand that things change...
I don't want mice in my house!
But...
No buts!
Ernest!
I'm hungry!
No!
Mice!
Thank you.
Celestine, I told you...
Hasn't anyone told you that it's impossible to get rid of mice?
Every bear knows that.
If you don't kill them, that is.
Your chocolate is burning.
Do you want to kill me, Ernest?
You can't do it with a broom, I'm too quick.
You could use the good old mouse trap,
but it's not that easy because we know very well how they work...
You could use the poison, of course,
or a glue trap!
They are the cruelest of all.
The poor little mouse walks on it and
her paws get stuck on it.
She can't do anything about it.
She is very scared, and her heart beats
so fast that it eventualy explodes.
Is that what you want, Ernest?
To make my heart explode?
Well no, Celestine, but a bear and a mouse can't...
What? What can't they do?
Mice should live below and the bears above, is that it?
Well yes. It has always been like this...
Allright, Ernest. Do you have a basement?
Um, sure...
Okay.
I get the basement and you stay here.
But...
No buts. Goodbye, Ernest. And stay above!
No! You rest down below, Celestine!
I don't want to hear you, let alone see you!
My chocolate!
... she is the one that didn't believe in stories about the bears...
...everyone warned her to stay away from evil bears...
It's just a nightmare.
Don't be afraid, I'm not your nightmare.
I'm Ernest!
Ernest, I'm worthless.
Worthless?
What are you saying?
I am!
I am alone in the world and noone likes me.
And I don't have a home anymore.
Oh yeah?
And me? Does anyone like me?
Did you paint this, Celestine?
It's brilliant!
It's just like me!
Celestine, who painted this, is not worthless!
You are a great artist!
Well, yes, but...
This is why I'm all alone.
They don't want me to draw,
they want me to be a dentist...
Oh yes...
I know what you mean...
I wanted to be an actor.
And a musician.
And a storyteller.
But no, of course, they wanted me to be a judge.
Like my father, and his father, and my uncle and his father.
Stop playing your music, Ernest!
Stop torturing our ears with your stories!
You should be studying law instead of singing!
Look!
No, Celestine!
You stay down below!
I don't want to hear from you again!
Isn't that a great picture?
Come with me.
Take your paints and brushes and follow me.
We're going to make you an art studio.
And what are you going to paint?
This is going to be my first real painting.
The big evil bear, for example!
Here!
Raise your arms!
Like this.
Lift your foot!
Perfect!
Now don't move!
So you'll look calm.
Can I see?
I told you not to move!
Ernest?
Are you ill?
I'm just a little tired...
Go to bed right now!
You have to drink a lot of water when you're ill.
Leave me alone! Help!
Calm down, Ernest!
I'm not your nightmare.
I'm Celestine!
Are there any marshmallows left?
Of course.
You didn't eat them all?
No, you dummie!
Promise?
Promise.
Good night.
Night.
Celestine!
You know what?
I'm cured!
I bet you can't juggle with four!
You bet?
Again, do it again!
Come on!
...and the president of the police department
Do you think they are talking about us?
(reports that the thiefs are still on the run)
and that they are still looking for them.
They say that it's only a matter of time before...
No, I'm sure they'd allready forgotten about us.
We will not rest until we find Ernest and his partner in crime Celestine.
We only have to wait until they leave their hiding place.
It doesn't matter how long it takes,
they must be punished!
And when we catch them, we will hand them over to justice!
Ernest will be prosecuted like he deserves,
and Celestine deserves a severe punishment.
He is the greates criminal of them all
and Celestine will be punished for this abominable crime.
We will severely judge Ernest.
Nor Ernest nor Celestine will escape their sentence!
You called for me, Ernest?
No, no, it's nothing, Celestine...
Everything is fine.
It's all fine.
You are getting better, Celestine!
Yes, but I've had enough of painting big evil bears.
Yes?
Did you find a more interesting subject?
I'd like to paint a winer landscape.
Well, you'll have to wait for spring...
Bears know very well how to do this.
Waiting for spring.
But the snow will melt by then.
Celestine would like to paint snow...
Celestine would like to paint some snow...
Go to work now, you artist!
Thank you, Ernest!
Ernest, I give you '' Winter ''.
In music, it would sound like...
Ernest, the truck!
What's up with it?
It's like a big red dot.
If they see it, they'll find us.
There's only one thing to do!
Ernest, did you see the fish?
Yeah, yeah...
I did.
Don't you want to take a closer look?
No, no, I can see them from here.
Celestine, we're going back, come.
...is still going on. We have yet to find Ernest, the thief,
and his partner Celestine.
Leave that be.
Don't be upset.
They'll never find us.
What was that?
It's that mouse again!
George?
My truck!
My shop!
Paint?
Ernest...
Luce, call the police!
I know where Ernest is!
Celestine...
Oh, look! What a sunny morning!
But the big evil bear is groaning...
He hasn't woken up yet.
He could eat me, that evil bear...
Good idea, after you've woken me up.
Well, we'll give him the breakfast for big evil bears.
If sir would like to open his mouth...
This is delicious.
I can't believe you can sleep in this sunshine.
Ernest, come see!
Go to the basement, Ernest!
You have to hide there!
And you? You have to hide as well!
Don't worry, I have a plan!
A plan?
Celestine, are you sure of this?
Stay down there!
Celestine?
He's here!
Where is Ernest?
Ernest? He went to town to search for honey, and he said he'd be back tomorow.
For the last time, tell us where Ernest is!
As you please. You know what's coming.
For the last time, Ernest, where is Celestine?
Allright. You know what's coming.
Read all about Ernest's trial!
Buy the newest deluxe story about him and Celestine!
It's him! There! Look!
The trial will now commence.
Bring in the accused.
Accused, stand up and introdouce yourself.
Celestine.
Celestine. Can you tell us where we can find Ernest?
What? You don't want to tell us where Celestine is?
Very well. In this case, you will be judged twice.
First time for what you've done,
and the second time for what she's done.
What? Celestine? What harm did she do?
She didn't do anything!
Didn't do anything?
She brought a rampaging bear in our town!
You call that nothing?
What was he supposed to do? Die of hunger
while the rich fat bears have everything they want?
But I helped her carry her bag full of teeth.
It was a lot too heavy for her.
Silence!
You wanted her to be a dentist, not me!
Ernest, you and that Celestine are accused
of a number of unbelieveable crimes.
Burglary and damage.
Theft of a truck.
Running away!
Causing injuries!
And there are many more!
And that's not all!
But the most evil thing that you've done, Ernest...
You are accused of an unforgivable crime...
You were scaring the children.
What?
Me? Children, was I scaring you?
Me?
I was upsetting the mother?
Maam', do I scare you?
Well, no...
A mouse! There! A mouse! Help!
I give the...
I give the word to the defense.
Ladies and gentlemen of the jury,
your honor,
I'd like you to put yourselves in my client's skin.
Being a bear ifs ifs fa fefifbe pfifn...
What did he say?
I don't know...
What are you saying?
I said that I didn't know!
Shut up, we're listening.
Yes, because you can understand him.
Of course I can.
Liar! You don't understand a thing!
You never understand anything.
Silence! Calm down!
Celestine, we are looking at an accusation wich is supported by...
...nothing at al!
I'm going to tell you what you are accusing me of.
You are accusing me of living with a bear!
How dare you!
All this is a result of your prejudgments!
Yes, Celestine is my friend!
That's what's bothering you!
Bears live above and mice below, that's what this is all about!
Is this how you want to raise your children?
In fear of mice?
Do you want them to be stupid of what?
Silence, Celestine!
You are the accused, not an attorney!
You are the one having to face the consequences!
Leave the house!
The trial is not over!
Come back!
Celestine, listen to me well.
Noone questions the foundation of our society!
Especially a mouse.
Silence!
Come back!
What are you doing?
We have to stop!
Don't come any closer! Return to your bench!
This is an order!
But Mr. Judge, you are on fire.
Obey me! Go back to your seat!
I will not say it again!
Climb down! I order you to climb down from there!
Let me go! Let me go, I tell you!
Mr. Judge! Go, quickly!
We have to leave!
Where did the others go?
They saved themselves.
Come on, let's go.
They've forsaken me.
All but you.
Let's go, now...
Tell me, Celestine...
If we make it out of here alive...
What do you want most in the world?
Find Ernest and never leave him again.
Allright.
But you know, Celestine, it's funny that you'd want to live with a bear...
Why?
Don't you live with a bear?
Oh, I do...
That's right, it's a funny thing.
How are you, Mr. Judge?
What's happened?
Well... There was a fire, Mr. Judge.
Ernest... You've saved my life.
How can I ever repay you?
It's allright.
It's not allright!
What do you want most in the world?
Now?
Of course now!
To find Celestine.
And stay with her forever.
You are free to go.
She saved my life.
Celestine?
Ernest?
No, Ernest.
But yes, Celestine!
No, I'm telling you that it's impossible.
And I'm saying that it isn't.
But think about it. We can't tell our story,
it's terrible.
To start, you found me in the bin and wanted to eat me.
That's funny!
No, I don't want to tell this.
But we could change some things...
Imagine:
you were a little baby, left alone in the trash.
Your eyes were not opened yet. Draw this!
I was a garbage man, and was sweeping the pavement,
and I suddenly heard a noise comming from the bin.
Was that me?
That was you.
And what did you do next?
Well, a bit like in reality, I lifted you from the trash,
and put you in my warm jacket pocket.
And then I brought you home.
And then?
Well, after that I took care of you and
decided to keep you as my own.
And we started living together.
This is how we met.
And after that? Are we going to tell other stories?
A lot of them, Celestine.