THIS IS MY DESIRE
Come in, factory, come in.
I read you.
Try the roller.
It's working.
I said it's working.
Okay.
They earn more than the Senators in the US.
In fact, Nigerian Senators earn more
than the US President...
They think we are fools.
So it's up to Nigerians.
I'm not talking about reform...
I'm talking about revolution.
21, 22, 23, 24,
25, 26, 27, 28, 29, 30.
What is it?
Madame, the junction boxes...
all of them...
they're unmanageable.
What do you mean by that?
Madame, they're all broken.
I'll see what I can do.
Thank you, Madame.
Thank you.
You've broken it.
Get his file.
I'm telling you, the passport is real.
So when you're ready to apply
for the visa you can come.
Thank you.
Tighter, tighter.
Yeah, that's right.
Here, give me.
Uncle. They broke my paddle.
- Again?
- Yes.
- Alright, leave it upstairs.
- Okay.
You want to turn it on?
- Hello, mommy.
- How are you?
Did you get it?
It's just the visa left.
I'll transfer the money
to your account tomorrow.
Thank you.
- C'mon! I'm still looking at it.
- Give it back.
You're going overseas.
I can't believe it.
Alright, I'm heading in.
- Money?
- Yes.
When they fight they get money.
Especially if they win a title.
How much?
Up to a million.
A million? Naira?
In a fight you can get up to one million.
Don't forget to buy "Assurance".
Which season?
Nine.
Will that show ever end?
What about you boys?
But he still beat Shawn Michaels.
- Answer your uncle.
- I already know what you want.
Celestine?
Your uncle is talking to you, Celestine.
Bring your paddle.
My spoon is not a screwdriver!
Goddey! Goddey!
I don't know what these kids
have done with my TV.
I just want to come home
and watch my show.
I've told them not to touch my TV.
What are you doing?
Mofe, talk to me.
Oh! It's working now.
Thank you.
You see.
I don't want them touching my TV.
They told her not to marry him!
She's in trouble now.
It looks real to me.
Yeah, it's real.
What are you guys doing?
Let me see.
You? Sanchez?
Is that the name your parents gave you?
It's my foreign name.
Your foreign name?
Alright, get back to your posts.
Sanchez...
Good morning.
I don't know why you guys
are wasting fuel...
like I have the money.
Goddey!
Give me the Oju Adewale file.
Mofe?
The mortuary guys are here.
- Morgue!
- Sir.
Come, come, come.
When can I take the bodies?
As soon as we receive the discharge fee.
What do you mean?
Discharge fee. See it here.
What if he can't pay?
We'll dispose of them.
What are you saying?
It's not right.
- Sir, please.
- Is next week okay?
You can pay whenever you want.
Just know that it is 3,000 per day.
- What sort of cruelty is this?
- Abu, it's okay.
Mofe, it's not okay.
It's not right.
Look, Madam, if it were your own kids,
would you stand for it?
Sir, please, I don't like how
you're talking to me.
Mind how you're talking to me.
- Why did you touch me?
- Abu, leave it.
Are you okay?
Hello, Aunty.
Fine, thank you.
Is Dad with you?
Good evening, Dad.
I'm fine.
Dad, I'm calling because...
I'm calling because Precious...
Dad...
Precious is dead.
And the children.
Accident.
No, in the house.
I don't know, something to do
with the generator.
I don't know.
Yes.
I'm bringing them home next week.
I said next week.
Yes.
Bye.
- This is Wisdom.
- Wisdom.
This is Wisdom.
This is the new electrician, Wisdom.
Don't touch these machines.
They need to be repaired.
Very dangerous.
You see?
So this is what we're running.
This is for the roller.
See how it's connected to the main cable?
When the roller comes,
you won't fix it.
If the machine spoils,
cut the wire here.
And connect it here.
You understand?
Okay. Show me.
Not that one.
Yes, that's good, that's it.
- Blessing will bring your drink in a second.
- Thank you, Aunty.
You know he came at the top of his class.
Well done.
And he's going to university next year.
So Dad,
I'm going to Okpara's tomorrow.
Is that where they are?
Yes.
- And you're going there tomorrow?
- Yes.
Alright, alright.
Is there anything you want to contribute?
Was she not my daughter?
Anyone home?
- Ah, Clarence!
- Welcome.
Good afternoon.
Hello.
Have a seat.
Clarence, this is my son.
Mofe.
Yeah, Mofe!
How are you?
It's been a while.
I'm Uncle Peter's son.
Peter Anabohri.
I was little then.
He's a lawyer.
I should be going.
- Hold on, let me pack your food.
- No, it's okay, Aunty.
- It won't take long.
- Leave him.
- What about your drink?
- He's in a hurry. I'll have it.
- Goodbye.
- Mofe, take it easy.
Bye-bye.
Clarence, Clarence.
- Clarence, Clarito.
- Don't you start.
If you choose this one,
we can give you a band.
But you'll have to tip them.
What about coffins?
We sell those ones.
Come, let me show you.
- Oh, no, it's too expensive.
- Too expensive?
If you want,
you can give us the money,
we can arrange the materials
and make something cheaper.
- How much are the materials?
- It depends.
Ebony, 12,000 Naira,
but that's because it's scarce.
Mahogany, 5,000.
And then regular materials,
1,000 Naira.
Listen, listen.
The way we leave this world
is very important.
Very, very important.
If you're burying someone,
it's good to show people
that they were loved.
That the lives they lived mattered.
- The deposit is 18,000?
- Yeah.
Give us a minute.
Dad? Dad?
Yes.
It's too much.
Dad, we discussed this yesterday.
These are your children,
your grandchildren.
I asked yesterday, and you said fine.
So you don't have anything?
Hold this. Here's 13,000.
Thank you.
You know, this is just the deposit.
- Good work. Good work.
- Thank you.
Thank you, ma. Welcome.
- Eat here or take away?
- Take away.
- Sorry for your loss.
- Thank you.
It's in God's hands.
Mr. Vincent.
You want tea?
Let me get you water.
Thank you.
- I'm so sorry.
- Thank you, sir.
- Generator?
- Yes, sir.
Jesus.
We're finished.
- Let me not disturb you.
- It's no problem.
No, I should be going.
Don't worry about next month's rent.
Are you serious?
Seriously.
Take your time.
I know it's not easy.
And you people have always been good.
Thank you, sir, thank you.
God will bless you, thank you.
Engineer.
Come in, please. Engineer.
I read you.
There's a problem with the cutting machine.
What kind of problem?
It's not working.
Engineer, come in, please.
Wait, let me try this side.
Are you okay?
Show me, show me, show me.
Alright, come over here.
Hold still.
Shouldn't I go to the hospital?
You're a mechanic now.
- Hold it.
- Boss, wait. This thing is painful.
- Please.
- Hold still.
Hold this on top.
Thank you.
Here, here,
let me take your passport photo.
He knows where he's going.
Get lost!
Harassing my client.
Don't mind them.
You're ready to apply for the visa?
Where's your letter of invitation?
Employment letter?
You need a letter of invitation,
letter of employment,
bank statements, six months,
and a medical report.
Go to the hospital, tell your doctor
to get you a medical report.
So everything is going to cost you 50,000.
You don't have a letter of invitation.
You don't have an employment letter.
My guys will get these things for you.
I'm the one doing the forms, right?
Cool.
Text me details on WhatsApp.
WhatsApp?
Okay.
I'll call you in three or four days' time.
You come back and if I need anything from you,
you'll bring it.
It's easier this way, right?
Great, no worries.
Are you Goddey?
No.
Because that's the only other name
on the account, sir.
Can I see the balance?
No, sir, it's for account holders only.
- Is Goddey the husband?
- No, it's her son.
- Oh, okay. How old is he?
- He's passed.
- I'm sorry for your loss, sir.
- It's okay.
- Are you the only living relative?
- Yes.
Hold on.
Bisi, do we have any probate forms?
I'm sorry for keeping you waiting,
we're still trying to move into
our new building.
Alright, so what can I do for you?
- Do you know how much is in the account?
- No, sir.
Alright.
I'm going to send you to my man...
Bonaventure.
Tell him that you're from Emeka's law office,
and you'll be needing an affidavit.
Now, when you get the affidavit,
you'll need to place notices
in two national newspapers,
announcing her death
and asking for people
who believe they have a claim
on her property to step forward.
One more thing...
I need you to fill this out.
It's a client form.
Don't worry, it's a formality.
My fee is normally
10,000 Naira plus ten percent
of whatever is recovered,
but since you're from Mr. Vincent,
it's 6,000 Naira plus ten percent.
How long will it take?
Everything shouldn't be more
than a few weeks.
Is 2,000 okay for now?
Put the last one here
then turn on the switch.
- This one?
- Yeah.
- All of them?
- All of them.
Did it shock you?
No, I'm dancing.
Sorry.
It's okay.
Yes?
- Good evening, Ma'am.
- Good evening.
Did you come to watch me pack?
No, Ma'am.
The junction boxes haven't arrived.
I've placed the order.
It will get here when it gets here.
Can you see what is causing the delay?
Engineer, I already told you,
it will get here soon.
The machines will spoil.
Okay, I'll check it tomorrow.
Good night.
Hey, Mofe!
How've you been?
Afternoon, sir.
Mr. Clarence is representing your father
in this matter.
My father?
Didn't you place the notices
for the next of kin?
Look, Mofe...
your father has made legal claims
on your sister's estate.
- Now the truth is that...
- Who told him?
I did.
Look, Mofe...
The law...
is very clear about this.
Your sister died intestate.
Legally, her property is to be shared
among family.
Considering you're not a parent or child...
you must wait.
Look, your father is not a greedy man.
He's willing to let you have
up to twenty percent
which is very kind, you know?
Because legally his claim...
I will die before he touches that money!
Come in, Engineer, please come in.
I read you, Ma'am.
What's happening over there?
Why is everything still down?
We are working on it, Ma'am.
Engineer, come in, please come in.
I read you, Ma'am.
What does that mean,
you're working on it?
Ma'am, we are working on it.
We need a few minutes.
Hurry up, please, we're behind.
Are you okay?
It's okay.
Calm down.
Are you crazy?
Engineer?
You sure you're not crazy?
Engineer, I'm talking to you!
I can't believe what you did.
You're going to have to pay for this.
Everything you're costing us,
you will pay.
Every Naira!
How can you do this? God!
You have nothing to say for yourself,
right?
Get out.
Get out!
Now!
Thank you.
Um...
Madam said I should collect your ID card.
Boss, you're traveling?
Please, please, I don't know.
Good night.
- Maybe it's the fuel?
- The fuel?
Yes, you know most of the fuel
we have here is dirty.
- What do you mean?
- I mean the quality is bad.
But wouldn't it show in the engine?
Not always.
Most times you won't see it.
You won't see a thing at all.
You want to eat?
Hell, yeah. Sure thing, man.
- I don't play when it comes to food.
- Well, in that case, you're paying.
No problem.
Should I leave this here?
Leave it.
If I don't vote and you don't vote,
how will we choose our leaders?
Anybody able to lead us
to a better Nigeria
is the best candidate.
Hello, Aunty.
Is Dad there?
Someone's been waiting for you
to get their hair washed, be quick.
Don't block the mirror.
Be quick, be quick,
she's been waiting all day.
- Afternoon.
- Good afternoon, Aunty.
- How are you?
- Fine.
Did you do your passport?
Grace.
Passport?
No.
What about your medicine?
- Your medicine?
- Yeah.
Long Island ice tea, with ice as well?
I know this man, Agbim!
Stingy Agbim!
Angela!
- But I know this man, he's nice.
- You see, he's nice.
Forget about him, he's so cheap.
Please, I'm sweating... where is Mercy?
Hey, so she said there's this new place
in V.I. we should try.
- Tonight?
- Why not?
Babe, I'm tired, I'm gonna go home.
- See you later.
- Alright, darling.
- Rosa.
- Bye.
Get home safe.
Babe, could you drop me at CMS?
You didn't go to school today?
I wasn't feeling too well.
What about your passport?
Grace?
I didn't have time.
So what are you doing now?
I'm sure they're still open.
I still don't feel well.
I'll do it tomorrow.
Do it today.
Here. Take.
Well, get up.
- I've been calling you.
- I've been busy.
But all week you haven't been
taking my calls.
Mr. Vincent, what do you want?
Nothing, nothing.
I was just worried.
- Are you angry?
- No. No, I'm not angry.
I'm sorry, please.
Have you fixed your light?
I brought you some bulbs.
Thank you.
Come on, let me fix it for you.
I haven't heard from you in a while.
Mr. Vincent, please,
I've got too much on my mind.
- What is wrong?
- Don't worry about it, it's not your problem.
Am I not here?
Please, talk to me.
- I need money.
- For what?
- Mr. Vincent, I said don't worry.
- No, wait, wait.
How much?
What if I ask you not to pay
this month's rent?
No!
What if I ask you to pay half?
Mr. Vincent, no, thank you.
You have to choose one.
I'm only trying to help.
If I agree, the condition is
that I'll pay you back next month.
Okay.
See, what I want is for us
to trust each other.
You need any help, ask me.
And if I can, definitely I will.
- What are you doing?
- They were closed.
Why are you like this?
Huh? I ask you to do something
and you can't even do it.
- But I told you they were closed and you said...
- You've had the entire week!
And what about school?
You'd better start behaving yourself
or I'll send you back.
Are you hearing me?
Afternoon. We came for a check-up.
What if he can't pay?
We'll dispose of them.
Grace, your folate levels are low.
I'm concerned.
Have you been taking your medicine?
I can't stress how important it is
for you to take your medicine.
You're risking the health of your baby
if you don't.
What's going on?
Grace?
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
I didn't mean it, OK?
Grace, I said I'm sorry.
You need to start taking your medication.
Promise you'll take them?
Alright, gimme a smile.
It's 5,000.
Card?
Take.
Thank you.
Hello, Mommy.
No, no, it's fine.
We're OK.
She's fine, you want to talk to her?
Hello?
Mommy?
I'm fine.
School is fine.
How is everybody?
Mom, Rosa wants her phone.
I'll call you back when I get credit.
Hello, Mommy. I have to get going.
I'm late for work.
Yes, Mom, take care.
- Hi.
Sorry to disturb, I'm closing soon.
Can I get the bill?
Yeah, sure.
Actually, can I get one more whiskey?
- Here.
- Thanks.
Here you go.
- Current or savings?
- Current.
I'm still getting used to this.
Are you from "Lahgos"?
What?
Lagos.
No, I'm from Abeokuta.
I'm not even going to try to say that.
- You're American.
- Yeah.
But you look Lebanese.
My parents are Lebanese.
I thought so.
We have a lot in Nigeria.
I know.
- Cheers.
- This is...
- Rosa.
- Ready?
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
- Oh, wait.
So sorry, I forgot to tip.
Thank you.
So, you're getting off soon right?
Yes.
You want to hang out
with me and my friends?
No, it's fine.
It's completely fine.
She can hang, right?
It's okay, really.
Really, it's fine.
Thank you though.
Alright...
If you want, I can give you my number.
- Yeah?
- Why not.
Hey, how are you?
Is your mom home?
- Aunty Blessing is here.
- Who?
- Blessing.
- Who is Aunty Blessing?
Mercy, baby!
My baby girl for life!
- So good to see you! You look great!
- Aunty, I'm just managing.
Shut up! What do you mean managing?
You look wonderful!
These are my friends.
- Come in, come in, come in, come in.
- Thank you.
- I like your dress.
Mercy, Mercy. Please, what can I get you?
Coke, Fanta?
- Anything.
- Lucia!
Go and get some Cokes, my love.
Make sure she doesn't break
my expensive glass.
So you're the one that's pregnant?
Yes.
- How many months?
- Almost four.
- And the two of you want to go to Italy?
- Yes.
That's good. I'm just coming back.
My husband is there.
- Have you got papers?
- Yes.
- Lucia, go and play.
- Thank you.
- Have you started prenatal?
- Yes.
Next time you come,
bring her medical report.
Okay, give me your number.
00...
32...
400...
206.
As soon as I get the visas,
I'll call you.
I've been doing this a long time...
Mercy will tell you
I've been doing this a long time.
He's American.
He went to school there.
He's cute.
- Does he have any friends?
- At your age!
- You know what your clothes look like?
- What?
Death.
- They're not nice.
- What about yours?
Grace, look at me,
learn from the best.
- Colour riot.
- It is not colour riot.
And the nice ones aren't yours.
Can you wear your sister's dress?
Has she got more?
Grace, Grace, see this one.
- Do you want her to kill me?
- She won't do anything, try this dress.
Blue colour plus your brown eyes
gives you blue-brown.
Take it from me, girl.
Turn.
No, show your face.
Put your hand behind your hair.
Yes.
What's up?
You guys doing a photo shoot?
What's up, baby?
Can I join?
How exactly?
Take a picture of us on Snapchat.
Grace.
Look how fine she is.
That's enough.
Take another one.
- Did you save it?
- Sure, pal.
What's the rush?
- I have somewhere to go to.
- Wait.
Relax.
Let me buy something
for you and your friend.
Anything you want,
I'll get for both of you.
You want something to eat?
I cut her in on this deal I was working on,
nothing major just a little forex thing.
She stood to make 10, maybe 15 US,
which isn't bad for a few months' work.
So the meeting's set.
We're about to close, and she calls to cancel.
You know what she says?
I have to go and see my "Uncle".
He's the one who sponsored my education.
You know what that means!
You should've known that
before you brought her in.
- You should've seen the signs.
- There was nothing I could do.
These people, you can show them
all the income statements you want.
It doesn't make any difference.
They're mostly interested
in working with someone...
who's willing to offer
a little extra on the side.
Put her in a tight dress next time
you pitch and see what happens.
Luckily, we were far enough along that we
managed to get it closed and move on.
Last time though. I can tell you that
for free. Never again.
Sounds to me like you
didn't have enough money.
15K is not that much money.
You should take the first bite.
Let me know what you think.
- And?
- What's this please?
It's tofu.
You'd don't like it?
No? How could you not like it.
It's so good. I love tofu.
Can we please have a menu.
We're going to order something else
with this as well.
- We don't need to order something else.
- It's fine.
Just the menu.
Please.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
I can't believe you don't like this.
- There's no pepper.
- No pepper?
Yeah and it just tastes like grass.
It's not grass.
It's broccoli, mushrooms, corn.
Grass.
- Is that a plantain?
- Yes.
Look at this one.
Good evening, sir.
Good evening, how are you?
- Good evening.
- Good evening, sir.
- Are you going to eat that?
- No.
I think our fridge is broken.
- Can I see it?
- Yes.
It's not cooling again.
But my friend can fix it for you.
- Yes, please.
- Alright.
Let's help him.
Good evening.
- You want to charge?
- No, I'm fine, thank you.
That's our fridge.
Oh, please. Sorry for the delay.
I'll work on it next.
It's fine, thank you.
So are you going to fix everything here?
Yes.
Did someone teach you?
I just understand it.
- Should I turn on the sound?
- Can you?
Of course!
- Enjoy.
- Thank you.
Grace?
How are you?
I'm fine.
You sure?
For me?
Wow, thank you so much.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Bring it, I'll keep it inside.
Thank you.
Oh, you're smiling now.
We ate on the roof.
I don't understand.
It was a restaurant, and I could see
the whole of Lagos from there.
What about the mall?
What don't they have there?
Clothes, electronics, food.
I wish you had seen it.
Grace, go out.
Good afternoon, sir.
- How are you?
- Fine.
- Have I not been taking care of you?
- You have.
So why are you disgracing me like this?
How am I disgracing you?
Rosa, take your time.
Take your time, I'm not a fool.
Why can't you love me?
What's wrong with you? Stop now!
What's all this?
So now you have somebody else
and you don't want me again, right?
Okay, no problem,
let him take care of you.
But I don't want you to call me again
for anything, understand?
Don't. Call. Me!
It's so tall.
It's similar to the building I told you about,
where I'll be visiting.
Have a look.
This is it here.
I know it's great, right?
I can't wait.
When are you going back?
I don't know. I need another 10,000
before I can apply for the visa.
Naira?
No, dollars. U.S. dollars.
The money has to be in your account
before they'll agree.
I was hoping I could get the money here,
but man, these guys aren't fools.
- Is it Seyi?
- Hell no!
No, I don't play with people like that.
He'll be looking at you like you're nobody,
but he'll still be looking at you.
I thought I was the only one
that felt that way.
If you make the mistake
of letting him sleep with you,
you're on your own.
My father is in the hospital,
and they won't treat
him until they get paid.
Maybe you can help?
You guys got it all wrong.
Yeah, we got it all wrong.
Just because she calls you daddy
doesn't mean she's your daughter.
I officially hate you.
We're done. We're done.
Has she asked you if you
can help pay her tuition
before she's kicked out of college?
Or her brother's application fee?
The best is when they say that they need
money to maintain themselves for you.
What's wrong with getting maintained?
This... all of this doesn't just happen.
There are levels.
You and her are not the same.
I can't believe
we are having this conversation.
Has she said,
"Please, could you buy me a smartphone
so I can send you better pictures?"
- No, you did not!
- Oh my God!
It wasn't an iPhone or anything.
I get here. It takes me forever
to get my luggage...
because everybody just like swarms...
People like shove each other
out of the way here to grab things.
- Welcome to Lagos.
- I noticed it yesterday in one of the cabs.
This lady just like shoved this man
out of the way to jump into a cab.
And...
That's how they push
people around in Lagos.
Anyway, so I grab my luggage,
and I'm on my way towards the exit.
And there's like these tables set up
with these army looking guys, right?
I guess they're your Customs people.
- If you guys have Customs...
- We have Customs in Nigeria.
Now? You didn't have them before?
We've always had Customs.
Doesn't every country?
I don't know.
Things seem different here.
So the guy is missing an eye,
and he points me out...
Sorry.
Why don't you just pick up the phone?
Don't worry about it.
So the Customs person...
The guy that was at the table.
He points me out and goes, "You!"
I go to him, and he doesn't look in my bag.
He just asks me what's in the bag.
You didn't open it for him?
He didn't open bag.
He just asked me what was in there.
I was like, it's just clothes,
and my camera was in there and some...
you know, toothpaste or whatever.
And he goes, "What did you bring for me?"
What?
I was like, "What did I bring for you?"
I don't...
Sorry. Let me just...
Hello.
Yes.
Mr. Vincent, what do you want?
Why are you calling me,
I don't understand.
No, I'm not at home,
I'm at my aunty's house.
I'm not angry.
No, I'm not.
When I come back.
Mr. Vincent, when I come back.
Bye bye.
Sorry about that.
It was my sister.
Everything alright?
Yes.
So...
What happened to the phone
that I bought you?
I gave it to my sister.
I hope you're not annoyed?
No, I just...
- Was it for her from the get-go?
- Yes.
Why didn't you just tell me
it was for her from the beginning?
Because I didn't want you thinking
that maybe I was just using you.
It's fine. It's fine.
I think it's actually really nice
that you did that for her.
Thank you.
Can I ask a favour?
Yeah, of course.
I really need help with my rent.
I swear I wouldn't you ask
if I had another option.
I'm having issues with my landlord.
Right...
- You know what, don't worry.
- No, it's fine.
I'm sorry, I was just...
My mind went somewhere else.
Your rent? Just your rent?
- Just my rent.
- Okay.
It's because of my landlord,
I don't want...
I get it. I understand.
I know it's hard.
Just let me know how much you need,
I'll take care of it.
- Are you serious?
- Yeah.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
I know it's rough.
It's all good.
Thank you.
How long did you say
you've been having these headaches?
For a week.
Okay...
If it persists or gets worse,
come back immediately and see us.
Okay.
But, Grace,
you really need to take it easy.
Okay.
Do you want to know the sex
of the baby?
Yes.
It's a girl.
- You're not changing your mind, right?
- No.
Okay, now...
You'll take an oath before
the baby is born.
But I want you to swear
that you'll give it to me.
- The baby?
- Yes.
- Okay.
- What?
I swear.
Swear on this.
I swear I'll give you my baby.
Now, don't touch that money.
You'll put some hairs from your privates,
some blood and one passport picture inside.
Now?
Not now.
When you're at eight months,
we'll seal the oath.
Take.
Alright, get going.
For transport.
Hi, I'm Peter.
Please leave a message.
Come here.
Where are you going?
I want to undo some of my hair.
Is that how you greet?
So you don't know how to greet?
They didn't teach you
how to greet in your house?
- Sorry, good afternoon.
- What did you come to do?
I've come to loose my braids.
Rosa!
- You're finally ready to remove it?
- Yes.
Yeah, the hair is tired.
Good afternoon.
Perfume? Body spray?
Good afternoon. Perfume?
Body spray? Powder?
- Do you like this one?
- How much is it?
2,000.
- What's your last price?
- 2,000.
2,000? No lower?
- It declined.
- The card?
Please, can you try again?
It's going.
Am I getting it?
Let me show you.
Do like this...
Tolu!
- Do you not have homework to do?
- I finished.
Then go sweep the floor.
Can't you see the house is dirty?
And you?
Don't you think you should be lying down?
Come.
Can anyone else attend to us, please?
Onyinye! Onyinye!
Why are you shouting my name?
Is there another doctor on duty?
Please, it's very urgent.
What's wrong with her?
My sister's bleeding from her privates.
- Just come.
- Thank you.
Thank you.
Doctor, they said you want
to keep her overnight.
Yes, so we can monitor her.
She's okay,
but her blood pressure is high.
I completely understand that,
but can I pay tomorrow?
I've been coming here for a long time
and Dr Ojo normally attends to us.
She knows.
Everybody here knows...
I don't ever delay on payments.
It's true.
You can be sure that I'll pay.
- First thing tomorrow morning. Understand?
- Yes.
First thing, or we remove her...
Hello? I'm on the street,
I don't know...
I've seen you.
- Good afternoon.
- How are you?
- Fine.
You called me.
Mr. Vincent, please,
I need your help.
- What'd you say?
- I need your help, please.
You need my help?
Is that why you called me?
- Please, mr. Vincent.
- Is that why you called me?
Mr. Vincent, Grace is in the hospital.
Please, I don't know what to do anymore.
I beg you, in the name of God.
Please, I know I treated you badly. I'm sorry.
Let me ask you, do you think I'm a fool?
That all you need from me is just help.
When you need money,
that's when you come to me, right?
Mr. Vincent,
I'm sorry for everything I did.
I've tried everything.
I can't raise her hospital bills,
and I don't want anything
to happen to her.
So now you remember Mr. Vincent, the fool?
The one you always get money from
and treat how you like?
Like some piece of dirt on the street.
I'm sorry.
Mr. Vincent, please, for the sake of God...
Don't do it for me, do it for Grace.
Loan me the money, don't give it to me.
Loan it to me and I'll pay you back.
Let me tell you something,
I can always help you...
It's not about the money.
But when you start to treat me as though...
I'm nothing.
Because you found somebody else,
and then you started to treat me
however you like...
Now you've come for help?
I'm sorry.
So Grace is in the hospital?
Good morning.
There's a problem.
It's supposed to be 30,000.
- Oh, we had to give her blood.
- Blood?
For what? Why?
Where is my sister?
Can I see my sister?
Calm down, let me call the doctor.
Doctor, why is Grace receiving blood?
I was here yesterday and she was fine.
Grace is fine. She's okay,
she lost some blood...
so we had to give her a transfusion.
But she's better now.
- She is okay?
- She is okay.
- Can I see her?
- Not immediately, she's in recovery,
but in a little while
you should be able to see her.
Lucia, please be careful.
Yes, mom.
Good afternoon.
After all the time and money
I wasted on you two...
I'm sorry.
It's not about sorry. We have a problem.
Sit down.
Thank you.
- So, do you still want to travel?
- Yes.
- Are you sure?
Good. Because I want you to travel.
You know I promised to take care of you,
and I like to keep my promises...
but our agreement was
I would have your sister's baby
in exchange for transport over there.
But as it is, no baby,
I've wasted so much money.
I paid for your visas!
I need to know that, if you travel,
I will be paid back.
- I can't.
- I know.
You will work for me,
and I will take it out of your salary.
What about my sister?
She will work, or do you want
to pay for her as well?
Come in, come in.
What can I get you?
Nothing, I'm fine. Thank you.
I wish you called, I would have
arranged the whole place.
- Sit down.
- It's okay.
Mr. Vincent...
If I marry you, you have to promise
to take care of my family.
Grace has to go to a private school.
And you'll open a shop for me
to sell clothes.
And you'll really be my wife?
You will love me, cook for me,
clean the house, all those things?
Yes.
Sit down.
I promise you, I will take care
of you and your family.
So what can I get you?
Nothing, I'm okay.
No, you have to have something.
I'll get you something.
Hi.
- Let me know next time you go out.
- Okay.
- What's this?
- Money.
From where?
I sold my phone.
- That one.
- This one?
But it's not going to be too big?
The same size as this,
and make sure it's straight.
Don't worry,
I'm going to make you happy.
If it's not straight,
I'll go somewhere else.
I'm going to make you happy,
don't worry.
It's my work, it's my job.
Engineer, welcome back.
How are you?
What about business?
Where's Wisdom?
Wisdom? At your house.
Do you mind staying?
I'll be right back.
- No problem, take your time.
- I'm coming back.
- Welcome.
- Good evening, sir.
Let me get back to work.
Later, Aunty.
Blessing, see you.
- Sorry, I'll be back.
- No problem, boss.
- How's work?
- It's okay.
Is that enough?
This okay?
How is it?
- Good, right?
- Yeah, it's good.
Well done.
Thank you.
Are you here all night?
Mostly, sometimes it's Wisdom.
Well, I'm happy you're doing well.
Thank you.
Mofe...
your father is sick.
So you've come for money.
No, we haven't.
Mofe, listen to me.
We didn't come for money.
Your father is already better.
He'll be out of the hospital soon.
We came here because...
Mofe, we're broke.
We've spent everything.
My money, his money,
even Blessing's money.
Mofe, we don't have anything again.
- I beg you.
- Please get up, get up.
Mofe, I beg you, take my son from me.
I can't.
If he comes back with me,
there's nothing there for him.
It's only me here.
I work for myself.
Why should I take care
of my father's children?
The first time he saw Precious' children
was when we came to bury them.
And you want me to
take care of his children?
Never!
Thank you.
Mind your bags.
Aunty, here's a little money.
Blessing, help your mother.
What about power?
When you're ready, we'll tap it.
You don't like it?
Should I show you another one?
Yeah.
Alright, let's go.
Hey, don't forget to close up.
It's ready.
Try it and see.
I know you're going to like it.
Now put it on.
We know what we're doing here.
Boss.
Come, take a look.
What do you think?
Good work.
Hello?
Hey, Aunty.
No, sorry, I was busy.
Yes.
Thank you, thank you, I'm fine.
Generator.
No, no, it's Wisdom I'm talking to.
Oh, no, it's no problem, no problem.
Truly, Aunty, it's no problem.
I hope it's not too
late for him to register.
We thank God.
If there's anything else he needs,
like books or anything else...
just let me know.
And I'll be checking in from time to time.
Bye bye.