Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
INSPIRED BY TRUE EVENTS
Oh fig Pickers
Leave the best fig for your beloved
And he who eats but doesn't pick And he
who eats but doesn't pick
Throw the lot over his head
We are late. The Sheikh will be upset!
Help me up.
Farha!
- Come on!
- Hurry.
Farha, come on
FARHA
IN PALESTINE, 1948
''If you do not aid him,
Allah has already aided him
when the unbelievers had driven him out as
one of two when they were in the cave.''
''And he said to his companion: 'Do not
grieve...'''
grieve. Indeed, Allah is with us.'''
''And Allah sent down his tranquility
upon him...
and supported him with angels you
did not see and made the unbelievers...''
''And made the word...''
''And made the word of the
unbelievers...''
''The lowest.''
''the lowest, while the word of Allah is
the highest.''
''And Allah is Exalted in Might and Wise.''
To God Almighty has spoken the truth.
Today, I will dismiss you earlier, girls.
As you know, tomorrow is Suad's
Henna Night.
I hope to officiate all your weddings
soon.
Or better to hope that we have a
school in the village, just like the boys.
You may all go now.
- How are you, dear?
- Good.
Pass my greetings to the mayor.
I will see him later.
Go, my daughter.
- Don't go too far from the house.
- Yes, Mother.
I can't believe you're finally here.
Me neither. If only I could live here.
Why would someone from the city want
to live here?
What's here in the village?
A few sheep?
There are trees, birds...
And you.
Listen...
Don't you dare come live here. What
if it works out and I go live in the city?
I'd kill you. Really, I would!
Imagine if I were to go to school in the
city?
I would have a school bag and
notebooks and pencils.
We would go to school together in the
car.
Speaking of school.
Any updates from your father?
I still don't know... I'm
hoping to find out today.
- Aren't those the English?
- Looks like it.
Go! Good riddance!
- How do you say that in English?
- I don't know... Maybe ''goodbye''?
Goodbye. Goodbye!
Look at the mess you’ve made! Even
while leaving!
- Get out of here! Go away!
- Out!
Wait for me!
I shot an Englishman!
What weapons? And what armed men?
You speak as if we have a real army.
Fully equipped with machines guns,
tanks, planes.
All we have are a few rusted weapons
and dud bullets.
Some bullets are even filled with wax.
Welcome Farha. My God, my God!
- I wouldn't recognize you in the street.
- How are you, uncle?
Great, now that I see you!
Yes, Farha is all grown up.
Now, it's time to see her as a bride.
Come on... She is still young.
Father, school registration
will close by the end of next week.
My dear, we already discussed this.
Now is not the time. Serve your uncle tea.
Thank you very much.
Thanks. Set it down on the table. I'll
drink soon.
Thank you for your hospitality, Abu
Farha.
- Sameeha! Where are you?
- I'm coming.
Hurry, so you can leave before it gets
dark.
Come on sister, faster.
You're leaving before receiving proper
hospitality.
Certainly not.
You've been more than generous.
You know how much I like talking with
you.
But you know the situation.
Our mother is sick and the roads are
not safe nowadays.
It's better to get there before sunset.
I hope your mother feels better soon.
And try to visit us more often, not once
every two months!
God willing. Listen. Take it easy on the
girl.
So what if she wants to get an
education?
What could happen? Educating the
young is like engraving in stone.
Well... We do not want to go against
the flow.
Let me find her a husband who can take
care of her in these circumstances.
Besides, you are the only one encouraging
her. She is already very stubborn.
Listen, the newspaper I got you has the
registration paper for the city's school.
- No...
- Listen!
Think about it, but don't take too long.
There's not much time left.
I will take care of her
when she comes to the city.
Farha can take care of herself.
Wait no longer, say yes
- Hello, sister.
- I am ready to go.
You are family and your word is of great
value. You know how dear you are to us.
- I will think about it.
- Good.
Where is Farha?
We want to say goodbye!
Where are you, Farha?
Come over here, precious one.
I won't be away long.
Take care of your father.
Hopefully, everything will turn out fine.
Right... We must leave now.
Remember what we discussed. Goodbye.
Goodbye.
I won't be long.
- Next time we should play backgammon.
- So you want to lose?
- Take care. See you soon.
- God be with you!
- Thank you.
- Take care on the road.
- You're always welcome here.
- Having you with us reassures us.
Thank you.
I need your advice on a matter.
Farha is smart and she's into education.
I'm thinking of sending her to the city.
So she can study.
I don't want to disappoint her.
You've educated her.
You know her as well as me.
We discussed this, Mayor.
She should remain by your side
under these unsettling circumstance.
- The situation is not safe.
- I understand.
And what education are you talking about?
She already learned the Quran. What
else is there to learn?
Geography, history, math, English!
Farha!
Where did she get this stubbornness?
- Who is it?
- Open the door. It's me, Naser.
- Yes?
- How are you, Farha?
Good.
Here. It's food prepared by my mother
until your stepmother is back.
- Thanks.
- Wait, wait...
- So you don't know how to cook at all?
- No, I don't!
I can't see!
I can't see...!
- Did you have fun?
- Yes.
- Isn't that Naser?
- Yes... Let's go.
What were you talking about with my
uncle and his son?
Father.
Father!
- Abu Fahed!
- Hello, mayor.
- How are you?
- Fine, thanks.
What were you talking about with my
uncle and his son?
You mean your future husband?
Go ahead.
What's wrong with your cousin Naser?
And why not get married? All the
village girls are getting married.
I don't want to get married.
What? What are you saying?
Stop where you are right now!
Shame on you.
This is how she speaks to her father!
Her father, who raised her
and brought her the registration paper...
so she can study in the city.
Really, Father?
Is this for real?
Hey...?
Ah wee ha - Farha is going to the city
school!
-Ah wee ha - Farida will be over the moon
-Don't make a scene!
Get down here!
Ah wee ha, and the mayor is the best
father in the whole village
This girl will be the end of me!
- Here you go.
- Thanks.
Almost all Palestinians
in the center and to the south are now
displaced.
And they are seeking refuge elsewhere.
And ever since my family was
entrusted with this village,
all we care about is to keep the
land safe as well as people's lives.
- So this is your final decision, mayor?
- I've said everything I have to say.
We welcomed you in our home and we
respect you as our esteemed guests.
Come on, men. We have no more time
to waste!
Abu Nimer! Listen to me.
I was promised that the Arab countries
will send both troops and ammunition.
It's better that we wait. When they arrive,
I will head this army myself.
- And I will be the first one to fight.
- This isn’t a truce. They are buying time.
Eventually, your land will turn into
ashes.
I never expected that you would let us
down. Goodbye!
I hope your troops don't take too long,
Abu Farha!
REGISTRATION PAPER:
FARHA, SCHOOL YEAR 1948/1949
Father?
Farha, why are you up so early?
What are you doing, Father?
I'm filling the gaps between the stones.
And mud holds the stones together.
Don't you want to go back to sleep?
I forgot to tell you, my father said yes.
- Really? For sure?
- Yes.
I can't believe it!
- Is something wrong?
- No, it's nothing.
You don't seem happy.
Of course I'm happy.
But I'm worried about my father.
It will be difficult to leave him.
That's all.
But he won’t be alone.
- I know why you're upset.
- Why?
- You lost the groom!
- Hey!
Enough! No, no. Stop!
I'll be quiet.
- Don't worry. He'll wait for you.
- Farida!
Fine, fine. Enough, I'll stop!
You know what I have decided?
When I finish studying in the city,
I want to become a teacher.
Then I open a school here in the village,
and only for girls.
When I grow up, I want to become...
Have mercy on your women and
children and save them from this bloodbath.
Get out of this village while you still
can.
Oh God! Oh God!
Go away! Get out of here!
Run! Run!
Get out by using the north road while
it's still open.
Are you hurt?
Where have you been? Let's go!
Farida! Farida, are you OK?
We must hurry! Go!
- Get in the car!
- Where's my father?
- Did you see my father?
- We will look for him. Get in, Farha!
Get in! Where are you going?
Hey! What are you doing?
Masoud!
Masoud! Please take care of her.
-Get in the car
-You heard your father.
No, Father.
My daughter, get inside now!
Are you OK, Farha?
From where are they coming in?
They surrounded the village from all
sides. Only the north exit is still open.
Go north, to Khallet Al Taweel.
I'll be behind you.
I'm not leaving you.
I'll secure the family, go to the other
village heads and come back for you.
Kamel!
- Look out. Look out!
- Calm down.
- Stop the car, uncle.
- There is no time!
- Let me out!
- Stay here!
- Farha, stop it!
- I have to stay with my father!
- Oh God!
- Take the women!
Farha!
- Farha! Farha!
- What are you doing? Get in!
Farha!
Why did you come back...
- Father?
- Farha!
- What's this, father?
- The village has fallen.
Where should we go?
What shall we do?
What are you doing?
Are we going to Farida's?
Farida... I told you to go with Masoud,
but you did not listen!
Are we going to the city?
Where should we go...?
Why didn't you listen to me?
- Come with me.
- Where are we going?
There is no time for food. We have to
go!
- We should follow them.
- Go in and wait for me.
- No.
- I will come back to get you.
- Do you understand?
- I will stay with you.
- I will be back.
- I want to stay with you, father.
It's not possible.
I will not repeat myself. Do as I tell you.
Come on. Get in!
No, I won't!
Don't be afraid. I'll come back for you.
There's no time for this!
- Listen...
- Father...?
- This is the safest place.
- Then stay with me!
I can't! I have to be with the people.
The soldiers have invaded our village.
Please, understand.
- No, Father!
- Calm down.
Wait here for me.
I'll come back to get you.
Don't be afraid. I won't be long.
Keep this with you.
Do you hear me?
- Father!
- I will not leave you.
Stay with me!
Farha...
I will be back.
Stay inside.
Do not be afraid.
Father...?
Father?
TO MY DEAREST FRIEND, FARHA
FROM FARIDA
Father...?
Get out now!
Take the boy and move fast!
REGISTRATION PAPER:
FARHA, SCHOOL YEAR 1948/1949
Ah wee ha
Farha is going to the city's school
Farida will be over the moon
Ah wee ha...
Come on...
There's a place here. Come on.
- Quiet. Keep it low...
- I can't!
Sit down here.
Take your sister and give her water.
It will be over soon.
Push! Push! Come on...
Keep it low!
I can see the head.
It'll be fine.
Push a little more!
A boy... Mohammed!
Congratulations, Abu Mohammed.
Give me a stone.
God is great.
I bear witness
that there is no deity but God.
I bear witness that Muhammad
is the messenger of God.
Here, take your brother.
Abu Mohammed!
I'm in here!
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
My father left me and never came back.
I'm worried about him.
Get me out of here!
The door is there.
Fine. OK.
Move away from the door!
Keep quiet...!
Leave your houses!
If not, you will be killed!
Abu Mohammed, where are you?
Don't make a sound.
Hide the girls!
Leave your houses
with your women and children!
Go and hide on the roof...
Get out, or you will be killed.
Get outside.
Or you will be killed in the houses.
Don't move!
I'm talking to you.
Come here!
Come here.
Hands up.
- What's this?
- These are my papers.
- Clear.
- Turn!
Turn!
Do you know him?
No. He's from another village.
He's not a fighter!
Shut up!
Sir, he just came out of here.
There is nothing in this house.
You cannot find any guns.
- OK. Search the house!
- Yes.
You. Walk.
- There's nothing here.
- Keep walking!
- There is nothing here.
- Come on!
I just passed by.
I say, I just walked by!
There's nothing here.
I just wanted to drink some water.
Walk! Go on!
There's no one here.
I don't know whose house this is!
Stand there. Keep your hands up.
What's your name?
Saleh.
I'm not from this village.
I'm from Aseera.
I was passing by and wanted to drink
some water.
What's this?
What's this?!
Where are you hiding the weapons?
I don't know.
He's not from here. I told you.
He's a villager, not a fighter.
This house is not his,
and you cannot find any weapons!
OK, I'll check.
You came back for the weapons.
You know where they are.
- Search the house!
- Yes, sir.
Clear, sir.
- Clear.
- Nothing here.
Hold on. Hold on...
Look what I found!
- Let her go!
- Don't move!
- This doesn't concern women!
- Stop it!
- Search her.
- Yes, sir.
You are pregnant?
- It's always the same hiding place.
- Shut up!
A key!
Keep it as a souvenir.
- Leave her alone, you prick.
- Quiet!
- Boy or girl?
- Girl.
- A boy.
- It surely looks like a boy.
- I also say it's a boy.
- What is he saying?
What do you say? Boy or girl?
- Stop it.
- You prick!
- Wait, Wait. She's just a woman!
- Don't worry, Muyassar.
She's just a woman.
- Let them be!
- Move.
They are just children!
Mother...
Don't worry. Don't worry...
Kill me. I'm the man here.
Kill me!
So you did not hide weapons.
But you hid something else.
Saleh!
Let them go!
- Take them to the wall!
- Move. Go on!
Why are you hiding your face?
You cannot hide behind a mask.
Betrayer!
Move. Move!
What are you doing?
You promised me. No women, no children!
You asked me for weapons.
- What are you doing?
- Fine.
- In position!
- Yes...
- Take aim!
- Please, you promised me. Please...
Don't do it! They are just children.
They are not fighters.
Please!
- Fire!
- You promised me. No!
- No, no...
- What are you doing there?
- Come and help me.
- Coming...
Hurry, hurry...
Go fetch water! Instead of doing
nothing.
He’s really heavy. We need help,
please.
Farha!
No, no.
We left the baby for you.
A boy. I was right, I win.
Finish him and come.
And don't waste a bullet on it!
Don’t be late!
Little baby Mohammed Sleep in your
bed
The little bird will come in the morning
And wake you up early
I'm here close to you
Sleep peacefully
All the children in the neighborhood
slept a long time ago
TO MY DEAREST FRIEND, FARHA
FROM FARIDA
Farha never found her father and his
fate after the Diaspora remains unknown,
but it is believed that he was killed in
the events of Al-Nakba (the Catastrophe)
in 1948.
Farha (whose name is Radiyyeh in
the original events) made it to Syria,
where she shared her stoyr,
keeping it alive for generations to come.
Written and Directed by Darin J. Sallam