A mark of the music
just for the hand
You speak movements
New designs, Ekabell
You show arms
and don't be afraid to fall
You show energy
and I want to see space
And the gorbe arm
back, more back
Foot and over your foot, try
more...
That's good, good, Bunny
That's better
try the second step first
yeah, more
good, that's better
Well, do I look?
Yeah, It's over
And use you body
trying once
yeah, more, and look out
over your hands
Good
Doesrt work...
Ok, stop...
The dance is
dedicated to freedom
To every kind of freedom
Fill me upon
the flarehead before...
Here we go again
Amsterdam especially
has kept strong ties
with the liberators
How strong was shown
on Liberation Day 1980...
when the population of the
capital honored them again
It was like the 1945
"May Days" again
Only the soldiers were now
35 years older
Amsterdam was thanking with
its cheers for the Canadians
all the allies who ended five
years of war and occupation
These were my heroes
the liberators of 1945
When they came back in 1980
it was scary
It didn't look like my memory
anymore
Could you be a bit more
explicit?
Mark, shut up
What I see takes me back
to 1980
which also takes me back
to 1945
It is a memory of memories
It's the essence of what
I mean in this choreography
and I don't see it, I...
Am I make myself clear?
Ok, we start from second times
The girls on the floor
You on the middle
Just before around the same
And that's try the lift
you practiced this morning
come on
You wrong
this different from before
yeah, I'm afraid of it
Could you search original idea
for ones, please
I resisted the motion
It's your dancers the same my being so clear
you never... explain
yourself probably
You can't doing
that's your dancers, period it
thank you very much
Maybe so...
Yes, no...
there is something else
Lifesavers
Yes, Lifesavers
you know those candies
The Americans, the Canadians
had them in 1945
I want to know the color
of the wrapper
Sweet, baby
Bye
Yes. That's him
yes
He changes your whole life?
Yes
He was my stepfather
he was on the war
My hero
Is this you?
No, this is you
Little prince
Do you still remember me?
I have to pee
Not over there
Have you gone crazy?
Where else?
You were there that time
stay
I have to go back inside
Yes, I know
but I wanted to ask you
something else
Are you alright?
You'll get enough to eat
over there
Promise me you'll behave
Here, look after this
Here, write your name on it
properly
Young man, come here
Here is your sign
write your name here
So, and one for you
Write your name here
You are too late
Here, this is give you
Jan
So, they're going to
fatten you up too
Nerve gas
Keep quiet
and you'll be alright
You, Heinrich, come here
Ok, go over there
You are much too late
(foreign language)
Thanks, bye
Holly shit
Did you pee your pants?
Go away, disgusting
What is your name?
Gertie
You know what?
From now on you're called
Dirty Gertie
Shove off. Move over
Right, that's much better
We'll stick together, Ok?
I mean when we get there
Just like fucking?
We won't let them
separate us, no way
We thank you, Lord
for bringing these poor
children
who need your protection
Amen
Well, I'm sure you
want a cup of warm milk
And you as well?
Nice
Nice, isn't it?
Nice and warm
Take off your cap
Go and sit over there
We'll get the lice out
Children, now you will
go to your new homes
Sjoerd Dotinga
can you take two children?
Kees Brinkman and Tom Ophuis
So, Arjen Boersma
Arjen Boersma
and Alie Van Der Does
And Alie Van Der Does
(foreign language)
Gertie Baowie
Dirty Gertie
And Jungluca
(foreign language)
Come in
A mistake?
Yes, it can happen
We asked for a girl
You know, for Elly...
Right, come with me
They mixed up two, Ma
He was left, this is Jeroen
Alright, we'll have to make
do with him, won't we lad?
Jeroen
that's a beautiful name
You're not scared of me
are you?
Can I have a look?
Lovely...
Henk
This is Jeroen
He'll have to wear
your clothes
Fine
You must be hunger
after such a long journey
No, Mrs.
But you wouldn't say no
to a "bolle"?
Bolle?
Slice of bread
It's gone
What's gone?
My ration card
What's a ration card, Ma?
Almighty God, Our Lord
we beg you
protect Your weak children
and lead us all to
Your safe harbor
Lord, bless this meal, Amen
I hope you'll enjoy it
blast. Ma
What's the matter?
He's pissed the bed
Be quiet, watch your mouth
Amsterdam is that way
And the pump is next
to the house
Ma?
Do you all pee the bed
in Amsterdam?
What?
Do you all pee the bed
in Amsterdam?
You mean, that was an accident
Can I go first?
Look here
This is how you do it
Pull harder
Havert you done this before?
I've done a lot of rowing
Eels won't bite you, Sissy
The Wrath of God
will smite the Godless
they will be exiled
to the outermost darkness
there shall be a walling
and a gnashing of teeth
So dear Congregation
it is written
Lord God, let your light
shine over this world
the light of Liberation
Breathe deeply
It must reach your lungs
It's really healthy
And Abraham made haste to
the tent of Sara, and sayeth
Make haste. Take the
three bushels of grain
I'm going home
Take the little boat
Henk will help you
Hold it firm
Come down, Jeroen
We need your help
Still some way to go
There it is
Here it comes
Come and clean it up
here, take it
And he sayeth, Jonathan
And bring David, in order that
the King could kill David
And then?
Jan
Jeroen
Haidie
Perhaps they read
another Bible in Amsterdam
You do it, go ahead
It tickles
In the bucket, put it in
There you are
Jan
Mister. I'm Jan
A friend of
Jeroers from Amsterdam
I have to keep an eye on him
Your ration card
I found it
You can't use it here anyhow
Yes, I know
Found it?
Old Pronk says your Dad
is the best eel-fisher
in the whole area
Have you ever seen her naked
or in her knickers?
Bondien, I mean
If there were no Jerries
I'd still be in Amsterdam
They should hang them all
You mustrt hate the Germans
Your mustrt harbour hatred
that's what Dad says
Hatred is a sin
or something like that
I want to go home
Amsterdam is that way
Take the little boat
You think you're funny?
Shall we escape?
One night?
Jeroen
back home?
Keep still
Come on young man
You out and Elly in
Nice and warm
Look
Stop it, Elly
That's enough
Elly, that's enough
Dear Mum and Dad
I'm fine. Enough food at last
I miss you both
Hurry up
Jeroen...
Jeroen, come
it's dangerous there
Quicksand
Come back
Idiot, you could be hurt
Go over there
I don't allowed you come here
next time
Idiot
Come on, show me your plane
Not this boat, it's Dad's
Come on, stop moaning
Not so hard
We should have waited for Henk
Mama's boy You should have
brought your little sisters
Catch
when I pull twice on the rope
pull me up
Understood?
43,44,45...
46,47,48...
Jan. Jan, come on. Jan
Dammit, eels everywhere
as thick as my wrist
I do nothing all day
but clean up shit
sheep shit, goat turds
cows hit
All sorts of shit
and they shit harder
than I can clean
and that's what keeps nature
growing and blooming?
The things we eat, yuk
know what you're thinking of
The big escape... True?
True?
Row back home
just along the coast. Easy
Well forget it, I'm not in
Come on, boy
Watch out. Mercy
Mercy. Fight
boy. Say it
Do you get a hard-on
sometimes?
A hard-on?
Oh yes, of course
Liar
Have you gone nuts or what?
How did you know we are here
Turn it on and go home
What did you see?
Why ask him?
So, what was it?
Wouldrt you like to know?
Secret, Jeroen?
I'll tell you later
I will tell you later
Those bloody Jerries
they should be smoked cut
The Americans have already
crossed the river Meuse
Stop, These bikes are complete
Come on Elly
go home, we'll keep going
Bloody Jerries
If I catch them...
They must be running
into the field
There's Dad's boat
Are we going the right way
Jan?
Be quiet
Are you sure?
Course, You see
it's getting better already
Let's get out of here
We're liberated
The war is over
Call that an army?
The Yanks
have women soldiers, too
I saw in pictures
They wear skirts very tight
But how can they fight?
Women aren't there to fight
Are you coming, Jan?
Here, take it
It doesn't work
I don't know
what's wrong with it
Did you check this fuse?
I don't know
You have old enough to know
right?
And you are real wise guy, too
anyway, listen to
all nice people
you say good night
good night
ok, that's quiet for me
Anyway, without
further introduction
Ladies and gentlemen
all the way from Canada
and sing for you tonight
our own... inevitable...
Harmonizes
Thank you the way, boys
You call them soldiers?
Don't doubt
Just look
Master, "sh'boom"
what does that mean?
Cigratte?
Cigratte
yeah
Sure, here
Pastor, "Sh'boom"
doesn't mean anything
Guess, he doesn't smoke
What are you thinking of?
Get on
Are you making fun with me?
I'm Walt, Walt
What's your name?
Jeroen
Jeoroen
Yes, sir
Taste good?
Really small?
Just like little foot
You know Galileo Travels?
What is the name of place
the Giant live?
It was... Bradingo?
Bradinlan...
Couldrt you assholes wait?
That was probably fuck up
for good
Jeroen...
Jeroen
There you are
No car
I'll walk you home
Walt
Come and sit down
Jeroen
You all sit down
to show us about t
Idiots
All they understanding
Would have everybody know
(Warning)
Jeroen
No mind
here, come
You... a soldier
Yes, I'm a soldier
Hold on
And you know what?
I hated the army
But I just doing that
just like...
My mother was proud of me
She cried
My father, he just
call me an idiot
And he start crying, too
War and me
I'm very happy so far
And I saw you
I sure you was different
I sure you may a kind guy
So what guy are you?
You special, Jeroen
You are really fuck special
Look there. Walt
The only ship I knew my home
by father in the bottle
Have you look telescope before?
You know sometime you can see
the face the enemy with it
Look the same face as us
But around in other side
That's not a good idea
Look there, a plane
That's our plane
Two seats, too slow
Poor guys
You and me... Sunday...
after Church?
Go to look at the plane
What did he say?
Forget it
They took the key away
Shit
I giving something inside room
you wait here
Shut up
Want to play?
Ok
That's fifty-fifty
Wait a minute
You try this
finest Virginia leaves
you'll never taste better
hello
How's my buddy?
Walt?
What is "buddy"?
"Buddy", that's you
That's best friend
My baby...
You know "Baby"?
No
I just...
you are my baby
He drove the fucking jeep
What does he say?
Maybe we have to walk home
Jeroen
Are you so cold?
You know how cold it is?
I've got a secret
Me too. Mine first
ok
Push and pull... your dick
I can join the Yanks
Then I'll see something
Coca Cola, fucking, so on
And go to Jerryland?
Not me
The water hurts my soar. Damn
Has it already healed?
Show me
first pay
like with a tart
So what's your secret?
No, not now
Tell it, boy
Speaking
Too late, Winne too said
but the Sperm already went ahead
Tell it, tell it or beg for mercy
No, never
Jeroen, come on
we've to go to Church
Push and pull, push and pull
We must believe the Bible
Those are ours
Thank you bring the freedom
thank you, Amen
thank you
Before we close this
Thanksgiving service
I want to give you
a word of warning
concerning the new guests here
our brave liberators
These healthy young lads
We have the side of the weak
The body has attractive
with us
Dear believers, be watchful
Protect your family
and daughter
Let us look to Him
our shepherd
He'll lead us from traps
drive the plage away
as He saved His Egyptian sons
so will there be salvation
for us
The old scripture tells
of this in the Revelations
And so let us serve the Lord...
The Lord is my shepherd...
Do you remember
what we make yesterday?
Do you remember? At beach
Yes
You still want to go see that
I'll meet you later
at the beach
see you
I have to...
You better come here
I've seen it Jeroen
and I noticed it earlier
We're not used to
that kind of thing here
Come on
It's wrong to keep the candy
you're given for yourself
The Lord says
Give unto your neighbor
and you shall receive
the Kingdom of God
You're right
It's hard to get in there
There are bodies down there
you know that?
They are holding
the seat belts
Still in parachute side
Do you understand, Jeroen?
Do you understand me?
Look, fish...
I should stay there
You see the plane was there
And when the current goes
it moves
And it sinks again
just like submarine
you know
Don't be scary
I'd take care of you
I'll right here
Don't rushing
You gonna like go smoothly
That's right
Now, smile
You got treat it gently
like a horse
Watch the breaks
Here they are
Crazy
Right, baby, kick
I love you
Check of the couple bodies
sign up the wreck
I want you ready for
a could pick them up, ok?
Aye, sir
Ran over my toes
You making fun with me
Cut it out
my button, my button
No
Where is it?
Don't worry, I fixed
I promise
I love you
My prince
You are mine
Come on
What did you favorite?
We do like this
one, two, three, four
And than say ok
one, two three, four
chocolate
I wish I were a boy
my Dad and Mum here asked for
a boy from Amsterdam
one, two, three, four
Please, don't forget your name
on the top
And we'll title it
"The Liberation"
when you're ready
make a nice drawing with it
Try to write neatly
You've got all afternoon
children
Write what the Liberation
means for you
The re-gaining of Freedom
the victory over evil
Not everyone in history
can be witness
to such an important event
For me, Liberation means
Have you heard news
from home yet, Jeroen?
How are your parents?
There is enough food
in Amsterdam now, son
Don't worry
The whole Netherlands
are liberated
This is a historical moment
Maybe the most important
in your life
You won't ever forget that
young man?
No, sir
You can go now, son
Yes, sir
Bye, Jeroen
Bye, sir
At last
Get your clogs and come along
We waited specially for you
Walt said to
Moving, the young
Dad, what's a photo?
A picture
Moving a bit, little more
Henk
Here Ma, your high heels
You ok?
You stand there
Smile, Jeroen
You are not here
That's me, there
You see, me
yeah, that's him
Catch
Put it at his neck
you will be remember
Really?
Walt, this is very special
yeah, come on, Walt
Come on, everyone smile
You have beautiful hands
Jeroen
You could be an artist
You could be painter or sculptor
You know? When I was your age
I was in American
We just have neighbor
Tell you and said
My hands make with my mind creative
You are like them
Shut up, I busying
You know?
Life's worse then you dead
I left
You make me happy, Jeroen
just past these days
Do't do that, Jeroen
Shit
Throw away
don't worry, you and me
always on, yes?
Yeah, we make ones, sometime
It's late
Yes, then?
You tell Jeroen, tomorrow...
You... soldier, Canada
Friend
Thanks
Yes
God bless
Beautiful, isn't it?
Gorgeous
yes
You know what he said then?
I love you
And then he came very close
but I told him, No
What are you laughing at?
What's that?
Gertie's going out
with a soldier
This is a farewell present
Mind your own business, Elly
Little girls have big ears
Farewell present?
Get out of the way
Are you ok?
Are you hurt?
Walt...
My photo
What have you done with it?
Bloody boy
you're a bike-thief
And now it's broken too
then Moses stretched his hand
over the sea
the waves parted
And Israelites were able to cross
but when Pharaoh's army
followed
the waves came together again
and drowned them
Wake up, Jeroen
A letter from your mother
Maybe she'll come
and visit you
There you are
Read it out, boy
we're so curious to know
Jeroen darling
how big you are
You look so well
I missed you so
I'll never let you go again
You should know
I'm off to America
Can I open it, Mrs.?
It's for you
It's almost 300 years old
folks, look here
Nice, isn't it?
What a nice watch
Your tea, madam
He has grown a lot, hasn't he?
We're very grateful to you
It's nothing
It was just our duty
This beautiful present
It reconciles us
to the farewell
Jeroen has become like
our own child
And now we have to hurry
otherwise you'll miss the boat
Yes, it's a long journey ahead
I'll pack his things
He won't fit into this anymore
I know
that's why I put these in
He lived in these pants
Military thread
He learnt them at school
A souvenir
Isn't that nice?
I found these things here
They belonged to
one of the Canadian soldiers
Maybe you could take them
for Jeroen
For later, we don't use
this kind of thing
Amsterdam. Here we go
I love you
Come on, Jeroen
We have to hurry up
Bye
Jeroen
will you send us a photo?
You were going to ask me
something
That photo
I didn't hear Dad ask for that
Yes, I did
I heard
but I wanted to forget it
It was the only photo on the
whole roll that came out
Forget the step...
Use your basis of energy
Use your personal energy
Think of... let I told you
Think the freedom, It's all up
Ok, you mark this
Make me happy
Alright?
Let I see
who's the new generation
Done it
And you both...
ok, here we go
you spire great
Just rehearsal
Alright, you concentrate
Here we go
The end