HIDDEN KISSES
- The end of the street will do.
- OK.
- How's my gear?
- If it's a geeks get-together, fine!
I'm not going.
I'm pulling your leg.
You're a handsome fellow.
I don't know anyone.
It's not easy changing schools
like that, but you're doing OK.
Already invited to a party.
- Spotted any nice girls yet?
- No.
Yes, you have!
I won't be the only one late!
See you in a bit.
- 'Evening, Chief.
- Hello.
- How's it going?
- Fine.
Hello, everyone.
Very well.
Don't get up, Thierry.
- Have a guess.
- What?
- Noise.
- The party?
It had to be us! What do we do?
Wait for a second call.
Don't want to embarrass our kids.
I'd like to know
what's going on, though.
- What's that?
- Chloé's profile.
She gave me her password,
in case of emergencies.
See, you're interested too.
They're having a great time.
- Look.
- Hang on, go back...
Is that Nathan?
Is that a boy?
Is he kissing another boy?
'Morning, Dad.
All right, kid?
Chloé's mum showed me
a photo of the party.
- What's that photo about?
- Which?
You, kissing a boy.
Oh, that's with a mate of mine.
We were a bit drunk,
it was just to amuse the girls.
- Were they amused?
- Yeah.
Nathan, we have an agreement.
You can go out, but no drinking.
We agreed that, right? OK.
We'll say no more about it, then.
Get ready.
It's a nightmare!
No, don't worry.
No one can recognize you.
See you this aft?
Why?
Just five minutes
so I can give you back your scarf.
OK, I'll call you.
Nathan!
- Do you know them?
- Yeah, sort of.
From school.
They're pretty.
They're OK.
- Go over to them.
- Nah, I'm good.
Shall we go?
It's that photo.
Tell them it was a joke.
Who cares? Come on.
They're laughing at you.
Go and tell them.
If you won't, then I will.
Dad!
Stop it!
I don't understand you.
- Don't you care...
- It wasn't a joke!
When I kissed him it wasn't a joke.
- What?
- I'm going.
We're only just getting started.
Yeah, it's great
but I'm knackered.
Don't go, meet me in the garden.
I have to talk to you
What do you want?
Look at this photo of the party.
Good morning.
Yeah, the new kid.
He's kissing another boy.
Look, it's the new boy.
Let me see.
Come on, get into class.
In class, everyone.
Good morning, Maxime.
Everyone in class!
Could we, just this once,
start a class in silence?
Nathan.
All right, everyone?
Can we start?
Today we'll look at how to represent
a function graphically.
Sorry.
I shouldn't have posted that photo.
- Who took it?
- No one knows.
Who's the guy?
I'm betting it's Julien.
- Is it?
- Aude!
Aren't you interested?
The graphic representation
of a function is all the points...
Tell us, was it Julien?
- I don't remember.
- I won't tell.
I don't remember!
Nathan, don't you think
you've attracted enough attention?
- Why doesn't Julien own up?
- It's obvious!
If I was gay I'd kill myself.
- We'd know if Lucas was queer.
- Nah, I say he is.
You ever seen him with a girl?
- You neither.
- What you saying?
What you saying?
Don't you call me a queer!
I'll take you apart!
Calling me a queer!
It's not me, it's Lucas.
Fuck right off!
Just 'cause Lucas is your mate.
I've seen them,
the way they look at each other.
Lucas and Nathan.
You can see it, it's obvious.
- Yeah, it's Lucas.
- It was them, snogging.
He's a fucking queer.
What the hell's got into you?
Lucas, sit down!
You too, hurry up!
Sit down, Lucas!
Who wrote this?
The other guy is Lucas
- Nathan, your nose is bleeding.
- I'll be OK.
- Actually, can I go to...?
- OK, off you go.
I know what's going on.
We all know about that photo.
But your behavior is inexcusable.
They're accusing me.
The real one should own up.
Eh, Julien?
Not wanting to go out with you
doesn't make me queer!
Ouch!
Are you aware of your language?
"Accuse"... "Own up"...
As if you're talking about a crime.
And the word "queer" is an insult.
What?
It's not an insult, it's just a word.
For having a laugh.
Words have meaning.
They can be violent.
If he wants to be like that,
it's his choice.
You think it's a choice?
Did you choose to prefer girls?
No, I didn't choose that.
They're attracted to me!
- Can I ask you something, sir?
- Yes.
Do you prefer men?
- What makes you think that?
- You stick up for gays.
And your style is a bit...
No, forget it.
Go on.
What's wrong with my style?
She means you lack
a bit of virility.
We're going to move
our thoughts higher
and discover the other prince
of elegant English writing...
Yeah, it's Nathan.
I'm at the factory.
You'll be OK, there's no one around.
I'll wait for you.
Call me back.
- Heard about his son?
- Yeah, glad I'm not him.
- Did you tell them?
- No, nothing.
- What's wrong? You're avoiding me.
- No, I'm not.
I don't feel like talking.
- Is she coming?
- You're always on about her!
Do you blame me?
Coming for a drink, Stéphane?
- Not tonight, I'm tired.
- All right, then.
You know where we'll be.
Dad, I was just passing.
I thought we could go home together.
If you get this soon, call me.
I'm still working. Don't wait for me.
Learn your irregular verbs.
You're just as bad.
- Can I have a word, Tristan?
- Of course.
We'll look at this again.
Get to work.
- Have a seat.
- Thanks.
Right...
You know me, Tristan.
I don't tell my teachers
how to run their classes.
But parents have called
to complain that you're talking
about homosexuality.
I wasn't.
I was talking about homophobia.
I can help them
to overcome their prejudices.
No, your job is to teach English.
Then invite an anti-homophobia
association to the school.
- The students are confused...
- Are you joking?
Can you imagine the general outcry
if I did that?
I have nothing against homosexuals,
I have plenty of gay friends.
Your private life
is your own affair,
but here you're just a teacher. OK?
Thank you.
You didn't tell him about your wife?
I don't have to publish a denial.
In my class
there was another name on the board.
Nathan got some stick,
a fight started...
- What name this time?
- Marco.
I don't think it'd be him!
What does that mean?
Do you realize what you're saying?
It's just a feeling.
- I wish we could help the kid.
- It's his fault too.
He should be more discreet.
What?
- What do you think, Catherine?
- I think...
I'll do my marking
somewhere quieter!
Catherine, wait.
Catherine!
I know what you're going to ask.
The answer's no.
You can talk to Nathan.
I knew it!
So I repeat, the answer is no!
I'm sure you could help.
You're so stubborn.
I pity your poor wife.
You know what he's going through
better than most people.
I'm his maths teacher.
I can talk to him
about equations and geometry.
That's my remit!
You told me you'd hate to go
through your teenage years again.
Remember?
Maybe it wouldn't have been so bad
if a gay teacher had explained
that you weren't alone.
You don't realize
what you're asking.
What are you afraid of?
That you're outed?
The times have changed!
I don't believe it!
You straight people
think we're paranoid,
seeing homophobia everywhere.
You think a law about marriage
made it all OK?
The stuff I hear, in class,
even in the teachers' room!
You were there just then.
It was Nathan's fault
for not being "discreet"!
No, listen to me!
When I was a teenager,
school was hell.
And now I'm still in school
because all I can do is teach maths.
My family barely talk to me.
I've fought the loneliness
with my work.
I only talk about my private life
to a few close friends like you.
Because I've got 140 pupils
and 280 parents watching me,
and I'm 50
and I want some peace!
- And Nathan?
- He'll cope like I did.
He'll suffer but he'll get over it.
It's me again.
I keep getting your voicemail.
Can't we talk?
Call me.
You like that, eh?
Fucking queer
Wrong floor.
Turn it down a bit.
Why not say who the boy was?
I don't remember.
He's threatening you, right?
No one knows he's gay.
I won't give him away.
But in the meantime
you take all the stick.
School is hell, my dad ignores me
and I get insulted online.
But I don't care.
Know why? Because I'm in love.
- What are you doing?
- Telling you the truth.
- You can't be in love at your age.
- Oh, yeah?
You told me you were
at the same age.
That's...
different.
With this boy it's not serious.
I'm gay, get over it!
I'm your only son.
It's not easy.
It's not easy to have
a homophobic twat as a dad!
The other guy is Louis
I knew it was Louis, I knew it!
I spent that whole evening
in his arms.
That's enough.
You're spoiling
the atmosphere in here.
That's enough!
One more word
and I'll give you a test.
All right.
Memorized everything?
The idea is to be fast.
It makes the investigation easier.
Let's get moving.
Can I have a word?
- I'm sorry.
- You're paranoid.
A few colleagues are gossiping. So?
Do you think it changes
my opinion of you?
- I don't know, I...
- Stop.
Don't tell me I'd take it badly
if it was my daughter.
Yes, you're right.
I never saw it coming.
We got on so well.
Now that's all gone.
The way he talks to me now...
And what's wrong with me?
I never imagined
I'd take it like this.
I thought I was open-minded.
We supported each other.
When his mother died, Nathan said,
"We'll get through this, Dad."
But now...
we're like strangers.
He's still your son.
Why do you keep phoning?
I didn't write that on the board.
I know that.
It's some shit-stirrer.
I didn't need to come here.
That's not why.
I wanted to see you.
I feel so lonely.
You're there in class, but I can't...
I'm not like you.
That kiss was just an experiment.
I see.
You got my scarf?
I want to keep it.
I'm not the only one who knows.
Whoever took the photo does too.
Who are you texting?
My mum.
- Want to dance?
- No, you go ahead.
- What do you want?
- Come with me.
I'm scared too.
Is somebody there?
- Want to go in the water?
- No, you can if you want.
Come on, it's nice.
Training time, Louis.
Great legwork.
Go, go!
- Did I hurt you?
- I'm OK.
- Want to win this tournament?
- Yeah.
Then you have to work
on your weak points. Go!
It's all in your head.
That'll do for tonight.
So he said, "Corinne...
"Could I have a balance sheet
for Monday? No pressure."
No pressure,
but there goes my weekend.
How was your day?
Lumbago and so on.
Shouldn't have been
a rheumatologist!
Théo, be a good boy and eat up.
I met Laura's mum.
We talked about our lovebirds.
Oh, please!
- You are, aren't you?
- We're not married!
You're quite serious.
But no grandchildren yet!
She was telling me
about a new boy.
He's called Nathan.
- She said he's gay.
- What's that mean?
Eat your tomatoes.
- For the parents...
- Can't be easy.
Do you know him?
No. Well, just to say hello to.
Keep your distance.
Like in the ring!
You didn't see that coming!
Keep up your guard.
- Don't worry.
- "Don't worry..."
I'll show you "don't worry"!
Pass the ball!
Now the yellows attack.
Get into position.
Pass the ball.
- What got into you?
- Don't touch me!
Hands off, poofter!
- What's got into you?
- Don't touch me!
- Hey, cool it there!
What's got into you?
He doesn't touch me!
Don't answer back.
Just go outside and calm down.
You OK, Nathan?
OK, here we go.
Hey, guys, look.
This scar.
A dog bit me when I was little.
Stop showing us your muscles,
you're exciting Nathan.
The girls' changing room
is over there.
He prefers watching us in here.
Have a good look!
Stop it!
Bastard!
Take that, you queer!
Nathan, are you OK?
Hi, it's Nathan.
Leave a message.
The school phoned,
said you're absent.
I'm not mad,
I just want to know where you are.
Call me back, please.
One of the suspects may be armed.
Good luck.
Excuse me.
- So what happened?
- A stabbing. A guy ran off.
- Any ID?
- No papers on him.
Tango 2 here, Rue des Bordes.
Man with knife wounds.
Send an ambulance
and inform the super.
- Got that.
- I had to run!
He dumped this.
Get back and fill in the super.
I'll stay here with Patricia.
Hi, it's Nathan.
Leave a message.
Nathan?
What's happened?
Show me. Show me, Nathan.
Show me.
What happened?
Talk to me, son.
Talk to me, I'm here.
Tell me what happened.
They beat me up, Dad. Him too.
Him too.
- Him too.
- Calm down.
I'm here now.
I'm here.
I'm here, I'm here, I'm here...
I took the photo.
Why'd you do that?
To get a reaction out of you.
I didn't think it'd go this far.
- Are you in love with him?
- No.
So why did you kiss him?
I didn't. He wanted to.
He's been after me
since he came to the school.
He was sticking to me
all that evening.
Kissing him
was the only way to get rid of him.
So I did.
But I'm not gay.
I couldn't care less about him.
You're the one I love.
I believe you.
Laura, are you staying for dinner?
Stay. I'd like you to.
How's Nathan?
He went to school this morning.
He said if he didn't go right away,
he'd never go again.
- What are you going to do?
- I don't know.
He wants me to keep out of it.
But if you'd seen
what they did to him...
I'm not a father
if I don't stick up for my son.
Is that for me?
We've been together for a year.
What's going on?
You're very quiet today.
Nathan, what happened to you?
He fell.
Nathan.
What happened?
I fell.
For the first hour
we'll finish looking at...
we'll finish
looking at probabilities.
No, I'm not going
to talk about probabilities.
I'm going to tell you about a girl.
This girl went to school every day
consumed by fear.
She did all she could
to avoid those who made fun of her.
Because...
she preferred other girls to boys.
And maybe this girl
would have felt less ashamed
if she'd known someone like Nathan,
someone as brave as him,
who dares to say he's different.
It takes courage
not to lie to yourself.
To meet the eyes of others.
Where's the courage
of those who hit Nathan?
- Miss.
- Yes?
Was this girl you?
How would you calculate
the probability that it was me?
I dunno.
When you toss a coin,
there's one chance it'll be heads,
one chance it'll be tails.
So the probability
of it being heads or tails
is one half.
Whether it comes out heads or tails
is the "outcome".
Not going for lunch?
When I was your age,
I spent hours at school
in a very dark place.
Sometimes I feel
I'm going through that again.
I don't want that for you.
You're in the right.
She just said she's a lesbian.
- Are you all right, Catherine?
- Fine, thanks.
Kiss me.
Kiss me!
All right! Put that telephone down!
Go on, move along!
What's got into you?
Usually, with people around...
Yeah, well...
Times change.
I'm not afraid of you.
What would you do
if I kissed you right now?
- You're mental, stop it!
- Kiss me.
- Come on, kiss me.
- Stop it, move your hand!
- Kiss me.
- Stop it!
There are people watching.
- You're scared.
- Get off!
Piss off.
I pity you.
I really pity you.
What do you want?
- Piss off!
- You think I'm going to shut up?
I'm not scared of you.
I'm not scared of any of you.
I'll take you on, one at a time!
The poofter isn't scared!
What's the matter?
Isn't that what you call me?
You're scared of everyone
knowing what arseholes you are!
That's what it is!
It's easy to beat someone up
in a gang.
But here, in front of everyone?
Come on, then!
Do it!
Come on!
You're scum!
Nathan.
Hi.
- You saw?
- Yeah.
"I'll take you on, one at a time"?
I didn't know what to say.
Get in.
Hi, it's Nathan.
Leave a message.
Nathan, it's Louis.
Call me back, please.
This is the only bit of the weekend
when it's just us two,
and you're working.
Yes, I have to do this balance sheet
for Monday.
No! It's crashed again.
I can't get the bloody table back!
Use Louis's computer.
- He'd go mad.
- He's not here.
- Do you know his password?
- No, but...
Try "boxing" or "Laura".
Know what mine is?
The name of my beloved.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I don't mean you!
I was just curious.
It's all everyone's
talking about at school.
So I checked out some forums.
That's all.
And those gay porn sites?
- I only looked once.
- You're lying.
We checked your history.
I don't understand.
What about Laura?
I'm talking to you! Louis!
I know these associations
are authorized to intervene.
But only I decide
whether to invite them or not.
But I'm opposed to it.
Not from conviction, though.
You know the parents will block it.
Nathan was beaten up
because we did nothing.
We can't let it happen again
on the pretext
of not upsetting some parents.
We're thinking of having a petition.
47 out of the 53 teachers
are in favor
of inviting an association.
- They're ready to sign.
- As will a majority of parents.
What do I tell the parents
when they accuse me of proselytism?
Tell them to look up "proselytism"
in the dictionary.
Then they won't use it incorrectly.
Sexuality isn't a doctrine
or a philosophy.
It's not a choice.
Put your gloves on.
Don't you want a family?
A normal family, I mean.
Do you want to be unhappy
all your life?
Living on the fringes of society?
I feel lost, Dad.
"I feel lost, Dad."
Do you know why?
Do you know? No?
Because up there you know
you're making a wrong choice!
It's not impossible to change.
Don't let that shit
get into your head!
You'll get over all this bollocks!
I've tried, Dad. I swear I have.
Tried? You've tried?
Look at me
when I'm talking to you!
Raise your guard.
Raise your guard!
Come on, box!
Is that all you've got?
Come on, get up. Get up!
Box!
You've tried?
Face me.
Face me! Punch!
That's it, like that!
Go on, punch!
Do you want
to win this tournament?
Do you want to win or not?
Get up! Come on, get up!
There! There, there, there!
You've tried?
Well, you'll keep trying!
No more phone! No more Internet!
You agreed, didn't you?
He stays at the house.
We have to fix this.
He has to go to school.
I'll write him a note.
He can be off sick for a few days.
Anyway, it's not really a lie.
- Is that the solution?
- You want him to stay like that?
No? Then stop
protecting him like that.
We can't let him ruin his life.
Only we can show him
where he's going wrong.
He needs time
to start to understand, that's all.
I'm sorry.
Do you trust me?
Yes, I trust you.
I'll get it.
- Hello.
- Hello, Laura.
I've come to see Louis.
He's not been replying to my texts.
He's in bed with a fever.
A really bad sore throat.
Can I see him?
Do you want to catch it?
Don't worry.
He'll soon be back on his feet.
- I'll tell him you called.
- Thanks.
Goodbye.
Coming!
Did you think I'd forgotten?
Sixteen!
That calls for a celebration.
Cool.
Just this once.
Blow! We don't want to eat wax.
Blow them out.
If you want to invite any mates
this weekend, go ahead.
No, I'm good.
Is it Louis?
You'll have to talk to him.
I don't care about him any more.
I'm not gay. I'm not gay.
But, Dad...
What? Come on.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, I'm sure.
Gentlemen.
Allow me to introduce my son, Nathan.
Hi, Nathan. I'm Serge.
I'm Marc.
Pleased to meet you.
Here, have a seat.
Welcome to our home!
It's our home away from home.
So, what do you do?
Still at school?
Two years to go.
A word of advice: keep studying.
- Otherwise you'll end up like us!
- We're not doing so bad.
You had your goth phase
as a teenager.
This was the same.
It was just to wind you up.
But I'm not really gay.
A crap idea, I know.
I know I've hurt you.
And Laura?
My love for her has helped me.
What's going on?
It was just to wind you up.
It's not true.
Forgive me.
Let him call Laura.
Have you used your phone?
- No.
- No? Are you sure?
I just tried to call Laura.
Nathan...
But no calls to Laura.
Take your phone and your computer!
Go and see who you like!
But don't try to talk to us!
Lying to us!
Treating us like your enemies!
From now on, we're ignoring you!
- Eat up.
- Don't like it!
Eat it.
- Where are you going?
- For the salad.
I can't eat on my own all the time.
I've done nothing wrong.
I had to lie.
He went totally mental.
Mum, talk to me, please.
I'll change.
I swear I'll change.
- But talk to me.
- Can I have a drink of water?
You scared me.
Are you spying on me?
I'm afraid you'll weaken.
- This is too hard.
- Do you think it's easy for me?
We have to hold out.
It's just a question of time.
- OK, little bro?
- Yes.
Théo.
- Come out of there, Théo.
- I want a cuddle.
Come here.
Come away from your brother.
Théo!
I'll read you a story.
Leave me alone for fuck sake!
You're dead to me!
What's going on?
I'm leaving.
- I'm never going home again.
- Tell me what's happened.
My parents have gone mad.
They hate me.
Because of the photo?
Answer me. Is that why?
Are you really gay, is that it?
Is it my fault?
Is it because you think I'm ugly?
Or because I don't kiss well?
What can I do?
I need money, Laura.
You have to lend me some.
- Dad.
- What?
I need your help.
- No idea where he might be?
- No.
Try and concentrate.
Did you hear anything?
What did he say?
- I think I heard a train.
- A train? Are you sure?
- Are you sure?
- I'm sure.
OK, we'll go to the bridge.
There's the old factory as well.
A description?
Blond, 16,
average height.
I'll let you know.
Go! I'll explain.
Sorry.
This is where we meet up.
There he is!
Louis, don't do it!
Leave me alone!
Don't come any closer!
Louis, I just want to talk to you.
I've nothing to say!
There are people who care about you.
Your little brother, your parents...
That's not true!
I'm already dead to my parents!
They treat me like a piece of shit!
They hate me!
That's not true.
Louis.
Look at me.
Take my hand.
Yeah.
I've never been
so scared in my life.
OK, Serge, see you tomorrow.
Thanks.
I'll take you home.
I can't go back there.
You have to go home.
Can't we put him up for tonight?
It can wait till tomorrow, can't it?
Here.
There.
Nathan.
But, Dad, I...
It's late, we all need to sleep.
Go on.
I'll pop in to see you.
Will you be OK, Louis?
I'll be OK.
If you need anything,
to talk or...
I'm in the next room, OK?
OK, thanks.
I'll be fine. Really.
Try to get some sleep.
Nathan.
I can't sleep.
Come in.
I was eight. My grandparents
came to the house a lot.
They always gave me funny looks.
I knew I'd never be like other boys.
But I didn't want
to cause trouble for my parents.
I had to put pressure on myself,
become paranoid.
When I started going out with Laura
my parents were reassured.
Then you turned up.
We have a new student: Nathan.
Please give him a warm welcome.
I'd never felt
anything like that before.
Let's carry on
with the "I have a dream" speech...
I felt so embarrassed.
I didn't know what to do.
You didn't throw it away?
No.
- What are you doing?
- It's your smell.
Seeing them in each other's arms
gave me a weird feeling.
I felt sort of...
stunned.
I'm just getting used to the idea.
Couldn't he take it slowly?
One step at a time, slowly.
Well...
I'd better go.
I hope I didn't wake Chloé.
No, she's not here.
She's at her dad's.
Well...
Stay.
Good morning.
- Are you going?
- Yeah.
See you later, then.
See you.
What do we do at work?
I don't know.
- Who cares, eh?
- Yeah!
- Hi, Dad.
- Good morning.
- I bet you wondered why Louis...
- Don't bother.
Did you...?
No.
I knew we'd have
this conversation one day.
I'd even prepared a speech.
But I'd expected it'd be for a girl.
What would you have said?
I'd have told you
about my first time.
I was still at school.
We were pretty nervous.
We took our time.
That first time was magical
because we were in love.
That works as a speech.
Yeah, you're right.
'Morning.
Good morning.
- Help yourself, Louis.
- Thank you, sir.
Call me Stéphane.
- Stéphane.
- Yes?
- When will you call my parents?
- I already have.
Your mother.
That must be her now.
I'll go.
It's Louis's dad.
Tell him I'm waiting downstairs.
- Come on up.
- I'd rather not.
Tell him to come down.
Where's Louis?
- Can we have a word?
- There's no point. Where is he?
Do you know what he nearly did?
Look, I know how you helped,
and I'm grateful.
But it's none of your business now.
He told me how things are.
Are you going to teach me
how to raise my son?
No.
I know how you feel.
I was angry too.
If he doesn't come down now,
it'll end badly for you.
Louis.
- I'm causing trouble for your dad.
- You can't go back.
It'll be OK.
I feel strong now.
Thanks for everything, Stéphane.
I've locked him in.
Do you know what he tried to do?
That's why I've locked him in.
To stop him doing it again.
- Give me the key.
- Not now, Corinne.
Stop it! Give me the key!
I have appointments.
I'll be back in two hours.
We'll talk to him together, OK?
Corinne... do you trust me?
Do you trust me, yes or no?
No, I'm not at work today
but go ahead.
Yes, call him from me.
I've got his number.
Hang on a sec...
Can I call you back?
- Louis!
- What?
I'm going to smash the door in.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
- Is my husband around?
- He's with a patient.
All right.
Goodbye.
- What are you doing here?
- We have to talk.
- Can't it wait?
- No, it can't.
What's going on?
Have you left Louis alone?
I won't let you
go on abusing him.
Abusing him?
What are you saying?
I love him like you do.
I'm trying to protect him.
- He wanted to die because he's gay.
- No, because we rejected him!
Because we made him feel
like he's a freak, unclean.
I feel so guilty.
If not for Nathan and his dad...
No, wait...
Is this that cop's doing?
It's up to us to change, not him.
Understand?
What are you on about?
- I no longer recognize you.
- Corinne...
I'm taking the boys
and moving in with my parents.
Let's be quite clear about this.
If you try to stop me,
I'll report you for child abuse.
Think of your patients
and your reputation.
- What's going on?
- Nothing. Come on, let's go.
- What's your new school like?
- I don't start till tomorrow.
I read your email.
It was like a novel!
I had to,
you weren't answering the phone.
- You hurt me, you know.
- Yes, I know.
I'll come
for the boxing tournament.
Great.
- Will you be there?
- I don't know.
- So you think I'm beautiful?
- Very.
A shame I'm not bi.
Idiot!
Are you there?
I have to go now.
But call me again, OK?
There's something else...
- I talked to Corinne earlier.
- And?
They're coming this weekend.
Yeah, I know.
Hang on... Stop.
Just a second.
Such a shame having a dad
in poor physical shape!
- Poor shape?
- Yeah.
Race you to the car!
What's on your mind?
Maybe I shouldn't have come.
Are you mad at me?
Not a great question, maybe.
You know...
I didn't have anything against you.
I mean...
I didn't mean to hurt you.
I don't really know what to say.
I'm not mad at you.
Feels weird, doesn't it?
Do you love him?
He wasn't for me.
Here it comes.
I missed you.
I can't get used to that.
I can! I think they're lovely.
What's going on?
- Where is he?
- Coming.
We're waiting.
It's OK.
- Isn't he with you?
- He doesn't want to fight any more.
What's the problem?
I don't want to box any more.
I thought I could overcome it.
But no.
What's the real reason?
It shouldn't be you, here.
Who are you boxing for,
your dad or yourself?
If you don't want to,
no one'll hold it against you.
But no regrets.
OK?
Think about it.
They're all waiting.
Can you help me put my gloves on?
Forget everything else now.
Take a deep breath,
focus on your fight...
There... OK?
Come on.
No head butting.
Have a good fight.
Raise your guard, Louis!
End of the first round.
What did I tell you? Look at me!
Keep your guard up.
Are you listening? Your guard!
Get him, Louis!
- Go, Louis!
- That's it, Louis, go for it!
Go, Louis!
Brave lad!
The winner is Louis,
by a technical knockout.
Did you see my guard?
I've improved, haven't I?
It's thanks to you.
Come and celebrate with us.
Stay, Dad.
Aren't you proud of me?
He needs a bit more time.
Come on,
everyone's waiting for you.
Subtitles by Howard Bonsor
Subtitling: Vdm
Subtitles Diego Moraes(oakislandtk)
www.opensubtitles.org