October 11, 1931, Los Angeles.
A conflagration of biblical proportions
incinerates nearly everything
and everyone inside
what was once the city of angel's
most celebrated medical facility:
The Vannacutt Psychiatric Institute
For The Criminally Insane.
But the secret this inferno burned free
was far more frightening than any picture
Hollywood could produce.
A sanitarium of slaughter
supervised by a surgeon gone mad:
Richard Benjamin Vannacutt.
Doctor Richard Benjamin Vannacutt.
Little known today, but
likely the most prolific
mass murderer of this century.
He out-butchered Bundy.
He made Manson look meek.
And the site of his
carnage still exists today,
restored almost to its original state.
But it has yet to be
inhabited because some say
the spirits of Vannacutt and his victims
still live within the walls
of The House On Haunted Hill.
- I'm Peter Graves,
- No shit.
We'll be back with more
Terrifying But True in just a moment.
No need, baby.
You just gave me everything I needed.
Price.
Evelyn, how nice.
Yeah, well that is so
totally fucking fascinating,
but I've gotta get back to you.
They're trying to shoot me here.
What is it, Mr. Price,
business or pleasure?
Neither, my wife.
We were talking about
your roller coaster
that is quote, "unlike any
that has come before it."
Absolutely, no cheap thrills.
A genuine journey to the brink of madness.
Sorry, but it just looks like
a generic roller coaster to me.
What's the gimmick?
Ever seen one that starts at the top?
20 stories worth of top?
Sources have told this
reporter that the real reason
your park's opening has been delayed
was a near-fatal accident
on one of the rides here.
I wouldn't be opening
this place tomorrow
if every single thing down to
the beheaded beanie babies,
hadn't tested 100 percent safe.
What the hell was that?
Growing pains.
New steel's gotta bend
and stretch a little
before finally settling in.
Don't worry.
In the 15 year history of Price Amusements
we've yet to lose a single customer
I've designed and built
six of these places.
Take my word for it.
Everything's fine.
Well, God forbid, if something
unexpected should happen
there's aways the safety cable.
That does what?
It keeps the cab from just...
Oh!
Do something!
Like what?
This isn't supposed to be happening!
Oh, Jesus!
Oh, God!
- Oh God!
- We're all gonna die!
You survived Terror Incognita,
please exit the elevator now.
From here on, it gets really scary!
Oh!
All right, Princess.
Now, what were you babbling?
Congratulations.
On a scale of one to 10
on the perversity meter,
you just hit a 73.
Why don't we go and celebrate
at some nice, quiet little restaurant?
Houston, I think we've got a problem.
Evelyn, Evelyn, go stir your cauldron
or something for a sec.
Oh, shit!
We're gonna fall, we're gonna fall!
Oh, my God!
Problem where?
Looked good to me.
Passenger six, he keeps losing his arm.
So, disengage the
flailing limb mechanism,
make him into a screamer.
Ah, okay.
Stephen!
Here, dear, with a
suggestion: Forget it.
Haunted Hill is exactly where
we're having my party this year.
Now, you'll find the guest list
on your desk when you get back.
I got your guest list
right here, Princess.
Shredded.
I'm gonna pull out
all the stops.
Excuse me, Mr. Price, the people
from HRS Entertainment are
getting a little antsy.
Tell them I'm right there.
Okay, hi, stop the car, get out.
Please, stop the car and get out.
Stop it, will you stop your car?
Stop your car and get out of the car!
Please sir or ma'am,
whoever's in the car, get out!
Hi, hello.
We're gonna have to
walk the rest of the way
because the driveway's out, okay?
So, let's, let's go.
Quickly.
Even quicker.
Did I say quicker?
I think I did.
Hi, hi, I'm sorry.
I'm Pritchett, I'm Watson Pritchett.
I own the house, okay?
So let's move, if we could.
So is this dump really haunted?
Uh, yeah, it's, yeah, it's pretty scary.
Uh, let's have a good
time, let's, let's go on...
Hold up, I got one question.
What's up with this?
Like why is this Price dude
inviting us to a birthday party?
I never even heard of him.
Neither have I until he
wanted to rent the place.
But right now I just have
to get you love people inside, okay?
Please?
This million bucks each, though.
That's for real?
Uh, good question.
Don't have a clue.
You might wanna ask Price that.
Is there a reason why we're
not moving forward at all?
Do you wanna?
Let me get a light, here a flashlight,
and that way we can
all see what's going on
and no one'll trip or anything.
Come on, come on, little piece of shit.
There, that's better.
Oh.
The lights are a nice touch, Pritchett.
Subtle.
Yeah, thanks, worked hard on it.
Uh, could we uh, move?
Guess we know where the Prices are.
Okay, let's go up further.
Hi.
Goddamn, this place is scary, yo.
Where's the party?
Looks like we're it.
Me and y'all three?
Ooh, let's boogie.
Where's our host,
the fabulous Mr. Price?
Fuck him, what in the
name of Christ is that?
Oh, it must be more of Price's
spook-house bogeyman bullshit.
Uh, actually that's always been there.
Back when this was an asylum,
uh, the guy running the place,
Dr. Vannacutt found it inspirational.
It's from the middle ages or something.
Driving demons from the mind.
Kinda scared me as a kid.
But uh doesn't really scare
me that much now, though.
So.
It's touching.
Are you gonna come in?
No, I'm good.
Mr. Price?
Mrs. Price?
Any Price person?
I don't think anybody's here, man.
So maybe it was ghosts.
Uh, I knew this whole
place would be pure goid.
If I can just get something
bizarre enough on tape
I think I can parlay it into
getting myself some sort
of a wackiest home videos gig.
Wait, you got your own TV show?
Had, sweetie, past tense.
Currently looking for the right angle
to either earn or fuck my way back in.
Looks like someone's
trailer park is showing.
I wouldn't worry, I'm
sure by the end of the night
we'll be hacked up into
little pieces by something or...
...somebody.
Who the fuck are all of you?
Oh, shit.
Wow!
I thought you were dead.
Not even fucking close.
Get off of me, you pervert.
Congratulations.
I don't think Evelyn's said those words
to anything with testicles.
Ever.
Very funny, Steven.
Have you?
I think you're taking this awfully well
for a woman who was just nearly killed.
Yeah, well, I guess you'll just have
to try harder next time.
That is, if you can get it up.
Not me, tulip.
The house.
I think it's marked you to be the first
to die this evening.
Isn't that how the story
goes, Mr. Pritchett?
You could say that, sure.
Isn't that how both your father
and grandfather met their demise?
Uh, well, uh, my grandfather
did build the place
but he actually died
in his sleep in Miami.
My father did get killed here
but that was during a
construction accident
while he was restoring interiors.
But I'm fine and I'm
still alive and I feel good
and I'd love to get paid now.
And on that mercenary
note, dear friends,
let the games begin.
Yeah, well, call me clairvoyant,
but haven't they already?
Finding that out is just one
of tonight's many amusements.
Sure is a funky old house, ain't it?
Let's have a word, sugarpuss.
Oh, I think we oughta have several.
This'll just take a moment.
You'll find food and
booze in the main salon.
Knock yourselves out.
I gave you a guest list two pages long.
Where the hell are they?
Shredded.
Sorry.
Decided to whip up one of my own.
A group so hungry for money
they'd be willing to do anything.
I thought you'd be more
comfortable with your peers.
How stupid of me not to expect something
this twisted from you.
Congrat-ufucking-lations.
Round one, you win.
Not quite.
See, those people down there,
they're not the ones I invited.
Yeah, then who are they?
You tell me.
I don't know how you managed to hack
into my computer, but bravo!
Oh, come on.
You think I'd invite that
bunch of social rejects?
Sure know it wasn't
me, and if it wasn't you
then who the hell did, Evelyn?
Ghosts?
Ooh, spooky.
You know, if you really
loved me, you'd find a way
to drop dead in the next three seconds.
Finding ways for me to die
is really your deal, isn't it, Evelyn?
Let's not forget the O.J. knife
with the not quite retractable blade.
Or your Jim Jones kool aid
that was exactly that.
Accidents.
All accidents until proven otherwise.
I'd be so happy if that
were really true, Evelyn.
And positively goddamned delirious
if you weren't fucking every
living thing in our area code.
Which part of that fantasy
turns you on the most?
Me with other men, or just the other men?
Everything you do gets me hot,
just not in the sexual sense.
You're hurting me.
I know.
Ow!
Well, there's the simple
country gal I married.
Let's go back down and greet your guests.
Show them the real you.
Corny as Kansas on the fourth of July.
My guests were shredded.
It's your sick little scene now.
Enjoy.
I'm gonna run scalding water on the place
you just touched me and
then I'm calling a cab.
That there're more people.
I don't even know.
What was taking
these guys so long?
How do I know, okay?
Don't talk to me.
Mr. Price?
I think I've done a great job
of getting your guests up here,
and I think I deserve my money, now.
Right here, Mr. Pritchett.
As well as five other bonafide bank drafts
for one million dollars each.
Made out to cash.
Ah, that's what I'm talking about.
And we get paid this money when, sir?
The second the sun hits tomorrow morning
assuming you've stayed the entire night.
And that you're still alive, of course.
What are you talking about?
Oh, sorry.
Detail I guess I forgot to mention.
You die, you lose.
Your check gets divvied up
by those still amongst the living.
But look at the bright side,
if there's only one of
you still upright at dawn
you'll be leaving here with
$5,000,000 in your pocket.
This is crazy.
Yeah, but hey, anybody
who's not comfortable
with the rules, you're
free to walk any time.
Seven digits poorer, goes without saying.
I'm ready. I'll walk. Now.
All right, Mr. Pritchett,
just let me sign the damned thing.
Oh, just for the record,
what are the rest of your names?
Donald W. Blackburn, MD.
Melissa Margaret Marr, celebrity.
Eddie Baker, pro, uh,
former pro baseball player.
And you, young lady?
Jennifer Jenzen, Executive VP,
Lathrup International Pictures.
Very good.
Well, I think I can say
with compete honesty
I've never heard of any of you.
Great, then why are we here?
Then how did you make
the guest list, Price?
Throw darts at a phone book?
I'm sure the unexplainable
will probably explain
herself before too long.
Jesus Christ.
That's it, I'm sorry to interrupt here.
Goddamn it!
You give me my goddamn check, right now!
Because I want it!
So you give it!
Now!
I'm serious!
I'm sorry, Pritchett.
Here you go.
I think you're gonna miss
the bash of a lifetime.
My loss.
Even if I give you a million as well?
I wouldn't know what to do with it all.
Thank you.
I think I gotta go now.
Interesting.
Fuck!
Now that's enter-fucking-tainment!
This ain't moving, man.
Is this your idea of a joke?
Pritchett's not laughing.
Open, open, open, you
stupid, asshole bitch!
- Open!
- What's going on?
What's going on?
Oh, doctor.
What happened here?
Lockdown.
What is that?
It's a machine from the old asylum.
It seals everything shut.
It's how they burned to death in '31.
Dr. Vannacutt threw the switch.
If he was gonna die,
they're all gonna die.
Well, no wonder
they're still pissed off.
Well, let's go to the other room
and I'll take care of your hands.
The only ones that survived were five
of the sadists on Vannacutt's staff.
Why hasn't that machine been disabled?
It was on my dad's list of things to do,
but the house did him first.
Wait, you said that was an accident.
I lied.
The house is alive, we're all gonna die.
Wait, why doesn't just
one of us call out for help?
There aren't any
working phones in the house.
- Oh, I've got my cell phone.
- I've got my cell phone.
That won't do any good.
It's the metal plates.
It's not the plates.
It's the house!
Why is no one listening to me?
Did you just turn deaf all of a sudden?
It's alive!
We're not going anywhere!
That's it!
So what, we're stuck here forever?
No, a cleaning crew's supposed to come
in at 9:30 in the morning.
Jesus!
Oh, so then we'll just
stay here till morning.
Yeah, I'm sure we'll be mutilated
beyond recognition by then.
Why do I feel like this is
some sick joke to scare us
out of our wits and a
hell of a lot of money?
You got that right.
Take a bow, you sick fuck.
You've outdone yourself tonight.
Scared the shit out of even me.
You've had your fun.
Open this place up.
Asking the wrong guy.
Wasn't me who closed it.
Sure it wasn't.
Uh, anybody else here make a living
with thrills and chills for the kiddies?
Don't all raise your hands at once.
You're that Stephen Price?
As in Price Amusement Parks?
Bravo.
All right, Pritchett,
this lockdown thing,
there's gotta be like a main control room
in this place, right?
In the basement, but you're
not gonna wanna go down there.
No, you don't want to go down there.
- No, I don't.
- We will both go down there
and try to put a reverse on this thing.
You're not gonna
wanna go down there.
It's a maze down there.
Then that leaves you with two options.
Either show me where and
maybe we get out of here
or it's spend the night, sleep tight.
Fine.
Uh, a word of advice, kitten.
God knows what kind of freak-outs
Stephen's got set to spring in this place.
If I were you, I'd bring
something to protect myself with.
Baby, don't you think now's the time
to break out your party favors?
What are you talking about?
Same exact setup you used back
in '94 for the son of Sam hunt.
Hilarious.
Firearms this time.
Jesus Christ.
The clip's been welded shut.
On all of them, probably.
So how's a girl to know if
these things are loaded, puff?
Only one way I can think of.
Woah.
No.
I think I'll let the
virgin have first crack.
I don't want a goddamn gun!
I'll take it, shit.
Let's just go.
I'll meet you all down there.
Uh, and where are we off to, Mr. Price?
Checking the wiring on
the animatronic mummies?
Just taking a leak
if it's okay with you.
Oh wow.
Careful.
I gotta say, coming down
here's a really good idea.
I know I'm having a great time.
Yeah well, you're
not helping matters much.
Smells fantastic.
Ain't you handy to have around.
I love how nothing works.
Let me get you some light.
Oh yeah, these things.
I knew I shoulda kept my ass at home.
Damn.
You're pretty handy yourself.
Take us where this thing's at.
- Come on, man.
- All right.
Thank you, got it.
Hey, Schecter!
At least give me a few of seconds notice
before you pull a stunt like that.
The lockdown thing?
I mean, very impressive,
scared all the right
people, but you know...
It wasn't me.
What do you mean?
I mean I was just sitting
here and it happened.
I had nothing to do with it.
Then who did?
No idea, maybe it was
just the thing's time
to finally fall apart.
Somehow, I don't know how, she did it.
You should really open up this place
to the public, Pritchett.
A spa for people without
enough stress in their lives.
That's funny, sharp.
Look, I'm the one who didn't
wanna come down here, remember that?
There haven't been any changes
to this part of the house
since, I don't know, 1931.
Is that a fact, Mr. Pritchett?
Oh shit.
- Sorry.
- That's a good way
to get your head blown off, man.
I'll recommend it to Evelyn.
What's in there?
Someone sure went to a lot of
trouble trying to seal that up.
I don't know, I've never been in there,
but it's not the way out.
Let's go down here and take a right.
This is electroshock therapy.
There's several of these
rooms hooked together.
Dr. Vannacutt liked to zap his
patients in multiples of 18.
More energy efficient, I guess.
Isn't that pleasant?
How about we go?
- Agreed.
- Yeah.
Oh, shit.
Guess we shoulda made a left.
What is this?
This is the saturation chamber.
What's a saturation chamber?
It's Vannacutt's
treatment for schizophrenia.
What would drive a sane man mad
would drive a mad man sane.
Something like that.
I don't know. Whatever.
It's supposed to bombard 'em with images
and weird noises and
scare 'em back to normal.
Lot of fun.
Did it work?
I don't know.
Oh, fuck.
Guys?
Hey!
Guys!
Pritchett?
Oh, I do not wanna be lost down here.
Price!
Pritchett!
This is not cool.
Let me try something.
Can you get me up?
Here, watch out.
Hey, pal, that wasn't code for...
For what?
Could you just shine the light here?
Absolutely.
All right.
What are you looking for
up there, what are you doing?
This whole place can't be
wired to just one circuit.
Careful.
Oh!
- Better than nothing.
- Not bad.
Down, big guy.
Thanks.
That was the most fun I've had all day.
You need to get out more.
So who are you really?
What?
You mean like deep down inside?
Well we can start with the name
you were given at birth, then
we can take it from there.
I told you already.
Jennifer Jenzen, executive vp...
You're lying, all right?
And I don't think so.
Why not?
I've never in my life met an executive
who could tie their shoes
much less rewire an entire building.
Well, there's always exceptions.
No.
Come on, what's the truth?
The truth is, if we keep taking rights,
we're gonna have end up where we started.
Look, we're all gonna be
outta here in a little while
and go our separate ways
a million bucks richer.
So what does it matter
who I am or who I'm not?
Okay, so let's say, hypothetically,
I'm not exactly who I said I was.
Okay, so you're right, you're a genius.
I don't know anyone that could've
seen through me like that.
All right, look, my real name is Sara,
and I'm an assistant.
Was, anyway, to the real Jennifer
bitch that was invited here.
And now you know and I'm begging
that you don't tell anyone
because I'm out of a job and
could use even a tenth of that money.
Eddie?
You know, if this is your
idea of funny, think again.
You know, in fact, you're
really starting to piss me off.
Eddie!
Eddie, wait!
Eddie?
Hey!
You know, for a second I actually
thought that you were a decent guy.
What is your problem?
Eddie?
Okay, you win.
You've successfully creeped me out.
Eddie?
What are you doing?
Eddie!
Come on!
Take my hand!
Eddie!
Come on, no, Eddie!
What the hell are you doing?
Eddie!
No!
Well, looky.
Looks like the games have begun.
Where is he, where's Price?
What happened to you?
Are you all right?
No, I am so fucking far
from all right it's not even funny.
Someone or something just tried
to drown me in a tank of
blood the size of a Buick.
Uh, let me give you a hint.
His initials are S.P.
All right, S.P.
As in sorry, Petunia
because I was with Pritchett
the whole time looking
for the master control.
It doesn't seem to exist.
Look at this, huh?
What is this?
That? What just happened to you there?
That's nothing.
You've just been playing
around with a ghost,
wait'll somebody lets out
the darkness in this place.
That's a whole, that's a
whole new bunch of crazy shit.
That's, you'll hate that shit.
What is this darkness?
It, the thing, the evil!
The thing that's the rotten core
at the bottom of this place!
The thing that's going to kill us all!
Death by corrosion, that thing!
Pritchett.
Are you currently under
the care of a physician?
No, I'm not, no, no I'm not.
Well, either we spend the
night and collect our money
or we try to find a way outta here.
Either way, I think we
should all stick together.
But maybe that's not gonna
fit in with your plans, baby.
You know me.
The more, the merrier.
I guess somebody better go
find the old game-show hostess.
Where is she?
Oh.
Oh, this is weird.
I guess old Melissa found
what she was looking for.
Jesus, she's dead.
She was cute too.
God, I'd love to get laid before I died.
How you doing tonight?
Yeah, I'm all right.
Is she all right?
I don't know.
What the hell is this?
It seems to just stop here.
Shit, she's gotta be somewhere,
because she couldn't have just
disappeared into thin air.
No.
Not air.
Into the house.
There's gotta be a
way out of this house.
Some way.
Pritchett!
What?
I'm talking to you! Whoa!
Look, if you're easy, easy.
- Damn, that wasn't nice.
- Easy.
Hey, if everybody's
gonna scream at each other,
could you do it in another room, please?
Watch it!
I'm about to
figure out exactly what,
or who, Melissa was taping.
What, then where will we be?
Out of scotch, thanks to you, ass!
Hey, I think I got something.
Bravo.
I know it's not good manners
to ask the magician how
he did it but inquiring
minds are desperate to know.
Just what did really
happen to little Miss Marr?
Asking the wrong person.
I mean, did she stage it
all for you and then go hide?
Or did you just flat out
kill the little bitch?
I pose you the same question.
Who's next on your list?
If I had one, Evelyn, whom do you think?
Oh for god sakes, we all know that
knocking me off is the bottom line here.
You know I'm not gonna
make it easy for you.
You think that's gonna do
the trick, do you, tulip?
I would never give you a loaded gun.
Jesus!
Funky old house, ain't it?
Friends, your hostess is now going
to retire for what's left of the night.
If you need me, I'll be
upstairs in the bedroom.
And if anyone so much
as peeks in the keyhole
I'm gonna empty this thing
into their fucking head.
Oh, come on.
I loaded them with blanks.
And even if I were gonna,
you know, murder my wife,
I don't think I'd do it in a locked house
with quite so many witnesses.
Hey, take this.
What good is a million
dollars if you're dead?
Okay.
Let's find a way to get outta here.
Right.
I'm gonna try to find Ms. Marr.
I'm gonna go find me something to drink.
Shit!
How is she pulling this off?
Ms. Marr?
You son of a bitch, I know you're here.
What is happening?
Electroshock!
Oh, Jesus.
No, God, no!
No! - Don't touch her!
Well, turn it off!
For God's sake, somebody do something!
Come on, somebody turn the damn thing off!
Pritchett, somebody, do something!
Turn it off!
There's gotta be a switch or something!
I'm sorry.
She's not dead, we just gotta
get her heart pumping again.
It's too late.
Oh no.
Oh.
Baby, I'm so sorry.
I swear to God, it's this house.
Fuck the house!
It wasn't the house!
It wasn't Goddamn ghosts!
This is, plain and simple,
good old-fashioned homicide.
Is it too complicated for you?
Let me spell it out for you then, kids.
A - Evelyn sure as hell
didn't kill herself.
B - I know I didn't do it.
Which just leaves us with C.
One of you motherfuckers murdered my wife!
You're talking crazy, Price.
Who's gonna tell me
about the strange guy
with the mustache and the lab coat
who I've been chasing all
over this goddamn house?
Vannacutt.
Jesus.
Oh no.
Some little shit working for one of you
with the hopes of pocketing
several million bucks.
Now I want some answers.
Oh, put that away.
Put the gun down, Mr. Price.
Back up, honey.
There's a one in four chance it's you.
Put the gun down!
Well let's see who blinks first.
What do we do with him?
Open this fucking door!
You sure this thing will hold him?
Oh, I don't think it'll be a problem.
Come on.
So, you gonna stay and
make sure he doesn't get out?
I'll stay and keep an eye on him.
You gonna be okay by yourself?
I hope.
I have to tell you,
I'm just a little bit
uncomfortable with this.
I'm sure you are.
Open the Goddamn door!
What?
I can't, I'm sorry, I can't.
What's this?
This!
Anything?
Open this fucking door!
How about this?
Come on, what are you doing?
Better?
Blackburn!
Great party!
I gotta go!
Blackburn!
All right, I think we shoulda
taken a right back there.
Back where?
Damn it, good point.
Let's just try down here.
All right, come on.
Okay.
Yo, Sara, look.
Vannacutt's office.
You've been sick, Mr. Price.
And what do you think, Dr. Vannacutt?
Hey, look it here.
What do you got?
Class of 1931.
That's a cheery-looking bunch.
Better living through electricity.
I think...
Oh, my god!
I know how the guest list was made.
Look at these names.
Head nurse, Ruthe Ann Stockard.
Electroshock, Adolphus Jenzen.
Franklin Baker.
Thomas Steven Price.
Jasper Marr.
They're all here!
Who's all here, I'm missing something.
Everyone that was invited
is related to one of the staff
that was here when the place burnt.
There was five of us.
And five that didn't die.
Booga-booga.
What are you saying?
Price didn't make the list.
The house did.
Because she's a vengeful, stupid whore!
Ow.
Wait, how's the house
gonna send out invitations?
There's a lotta energy in here.
It likes to travel through light beams
and sound waves, electricity, whatever.
A phone line?
Yeah, sure, now that we're
in the twilight zone, mhm.
Into an online computer
through the Internet?
No, no, no, stop.
Wait, this is crazy.
You don't get it, do you?
This house is pissed.
It has no morals.
Because it's a fucking house!
- This is insane.
- All right, calm down.
All right, I'm sorry, sorry about that.
All right.
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
How come Blackburn's name's not on here?
The late Mrs. Steven Price.
Tragic.
Tortured.
Lovely.
And suddenly very cooperative, Mrs. Price.
Cool.
What do you think you're doing, mister?
Easy, easy, lie back, be still.
Last thing we need is for you
to have a real heart attack.
You're the doctor, kid.
I guess that atropine crap worked, huh?
Yep.
Convinced all those
that needed convincing.
You are officially one dead lady.
Trust me, I've been dead for years.
Speaking of which, what's Steven's status?
Well, he's still alive but it's
just a question of moments.
And then your miraculous resurrection.
Oh no, officer, I'm very much alive.
Just a little joke to beat my husband
at his own clever game.
Well, I'm sorry, ma'am,
your husband's dead.
What do you mean, he's dead?
Oh, no, it's all my fault.
I may as well have killed him myself.
No, no, not at all.
We have all these witnesses that saw.
Well fill in the blank,
whoever it's gonna be that shoots him.
I don't know.
Puff Eddie?
You know, this could be a big surprise.
I think the Jenzen girl.
She's got the right stuff.
Did you ever find out what
happened to that little TV reporter?
No, we never found her.
So we don't even know if
the little bitch is dead or alive.
Well, but I think
Price must've killed her.
There's no other explanation.
There's plenty, you moron!
For all we know Stephen's got
her spying on us right now!
Oh, bullshit.
God, this whole fucking
thing's falling apart.
It's not, baby, it's not.
Somebody's gonna pull the trigger.
But nobody has yet, Donald.
They're not at the breaking point.
The bozos have to believe that
their lives are in danger!
They have your death at his hands.
How much more do they need?
But they didn't see it happen.
They still have their
doubts, they're confused.
What we need is another body
and Stephen's bloody
hands right next to it.
Well, how the hell are we gonna do that?
I don't know,
this may sound a little
crazy, but hear me out.
This is all I could find.
This here.
- Well, it's gonna have to do.
- Yeah.
Are you coming, or
waiting for Blackburn?
Blackburn's dead.
Excuse me?
He would've been back by now.
He's dead.
Blackburn!
Oh, shit.
Where is he?
Blackburn!
He's gotta still be down here...
He's dead, all right? We're all gonna be dead.
- Will you stop saying that?
- Pritchett, shut the fuck up!
I just wanted to ask you a question.
Price is behind this.
How could he be? He's still locked up.
Let's go see.
It's Blackburn.
- Oh, my God.
- Shit!
Price, you murderer!
Melissa?
It's Sara.
Help me.
Somebody!
I'll help you. Oh God.
Just keep talking.
Oh God.
- Oh, oh, oh.
- It's okay.
Okay.
It's okay, it's okay.
I woke up on the floor.
It was Blackburn.
Stay the fuck back!
I don't know what happened!
I do.
Please, tell me.
Help me.
I don't think so!
You gotta help me.
Not even for a million bucks, Mr. Price.
Help me.
Oh, shit!
Whoa!
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Grab her gun.
Okay, damn, she emptied it.
I got this.
I got this, baby girl.
Give, let go.
All right, there we go.
I'm gonna put this right here. Okay?
Look, it's cool, it's me.
Okay, it's me, Eddie, look.
Poor Mr. Price.
Fuck Mr. Price.
Come on, baby girl.
I got you.
I got you, come on, it's cool.
Let's get the Hell outta here.
I got you.
Okay, don't look, don't look, keep going.
Up we go, up we go, baby girl, okay.
Almost there.
You just get upstairs.
All right, easy, don't look, don't look.
Stephen.
You poor clueless old geek.
All it would've taken was a simple divorce
and ripping our prenup to
teeny, itsy-bitsy little pieces.
But no matter how it ended
please just know one thing:
From the first moment I set eyes on you
I have always, always loved...
...your money.
On the other hand, just the sight of you
has always made me want to puke.
Is that a fact, Princess?
Maybe you could have saved
us all a great deal of time
not to mention money, if you
just let me in on it years ago.
How--
You must be kidding!
I'm Stephen Goddamn Price!
Every place you've gone,
every person you've seen,
every word you and Blackburn
ever said to each other, bugged,
taped, seen and heard
by me as it happened!
Sweetie?
Anything, angel!
Just speak it!
What are you gonna do?
Just what you wanted everyone here
to believe in the first place!
I'm gonna murder you, Evelyn,
with the greatest of pleasure!
Witnesses.
You're already dead, Evelyn!
Happy birthday, baby!
Evelyn?
Get up.
Stephen, are you doing this?
No.
Get up!
Now!
Stephen! Stephen!
Oh, Ms. Marr.
Stephen, I want you.
I've always wanted you.
We all do.
They're all here.
Everyone who's died.
Everyone who's responsible.
It's your turn.
One, two, three.
Open the door!
Somebody open the door!
Oh, my god.
- Oh God, open the door!
- It's Price.
- Open the Goddamn door!
- Price?
- Somebody, please!
- Price is dead.
Open the Goddamn door!
Pritchett!
Open the door!
No!
Go!
Run!
Come on!
What was that?
It can't be, you're dead!
Pritchett was right.
The house is alive.
There's gotta be something.
Pulleys or something.
The attic!
Come on!
Let's get to the attic! Hurry!
Terrific!
Fuck!
So much for a Ph.D. in engineering.
I found a way out!
What, where?
Up here! Better hurry!
There is something of a time issue here.
Sara.
Come on!
Where are you going?
Sara, you have to stay for my show.
Oh, God!
There's light, there's light!
Stay here, I'm gonna go and
see if we can get out this way.
Sara, come...
Oh, shit.
Go!
Sara!
- No!
- Eddie, oh my God!
Help me, Eddie!
The doctor is in.
No one gets out of here alive.
Not me, not you.
No.
Next patient.
Ah, Mr. Baker.
It's time to take your
rightful place with the others.
I had nothing to do with this!
I was adopted!
Oh, God.
What is this?
What is it?
Oh, my God.
That was one kick-ass party.
Okay, one more thing: How
do we get down from here?