Hi! Hi! Hi!
Does it hurt?
Okay.
Name?
Kevin Abdela.
Kevin Abdela. Good, Mary. You'll be fine.
So, fine.
She has to keep it on for four weeks.
Even when the pain stops, she has to keep it on.
Let's wrap it up in ten minutes,
folks, please! Ten minutes, thank you!
Najeeb?
Yeah?
We take two more, each.
Two?
OK, we can have four more.
She will have to give her something for the fever.
Three times a day.
Come back here...
Najeeb, stretcher please!
Prepare to operate!
Easy, easy. Come, come, come.
Tie me on the back.
I need help here.
She can make it.
Check her pulse. She can make it.
I need some light.
Patient asleep?
Yes, doctor.
Swabs.
Take the swab.
Clamp.
What's the pulse?
Pulse at 78.
Stable.
Okay. Hold tight.
Clamp.
Looks stable now.
I didn't think she'd make it.
I've seen that type of injury before.
It's the work of a local villain. Big Man.
He takes bets with his boys as to what sex the child will be.
Then he cuts the girls open to see.
"And Death gave back these treasures for a song.
The nightingale sang on.
It sang of the quiet churchyard, where white roses grow,
where the elderflowers make the air sweet,
and where the grass is always green,
wet with the tears of those who are still alive.
Death longed for his garden.
Out through the windows drifted
a cold gray mist as Death departed.
'Thank you, thank you,' the emperor said.
'Little bird from Heaven, I know you of old.
I banished you once from my land,
and yet you have sung away the evil faces from my bed,
and Death from my heart.
How can I repay you?'
'You have already rewarded me,' said the nightingale.
'I brought tears to your eyes when first I sang for you.
To the heart of a singer, those are
more precious than any precious stone.
But sleep now, and grow fresh and strong while I sing. '
He sang until the emperor fell into a sound, refreshing sleep,
a sweet and soothing slumber."
She used to read it to me before I'd go to sleep.
I think it's good that he did it.
So do I.
Hey, Hanna. This is my mother. This is Hanna.
You're the one they'll be staying with?
Yes.
I think Christian is looking forward
to getting back home, right?
It's so hard to believe she's gone.
Christian?
I just want to tell you that you did really well.
I'm really proud of you.
Mom would have been too.
You don't have to say something all the time, dad.
We can talk, can't we?
You don't have to on my account.
Are you ready?
Coming.
Good morning, Mohammed.
Good morning, sir.
OK, let's go.
Hello.
Hello, my darling.
Welcome.
Hi, mom.
Here's so much space.
Lots of peace and quiet. I won't bother you.
Internet has been installed for you,
and you can choose which room you want.
This is the smallest room.
It's fine.
You don't have to decide now.
Can I choose myself or can't I?
Of course, but your desk and your bed won't fit in here.
But you decide.
Your call.
The view is great.
You'll get it.
What's up, ratboy?
Got air in your tyres?
Lost your bottom jaw?
Excited?
Yes.
Want me to come with you?
No. Of course not.
Take care.
Yep.
See you.
Crawl between our legs, rat.
Go home and eat some cheese.
Aren't you a rat?
Is there a problem?
Walking fountain.
Damn swede.
Mutant! Damn, you're ugly!
Fucking rat!
Please sit down, and try to be quiet.
Sit down!
Whose is this?
This is Christian.
Be quiet.
Christian lived in lots of countries
and has just moved here from London.
Does he speak danish?
Of course he does, Trine.
Well, I'll just mark your birthday on the calendar.
When's your birthday?
July 7th.
The same as Elias. That's quite funny.
That's quite funny. Be quiet.
You can sit next to Elias then.
Stop it!
Poor you!
Then we can talk about London
during form time. That'll be fun.
Now please get out your history books.
I don't wanna fight you.
No!
Want to borrow my bicycle pump?
No thanks. It's all right.
The took the valves too.
They always do that.
I'll just walk. It's okay.
Why not take some from the other bikes?
Then he'll have to walk.
Then today is his turn.
Here.
Thanks.
Letting other peoples' tyres down?
And who the hell are you?
I'm Christian.
Christian?
What are you doing with ratboy?
Ratboy?
Yeah, he's got the teeth of a rat.
I don't go around looking in other peoples' mouths.
You're supposed to catch it.
And you'll just walk home, ratboy.
Are you okay?
Yeah.
I'm really sorry.
Want me to help you?
No, I'm OK.
You sure?
Yeah.
I'm really sorry.
That one was really stuck in there.
How many did you eat?
Hi, sweetheart.
How was your day?
It was all right.
Look at me? Are you sure?
Yes.
Sure?
If you lie to me, I'll eat you up!
Me too!
Leave me alone!
Just leave me alone.
Elias...
I hate you.
Aren't you sleeping?
No, I had to finish my game.
Is that blood on your shirt?
We were playing soccer.
Did someone punch you?
No.
It was an accident.
Won't you come down to the kitchen
and keep me company?
That'd be nice.
I'll be right there.
Hi, dad!
Hi, sweetheart.
It's so good to see you.
You too. I missed you.
How are you?
How was your trip?
Long. But all right.
Hi.
Morten made you a present, in case you were hungry.
Did you get a haircut?
No.
It was good hearing from you, Elias.
But now we'd like to talk
to your parents alone, if that's okay?
What do you say?
Let's be reasonable.
Elias isolates himself a lot.
We have to relate to that.
His tyres are let down every day.
The other kids call him ratboy.
It's not Sofus who lets his tyres down.
Maybe not him personally,
but he has his own little mafia.
He'll get the others to it, but he's behind it.
We shouldn't give Sofus too much credit...
Other pupils' tyres are let down too.
We are of course aware of that.
It's not an easy situation for Elias...
With you, Anton, who travels a lot.
It must be hard for Elias, that his father is away so often.
And if there are other problems between you...
What problems are those?
Your separation, Marianne.
Let me tell you something.
Don't you interfere with our personal life.
That has nothing to do with anything!
No, stop.
I'm shocked that we have to listen to this.
We'll end up having to move Elias
to another school, because Sofus is a...
...sadistic little psychopath!
If we could try
to be a little constructive, what do you suggest?
Maybe you should try buying some flowers for mom?
Or some chocolate.
You're even uglier up close.
Fuck off!
Shut up. You're from Sweden.
Kiss my shoe if you want to pass.
What's up, loser?
You're so gross.
What's up, Elias?
You know, yesterday?
If anyone asks...
I won't tell.
Nothing happened to him.
Just keep your mouth shut.
If you talk, you're dead.
Never touch me again!
I won't do anything.
Not me or anyone else.
I don't give a fuck if you die.
Do you understand?
Hide the knife. You'll be expelled.
We changed your medication.
You might get a little confused.
Did you eat anything yesterday?
It ate it all. Pork roast.
It was delicious.
Then you are getting really confused, huh?
Marianne?
They have called twice from Elias' school.
You have to call them back.
Did they say what it was about?
You forgot to turn on your cellphone.
I don't have it on me.
You're lying, Elias.
Why are you lying?
I'm not lying.
Christian admitted that he had a knife.
He hit him several times in the head with a bicycle pump.
I only saw them hitting each other. There was no knife.
Listen to me.
Elias just told us that you had a knife.
I didn't have a knife.
Okay.
If everyone is lying, then you tell me the truth.
He hit me.
Then I hit him.
You hit him with a bicycle pump?
I had to.
He's much bigger than me.
He was going to beat me up.
Elias,
this is serious.
He might go blind in one eye.
Then he should leave people alone.
Hi.
Hi, Marianne.
Where is Elias?
They're talking to the police.
What happened?
It was a vicious assault.
Apparently, there was a knife involved.
That can't be right.
That doesn't sound like Christian.
They haven't found one.
What has this got to do with Elias?
Did Elias hit Sofus?
We don't know.
The police are interviewing them,
and then we'll find out what happened.
Is it true that Sofus has been blinded?
Who told you that?
The police.
No.
He will have a headache, and probably
get a scar, but he will be all right.
It could have been much worse.
Why didn't you tell me that he hit you?
Then we could have talked to him and his parents.
A lot of kids saw it.
That's no answer.
If I hadn't fought back,
then everyone would think I was weak.
Just tell me if he had a knife.
I promise I won't tell anyone.
He didn't have a knife. Stop asking.
If you hit him, then he'll hit you. It'll never end.
Don't you understand?
That's how wars start.
Not if you hit hard enough the first time.
You don't know a damn thing about it.
It's like that in every school.
Now no one dares touch me.
I'm not going to ask you about the knife again.
You understand?
But I want you to know
that you can tell me everything.
Understand?
Yes.
It's me.
Hi.
Were you sleeping?
No.
What are you doing?
I'm at a discotheque.
What do you want?
Just talk.
I'm bored without you.
Did you talk to Elias?
Of course.
I miss you.
Don't do that.
I told you I was sorry.
And I mean that from the bottom of my heart.
I was quite proud of us actually.
I was.
Proud that we weren't like all the other idiots
who just give up and get divorced.
I was proud that we loved each other.
We still do.
But Anton...
I messed up big time.
I tried...
I tried to explain, how it got that far
and I was so stupid. I tried...
You only paid attention to her, every time you were home.
It still hurts.
Everything we had together.
And when you were here, it was all lies.
It was all make-believe.
I love you.
I would like to forgive you, but I can't keep up.
That's how it is. Good night.
No, wait. Don't hang up.
I think, we can consider this matter closed.
You have messed up.
All three of you.
But you have learned that no good comes from fighting.
That's right.
It could have ended much worse.
Now Elias and Sofus shake hands.
I'm sorry, Elias.
Good.
And Christian and Sofus. Please shake hands.
Sorry.
And you'll be back Monday. No hard feelings, OK?
Looking forward to the theme week?
Yes.
The whole school is excited.
We're looking forward to it.
What will you be doing, Sofus?
I'm in the weapons group.
We'll be making muskets.
Of course you will.
And Elias?
I'm in the same group as Christian.
We'll be making a model of The Round Tower.
I'm looking forward to that.
Want to walk with me, Christian?
No.
Come on, Elias.
Here it is.
Do you want it?
Thanks.
Cool!
Christian?
Yes?
I'm leaving now.
I'll try to make the flight at four tomorrow.
I'll call you.
You can stay for dinner, if you want?
Thank you, but I should be going home.
Then maybe on the weekend.
Just go, dad.
See you.
Take care, Elias.
You too.
Where's he going?
London.
Where's your mom?
She's dead.
My parents are in the middle of a divorce.
Why did she die?
She had cancer.
At first they thought she'd get well, but she didn't make it.
She was cremated.
Okay.
Funerals are disgusting.
The bodies rot and seep into the groundwater.
I want to be cremated when I'm dead.
What about you?
Perhaps.
I never really thought about it.
What are we doing here?
Going up.
You can do that?
Of course.
Come on.
Wow, this is crazy.
Yeah.
I used to come here when I was home on vacation.
Where's your house?
My house?
Out there somewhere.
Okay.
It's a long way down.
Yeah, like that.
We were on this silo down by the docks.
You can't do that.
Christian is up there every day.
You can see our house from up there.
I know it. That's why I tell you not to play there.
It's dangerous.
Promise me that you won't do it again.
Don't "mmm" me.
Promise. Where's the pump?
Here you go.
Promise?
Yeah.
Promise what?
That I won't go back up there.
Let's pump it up.
Put it down here, boys.
Can we have an ice cream?
Yes. Put it down gently.
I wanna try the swing.
Thanks for the help.
Kayaking was so much fun.
Don't!
Come on, boys.
Hey!
What are you doing? Morten!
Stop that. What are you doing?
Why are you fighting?
What's going on?
He took my swing.
Why?
He punched me for no reason.
Why did you hit him?
I didn't.
Why are you fighting over a swing?
What's going on here, man?
I was just using the swing,
and he came up and started bothering me.
Don't steal his swing!
Kids will be kids...
I don't wanna see you touch my boy again.
You understand?
I didn't touch him.
Get the hell outta here.
Fuck off!
What the hell is wrong with you? Look at me.
You're always fighting.
Always fucking trouble with you.
I'm sorry, dad.
You did nothing wrong.
Doesn't it hurt? Are we going to the hospital?
No, we're not.
I'm very sorry.
Shouldn't you call the police?
Yeah, dad. Call the police.
No, I won't do that.
He hit you.
Let's go home. You can't eat your ice cream in the car.
End of discussion.
We shouldn't be up here.
Why not?
What are you doing?
Just hanging out.
I gotta get home.
There he is.
Who?
The idiot who hit your dad.
Come on.
There he is.
We'll look up his address online.
Hey! What the hell are you doing?
Run dammit!
Hey, dad.
Hey.
Come, sweetheart.
You okay?
Sure.
What are you doing here?
I just wanted to give you this.
I know where the guy who punched you works.
How did you find out?
I just did. He works there.
Christian and I saw him. It was on his car.
Have you been up on that silo again?
No, no.
Christian might have been. He's up there every day.
But you haven't?
I haven't.
Are you sure?
Yeah.
Aren't you going to do something about it?
Like what?
Go and beat him up.
Are you serious?
Yes.
Are you afraid?
That's not the point.
You don't go around beating people up.
Nobody benefits from that.
What kind of world would we live in then?
He's an idiot.
If I beat him up, I'll be just as big an idiot.
I'll go to jail, and you'll have no dad. He wins.
Maybe mom would like it if you weren't such a wimp.
I promised mom I'd be home, so I'd better get going.
Who's the wimp now?
You are.
Bye!
Say hi to your mom.
Hello?
Hi.
I'm looking for a Lars.
Say what?
Does a Lars work here?
Lars?
Lars!
Sweden calling.
Hi.
Remember me?
I'm Anton.
We met on the playground.
You slapped me.
Remember?
Yeah, I remember.
What do you want?
Why did you do it?
Don't touch my kids.
I broke up a fight over a swing.
Good for you. Know what you should do?
Stay away from me and my son.
And nothing will happen. Okay?
You understand?
Do you want me to tell you why you did it?
No, shut the hell up.
And get your ass back to Sweden.
Nobody understands you here anyway.
Did you hit me because you could?
That's right.
Maybe you should shut up now, Lars.
Do you want me to hit you again?
You're an idiot who likes to feel he's in charge.
You're not.
Stop it, Lars.
It's all right, boys.
What do you want?
What do I want?
Yeah, what do you want?
I want to show the children that I'm not afraid of you.
You can't hurt me.
You're not afraid of me?
And I can't hurt you?
That's exactly what I can do.
I think you should go now.
Take your kids, and go home.
You frightened the children
when you hit me.
Good.
They were very upset and found out where you work.
That's why we're here.
That's very clever of them, finding out where I work.
Good job.
You're such a big idiot that you can't even apologize
when I'm here with the kids
but continue to fight.
Huh? Want some more?
Let's go home.
Want some more?
Get the hell back to Sweden, you fag.
It didn't hurt. I'm okay.
Let's go. Thank you for seeing us.
It didn't hurt.
Nothing to be afraid of.
That's all he knows how to do. He lost.
He's a moron.
You understand?
Understand what?
That he's a moron, and not worth our time.
He's a big moron.
Exactly.
I don't think he feels he lost.
Maybe not, but he did.
I'm not sure.
Let's go. We're done here.
Giant wanker moron.
Get in the car.
He was such an asshole.
Giant wanker moron.
That's enough.
Giant wanker moron!
Put your seatbelt on. All right, stop.
Should we let Morten try?
Yes!
Wait a second.
There.
Come on, Morten.
Perfect!
No, let go at the same time.
Look at that.
Has the fever gone down?
Yeah, it's gone down.
That's perfect.
There he is.
Everybody's afraid of him,
but no one does anything about it.
I'll try to find something we can use as a fence.
Come here for a second.
Must be something my granddad bought.
We shouldn't keep it here.
It could blow up the whole house.
They're just fireworks.
You know how much black powder's in this?
Several pounds.
You could make a huge bomb.
Really?
Yeah.
I'll show you online.
He just kept hitting your dad.
Your dad might not be afraid,
but he just kept hitting him.
If we get back at him, he might learn his lesson.
How loud will this be?
Very.
Won't anyone hear?
Not out here.
Hold the bomb.
You want to light it?
You'll have to run.
You do it.
Are you sure?
Run fast, OK?
Yeah.
Fuck, that was sick!
Imagine if we use one of the big ones!
His car will be blown to pieces.
Whose car?
That asshole, Lars'.
You want to blow up his car?
Sure.
Someone will find out.
A car is really expensive.
Your dad will be pleased.
I'm not so sure.
Doesn't matter. No one will find out.
Are you in or out?
I'm not sure...
If you're not in, I would like my knife back right now.
Easy, easy.
Stretcher! Stretcher!
Lift.
Keep on moving. There's a pulse.
Move on! Up, up, up.
Prep the patient. Put down IV.
Antibiotics.
Thank you. Patient asleep yet?
Yes.
Let me take a look.
Swab. Thank you.
Swab. Hold that, please.
Tell him she's alive.
We've done all we can. Now we must wait and see.
Thank you, doctor.
Ask him what happened.
People came in cars. His wife could not run fast.
The Big Man cut open two other girls, who died.
We'll know tomorrow.
What have you got there?
Nothing special.
If it's nothing special, then I can see it.
No!
Mom, you can't do that!
Elias, this is a knife.
Have you been lying to me and to the police?
Have you gone mad!?
No.
What the hell is going on?
Nothing.
Nothing?
Christian...
Christian.
What the hell were you thinking?
Stabbing someone?
You want to ruin your life?
Look at me.
Look at me, Christian.
Look at me!
Christian...
I love you. But this isn't easy for me either.
We have to talk to each other.
Did you fuck her?
Did you fuck Elias' mom?
Why would you say that?
You want to. I can tell.
You achieve nothing by acting like this.
You said we should talk.
Stop it, right now!
Stop thinking and saying crap like that.
It's not crap!
It's crap!
Is that why you're upset with me?
You're such a liar!
Mom knew you were lying. Everyone knows you're lying.
You know what, Christian?
If mom could see you know,
she would be very unhappy to see what you've become.
Why do you say such mean things? What did I do to you?
I don't care who you're banging.
You don't tell me what's right and wrong.
This is wrong. And illegal.
Never bring a knife to school again.
Do I make myself clear? Never!
You wanted her to die.
No, I didn't.
Yes, you did!
You can't just say it was the best thing for her.
She didn't want to die, and you gave up.
I can't stand people who give up.
Okay?
Christian...
Hi, Sofus.
See you later. Have a nice day.
I didn't tell.
My mom found the knife and freaked out.
Don't you believe me?
Just leave me alone.
Don't text me anymore.
It hurts all the way into his hand.
I can imagine that. I'm gonna give
him some pills, and it will get better.
Easy. Easy. Stay calm.
Are you doctor?
Yes, I am.
Can you fix my leg?
I want to keep it.
I don't want you to cut if off.
I can try.
You can't have any weapons in the camp.
I decide that!
No.
I decide.
Weapons and cars gotta be far away from the camp.
It's Big Man. He's the one that cuts the pregnant women.
He's a monster.
Cars gotta go away.
Cars and weapons gotta go far away from the camp.
Otherwise I can't treat you, and you might lose your leg.
Nurse...
Nurse?
Don't help Big Man. He's evil.
Why do you want to help Big Man?
Because I have to.
He killed all my babies.
I'm so sorry.
He's evil.
I have to go.
You are a strange man.
I think it's malaria. I'm treating her for malaria.
She will be well in two, three days.
I thought we agreed upon only two here at a time.
Take it easy, doctor. See what they've brought me.
They leave now.
Still bad.
Why is it taking so long?
It's a bad infection.
It takes time. Okay?
I have to regain my strength.
You see Omar over there?
He wants to take my position.
Are you my friend?
No, I'm not.
But I'm doing my best to help you.
Everybody has killed here.
Men, women, children.
As long as I don't kill you, we could be friends.
I can be a very powerful friend.
Answer me!
Bag.
Anton.
Anton!
She's gone.
Bag.
Anton.
Check her pulse.
Please, Anton, stop.
She can make it.
Look at me. She's gone.
She's gone.
Help me please.
Little pussy, big knife.
What did you say?
Are you done with her?
Maybe Omar can have her.
Omar likes things that don't move.
Now you go. Out.
Out, out! You leave! Leave! Leave right now!
If you can stand up, you can go! Go! Go!
You're not sick anymore. You leave! You go!
You go!
You're not sick! You leave the camp!
Doctor, I'm unarmed. I've got enemies all over.
Not my responsibility. You go now. You're not sick anymore.
Elias.
Hi, sweetheart.
Hi, dad.
Good to see you, my boy.
Did we talk about calling each other today?
I just wanted to talk to you.
I've had such a busy day. I couldn't remember if we
planned to talk today.
You know Christian?
His granddad died a long time ago
and left some fireworks in the barn.
Nobody found them.
Dad, can you hear me?
I have to tell you something important.
Christian made a bomb, and he's going to blow up a car.
Hello?
Dad?
I'm here.
Could we... I have had a very stressful day.
Could we talk again tomorrow, same time?
Are you okay?
You seem weirder than usual.
I'm okay.
Can we talk tomorrow?
I have to go.
Okay, dad.
I love you. Kisses.
Come on.
I'm in.
I want to make that bomb.
Let's blow up the asshole's car.
I agree. He deserves it.
Come on, we've got classes.
What about the other cars?
The ones next to it will be hit too.
A lot of windows.
What if there are people?
There won't be any.
How do you know?
We'll do it early in the morning.
We'll do it Sunday, when everybody's
asleep, and no one will get hurt.
I have a soccer match Sunday.
Not at seven in the morning.
Don't be such a pussy.
I'm not.
You can't back out now.
Let's do it.
Sure.
Hold the fuse.
Finished playing?
If I died, would you stay here?
I don't wanna argue with you. Don't give me that look.
You're not going to die.
I could.
No, you couldn't.
Would you move back to London or live here with grandma?
I would be so devastated
that I wouldn't want to live anywhere.
It would be good.
You would have to live somewhere, even if I wasn't here.
Why won't you answer my questions?
What do you want me to say?
Like you would be homeless, if I died.
Why do you keep lying to me?
This is crazy. I have never lied to you.
Look at me. I haven't lied to you.
You told me that mom would be OK!
You told me she wasn't in pain.
I'm just as upset about it as you.
I don't think you are.
You wanted her to die.
I know it. Admit it already!
You wanted her to die!
I did want her to die.
In the end.
Because she wanted to.
I couldn't take it anymore.
And she couldn't take it anymore.
She was screaming in pain,
and her brain was eaten away by the cancer.
She asked me to help her so many times. To do it.
I couldn't do it, because I knew how sad it would make you.
And if that is giving up, then I gave up.
I gave up.
But that doesn't mean that I wanted her to die.
Christian.
Are you sure about this?
Yep.
You made it bigger.
Come on.
Okay.
We've got about a minute before it blows.
We'll walk calmly back to our bikes.
Don't look back.
No!
What is it?
Elias!
Stop!
Go back! Back! There's a bomb!
No!
Elias!
Call an ambulance!
Elias? Elias!
What have you got?
Elias, age 12.
He blew up a car.
How is he doing?
Breathing steadily, but unstable pulse.
Okay. Someone take care of the mom please?
He's got a large open wound in his abdomen.
Any other injuries?
Stay here.
We'll pack the abdomen with tissues
and examine him thoroughly.
Listen to me. What you did is very bad.
But if others are involved, that's another matter.
I have to make sure there isn't.
I did it all on my own.
With Elias?
It was my idea.
He just tagged along.
I called the shots.
So you haven't talked to anyone online?
Gotten ideas from someone?
No.
Only the websites I told you about.
One of my colleagues is going to
ask you all these questions again.
How about your other son?
How's he doing?
He's at my mother's.
He doesn't know.
I would like you to stay here.
Just...
Just stay here.
Sure.
Christian is out here. He would like to see Elias.
Can I send him in?
How is he?
Why aren't you with the police?
I was.
My dad picked me up.
Where's your dad?
I would like to see Elias on my own.
You shouldn't be here.
You hear me?
You killed him, you psycho!
You killed him.
I did?
Just stay away, okay?
Just stay away.
You killed him because you're such a
spoiled, little brat who thinks
he can control other people's lives.
Just get out!
That's enough. Stop!
Come with me.
Marianne, we have the results of the CT scanning.
No hemorrhaging in the brain.
Minimal free fluid in the pelvis.
Most likely from the operation.
And no sign of other injuries.
Thank you.
That's all from me. Thank you for the help.
What will happen to them now?
I couldn't say.
Could they take him away?
No.
There are mitigating circumstances.
It will be a case of malicious property damage.
Social services will take over.
Remember that your son saved those people.
Hope he gets well soon.
Thanks.
Elias?
Good.
I'll just remove this.
Look who's here.
Hi.
I'm sorry.
Honey...
Don't be mad at Christian.
We'll deal with that later.
Later.
It was my own fault.
I wanted to do it.
I talked Christian into it.
We'll talk about that later. You just rest.
How could he do such a thing?
I don't know.
He'll be fine.
He'll be okay.
Yes.
I'll take you home, and then I'm going to the summerhouse.
I don't know what to do.
Eva said he would hate me.
Do you think he hates me?
She was so mean in the end.
She was...
She was so mean.
Bitter.
I don't know how to make it better.
He's my little boy, you know?
Yes?
Is that Marianne?
Yes.
Hi, Marianne. Claus here.
Christian's dad. Sorry to call you at this hour,
but I can't find Christian.
Is he at your place?
No, he's not here.
What was that about?
That was Christian's dad. Christian is missing.
I'm the one who called.
I checked the workshop, but he wasn't there.
Christian!
Christian.
It's Elias' dad, Christian.
Step away from the edge.
Get away from the edge, Christian.
Elias is going to be all right.
He's going to be okay.
You think I would come up here
if Elias wasn't going to be okay?
I would be with him.
Wouldn't I?
He's going to be okay.
You have to believe me.
So I didn't kill him?
No.
I thought he was dead.
He's alive.
And he's going to be okay.
I couldn't picture him.
I don't know if children look younger.
When they are dead?
Adults look like children when they are dead.
I know my mom did.
She looked like a little girl.
Like she never grew up.
Like she was never my mom.
I miss her so much.
Sometimes it feels like there's
a veil between you and death.
But that veil disappears when you...
...lose someone you loved
or someone who was close to you,
and you see death clearly
for a second.
But later the veil returns
and you carry on living.
Then things will be all right again.
You think so?
Christian?
Elias' mom is downstairs and would like to talk to you.
Ow!
Stop it. Just stop it.
It's not funny. Stop it!
Ow! Stop it!
Morten, stop it already.
That's enough.
Take it easy.
Stop it.
Morten is so annoying.
Morten, come on. How are you?
Look at this. He can't do anything.
Stop it!
Let's leave them alone and go to the cafeteria.
I want a Coke!
You can have a small one.
A large one.
Didn't you have one when we got here?
I would like another one.
Doesn't it hurt?
They give me these pills.
I told the police everything that happened.
Me too.
It's weird. I've slept for days, but I'm still tired.
I just want to say I'm sorry.
You don't have to.
Yes, I do.
I've been an idiot.
That's all right.
I can't wait till you're back in school.
Same here.