A cloud is over from the west
Snow sleet in the central region
But in the morning
But some people will say that the problem is solved first
Would be better hope you all have a good day
One more story
I have been flying in the universe
mom
Hello there
I don't know why
That is not me
It's my wife
Then your wife must come in person
I want to know first
Ah Young
Dear what's wrong
do not know
Don't you like it
Didn't you go to the cram school?
is it
very scary
Good luck
Will hear
So envious
I also want to use the money my husband made
Buy coffee and drink
Then you marry
You talked a little bit.
I find it too difficult to go to work recently
Or get married
Aren't there Minister Kim?
really
mom
Yes, mother will come
Reason
Well done, Ah Young.
Here is dad
father
Hurry up and wash out
Uh uh
I want to bathe her
Thanks
You didn't eat dinner
Here is dad
Dad will bathe you
Ok
Did not take yours
I'm fine, Oppa.
Hurry up
How is your wrist?
Just use it too much
Do you know what is really sad
The doctor said that the rice is made with a rice cooker
Clothes are washed in a washing machine
Why does it hurt? Ask me like that
really? Eat it all
Are company employees easy because of the electronic products?
Does work become easy?
Yes
Everything can make me sad lately
Really strange. This one
That is not strange
Why does it hurt to talk to someone who hurts?
This
Let's go on a holiday
Don't go to my house or your house
Do you want to rest at home?
I'm so tired recently
Do you want to be trained by mother?
And the person who works is me, not you
It ’s not just this holiday season
I'm really tired
The thought of driving to Busan
It's dark before me
How good to say earlier
What?
I said when I was newly married
Every time my parents’ birthday passes,
Every time the festival passes, it will be a bit tired
When you said that two or three times a year would be fine.
How can I do this?
I still say this
Didn't I go when I was pregnant?
And if you don’t go
Who would be gossiped
Can you blame your own son
They will blame me
mom
Today is the first day of the Spring Festival holiday
Roads are clear in most areas
Better road condition than last year
The long vacation lasted five days, so the traffic flow was dispersed.
This Spring Festival Expressway
After finishing these, make dumplings.
Yes
Why is there so much
Doing dumpling business
Who can finish eating?
What's wrong with you
Making fuss
Recently, holiday takeaways are also selling very well.
It tastes good too
The family eats together once a year
Is it necessary to order takeaway
No, I'm afraid you will be affected.
Are you worried about me
A lot of dishes  to wash
Let me do it
Go and wait
My daughter-in-law really has a good husband.
Mom, I make it at home
I didn't say anything
I said my son was handsome and I didn’t say anything to you
Not that
Mom, you should have more sons.
Then there will be another daughter-in-law
Dad, what are you doing? No more fuel?
Kick the accelerator down
Is this kid crazy
Are you looking for an uncle?
What happened to you two today
Mom
Why don't you sleep more
I got enough sleep
Mom, do you have to cook all spinach?
Yeah
Ah I have something to give you
I don't know if you like it or not
Mom, what is this?
Mom is so pretty.
Do you like patterns?
I have a long queue to buy this.
Thank you
This is Ah Young's friend, Bolubu.
Isn't it hot?
Don't scorch
Grandpa, look at this
The luggage is packed and dry
Hurry up after finishing this
Okay, let's go first.
Mother-in-law, here we are.
Hurry up hurry up
Grandmother
Bought something on the way
I bought some on the way
You can spend a lot of time exhausted
Come in fast
I'm afraid you are leaving
Why do you buy so much?
Isn't a family reunion a festival?
Ah Young Ah Young
Like look at this. Look at this
Oh my god
When did you buy it?
Just bought some
What else
it's beautiful
Oh my god
A daughter is the best
Yes yes
it's beautiful
We are so happy.
Aunt bought so many beautiful clothes
She's still the cutest.
Of course, she is so cute
Mother-in-law, you know
You are still the best
You must have very tired today
Yes, I did a lot
By the way, make some oil cakes
Bring chopsticks, spoon and scissors
Mom, I can get it myself
You're not at your in-laws.
Ji Young, you are tired, come back to rest.
Mom, I bought it well, right?
Yes, it ’s great.
Oh my princess, little princess, yeah
My granddaughter is so cute
You deserve to be my granddaughter
Pretty pretty
Mom, honestly, do you miss me more or Da Hyung more?
What are you talking about
that's it
I know
mother-in-law
Really want me to rest, just let me go home
Isn't this what it should be?
My mother will want to see her daughter happy at the festival, right?
I also want to see my daughter
What does this child say
Since your daughter is here
And let my daughter go.
This
You have to take care of your in-laws and leave.
How sad should my family be?
Ah Young, what are you doing?
In-laws
I am also a daughter
This is for a reason, I will explain to you later
This
Oppa, I'm going to the bathroom
Is it still far from the service area?
I will stop at the next service area
Ji Young is a little bit
Not very uncomfortable
Don't let mom call Ji Young.
Oh got it
Oh my god
Can I help?
No need
Just don't let mom call
Understood
I will live in vain
We care too little about Ji Young
What should I do
It's okay, no problem
Bye
Oh, I see
How much longer
Mom must be waiting.
Are you tired?
No, I miss mom
We are so good
Do you miss grandma
Eun Young, get some rice wine for Mr. Jung
Jiseok
What did you ask me to do?
I can get it myself
No, I don't
Jiseok
Kim Eun Young. Kim Eun Young
Brother-in-law, you know
How tired is it to be a man in this home?
Hello, think about you. Since 1988,
you are enjoying the benefits
That's me, but my son
Dad, stop talking.
But Ji Young has been sleeping
I think she is tired
Is it
Did you catch it?
Unnie, our country is as such a small country
Yeah, the world is so big
Let's make a mark on the country we want to go to
OK, Ji Young is going to get the stickers
Ok
Unnie, which color do you choose?
I choose green
Then I choose purple
I choose the United States.
How about Unnie?
I choose Sweden.
Denmark
Finland
Why are you going to these strange places?
Because there are no Koreans there
What do you mean?
You don't need to know
Don't
Noisy
Why are you so noisy when you first moved here?
Girls must be quiet
Got it? come out.
Help mom eat food
what
Grandma... grandma
Unnie grabbed my candy and make it dirty
How is your wedding?
Oh oh
Nothing
You haven't come, he's quite dead!
I won't die forever
Now that you're married, let's do it.
Misuk
For your brothers to go to school, you have to suffer
Really?
Stop talking, mom.
Hurry and go back after lunch.
Ji Young, Eun Young
Put the tableware
Yes
Mother-in-law
Are you happy to move?
I also go out and played for several days.
Oh, because of my second son.
Yes, son-in-law is amazing
Mom, eat.
Come and eat
Anyway, there must be at least four men in the house.
I hope my daughter can have a son again.
This is all for your own good.
Gave birth to Jiseok.
Space r card
Grandma
Second Uncle and third uncle are unwilling to see you.
You still likes your son so much?
Hey, what did you say?
Who did she follow?
I will honor my mother.
Ouch, this kid
The small mouth is so sweet
When you grow up, try to get married
I won't say that by the time
No, it ’s not
Ji Young, eat more
Auntie
Are you ready?
The most useless worry in the world
I was worried about Kim Eun Young.
Everyone is together
Is it any holiday today?
Oh, our Kim Ji Young hasn’t woke up yet.
She looks tired
Jiseok, this pen
Where did you find it
Under the table
Isn't that pen? When Dad went to England on a business trip
Did you just buy it for Jiseok?
It's a notebook for both of us
It's also a British notebook
Right, dad?
Start again. Start again.
Really
Brother-in-law
Be careful with Kim Ji Young
She is super persistent
I asked for that for ten years.
But you didn’t get it you due to stubbornness
Oppa, this is a little weird
Um what
About Mom, why didn’t you give Gui this time?
I said it’s not necessary.
Why don't I remember?
Always forgetting things recently
Don’t you have amnesia after giving birth?
Someone in our group had a child not long ago
He said his wife had postpartum depression
What kind of disease? Is it very serious?
It seems that you can’t just wait and see.
Yeah, I read the news too.
How about you?
Me?
This should be fine
I always think about the past
I feel empty when the sun goes down
But this is not always the case
Otherwise, you can go to psychiatry.
Why do you think I'm neurotic?
Hey, who said it was mentally ill recently?
Many people in our company go to a psychiatric clinic regularly
Chat with a doctor
Maybe you can sort out the feeling of chronic depression
Then, should I go there?
Ask why the heart is empty when the sun goes down
Alright
Colleagues say there is a nice place
You go there
I'll give you contact information. Okay?
I am out of breath
What happened to you recently?
Mom
Welcome
I am not the first customer
Who cares about this recently?
And our shop
I like women as first customer.
Is it?
Dad, I took these,
It is good
I'm going out
Careful on the road
I heard she found a job this time
Yes, it's so worrying.
The planning team released the list
Have you seen it?
Yes
Good morning
Congratulations
You have been selected into the planning team
I really don't want to go.
Hey, it's you, who is chosen by Team Leader Kim.
You have to feel honored.
He only chose men.
Team Leader is particularly fierce
It's ruthless.
Reinstated less than a month after giving birth.
Who will take care of that child?
Captain Kim lives with her mother
Wow, isn't her husband amazing?
The child is taken care of by the mother
Why is her husband amazing?
It’s harder to living with in-laws.
Interlude son-in-law
What did you say?
What are you going to do?
Yes
Is it done?
Director Yang is here
So fast
Chatting with Team Leader
Unnie
Let's take advantage of the atmosphere of the Beijing Olympics
How about sports stars Park Tae-hyun?
He must be expensive
Our team leader’s child is not that old
No, he will go to middle school this year
Middle school
This is worse. This is worse.
It's going to be a storm
These children brought up by the mother
The period of rebellion is very serious
Well, my mother takes good care of it
Grandma and mother are different
The child must stay with his mother
Otherwise, he will go wrong
If the career is successful, how can the child ruin everything?
Really worrying
This feels good as a promotional word
Because mother didn't bring up
And the children's vitamins
"Sweeping breath training prepared by mother's mind"
It's better to say so
I will be stung by moms at work in the future
Then you have to hit me once.
Team leader, this is a bit overdone, right?
Chief Kim, I can’t afford to joke
It’s scary, don’t do this
That's why Team Leader Kim can survive to this day.
This is a pity
I should be born as a man, right?
director
OK, how about a meeting?
Alright
The strategy for this event
Is to expand influence on digital media
Compare to 10% of digital media advertising today
Expanded to about 30%
Actively participate in promotional activities
Team Leader is so cool
She talked to Director Yang with a smile.
Terrible
You are dead
I was worried about
I am afraid of Director Yang being angry
Then you have to beat me once.
OK, how about a meeting?
Come to my office
Yes
These words are good for journalists.
Humor is just right
You don’t need to modify it at all.
Keep it up
Thank you
Go back to work
Is there anything else to note?
I don't. I just ask you to come to praise you
What's wrong?
I thought you hated me.
Why? Is it because of the planning team?
Yes
Why didn't you take me to the planning team?n
It's not because you are not strong enough
The company hopes to form a long-term team
But the female employee is to be on maternity leave
So it ’s hard to last long
Even if I insist on adding you
I'm afraid there will be a lot of burden
No, I can do well
Ji Young, do I look good to you?
Yes.
What's good?
I am not a good mother.
Not a good wife, not a good daughter.
But you are still cool
Even if I get married and have children,
I am confident that I can work well, just like you
Bye
Go to our house
Really?
Mother, Eunsuk and Ms. Shuxi are both upset
Ah Young's mother
We are going to have a cup of tea together
Come with us too
Ah, I still have something
Ah do you work?
Young Ho is pretty good
What awesome
Let him try as an idol
What idol?
What's Ah Young's mother doing?
Come and sit
Do you have older children?
That's the problem I solved
Come over and sit down
Come over
How many hours do I have to solve?
The strange thing is that when solving math problems
There will be dim sum
Oh my god
Young Ho's mother is a science student at Seoul National University.
I don’t know why I studied so hard
In order to teach Young Ho the multiplication
One is so
I just came over
But what is Ah Young's mother's major?
Mine is Mandarin
The novelist?
No, it’s just a dream at school
After graduation, to work at a publicity company.
That's it.
What is your profession?
I'm studying for my family
I took the performance department
Yes
Mirror, mirror
Who is the most beautiful person in the world?
Snow White
I want to kill her
Is your child okay?
I am so angry that I will cry
This act has some tricks
After sending the child to school
It’s just in the morning.
If it weren't for a move, I would love to continue.
It’s not too difficult to just look after the cash register.
it is good
Hello, Unnie
Oh come on
Good good
Oh, Ah Young is so good
She can speak now
Is it so fast?
Not a genius
But like my Oppa, he is very talented in language.
Um, it's Dae Hyun.
Oh, Ah Young is so good
You're almost there
But Dae Hyun is too energetic, right?
Why are you blaming my Oppa?
He often helps me
What does it mean to help you?
right
By the way, there is news
Team leader Kim is resigning
why
Maybe she can't stand it
Hey, what about it?
The problem is that you can't be promoted.
I heard she want to start a company.
Focus on the promotion team
Feeling like Mi Jung is also going to go
What about you?
I was promoted this time
So I want to see it again
Congratulations congratulations
congratulations
What are you talking about?
Male colleagues joined in the same period last year
Can all titles be changed?
Jealous
Just think about it, I'll be jealous again
Anyway, I envy you
You call Team Leader and try
me?
Yeah. You go back to work
I can't
Occasionally part-time
I'm afraid it's hard to go to work.
Okay then, don't go to work
Hello, bring up Ah Young well
That is also a great thing
Ji Young, there you are.
I am a spinster
Work hard all my life until I die
Don't you think it's funny, I'm a spinster
Funny
Do you have to laugh?
It is funny, Unnie
Bye
Ah, you are Ah Young's ....
Are you ok?
I thought I was running late
Note again
Ah Young
What?
Ok
This rice is really getting worse
Is it really hot?
What
Look at this again
What are you looking at
It's nothing
okay
What are they looking at?
Don't you know?
After nothing more than setting up a chat group
Upload Erotic Photo
Should be considered a beast
Unreasonable
so envious
what?
No, they have at least time to be ridiculous
So feel envious
Ouch, as long as I go home
Children scramble for me to play with them
Where is the final photo? I still have to see his wife's face
That is, ten is dizzy, dizzy
Suddenly depressed again
I always feel like going to the hospital
It would be better if I went to the hospital?
I mean like depression
You suffer too
Let's go together
Hello, let's go and see together.
You've given a lot of evidence recently
No, it's not me
But my friend's wife thinks
Occasionally makes him feel like they are
What is it? Is it a ghost? Is it psycho?
Not that kind of thinking
That's crazy
No no
Does his wife know his status?
I don’t know. My friend didn’t tell her.
Why?
May be afraid.
Must be afraid
If that person knows his situation,
Will it get worse?
Just right just right hey
It’s a laughing stock to live with that kind of person
Wait and see, that woman will be psycho soon
Soon I will be carrying a sword or something
Sooner or later, he will be stabbed.
Weird
Like a crazy woman
Should be isolated from society.
Sorry, I thought it was empty
Damn, what happened to him?
I said, do you want to go to the gym?
How can there be time for that?
It's for fitness
Will make you feel better and help your health
Oppa
Then, I'll go to the bakery for a part-time job.
Just across the road
Do you want to do?
What?
Ji Young, what's your situation now?
No, you're tired of taking care of Ah Young
Only in the morning
Don't do it
Should not be too tired
No one wants you to do that part-time job
Ji Young,
I stop you from doing what you want
Let alone watch what you don’t want to do
Your body is tired too
I just thought
Oppa, thank you.
Thank you for caring about my body.
Are you drinking?
Are you angry?
Don't you know how to drink?
It seems you are angry
Hello, Jung Dae Hyun
Ji Young is suffering recently
Although weaned, her body was a little relaxed
But she was so anxious
Talk to her more
Well done, thank you
Ji Young
Hey, I know you like Ji Young
Stop calling, be careful.
do not do that
In your eyes
I'm still the one who was so nervous and shivering in the midsummer
Are you still 20-year-old that Che Seung-yeon confessed?
Cha Seung Yeon is my college classmate.
She is also the school senior of the mountaineering community that Ji Young joined.
Ji Young likes Seung Yeon a lot.
But something happened last year when she gave birth.
It makes Ji Young sad for a long time.
She has been depressed for a while.
Is that the cause?
Anyway, I want to see her in person.
Oppa, really?
A few days ago did I really drink?
Yes.
Really?
I wake up in the morning with cans on the nightstand
I still have alcohol in my mouth
But why am I not impressed?
So be sure to check it out today
Ok?
Got it, let me go
Definitely
Okay, be careful, be late.
Surely
I know
Mom are you in the shop?
At this time, of course, in the shop
Where is Ah Young?
Yeah but
Do you need a receipt?
Ji Young, wait a minute
Thank you for your patronage
Ji Young
Mother is busy now
Ok
By the way, come this weekend
Of course
But, Oppa have to attend a company seminar
Ah I heard
Welcome
If it's okay, I'll hang up.
Do you have to do this?
Yes
How much is the inspection fee?
There are three checks to be done
The cost is about 350,000
So I came out
Don't you know?
what did you say?
No, aren't you all registered?
Do you know what the inspection fee is
I can't bear it, I'm not serious
Ji Young, you
Oppa
Do I talk in my sleep?
I don't understand. Why would you want me to go to the hospital?
It's not
Because you say forgetfulness and uneasiness
No
Usually forgetful after giving birth
It's not that I'm upset.
Blame me for talking
Rest assured. I'm fine
Hello, Ji Young.
Hey, I want to ask you something.
Um what's up?
Didn't Team leader Kim's phone change?
of course
The team leader is going back to the office
Would you like her to answer the phone?
Not very convenient now
No, no,  Unnie, I will hang up
Yeah, come back later
Okay, ok, wait for me
I will go out.
Don't go to the toilet on the third floor
Why? Why?
Just listen to me
You must tell me why.
If not, I still have to go
No, I'm going crazy
Wait a minute
Do you have a tablet?
The third floor is broken. Go to another floor.
No, I went to just now
Unnie
What's wrong with your face? Is it uncomfortable?
Come here
Did you say that the hidden camera is installed?
Yeah
What about that security guard?
That bastard is the installer
But the person I'm angry with is Mr. Wu.
No. Since I found that photo on the Internet
If you know it's our company, you should call the police.
How can I sit it with my male colleagues?
Too ridiculous
I always go to the bathroom on the third floor
I thought of going to the police station tomorrow to verify my photo
My heart is terrible
Honestly, everyone is comforting me
But when I think of that bastard, I see my ass.
I'm so mad at him
This is terrible.
Hey, when we go to the bathroom,
Must check it out
Check for small holes
Hey, who cares about those photos when you are in a hurry?
Urinal
Hey, how can you hold a urinal?
Ji Young
Are you using Ah Young with wet urine?
Are you uncomfortable?
Do you want to sit?
No need.
Hey
Don't go
Did you hear me calling you?
Classmate
As soon as you got off the car
I am frightened
it's okay, no problem
Ji Young, Ji Young
Dad
What's up?
It's okay now
Why are you going to such a cram school?
Replace it immediately
You must be dressed appropriately
It is hot and see how short the skirt is
And don't smile at people
I didn't smile, I don't even remember the guy's face
That is the problem
Why can't you remember?
You should always pay attention
Don't take it lightly and avoid that kind of person
The guy came by himself
Can he bear it?
If you can't avoid. It is your own fault
Got it?
Are you ok?
Ah yeah
Ji Young
Are you Ji Young?
what are you talking about
What's wrong with you?
Mom
I can't understand
Why did you leave like that?
God
Really weird
Sorry
Also you said sorry.
What are you sorry about?
I have to go back to the company
Then I have to go back too
You go back to my house, as long as you don't tell Ji Young
I looked at her who was ill
I'm thin-skinned
Are you ok?
Certainly
Hey it's strange
Why is she?
Hey
Hi, mother-in-law
It's me. I'm in Seoul
Are you in Seoul?
I came over once
I'm going back now
Why don't you come and sit at home?
Just go back
I have something tomorrow, I have to go back
The thing is..
I know a Chinese medicine hospital is famous
I'll prescribe some tonic and send it to you
You have to eat on time
I should prescribe it for you
Eat well
Looking at children and not eating on time
It will hurt me
Ok
I hang up. Bye
Where is that blue muffler?
It is hanged
No upper left corner
Why is the seminar today?
Otherwise, I won't go
Nevermind
You should take a taxi. Promise me
If you feel tired, just call me
I'll call you, can you run over right away?
Okay, hurry and be late
I'm leaving
Ah Young, dad is gone.
kiss
Your princess is wet.
Sorry
Alright, alright
Ah Young
Wait a minute
Mom goes to the toilet too
The teacher's handwriting looks good
I used to want to be a teacher
Really
When mom was in elementary school
Among the five siblings
Mom's learning is the best
Better than my sister-in-law
But why didn't you go to be a teacher?
To make money for my brothers to go to college
What do you make?
Mom is..
Making clothes in Cheonggyecheon
It's okay. The girls at that time were so white and vivid.
All come here
Then you can be a teacher now.
Now, she's Ji Young's mother
I have to take care of you
Is it because of me, you can’t do it?
mom
You've slept
Is the seaweed soup ready?
Should I do it?
No more. No more.
Where are you, Ah Young?
Eun Young scared me and made me do nothing
What will she do?
I should buy it if Kim Eunyoung
I don't know. Jiseok called.
Where's dad?
Dad went to pick up the aunts,
You should be very tired to bring your child here.
She pooped on the road
Whoops, Ah Young still poops
You are just like my daughter
Or to say
You’re like my Oppa. You just touched your abs.
What a fuss is drunk
Yes
If she is someone's daughter or someone's sister
These are all considered sexual harassment
Do you understand?
Maybe you will wear handcuffs.
Why on earth do you have to attend this class?
Where is the purpose?
All because you want someone like you to provoke
When you treat female employees, be safe
The times have changed
Abominable
I should be born in the Joseon era
Come here. Please leave me
Why are there so many things to be careful about lately?
It’s hot
I think of my wife, my heart is very dull
It’s better than my wife’s wishes.
Parental leave
Yes, my wife asked me to ask for parental leave.
Otherwise, she gave all the money she made to the babysitter
Go to work by herself
So be it
You go on like this
It's the same as Agent Park's end.
When you come back, your desk is goodbye
Did he retire?
How could that be said
See the seniors taking parental leave
They look all over their faces
The atmosphere is like this
Just feeling
What on earth do you want me to do?
This color is so pretty
Thank you  Unnie
how about it
Nice mom
Unnie, we are going to wear this elegant thing recently
Of course
That dress should be more gorgeous
What's wrong? I'm fine.
What good
Ji Young
No matter how difficult it is to raise a child, you must dress yourself up
Women should be beautiful
I'm pretty without clothes
What are you looking at?
Why is Jiseok not seeing anyone?
Yes, where did Jiseok go?
coming
Come over
What are these?
Are those made by Eun Young?
Where can I cook?
I found a gourmet restaurant
Why should you buy it
Mother makes some meals
On dad's birthday, mom will cook
Mother ’s birthday
Isn't it good
Yeah, the eldest daughter is the best
Jiseok, come here.
The daughters of this family are really special
Just order takeaway.
Why are you asking your younger brother to move things?
Where is he young? He is over thirty
Even if you have gray hair, youngest is the youngest.
You don’t know how to cherish your brother
Aunt, then me
I'll have a daughter too
Sons are useless
Watch them set the table for mom
So filial
Eun Young, aren't you planning to get married?
Aunt, stop talking.
It's good now. What should I do in the future?
Able to live by myself
Regardless of ability
I can live well by myself
You are so special
She is special
mom
No, I mean you are exceptional
Go to the dining table
Jiseok
Ok
What happened?
As soon as you wake up
Are you awake then?
This this
Really
I haven't seen aunt for a long time
a bit tired
I said a family had a simple meal
Anyway, she has a lot to do
Unnie, you don't let it go
Aren't you tired?
Is this coffee?
I said, am I tired?
But what should I do to fight back?
Hey, isn't there that kind of character in the game?
The more they are beaten, the more the energy value rises
I asked them to play a role called Teacher Kim
Fun
People hit you like this
What's wrong with Jiseok?
How did you grow up like this?
Very cute
I miss grandma
How grandma doted on you..
She always say our Jiseok, our Jiseok
But our Jiseok
Grow up into a nice man
Are you popular?
I think so.
Kneel
What?
You made me
kneel
Ouch
It's so painful, Kim Eun Young.
What are the children doing?
Aunts are going back
OK, coming out now
Oops
I kicked them
Then he got on his knees
Unnie
Kim Eun Young, you really are
Be careful
This impulse will cause something big
I don't want to see you
Are you worried about me
Oh, you don't have to worry
I'm strong against that kind of person
Yes, when my Unnie was in high school
Partnered with friends to catch a seductive boat
Yeah, I caught him and gave him to the police.
Then I was taught a hard meal by the teachers
Schoolgirl doesn't know me
I cursed those teachers
But I became a teacher
Unnie, didn't you want to go to normal university?
What resistance
Yeah, my mother said that because of the situation at home,
So I went to the normal school and cried for a long time.
Really?
My father retired because of the economic crisis
You still have to learn
It ’s a good choice in every way.
I'm sorry because Jiseok and I coaxed
What are you doing?
You also wanted to be a writer or reporter
After all, I'm looking for a job.
Each other is a concession
Sensible
No I'm eating rice cake
Really naive
Do the students hate my  Unnie?
No, my popularity is really strong
Who?
What's wrong with your expression?
You are good
Stop it.
How are you?
Good. How are you?
OK
How are you doing?
It's been 26 months now
Although it’s hard to raise, it’s very cute, right?
Yes.
Team leader
what?
Are you surprised that I sent you a message
Ok join
me?
Yes, it's exactly the same as the work in previous company
But the monthly salary is only 80% of your previous salary.
But I will give you a guarantee
Monthly salary is not a problem, can I do it well?
I haven't worked for several years.
How did you become a coward?
Our company is small, are you dissatisfied?
No, you can invite me, I'm very grateful to you.
Let's work together
Ah thank you
I will work hard
Ji Young's graduation day
How can we stop business temporarily?
Why not just open at night?
I don't know
I won't go anyway, I can't get a job anyway
You kid, you will regret it later
No graduation picture
Forget it, I won't regret
Ji Young
Stop talking
Don't do anything if you are so sad
Just w ait to get married
This suits you
What did you just say?
What time is it now?
He said such a cliché
Ji Young, you can't be quiet
You need to be lively
Did you hear?
Damn
Give me water
Really
What are you doing?
Um, it ’s all right
Hey
Daehan Planning?
Ok
Mom, I'm qualified.
Really?
is it?
What should I do, Unnie?
Good
Dad, you don’t support me either
Let's eat
We eat
You eat meat
eat more
Ah  Unnie
I met Team Leader and talked about work.
OK, but can you
Yeah, you have to work hard to make it happen
Yeah, try to do what you can
Ji Young, come on
understood
Is it my birthday today?
what?
Oppa, I found a job
Is Ah Young going to work all day?
Let her stay in the kindergarten all day
I think Ah Young will be very uncomfortable
I inquired about Baoma group
Between five and seven
It’s better to hire a babysitter
And government support for childcare
But that waiting time is too long
I sign up first
Ok
Oppa
Don't you want me to go back to work?
No
I'm afraid you and Ah Young will suffer
Then I won't go
No, if you are happy, I am happy
Ji Young
Are you angry?
Yes, I am.
Why should you care about that?
I'm hungry, can you cook for me?
Cook for me. Cook for me
Really?
Why are you in the presence of your in-laws?
What about our family plans?
Adults love to say this
Because there is nothing to talk about
Get married early when we're not married
When married, they urge us to have children
Having a son, they urge us to have a daughter
Having a daughter, they urge us to have a son
I have a good way
what?
Let's eat first
Forget it
To be tossed every time I go home
Give birth to one
what?
We'll have one, and I will take good care of you
It ’s like buying watermelon and oranges in the supermarket.
Anyway, we have to give birth
Rather than being urged to live,
Have a child
It can't affect our lives.
Could it be so?
I will help you well
Hey
I change her diaper
I think I have to change a lot
What would you change, Oppa?
me
I will of course change
I have to go home early, can't drink, can't see friends
If the child looks like you, it will be cute
Forget it. I'm depressed
You are depressed because you are hungry
I have low blood sugar. Hurry up and cook for me.
Oppa, I'm really depressed
Oppa, what makes you uncomfortable?
What are you doing?
Oppa, are you okay?
Let's try my waist
Create a baby for me
Let's have a child
Hey really? hey
Is she still here?
Seems to be
She used to be responsible for her work
After maternity leave,
She came to slacking
Sorry, the child has HFMD
Can't get him to kindergarten
Report on the analysis of industry trends yesterday
Come here quickly
What is this?
Mom told you to be quiet
Auntie will come here in the future.
Got it?
Come see goodbye to diapers
Ah Young, try it too, goodbye diapers
Goodbye good job
I didn't make a call
Really?
Well, I think it’s the same result.
Recruitment website did not contact
Let me see
Should I
take parental leave?
Oppa?
I will take care of Ah Young for one year before returning to work
Will there be a solution at that time?
Next year,
She will adapt, too.
It ’s all brought up like this
I went to primary school in a flash.
Can Oppa's company take parental leave?
Since there is a system, we should make good use of it
Don't worry, do what you want to do
I also take this opportunity to read the book
Learn a little bit more
Oppa
Right, are you loving me more and more?
I became more handsome, right?
Ah Young, mother can go to work now
Tell your mother, Fighting
High five
Good picture
So happy
Ah Young, do you think
mom should call grandma?
Yeah
Mother-in-law, the Chinese medicine you delivered is arrived
Eh yes hey
After taking the Chinese medicine you made for me, I will work hard
What job are you going to work?
Boss who worked together before
Invite me to work at her
What are you talking about?
Yes?
Hey are you crazy?
Isn’t it too much?
Mother-in-law is not like this
My son has a bright future
Why are you so impulsive?
Mother-in-law
Don't want to listen, you hang me up
Ah my dear, mother, hello
How much can a baby's mother go out to make money?
If she want to work, shs can have a part-time job nearby.
How can she ask her husband to take parental leave?
Isn't it too much?
Mother-in-law
Ji Young should learn from my family.
She also worked hard
Ji Young gave birth to the child.
It's Ji Young who brought her own child.
Go to each other to support the test of life,
help each other live
He is slacking and he also has problems at work
Ji Young is not feeling well.
It seems you don’t know the problem
Mother-in-law, your daughter is abnormal now.
Haven't you heard about the festival last time?
Yeah, how can you tell like that, mother?
Hey me
See you so anxious
Isn't this about you?
Till when are you going to hide?
Mom, can you do this if you are sick?
It's too sad for you to say this
Maybe you want to let Ji Young who is sick go out to work
Ji Young works outside if she faints.
Mom, why are you suddenly going to the second Noona's house?
You will close the store before you go back
Mom phone
mother in law
Ji Young
I'm thinking about mom
It's all a lie. Right?
what?
What are you doing, mom? Anything w rong?
Nothing
I just miss you
Ji Young, eat on time
You have to be healthy to do everything
Mom will sort it out as soon as possible
Come here to help you look after Ah Young
Go to work
Mom will help you
Do what you want
Mom left first
I'm leaving
Misuk
Don't do that
When you were in your youth
To take care of your Oppas
Stepping on a sewing machine in Cheonggyecheon
Thin face
Whenever you get your salary back on time
Mom's heart is like cut by a knife
You were too good
You got your hands back like that with a sewing machine
Don't mention how heartbroken I am
I couldn't hug you well
I couldn't say a word of thanks, Misuk.
Sorry
Ji Young, even if she works hard,
You made her strong
My child
my baby
Jung son-in-law, how can my child be like this?
How could Ji Young become like this?
Ji Young, yeah
Oh, Ji Young.
Ji Young
mom
What happened?
Jiseok scared me.
He call me and tell me mom's sick.
What happened at Ji Young's?
Jiseok?
Is this medicine for mom?
No, your mom drank another.
This is a good medicine for men
What is it?
What is this stuff?
Is there only a son in your eyes?
Because she can't do anything she want
Ji Young is almost becoming an empty shell.
You still carelessly whispered in a bag with a limb
Are you still a father?
What's going on?
All the elders opened his son's hospital
I helped line a box
So
If you want to buy a box
Why not buy for the daughters
Can the girls not get sick?
My child
Ji Young, Ji Young
Um all photos
What?
I need a box
My daughter
Can you help with me on Sunday?
Of course you can be busy
Ji Young, are you uncomfortable?
Where I am not comfortable?
Not looking well
Recently a bit
Unnie, I'm afraid I can't go to Team Leader Kim's company.
Why is it because of the child?
Yeah, there is no place to entrust Ah Young.
What Dae Hyun said?
Oppa said he would ask for parental leave.
Then it's fine
But  mother-in-law said it wouldn't work
Ji Young, isn't this fair?
You are also like your husband
Read books, walk into the society and work
OK, pregnancy can be said to be impossible
Children can always be born
Unnie, is that easy to say?
Actually, mother-in-law didn't say anything wrong.
I can't earn as much as my Oppa when I go to work
The money I made
May not be enough to pay Ah Young nursery and nanny salary
Really depressing
Wait a little
Come
Just sleep
Noisy
I'm going to talk to Team Leader in person
That I can't go to work
Think about it
No way, can't it?
Tired before reinstatement
Yeah, take a break
You also rest
I'll get better when Ah Young grows up
Is taking care of the child resting?
But right.
I know this is not good
But I can't stop speculating
Is Oppa like mother-in-law?
Don't want me to go to work
Did you regret taking parental leave?
Ji Young, it's definitely not the case.
I didn't think about taking childcare too hard
I really said that for your sake
Stop talking about it for me
To be honest, I don't believe it
You, mother-in-law and my family are the same
It's none of your business anyway
It's only me in war
Ji Young, calm down and listen to me
Didn't I tell you to go to the psychiatry?
you.
I am sick now
What do you mean?
Does that make you feel relieved?
Where am I sick?
Ji Young, you occasionally become another person.
Ah Young
What are you doing dear?
Daughter-in-law, it's Dahan today
Although it's not as cold as Osamu, the wind is quite cold
wear more clothes
Honey, you look like mother-in-law
Are you here, grandma?
Stop bullying
What should I start with?
As long as I get treatment, right?
Fortunately, Ah Young is still young.
If she is sensible, she will find me strange.
It’s not often
Only occasionally
You must be very hard, Oppa.
I'm still scared of
I'm afraid you have gotten sick
I always think you are like this because of marrying me
It's all because of me,
Put straight into the refrigerator
Put it all together
Ok
give
Take it, be careful not to spill
Ok
Hey
Oh Jiseok
dad
Oh, I'm going to the second noona's house for a side dish
What, what
What does second noona like?
Ji Young?
She likes bean paste bread
Red bean paste
Oh
What is going on with these breads?
To give it to you noona.
You will bring things when you come to my house
It's like becoming a person
Do you want bread?
Ah Young doesn't like to eat bean paste bread
She doesn't like this
Do you say you don't like bean paste bread?
Eat
I just pull out the red bean paste
What the hell?
Dad said you like to eat bean paste bread
It’s you who like to eat red bean paste
I like cream
what is this?
Give it to you
Can I take this?
Or wait for you to make money
Buy me a better one
You know it's obvious that you're doing this
I'm leaving
Ah Young
Go After dinner
I have an appointment
Don't get sick, Noona,
I'll finally hear you call me as Noona
Jiseok, thanks.
Next time I will buy cream bread
Finally met?
That is,
The sick person is me
I am the last one to know
How do you feel?
I heard if I scared you afterwards.
I’m so scaed.
You know when I'm treating a patient
What is the hardest process?
The hardest part is getting the patient to sit in front of me
To come here
Sitting in front of the doctor
It means the treatment was successful
Just listening to you say that
Also makes me feel good
Yeah mom
Are you in the shop?
Um just came out
What about you? Have you had breakfast?
Yes
I ate it with Ah Young
How about you?
Your dad's breakfast is always on time
I will of course eat it
mom
Yes?
Mom, do you remember
When I was born?
Then of course, how can I not remember it?
The day you were born
The cherry blossoms in the sky are beautiful
I hurry to pack up and go to the hospital
Cherry blossoms flying
It’s like snow and goose feathers
I may be with you
The day Ah Young was born
It's snowing
I gave birth to such a beautiful daughter
Too bad
Come
What is the name of our company?
Is it good with me?
Superb
Don't lie to me
What is this?
Wish you business
Thanks
What are you doing as a guest?
It's a ghost
What's up?
talk about it
Team Leader Kim, I'm afraid it's difficult.
Why didn't you hire a babysitter?
Yes
How about doing a part-time job?
That's not OK
I
Get treatment in psychiatry
This time
People who don’t go to the hospital are even better.
This job requires a lot of field trips and meetings
How dangerous
If I talk nonsense during the meeting
What should we do?
When I'm fine enough to come to work
I will contact you again
Dr.
I think it's good to live like this
As someone else's mom
Someone else's wife
I feel happy sometimes
But sometimes
I feel like I'm locked in somewhere
I always feel over the wall ~
I should be able to find the exit, but still return
Even if I find another way, I still run into a wall
Sometimes I want to say
Is there no exit from the beginning?
I'll be angry for this too
Yeah
But then I understood again
Actually all this is my fault.
Others should also find their own exit
I am just incapable of myself
Just outdated
It's not your fault.
Then why only I live so embarrassed?
When you were angry before?
How did you do it?
Why do so many women bring children here?
Really noisy
I have to find a child-free area in the future.
Where's the child-free zone?
It's really noisy.
Assuredly
Oh wait
Why not?
Ah Young
In trouble
What a nuisance
How good it is to drink at home?
yes
How can I clean this up?
Really a mother worm
Hello, people will hear
Mom Worm is Mom Worm
Hello, this is really speechless.
Let's go drink in the park
Will be a little cold there
Better than here
Yeah it's too noisy here
That is to say
Excuse me
Do you know me?
what?
Why am I the mother worm?
Let's go
I ask you why I am a worm
No, I didn’t tell you.
Who did you say that to?
Come here for some coffee
You meet me for only about ten minutes.
Just know how much you know about me?
What kind of things have I experienced?
What kind of people have you met?
Do you know what you think?
I have only seen you once
Would you like me to evaluate you too?
Tell me what kind of person you are
What does this aunt say?
But it’s what we said ourselves.
Since you said it yourself
Please don't let me hear
Why spend energy to hurt others?
Let's go
Go
do not talk
Just leave
go
Let's go let's go
Hurry up
mom
Mommy mommy
Ah Young, it's okay
All right
Mommy mommy
See if mom doesn't cry
Mother is strong
So don’t you cry, Ah Young
Mommy mommy
OK, don't cry
Ah Young doesn't cry
Well done let's go
So, do you feel happy?
It's not
Neither happy nor depressed
But
It's not bad.
Oppa, it's spring
Can you see over there?
Sprouts have sprung up.
What's wrong?
You crybaby
I'm fine
I'm ok
Let's go
Dad, let's go.
Did you have fun?
Yes
Let's go
It is good
Are you hungry?
Yes
What to eat at night?
Ice cream
We will eat
Then I want to eat a lot of fish
She was born on April 1, 1982
A maternity hospital in Seoul
50 cm in length and 29 kg in weight
When she was born, her father was a civil servant
Mother is a housewife.