THE BEST OF YOUTH
ROME, SUMMER OF 1966
Can you give me a hand
with the TV?
I'm studying.
Come on,
it'll only take a minute.
My exam's in a few days.
Ask Nicola, he's with Carlo.
Fine.
I'll ask Nicola,
he's with Carlo.
"Natalino Sapegno.
World History..."
Who's that?
An Italian literature
professor.
-Is he famous?
-I'd say so.
-He gives the exam?
-No, he has assistants.
-Don't they know what they're doing?
-Of course they do, Dad.
Your thesis got published in
Il Messaggero.
You should show that Sapegno guy
what a genius you are.
Maybe he'll give you a scholarship
to study abroad.
I'll talk to him if you want.
You, talk to Sapegno?
Why not?
I'm not ashamed.
Well, I am.
This is what I get
for offering...
When do you leave for Norway?
-After my exams.
-I know people there.
I can give you addresses.
They might know girls your age.
Talk to them,
they're the experts.
-Dad!
-Yeah, I'm closing it!
Thanks.
Boys, I have a mission
for you two.
Good, we're due for a break.
I'll leave it open.
Careful.
-Nico, have you got keys?
-Yes.
Then I'll close it.
You never know.
How's it coming?
I'll get the door.
-Where?
-Right here.
Put it on top,
otherwise it'll move.
-On top?
-Yeah, I got it.
-Slowly.
-Careful. You got it?
-Here.
-I got it.
-There.
-All set.
Hold on.
-It should be tied.
-I'll do it.
-You will?
-Yeah.
-Bye.
Carlo, I have a question for you.
Nicola won't answer me.
-You know Matteo.
-Sure.
Tell me, what's his problem?
-What do you mean?
-I mean...
-Come on, we have to study.
-We're talking!
That's all you ever do!
Hold on, I've had this
in the car for a week.
-What is that?
-Nothing, I got a good deal.
Why give it to me?
You study medicine,
it'll be useful.
It's now...
or never.
Now that you're holding me
in your arms.
The music's about to stop,
and you still don't know
what to say.
I see you,
don't you see me?
Why?
It's now or never...
How's it going, old friend?
All right I guess.
But if things...
If the situation evolves...
Can I use your house
at the beach?
-No, no.
-Yeah, good idea.
Don't even think about it!
Why not? It's perfect!
Last time you made a mess.
My mom's still hot over it.
Here we go again!
That's right!
By the way,
I spoke to Dad.
-Well?
-We can use the AIfa Romeo.
Great!
That's great news!
-Did you tell him where we're going?
-I said it was for a field trip.
Leaving after exams, eh?
He said no higher than
4,000 R.P.M.
Well?
Are you coming to Carlo's
beach house?
-Me and you?
-Yeah.
-Alone?
-Of course!
It's beautiful. Golden beaches,
briny Salt-ceders...
leaping dolphins...
I love you, I love you.
-Always kidding around!
-No, I love you, I swear.
Come on, let's dance.
Did you talk to your dad
about the job?
Meet him Tuesday
at the clinic.
You know where it is?
It's scientifically known
as speech therapy.
In practice it entails going
for a stroll with a patient,
having a chat,
helping her to feel normal.
The relationship shouldn't be
too friendly. It's rehabilitation.
Giorgia hasn't had a crisis
in ages,
so twice a week
should suffice.
Come.
There she is, that's her.
It'll be easier
than walking a dog.
What's your name?
-Giorgia! Don't talk to strangers.
-What's your name?
-Me? Matteo.
-Matteo, mattress, meatball...
-Be careful.
-Don't touch me!
I won't.
But be careful.
Always look both ways
before crossing.
Go on.
You like it here?
I come here often.
It relaxes me.
And there are no cars.
Look, I know a great place.
You want to come?
Would you like that?
I come here when
I don't feel like studying.
I like it.
And it's empty at this hour.
Shall we read something?
Yes. The trains.
What trains?
When they leave,
when they arrive...
Oh, the schedule.
There isn't one here.
I have a book
I'd like to read you.
A poetry book.
Where is it?
American literature...
"Life is a bet
that's hard to cover.
We're dealt a hand
while we're weak
and not when we're at our best,
and we're given 70 years
to play.
If 70 years isn't enough,
you'll never make it.
Leave the room if you lose,
leave...
when your time is up.
Only cowards hang around
groping the cards."
Watch out for the cars!
Careful!
Damn...!
What are you doing?
-Don't touch me!
-I'm not!
-Fuck you!
-Up yours!
I'm not touching you!
You want to get run over?
You fucking dickhead!
You know what dying means?
-Asshole!
-You're the asshole.
-Fuck off!
-Fuck...!
Are you stupid?
Come on back to the clinic.
You don't want to do this again?
Fine, we won't.
Just say the word.
Here.
Here!
Right, it happens.
But what am I supposed to do?
Nothing. Don't react.
If you don't react
they calm down.
-But professor...
-Don't be so formal.
Okay, but maybe I did
something wrong.
You did nothing wrong, son.
The disease is at fault,
that's why we're here.
All set?
Have you washed my car?
I let them wash my car
sometimes.
They like that.
It gives them
something to do.
We mustn't! We mustn't!
Mortgage the house?
It's for the kids!
We'd have nothing!
Mortgaging the house is the most
normal thing in the world.
You know what your problem is?
You're from Milan!
You're extraordinary,
intelligent,
full of vitality...
-So what?
-You have no imagination!
-Right.
-lmagination like me.
Oh, right.
Alice, what are you
still doing up?
Come here.
-They been arguing long?
-Since the movie ended.
-Did it end well?
-Yeah.
He found out he was king
and married
-the princess.
-Big mistake.
-Why?
-Because
they'll end up fighting,
like Mom and Dad.
Promise me when you grow up
you'll do like me:
never get married ever.
I want to marry you.
And Nicola, too.
A sister can't marry her brother.
Especially both brothers.
Go to bed, Alice.
We'll make them stop.
Someone with a head
on his shoulders!
-Hey, would you cut that out?
-Had enough?
What are you doing here?
Poor thing,
you're still awake?
-How is anyone supposed to sleep?
-Tell me what to do then.
Leave Matteo out of this.
You two should defend me
from your father.
From what?
Matteo, tell me.
-Am I a bad father?
-Oh, right.
He's a great father.
He mortgaged the house!
-This house?
-No, the palace!
Of course this one.
Did you hear that?
If things get tight
we'll have to sleep under a bridge.
Under a bridge!
What fun, Matteo!
Finally someone
who likes adventure.
Right, we'll live under a bridge
as beggars.
Who cares if things
are tight or not?
You're crazy as well.
No, he's right!
What's so crazy?
Leave it to me.
I'm the head of the family.
-What does that mean?
-That you should trust me.
This is the time to invest,
to grow, to beat
the competition.
This is how it's done.
I can feel it in the air.
We'll all be feeling the air
living in the street.
-If only divorce were legal here...
-Like in America!
Yeah, like in America.
-I'm going out.
-Again?
-Yeah, they're waiting for me.
-Where are you going?
I don't know. Out.
Girls?
Maybe.
Where could she be?
Probably with a client.
Should we wait here?
Yeah, this is her fire.
It's embarrassing.
Why? She'll be back.
Is it her?
Yeah.
What's wrong?
Hi, Cati.
Hi, Matteo.
Who was that?
-And them?
-My brother and two friends.
Hi.
Should we go to your place?
Come in.
Mind if I leave the light on?
That way the chickens
think it's day
and they eat.
No, fine.
Won't you undress?
Are you embarrassed?
Fine. I'll turn around.
Hey, we'd better not
do anything.
I'll pay you the same.
Are you sick?
Me? No.
No, I just...
I don't know, maybe...
Oh, come on!
-You're Matteo's brother?
-Yeah, why?
You're so different.
-Not at all like him.
-What's Matteo like?
Weird.
Okay, let's go.
Let's do it.
We're wasting time.
No kissing on the mouth.
Hello, Giorgia.
Why are you in here
with the blinds drawn?
Feel like coming outside?
Everyone's in the garden.
How about a few photos?
The light is good.
Come on, look at me.
Well?
Fine,
I'll photograph your hands.
You have beautiful hands.
What's that?
What happened to you?
Here. Read it and comment.
It's a poem by
Sennuccio del Bene.
Yes, but what comes to mind?
-Actually, nothing.
-Nothing?
Why nothing?
Because it's empty.
Even he's empty.
Then give me an example of religious
poetry that particularly struck you.
Il Beccaio.
Are you kidding me?
Are you telling me Il Beccaio
by Cecco Angiolieri
should be considered
religious poetry?
Someone who curses his parents,
the very seed from which he came?
-I think so.
-Well, I don't.
And I'm the expert here,
thank you.
What are you doing?
I don't feel like staying here.
They're signs of
electric discharge.
They gave her electroshocks.
-Where did you get these?
-Isn't that illegal?
Unfortunately not.
-Who's the girl?
-I'll tell you later.
Go study.
Isn't your exam tomorrow?
My professor's a jerk.
I'll never get a 30 like you.
"A 30."
Are you coming tomorrow?
We can leave as soon as I fail.
Come and get me at the "hole."
I'm sleeping there tonight.
A girl?
-Hi, Antonio.
-What are you doing here this late?
I left a book upstairs.
-I can't budge from here.
-It's okay, I'll go.
Don't wake them up,
or they're your problem!
"Giorgia Esposti. Pietracamela."
Giorgia.
Giorgia, wake up.
Wake up, Giorgia.
It's okay.
It's me, Matteo.
Listen to me.
Get your things, we're leaving.
I'll get you out of here.
You deserved a 28 or a 29.
I gave you a 30 because
I used what I call
"the sympathy quotient."
Nothing drastic,
but enough to get you the 30.
Some people disapprove
of my "sympathy quotient,"
but I believe
that sympathy, in the sense
of the term "sympasin,"
which means to share "pathos,"
the suffering of others,
is important for doctors.
To others I apply
the "apathy" quotient.
Which means I subtract
2 or 3 points.
Apathy is the worst thing
for a doctor.
In any case,
you earned it.
But don't be too confident.
You have two more
exams with me,
and I could still destroy you.
Friends of yours?
-Is that your clan?
-No, I...
We're going on a trip after...
Are they in my class?
I don't remember them.
No, Carlo studies Economics
-and Berto, Philosophy.
-Spare me the biographies.
Just as long as
they're bothering
somebody else.
Economics, Philosophy...
Wonderful.
As I was saying, you show promise.
I'm probably wrong.
But here's some advice.
-Are you ambitious?
-Well...
Then get out of Italy.
Leave before it's too late.
You want to be
a surgeon?
I don't know.
I haven't made up my mind.
Whatever you decide,
go study in London or Paris
or the U.S. if you can.
Just get out of here.
Italy is doomed.
A beautiful, useless place...
doomed to death.
Are you referring to
the coming Apocalypse?
I wish. At least
we'd be forced to rebuild.
But nothing changes here.
The dinosaurs always rule.
Trust me, get out.
Why haven't you left,
professor?
Why, you ask?
Son, I'm one of the dinosaurs.
Excuse me, pardon me...
Come on, come on...!
All aboard!
A thirty! A thirty!
A thirty on your first exam?
I hate you!
-We're picking up Matteo, right?
-Come on, let's go!
What?
My dad said 4,000 R.P.M.
4,000 R.P.M...
4,000 R.P.M., come on!
4,000 R.P.M., here we...!
Go, Berto, go!
Yeah!
Giorgia.
Giorgia!
Wake up.
We have to leave.
I made you coffee.
Sugar?
One, two?
None?
If the professor was talking
about specializing, I agree.
But working abroad...
I don't know.
So you think there's work
here in Italy?
Yeah. There's 7 percent
annual growth,
and 3 percent unemployment.
-So?
-Thing's are good.
Unemployment only goes up
if growth dips under 4 percent.
So there'll be plenty of work.
No, I don't think that's
likely because
in the next few years
the generation born after the war
will all graduate.
Inflation will increase,
the job market will be tight.
I'd estimate that
one out of every three graduates
won't find work.
By far the dumbest
of the three.
Would you cut it out already!
I think the Appenine highway
is much better.
It would take us 20 days
to get to Turin!
We haven't seen a single
attractive hitchhiker.
That's all you ever
think about.
-What exactly?
-Where's Matteo?
How should I know?
Go find him.
-Fine, I'll just grab the keys...
-There he is.
-Just as well.
-Come on.
Come on.
-Who's that?
-No idea. I don't know her.
-Wasn't he coming alone?
-He didn't mention anything.
-Hold on, I'll go see.
-Find out.
We said no girlfriends.
Let's see what he has to say.
Maybe she's not coming.
No.
That girl is strange.
There's something...
Who is she,
the one in the photos?
-What's the problem?
-It's a delicate situation.
Well?
We'll meet in Brennero
in two days.
Are you crazy?
We were sleeping in Brennero
tonight. We'll lose two days.
-When will we get to Hamburg?
-In two days, at customs.
Because of that girl?
Yeah, because of her.
Is she a runaway?
More or less.
-Come on, we'll take you.
-No, it's okay.
We can handle it.
Have a good trip!
-Take care.
-Have fun.
Have a nice trip.
No speeding, -eh?
When I saw the state
she was in, I thought...
-You did the right thing.
-And the electroshock therapy...
You're right, it's awful.
But we have to
take her somewhere.
Her mother is dead.
Her father lives in Pietracamela.
-Where's that?
-I don't know.
In the Appenines, I think.
We'll drop her off there.
Okay. Giorgia!
Giorgia!
Come here.
You see how she acts?
She's weird.
What's wrong with her?
She's crazy.
No, she isn't.
She has intelligent eyes.
You and her...
Nice couple.
Giorgia!
So you do remember, eh?
How are you, Giorgia?
My priest can't remember me,
but you sure remember yours.
You're so beautiful!
You look absolutely wonderful.
-Who are they?
-Hello.
-Nicola.
-Vito, nice to meet you.
-Likewise, Matteo.
-Can I help you?
-We're looking for Giorgia's father.
Giorgia's father
left years ago.
-He went to Ravenna.
-Ravenna?
Three or four years ago.
Are you from the clinic?
Yeah, we're from Villa Quieta.
So young?
So why have you brought
this beautiful girl home?
-For a vacation.
-A vacation.
I had her confirmed.
We're all God's creatures.
Giorgia, tell me,
what were your lines?
What did you say?
"Lord, I am not worthy of You...
...but a single word of Yours
will cure me."
Very good!
When she was little
she knew the whole Angelus.
Though for her
the word of God
was like a game, a routine,
nothing more.
It happens to many.
You're right.
What's your name?
-Matteo.
-And you?
-Nicola.
-Hello, Nicola.
Maybe because her mother died
when she was young.
And she became obsessive.
She'd clean everything
and then start all over again.
The bedrooms, the kitchen,
the stable...
I don't know why.
When's the next train
to Ravenna?
It just left.
You should have asked sooner.
You can take it tomorrow at 7
and arrive in the afternoon.
Tomorrow?
We have to leave now!
That's impossible, okay?
-You know what that means?
-Then what do we do?
I have a place where
you can sleep. It's a...
Not a stable, a shed.
Better than a punch
in the face.
Am I right?
Here we are, Madame.
We've prepared for you
the imperial suite.
Make yourself comfortable
on this magnificent
bed of straw.
We also have a beautiful divider
to provide you intimacy
from the two heroes,
Ajax Paddycake
and Achilles Quick Foot.
We have a lovely blanket,
kindly donated
by the clergy of Pietracamela.
So if you're cold
you can cover yourself.
My dress stays on, eh?
My dress stays on.
It stays on.
Fine, leave it on.
You know what?
I'll leave mine on, too.
Let's go to sleep.
Giorgia.
Tomorrow you'll sleep
at your father's.
I have no father.
Thief! Thief!
Let go, you bastard!
You're a thief!
A thief!
-Calm down!
-Let go, it's mine!
Thief!
Giorgia!
Come here!
Let me go!
-What?
-Leave me alone!
-Let go!
-I didn't know.
-Let go, thief!
-Listen.
-Thief!
-No I'm not!
-You're a thief!
-I didn't know it was yours!
-Thief!
-It was on the ground...
-Stop it!
-I didn't know.
-What happened?
-Nothing, I picked up...
Stop! You have to leave!
-It was on the ground.
-Go away.
I didn't do anything.
I'll handle it.
Giorgia.
-Come in, it's raining.
-Stop it!
Come on, we'll get wet.
Giorgia, let's go inside.
Come on!
You should put something on.
Try something of mine.
You like it?
Go on, put that on.
Are you ashamed?
Go behind there.
Go on.
Next time you want a shower,
I'll take you to the Grand Hotel.
Ready?
-What's taking so long?
-The buttons...
-Can I?
-Yes.
I'll help you.
Sure, the buttons are
the most complicated part.
So are the shoelaces,
but the buttons
are pretty tough.
lmagine if the priest
came in right now.
He'd curse us
and we'd go to hell.
You're pretty when you smile.
You did it, see?
Go on, go to sleep.
Good night.
-Shall I turn off the light?
-No, no.
Okay, the light stays on.
Good night.
What happened?
Nothing.
-Good morning, ma'am.
-Good morning.
-Do you know where Mr. Saro lives?
-Here, he's my husband.
Where can we find him?
What do you want?
Nothing.
Personal business.
Aren't you Giorgia?
Shouldn't you be at the clinic?
Who are these two?
Bitch.
Giorgia!
What are you doing here?
-What happened?
-Nothing.
We think the clinic
isn't right for her.
What do you mean?
They mistreat her.
They give her electroshocks.
Electroshocks?
What does that mean?
-Electrical discharges.
-What?
Doesn't that hurt?
It isn't pleasant.
I pay a fortune for her to be
at the clinic,
so that she's all right...
So she gets better!
Why not keep her at home?
How can I?
What about my other kids?
Brothers live together.
They're not her brothers.
They're Rosa's kids.
But Rosa loves you.
And them, too.
It's you,
you're the one out of place.
Look, I...
I took you there
so you'd be all right,
so you'd get better.
Giorgia.
Giorgia, now...
We'll take you back
to the clinic.
Why not give it a chance?
We'll take you back
to the clinic, that way
you'll be okay and...
What Giorgia needs is a father!
But I... I am a father!
Giorgia, I love you.
You know that, don't you?
Then prove it.
Keep her here with you.
How can I?
Life is expensive!
With what the clinic costs me...
She needs family affection!
-We tried, but...
-Oh, right! You're too sick!
I won't discuss private stuff
-in front of strangers.
-What kind of father are you?
-Who are you?
-It's your daughter!
I know it's my daughter!
Mind your own business!
-What did you say?
-Calm down!
-Don't touch me!
-What?
Calm down!
-Stay calm! Relax!
-Damn!
-Now where do we go?
-I don't know.
Did you have to rough up
her dad like that?
She can come with us.
Where?
To meet Carlo and Berto,
in Brennero.
How do we cross the border?
She has no passport.
Think a little for a change.
What do you want to eat?
Nothing.
You don't eat or drink...
Besides...
Leave her alone.
She cut herself.
Don't sit there,
get a napkin.
-What if she hit a vein?
-What vein?
-She should go to the hospital.
-Just get a napkin.
Cheyenne method.
Make a tourniquet.
What happened?
Nothing, we broke a glass.
-Korea scored.
-Who cares?
That's right, we could care less.
We don't give a hoot.
You know what?
I want Korea to win.
Korea, Korea, Korea!
Porto Marghera Station.
Connections to Mestre,
Ponzano Veneto...
-Bye.
-Okay, wait for me here.
-What will you tell Giovanna?
That we had a problem
after we left.
How will you explain
Carlo and Berto not being here?
Trust me.
I'm a specialist, right?
I don't trust my sister.
-She'll have all 3 of us locked up.
-That's why we're not all going.
-And what should we do?
-Use your imagination!
There's a bar, have a drink.
I'll leave my stuff.
All right? See you later.
Bye.
You want something to drink?
Oh, you're angry with me.
Don't talk to me.
Give me a sign.
Say yes or no.
What's that, a yes?
-Hello.
-Hi. What'll it be?
What do you want to drink?
Giorgia.
You want to hear something?
What do you like?
EIvis?
Sandy Shaw?
What does that mean?
Oh, "A chi," Fausto Leali.
I'll see if they have it.
Here it is. B3.
B3.
Who will
I smile at
if not at you?
Who...
if you're...
not here anymore?
By now...
it's over,
it's over
between us.
Your friend Berto
is in trouble.
The girl's father is her legal
guardian. It's up to him.
It's the law.
He thought they'd kill her
if he left her there.
He should have reported it
to the authorities.
He took control of
another person.
-Do these things happen to you?
-I don't let them.
You wouldn't know it,
but thousands work in there.
Lots of problems?
The usual. Labor issues,
firings, diseases, accidents...
We have it all.
The factory never closes.
They work day and night,
through summer and winter.
That's why the sea and sky
have changed colors.
They say it's nothing
to worry about,
but last week
they handed these out.
-Toothpaste?
-Yeah.
The message was make sure
you brush before eating
and not after, get it?
Not really.
The dust that gets
on your teeth
and in your nose
is toxic.
In the long term
it can cause cancer.
Listen.
This happened to you, right?
I mean, Matteo.
-He got you into this.
-No, it was Berto.
Why don't you contact the
psychiatric hospital in Gorizia?
I'm sure they're great.
But it's still an asylum.
At least they don't
tie people up
or electroshock them.
What if we bring her here?
I'd have to report it.
They'd come
and take her back
to her father, got it?
When does the train come?
In half an hour.
Hey, go buy three ice creams.
-Me?
-Yeah, you.
No, not me.
Why not? It's easy.
You have legs, don't you?
-I'll go.
-No, wait.
She's going.
Go on, three ice creams.
-I won't be able to.
-Sure you will, it's easy.
Yes, young lady?
-Three ice creams.
You think taking her to Gorizia
is the answer?
I think so.
Giovanna says
it's a good hospital.
If the doctors
don't convince us,
we can take a vacation
or something.
How about Sicily?
Here.
Your change.
Miss, wait! Your change!
-Afternoon.
-Two coffees.
-Coming right up.
Miss, your change.
-Your change.
-Your change, Miss.
-Do you know her?
-No.
-She just came in.
-Is something wrong?
I don't know,
she won't take her change.
-I see.
-Are you with someone?
-No, I'm alone.
-Have you got any ID?
She won't answer.
We'll take her in.
Come with us.
Come on.
What do we do with this?
I don't know.
What will happen to her?
They'll take her back
to the clinic, I guess.
Can't anything be done about it?
We'll take the train
in the morning then.
-We continue the trip, right?
-Yeah, sure.
Okay, let's get some rest.
Now arriving on platform one,
the 02:10 train to Padua,
Florence and Rome.
Now arriving on platform one,
the 02:10 train
to Padua, Florence and Rome.
Matteo, what are you doing?
-My trip is over.
-Over?
I'm going back to Rome.
Why?
What's wrong?
Have you gone mad?
You know that exam I had?
What about it?
I failed it.
You failed it?
Why didn't you tell me?
What's that got to do
with the trip?
-Nothing.
-Then get off.
The train's leaving!
Get off!
You leave me sitting here
on a bench?
-Get off!
-Goodbye.
What do you mean, goodbye?
Nicola!
Where's the recruiting office?
What should I do if I want
to join the army right away?
What should you do?
Have your head examined.
Dear Matteo,
I assume Mom and Dad
will know how
to get you this letter.
Where are you?
Any news from Carlo and Berto?
I haven't seen them.
I took the trip alone.
But here I am.
Norway is magnificent,
I'm especially impressed
by the people I've met.
Martin, for example,
an American desertor.
He fled America to avoid
having to go to Vietnam.
-Who wrote that?
-A genius.
-What's his name?
-AIlen Ginsberg.
I've left my friends
and I continue north.
You won't believe me, but there's a
wooden church right in front of me
a few feet away
from a marker that says
that the Arctic Circle line
passes through here.
Right now my classmates
are probably arriving
at class with the old dinosaur.
I don't feel guilty,
no sense whatsoever
of time wasted.
My dear animal,
here's some important news:
I'll never shave again,
or get a haircut.
I'll send a photo.
I look good, eh?
What the fuck are you doing?
Get back or I'll break your arm!
-Relax!
-I'm not kidding!
Don't joke around!
-Cut it out!
-Are you nuts?
Don't bust my balls!
-He's crazy.
-Are you bonkers or what?
Are you okay?
He hurt me.
I've run out of money,
I'll stop at a sawmill.
They pay well
and they always need people.
The girls are beautiful,
easy-going,
without all the usual
Italian melodrama
when you give them
a compliment.
Move!
Come on, move!
Move your ass!
You want to get killed?
You bunch of pussies!
Come on, move it, fuckers!
You'll be at it all day!
I'll kick your asses!
Move it!
-Shave!
-Keep quiet! Step forward!
Remember,
you represent more
than just yourselves.
You represent the army,
got it?
And let's get
one thing straight.
No smart-asses.
No clowning around.
And no bullshit.
Got it?
-Necktie!
-Step forward!
-Dirty shoes!
-Is that a backpack?
-Sorry.
-Back in line!
-Step forward!
You can't do this to me.
I called my mother,
she's all alone.
My father's ill.
I'm the only paycheck they've got.
Ten hut!
-What are you doing?
-I'm not going.
Wonderful.
Then you won't go
tomorrow, either!
Shut-ins stay in the barracks!
Everyone else outside!
Sometimes I remember Giorgia.
How she got away,
how we couldn't protect her...
When I get back
I might study psychiatry.
Something must be done
for people like her.
We can't leave them at the mercy
of electroshock therapy.
You're amazing, Matteo.
You sure got up
the lieutenant's ass.
But you're odd.
You got yourself
shut in for 3 days.
Well, you could have come up
with a better excuse.
A sick father,
a sister out of work...
What excuse?
It was all true.
You don't get it.
I don't have a job.
I'm hoping to enlist.
But you said you were
already getting paid.
Okay, that was my only lie.
And you know what?
You should enlist as well.
Are you stupid?
You could make general.
Move it! Get moving!
Nicola!
Ten hut!
Five minutes of rest
and we start.
At ease!
Fall out!
Nicola!
Matteo?
Hey!
-What's with the disguise?
-It's real.
-What about school?
-I dropped out.
I'll explain later.
Luigi, come here.
This is Nicola, my brother.
-Hi.
-Nicola.
Is this my brother?
How should I know?
You don't look alike.
Coming through.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, pardon me.
Thanks.
Excuse me, professor.
Anything valuable?
-Yes, I'm checking.
-I'll send people.
Thank you.
Slowly, careful...
Careful with the water.
Slowly.
Watch out...
Watch your step.
They're valuable books.
There's no hurry.
It's slippery.
Carati, where are you?
Over here, sir!
-You guys all right?
-Yeah, no problem.
Then Pezzuco can come with me.
Yeah.
What's with that expressive,
vernacular gesture?
I can see you've never served.
-I wouldn't want to.
-The guy with the beard.
The guy with the beard
who saved up a ton.
They pay great up there.
Yeah, congratulations.
I won't go back to Rome.
-What about school?
-I'll study somewhere else.
Careful.
After seeing Europe,
going back to Mom and Dad
depresses me.
What about you?
When do you get out?
-Never.
-What do you mean, never?
-I'm going to enlist.
-Enlist?
-Yeah, to be a cop.
-Are you kidding me?
Not at all.
You're going to be a cop?
What are you talking about?
You fell for it.
-You were kidding?
-Nicola!
Look!
Who knows what it was before.
-Illumination code, in Latin.
-I've got a flashlight.
"Lux prima Anno Domini..."
"In the year
1 126 of Our Lord,
the light..."
-No, "the first light."
-Yeah.
"The first light of dawn
shined upon the head
of the believer..."
What the hell are you doing?
Why did the line stop?
Come on, boys!
-Move your asses!
-You hear that?
lmagine an idiot like that
your whole life.
Move it, move it!
He's right,
we're wasting time.
-No!
-I can't believe it!
-Carlo! Berto!
-When did you get here?
-Three days ago!
-That's great!
-You've got a beard!
-You're ugly!
-I'm "the good savage."
You look like a lumberjack.
-We waited two days in Bolzano.
-Three.
You weren't there
so I kept going.
Liar. He called your mother.
I called your mom.
"He's in Hamburg."
Let's have a look around.
What do you say?
-You left me at the exams.
-You failed three times!
-Sorry, "cogito..."
-"Ergo sum."
-Why did he fail?
-How about a letter? Your hand hurt?
I was in the wilderness,
with no stamps.
What about girls?
No...
-Where do I put this?
-They said over here.
-No, over there.
-Make up your mind.
Watch the step.
Otherwise the bottles bre...
There, good.
Here they are, the soldiers
have come to help us.
Give them a sandwich.
-And a bottle of wine.
-Very pretty!
What have they got?
Wine, bread, stuff...
Nice coats!
They're Lorenzo the Magnificent's
grandchildren!
-Full of mud.
-He's unbelievable.
A wonderful character,
right out of Chekov!
Right out of
"The Cherry Orchard."
-Firs, it's him.
-Who's Firs?
The old crippled guy, right?
The angels of mud have come
from everywhere to help us.
Give them a sandwich.
That's it, good.
Let's see how
those boys are doing.
Good morning, ladies.
-What are you doing?
-I was kidding.
Oh, right.
Give them some, too.
A bottle of wine,
a sandwich...
Just one, you see?
-There.
-Who are the girls?
The Riccobaldi daughters.
You could say we were lucky.
The house is high up
and suffered no damage.
The Marquis wanted,
through his daughters,
to offer...
a gesture of gratitude.
How nice of the Marquis!
And I'm stuck
with the wheelbarrow!
Well, I don't know.
I'm joking, of course.
I started studying piano
when I was ten.
Now I'm studying Mathematics
in Turin.
What's that got to do
with the piano?
The piano was my mother's choice,
Mathematics was mine.
Who would choose Mathematics?
Someone who wants to solve
the jealous husband problem.
What's that?
-What do you mean?
-Never heard of it?
It hasn't made it to Rome yet.
Let's see.
Three couples.
-Couples.
-They have to be couples.
-Yeah.
How boring!
They have to cross a river.
There's only one boat
that can only carry
two people at a time.
But the jealous husbands
don't want their wives
to ride with anyone else.
-No wonder.
-What's the game?
How all six of them
cross the river.
It's simple, look.
Well, first...
two women cross,
they reach the other side.
One of them goes back.
Her husband gets in,
they cross together...
What do you know?
She leaves him there,
goes back again...
-No.
-Drops him off, goes back...
No, no, wait.
First the two husbands cross.
-It's the same.
-It's the same!
Where are we going?
I give up.
-Good.
-It's not so hard.
-I can tell you.
-Another time.
Okay? Another time.
-Hey, tell me.
When you finish,
will you be a math professor
-or a musician?
-Not a professor.
I don't think a musician,
either.
She's got her ideas straight.
You have to be
one or the other.
Yeah, right.
We should all enroll in Turin
like her.
Why in Turin?
In Turin, in Turin.
-He's crazy!
-Basically, yes.
-Berto, let's go to Turin.
-Right, Turin.
I won't even finish
my studies in Rome.
My dad wants me
at the factory.
-It's not funny.
-What about you, Carlo?
You like Turin?
Turin?
Agnelli, Fiat...
All that candy...
-Come on!
-I don't know.
Are you cold?
-What are you doing?
-Giving you this.
-No.
-Come on.
-Berto.
-Yeah.
I think it's time for bed.
-I'm not sleepy.
-Good night.
Come on.
Oh, good night.
-Good night.
-Bye.
Good night.
You didn't get rid of them...
No... just good night.
Listen...
if I come to Turin,
can I stay with you?
You're out of your mind.
I don't even know you.
TURIN, FEBRU ARY OF 1968
Nicola!
No, you have to pull...
A bit further...
No, to the right.
A bit more on the...
No, no, no.
No, no, look.
Watch what he does.
No, no. Nicola.
Nicola!
Nicola, I love you.
I love you with all my heart.
Nicola! Nicola, careful!
The riot police!
Let them go!
Police, get out!
Hi, Paolo.
Bring your bike inside.
Sure, with all these people
from the south around...
Shut up and make the puree.
-Right away, dear.
-With those hands?
-That's right.
-Where's Carlo? Carlo!
Come here.
Your master calls...
Vitale, we need information
as well.
Someone needs to find out
what they want.
Why even read the papers? They want
to stick it to us right here.
How English of you.
-"Very British."
-Oxford.
All right, guys.
No more calling me a hick.
I'm really from Turin.
Really?
Look at that.
It's not even funny.
While the cops fight with
little rich boys like you...
That's enough!
Yeah, let the painters
and reporters step forward.
That would have
the riot police running!
Cut it out!
Run!
The union said
not to provoke anyone!
Watch what you say
about the union!
Yeah, very funny.
Did some friends of yours
write this?
Have you read it?
Here.
They were handing these out
yesterday.
-Yeah, well...
-What is it?
"The school should be demolished,
not changed."
I don't want to demolish
the school.
What does that mean?
I want going to school
to be a right.
For me, since I couldn't go,
and for my kids, who will.
What kids, Vitale?
As if you had any!
Learn how to speak!
He's right, Vitale.
You have no kids.
Well, I'm still young.
I don't mean to pry,
but don't you have to go
to your Economics meeting?
-Can someone make coffee?
-I'll do it.
Didn't you have
a factory meeting?
What, are you afraid
I'll get in trouble?
No, I just want you to leave.
What's the hurry?
I have to study,
I have an Anatomy exam.
-What do you have to study?
-Anatomy!
Anatomy!
-Good morning, Mr. Piero.
-Hello.
Hey, watch it, Naples!
-Hi, Giulia.
-Hi.
You see?
She passed Anatomy.
-My lip hurts!
-Sorry, I forgot.
-You're freezing.
-I came running. I'm hot.
It's freezing out.
Because you're standing still.
You have to keep moving.
Moving?
TURIN, SPRING OF 197 4
Go, go, go!
Open up!
I'm pregnant!
Please open the door!
Please!
Open up!
Come on!
With all the chaos outside...
This is a paradise.
Pretty, isn't it?
Would you live here?
Yeah, I'd live here.
Why, wouldn't you?
What are you doing?
You've got stones
in your pockets?
You saw the cops
beating people.
Well, so what?
What are you doing?
Throwing stones?
No.
But if they come after me,
I know how to defend myself.
How strange.
Someone let us in,
but it looks like no one's here.
I love your excuse.
"Help, help!
Open the door!
Help, I'm pregnant!"
Careful, don't lose them.
Stop at the corner.
First and second on the right.
Third and fourth on the left,
come on!
Keep going!
Slow down.
I don't like this.
Not at all.
Back up!
Everyone out!
Let's get out of here!
Regroup!
Back here!
Turtle formation!
Are we all here?
Luigi!
Luigi! Luigi!
Bastards!
Luigi!
Gigi...
How are you?
What a way
to see each other again.
I thought you were in Treviso.
Yeah, they asked for
reinforcements
for the protest.
What a joke.
It was legitimate
self-defense, right?
If they hadn't pulled me off
I would have killed him.
Are they going to
discipline you?
I don't know.
I'm getting a transfer.
-Where to?
-Bologna.
I leave tomorrow.
The guy you hurt will survive,
fortunately.
I don't give a shit.
Are you going to keep this up?
All right, let's start over.
Hi, Matteo.
How are you?
You want to come with me?
I'll show you my house.
We can relax a bit.
How do you get out of here?
What do we have to do?
Ask for permission from
the Minister of the Interior?
Lick the police chief's boot?
Pray to St. Michael the Archangel,
the patron saint of the police?
All I need is
the boss's signature.
Then sign it already!
And this is the patio.
Good morning, Tota Bianco.
"Tota" means "miss"
in Piemontese.
I'll go buy a cake.
We should celebrate.
-Celebrate what?
-I'll explain later.
May I help you?
Light of my life...
-No keys again, eh?
-Sorry, honey.
This is Matteo.
Hi.
Come in.
Thank you.
Gigi will be paralyzed.
You two met, at the floods
in Florence, remember?
Right, in uniforms
we all look the same.
-He's a friend of yours?
-Like everyone in the section.
Bad idea.
Why's that?
You're on the wrong side.
-Oh, yeah?
-Yeah.
And what's the right side,
the poor people?
Luigi knows more than you do
about defending the poor.
He's poor.
The guy who hit him wasn't.
-Are you poor?
-What's that got to do with it?
-I don't beat people up.
-Right, you don't.
We're sitting here having cake,
and he's in a wheelchair.
-I won't listen to this crap!
-Giulia, please!
She's nice.
You two hit it off.
Anyway...
We're celebrating.
We're having a child in September.
A child?
What will you name it?
Sara.
How do you know it's a girl?
Giulia thinks so.
I trust her.
Sara's a nice name.
A biblical name.
Is that her?
When she plays she seems nice.
She is nice.
She thinks she's always right.
Good. Just like you.
Go to sleep.
Nicola...
Does the baby have
to sleep in here?
It's not exactly a good idea.
Be quiet.
Sara.
Could you go
in the other room?
Go on, Sara. Daddy
has to do something
with Mommy.
Go on, Sara.
Go.
He could have picked us up.
A 9-hour trip and he's busy?
Try to be nice
and say pleasant things.
Don't say it's crazy to have kids
without a steady job.
Because Nicola has one.
Right, a six month contract
at the asylum. That's a job?
-She works, too.
-In a junk store?
Wait till they have to buy
clothes, shoes, mini-skirts...
Mini-skirts already?
And don't mention them
having kids out of wedlock.
Who gets married nowadays?
What, you wouldn't marry me now?
Is it pretty enough for you?
What are you talking about?
Staircase A.
-Hello.
-Hi.
-How are you?
-Fine, how was your trip?
-Fine.
-Can you open it?
-Yeah.
-Here we are.
-What is it?
-A carriage from England.
I ordered it special
for the lady.
Thanks.
-How pretty!
-Here's the rest.
Leave it here.
Hi, beautiful.
This place is spacious.
Yeah, we got lucky.
-Was it already painted?
-No, I painted it.
Very nice, well done.
Is she asleep?
Hi.
Hello, gorgeous!
I'm your grandma.
I'm your grandma
and this is your grandpa.
Look at that face.
My goodness, what eyes!
And the chin, too.
She doesn't look at all like you.
I was hoping she wouldn't.
Wait till she grows up.
You can't tell yet.
My how she's grown
since the last time!
We become grandparents
overnight.
Sarita? Sarita!
You like having such
a young grandpa?
She's looking at me!
She's in your pocket.
Where's Nicola?
At court.
-What did he do?
-They're prosecuting
a psychiatrist from the asylum.
A monster.
He did lots of horrible stuff.
-He went to help.
-By testifying?
No, not him. The patients.
They've been admitted
as witnesses and we're hoping
the judge will hear them out.
It'd be a first in Italy.
No, a first in the world.
Marino, when they ask you
"Do you swear to tell the truth...?"
Girolamo, listen.
You'll all be asked this.
You have to say:
"I swear."
-Marino, say "I swear."
-I swear.
Okay, otherwise
they won't listen.
How old were you
when you were committed?
-I don't know. Four, nine...
-No, you have to be specific.
You have to say "eight."
Eight.
Yeah, eight, I remember
I wanted to dress like a girl.
-They shouldn't have locked you up.
-Nicola.
I'll kill the electrician
when I see him.
I'll rip him to shreds...
No, don't.
You have to be good, AIdo.
Nicola!
Just sit by me and stay calm.
You promise, AIdo?
Look me in the eye.
Nicola!
Are you calm?
Will you be good?
What's wrong, Mario?
He looks like my cousin Ignazio.
Yeah, he does a bit.
What's that?
Where did you get that stuff?
I found it
behind the statue.
Don't take anything.
Don't pick up anything
off the floor.
Whose pamphlets are these?
RED BRIGADES
Do you swear to tell the truth,
the whole...?
They had us all go in
and lie down
-beside each other.
-No, excuse me.
Wait, you have to say "I swear."
I swear.
Eight years old.
Committed ten times...
Objection.
The witness is reciting
from memory.
Counselor, the witness
needs to calm down.
Your honor.
Mr. Levi,
please just say "I swear."
I swear.
Fine, proceed.
When... he'd come in...
the electric doctor...
I'd close my eyes. I could hear
the ones that went before me
screaming.
Four nurses held my arms
and legs.
A hand put an eraser
between my teeth.
Then the first shock.
I escaped from the asylum
one time.
But I got caught.
They beat me up
and tied me to the bed.
Then the electrician showed up
with his machine.
While...
he gave me the charges,
he'd scream:
"Tell me who helped you escape!"
"Give me names!"
But since I didn't want
to give him names,
I clenched my jaws
as tight as I could,
so tight
that I split all my upper teeth.
Giovanbattista,
can you hear me?
I have your statement here.
You must repeat
everything you know.
Look at him.
Is that the man you spoke of?
Can you speak,
Giovanbattista?
You said,
these are your words:
"The doctor said he gave me
electromassage because I drank."
Is that true?
"In five days
they gave me five treatments,
once a day."
Is that right?
It's normal in cases
of alcoholism.
-Plenty of publications...
-Shut up! You're finished!
-You can't kill any more people!
-AIdo, calm down!
If that happens again,
I'll have to clear the room.
Your honor,
please forgive AIdo.
And the others.
They're very upset,
they can't help themselves.
As you can see, Giovanbattista
can't even speak.
I know silence proves nothing.
But it's all he has left.
He should get a life sentence.
I'd settle for a day.
I'd settle for that.
It's a question of principle.
Why exactly did Dad
come to Turin?
He's looking for investors
for his projects.
He thinks typewriters
could end up being replaced
by processors or calculators
or something.
Listen.
I have something to tell you.
He doesn't know I found them.
He hasn't said anything.
But I saw that he was worried.
I'd never gone through
his drawers before.
You're a doctor.
Is there anything you can do?
No, Mom.
But there is treatment
that can slow the process.
It might give us
a few years...
Yes, I know.
I've read everything I found.
It all says the same thing.
That it's hopeless.
-What are you writing?
-A memoire for the organization.
For the trial.
You still type with two fingers.
Come on, let me.
-No, let me.
-Oh, come on.
I'll give you a hand.
"The lawyer has sustained
that the treatments
were not intended
as punishment,
and has chosen to specify
that homosexuality
is a disease
that requires
precise treatment."
-What, it isn't a disease?
-No, it isn't.
-Are you sure?
-Positive.
If you say so...
Look at that!
At least change the cartridge.
I like it that way.
Forget it.
Forget it?
You need a new one.
I have an idea.
I'll find an investor.
Better yet,
if you don't mind,
I'll stay in Turin
to find some financing.
-There are good mechanics here.
-Fine, good idea.
And I thought
you'd say I was nuts!
You're not nuts,
you're just thinking ahead.
You're a visionary.
Is Mom staying, too?
No, she's going back.
Her leaving Francesca 4 days
is already a miracle.
Hey...
I'd like to go to Milan
to see Giovanna.
I'll catch a train...
-No, I'll take you.
-No, why?
That way I can see Carlo.
-Remember him?
-Of course!
-I thought he taught in England.
-He's visiting.
-I'll get to see him.
-I can tell him about my project.
In England
there are investment banks,
not like here.
He might know someone.
Go on, dictate.
What, are you out?
Out of what?
Two sixes of clovers,
you can't.
Sorry. But that's 40, right?
No, count them. Is that 40?
Count them.
-6, 18, 20...
-No, it's 40.
No it isn't.
Okay, I'll take them.
-Hey, Adriana.
-Yeah?
About the subject of people
not marrying nowadays...
I think that today
I would marry you again.
My little girl!
Don't be silly.
Have you got an apartment?
-Lodging?
-No.
There's a room here,
but no one wants to use it.
Fine by me.
I don't like houses.
So why did you change
from Bologna to Sicily?
I got transfered.
-I heard they need people.
-You could have refused.
I never disobey an order.
Don't just stand there.
Put that down.
What's inside?
Books.
-Books?
-Yeah, books.
You're weird, you know.
I read your personal attributes
and what do I see?
Nothing, I see nothing.
Besides an occasional mess.
Bad temper, but a soft hand.
Why did you join the force?
What were you looking for?
Rules.
To do what?
To be applied.
-Applied?
-Yes.
I do as I'm told.
And I keep to myself.
Then you'll be fine.
Sicily is the kingdom
of people who keep to themselves.
It looks like he got shot
in the head.
-What?
-Shot in the head.
He has a hole in his brain.
You live around here?
-We're finished.
-One second.
Did you find the body?
Yes.
-First thing this morning?
-Yeah.
Why were you here?
I was grazing my donkey.
Right, grazing.
Yeah.
You or the donkey find it?
I did!
And did you touch it?
-No.
-Right.
Good, never touch it.
But did you see him?
Is he from around here?
-Yeah.
-So you know him.
Did you know him or not?
-No.
-You didn't?
If he's from around here,
why didn't you know him?
Did you recognize him?
-You know him?
-Yeah, I know him.
Good. You see?
You know him.
Tell me, who was he?
-Was he a good person?
-He was a good Christian.
Anyone who knew him
knew that.
So tell me, why is it you say
he was a good person
and others thought
he was a bad Christian?
How should I know?
I don't know anything.
Sure, you don't know anything.
Nobody does.
The pigs were about
to eat the poor guy...
-May he rest in peace.
-Yeah, whatever.
That's good, okay?
I remind you all that you must
respect this court.
Whatever the verdict,
I will not stand for
any outbursts.
The court,
in view of articles 483
and 488 of the Penal Code,
declares the defendant guilty
of a crime,
and sentences him
to five years in prison
and orders he pay
the costs of the trial.
Silence!
The colors aren't so bad
once you get
used to them.
Besides, dolls are pretty cute.
Well done. Congratulations.
Listen.
-Can I ask you a question?
-Yes.
That piano over there...
-Why don't you ever play it?
-I never play it because
I'm not good enough.
And since talent
can't be learned,
I decided to give it up.
I'm not talking about
playing in public.
Why not play at home?
-At home, for you.
-For me?
-What?
-That's enough.
-Why?
-I made lots of mistakes.
I didn't hear any.
You didn't, but I did.
It's for me
so it doesn't count.
Go on, more Ravel.
I like Ravel.
Don't you ever ask her to play?
No.
Why not?
Because she doesn't want to.
That's not it.
She played the other day.
She did that for you,
to please you.
It was a special case.
You haven't got a clue.
You're smart,
but some things
just escape you.
Always tell women
how smart they are,
how pretty,
how important they are
to us. Tell her: "Giulia,
play for me,
for the two of us."
-Like I do with your mother.
-All you two do is fight.
Fighting is good.
It keeps you in shape.
The 26 principles
and the 109 recommendations
of the United Nations,
approved two years ago
in Stockholm,
are constantly broken
here in Italy.
By people like those
we judge here today
and for whom I request
the maximum penalty.
I also request they be ordered
to pay the costs of the trial
as well as punitive damages
for having dumped
industrial refuse in a river
with grave consequences to
the environment and public health.
Consider that
in the last 10 years
almost 2 billion dollars a year
have been spent
per year on military expenses.
Right now half is unaccounted for,
including in Italy.
-Will you have them arrested?
-I need names.
-Tell her about the state companies.
-Putting words in his mouth?
No, you know the state companies,
they're in the papers.
You read the papers, right?
-Dad!
-What?
Look.
-The chopsticks.
-Dad!
Fork.
-Yeah, okay.
-It's the crab technique.
Forget it, Carlo.
I eat with a fork.
Will that little car of yours
make it to the airport?
How dare you!
Take a taxi!
You're going to Cambridge
with all there is to do here?
No, I'm coming back.
After I finish my master's
next year.
I want to get a job with
-the Bank of Italy.
-You see?
He wants to be governor,
he wants his name on money.
-A toast to the governor.
-To the governor.
To the governor.
Long live the governor!
This may sound absurd,
but if you want him to believe
he can be cured,
you have to believe it
yourselves.
-He doesn't know we know.
-That doesn't matter.
Your father can sense it.
He senses everything.
-He senses that you know.
-I don't believe in miracles.
-Forget that you're a doctor.
-Okay, you want to help me.
Thanks, but that's enough.
Okay, sorry.
Thank you, thank you.
I think that's mine.
-Sorry about before.
-No, I'm sorry.
I'm full of shit.
Don't let England
make you stupid.
Try not to let Italy
do the same.
Bye.
I haven't told anyone.
Not even Nicola,
he'd have psychoanalyzed me.
All that psychological crap
about the will to live
and all that.
I can tell you.
But not him.
Keep it between us.
Promise me
you won't tell anyone.
Okay, but stay with
the treatment
so that you can get cured.
All of it.
All the treatment.
Everything.
Be patient with Matteo.
I don't know why,
but I can never
understand that boy.
He agonizes over everything.
Then there's Francesca, Mom
and Nicola.
Nicola's strong.
Well, he seems strong.
He's like the others.
And most importantly,
think of yourself.
You have to laugh,
be happy.
Try to have fun.
Where's your husband?
-On a business trip?
-We never see each other.
It hasn't been working lately.
-Is there someone else?
-No way!
It just isn't working,
that's all.
We're getting a separation.
A separation?
And you didn't tell me?
-I'm sorry.
-I'm not.
It's for the best.
Right, we'll find someone else.
Are you looking for mystery?
Are you talking to me?
You have to find your soul.
How do I do that?
You have to search,
deep inside yourself.
PALERMO, SUMMER OF 1977
You know how to do that?
That's right.
You see that boy?
Look at his hand.
Sure of itself, demanding...
Powerful.
The top of his class.
Maybe.
You see that elderly woman?
Two rings on her ring finger.
A widow.
And she's lonely.
You're not Sicilian.
Are you kidding me?
Did you see "Stromboli,"
with Ingrid Bergman?
Yeah.
I live there,
for the moment.
I did a librarian's course.
I want to leave the island.
Very nice.
-A professional camera.
-You understand this stuff?
I also know a lot
about libraries.
-Really?
-Yeah.
Then which library
should I request?
In Palermo I don't know.
In Rome...
Villa Celimontana.
A beautiful old one.
-Give me a little mystery.
-Oh, come on.
What mystery!
I have to go.
-Right now?
-Yes.
-What's your name?
-Me? Nicola.
-Mirella.
-Nice meeting you.
Goodbye, Nicola.
-What is it?
-A corpse.
-You have to take photos.
-I haven't got a camera!
I've got one.
You think of everything.
Where did you get it?
Watch what I do.
It's easy. Watch Daddy.
Look, watch Daddy.
Watch Daddy.
I'm hurt!
Sara should be asleep by now.
Is that what the doctor said?
Daddy's the doctor!
Listen to him!
Go to bed.
-What's wrong?
-I'm tired.
I had a fight with Stefania.
I told her it's over.
I'm fed up with arguing.
-You used to like it.
-That was before.
It's for the best.
Maybe you can play piano again.
I sold it.
They're coming tomorrow for it.
Are you crazy?
It's possible.
Where have you been?
Are you checking up on me?
At one of the group meetings.
-Any objections?
-Too bad.
What's that supposed to mean?
Everything in this country sucks.
And we just sit here watching.
You hear about the kid
that got killed in Bologna?
-Yeah.
-What about us?
When will we make them mourn?
Make them mourn?
Take that off,
you look ridiculous.
-Listen...
-Don't touch me.
You can't stand me either?
No!
No, I can't.
All you care about is the hospital.
I have to do everything.
I disagree.
I hate these arguments!
I hate couples that argue!
Gentlemen...
If you're going
to make so much noise,
Bobby can't sleep.
You're right, darling.
We'll be quiet.
Dear Carlo:
I'm glad to hear things
are going well at Cambridge.
Here nothing has changed.
It's hard to work
with so many institutions,
trying to change them
little by little.
Things with Giulia are bad.
She's become agressive,
hostile,
dissatisfied with something
I still don't understand.
We haven't made love
in 6 months.
This way,
I'll show you the room.
I'd like to know
who orders these inspections.
The Minister of Health.
And what are you, a lawyer?
A judge? Come in, please.
-A psychiatrist.
-Good.
This is the room.
As you can see,
everything's clean.
Everything's in order.
-Where are the patients?
-I sent them on a field trip,
to the sanctuary at Oropa,
because I care about them.
I want them to be entertained,
normal, like anyone.
Where are you going?
There's nothing in there!
-It's the basement!
-What's inside?
-Nothing, storage.
-Open this door.
-No, I won't!
-Do your thing.
-The chain.
-Show me a warrant!
I want to talk
to a lawyer first!
You hear me?
Where are you going?
Are you satisfied?
There's nothing to see,
just...
Trash!
Where are you going?
-No, you can't!
-What's in there?
-There's nothing!
-Restrain her.
-You have no right!
-Get out of the way!
-It's not fair!
-Put her in the car.
If she resists, cuff her.
-I'll call my lawyer!
-The door.
I'll get you for this!
You can't treat people
this way!
I protest! I protest!
Order ambulances.
Untie them and cover them up.
Call headquarters.
Ferrario.
Give me a hand.
Giorgia...
Giorgia,
here's your jacket.
Be good.
We'll give it to you
and you can put it on, okay?
Look, I'll leave it here
and we'll turn around.
Here, Giorgia.
No, it's okay.
Thank you.
How are you?
Have you eaten today?
You want some?
You remember our trip?
To Vito's village?
That time we slept in the barn?
The soccer match?
Italy lost and we laughed
and laughed...
You remember Matteo?
The orange.
They need water.
You're right,
I always forget.
Sorry, I won't touch you.
I'd like you to come every day.
To keep the plant alive.
Have you called the judge?
-Yeah.
-When?
Two hours ago.
He isn't here yet?
Are you smoking?
-In a slaughterhouse?
-Get rid of that.
We have to go.
Can we move him?
After the judge gets here.
Always the same question!
Our shift is over.
Your shift?
There's a dead person here!
Enzo, what did I tell you?
Keep them quiet.
-They don't want to.
-I don't care!
Come on, get moving.
Outside.
Please, get going.
There's a kid!
Get out of here!
Are you his father?
Get him out of here!
-He's not hurting anyone.
-Get him out of here!
Who do you think you are?
How dare you.
You like the show?
There's a dead body!
This isn't a movie!
Where were you
when he got shot?
How should I know?
I forget!
You know nothing!
Nobody knows anything!
The same old story!
He died by himself!
And bringing kids in here.
-Go on, get out.
-Don't touch him!
What are you teaching him?
Don't touch my son!
Who do you think you are?
Here's your leave of absence.
I don't want to see you
for two weeks. Take a vacation,
go home,
just get out.
I have enough problems.
What are you, a vigilante?
Some kind of savior?
Get out of my sight!
-What's up, Carati?
-Nothing.
-Transfer?
-No, leave a absence.
-Typical.
-It could have been worse.
Here, this came this morning.
Dear Matteo:
I'm writing you with good news.
I found Giorgia.
I think she's suffered a lot
these last years.
For her it's as if
time stood still.
Seeing her
has really affected me.
I'm reminded of that summer
so long ago,
when all of our lives
changed so drastically.
And I thought:
why don't you take a break
for a few days
and come to Turin for a visit?
"What happened in April
is no isolated case.
After 50 days of striking
at FIAT,
in which many have intervened
by blocking the production line,
represents a high point
for the organization
achieved to date
by the worker class."
No good. Too bureaucratic.
You have to distinguish
between wishes and needs.
Needs are a serious issue.
They lead you to question things
and take risks.
Even to die or fight,
if necessary.
The need for communism,
for example.
-Afternoon.
Excuse me.
-You finished early today.
-Yeah.
I finished early.
-Hi, Sara.
-Hi.
-Are you drawing?
-Yeah.
-Let's go for a walk.
-Yeah!
It's bad for kids
to be inside too much.
And for people's brains.
"The need for communism..."
I need to drink, to eat...
Sara, don't listen
to that bullshit.
-That's a bad word!
-You're damn right.
What do you say to someone
who lies at kindergarten?
-Lying bastard!
-Very good.
Come on, let's go
for a nice little stroll.
-Bye!
But it's cold,
it's cold...
Let's take our coats.
Come on.
Let's get some air,
sweetie. Come on.
-Giulia...
-I know, I'll deal with it.
-Good morning.
-Luigi Pezzuco.
-Look inside.
Thank you.
Despite my misfortune,
I was lucky.
The doctors always say that.
Two millimeters more
and I'd have lost both arms.
Anyway,
that's how things always work.
Well, almost always.
I even met a woman.
Her name's Patrizia.
I want you to see her.
I have a photo.
It was taken of us
at a party.
It's in here.
I know it is.
Here.
Very pretty.
Congratulations.
She is pretty.
We're getting married
in September.
And we want kids, too.
Lots of kids.
You're wondering how we...
Slowly,
with a little patience.
It's nice that way.
So she says.
Sure.
Reaching this point,
where I am with Patrizia,
would have been impossible
without your mom's help.
-My mom?
-Matteo.
I have tons of notebooks
like this one.
Without your mom,
I'd never have recovered
the use of this hand.
He's been visiting you
all these years?
Once a week.
He's never missed.
-You didn't know that?
-Of course I did.
He's helped me
with more than my hand.
AIso my brain.
I'd never read poetry before.
Listen to this:
"Tears of honor you shall have,
Hector,
for holy are the tears of blood
spilt for one's country..."
I can't read this.
"...as long as the sun shines
on human misfortune."
Dr. Carati?
What a surprise!
How are you?
-Fine, you?
-Fine.
-Where's your beard?
-Sara said it scratched too much.
-Scratched?
-So I shaved it off.
Speaking of Sara,
this is for her.
Thanks. Very nice.
What is it?
A doll.
You can play with it, too.
Great! Did you go through Rome
on your way here?
Yeah, but I didn't go home.
These drawings?
My patients do them.
We're organizing an exhibition.
-An exhibition?
-Yeah.
Did you know Mom's
been helping Luigi?
That friend of mine
who was paralyzed?
Yeah, I knew.
-Who's that?
-My mentor.
Franco Basaglia.
-The one who would free the mad.
-He has this crazy idea
that they're not actually inmates,
but people.
And that mental illness isn't
a sin to be expunged.
How about that!
How is Dad?
He's...
-You should go see him.
-I will!
I will.
I'd already decided to.
-Let's go see Giorgia.
-Yeah.
-How is she?
-Better.
You'll see.
If she keeps improving
we'll release her.
We try to release them
as soon as possible.
Find them jobs,
an apartment...
What's wrong with them?
Doctors used to diagnose them
with schizophrenia,
but that has no meaning.
It means they're split in two.
Who isn't?
Are you just a cop?
Am I just a doctor?
The truth is,
we know nothing.
Just that these walls
make them crazy.
-How do you treat that?
-By opening the patio.
-I'll wait in my office.
-Don't leave me alone with her.
-What will I tell her?
-Maybe she has something to say.
Hello, Giorgia.
It's good to see you.
How are you?
Are you okay?
Right, "are you okay?"
is sort of an absurd question.
It has no meaning.
Nicola said you can go out.
You want to go for
an ice cream?
We'll find a jukebox
and play some music.
You used to like music.
He also said you read,
that you like books.
What do you read?
What words are in your head?
You can't hear.
Sound... air...
concern... nothing.
Nothing gets through.
The response would be:
"absent."
Absent.
As if you didn't know.
You remember that summer,
when we were kids?
What were you like?
What was I like?
Crazy.
Crazy Matteo.
Giorgia!
-You think she'll be okay?
-Of course, you'll see.
It reminded me of that time...
Remember in the station?
Yeah, what about it?
Nothing, we were there,
listening to the song...
And she turned
and looked at me.
-You were in love with her.
-No, you were.
Well, we both were a bit.
-What song was it?
-"A chi," Fausto Leali.
Nicola!
Your father...
Matteo,
can you slow down?
Slow down.
Nobody's chasing us.
You want to drive?
-Just slow down.
-This is how I drive.
-Shit, Matteo, slow down.
-Giulia, please.
I'm scared. There's a child
in the car.
You understand?
Why don't you answer?
If you want to get out...
Stop the fucking car!
Tell him!
Stop!
Stop the car!
Get off the fucking road.
-I'll bust you up!
-Okay, I'll pull over.
What's your fucking problem?
Turn around!
Matteo!
Thanks for coming.
Hi.
Thanks.
And your mom?
-How is she?
-She's devastated.
Hi.
Hi, I'm Francesca.
Cops nowadays haven't got
a moment free.
He said he'd come after work.
If he can make it.
Why don't you come to Milan
for a while?
Francesca can manage
on her own.
It's not Francesca.
My work is here.
I know the school
would fall apart without you.
But you should think
of yourself.
That's what I'm doing.
Working helps me.
Giulia.
-How about some coffee?
-I'll make some.
No, I'll do it.
-You want a coffee?
-Yes, thank you.
Excuse me, Francesca.
-Where's the coffee pot?
-In that cabinet.
No, the one on the right.
Nicola says you'll make head of
the Treasury Department in 10 years.
Does he?
I've only been at
the Bank of Italy for a year.
Besides, that's a whole
different job.
Meaning?
Well...
that would be
a political office.
We're mere specialists.
Go on, be modest. Nicola says
you're smarter than he is.
Very impressive,
coming from my brother.
Nicola's crazier
than his patients.
You're right.
God!
You're a clumsy one!
-How are things?
-Well, I passed my exam.
I start university this year.
Letters and Sciences.
I want to study Archaeology.
Travel the world.
-Sounds great.
-Yeah.
I've competed in plenty
of student competitions.
I cook and play the violin.
-Is that it?
-Lots of other things.
I get bored doing
only one thing.
You're bored now,
making coffee.
I'm making coffee,
preparing
sweets with Sara,
and talking to
the Bank of Italy.
That's plenty.
-Auntie, come quick!
-I'm coming.
-Look how many I made.
-Good Lord!
Look at all those!
You're a genius!
-Ladies...
-Would you like more pasta?
-Yes.
-Can I take one?
-Carlo, get lost!
-Not yet. Go on.
Francesca is great with kids.
Not me, though.
-I just don't have the knack.
-There are mothers of all kinds.
All different styles.
I wasn't a good mother
for Matteo.
At least, I wasn't
the mother he wanted.
You were a wonderful mother.
I can see that by Nicola.
Excuse me.
-I'll go for milk.
-There should be some.
Yeah, but not enough
to last till morning.
I'm going for milk.
I already bought some.
Is there no way out
of this house?
Sorry.
Sorry, darling.
Forgive me.
-You're late.
-I'm sorry, I had problems at home.
You shouldn't keep
people waiting.
It's dangerous.
Sitting here with a briefcase
is suspicious.
-Have you got the keys?
-They're inside.
With the money, the papers
and the gun.
Know how to use it?
No.
You'll learn.
Let me go.
Let me go, let me go.
Nicola, let me go.
Let me go.
What about your daughter?
Just tell me why.
Let me go.
...an organized military group
with arms and ammunition.
The police in Turin
released today the identities
of three men and two women
who visited the hideout
of the Red Brigades
discovered in Turin.
Only on of the detainees
has refused to speak
with authorities.
The arrest warrant
included allegations
of trying to subvert
the social order
and destroy the institutions
of democracy.
Give me another piece.
Give me another piece
of gazelle!
Yes, little lion.
Daddy the hunter
will bring you some.
Daddy, I don't want to go.
-I don't want to go to fencing.
-Why not?
It was your idea,
so you're going.
-Where's Mommy?
-I told you, she's gone.
She left. She's gone.
I'm sorry, Sara.
Sorry, I was wrong.
Sara, please.
Let's make up.
In line, salute.
One, two, three, four,
five, six, down.
En garde.
Step forward...
Step back...
In back...
En garde.
Step forward...
Step back...
You're all over the place today.
Let's start over.
Everyone line up.
Come on, line up.
First position.
Salute.
One, two, three, four,
five, six,
down. En garde.
SPRING 1980
Do you, Tommaso...?
Carlo.
-What?
-Carlo Tommasi.
-Not Tommasi Carlo.
-Right, sorry.
-Do you, Carlo Carati...
-No, no, Carlo Tommasi.
Francesca Carati.
There's also a male Carati.
Yeah, that's me.
Nicola Carati,
brother of the bride,
Francesca Carati.
So you're...
The brother of the bride.
Congratulations.
You should be sitting over there,
by the girl with the hair.
-Because...
-No, I'm...
I'm the best man,
he's a friend of mine.
Oh, you're the best man,
but also the brother...
...of the bride,
which means...
A coincidence.
It's not illegal.
Right, let's start over,
as if...
Carlo Tommasi,
do you take as your bride
the here present
Francesca Carati?
I do.
Okay, that's good.
Francesca Carati,
do you take as your husband
the here present
-Carlo Tommasi?
-I do.
Good, very nice.
You can exchange rings now.
Careful.
Sorry, it's my first wedding.
Mine too.
You have to meet my friends.
-They're dying to meet you.
-No, come on.
-I'm stealing him a second.
-Excuse us, please.
-They want to see your blue eyes.
-That again?
-After all these years...
-My brother, Matteo.
-Carlotta.
-Hi.
-Teresa.
How about this?
Look.
-Sara, hi!
-My niece, Sara.
Give your uncle a kiss.
Nice wedding, eh?
-When are you getting married?
-Who would marry me?
What? You're a real catch.
Brakes and muffler repair,
blue collar aristocracy.
I was a real catch.
What do you mean?
This just came.
They fired you?
Basically.
Laid off with minimum benefits.
They sent out 23,000 of these.
-Can't you do something?
-We've been on strike for a month.
You said things were okay.
I didn't want to ruin
Carlo's wedding.
Read this.
What do you think?
Do you study this
at the Bank of Italy?
Yeah, more or less.
So what can be done?
Fiat is 7 billion lira
in debt.
Lots of smaller companies
are worse off,
they don't produce enough.
They can't compete with
-the international market.
-So?
The workers can't win.
That's his opinion.
He's not a genie.
-I wish I were wrong.
-Pay no attention.
You've got unions.
The unions, right.
They're legs are broken.
People are scared.
Carlo, say something!
They can just fire him?
Like 100 years ago?
What, you want me to lie?
They're reorganizing
the industrial system.
The industries are modernized
and they reduce costs
-to remain competitive.
-Who cares?
I don't know.
We have to pay them
to screw things up?
To hell with the system.
Please!
To hell with the system?
Then what would you
replace it with?
-Any ideas?
-Me?
You're the ones
who should have them!
Okay, that's enough.
No need for an arguement.
This is a party.
Forget about it.
I already knew
this was our swan's song.
They'll have forgotten us
in a few years.
Don't worry, doc!
They can't beat me.
I won't sit at home
crying.
What do I care?
Vitale'll find another job.
Or I'll invent one.
I'll fix kitchen sinks,
TV sets, radiators...
They fill our homes with appliances
which inevitably break.
Somebody has to fix them.
-Why not me?
-lmpeccable logic.
Or I'll check into a clinic,
dress up like Napoleon...
Yes, sir!
I feel like dancing.
-Come on, let's go dance.
-Okay.
Come on, you two deadbeats!
Come and dance.
-You know "Anatomy"?
-What's that?
-"Amado mio."
-That one.
Mrs. Tommasi,
may I have this dance?
Hey, careful with my mom!