For best IPTV provider, please visit: www.IPTV.CAT
Eh?
Have you noticed
the sun is following us?
It's following us.
Good morning, tickets please.
Sir?
Were you dreaming?
Sorry, you'll never know
how it ends now.
May I see your ticket, please?
What a strange ticket...
Ask him...
Excuse me. May I...
Where are you from?
Somewhere far away?
- Yes, sort of.
- And where's that?
It doesn't matter.
You're local.
Yes.
- Is it so obvious?
- Yes... I can tell.
Of course! You're such a bumpkin!
You look like...
like some paintings...
ancient ones...
Your profile.
- Mine?
- Yes.
Yes, perhaps...
maybe you've seen them.
A profile like yours.
A big nose?
Oh no, just the opposite.
It's nice... it's nice.
So you're a scientist?
No, no, I'm...
Jeez, it really stinks in here!
This fine gentleman
doesn't like water?
When did you last
change your socks, mate?
But it's your lucky day,
look at this.
Because you need some new socks
You really stink!
Buy some perfume
to soothe your delicate nostrils.
You tell him. Such a charming man,
but he stinks.
How can you pretty girls
put up with this stench?
- He's smoking to hide the smell.
- That's enough.
Not even jail smelled this bad.
Enough! What the fuck!
Take it easy.
Be careful, this guy's dangerous.
You know what? I'll gift
you some socks... Here.
Skinflint.
There's a six-foot criminal
on the train, folks!
Come on, sock him in the face...
Buy my socks!
Socks, perfumes, aftershave!
- What can you see?
- People.
Can I have a look?
THE CHIMERA
Arthur!
Come on, jump in.
- What are you doing here?
- Spartaco told me you were coming.
He is the one who paid the lawyer
to get you released!
Eh?
- I'll. pay it all back.
- There's no need.
- He just wants you to go and say hi.
- Say hi?
Fuck that!
Come on, Arthur!
Don't be like that!
Don't be stupid!
Please wait, listen...
We're sorry about that day,
I mean that night.
We honestly didn't notice
you'd fallen behind.
Don't waste your saliva.
"Don't waste your saliva"?
I taught you that expression.
Take me home.
I said home, not here!
I don't want to see anyone.
No one.
Just five minutes...
A toast with your friends!
Here they are.
Here he is at last!
Well then?
Short hair, so pale. What happened?
I'll take Arthur home,
he can settle in,
then he'll come back and celebrate.
Not even a toast after all this time?
- No, thanks.
- Then we'll come with you.
Mario, fetch a bottle.
What the fuck!
I did try...
Here, chicky chicky...
Sorry.
- Arthur?
- Yes.
It is you, isn't it?
Yes, I'm looking for signora Flora.
I know.
You're all she ever talks about.
Arthur this, Arthur that...
- Can I see her?
- Yes.
I reckon so.
Right now?
Yes, of course.
I'll come with you.
Ma'am.
Have you been smoking? I told you
not to! It spoils your voice!
He's here.
At last!
My friend.
My dear friend, my only friend.
Take me in there.
What a catastrophe!
This leg works, I can move this one.
But not this one,
hence the wheelchair.
It's comfortable.
Wheelchairs are a great invention.
You see? I told you he'd come back.
Woman of little faith.
This is Beniamina's boyfriend.
Go and make some coffee, go on.
Beniamina...
Don't lose hope.
Yes, but...
But you always find everything...
Yes, of course.
That was quick!
It's cold!
No, make some fresh coffee.
It's fine. Thanks.
He's so polite. You're so sweet.
What are you doing?
Don't just stand there!
- What must I do?
- Warm up your voice!
No, bring some wood in,
physical exercise helps.
You don't sing with your brain,
you sing with your body. Go on!
Nosy Parker.
Tone deaf.
She's completely tone deaf.
Poor thing...
- Hi, Sista, how are things?
- Fine.
- Hi, Grandma.
- My little flower.
- Good morning, Mum.
- Look who's here!
- Grandma.
- Darling, how are you?
- Mum, how are you?
- Just great. Look who's here!
- Are you glad he's back, Mum?
- Of course. Here he is!
Arthur's back.
Arthur, your eyes are glassy.
Don't you feel well?
You're dressed too lightly.
He's bound to fall sick like that.
Have you got any clothes?
Let's look in Dad's room.
Trousers, sweaters.
I'll put some together.
He can't wear a dead man's clothes.
Do you remember... What's it called?
- The shearling jacket!
- Yes, perfect, it's nice and warm.
Okay.
Thank you, Italia.
Thank you, my dear.
Eat up.
Who's this? The new student?
Hasn't he had lunch yet?
- Call that lunch?
- Expect her to make roast beef?
- That's overcooked and bland.
- No! It looks delicious!
- Is it good?
- Yes.
Italia is a fine cook
with a talent for music.
Music? The music's
about to change though.
- Will you tell him?
- Yes.
Arthur, we've found you a job.
A proper job.
At a builders' warehouse.
No more living on Mum's shoulders.
You can start work as of tomorrow.
No, thanks.
You're stuck up, you know that?
And to think Beniamina loved you,
how could she...
She still loves him!
That's enough, Nella, sit down!
Sit down!
- Are you okay, Mum?
- Yes.
Italia, can you take his plate away,
please?
Bring Arthur a light
for his cigarette. Thank you.
You let him smoke in the house?
Because he's a man. No one else can.
You never allowed us to.
- I'll get him some clothes.
- Your student's very obedient.
She's a servant
disguised as a student.
- We all know that.
- Of course we do.
Mum's clever at finding maids without
having to pay. She's manipulative.
Okay, let's end it here.
We'll never agree.
Every time we come here
we start arguing.
That's enough! Enough!
- What's up?
- Did you hear that?
- What?
- I can hear a baby crying.
- It's a little lamb.
- No, it's not...
- It's a baby crying.
- I can't hear it!
What are you doing here?
Signora Flora told me to bring you
these things.
Here.
For the fever.
Take your temperature.
What are you doing?
Are you crazy? You'll break it.
You'll break it...
You've done a good job here.
Nice.
What are all these objects?
Just old stuff.
Eh?
Things many "hyes" have seen.
Eyes.
Not hyes, eyes.
Thanks.
can give you a crash course
in Italian if you want.
You?
Sure!
It's a nice hiding place here.
All those plants, al the trees...
There were lots of trees
where I was born too.
Andiroba trees...
Jacaranda trees...
It was the only thing
I liked about that place.
Why are you laughing?
Look at that. Isn't it strange?
It looks like a person
planted head down in the ground.
Yes, there...
where the branches split.
See?
No.
This one's better.
Maybe you can see it better
from here.
No, no, no!
What's this?
Fuck!
Arthur?
Your things are in here.
Your beloved pots.
Did you think we'd stolen them.
from under your tree?
Here you are. It's all here.
We couldn't leave them
with the police rummaging around
after you got arrested.
They wanted to nail you
and increase your sentence.
And instead of thanking us
you barge in here?
- What will you do with them?
- I don't know, eh?
Leave it to me. I'll take them
to Spartaco to pay off my debt.
Take them to Spartaco?
He'd only laugh at you.
Instead of taking Spartaco
these cheap pieces...
why don't we find something
to put with them?
- Now we're back together again...
- No, thanks!
- That's my uncle.
- What do you want?
- The hoe.
- Hurry up!
Not dead yet, eh?
Don't be a nuisance!
Get out of here.
Move it!
Arthur, wanna end up like him?
Soft in the head from the toil.
Bent over by life
and with a limp dick.
Come on... don't try and fool us.
I know you can't rest knowing
those things are still down there.
There's a lot down there.
For sure!
Arthur...
The witches are coming!
Happy Epiphany!
He's stone drunk.
Wait, we'll take it off here
and put it on here!
You look so beautiful!
Excuse me.
Excuse me, please.
Excuse me, can I take a photo?
- Can I take your photo?
- A photo...
Just one.
Don't hide!
Just one photo!
Okay.
No!
Please!
- Have we met?
- No.
But people have told me about you...
and him. the Englishman.
Me?
I'm Spartaco's friend.
- Ah, you're Spartaco's friend?
- Yes.
- Your friend is very rude.
- No...
He's like that when he drinks.
- He's an oaf.
- You say that 'cos you're in love.
What if I were?
Would you recommend him?
We would recommend him,
but he doesn't look at girls anymore,
he only thinks of the one who's gone.
You see?
Hold it there!
Come on!
Mister...
come with me, I have a gig for you.
I want to show you something big.
Filled with stuff.
But then we'll go halves. All right?
Mario?
You should see what a perfectly
round hole she left.
My granddad said, "Before you marry
a woman, take her to pee on the sand.
If the hole she leaves is nice
and round and deep, marry her!
But if she drips here and there..."
That's why you never married.
But maybe she's the right girl, eh?
Have you seen her?
That woman is an ornament of nature.
If you say so.
Melodie, do you know what you are?
An ornament of nature.
Thanks, Pirro.
Help me. How do I get in?
Did she have to come?
Maybe we can sell her something,
she's rich.
Careful does it.
There you are. Careful.
Now spin around.
We'll show you things
even archaeologists would die for!
I find the Etruscans so fascinating,
so "bohemian",
so distant from the myth
of the Roman world.
Pirro!
As my aunt says...
If the Etruscans had still been here
wouldn't be all this machismo in Italy
Did you know the women
were in charge in Etruscan times?
Well done, excellent observation!
- Here I am.
- At last.
I'm late.
- We were waiting for you.
- Let's go.
- Come on.
- Mister, let's go.
- Where is it?
- Over there.
- Over there?
- Yes.
It's under here. A treasure!
It's full of stuff!
But remember what we agreed.
No tricks now.
There's nothing here, Katir.
There are no signs of a tomb.
- It's a hole.
- You were wrong.
- It was probably a cattleshed.
- What?
My ancestors found
a load of stuff around here!
Vases, a spear! Even a statue!
Where are all these things now?
They dumped them, they got scared.
What fools!
But if the expert wants
to check the place out...
Mister...
Okay.
Won't you offer the maestro a drink?
Before he gets to work?
You've got some
You've got some. Of course you do...
There you are.
Hold your horses.
My turn now.
Hurry up, I'm thirsty.
Pirro, me too?
Coming up.
Well?
What was in this? He's sick.
Only fernet.
- Only fernet?
- We all drank some.
How do you feel?
- I feel sick!
- He's sick.
- I feel sick...
- I feel sick too.
He's faking it.
He's sick because the rod
found something.
Don't talk rubbish.
You put poison in it!
- You're trying to trick me.
- No one wants to trick you.
- I want to dig too.
- Shut up.
- You promised.
- We promised you?
Who said anything about digging?
Does it mean so much to you?
Then why don't you dig on your own?
- Not on my own.
- Why not?
- Why don't you dig on your own?
- No, not on my own.
Why not?
Because of the spirits.
- You know about the spirits then!
- No, not on my own!
You're afraid of the spirits!
Afraid they'll grab you?
And follow you home!
You're scared
they'll get into bed with you.
- Where is it?
- There.
Here?
No, that was the wrong note. Listen.
Okay, let's start.
I'd like to explain to you, O God
Where my suffering lies
Italia? There's a leak here too.
Bring a bowl.
Oh darn this rain!
What a disaster!
You're flat.
Your character's asking to speak
to God, to explain her feelings.
It's not the right time to sing flat.
Go and do the ironing,
careful with the crease.
Right note, perfect crease.
Are you listening?
Italia...
What a scatterbrain!
Carry on ironing.
- All right, ma'am.
- Discipline.
I'd like to explain to you, O God
Where my suffering lies
But fate condemns me
To weep
What's that?
It's not "what".
It's who.
Colombina, come here.
Come here!
Take your brother.
Take care of him
and hide in the bedroom.
Don't cry.
Go on!
What are you looking for?
An iron rod?
A long one?
I put it on top of the wardrobe.
It looked dangerous.
Italia?
Yes, ma'am.
Here it is.
Rock.
More rock.
Here it is.
Guys, there's a passage.
But someone's already been here.
The stone's smashed!
How horrible!
What can you see?
Look at this... There's nothing here.
- Nothing?
- Not even a fibula?
Not even a ring...
- Here.
- The grave goods are over here.
There's loads of stuff.
Melodie?
- Yes.
- Hold this.
There's a lekythos.
Look at this!
Red figure.
Lovely.
Grab everything!
Those who work hard come off worse,
they travel on foot, never by horse.
Those who work hard are full of woe,
those who don't, make all the dough!
Let's toast, let's toast,
let's toast!
Katir's here.
Ah, here you are!
Phonies!
You phonies!
You're celebrating with the profits
from my stuff!
Get lost!
Even the pigs would spit you out!
THE POOR "TOMBAROLI"
The Adventures of Arthur the Dowser
Friends, we'll sing you a song
that ends badly for those involved,
but at the time they devoted
their hopes and skills
to the cursed need
and desire to upset fate.
Now for the first tercet.
There's this stranger,
charming and tall.
From Ireland, or was it England?
And thanks to
his dowsing skills and all
he's the real leader of a gang.
In love with archaeology was he
but he never married it
and now he deals in contraband.
Whatever the ground offers up
when they dig
to him and his friends
on a grave-robbing gig.
They've a connection
with the underground
They're seven grave robbers,
and we call them "tombaroli"
Some people rob graves to fulfil
the collective dream of poor peasants,
to find a treasure as a way
of emerging from poverty.
Others are just victims
of the yearning for wealth
that afflicts humanity.
In these cases,
it is easy to resort to villainy.
Not everyone is capable of defying
the law, the darkness
and the souls of the dead.
Some people are scared of dying
and others for adventure are bred.
Nights on the lookout
when danger is rife
with flights through woods
with stealth.
It's a thrilling and risky life,
it's the dream of redemption
and wealth.
The poor "tombaroli"
petty criminals for the Law
all they want is a well-paid job
Just think, dear folks,
what the law's there for,
to protect those
who exploit your labour.
What's the point of judging then,
the "tombaroli"
are just a drop in the ocean
Ah, a drop in the ocean.
I can't see anything.
Let's look over there!
What's the point of judging then,
the "tombaroli"
are just a drop in the ocean
Ah, a drop in the ocean...
There they are! Come on!
Hey you... photo.
Photo?
Photograph.
Wait.
There you go.
Oh, thank you. Very nice.
- Nice.
- Is this a temple?
- Yes, yes, temple.
- Nice... nice.
Bye Bye.
CRASH COURSE IN ITALIAN
CRAFTY
PILFER
I'LL "KIL" YOU
SO HEAVY!
Italia? Bring us some tea.
Look...
Biscuits...
WE AGREE
SECRET LIAISON
EXCELLENT
WHAT DO YOU WANT?
NOTHING
Thanks.
May I go?
Yes, go on... go on.
Fabiana, how long for the pasta?
Just a sec.
Careful.
Forks!
- I'll get the thermos flask.
- Good girl.
She forgot the thermos flask
but we're about to leave.
You're coming too, aren't you?
Yes, of course.
Arthur, you're so thin...
Really thin.
- Are you eating?
- Yes.
When Beniamina comes back and
sees you like that. it's not good.
Get some biscuits from the kitchen.
They'll buck you up.
I've told you before,
madam mustn't see you.
- Mummy, can we come with you?
- No.
I said no!
How long will you be?
I'm coming.
A couple of hours. When you hear
the gate, go to your room.
- Please!
- That's enough.
Bye.
Look after him.
Wait.
May I?
What's that?
It's a thing that rings.
May I?
Yes.
Bell.
It's called a bell.
Madam calls for me with a bell.
You can keep it.
A present?
- For me?
- Let's go.
Thanks, but...
Wait...
Look, that's the station.
- Okay, yes.
- We're nearly there.
I yearned to see this place again.
The city and the countryside.
I often came to this station
to pick up my daughters
back from a trip...
RI-PAR-BEL-LA.
- This leg is still a bit painful.
- Riparbella.
I encouraged my daughters to travel.
It's important to travel...
I couldn't hold Beniamina back...
she'd jump on any train.
She's really curious...
She'll have so much to tell us
when she returns.
- Who does it belong to now, ma'am?
- The station? No one.
What do you mean?
It's a public building.
It belongs to everyone.
Does it belong to everyone or no one?
Stop nitpicking...
It's an abandoned station.
All right then.
I'll see you next week.
Good morning. We brought the puppies.
Just a minute, please.
The Englishman's here.
Yes, he's here.
- Is that a puppy?
- Yes.
- Can I have a look?
- Better not.
It's sick.
Mr Harrison, what a surprise!
Welcome back.
Please come in.
Excuse me, but I was here first.
It's a special case, ma'am.
An emergency.
Spartaco will be very happy
that you're back.
- How many pieces?
- 18.
18.
- Is that all?
- That's all.
He's weighing them up.
Spartaco says,
"You've remembered me at last."
Listen, keep my share.
I don't want any debts.
Only his share though.
Spartaco was expecting
better after all this time.
What?
There's a lekythos from IV BC,
with the veiled woman.
Very rare!
- What about the kylix?
- And the running fawn?
Spartaco says
they're just everyday objects.
- Tombs of poor folk.
- What?
- They weren't all pharaohs!
- It's absurd.
Received.
He'll take it all.
The payment.
- Take it or leave it.
- We'll take it.
Check if they've expired.
This shovel?
What do you need a shovel for?
To plant beans, officer.
Beans at this time of year? No way.
Maybe that's why
they didn't sprout, Melchiorre.
- I told you it wasn't time.
- I didn't know.
Don't act smart,
we've got our eyes on you all.
Especially him, the Englishman.
Got that?
- Your papers.
- Thanks.
Sorry
May I? Thanks.
What's that?
Is that property of the state?
- Which one?
- That there.
- This?
- Yes.
Is it property of the state?
No, this is mine...
What did you cal it, Arthur?
It's an apotropaic phallus.
A "troparic" phallus.
- You know what that is, right?
- I know what troparic means.
Yes, I've seen them.
His granddad gave it
to my granddad...
Mario?
- This is yours.
- Thanks.
- I'll count it.
- Go ahead.
- I'm 50, 000 liras short.
- Count it again.
Jerry and I got less than Mario.
We could build a cabin like this
Would you like it?
It's horrible.
It's my round tonight.
Arthur.
I wanted to show them your home
Hi.
She's like a broomstick!
She kissed him
All these people.
Cirillo.
Colombina.
and I'm Italia.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- Hi.
Long live Italia!
You put the ice in first.
Who taught you to mix drinks?
You're an idiot!
I said it's fine.
Thanks.
Great! Long live Italia. Let's toast!
I'll take this.
She might be a broomstick
but she's good with men.
I want to sing too!
- CanI sing?
- Is he going?
What's Katir doing?
Go on, Katir!
Come on, Katir!
Thanks.
Cool, Katir!
Hooray for the power station!
Get 'em off!
Come here.
My mates...
Such assholes!
Come on, let's go.
Arthur.
Come on!
Jerry, don't get wet!
Keep away from me if you do!
It's disgusting!
Guys, look what I've found.
The Euphronios Krater!
You're braver than me
taking a dip in that water.
There's toxic waste in there.
Fabiana, this is electrifying water!
I came out in a rash last time
It improves your looks
- Have a swim.
- Grab Pirro.
No, grab Mario.
What have you done to him?
You've cast a spell.
You're a witch.
What is this place?
It looks like a tip.
No, we always come here.
It's a kind of cemetery.
Just look at those guys!
Cemetery? In what way?
In what way...
See those holes... That one,
and that one, they're tombs.
Well done.
Let's get out of here. It's horrible.
Are you scared?
Yeah, you're scared.
Long-live-ltalia is scared of tombs.
They're 2000 years old!
The maestro has felt something!
Watch out!
Is he sick? What's wrong?
No, he's lost in his chimeras.
Hasn't he told you?
- How we make our money?
- No.
Go and get the tools.
We open tombs.
Tonight of all nights
when we're in our best clothes you
have to go after your visions!
Well?
Hold it... hold it!
Let them concentrate,
they might find something.
Something?
The grave goods.
- What?
- The stuff they left the dead.
They believed they helped
to save their souls, right?
The souls...
Fabiana, go and check
no one's coming. Move it!
Fabiana do this, Fabiana do that.
Arthur...
did this belong to a dead person?
Let me see... it's possible.
A child's grave.
Fabiana, help me stop them.
- Please!
- No, leave them to it.
What are they going to do?
Steal from the souls?
What a pain in the ass she is!
Those things aren't made
for human eyes...
but those of souls.
What the fuck was that?
Hear that, Arthur?
They aren't made for human eyes.
Miss, we really liked you before,
but now you're being a pain.
Go away!
- Fabiana, help me.
- Be quiet!
- We have to call the police.
- What?
- The police?
- Be quiet, you fool!
What about Beniamina?
Does she know what you do?
He didn't tell you Beniamina's dead?
Just great!
Go home.
What the fuck!
- Let's go.
- That's how it's done.
I'll come back for you.
- Get rid of the broomstick.
- Get lost!
I curse you!
That's enough.
You're asking for trouble!
If they tell you to shut up,
you shut up!
Are you listening? What a nerve...
Go on.
I can feel something.
We need to widen it.
Go on...
Mario!
Let me see.
Feckin'hell, it's untouched!
It's still sealed.
Careful. careful...
- Wedge it in there.
- Further down.
Wait!
Give me the torch.
Mario, pass me your lighter.
Oh God!
- Some animals.
- Jeez!
How sweet...
They look like votive offerings.
There's some water.
It's covered in paintings.
This is amazing. Just look at this.
This is beautiful.
Oh, God!
Never mind the souls...
The Etruscans left these here for us.
She's been waiting for us
for 2000 years!
It's a gift to us!
This is amazing!
Just look at all this stuff!
Mario... It's a goddess.
I don't believe it...
This is not some funeral stuff.
It's a shrine.
A temple.
This will make us all rich.
How do we get it out of here?
We don't even have the car.
We'll carry it outside for now.
Then hide it in the wood.
Then we'll load it into the car
when Fabiana gets here.
Come on, come on.
I'll put it here.
- Ready?
- Once sharp blow.
One sharp blow.
Perfect.
Pass it to me.
Jerry, let's section it here.
What?
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Calm down!
- What the fuck!
- Calm down.
We'll put it back together.
We've done it before.
We'll take it out in pieces.
How else would we get it out of here?
We'll put it back together again.
Take it easy.
- Easy.
- We'll put it back together.
Fuck...
I'll go and see.
We have to run.
My father wil kill me
if we end up in jail.
She really did call the cops.
There are two of them.
We outnumber them.
Fuck, they'll nab us.
- Hey, calm down.
- Two officers.
- Two of them...
- Two what?
Two cars.
How many men?
One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven...
Have they upped the police budget?
There are too many of them,
we have to run!
Come on.
Let's go,
the place is crawling with cops.
- Come on, guys!
- Drop everything.
You liked jail then?
Arthur, Arthur!
Let's go, Arthur!
There they are!
Where are you going?
Do something!
There's another one!
There, look!
There they are!
Suckers!
- Arthur!
- Come on.
Arthur! What have you done?
- That's all we needed!
- Bring him here.
Darn it!
Why?
Why aren't they chasing after us?
- Thank goodness they're not.
- Damn it! We'd struck it rich.
Why aren't they chasing us? Why?!
"Police"
Rospo, bring me that rope.
Get a move on.
Close it up.
Thanks.
- What's wrong?
- It's Arthur.
- He's come back.
- I thought it was a ghost.
It's Arthur.
- I'll get you a drink, Mum.
- We kicked her out.
- She found the kids.
- Italia. the witch!
I told you that girl
was a piece of trash.
- I never liked her.
- I heard the baby crying.
We all said so. Stop it.
Know what Mum found out?
She wasn't hiding one child...
- But two!
- Yes.
- Maybe more than two.
- And you made fun of me...
- Here you are, Mum.
- "A little lamb"...
She took Mum's thermos flask.
I'd have taken it if I'd known.
She's a liar and a thief.
It must have been awful
to find those children there.
You were children once too.
Poor kids, she hid them
under her bed.
How do you feel now?
Old.
It's this house, Mum.
It's falling to bits. It's a hovel...
Can't you feel the damp,
it's not good for you...
We'll find you a nicer place to live.
No more singing lessons.
You'll see, Mum, we've found
this beautiful nursing home.
They'll look after you.
A big garden, lots of flowers,
you'll meet new friends...
It's for your own good, Mum.
Can I have this? You don't use it.
Or did you want it?
- We'll sell everything in here.
- This is madness!
What if Beniamina were to come back?
There won't be anyone
waiting for her.
Mum, she's not coming back.
- Spartaco.
- There's no one here. We're closing.
Open the door, it's important.
Then call him for us.
I'll talk to him, I'll smash
this phone if he doesn't answer.
- Pirro!
- Melodie?
Where's Spartaco?
Spartaco isn't here.
He'll be back next week.
Do you need anything?
Can I help you?
Please...
The back, please.
Details
Please.
Which one's Spartaco?
That's her, my aunt.
She's very strict.
That's Spartaco... the blonde woman.
Scheming bitch!
Be quiet!
Excuse me, look who's here.
Documents.
Documents, please.
The documents!
Why have you brought them here?
This is a private auction,
for museum curators.
But, it's important.
The Englishman is here.
You have to talk to him.
Listen, Spartaco...
Finally you can see my face.
Wait!
My niece had a lot of fun
witnessing your...
What is it you call it?
Oh, yes, your gift.
Here.
The gift of finding lost things.
Aunt...
Excuse me, the Americans
want to talk to you.
Pour them some more champagne.
Go on!
Quick.
I'll be right there, go on!
You can soil your clothes and act
the crook as much as you want...
but you'll never change
from what you are.
What's she saying?
I was asking my friend Arthur
if you like my statue.
Didn't our friend Arthur tell you?
That's what we've come for,
the statue.
It's ours and...
Nonsense:
The statue already has
a certificate of origin.
- And we have the noddle.
- The what?
The head. We found the statue.
And we have the head.
Yes, it's in here.
Come here, Arthur, you take it.
I told you it was important.
You said the statue is priceless.
How much is the head worth?
- Are you blackmailing me?
- Yes, we are.
Or we'll walk in there and tell your
friends where you get your finds.
Show me this head.
Let's see if it's worth anything.
- Price first.
- Head first.
- Money first...
Price first!
Don't push your luck,
I'm the only one who can buy it.
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
- We'll see about that... Messieurs?
- Quiet. It'll be a fake.
- What?
- It's real.
It's real, we found it.
The price.
we want to hear your price.
Arthur, my dear...
show me this head.
You've seen it now
You're not made for human eyes.
Arthur...
It looks interesting.
What the fuck?
Excuse me...
Oh, it's you!
Have you got a light?
Keep it. You might need it.
While you're here...
I wanted to ask you.
You don't know what happened
to my goods?
Your what?
My grave goods.
There was a painted askos,
and two grey ceramic ollas,
a large one and a smaller one,
there was also a golden fibula,
it was pinned here.
It meant a lot to me,
so I thought maybe.
But l...
I don't understand.
Forgive me.
While you're here,
we have a question.
We've lost part of
our grave goods too.
There was a kylix with eyes on it,
the big ones for drinking...
- What was painted on it?
- A fawn running.
It was nice, I really liked it.
Whereas they'd left me a little bell
with a little bird on it.
- It was nice.
- It was in bronze.
Have you seen it?
Buddy... buddy.
Fancy that... look who it is!
Wait a sec, please.
I need to ask you something.
Thanks, may I?
I wanted to ask you if you've seen
Something that was mine
but I can't find it...
In the world's soul,
there's death, love and life
Lots of mystery deep down,
joy and strife.
But if humans were
more like birds in flight,
if they didn't crave
treasure shining bright,
they'd live in better harmony
between bliss and the arcane.
Not alienated from the sacred
and the profane,
nor afflicted by immediate gain,
by the anxiety of profit
which only adds to the strain.
And while they concluded
this important deal,
rebellion raged in the stranger
with his nerves of steel.
But he was misunderstood,
they considered him mad,
they gave him a hard time,
this fool turned bad.
They shouted insults
and their amazement grew
but he was left untouched
by whatever they threw.
All he longed for was a fuller life,
his heart nourished
by a richer source
He tried to fly, fly over the hills
but he remained on the ground
with all his old ills.
He decided to come back
after wandering around
But he found
that everything had changed
Too much had changed.
Melchiorre...
Forget about him. He's dead to us.
Let's have a toast.
Mister, mister...
Come here, I'm talking to you.
What are you doing?
- Well?
- Look at the state you're in.
- What the fuck have you done?
- You're a total mess.
- Come and eat with us.
- Yes, come on.
We'll get rid of those wretched
friends of yours.
They're fucking thick!
- We'll treat him to dinner one day.
- Yeah, we'll take him with us.
A nice place.
with a nice glass of wine.
A good meal to strengthen you up,
you look like a fakir.
Just look at the state this guy's in.
We'll spend a nice day together.
We'll take you to this nice place.
- A nice place.
- Okay?
When?
Hey!
If you want to see Mum,
clean yourself up.
That's an order.
This one?
Eh2
Yes.
Is he going to the ball?
- Shall I?
- Go on.
- A bit shorter.
- Shorter?
Give me a hand.
- Is that better?
- Much better.
This un?
This one!
It's changed a bit.
Hi.
Hey, who are you?
Hello.
May I?
I didn't know who you were with...
where you were.
No one knew where you'd got to...
It's not done.
Don't ever do that again, Colombina.
I didn't even know you'd gone out.
It took you ages to get back,
I was so worried.
He followed me here.
You found us.
What have you done?
It's all changed. It's beautiful.
- We're squatting in the station.
- Yes.
- We've worked hard on it, eh?
- There's still a lot to do.
- If you want to help...
- It didn't belong to anyone.
Or it belonged to everyone.
It's only a temporary setup.
Life itself is temporary.
- Fabiana?
- Yes.
She lives here too.
Look who's here!
H
Who'll give me a hand
to empty the car?
- I will...
- Let's go, kids.
- Hurry up.
- Let's go.
What have you bought?
- Let's unload the car.
- Did you get everything?
Hope we have some crisps and popcorn.
Just popcorn, if you're good
when I put the treatment on.
They'ye all got lice. So be careful.
Come here,
I'll put the concoction on you.
- No, Fabiana.
- You'll have lice too.
- Did it drip in your eyes?
- No.
I'd had enough of them too.
Always in charge, giving me orders.
But where did you get to?
Excuse me.
I was thinking.
Maybe Arthur could stay here too?
- Me?
- Yes.
- For how long?
- A while...
Are you any good with kids?
He can babysit
when we're out at work.
- Or fix the electrics.
- Or change the windows.
- He could clean the bathroom.
- We needed a cleaning man.
- Can you cook? Make meat sauce?
- Pancakes?
- I need a massage
- You're all crazy.
Will you be our servant?
Bring us breakfast in bed
every morning?
I've found one.
- I've found a head louse.
- I don't believe you.
Come on, let's rinse it off!
No, no.
The servant.
What do you want?
Nothing.
don't care, go away.
What a bore...
Come here.
Me and you.
we have a secret liaison.
Yes.
No luck.
- Are you tired, Arthur?
- Are you tired already, mister?
There's nothing here.
What do you mean? Spartaco told us
you're an expert in the field.
She says you're good
with this divining rod.
I'll take you to talk to this guy...
Come on.
- Hey, whatshisname!
- Come on...
I'm talking to you! Hurry up!
Rospo, go and get him.
- Is he dead?
- No, he's alive.
Come here.
Come on! We won't hurt you.
Come on. Help him.
Is this your dog?
- What's in your pocket?
- Show us.
No one's going to steal it.
- Show us!
- Come on!
It's gold.
Pure gold, see?
- It's a golden sun!
- Tell him where you found it.
Where did you find it?
What's he saying?
Are you capable of finding
these suns?
Here.
I see something!
There's something there, a tunnel.
Arthur?
Arthur, come here.
Come here, Arthur. Jump in.
- Jump inside, Arthur.
- Jump in.
- Why me?
- You get the honour, you found it.
That's how it works here.
Go ahead.
Jump in.
- Tell us what's down there.
- Be careful.
Arthur!
THE CHIMERA