I didn't think I'd find
a friend like Bruno in life
nor that friendship was a place
where you put your roots
and what is waiting for you.
I was raised as an only child
in a city apartment.
I wasn't used to doing things in twos.
But in the summer of 1984
my parents rented a house
in a mountain town,
where, ironically, there was only
one little boy living at the time.
Bruno.
Bruno!
Excuse me, there's one here.
Come on!
Come on.
Ah!
- Oh! Oh!
- Thank you, thank you.
- I'm Frances.
- Hello, Wilhelmina Sonia.
- Pleasure.
- I'm going.
Goodbye.
- Love!
- Hmm?
- Come on, it's late.
- Okay.
- Good night.
Hey!
- Would you like some breakfast?
- Hmm.
We have just arrived,
but we have things.
- Do you want a biscuit?
- Yes.
- Do you live here?
Do you have brothers, Bruno?
No,
I'm the last child in the country.
- I don't understand.
- I'm the last kid in the village.
Hello, Pietro!
This is Bruno.
Hi.
- Are you coming to have breakfast?
- Hmm.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
How old are you, Bruno?
- 12 in November.
- Same as Pietro!
Only he's in January.
Where do you live?
Over there, with my uncles.
My father isn't here.
And where is he?
He's away, he's a bricklayer.
In Switzerland or maybe in Austria.
And where is mom?
- Can I have another cookie?
- Yes.
- Ready?
- Wait.
Yes!
One two three!
Ah!
- Hey, Bruno.
- Hi.
Holy shit!
You scared me.
Are you hurt?
No, it works, let's go.
In Grana there were 183 people.
Oh! And now?
- 14, including me.
- Hmm.
There were two shops, a bar,
the school, the bakery...
At a certain point,
they built the road.
You know, to get people to Grana.
- But do you know what happened?
- What?
They've all gone away.
Ah, so your father too?
Yeah, away. Even yours?
Yes, he's at home in Turin,
he's working.
Meanwhile I'm here with my mother,
because we rented the house
for the whole summer.
What does he do?
So, he's an engineer
in a huge factory,
where, he thinks, 10,000 people work.
- Damn it?
- Eh!
-  Bruno!
- 10,000.
Where are you?
Shit, my aunt! It's time to milk.
Ah!
According to my father,
for every season of lightness
there follows one of gravity,
work time,
of the plain and the black mood.
Shit! But what the fuck are you doing?
Go...
Wait!
Go! Go now! Go!
Meanwhile
my legs turned pale,
the scrapes and scabs healed
and they forgot the itch of the nettles.
The days of Grana
seemed so far away,
I wondered if they really existed.
- Ah, I see you!
- Argh!
Argh!
Argh
I'm glad you're back, Berto.
- What did you call me?
- Berto.
Means "rock" in my language,
like "Pietro".
- When you're here, I'll call you that.
- Oh.
"Berto".
Come on, can you teach me your dialect?
All right, what do you want to know?
Um...
- Trees.
- Okay.
Like that one there.
That there is an "Iares"
and it has soft needles.
Bruno!
-  Bruno!
-  Fuck off!
Bye.
- I didn't hear anyone.
- Oh! Really?
Argh!
Hi Dad!
These lines are called
"level curves".
Hmm.
The closer they are, the steeper the slope.
Okay.
The numbers, on the other hand,
are the altitude.
- It's here...
- Like this, this, this...
Exact.
This is where I want to get to tomorrow.
- "3010".
- Hmm.
Madonna!
Can I come too?
Are you serious?
- Tell me you know what are you agreeing to?
- Yes.
Are you sure?
There's no going back.
Here they are.
Matterhorn, Grand Tournalin, Breithorn
and that is the Lyskamm.
The crest they call it
"Man eater". Did you know that?
No.
Huh.
Don't you miss that crappy city?
No!
Let's go?
Come on, dad, we just got here!
Okay.
How is your friend?
Well, I believe.
He went to the pastures
with his uncle to help him,
so I never saw him again.
It takes an hour on foot to get there.
An hour isn't that much, is it?
We can go together if you want.
What do you say?
All right.
Done.
Okay.
- Let's go!
- Wait!
- Come on, boy, go! Go!
- Wait, wait!
Excuse me for continuing to insist.
I think I understand
he didn't go so well,
so, he must repeat the year?
I don't know.
Well, if he failed ...
Bruno is smart. It would be a pity,
if he stopped studying, right?
Oh.
He needs someone
to help him study
so definitely passes.
Yes, you should talk
to my husband about it.
- Hello, Pietro!
- Hello, Bruno!
Hi, you must be Bruno.
Pietro told me a lot about you.
- Good morning.
- Hi.
- Is that your uncle?
- Yes.
Come, I'll show you something.
- Let's take the black and white one over there.
- All right, let's try.
Heh! Heh!
Do you like it?
Yes.
I'm learning to be a cheese maker.
What does it mean?
- The one who makes the cheese.
- Did you make these yourself?
No, my uncle. I turn them round
and keep them in order.
- It's too little.
- Eh.
There are absurd rules, we
get by, but it's mostly hard work.
The mountains,
what are their names?
- Grenon.
- Which one is Grenon?
The lot. We don't name the peaks here.
The glacier then?
Has he ever gone there?
No, never had the time.
In the next few days
I want to go there with my boy.
If it's okay with you, we could take you
too, Bruno. What do you think?
All right.
Pass the wine.
- Pietro, do you know that once I touched...
- Shh!
We'll talk later.
Now we don't talk,
we talk when we stop.
Okay.
Isn't that wonderful?
Yes.
The glacier fascinated the man
of science that was my father.
It reminded him of
his studies in chemistry and physics,
the mythology on which it was formed.
He told us that the glacier is
the memory of past winters
that the mountain holds onto for us.
Above a certain height
it retains the memory
and if we want to know
of a distant winter,
that's where we must go.
The water you are drinking
it's not last year's snow.
That will be water from 100 years ago.
- 100 years?
- Maybe even 150.
It's hard to know.
The beautiful thing about the glacier, then,
is that it never stands still.
In your opinion, why?
Why does everything go down?
Good boy.
You're smart.
Because everything goes down.
- What a beautiful day, huh?
- Hmm.
Your father knows a thing or two!
Yes.
It's nice that he teaches you too.
Why, doesn't your father?
Eh... My father is always away.
When I see him, he speaks very little.
It seems like I bother him.
Are you OK?
Yes.
- Do you want a glass of water?
- No, no, no.
- Shall I call your father?
Now I'll try to sleep, OK?
- Good night.
Where are you going?
On the glacier?
Yes.
Nothing in particular,
let's go for a ride.
Please,
be careful with these children.
Go.
Oh! What happened?
Nothing.
Let's not stop, let's go.
Rhythm!
Oh!
You jump first,
Bruno, go!
Take a deep breath and jump.
Ready?
Watch out for the ice axe.
One, two... Go!
Good boy. Come.
Good boy! My God...
Incredible! Give me five.
Good boy.
Go, Pietro!
It's your turn now.
- Oh!
- Everything OK?
What happened?
- Nothing, nothing.
- Everything OK?
-  Did you slip?
- Yes.
- Nothing, nothing.
-  Go.
Jump!
Dad, I can't do it.
Yes, you can do it, come on!
We can't go back, forward.
You just want to, come on.
Bruno did it, come on.
- Come on, Pietro!
- Oh!
Pietro! Pietro!
Come on, hey. Everything OK?
- Sorry, dad, sorry.
- Shh. No need to be sorry.
It's just a bit of altitude sickness.
It's nothing.
Shh, look at me.
It's a little altitude sickness, okay?
It's nothing, get up.
Breathe, take small breaths.
All right?
- Bruno, can you jump?
- Yes.
Take your ice axe and watch the ropes,
which are intertwined.
Good boy! Good boy.
- Are you good?
- Yes.
All right.
Now get up.
You'll lead the rope, okay?
- Are you leading it, okay?
- Okay.
Don't worry, it's nothing, now it's over.
The lower we go down
the more it passes.
Bravo, you are a champion! Go.
The next day
my father returned to Turin,
but the memory of that morning
would remain with me forever.
Together on the glacier,
just the three of us,
like it would never happen again.
Hello!
Come, come! Sonia?
No thanks, I'll leave you.
"I don't know
how long our sleep lasted,"
"but it was undoubtedly lo... long."
"Long, because..."
"Because it refreshed us..."
- "Refreshed..."
- "Completely."
"I woke up first and carefully exami..."
"Examined..."
- "I carefully examined our cell."
- "Cell."
Pause.
"The waiter..."
"The waiter,
taking advantage of our rest,"
"he had cleared the table, but..."
Hey!
Do you still have a lot more to do?
Go outside, I'll be right there. Go!
Come on.
Your parents have spoken
with my uncle, did you know?
No.
- Strange, I don't understand anything anyway.
- About what?
The secrets you keep between you.
What did they talk to your uncle about?
That after the summer you'll take me
with you to Turin to go "liscio".
- High school?
- Yes.
They made me pick a school,
and I'll live with you.
And your uncle what did he say?
- He's fine with it. Do you know why?
- Why?
For the money,
he cares only about who pays.
They said they'll take care of
food, lodging, and school.
- What?
Would you like that? Would you?
I don't know.
I've never been to Turin,
I can't even imagine it.
You know, it's different.
You stay inside all the time,
because everything is a danger,
you can't go out.
And you? Would you like it?
Pietro, it's for Bruno's good,
it is for his future.
What's the problem if he grazes cows
and makes cheese?
- None.
- Here you are.
But he has the right to study, then
decide whether to go back to his cows.
You want to bring Bruno
to that shitty city we hate?
We don't hate the city, Pietro.
- Turin will ruin someone like Bruno!
- It's not true.
I don't understand you.
It can be a beautiful thing
for him and for you.
This was your idea, not mine,
but he's my friend, not yours!
Well, that's a bit selfish...
- Fuck you!
- Oh! Don't you dare!
Don't be vulgar, it's not like us!
Damn it!
What is this lake called?
- Grenon.
- Oh.
But maybe you should tell him.
What?
That you don't want to go to Turin,
that you want to stay here.
No?
You're crazy?
I've been going up and down
this mountain all my life.
Oh!
It's me, Guglielmina Bruno,
and I'm leaving!
Understood?
Yes?
- Good morning.
- Sonia!
- I hope I'm not disturbing you.
- No, come on, have a seat.
Can I make you a coffee?
No thanks, I just wanted
to leave you these.
So many eggs!
How nice, you didn't have to!
- Where are you going?
- To Bruno.
Bruno’s gone.
Where?
His father took him away,
to work with him.
He didn't want him to go to Turin.
Bruno will be away all summer.
I'm sorry.
Pietro!
My parents' urgency
to help Bruno, to educate him
had separated us.
While I was bored in the summer,
he worked with his father
on construction sites.
His adult life
started when he was 13.
Mine, who knows.
I don't think he knew
what adolescence was.
- Hello.
- Hi.
- Been waiting long?
- No.
-  Hello!
-  Hello.
- Can I ask you for a cigarette?
- Yes, certainly.
- Thank you. And do you have to light?
- Yes.
- Yes, they 're here...
-  Hello! Hi, Paul!
Hello, Alessandro, are you alright?
How is it going?
He nodded his head.
I raised my hand
and then nothing else.
-  I'll pay.
-  Bravo, bravo!
I didn't ask him how he was,
how much he earned,
if he had a girlfriend,
what he wanted from the future,
what he thought
of what had happened.
He didn't ask me how I was,
how my family were
and I didn't answer:
"My mother's well, my father I’ve no idea."
Oh, fuck.
There’s also those to bring in.
- Lunch...
- Holy shit, come on.
- Don't worry. These tie on the outside.
- Yes.
- Come, try it, this is yours. Come on.
- Yes, wait.
Here. Come on.
It's heavy.
- Will you be okay?
- Of course he will.
- Hop!
- I can't do it.
Yes, you can!
- No, sorry, it's too much.
- Put it... Let's empty it a bit.
- No, it's not necessary.
- All right, don't worry.
Wait.
Now, let's do it again together, okay?
- That's no good.
- What's wrong with it?
- Nothing's right.
- Let's move things.
- What "nothing"? Come on!
- The tent, the lake, nothing's right.
Pietro, please!
What do you expect from me?
What, am I going fishing with dad?
Maybe we'll light a bonfire, uncork
a bottle and sing together, huh?
Pietro...
- It's stuff you do with friends.
- Come on, Pietro.
- You have no friends.
- Pietro, please!
So, you ask me to do these things?
- Come on, Pietro.
- I don't feel like it.
The following year I returned to
the mountains just for a few days,
after that I stopped
going there altogether.
Bruno and I would never see
each other again for 15 years.
Why can't I make my own choices?
Do you want to make
your own choices? Make one. Hm?
Do you want to do... doc...
- Documentaries.
- Documentaries? Hm?
Do you want to study American Literature?
What do you want to do?
Write? Travel around the world?
You've started your studies.
Finish them! Concentrate!
There will always be time to...
fucking dream!
Pietro, I beg you.
Don't throw your life away.
Listen to me.
- You're the one who wasted yours.
- Pietro!
Ri... Ri...
- Take back what you said.
- No.
Take it back.
I know one thing.
I won't become like you.
I swear.
- Hey, Pietro!
- Hey.
Are you coming with us to Mad Dog? Huh?
- Come on, when you get off, come.
- No, I wanted to wake up early tomorrow.
- Yes, okay, as usual.
- Yes, well. Bye, Pietro.
- Bye.
- We'll see each other later.
In this first half
Juventus showed little attention
in the opponent's half.
Enter the area...
- Cannavaro's advances...
- Ah...
Cannavaro finally
gets rid of the ball...
Yes.
- Mom, is there anyone there with you?
- Alessandra is here.
- Is there anyone there with you?
- Alessandra is here!
Yes?
- Okay, I'm coming home.
- I didn't hear.
- I'm coming home!
- All right.
Okay.
Hi, Bruno.
Hi, Pietro.
Condolences.
Thank you.
- Thanks for the fire.
- No, my pleasure.
Nice beard.
Yours is more beautiful, a real beard.
Come on, let's go, it takes a while.
Jump off.
- Here?
- We'll walk.
"We'll walk".
Go.
If you stop, it's worse.
Yeah?
This is the terrain.
Those are the old walls.
It's a ruin.
When your father saw it,
he immediately understood
that it was the right one.
Then I had to look for the owners
and get them to sell.
It's called Barma Drola.
- What?
- Barma Drola.
- What did he want to do with it?
- A house.
"A house"?
He wanted to build a house here.
He asked me to build it.
I inherited a pile of rocks.
I'm free this summer.
- For what?
- To build it.
No. Thanks, no need.
I promised him.
It was right there
where are you now,
when he made me promise.
Even if he's gone,
for me it doesn't change anything.
And with what money?
- It's just buying the material.
- Who'll pay you?
Don't worry about me.
The only thing I need
is the labourer.
No.
So, we finish
in three or four months.
I'm clumsy.
I'm sorry.
I'll teach you.
Four months?
Well then let's get started
after winter,
after the snow's melted.
Thank you.
My father died
when he was 62 and I was 31,
the age he was when I was born.
But I wasn't married,
I hadn't had a child,
I didn't even have a steady job.
My life seemed to me
half that of a man
and half that of a boy.
What was my father's wish?
He, who never succeeded
in stopping work
and that hardly a summer day
passed in the mountains.
What was I to do
with his lost dream
and with a promise that wasn't mine?
I must be the red marker,
because he's always been the black one.
This is when we went
on the glacier with Bruno,
so Bruno must be
the green marker.
No?
They often went to the mountains.
Up?
Yes.
Bruno was very close to us
in these years.
Yes?
And dad helped him a lot.
How so?
Hmm, with everything.
At some point,
Bruno had a fight with his father
and when he needed advice,
he came to us.
He trusted what dad said.
Okay.
That's what happens to those who leave.
What?
The others continue
to live without him.
Bruno always asked for news of you.
He asked?
Yes, and I told him
everything I knew about you.
It wasn't much,
but I told him.
On three, push.
- Are you tearing down the wall?
- With your feet, come on.
One, two, three.
Go, go! Go!
It will take a week
to clear it.
It's possible, yes.
Oh shit.
Are you saying we can do it?
It's hard to know.
This here is a strange plant.
It's strong when it grows where it was born,
but it's weak if
you put it somewhere else.
- Have you already tried it?
- Yeah.
- How did it go?
- Bad.
- Shall we leave this stuff here?
- No.
I'll stay with it too.
You want to sleep up here?
I can't lose
four hours of work travelling each day.
The bricklayer is
on the construction site,
that's how it's done.
So, I go up and down
and you stay here for four months?
That's what it takes.
Then on Saturday I go down
and I sleep in my bed.
I'll wait for you at 9 in the morning.
At six you are free.
Is that okay with you?
Yes.
Well.
Then bye.
Bye.
Shh, calm down.
Shall we put it on?
Okay, later. We'll do it later.
Hey, hey...
Hey! Hey!
Hey! Hey! Hey!
You don't have to think too much in this job,
otherwise, you'd go crazy.
Look, what a beautiful day.
What's it like when it's bad?
Berto?
Let's go!
Absurd... I remember it much bigger.
- Here.
- Hmm.
In the last ten years
I never spoke to my father.
I know.
Did he talk to you about me?
No.
And your father?
Is he still there?
He didn't leave me alone.
I finally had to give him one.
I must have hurt him,
because I haven't seen him since.
I'm sorry.
Old drunk.
I imagined the evenings there among them
when Bruno was 20, 25 years old
and he was there talking
with my father instead of me.
Maybe it wouldn't have happened
if I had stayed,
or maybe we would share those moments.
I felt like I lost
the most important things,
while I was busy with others,
so trivial that I don't even remember them.
concrete, stones, concrete, concrete,
stone so to speak.
Ti, ta, pum, concrete, the house.
- "The House".
- Broadly speaking.
A great master build.
All thanks to Bruno.
Seriously, he's very good.
I'm just the handyman.
Starting tomorrow I'm moving up too.
- Oh.
- Yes.
He would have been happy
to see what you're doing, you know?
Yes?
Thank you.
Hey, hey.
Let's go.
Roy!
Ah...
Easy, Roy! Where the fuck are you running?
Bruno, come here!
Let's go.
- Ah!
- Go on, go on.
Ah!
Wait.
- Go.
- Ah.
Go on.
Wonderful.
How do you get to the top of Grenon?
It's easy, there's a path.
You arrive at the stony ground,
continue straight on and get to the top.
You can't go wrong.
Ok, I'll try it on Sunday.
- Go now.
- No, not now.
- Go now!
-  No, not now.
- Today I'll manage here.
- No.
Don't worry,
take the day.
- No, no.
- Go now, I told you! Go!
Bruno!
Pietro!
No?
- Yes.
- Yes?
We finished?
"Finished" is a big word.
There's the roof.
Let's go down.
Come here.
Bomb.
Oh, damn...
What are you doing?
Nothing.
I'll wait.
Too bad the summer is over.
But you'll come back, right?
Of course, I'll come back,
it's our home.
- What are you laughing at?
- It's your house.
No.
This is home to us both.
- You're crazy.
- Look, I'm not kidding.
This is our summer house.
We'll see each other here every year.
Alright.
"Alright".
We're finished here, what are your plans?
I'd like to restore my uncle's pasture.
- Lovely.
- Hmm.
Get some cows, like this,
they don't cost anything anymore.
Do they make anything, at least?
If it was just for the money,
I'd continue laying bricks.
I wasn't born for this.
What was it you were born for?
To be a mountaineer.
All my ancestors lived
on the mountains with the beasts.
My father was the first who quit
and he took me away too.
He would have electrocuted
the cows with the current.
My uncle screwed up too.
It's a nice project, really.
Really.
- And you?
- Hmm?
- Plans?
- Me?
Nope, I guess I don't know.
What have you done these years?
I've done a lot of work,
But... actually nothing.
Your mother told me that you write,
that you tried to write a book.
No, it's not for me.
I'm not good enough.
Me, if I like something,
I do it, or at least try to.
What projects do I have?
That was the question..
Look,
a nice bonfire,
the fish,
a few mountains here and there
and you.
Stop this.
Don't move.
Stop.
Thank you.
Here you are.
I think I could stay like this forever.
I'm going nowhere.
Hello, Pietro.
- Fili, do you want a coffee?
- What?
- A coffee, do you want one?
- It's here.
Yes, thank you.
Go on.
Go! Let's get it out there.
- Where are you going? Who's that? Go.
- Come on!
This!
# And now
we complain so much
# Our spirits are in the clouds
# And they make it rain #
- They're coming next week.
- Who?
-  Friends from Turin.
- Ah okay.
When they get here,
I'll go down to the pasture.
No.
Yes, I'll sleep on the construction site
and work a little.
There is space.
Okay.
- It's a smash.
- After work.
I'll do it. Of course?
- Go.
- Why not?
- Oh!
- This is where we eat, outside.
-  You're welcome.
-  May I?
- Voila, here we are.
- Wow!
- It's gorgeous.
- Huh?
- Nice, huh?
- Holy shit.
- I mean, but what is it?
- A picture.
Look out.
- No!
- Eh?
- Huh?
- It's beautiful.
This is Bruno's brilliant invention,
not the light bulb
but a mill
which he built down by the creek.
We have enough electricity for you.
- For you.
- For that.
- All right.
- It's enough.
But guys...
Sir?
So, you conquered it?
Yes.
- I'm making a mess.
- I'll do it.
- I told you the trick.
- Thank you.
- Eh!
- Bruno! Bruno!
- Hey.
- Come, come.
- This is Massimo.
- Hi.
- Barbara.
- Pleasure.
- And Lara, from Turin.
- Hello.
Wow, Bruno, I have to tell you,
this place is beautiful.
- I would never leave.
- Sure, come back in November, then we'll see.
I miss the mountains.
- Do you come from the mountains too?
- Yes.
My love, we should buy
a place like this, a ruin.
We'll renovate it.
- We'll make it more beautiful than yours.
- Yes, fine.
- Enough, we're done with Turin.
- Yes.
We'll invite all
our friends from Turin to come.
We'll make ourselves a nice ecological village
here in the middle of nature.
Nice huh?
Nice.
It's just you from the city
who call it "nature".
It's so abstract in your mind
that even the name is abstract.
I get it, what do you call it?
Here we say...
woods, pastures,
river, rock, path.
Things you can point too with your finger,
things you can use.
Wait, you want to tell me
that one can't simply enjoy
the beauty of nature?
Yes, of course, and eat air.
Shot that one down.
We create good land,
we garden...
- Hmm.
- Nice.
Then in winter what do you plan to do?
Look, there are meters of snow here.
Then what do you eat?
polenta and potatoes like the old folk?
All right, I won't call it "nature" anymore,
but you'll let me dream?
- You'll let me dream? I beg you!
- Let him dream.
Please, can you let me dream?
What was it?
He doesn't kiss.
Shit, it's freezing!
- Yep.
- Oh God.
- Are you coming?
- No.
- Come on!
- No, go.
- Go, go, go!
- Oh...
- If you want, I'll count.
- I'm going, eh.
- I'm going.
Look at me.
One!
Two.
Three
Oh!
Wow!
Hey
In the winter I work two jobs
and the summer I try
to stay ahead as much as possible.
Then there's the mortgage, the bank...
I don't sleep much,
but it's worth it.
I'll make cheese like it used to be.
Now it's a little more difficult
with the new rules.
- When would you like to start?
- With the inarpa.
- Heh?
- In June.
When you go up to the mountain pasture.
- We'll see.
- Hmm.
- Here.
- Hold the dishes.
- Table two.
- Give me the plates, come on.
Go.
OK, perfect.
- Did you finish?
- Yes, I'll continue.
Hurry up please
we're in trouble.
- Ready?
- Hello, Pietro.
- I'm Bruno.
- Bruno!
- Yes.
- Everything OK?
- Sure.
Listen, listen,
I wanted to ask you something.
Come on!
Lara came.
- "Lara"?
- Yes, YES.
She wanted to see the pastures.
Move! Do you need to
be on the phone right now?
- A minute!
- There's a mess!
I was saying, she was interested in the pastures
and I took her up to see it.
- She told me that she’d like to work for us.
- Okay.
I like the idea, but is a woman
in the mountains a good idea?
She's one who knows how to do it,
and she has a hard head.
Seemed that way to me.
- What?
- It seemed that way to me, yes!
So?
What I don’t know
is how things are between you.
Oh! There's nothing between us.
Are you sure?
There's nothing between us,
we're just friends.
- Are you sure?
- Yes, absolutely.
- Ah.
- Yes. No, really.
Alright, see you.
- Huh?
- See you, bye.
She is very delicate.
Really?
First, you have to make her relax.
Ah, here we are.
What's up?
You said she needs to relax.
Hmm? Ah...
We have been lucky.
I think she likes you.
Yes, it's coming out well.
- Hi.
- Morning.
Oh.
I'll help you.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
Come on, go. Very, very good.
I'll act as a sideguard.
Go, go, go!
Let's go. Let's go.
- Go.
- Come on!
The calf's stomach?
Without that piece,
cheese would not exist.
Imagine who the fuck figured it out.
- The wild man.
- "The Wild Man"?
Part man, part animal and part tree,
like me.
- How do you say it in dialect?
- "Omo servadzo".
And the "servadza" woman?
She's fantastic.
She is strong, she never gets tired.
She also takes care of the accounts,
thank God. I hate that stuff.
She even brings down the books.
Even? Why don't you bring them?
No.
The mountaineer is in the mountains.
The mountaineer's woman goes up and down.
Sorry.
What?
I wish I could have
spent more time with you.
I never leave here.
Things change.
Hmm.
I'll wait for you outside.
For Bruno there were neither Saturdays
nor Sundays in the mountain pastures.
Even if it took a long time,
he persisted in milking the cows by hand.
There was a right way in his life
to do everything.
The summer that followed,
Lara was pregnant.
I saw her grazing the cows,
alone, in the wind,
with a round belly and thick ankles.
More and more a creature of the mountain.
The following year she went out to pasture
with a little girl in her arms.
Even if Bruno and Lara
always invited me to stop there,
something pushed me
to say hello to that family
and to take the path to the Barma.
Sometimes I wanted to talk
with my father.
"Did you see, dad?"
"One of your children
has found its way to him."
"The other one hasn't."
I was tired of that old me.
I wanted to transform, evolve, leave
for a new, brand-new Pietro.
Yes?
Thank you. Thank you.
- Hello, "namasté" to you.
- I sure hope the Wi-Fi works here.
Does the wi-fi work?
- Namaste.
Can you believe that yak on the road down there?
Yes.
I thought it was going to chase you,
I was scared for a second.
- Would you like something to drink?
- Yes.
What do you think she has...
Do you think she has a root beer?
"Sati".
- "Sati"?
-  Hmm.
- "Puri".
- "Purì"?
Huh.
- "Puri".
Oh.
You...
"Purò".
- "Pure".
- "Purò, purì".
"Purò, purì".
- "Purò".
- "Puri".
"Purò, purì". Okay.
Husband, wife.
No "puri".
- No "Puri"?
- No.
"Purò".
I was wondering what
Bruno would have thought of the houses,
how they built them
of their way of working the land,
in the hands of women,
of children's games
among the cattle.
Perhaps he would have thought the mountain
people of the world are all one.
He would have liked the Himalayas too.
Heh! Heh!
Heh! Heh! Heh!
- Eh!
- Oh! Oh!
- Hey!
- Oh!
It's Pietro!
Hey!
Hello, Anita!
Hm...
Yak butter has a stronger flavour.
Yes, but they use it
for everything,
for lamps,
as a hair ointment
and in sky burials.
There is not enough wood in Nepal
to cremate the corpses.
They skin them and leave them
on a plateau for the vultures.
They come back after a few days
and find only the bones,
which they crush
and knead with butter and flour,
which then becomes food for birds.
And so, the corpse disappears completely.
How horrible!
What an image, the sky burials!
Why "horrible"?
Can you imagine your mother skinned
and torn apart like a...
- It's not like they don't eat it buried underground.
- At least you don't see it.
I like it.
Bird feed and go, right?
- Anyone want another grappa?
- Me.
Not for me,
it's already going to my head.
That means it's good.
What are you doing?
Ah, shall we mix a little here?
Hmm.
- Oh!
- Let's give them some too.
Alright.
The women, Berto?
Around the world are they
as beautiful as those of the Alps?
Oh:
Heh!
Come on, we know they're after you,
now that you're famous.
"Famous"... A book they published for me.
- Don't torment him!
- I worry about my friend.
Yes? You worry?
Have you become a Buddhist monk?
Look at me, oh!
- That?
- No.
- No?
- No!
- Uh!
- Hmm.
- Do you want to hear some bullshit?
- Yes, yes.
Does this bother you?
- When I was in Nepal...
- Hmm.
Someone stopped me and then...
Someone stopped me.
He told me: "Are you doing
the tour of the eight mountains?"
And then he did this, look.
And he begins to draw.
Ah...
He tells me ...
He tells me:
"This is the world for us."
"There are eight mountains and eight seas"
This in the middle..."
Do you see this?
It looks like an asshole, but this...
This is the world for us
and at the centre is this...
There's this big mountain,
Mount Sumeru.
The question is this, listen to me.
The question is this:
"Who learned the most,"
"who has seen the eight mountains
and the eight seas"
"or whoever made it to the top
of Mount Sumeru?"
Answer.
I am the one
who is on the mountain
and you're the one
who made the rounds...
- Of the eight...
- Very good, good.
- Who wins?
I win.
Always.
Put a little grappa, the last one,
goodnight grappa.
I'll sleep here, Bruno.
Good night.
Espresso.
- Hi.
- Hey, hi.
- How are you?
- Well.
- Can I take this?
- Yes.
An espresso, "krpaya".
Cold if possible.
Yes.
"Krpaya" is not a word
that we use every day.
- No?
- No.
It's a bit outdated.
- We say "please".
- As in English.
- Yes.
- "Please".
- How do you say it in your language?
- In mine?
"Per favore".
How, sorry?
- "Per favore".
- Per fava...
- No, "per favore".
- "per flavour".
Ah...
One...
- Ready?
- Yes.
Smile!
Hmm.
Berto?
Hey!
Do you want me to pass them to you?
Yes, I'll do it first.
- You know what we say here when we're sad?
- What?
- "I'm elsewhere."
- "I'm elsewhere?"
"How are you?"
"I'm elsewhere." That's it.
It's when I started
to read that I understood
how many ways there are
to say things.
If not... poor words, poor thoughts.
Beautiful.
I'm happy that you have found
your words, Berto.
Yes, it's absurd.
There is a publisher who believes in you
and poof, he changes everything.
I won't get rich, but I can stay
quiet in Nepal for a while.
Do you like it there?
Yes.
What?
I met someone.
- Oh!
- Yes.
- I knew it.
- Did you know that?
Her name is Asmi.
She does the same job as my mother, more or less.
The other day I was
thinking that it's absurd
how one finds
one's place in the world
in the least unpredictable ways
than one imagines.
Nice.
I'm happy for you.
I don't know if I will come back next year.
It's time to milk.
- Come to dinner one of these days.
- Yes.
"Here with my 11-year-old son Pietro."
"This will be my last as lead climber,
because in a while he'll pull me up."
"I will always carry the memory of
these days as the most beautiful refuge."
"Giovanni Guasti, August 1984."
"Went up from Grana
in two hours and 37 minutes. Great run."
"Sighted six ibexes and an eagle."
"Today I'm 21 again,
like my companion here."
"John Gusti
and Bruno Guglielmina, July 1994."
Then I found what must
be the last message from him.
"It would be nice to stay
up here forever,"
"without seeing anyone, without having to go
down to the valley again."
Here is the sentiment that had made him
dream of a home away from the world.
Only now did I understand, I had two fathers.
The first was the stranger
with whom I had lived 20 years in the city.
The second was the mountain father,
whom I had only glimpsed,
yet known better.
This other father had left me
a ruin to rebuild,
but maybe he didn't know
it would be another's greatest gift.
Maybe we could rent rooms, right?
Farmhouses work well.
We quit selling to the cooperative.
We sell directly to customers,
which is quite a difference.
- It takes longer.
- Certainly.
Luckily Francesca is here.
I use her car and she also does me
the pleasure of looking after Anita.
Without her I don't know
what we would do, huh?
- Hmm.
- Don't you agree?
Yes.
Now we have to make
some more effort.
We can't keep up with the payments,
because they give us contributions,
but they are not enough.
At the bank, they always
blame the crisis.
One jerk told me
that it was better if I asked for 20 million
on loan instead of 20,000 euros.
You understand?
We’re of no use to them.
We'll sort it in the summer.
We are at our limit,
but we'll make it in that period,
we are self-sufficient,
but winter in Grana
it's a whole other story.
We have stable rent
and all other expenses.
How do we do it?
We won't die of hunger,
we have a lot of cheese.
God! There it is. When he doesn't know
what to do, he makes jokes.
- Come on, Lara... - What "come on"?
Do you hear me when I speak?
We have terrible debts,
open your eyes to reality!
- Shall we discuss it now?
- God...
- We never see Pietro.
- So, what are we going to talk about?
- You decide.
- Yes, go...
This one lives on top of the mountains,
but he’s unfamiliar with the problems
of us mere mortals.
- You got yourself into this mess!
- Indeed.
- Huh.
- So don't go crazy over it.
Hm?
- I'm going.
- Stay, I'll go.
Love. Love.
Shh.
She's right,
but it's not like talking will fix it.
How much do you need?
Too much.
Way too much.
I'll help you.
I don't have much money
but I can stay here to work. Huh?
I've decided, let's do this.
You already have a lot to consider.
- Like what?
- Your girlfriend.
- Don't worry, I'm glad...
- No!
Even if sometimes I would have
liked to talk to him when we were apart,
Bruno and I felt very little,
as if our friendship
didn't need any help.
Namaste.
- Namaste.
A computer?
uh!
Thank you.
It was my mother
gave us news of each other.
She was used to living
among silent men.
They took away my pasture,
you know that?
- Pietro? Pietro?
- Yes, yes!
Bad news.
Yes.
How is Lara?
And Anita?
Anita is with Lara at her family,
they have a place there.
They're fine.
Look, I wanted to ask you
if I can stay at the Barma.
Do you want to go up alone?
Yes, I don't want to see people.
It's winter.
For now, I'm not sure where...
I want to stay in the mountains for a while.
And it's your house, you know.
Thank you.
- Bruno?
- Yeah?
Do you want me to come there?
Eh, yes, that would be nice.
Then I'll be there as soon as possible.
"Diaul porcu"!
Shithouse chainsaw!
Bruno.
Hey.
- Hello, Berto.
- Hello.
Let me finish this.
Do you need help?
There's plenty to eat.
- These?
- For the snow.
Turn off the light.
Go.
Okay, I'll prepare it.
Maybe tomorrow
we can go to the lake.
It was beautiful, huh?
It was beautiful, yes.
When I woke up early in the
morning to milk
and they slept,
it was my favourite time of day.
I was under the impression
everything was under control,
I was taking care of them.
Stupid, huh?
It's not stupid.
It's stupid because it's impossible
really, caring about someone else.
When are you going
to visit Anita? At Christmas?
No, not at Christmas.
Then when?
Maybe in the spring.
Maybe in the summer.
What's the difference?
It's all the better
if she stays with her mother.
- You are a good father, Bruno.
- Hmm.
What should I do, bring her here?
See, there's a world out there.
You invented this border yourself.
- Yes?
- Yes, in your head.
Find yourself a normal job,
at least for the winter.
Berto, do you remember whose son I am?
- Yes.
- Hmm.
Your father, the asshole.
And now what are you doing?
Abandoning your daughter,
like he did with you.
Go away.
What?
What are you doing?
On the Alpine reliefs
heavy snow is expected,
over 1000 meters.
Decreasing temperatures.
- Hi!
- Hey there.
She's already in kindergarten.
At first, I can't tell you what a struggle it was
to make them follow the rules!
But she's getting a little better now.
I would like to help him.
You can't help someone who does
not want to be helped.
We could have found other solutions,
you know, other jobs.
They were looking for people here
at the chair lift.  Nothing.
For Bruno there is no other possible life.
At some point, I realized that Anita and I
we were much less important
than his mountain,
whatever that means.
Sometimes love wears out slowly,
other times it dies suddenly.
No?
You're asking me?
How is it in Nepal?
Good, right?
I went too far,
I should have stayed here.
No.
Berto!
Heh!
Hey!
Ah!
Shit... Hey!
Hey.
Oh!
What the fuck are you doing?
Are you okay?
Not bad, huh?
I've been training for a week.
You're an idiot. Yes.
Wow.
Ah... Fuck you.
- It doesn't fit anymore.
- Here.
Bubbles, bubbles, bubbles!
I'm sorry about last time.
Me too.
I'm glad you're back.
We're still friends, aren't we?
Fuck you.
I was angry.
I was angry, because it's no-one's fault,
but mine.
What did I want to be,
the entrepreneur?
I had to build myself a cabin like this
and bring up two cows.
This was supposed to be my life.
I don't know anything about money.
At some point in life, one has to
stop and ask oneself questions, right?
Say to yourself, "Well, this I can do,
This no."
I am capable
of living alone in the mountains.
- It's no small thing, is it?
- It's not, no.
Berto, don't worry about me.
This mountain has never hurt me.
- They called me from Grana.
- Yes?
It snowed a lot.
Bruno's cousins were worried.
They called for help and
a team went up with a helicopter.
At that point, they expected
to find him in his bed.
Maybe with an illness, right?
You know, the cold...
But he wasn't there.
They also scoured the surrounding area
with dogs, but they found nothing.
Imagine, with all that snow...
In short, they have decided
that it makes no sense to keep looking.
Okay.
They say they'll find him
when the snow melts.
In your opinion, was that what he wanted?
No.
I said no, but I was lying.
I wondered who had known him
besides me on Earth,
and who had known me besides Bruno.
If it was only ours
what we had shared,
what was left of it
now that one of us was gone?
Then it occurred to me,
that there was a house up in the mountains
with a hole in the roof.
That wouldn't give her long to live
and I felt she was no longer of any use,
because in some lives there are mountains
to which it is not possible to return.
- Come on, let's go!
- Okay, okay!
One cannot go back to the mountain
which is at the centre of all the others,
as well as at the beginning of its own history.
Go!
All that remains is to wander
the eight mountains,
for someone like me,
on the first and highest,
I lost a friend.