Bolsonaro will be the 38th president
of Brazil.
PSL’s candidate won 55 percent
of the vote in the election
against Fernando Haddad
of the Workers' Party.
The Workers’ Party's first presidential
defeat since 2002.
We're going live
to Barra da Tijuca in Rio de Janeiro.
Nina, wake up,
you’re gonna be late.
Time to get up, come on.
-Good morning.
-Good morning, Wellington.
-Hey, Moisés. You good?
-Yeah. You?
-Good morning.
-This is Flávio.
-Wellington, right?
-Yeah. Nice to meet you.
-You too.
-He'll replace Doriva.
-Right. Welcome.
-Thank you. Appreciate it.
-Stick with him. He's the oldest in here.
-For sure.
-Do as he says.
I could tell he's an OG.
-Like a griot.
-I'm heading out.
-Count on me. Get some rest.
-Thanks. Have a good day.
-See you tomorrow.
-See ya.
There is a divergence here.
CNJ says the prison population
declined to 602,000,
but Brazil still has
the world's third-highest
prison population.
And now we have to pay
special attention to this.
The platform that won the election
supports the US political view.
And how does the US
handle their prison population?
By privatizing their prisons.
Tércia!
-What?
-Come here.
-What is it?
-Hurry.
-God. Wait, wait.
-Come on.
-What is it?
Tokinho!
That's amazing.
I'm friends with a celebrity!
-I was so straight.
-Yeah, right.
-Your hair was different.
-Too much beauty.
-Look!
-Check it!
My God! Tokinho!
My jaw just dropped!
Magma is the molten material found
beneath the surface of Earth. Right?
Well…
This magma is between the mantle
and the crust.
It stays there for years.
Here we have heat, pressure
and intense gas formation.
When the pressure is too much,
this is what happens.
Volcanic eruption.
Leaking lava,
pieces of rock, gases, ashes.
Cool, right?
-No, Mom. I already have it.
-Son, you gonna eat the beet today.
Mom, no.
You better eat, Deivinho.
-Remember what we have on Saturday.
-Uh-huh.
You coming to see him play on Saturday?
-No, baby. I get too nervous.
-Don't be silly.
And I can't, I gotta work.
Cleaning at Dona Bia.
-On Saturday?
-She'll throw a party on Friday,
and asked me to go on Friday
and on Saturday. I thought it was great.
-I’ll get paid for both days.
-That's good.
-Wash this right, girl. Harder.
-Here, I'm washing it.
You don't know how to wash a bowl,
to scour a pan.
You know what your grandma
used to do to me?
She'd tell me to wash
all the pans and the cans.
I couldn't use steel wool, honey.
I had to use sand.
Mom, that's awful.
-You know when I could stop?
-When?
When she could see
her face in the pan lid.
-Jeez.
-My nails were short as hell.
-Mom?
-Huh?
You could tell Deivinho to do more stuff.
-What do you mean?
-Stuff around the house.
-Don't be easy on him.
-Right.
He'll grow to be just like dad.
Dad doesn't wash a bowl, doesn't cook.
I enjoy doing it.
I like to take care of you guys.
Mom, Deivinho needs to learn
how to do these things too.
It's important.
Now you wanna tell me
what to do, Eunice?
Okay, then. It's up to you.
Yeah, but they're taller than him.
Go, Colo-Colo!
Come on, Deivinho.
Come on. Come on. Go. That's it.
Dribble him! That's it!
Go, boy! Go!
Goal!
I told you he was good.
Deivinho, dad loves you! Dad loves you!
-Fuck, I'm sorry. I'm sorry, guys.
-It's all good.
People are pushing and shoving.
-Don't worry.
-Come, I'll get you another one.
No need. I was almost finished it.
Thanks.
I see you, girl.
Go for it.
It's the orchid I told you about.
Each one is a different kind.
This one has its roots out
so it takes nutrients from the air.
You can help it too.
You mix a cup of eggshell,
a cup of raw rice and a cup
of used coffee powder, with no sugar.
You put it in a blender
and then in a plastic bottle,
with two liters of water.
Cover and leave it for three days.
After that, you water it
just a little bit.
Don't use the powder, just the liquid.
Just the liquid.
Man, the plants love it.
You know a lot about plants,
Mr. Wellington.
In general, you throw the seed,
you fertilize the soil, water it,
and if the sun goes out
the plants will like it.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I'll get some plants too.
What is this medal? What does it mean?
This is four years
with the Alcoholics Anonymous.
Really? You drank it a lot?
-Yeah, I used to get pretty wasted.
-Really, Mr. Wellington?
But now I'm sober.
Thank God, because alcohol,
if you can’t handle it…
It destroys us.
-Good morning.
-Are you Wellington?
-Yes, I am.
-Nice to meet you, Juan Pablo.
-Nice to meet you.
-You’re Sorín, right?
-Yes.
Sorín? Welcome, man.
-Nice hair.
-You like it?
-You moving in, right?
-Yes.
I can't believe you moving in here,
near us, man.
Cool, man.
-Moving again.
-Good.
-You taking care of the plants?
-Yeah, taking care of the orchids.
-You like orchids?
-I do.
Yes.
-Flowers are nice.
-Very beautiful.
-The view too.
-Yes.
I look at you and remember
that Cruzeiro game on Sul Minas.
That was amazing, man. Right?
-Ow! I was at the stadium.
-Were you at the Mineirão?
The crowd went crazy. Unforgettable.
-Forever in my heart.
-In ours too. We love it.
-It's wonderful.
-Very nice.
-You coming with your stuff, right?
-Yeah, the truck is here.
Let's open the gate for them.
Remember I taught you how to put the liner
on the freight elevator?
-Yes.
-You do that.
-To protect his furniture.
-I got it.
-Be careful with your back.
-Welcome, Sorín. Thanks.
When you have time,
I'd like to show you a video of my son.
-Sure.
-He's a star player.
-He plays soccer? In a team?
-He plays at Colo-Colo,
it's a nice youth team. I'd like
to show you a video on my phone.
Sure. I'll see you around
and you can show me.
-You got it. Welcome.
-See ya. Bye.
-Let me know if you need anything.
-Thanks. Bye.
Man!
Look at that.
Created in 2011 by the Dutch engineer,
Bas Lansdorp,
Mars One is a project that aims
to establish a permanent human
settlement on Mars by 2030.
The idea is that a manned mission
to Mars is possible nowadays,
as long as there's no return phase.
That is, to make one-way trips.
Critics don't know how
a 6-billion-dollar colonization mission
can be funded with sponsorship only.
Still, Mars One
has strong ambassadors like
Gerard't Hooft, 1999
Nobel Prize in Physics
and the friendly 13-year-old mascot,
Aisha Jordan.
You watching porn, Deivinho?
So, do you know what gift
we can get for mom?
Not really.
Dad gave us some money,
to buy clothes or something.
Again? We gave her clothes last year.
You’re right.
Just give me a suggestion.
I saw a Cruzeiro washing machine cover.
A washing machine cover
as a birthday gift, Deivinho?
Are you kidding me?
I won't give anything
for laundry or kitchen.
Let's do this, I'll choose the gift, okay?
Okay. I'll write her a letter then.
Deal.
Who are you texting?
A boyfriend?
Come here.
A girlfriend?
Kind of.
But don't tell mom and dad.
Do you think it's wrong?
Why would I think that?
TÉRCIA, WONDERFUL WIFE,
MOTHER AND FRIEND.
CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR DAY.
YOU'RE A GIFT IN OUR LIVES.
HAPPY BIRTHDAY.
Did you know that the sun
we're seeing now is the sun of the past?
But how come we're seeing it now?
It's like, it's not happening
now, you know?
-But why is it there?
-It's an image.
The sunlight takes
a long time to reach Earth.
So, we see the sun from eight minutes ago,
'cause it's too far.
That's awesome!
Don't pretend you got it, Thiago.
-Come on, you chicken.
-I dare you! No brakes!
-You chicken.
Damn. Things got ugly for me.
I just lost my job.
Brazil is not for amateurs.
It's fucked up, a whole mess.
It's fucked up, ma'am. No joke.
On top of that my wife cheated on me
with my best friend.
Cuckolded by my best friend.
Lost my job, don't know what's left.
Here's the deal.
I'm gonna kill myself.
I can't take it anymore.
No Christian can take this.
-Don't do this, sir.
-Would you take it? You wouldn't.
The country is in crisis.
You can find another job.
It's too humiliating.
Trust God. Jesus loves you.
He has a purpose for you.
-Yes, Jesus loves me.
-Don't give up on yourself.
That's why everybody
is going to see him with me.
-We're all going to meet Jesus.
-Sir, don't do this.
-Let us all hug Jesus now.
-This man is crazy.
Let us all go to heaven!
That's it, guys.
Ma'am, it was just a prank.
Don't worry. There's the camera.
-Thanks, Pablito. Congratulations.
-I'll get you some water.
Good, Pablito. You did it again.
-What's this petition thing?
-Petition is like a formal letter,
that you write to explain
everything that happened.
It has to be written
within the legal terms.
It needs to be well written
and at the end say that
if they don't respond you'll sent it
to the Consumer Protection Agency.
But he won't know
how to write that, me neither.
I'm not good with words,
to write this petition.
Tell him I'll go there,
we sit together and write it.
I'll tell him, he'll appreciate it.
That's great.
-We'll get it right.
-I'll call him later.
Baby, you okay?
Yes.
You're quiet.
Today, I…
I was at a diner in the city center today.
In… in the city center.
A man came in…
-and said he would kill himself.
-Jeez.
How crazy…
Mom, you okay?
Then he…
he…
-blew up a bomb.
-A bomb?
These bombs people take to stadiums?
*
-Dynamite.
-Dynamite?
What? It can't be, Mom.
Dynamite is heavy stuff, to blow up
buildings and things like that.
Are you hurt?
No, because in the end…
it was a prank, you know?
Like the ones on TV, right?
Lots of people.
Yes, a prank.
Yes. It was a mess.
Did you fall for it, is that it?
What channel will it be on?
No, It's not funny. Not funny.
I feel bad about it.
-What channel, Mom?
-Let's get together to watch it.
Guys, stop. It's not funny.
It's serious. I don't feel good.
Why, baby? Wasn't it a joke?
Do you wanna do something crazy?
Well, there's one here that seems
to be what you're looking for.
-Around here?
-Yes.
It's a penthouse
three blocks up the street.
So you only want to see
the penthouse, right?
Yes.
ID, please.
You're such a smart ass, girl.
I can't believe this.
So many words
Half-words
Our apartment
A piece of Saigon
You wrote goodbye
With your lipstick on the mirror
My star
Go on and shine your light
Over this whole city
Like the neon skies
Your brightness silences everything
Sometimes
You go around
Giving yourself
Dreaming so you won't fall asleep
And I often think about leaving you
But every time you come back
I forget all about myself
The night has come
I look up at the sky how great it is
To see the stars in the dark
I wait for you to come back
To Saigon
It must be dope to live
in a flat like this, right?
Yeah.
But I don't think one needs all this.
You're already used to it.
Big house, a lot of space.
I always lived in big houses,
but I think it's a lot for two people.
I've been wanting to leave
my parents house for a while.
Tell me about it.
Spitting freestyle
Check it out to get the vibe
Workin' in the sun
In the pool I cannot dive
But that's okay, in life
We ain't got the perks
And if we short on money
We gotta make it work
That's how it goes, we cannot get lost
Please, Mr. Wellington
Give it up to the boss
-Good afternoon.
-How are you?
-I'm all right.
Let's get straight to the point.
Check it out, Mr. Wellington.
Time to get paid.
-Sign here, please.
-Nice.
Wellington, I brought that flour
you liked it, from Tchó Tchó.
I loved that flour, that's good.
Thank you.
I wanna thank you for taking care
of Galvão and my flat.
No problem. And your sister?
Did she get better?
-She's getting better every day.
-Good.
That's important.
Sign here.
How great.
Look at him peeking.
Calm down, I'll give you yours.
-Here's your check, Wellington.
-Thank you, Dircinha.
-Thanks. Bye.
-Bye.
Let us know if you need anything.
Mr. Wellington, for real now,
have you seen how much
we make per month?
-This salary is a joke.
-Well, isn't it the deal?
Let me tell you something, Mr. Wellington.
Not every deal has to be accepted.
Imagine if every hardworking employee
who works
in a condo like this,
full of reactionaries,
decides to occupy the place,
how dope that would be. Think about it.
You're full of revolutionary ideas,
sounds like my daughter.
I mean it, Mr. Wellington. Think about it.
We work hard, we carry these people
on our backs our whole lives, man.
People like you and me,
we're exploited daily.
These folks have all this,
living in a mansion with a pool.
They don't use a third of it
and we livin' a rough life in the hood.
We work hard as fuck
and these dudes living in La-la land.
They make millions on our backs,
Mr. Wellington.
Let's think, let's mobilize
everyone here, Mr. Wellington.
Let's occupy, take it by storm,
what do you think?
I think you should
keep on cleaning the pool.
-It's full of dirt, look at it.
-Come on.
One day you'll understand it,
Mr. Wellington.
You're not ready yet, you don't get it.
This is way ahead of you.
You should go ahead
and clean the pool all the way.
You have to clean it down there too.
We have to dive in this pool,
Mr. Wellington.
One day I'll get here crazy
to dive in this pool.
If you could recommend me to someone,
so I wouldn't be that short on money.
Yeah,
don't worry, go travel.
I'll figure it out.
All right then. Have a nice trip.
Take a lot of pictures, record videos.
All right. Give Tokinho a hug.
Fine. Slay at the Champs Elysees.
Okay. You too. God bless.
I've always… sometimes I say…
I never liked…
It's not because I'm vain,
but I never liked for my kids
to ask others for anything.
Never let my kids be poorly dressed.
And I never had people saying
I raised my kids asking
for the help of others. No, thank God.
Today they're all graduated, not to brag.
Geraldo knows my family, my place.
I have a son who is a teacher,
he teaches three languages.
All my daughters graduated
from university.
AVOID THE FIRST SIP.
ATTEND THE MEETINGS.
None of my kids drink alcohol,
only beer once in a while.
I tell them,
The day you think
you need help, you know the way.
TIME TO TALK.
Every year they come with me…
TIME IS UP.
…to get my medal. I'll wrap it up.
Thanking once again the higher power.
Thanking the coordinators
and everyone's attention.
What I wish for myself,
I wish for you all,
Just 24 hours more.
Thank you, Comrade Judite.
It's time to talk.
Comrades. Good evening, everyone.
For those who don't know me,
my name is Marcelino,
another recovering alcoholic,
who joined this wonderful work
in which I proudly carry the number 2725.
Tércia? Tércia?
Help!
Hey, Mr. Daltoni, do you have
any kind of magnifying glass?
Deivinho, here we have all kinds of stuff,
I've stored a few pieces,
I can look at it and see
if I find what you need.
If not, we keep looking until we find.
I've found some PVC pipes,
I just need the lenses now.
The lenses? Well,
we can take a look around,
there's a lot of stuff in here,
you can find what you need.
So, can we count on you
to play in our team? At Milanez?
My dad takes care of this stuff.
I don't know much.
We waiting for you to play there.
Deivinho, did you know that, Thiago
is in love with your sister?
Don't listen to her. She's lying.
He's really into her.
Eunice,
Jô told me about the apartment,
if you decide to close the deal,
you can count on us, okay?
To have a guarantor and all that.
Okay? You can talk to me.
So, Dad, Nina is studying law.
How nice, it's what I studied.
Joana told me.
-At the Federal University, right?
-Yes.
That's really good.
We need to arrange for us
to meet her parents.
We'll do that.
By the way, can you believe
I haven't met her parents yet?
What? Am I lying?
All in good time, honey. Right, Eunice?
Look at him.
-Nice finishing.
-Yeah.
That's great.
-He's a star.
-Very cool.
Let me tell you.
I'm gonna pause here.
Usually, the trials happen
at the end of the year,
but if something comes up
earlier I'll let you know.
-Appreciate it, Sorín. Thank you.
-I'll let you know.
-See ya.
-Thanks.
-No problem.
-Let me see it.
-The boy is really good, Mr. Wellington.
-Right?
Besides the headache, Tércia,
what's bothering you?
So…
I had a headache for a day
but the insomnia is all the time.
Are you taking something
for the insomnia?
I'm drinking passion fruit tea,
but it's been a long time since
I have slept more than
four hours per night.
Right. Tell me, how are things at work?
Stressful?
No, I haven't worked that much.
-Have you had a fever recently?
-No.
It's insomnia and sometimes a malaise.
What kind? Stomach?
No, it's like, something inside,
like in my bones. Sometimes a chill.
And I've been a little scared too.
Got it. Come with me.
-Thanks.
-You can sit down.
I'm going to ask for some tests,
so, we can check what's going on
'cause it's not clear yet.
Also, I'll ask you to drink
water during the day
and avoid heavy meals at night.
-To have a salad, right?
-Yes, salad, juice, some vitamins.
And TV as well, TV shows
at night can get you agitated.
It's best to avoid it.
I won't prescribe you
any medication for now.
-Nothing?
-No, we'll wait for the tests.
You'll keep drinking the passion
fruit tea until then.
Be kind, give me a card.
-Take it. Take it.
-Look at the card you played, Nina.
-Pay attention, girl.
-Our team thanks you.
It's a gift for us.
Come on, give it to me.
Honey, the game isn't over.
-You lost.
-Dad, Mom.
There's no going back,
you've played your card.
I'm searching for an apartment.
What do you mean?
I thought I should tell you
before I decide anything.
Decide what, Nina?
But, Nina, are you thinking
about living by yourself?
No, Dad. I'll live with a friend
and we're gonna split the rent.
-But how's that gonna work?
-I don't know about that.
That will have a cost.
How much is that?
Well, Mom.
-800 reais at most.
-Too expensive, Nina.
-Dad, don't start.
-Don't start?
I said 800 reais at most.
I'm searching for cheaper places too.
That's not easy, Nina. Not easy.
And who is this friend, Nina?
-Where did you meet?
-It's Joana, Mom.
We met in college.
And how are you
gonna pay for this, Nina?
I'll keep on tutoring.
I'm also looking for other things to do.
And I'm almost getting an internship.
Nina, you should be patient, honey.
-Graduate first.
-I'm almost graduating, Dad.
Then do it first.
-Then you get a boyfriend.
-Nonsense, Dad.
-Then you get married.
-Who said I wanna get married?
You don't?
So, for me to leave I have to get married?
-Why are you leaving?
-I won't get married.
-You have everything here.
-I want my freedom.
More freedom than you already have?
-Dad, it's not like that.
-How come it isn't?
-I wanna leave, that's all.
-Leaving…
-you're just a child.
-A child, Dad?
-How would that work?
-You keep treating me as a child.
-Two girls living in an apartment.
-What's the problem?
-And what if something happens?
-What would happen? It's safe.
-Who would take care of you?
-I can take care of myself.
Enough! Enough! For God's sake.
You already screwed the game up.
What a fucked-up Tuesday.
Nina, you find a way
to bring this girl here.
-What for?
-What for, Nina?
Girl, you aren't uncared for.
You have a mother, a father, a brother.
You think you can come in here
and just tell us you're leaving?
It's important to bring her here,
-right, Deivinho?
-Yeah.
Right, Wellington?
I wanna know about the game,
whose turn is it?
Your turn.
Why didn't you tell me
you were gonna leave?
I wasn't sure yet, Deivinho.
I’m still not sure.
Are you gonna move too far?
Maybe.
Downtown or the East Side.
But we'll see each other
all the time, Deivinho.
I'll always be with you.
Seeing you play soccer, becoming a star.
Nina, do you think dad would be mad
if I didn't play soccer anymore?
Don't you wanna play?
I don't know if I wanna become
a professional player.
Then talk to dad, Deivinho.
He can't make you do
anything you don't want to.
It's not that I want to stop playing,
I just think about doing other stuff too.
Yeah? What stuff?
What is it?
You'll think it's stupid,
I can’t tell you.
Tell me, don't be silly.
My dream is to become an astrophysicist
and go on the Mars One mission.
Mars One? What mission is that?
It's a mission that will happen in 2030.
Humans will try to colonize Mars.
Wow, Deivinho.
I don't even know what to say.
Is that what you want?
To go to Mars?
I'm even building
a telescope to observe better.
A telescope?
-I knew you'd think it's stupid.
-No, Deivinho. I don't think that.
It's beautiful. A beautiful dream.
I laughed because I never
heard you talking like that.
You wanna go to Mars
and worry about me moving far away?
Don't forget about me, okay?
Never, Deivinho.
Hey, go get the ball, boy.
Come on, Deivinho,
You're just walking there.
Don't do that, son.
Go get it, Deivinho. Come on, boy.
The right wing was trying
to pass you the ball
and you didn't pay attention.
You lost the ball twice, Deivinho.
Man up. Come on.
Pay attention to the game.
What's wrong, Deivinho?
Are you listening to me?
You're not paying attention.
Deivinho?
If they disarm the attack,
they're the best in the league.
-They just have to score, Dad.
-Yeah, but…
-Dad? Mom?
-Hey honey.
Hi, young lady.
-So, you are…
-Joana.
-This is my mom, Tércia.
-It's a pleasure.
Welcome.
Our daughter's friend is our friend too.
Thank you.
-This is my dad, Wellington.
-How are you? Nice to meet you.
Nina, if I knew
you were bringing a fan of Atlético,
I'd have saved on the fireworks.
The girl will be terrified here.
-Sit down, honey.
-Excuse me.
And you must be Deivinho.
Nina talks a lot about you.
Do you want some water,
coffee, juice, soda?
-Juice would be fine.
-I'll make you a lemonade.
-No need. It can be a soda then.
-No, it'll take just a minute.
You eat some pudding now.
It's a family recipe.
-I think you'll like it. Excuse me.
-Thank you.
-Make yourself at home.
Come on. Come on.
Damn it. Come on.
What the hell?
I give up.
This guy looks like
he's got two right feet.
What is it, honey?
-What a shitty game.
-Deivinho seems off.
Goal! Goal!
Atlético!
What about the fireworks, Mr. Wellington?
-Fuck, Cruzeiro! Motherfucker!
-Hey.
What should be done about the fact that
our kids lag woefully far behind
children in other countries in the areas
of physics and mathematics?
You know what my first reply is?
As a parent? Get out of their way?
When your kid… You're born
a scientist. What does a scientist do?
We look up and say,
"I wonder what that is?
Let me go find out."
-Right.
-Let me poke it. Let me break it!
So, you talk about events that can cause
the end of the world.
Does this knowledge
keep you awake at night?
Yes! Yes.
LECTURE AND Q&A WITH NEIL DEGRASSE TYSON.
FRANCISCO MUNIZ THEATER
LECTURE AND Q&A WITH
NEIL DEGRASSE TYSON.
Now in Contagem,
it's 2:20 p.m. of a new day!
What a joy it is to experience
a new sunrise!
If you're out there feeling lost,
not knowing where to go,
I wish you luck in a brand-new day.
May it come full of smiles
and hope in your path.
May the sun light up your life
and God bless your encounters.
Today is the 10th. Month, December.
Christmas is coming!
Have you got your gifts yet?
No? Look for Malute's Stores!
Sales at all times!
We will be giving away
gift cards later on.
To our beloved audience!
Meanwhile let's enjoy a song
to warm up our hearts…
The bathroom floor isn't good
but I think it's easy to fix.
Girl, there's a ceiling fan.
Oh no.
-It scares me a little.
-Stop it. It's fancy.
Yeah, right.
Did your dad get angry that day?
Joana, my dad can get
very annoying with soccer.
-Do you think I should call him?
-No, leave it alone.
There are other things involved.
Your mom didn't like it either.
No, my mom is all right.
She looked at me
with a strange expression.
You had the wrong impression.
So? Should we close the deal?
Should we?
-Baby?
-Yeah?
-Come here real quick, please.
-Just a second.
-Tell me.
-I'm going over the bills here.
Things aren't good.
It really isn't.
I'm coming from the supermarket now,
-and it cost me a pretty penny.
-Really?
-What about work? Nothing?
-No, nothing at all.
I thought it was gonna get better,
but it just got worse.
The guys will take
two weeks to come back.
-Beatriz is going on vacation.
-Jeez.
I asked Claudete for help
but nothing came up.
It's difficult.
There's no other way,
we gotta cut some expenses.
I was thinking, where's the cable bill?
It's very expensive.
-We could cut the pay per view.
-But, baby. The soccer games.
It's just a little something.
A little something?
The only thing I like
to watch is Cruzeiro's games.
-And we gonna cut that?
-You need to think about Cruzeiro now?
Don't mess with Cruzeiro.
Let's think about something else.
One thing I saw here,
the electricity bill, it's absurd.
But I save on that, honey.
I know you do,
but everybody gotta help with that.
-Nina takes 2 hours to wash her hair.
-But her hair is beautiful.
I know, she gotta take care of it.
But we need to save.
That's funny.
When you had your afro, how did you do it?
Baby, I washed my hair
in the laundry tub,
and let it dry in the sun.
-She takes two hours with the hairdryer.
-No, we won't mess with Nina.
You know what I think?
You should ask your boss for a raise.
I've tried. They won't give
me a raise just like that.
Your boss is an ass.
She'll ask you to take care of her cat
and instead of paying you,
she'll bring you flour from Tchó Tchó.
Who needs that?
If I tell you there's no way
it's 'cause there's no way.
All right, all right.
But Baby, see…
Let's just breathe.
It's not the first time, is it?
-We'll get through this.
-Yes.
-Thanks, I really liked it.
-Really?
Then give me a kiss.
-Merry Christmas.
-To you too.
I loved it. This one was a star.
Damn, he could play ball.
-For you to read on your way to work.
-Thank you, honey. I really liked it.
Here.
GOOD FOR ONE NEIL DEGRASSE TYSON LECTURE.
-You're kidding?
-No,
I’m serious.
-You sure?
-Yes.
-Absolutely? For real?
-Yes. Yes.
Thank you.
The card was just to hand you something,
but I saw the page
for the lecture open on the computer.
And I noticed you won't stop
watching his videos on YouTube.
So, I decided to give it to you as a gift.
Thanks.
-You really wanna go?
-Of course, I do.
-But it's not too expensive?
-No,
I got some money from work.
-Joana helped as well.
-That's nice.
She sent you a kiss
and says Merry Christmas.
-And we'll help you with the trip okay?
-Okay.
-But what if mom and dad won't let me?
-We'll deal with that later.
-One thing at a time, okay?
-Okay.
-Merry Christmas.
-Thank you, best gift ever!
Listen.
Merry Christmas.
Oh, honey, Merry Christmas.
All the best. Merry Christmas.
For all of us.
…the vice president Hamilton Mourao
followed by first lady Michelle Bolsonaro
and Paula Mourao return to the speech
Bolsonaro will give the nation
Hi, good afternoon.
Sorry to interrupt you at lunchtime.
-You wanna join us?
-No, thank you. Enjoy.
Wellington, I just came to give
you the key to my apartment,
'cause I'll be traveling, so you take
care of Galvão and my plants, okay?
Okay, got it.
-So you’re going on a trip?
-I am.
Don't hate the player, hate the game.
-Be careful.
-No need.
Don't worry, we got it.
-Don't get crazy.
-Never did.
Who didn't want to wake up
early, did it like this.
-What's this for?
-To shave, can you believe it?
-No way.
-It's true.
You'd put it in the shaving foam,
apply it to your face,
and then used the razor here.
It cuts right here.
Cool.
-It sounds cool.
-Yeah. It was from your grandpa.
His watch.
I'm gonna keep this, his glasses,
his documents.
Here is his musician ID.
Your grandpa was amazing. Amazing!
He played the trombone
in the band of Mariana.
He sang beautifully.
He learned to speak English,
-and needed no classes.
-Jeez.
-He was that good, huh?
-He was great.
He did some things, he was like
Gyro Gearloose.
He had a small room full of stuff.
He'd build and fix things.
He made a sewing machine
and gave it to me on my wedding day.
-No way. He made it himself?
-He did. It's true.
And it worked.
He got a box,
put the engine and everything.
He was very smart.
God, look at this, him playing.
Wow.
-That's dad, right?
-Yeah.
-He looks funny.
-No, he looks beautiful.
That's when we started dating,
we'd go dancing every Saturday.
With money or not.
He loved to go to the Black Mask.
They played Black music there.
-Your dad was a great dancer.
-He was?
He'd go with your uncle, Zé Maria.
Your uncle couldn't dance.
I got the best one, of course.
I'm not silly.
So beautiful.
-Dad was already a fan of soccer?
-Yeah, he always loved soccer.
I think everyone has something
that motivates them, you know?
-Yeah.
-And for your dad,
-that's soccer, even today.
-Yeah.
-Can I get a few things here, Mom?
-Yes.
Your dad probably doesn’t remember
these things are still here.
After you get what you want,
I'll deal with the rest.
Will you take this? What are you gonna do?
Something I'm working on, don't worry.
-Did you take photos, record videos?
-A lot.
-Did you slay?
-Sure.
This one here complains a lot.
-I hired a guy to take our photos.
-Really?
I had to complain, he wanted
to bring all of Paris in his suitcase.
Oh no!
He wanted to buy
all the souvenirs, unbelievable.
Tell me about the men in Paris.
Amazing.
You know. If he just complains,
I have to make my moves.
The window here is really high, okay?
-You let him make his moves?
-I'll show you his moves.
Look at the expiration date,
I'll see what happen to him, Tércia.
Smoke of caboclo, that smells like Guiné
Let the smoke help this child of faith
May this smoke open your path.
Free you from all the danger and evil.
And may you walk in clean,
clear, open paths.
With the grace of Almighty God.
-You think this is gonna work?
-It's already working, Deivinho.
Look,
we have to start planning
the trip as soon as possible.
Yeah, but have you talked to mom and dad?
Yeah, they just asked us
to remind them later,
-so they can arrange everything.
-Cool.
Don't worry. It'll work.
Here.
-Now will you help me finish packing?
-Let's do it.
-The books go in this box, okay?
-Okay.
Honey, you arranged everything
so fast that I still…
can't believe you're leaving.
You deserve all the best.
Congrats, okay?
-You promise to visit soon?
-Yes.
Sorry I didn't go earlier,
but it was all so fast.
I know, Mom.
I just want you to know
you'll always be welcome there.
You too, honey. Come visit.
Come to eat mom's food.
I'll keep praying and cheering for you.
Take it easy, Mom. Stop with the drama.
For you and Joana.
That's beautiful, Mom.
God bless you, honey.
-Dad?
-Hi.
We're leaving now.
All right.
Eunice,
this chair has more than 70 years.
It has been in the family all this time.
There was a whole set
but this is the only one left.
I fixed it,
and I want you to have it.
It's still good to use it,
but if you don't want it…
you can put it in a corner
with a plant on top.
It would still look good.
What's up, Wellington?
-How are you doing, Sorín?
-You all right?
-Doing some cleaning?
-Yeah. It's practically done.
-It's good to use it.
-Swim a little bit.
It's 32 degrees.
I've measured just now.
-Good.
-It's warm.
I'm passing by, going to an event.
Remember I talked to you
about the tryouts?
-I do.
-Here.
-You kidding?
-On Saturday.
-Next Saturday?
-Yes.
-My God. All right.
-Just call this number.
Deivid will compete
at the same level as the other boys.
There's a chance. I don't want
him to go to another team.
He should play for Cruzeiro.
Thank you so much.
-Tell him to get ready.
-You bet. He'll do well.
-I'll let you know.
-Have some fun.
-Thank you so much.
-Have a nice day.
Thanks a lot.
You went to see a doctor, right?
-Yes, Tércia.
-What about the tests?
-It's all good.
-Nothing wrong?
No.
And you stopped throwing up?
How are you? I wanna know.
I'm fine. Flawless.
-I'm great.
-Headaches stopped?
Yes, Tércia. Everything is okay.
But tell me,
right now, at this moment,
-are you feeling anything or not?
-Right now, I just wanted… you know.
Toquinho, for God's sake, I'm serious.
But, Tércia, that's annoying, girl.
I'm fine.
It's not annoying. I wanna know.
I wanna know everything.
-What? I'm fine, flawless.
-You’ll tell me if you feel anything?
-Yes, Tércia.
-Okay.
-But make sure to let me know.
-Okay. This girl is crazy.
Dude?
Stop the bus!
Oh, God.
-You owe me his autograph, Dad.
-I do.
-Is he a nice guy?
-He's really nice.
You remember I told you I showed him
a video of Deivinho playing?
The goal you scored in Colo-Colo
was in the video.
You know what happened?
He gave me a contact to take you
in a closed tryouts for Cruzeiro.
Can you imagine, son?
Imagine that,
we going to Mineirão to watch you play.
Recording your games on TV.
Hey, I know you feel pressured
about this,
but just be calm.
All you have to do is play,
do what you know and like to do. Okay?
The tryouts are next Saturday,
so I need you to be good.
Don't need to go to school on Friday.
Just relax.
-But, Dad, this Saturday?
-This Saturday.
-You sure? Real sure?
-Absolutely. Yes.
But I already have something.
You already have something
on Saturday, Deivinho?
It's a trip with Nina,
didn't she tell you?
What trip with Nina?
She said something about it,
but she didn't give details.
-Is it this Saturday?
-Yeah, Mom.
-São Paulo, right?
-Yeah.
-But what is it again?
-It's a science fair.
Nah. What a science fair
has to do with it?
No. You're playing ball, don't be crazy.
But she already paid for the ticket.
And they accepted me
as a participant in the event.
You did it wrong.
How do you arrange this without
asking for my permission first?
And how did you pay for this ticket?
-But she said she talked to you.
-She wasn't clear about it.
Tryouts for Cruzeiro, boy.
This could be the chance of our lives.
We can try to do both, Wellington.
How am I gonna explain to Sorín,
an idol of our team, that our son
didn't make it to the tryouts because
he was busy.
How is Sorín gonna explain to the people
that opened the doors for you?
People that trusted you. How is he
gonna tell them you didn't go?
No. You'll go and play your best game.
You'll play like never before.
Everything has a limit, Wellington.
You stop pressuring the boy
the way you're doing.
It won't do any good.
He'll get there on Saturday
won't be able to play well.
The boy needs to be educated, baby.
He needs to understand
that if he wants something in life,
he'll need discipline, responsibility.
Things aren't easy.
This way you're not motivating him,
you're putting him off.
-Have you seen his face?
-That was because of the scolding.
When he gets on that field,
in the green lawn with the ball rolling,
it'll be the same Deivinho,
putting on a show.
You trust too much.
I'll have to get out of here.
What is it, baby?
I'll have to get out of here, baby.
I'm attracting a lot of bad things.
This nonsense again.
If you're not feeling well,
go get some help.
If the people you saw didn't help,
get a different opinion.
I've tried, it didn't work.
I can feel I'm attracting bad things.
But baby, if it was like that,
something would happen to me too.
-How come nothing happened?
-Yet. It hasn't happened yet.
-You're overreacting.
-No.
I'll find a way to get out.
I won't be near Deivinho.
Saturday is coming, if something happens,
I'll never forgive myself.
Baby…
if it'll make you feel better,
I don't know,
Take care of yourself.
Go for a walk, a trip.
If you really believe that
you being around can jinx
the tryouts for Deivinho,
then you should travel.
But travel to a place close by,
a place we can afford.
Only a weekend.
A place nearby.
I'll go on Friday. It's decided.
Fine.
-Flávio?
-Yeah, Mr. Wellington.
-I'll need a favor.
-Sure, Mr. Wellington.
I'll need to go get a medical
certificate for Deivinho.
-For Deivinho? Is he sick?
-No, it's for the tryouts.
-Wow. So it worked?
-It did.
I just need to get a certificate
to prove he's healthy to play.
-That's great.
-Here's the thing.
I need you to go to Dircinha's apartment.
It's simple. Water the plants,
clean the litter box and feed the cat.
-I'll do it now.
-Not now. There's a schedule.
-You can do it before you leave.
-All right then.
-Ten minutes before you leave.
-Mr. Wellington, you're the boss.
You'll get in there and you'll see it.
It's in the service area.
-You'll see the cans, the pet food…
-Mr. Wellington, you can go. I got it.
-Text me if you need anything.
-It's all cool.
-Here, I'll leave the keys with you.
-Leave it to me.
-Can I go then?
-Of course, Mr. Wellington.
-I'll go sort that out.
-Good luck. Go get it done.
Thanks a lot.
Baby, can you help me
install the new shower?
Uh-huh.
What is it?
I don't know.
Did something happen?
I'm worried about the trip.
My parents didn't say anything,
Deivinho neither.
Do you wanna call them?
I will.
I'm just upset my parents
haven't come here yet.
I'll go clean outside, okay?
It will be all right.
My man, Moisés. What's up?
-Good morning, Wellington.
-Good morning. Is everything okay?
-Okay for who?
-What happened?
Dircinha wants to talk to you.
Things are bad for you.
For me? Why?
-Go look for Dircinha.
-Where's Flávio? Is he here yet?
Don't know about him.
Go talk to Dircinha.
Dircinha, good morning.
-Good for who?
-What's happening?
I'm the one wondering what’s happening.
I traveled, left the keys
to my apartment with you,
when I got here,
my apartment was robbed.
My wardrobe wide-open,
my living-room TV is gone,
-even Galvão is missing.
-My God,
-have you talked to Flávio?
-Why would I talk to him?
-If I left my keys with you.
-I had to leave a bit earlier,
and I asked Flávio to do the favor
to water your plants,
and feed Galvão.
But it was a quick thing I had to do.
So you left, gave the keys
to some scoundrel. Right?
-You told anyone you were leaving?
-No. I just talked to Flávio.
I had done all the work in advance…
So this Flávio stole everything,
even my jewelry is gone.
You can be sure I'm gonna call
him and find out what happened.
Look, Wellington. I like you,
I have respect for you,
-but I'm very disappointed.
-But Dircinha…
I'm the manager here.
I owe the residents an explanation.
How am I gonna talk to them now?
-You've known me for years.
-Yes.
And if it was up to me,
I'd give you another chance.
But unfortunately, I can't do that.
You put me in a difficult position,
and I'll have to fire you.
Don't do that. I have a family.
You should've thought about that before.
Now it's too late.
-It's no use crying over spilled milk.
-I'm gonna work this out.
What you did to me,
I could never imagine.
I feel like you stabbed me in the back.
-And it's still hurting.
-Don't say that.
Next week I'll call you
to make your arrangements.
-Give me another chance.
-There's nothing else I can do.
Dircinha, I can work this out.
-Do you wanna go flying kites?
-I do.
-I don't.
-Deivinho, you're so boring.
Are you sick?
I'm gonna go. You're too slow.
Let's go Thiago?
Let's.
-You chicken.
Miss? Good afternoon.
I wanna buy a ticket,
the cheapest one.
-Any city?
-Yeah.
There's Juatuba,
it takes an hour and a half
and it costs 18 reais 90 cents.
-It's 18,90? And it's the cheapest?
-Yes.
I'm here at this bus station,
talking to you because I suffered
a horrible accident.
I ask you for five cents,
ten cents, 25 cents.
Too little with God is a lot,
too much without God is nothing.
Due to this terrible accident,
I'm unable to work.
-You son of a bitch.
-For God's sake.
What have you done?
You ruined my life.
I'm gonna kill you.
-You bastard.
-She's hitting a cripple.
-Take your hands off me.
-Ma'am, it's a prank.
Fuck your TV prank, bitch! Fuck you!
-What's this?
-Calm down.
I didn't know
if I should call your mother,
Deivinho told me to call you,
so I called you.
-He's over here.
-Deivinho,
what happened?
He rolled over and hit his leg
on the bike hard. It was crazy.
And you with these adventures.
Hey, honey.
Guys, what happened?
My goodness.
Excuse me, honey. Let me see.
Deivinho, this broken leg, baby!
How are you feeling? Your arms…
-I'm fine.
-Let me see it.
-Just don't touch it, it's burning.
-Let me see your face. So pretty.
-Your back is hurting? Your belly?
-No.
-Your head?
-No, I'm fine.
-And your teeth, honey?
-My braces didn't break,
-Thank God.
-You won't need to pay for that.
-Guys, what happened?
-He got hurt.
What happened, Deivinho?
Have you broken your leg, son?
-What happened, guys? For God's sake.
-He fell off his bike, Dad.
Have you been hit, son?
Huh?
Answer me, Deivinho.
I was riding my bike, then
I went down the hill and fell.
But, Deivid.
Hadn't we agreed that
you'd stand still at home, son?
Didn't I ask you to stay
at home, Deivid?
-Huh?
-Wellington, don't yell at him.
Damn.
The only thing I asked
was for him to be quiet at home,
and you decide to go down
the hill in your bike, Deivid?
Dad, calm down. There's no need to shout.
-No need to shout. Calm down.
-Look,
I don't ask you for anything.
I don't ask for anything in this house.
The only thing I asked
was for you to stand still.
For you not to go out,
to take care of yourself for tomorrow.
Wasn't it, Deivid?
Damn. Then you go down
on a hill with a bike, Deivid?
Don't yell at the boy. It's over.
Yeah, it's over.
The tryouts, my job. It's all over.
I got fired, baby.
Baby, damn,
there was this chance tomorrow.
There was a chance…
and this fuckin boy
goes out with his bike.
Dad, shut up. You're being an asshole.
-Don't tell me to shut up.
-Stop yelling at my brother.
What are you gonna do?
Are you gonna hit me?
Guys, for God's sake!
We're fucked, baby.
Wellington, let's go
to the bedroom.
Wake up, Wellington.
Let's get you in the bedroom.
Come on, get up.
I'll get some water, honey.
Tragedy at 381
An accident closed out
the traffic at BR381
in the metropolitan region
of Belo Horizonte on Friday afternoon.
Yesterday afternoon, around 2:00 p.m.,
a travel bus left Belo Horizonte
towards Juatuba
and collided with a truck whose
driver lost control of the vehicle.
The two vehicles fell off a cliff.
There were no survivors.
-The passenger list has not been…
-Mom?
Are you okay?
What happened, Mom?
I'm alive.
Bye, Mom.
Bye, guys.
SKY EXPLORER
I can and I am building a new time.
A time of sobriety.
A time of greater understanding.
A time of making our lives worth it.
I thank you for allowing me
to live again with joy,
with enthusiasm
and the desire to do many things.
Once again, I thank the coordinators,
Oscar, Judite, Valéria,
may we have a great week
and may the higher power enlighten us.
Twenty-four hours of sobriety for us all.
And it's time to talk.
-Good evening, comrades.
-Good evening.
Good evening, coordinators.
For those who don't know me,
my name is Wellington.
Yesterday…
I broke a four years medal of sobriety.
I liked this 24 hours thing.
Yeah?
For people to take it 24 hours at a time.
Tell your friend I apologize.
She's my girlfriend, Dad.
And I think you can apologize
to her in person.
You are a lot like me.
More than you think.
Damn.
You really did it.
Wow.
That's crazy, Deivinho.
I'm trying to improve it
so we can see it better.
But that's it for now.
Come see, Mom.
It's here, right?
Wow.
-What's this, son?
-It's Mars, Mom.
That's cool.
-Where did you get all this stuff?
-I made it.
-You made it, Deivinho?
-Yes, Dad.
Remember that day
we were seeing some stuff in the room?
I took some things from grandpa's box,
things you let me,
then I got some stuff I already
had and build it.
That's so interesting, son.
He would be very happy, you know.
He would be very proud of you two.
Son?
Your dream is to go to Mars, right?
Yes, Dad.
Mars must be far as hell.
Like a hundred thousand
kilometers, right?
No, Dad. It's way more.
The distance from Earth to Mars
is approximately
60 million kilometers, Dad.
Deivinho wants to go on a mission
called "Mars One," dad.
To colonize the planet.
And how do you get to participate?
Is it expensive?
Millions of dollars, Dad.
Well,
we'll find a way.
Mom fell asleep.