You don't make up for
your sins in church.
You do it in the streets.
You do it at home.
The rest is bullshit and you know it.
The night we met
I knew I needed you so
And if I had the chance
I'd never let you go
So won't you say you love me
I'll make you so proud of me
We'll make them turn their heads
Every place we go
So won't you please
Be my, be my baby
Be my little baby
My one and only baby
Say you'll be my darlin'
Be my, be my baby
Be my baby now
Whoa ho ho ho
I'll make you happy, baby
Just wait and see
For every kiss you give me
I'll give you three
Oh, since the day I saw you
I have been waiting for you
you know I will adore you
Till eternity
So won't you be
Be my, be my baby
Be my little baby
My one and only baby
Say you'll be my darlin'
Be my, be my baby
Be my baby now
My one and only baby
Whoa ho ho ho
Be my, be my baby
Be my little baby
My one and only baby
Ohh
Be my, be my baby
My one and only baby
Whoa ho ho ho
Be my, be my baby
ohh
My one and only baby
Ohh
Be my...
What the hell is this?
Not in my fucking place!
Keep out of my place! I know your face!
And you, scumbag!
I told you about passing
that shit in my place.
I didn't do nothing!
You're supposed to be the bouncer.
- I didn't do nothing.
- That's it. You didn't do nothing.
Come on, hurry up with that shit, huh?
What's this, more shit?
No, that ain't shit. That's a German lens.
Got two shipments of those.
That's good stuff.
Can't use it.
What do you mean you can't use it?
That's a telescopic one.
That's the best one they make.
It's not German, it's Jap.
This is an adaptor, it's not a lens.
You bought two shipments
of Jap adaptors, not lenses.
Jap adaptors.
Lord, I'm not worthy to eat your flesh.
Not worthy to drink your blood.
Okay.
Okay, I just come out of confession, right?
Right.
The priest gives me the usual penance:
Ten Hail Marys, 10 Our Fathers,
10 whatever.
Now, you know next week I'll come back
and he'll give me another 10 Hail Marys...
...and another 10 Our Fathers and...
I mean, you know how I feel
about that shit.
Those things, they don't mean
anything to me. They're just words.
Now, that may be okay for the others,
but it just doesn't work for me.
I mean, if I do something wrong,
I just want to pay for it my way.
So I do my own penance
for my own sins.
What do you say, huh?
It's all bullshit except the pain, right?
The pain of hell.
The burn from a lighted match
increased a million times.
Infinite.
You don't fuck around with the infinite.
There's no way you do that.
The pain in hell has two sides:
The kind you can touch with your hand.
The kind you can feel in your heart.
Your soul, the spiritual side.
And you know...
...the worst of the two...
...is the spiritual.
I...
Want you back again
Want your love again
I know you find it hard to reason with me
But this time it's different
Darling you'll see
You gotta tell me
You're coming back to me
Tell me you're coming back to me
You...
Said we're through before
Walked out on me before
I tried to tell you
But you didn't want to know
Hey, Charlie, you're crazy.
- The priest taught me that.
- Terrific. You know any other tricks?
Yeah, but I'll show them to you
when I learn this one.
You gotta tell me
You're coming back to me
You know something?
She is really good-looking.
I gotta say that again.
But she's black.
You can see that real plain, right?
Look, there's not much
of a difference anyway, is there?
Well, is there?
I hear the knock
On my door that never comes
- Oh, great.
- Great.
Hey, Marlboro?
For these prices, Charlie,
you shouldn't complain.
That's the best I could do.
Maybe next week I can do better.
If you can't smoke them,
maybe you can sell them.
No, I'll be okay for a week.
Bless you.
You seen Johnny Boy?
No.
He's supposed to be here.
But who knows what goes on
in that kid's head, right?
I'd like to know, Charlie.
I think the kid's trying to duck me.
Think you ought to care more
about Johnny's payments to me?
I think you should. You know that.
Michael, Michael,
nobody's out to screw you.
I guarantee that.
Well, you're not looking
at it from my side.
You vouched for the kid.
What happens if he doesn't pay?
I gotta collect from you?
- I don't wanna do that.
- You're right.
I made a deal with him, not you.
Right. I'm not gonna pay his debts,
believe me.
- I'll straighten him out.
- Straighten him out?
- The bum owes money left and right.
- Don't worry, Michael...
Hey! Hey, come on!
- Get out of here!
- Come on.
- Come on, sit down.
- Take it easy.
- What's the matter with you?
- Everybody's friends here, right?
Come on, sit down.
You know, Charlie,
I don't understand you.
I don't understand why you hang around
with a punk kid.
He's the biggest jerk-off around.
Don't say that.
Don't call him that, will you?
What's the matter?
Family things, it's complicated.
I can't explain it, all right? Ahem.
But really, he's a good kid.
All right, sure. I'll see you.
Right, later. Be well.
Come on, girls. Give her your coats.
Give her your coats.
If you don't mind, young lady,
I would like to check these.
But I'm keeping my skin pants.
- Hey!
- Hey, here he is!
Hey. Hey. Whoo!
Are those the shorts
with the hearts on them?
Girls, after you.
All right, okay.
Thanks a lot, Lord.
Thanks a lot for
opening my eyes.
We talk about penance
and you send this through the door.
Well, we play by your rules, don't we?
Well, don't we?
- Hey.
Giovannino.
- How are you?
- All right. How are you?
I want you to meet
two beautiful young ladies here.
This is my good friend Charlie.
This is my good friend Tony,
he owns the joint.
This is... What's your name?
- Sarah.
- Sarah. Sarah Kline, right?
Sarah Kline, this is Tony.
- And what's your name?
- Heather.
Heather. Heather Weintraub, right?
- I met them in the Village.
- Bohemian.
Yeah, over at the Cafe Bizarre.
- So, what do youse want to drink, girls?
- Tequila.
- You got tequila?
- No.
Never mind. Listen...
Have a Seven and Seven,
it's good for both of youse.
Tony, give yourself a drink. Give Charlie
and me a J&B, will you, please?
- What's this?
- What's what?
- This.
- What?
- That. What does this look like? Huh?
Where did you get this?
- What?
- Where did you get this?
- This.
- What?
- This?
- Yeah. In the back, come on.
- Hey, hey.
- Come on.
What are you doing? Heh, heh.
Hey, you're making me look bad, Charlie.
Ha, ha. In front of the girls over here.
Oh, excuse me.
I didn't mean to be rude, girls.
Mr. Civello, I'd like your presence
in the back room, if you got a moment.
What, you mean you request my presence
for a moment or two in the back room?
I most certainly do.
Well, after you.
- No, after you.
- Hey, Mr. Civello, after you.
- In the back!
- Ha, ha, ha.
Tony, give them whatever they want.
Hey, girls. Hey, girls, excuse me.
Tony, keep an eye
on these nice girls here.
Don't let none of the vultures look, okay?
- What are you doing?
- What do you mean?
- What are you doing to me?
Michael's on my back all night.
He's bothering me.
Why didn't you make your payment
last Tuesday?
I made my payment.
What are you talking about?
- You paid him last week?
- Yeah, I paid him.
What did he say, I didn't pay?
He's a fucking liar. Where is he?
- You paid him?
- Yeah, I paid him.
- Last week?
- Yeah!
- Last Tuesday?
- Yeah.
- You don't know...
- He's here.
- Where?
- Out front.
- He's here?
- Yeah.
So, what do I care?
Let me go get him.
We'll straighten this thing out, all right?
Hey, wait a minute, Charlie.
- What?
- Well, you're right.
- I'm right?
- Yeah, was it last Tuesday?
The Tuesday that was last week
that's before the one about to come up.
My mistake, I'm sorry. It was last week...
The week before that I was thinking of.
- Oh, yeah. It was, huh?
- That's right. That's right.
What's the matter with you?
You can't bullshit people that way.
You give your word, you gotta keep it.
You know what happened?
I'm depressed about other things.
I can't worry about payments, you know?
I come home last Tuesday. I had my money
in cash, you know? Blah-blah, bing-bing.
Coming home, I ran into Jimmy Sparks.
I owe him 700, like for four months.
I gotta pay the guy.
He lives in my building,
hangs out across the street.
- Yeah.
- So, what happened?
I had to give some to my mother.
I wound up with 25
at the end of the week.
And today, you won't believe,
it's just incredible.
- I can't believe it myself.
- What?
I was in a game.
I was ahead like 6-, 700 dollars, right?
- You're kidding?
- On Esther Street. You know Joey Clams?
Joey Scala, yeah.
- I know him too, yeah.
- No, Joey Scala is Joey Clams.
- Right.
- They're the same person.
- Yeah.
- Hey.
So I was in there playing
bankers and brokers. All of a sudden...
...I'm ahead 6-, 700 dollars.
I'm really winning.
All of a sudden some kid walks in
and yells that the bulls are coming, right?
Cops are coming. Everybody runs away.
I grab the money. I go in.
It's an excuse, like to get away.
I'd give everybody the money later,
and that way I'd get out.
I don't have to get into the game
and get a losing streak.
I come out in the yard,
I don't know this building.
I couldn't get out. It was like a box.
Big, like this. So I gotta go back in.
Not only do I go back in,
but this kid says it's a false alarm.
Imagine that? I wanted to kill
this fucking kid. I mean, I want... Ugh!
I was so crazy, I wanted to kill this kid.
Meanwhile, I gotta get back in the game.
Bing-bing-bing. I lose $400.
Meanwhile, Frankie Bones is over there.
I owe him 1300 for seven,
eight months already.
I can't walk on Esther Street
without ducking that guy.
He's, like, waiting for me.
Like I can't move, you know.
He sees that I'm losing, right?
So he's waiting for me.
He's tapping me on the shoulder.
Tapping me like this. Like a hawk.
"You're losing. Give me some money."
I say, "Frankie, come on. Give me a break
over here. Let me win some back.
I got debts. I'm in a big hole."
He says, "Never mind, give me the money."
I say, "Okay."
So I gave him 200.
Meanwhile, I lost the deal.
I go outside, I'm depressed...
I'll cut the story short.
You don't want to hear all this.
I know, I know, I know.
To make a long story short.
Anyway, I went to Al Kaplan.
Got a new tie, got this shirt.
You like the shirt?
It's nice. This tie...
Michael doesn't care if you're depressed.
What is he, your priest?
Why are you going shopping
when you owe money? That ain't right.
How much you got there?
I'm gonna pay him next week.
I'm gonna pay him!
You're gonna and you don't do nothing.
How much you got there?
I got about... I got another $40.
What are you doing?
I got about $40 there. That's all.
What? What are you doing?
I'm holding on to this till next week,
till you make the next payment.
What? There's a little more than 40?
- It's a mistake.
- Yeah, a mistake.
Hey, listen, I swear to my mother,
you come with me next Tuesday...
...I sign the paycheck over to you. I swear
to my mother, swear to Christ, okay?
Come on, it's $110.
You give it to Michael.
Come on, give me some money.
We got those beautiful girls.
We're gonna get laid.
I met those chicks in that Cafe Bizarre.
They were fucking around
with these two other guys.
That one, Weintraub, is very nice.
Very nice. I want to bang her like crazy.
Here.
- Come on.
- That's enough for you.
- Come on, give me another 5. Come on.
- Which one do you want?
You're leaving me nothing.
We gotta go eat chinks?
- Make do for this for the week.
- All right.
- Which one do you want?
I want Weintraub.
She's nice. I like that one.
She's the one on the left?
No, she's the one... Your left or my left?
- We were both standing the same way.
- It don't matter.
Hey, girls, we
had a little business
to talk over.
Everything's okay now.
Excuse me for a minute.
Hey, Tony, you think maybe
you could put this on the tab?
Because something happened before.
You'll be doing me a favor, you know?
- Huh?
- Big tab or the little tab?
Don't you think it's better
that you should put it on the small tab...
...so that it balances out
with the big tab?
- Oh, so things even out?
- Yeah, right.
Joey, where'd you get those beads?
How about me, John?
I don't get a drink?
- Hey, Mikey.
- Long time no see.
You don't get a drink?
- Does a bear shit in the woods over here?
- Ha, ha, ha.
Go ahead.
Give him a double.
Tony, give him a double.
- Long time no see.
- I know what you'll say, but don't.
One, I'm not paying for these drinks.
They're on the tab.
Two, I'll see youse Tuesday payday,
I swear on my mother.
Not on my mother,
but Jesus Christ and... Okay?
All right, I just wanna tell you
to stay on top of it.
- I will.
- We don't want it to get out of hand.
- Don't worry, it ain't gonna get
out of hand. - I'm doing it for you.
- Have a drink.
- Okay.
Gentlemen.
- The queen.
- Queen.
You know what the queen said?
"If I had balls I'd be the king."
Ooh.
Tssh.
Hey, they told me you were here,
and you're here.
- Hey.
- How are you? How's the classes going?
Okay, Oscar.
How's everything going with you?
I was in the basement fixing the freezer.
Would you believe that?
Charlie, you're a good boy.
Will you tell your uncle I have nothing?
I can't make this week's payment.
Listen, you talk to Giovanni, not me.
I should hand this place over to him.
I don't need this aggravation.
He'd rather have the loan paid.
You know that, Oscar.
Your uncle's a good man.
I won't stick him.
He either gets the money
or he gets the place.
Right now it looks like
he's getting the place.
You tell me why I should care.
I got a partner who is a bum.
He disappears!
I don't understand. Where's Groppi?
I should know? His wife don't even know.
If he don't give a damn,
why should I kill myself?
Thank you very much, Natalie!
How are you feeling?
About that shooting last night,
I was there, uncle.
No, you were not.
Yes, I must have confused it
with something else.
Yes, you did.
So?
About Oscar.
I think he's putting on this act
about the restaurant being in bad shape.
He says he can't make the payments.
He says his partner has disappeared.
What should I do?
Don't do anything.
His business is bad.
Can I help?
Yeah, you can help by waiting.
Don't be impatient.
You like restaurants?
Yes, sure.
Oh, you know what I do have?
I got a good buy on toilet paper now.
Leave me alone. Leave me alone.
What kind of toilet paper? I get Scott.
No, I got toilet paper
coming from the PX, the Army.
Now you're stealing from the Army?
- I can get it cheap. You want it?
- Steal from the American Army.
- Army of the United States of America.
- Hey, you sell firecrackers?
What? Come here.
- What do you want?
- Firecrackers.
No, that's illegal.
We went to Chinatown.
They don't have any stuff.
Keep away from those chinks.
All they have is shit.
We have $40.
Well, why didn't you say so? For $40...
We don't know
if we want to spend all $40.
- You want good stuff or shit?
- We want good stuff.
You know where this stuff comes from?
Maryland.
- You know what that means?
- That means it's good.
- Tony, we borrow your car?
- Sure.
Come on. Across the street.
- You got sparklers?
- Yes.
- Cherry bombs? Ash cans?
- Yes. yes.
- Cones?
- Cones, yes.
Women?
What are you, a comedian?
Comedians, Tony.
Thank you.
- Nice car.
- Yeah, well...
Must've cost a lot.
You got a good buy on this,
didn't you? You need a tune-up there, Tony.
You kids come down for the feast?
- Yeah.
Now what we're gonna do is let you
out right over there on that corner.
- We'll come back for you.
- Can we come with you?
No. See, I can't let anybody see
where I got the stuff.
That's good business,
you know what I'm saying?
- Be back in about 30 minutes.
- Okay.
Wait, wait, wait. What about the cash?
Take a check?
- Where are you guys from?
- Riverdale.
Maybe that's what they do up in Riverdale,
but down here we gotta take cash.
Now, you got it or you don't got it.
Okay, here.
All right, now wait over there
and keep your mouth shut.
Checks? Tony, you take checks, right?
Sure, I take checks.
How much did we get?
You know, I don't know.
Let me see here. What do we got here?
What do we got here? Mathematician.
One, two, three, four, five, 10, 15.
What do you know,
we got stiffed by them kids.
They only gave me $20.
Here.
Take 5.
Tell you what, I'll write you a check.
- I'll tell you what, get out of the car.
- I'll tell you what, take the 5.
- Give me the 5.
- Okay.
Let's go to the movies.
And the movie's on you.
Pull over here. Pull over here.
There he is. There he is. Hey!
Hey, Michael.
Charlie, get in the car. Come here.
- Coming in?
- No, come here.
Sal, I'll see you tomorrow, right?
Frankie, be good.
- What's the matter?
- We just stiffed a couple of kids.
- How much you take them for?
- Twenty.
What are you laughing about? Twenty?
Let's go to the movies.
- And the movie's on you.
- What are you talking about?
- This is my business.
- Believe it.
- You guys better enjoy yourselves.
- Heh, heh, heh.
It's costing me a lot of money.
Hey, get your hands off me, man.
Leave me alone!
I ain't doing nothing, lady.
Give me a break,
I'm trying to watch the picture.
You watch it. I'll get the manager
in here. He'll throw you out in the street.
Go ahead. Go get the fucking manager.
- He's a fruit.
- You're a fruit.
Me? I'm a fruit?
It feels good, huh, Charlie?
Streets are empty. Nice.
I mean, with that feast on, you can't
even move in your own neighborhood.
I hate that feast with a passion.
Hey, never mind the feast.
Just remember, I'll do the talking.
That's the trouble. You do the talking.
Don't fool around, John.
Jimmy asked me to settle this.
- How much do they owe him?
- I don't know, a couple of hundred.
Look at this character.
Hasn't taken a bath since last Christmas.
He's probably an ex-judge.
He's the mayor's aide.
- Where's he gonna meet us?
- In the pool hall.
- Near Sullivan Street?
- Yeah.
No, it's on King Street.
What are you doing?
Show me where. I don't know my way.
Make a right turn over here at the green,
when the light turns green.
Next time Jimmy don't bet
outside the neighborhood.
Come on with this light. What is this,
a coffee-and-cake light over here?
John, you wanna keep your father away
from the car, please?
It'll be okay. I know these guys.
They're not gonna stiff him.
How do you know?
Shut your mouth.
I'll take care of it.
- Just don't say nothing.
- I'm not saying nothing.
- Where the fuck is he?
- Here he is.
Charlie.
Listen, the number I bet was 235.
I bet a combination.
I dreamt of my grandfather.
- How much did you bet?
- What did I say?
What?
Calm down.
Clark, you seen Joey Gatucci around?
Yeah, he's in the back room.
When he died, the number
on the funeral parlor was 235...
...so I figured I had a good bet,
you know? So I placed it...
Hey, Joey.
Well, well, well, Saint Charles is here.
Everybody, benediction!
Hey, you may rise. Rise, please.
Thank you.
My good friend Tootie over here.
Tootie. Tootie.
- You can't lose with that.
- How about Mushy?
- Mushy. Here's one for the lamp.
- One for the lamp.
Mushy, this will definitely
get you to Hollywood.
- The chalkboard.
- Chalkboard.
- The pool cues.
How about the balls? Bless my balls.
- Yeah, bless his balls.
- Hey.
- How you been, Joey?
- All right.
Looking good. Look like you
took off a couple of tons. Ha, ha, ha.
- What brings you down here, Charlie?
- Ha, ha, ha.
Look, Joey, on Friday the 25th
I placed a bet with Sally.
- Never heard of it.
- Never heard of it?
Never heard of Sally.
Who the fuck is Sally?
Oh, Joey, really.
We're all friends here.
Let's cut the bullshit, huh?
Well, uh... Hey, Jimmy,
you know you got a good friend here.
Wonderful.
- Come to think of it, I do remember now.
- That's a real scumbag.
Shut up.
Hey, Friday's a busy day.
A mistake can be made, you know?
- Right, no problem.
- All right.
I forget myself too sometimes.
- Okay, let's have a drink.
- Good enough.
Come on, now let's have a drink.
Jimmy, Tony, finish the rack.
- Who's buying?
- Me.
Forever they will haunt me
- Hey. Hey. Hey.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Those oldies but goodies
Can I have a beer, Joey?
Go ahead. I got scotch here.
I got a dry throat.
Hey, where'd you get the hat?
You like this hat?
This is a $25 Dobbs hat.
Where'd you get those sneakers?
- These are $2 sneakers.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Why don't you lower the jukebox?
I can't hear.
Hey, the girls like the music loud.
Girls? You call those skanks girls?
Hey. - Hey, what's
the matter with this kid, huh?
Ain't nothing wrong with me.
I'm feeling fine.
- Keep your mouth shut.
- In front of this asshole?
All right. We're not gonna pay,
we're not paying.
- Joey.
- Why? We just said we'll have a drink.
We're not paying because this guy...
This guy's a fucking mook.
But I didn't say nothing.
And we don't pay mooks.
- A mook? I'm a mook?
- Yeah.
- What's a mook?
- A mook? What's a mook?
- I don't know.
- What's a mook?
- You can't call me a mook.
- I can't?
No!
- I'll give you mook!
- Hey.
A fight.
A letter for me
I've been standing here waiting
Mr. Postman
Hey, hey, hey!
Come on, I got a bad hand!
For just a card
Or just a letter
Saying he's returning home to me
Mr. Postman
Mr. Postman, look and see
Oh, yeah
If there's a letter in your bag for me
Let's get him up against the wall.
Oh, yeah
Since I heard from that boyfriend of mine
So many days you passed me by
That's it. That's it.
You wouldn't stop to make me feel better
By leaving me a card or a letter
- Come on, get him!
- Get him!
I got him.
- Watch out!
- He's got a pool cue!
Mushy!
You gotta wait a minute, wait a minute
Oh, you gotta wait a minute
Come on, grab him!
- Hey, watch out!
- Get him!
Can you check and see
Just one more time for me?
Damn it! Grab his arms!
Deliver the letter
The sooner the better
What's the matter with you, Joey?
Wait a minute
Please, Mr. Postman
What's going on here?
The cops. The cops.
- Hey, officer. Can I get my hat?
- No.
- Can I call my wife?
- Nope.
What you got here?
That's a nail file.
- That's a knife.
- No.
- This is a knife.
- It's got a toothpick in there.
Davis, Davis, this is very embarrassing.
Look, how long have I known you,
Davis, huh?
You've never seen fights like this.
These are my friends.
- This is my cousin Charlie. We're friends.
- Friends.
- Your cousin? Where you from?
- East Side.
The East Side. What is this, a knife?
No! It's got a toothpick in there.
You see over there?
Davis, come here. I wanna talk to you.
You covering for the East Side
or the West Side?
- Let me just talk to you over here.
- What are you gonna say about this knife?
- It's a harmless penknife.
- Harmless?
It's a dangerous weapon.
Do you know the penalty?
- I'm sure we can settle this.
- How are we gonna settle this?
- Let me give you some car fare.
- All right.
Took you a long time. Where you going?
- New Jersey.
- New Jersey. All right, here.
- This is for you and your partner...
- Going to Philadelphia.
Here.
- Thank you.
- Okay.
Thanks a lot, Davis.
- Here.
- Thanks.
Johnny, come on.
- Thanks a lot, Davis.
- And you guys here, listen.
No more of this fooling around, huh?
You guys'll get hurt like that. All right?
Okay.
So long, Davis.
Come on, let's have a drink.
Come on, let's have a drink, everybody.
Who were those mooks that jumped us?
Every day is Christmas with these cops.
We were gonna pay you.
We just don't like being pushed around.
- Come on, Joe, we're pushing you around?
- Yeah.
- Let's have a drink and forget it.
- This is the drink we never had before.
- Come on, salute.
- Salute.
Ah.
All right, there's your money.
- You don't have to count it. It's all
there. - No, go ahead. Count it.
Hey, come on, no bullshit. Friends.
- Hey, don't fucking touch me, scumbag.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- Fuck youse all!
- Relax, huh?
Come on! Come on!
Hey, that's for you!
Up your ass!
Come back here again,
you'll find out what's gonna happen to you.
Fucking douche bags!
- "Mook." I don't know what that is.
- Johnny.
- We're gonna look it up.
- Stop with the "mook."
Look at that, look at that.
- Don't touch it, it hurts.
- You look great.
- Got something we can put on his eyes?
- I got something.
- First, I wanna show you something.
- What does "mook" mean?
Hey, Jimmy Mook.
Okay, baby, just relax.
Take it easy. That's it.
Uh-uh. Time out.
George, you're supposed to be working.
Tony, give me a break. I'm with a girl.
- Yeah, go out and work.
- Oh.
Charlie, give him a break.
Close the door, George.
- Before we take care of you.
- Smells like shit.
There's something I gotta show you.
Watch this.
Oh, hey!
Where did you get this?
Look at the size of these guys!
- Tony, you gotta be kidding me.
- That's crazy.
Look at this one. That's beautiful.
That panther. Where did you get this?
How many pounds of meat
you feed him, huh?
Keep quiet about this.
I don't have a license for him.
- Where did you get him?
- Nobody can go near him but me.
I'm the only one who can feed him.
Watch.
- You got claw insurance, or what?
- What are you doing?
Hey! Hey!
- You crazy or what?
- Be careful.
What are you, out of your mind, Tony?
What are you doing, cowards?
No wonder Italy lost the war.
Here's Daddy. Here's Daddy.
Tony, be careful.
I really wanted to get a tiger, Charlie.
Old William Blake and all that.
Okay. Come on. Come on.
That's it. That's it.
That's it. Hug Daddy. Hug Daddy.
Come on. Come on.
That's it, baby. Good girl. Good girl.
Come on. That's it.
That's it. Don't bite. Don't bite.
That's it. Good. Good girl.
You believe anything anybody says.
That's right, I believe anybody.
That's my charm.
Some charm, pops.
- What about the time you went on retreat?
- What about it? You... Hey.
Charlie goes on this retreat.
He tells me this story about a priest
who used to, uh...
...let this couple
borrow his car for dates.
They didn't make it,
because they weren't married.
But two weeks before the marriage,
they decided to make it.
So they pull over to the side of the road
in the priest's car.
Boom. Mack truck comes along,
and they're both killed.
That's great. That's true?
This really happened? Madon.
No, wait.
Charlie believes it.
I tell him two years before that...
...I went on a retreat
and the priest tells me the same story.
It's a different priest,
it's the exact same story.
- So that...
- You get it?
Yeah, you mean the story
ain't true, right?
Yeah, but the point is, he's really upset.
What he don't understand is...
...it's a business, it's work,
it's an organization.
You got a way about talking
about one thing and then, zap...
...you slide right into something else
like nobody's even supposed to notice.
I was mad because they lied to me.
I'm gonna tell you one thing:
I ain't never going on no retreat.
Never.
Why do you let those guys get to you?
Because they're supposed to be guys.
Hey, listen, that's where you and I differ.
What can I tell you?
You want me to say it?
You gotta be like me.
You wanna be saved.
Bar's closed, kid.
I'm just waiting for Joey.
All right, sit down.
I gotta go to the bathroom.
So go ahead. What do you want,
somebody to hold it for you?
- Jesus.
- What a jerk-off.
Charlie, hold it for him.
Hold his ding-dong.
George.
You wanna do something?
Yeah. You know how he gets.
You know how my chairs get?
Hey, hey.
What is it with this guy?
- This place is really getting depressing.
- That's an understatement.
If I had my place, every night...
...get bums like this down,
have things happening.
Call it something like
Season of the Witch. Get it?
- Got it.
- Good.
Bullshit.
Who's talking bullshit? Who's the guy
with William Blake and the tigers?
Hey, come on. Will you guys shut up
with the tigers and the witches over here?
Let's get out of here.
Come on, close the place.
I'll get out of here
when the place is ready to close.
Close it now.
We get out of here, get something to eat.
When everybody leaves, we close.
Don't forget what's-his-name
in the bathroom.
Charlie, come here.
Let me show you a picture of yourself.
Hm. Not quite, but keep trying.
Dummkopf.
- You wanna have a game after we close?
- No.
Yeah, come on. For how much?
Scumbag.
- Don't call me no scumbag.
- You can't pay what you owe.
As soon as a game shows up,
you, bang, wanna jump in.
"For how much?"
Why don't you use your head?
Hey, hold! What's the matter
with you guys? We're friends!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
- Me? He's calling me a scumbag.
- You too.
- All right, enough.
- Fucking moron.
- Moron?
- Yeah, moron.
Go ahead. Hit each other
with the fucking chairs, why don't you?
- Come on, we gonna go eat now?
- All right, enough.
- You ought to know better than that.
- I'm sorry.
Sorry.
I'm sorry, okay? I'm sorry.
- Wanna play a little cards?
- No.
Anybody wanna have a game?
Michael, I've got a game
you cannot say no to.
No.
You said no.
Lot of sports.
A little blackjack?
Eh.
Somebody get the gun!
Everybody out!
George, kill the lights!
Don't run! Split up! Split up!
Don't run!
Don't run, just split up. Don't run.
Don't run! Just split up!
Hey! Don't run!
George, where are you going?
Where's your car?
Mikey.
Michael, let us go with you.
Hey, chauffeur!
- Hey, chauffeur...
- Shut up. Quit your hollering.
- It's too pack. I'll ask him.
- Uptown, Jeeves.
Come on. Hurry up.
Where are we gonna go?
Michael, give us a lift.
Get out of here. Get the fuck out of here!
- Hey, get out of here!
- Get out of here!
Hey!
You're making too much noise.
Just get in.
I'm standing out here in the rain.
What's the matter with you guys?
Hey, stay there. Come on,
get away. Get... Hey, move over.
Stay over there. Stay on your side.
Don't touch me.
Where are we? Where are we?
Sammy, get control of yourself.
Will you behave yourself.
I'm terribly sorry.
It's just that he's frightened.
Just keep him quiet, all right?
- Are these friends of yours, Mike?
- What are you, a comedian?
I can't get over the way
he kept going at him.
Yeah, must've been
all that liquor in him, boy.
Yeah, chetarsi.
You know what chetarsi means, Sammy?
Sounds like something dirty. Heh, heh.
What are you looking at?
What are we doing with
these faggots? Throw them out.
You nuts? What do you want me
to do, leave them in front of Tony's place?
Hey, Benton, look at that number. Wow.
- Hey, shut up!
- Hey, beautiful!
Hey, hey, hey! Keep him down!
- Keep quiet.
- What's the matter?
Look at this. We're embarrassing.
Sammy, behave yourself.
I won't. I won't. Why should I?
- Let me out of this car!
- Sammy, stop it! Come here!
Look at that one!
Oh, my God!
Hey, baby, got any meat?
Hey, baby, I want to suck on that! Baby!
I want to suck on that!
I want it all!
Get them out of here! All right, that's it.
Get out of here! Get them out of here!
Don't push!
- What do you mean, get out?
- Get out of here!
I just got in.
Go, go!
- Animals!
- Take it easy.
All right, just a minute, please.
- Thanks for the ride, Mike.
- See you around.
Wait a minute. What is this?
Hey, fellas, you going my way?
Come on.
What you bothering with them for?
What's your problem?
Bullshit.
Hey, look at that piece, Johnny.
It's one of those little jobs
cops carry in their sock.
Yeah, cop hit me on the head
with one of those.
Remember that time I got that beating
from those cops?
Yeah, you never recovered from that one,
did you?
I never recovered?
If I wasn't there to be used
as a punching bag...
...to enable you to leave fast...
That's because you're stupid.
You should've ran and left safely with me.
With you?
I'm stupid for getting my head punched in?
You schweinehund!
My bad hand, my bad hand.
- Wait a minute.
- What are you doing?
Shh. Joe Black.
Joe Black. I owe him money.
- I don't think that's him.
- Yeah, it's him.
Where is he?
He turned the corner.
- Is he gone?
- Yeah, he turned the corner.
That don't mean he's gone.
Get over here. He turned the corner.
What's the matter with you?
Come here. I'm talking to to.
Watch out for that.
You can't go home like that.
Stay with me.
Your mother ain't there?
She's on the island
taking care of my grandmother.
Hey, let's get some bread
from my uncle's store.
- I'm sick about my hat.
- Here.
Your grandma's gonna die, right?
Yeah, right.
Did you like her?
What do you mean?
She's my grandmother.
So what? That don't mean nothing.
"So what?"
- What's the matter with you?
Jesus. Anyway, she ain't dead yet,
God forbid. So shut up.
- Charlie!
- What?
You ain't got nothing to eat over here.
I could've told you that before.
Got nothing.
I tell you what, you know what we do?
- What do you want?
- Tell you what we do.
I'll go to my aunt's. She's got food.
She keeps food all the time.
I'll go through the fire escape.
Don't do that. You'll scare your cousin
Teresa, you go in there that way.
Oh, that's right, yeah.
Hey, you know what we can do?
She can have a seizure.
Then we can watch.
That's not funny.
You gonna be a jerk-off all your life?
Grow up, huh?
You want some food from your aunt,
go and knock on her door.
Forget it. I ain't hungry now.
Go to sleep.
Besides, where are you going
at 6:00 in the morning?
I don't know.
- Did you say your prayers?
- Ha, ha.
Very funny.
Hey, why don't you tuck me in, sweetie?
Teresa, I had a dream last night
about you and me.
I gotta tell you this.
We're in this room and we're both naked.
And there's this huge white bed and you're
lying on it and I'm standing over you.
And we're just about to make love
and I come.
The only thing is, I come blood.
Heh, heh, heh.
And blood went all over the place.
Squirting all over the place, all over you,
all over me, my hands and everything.
I don't think that's funny.
Girls bother me.
They got no sense of humor.
Well, I'm a girl.
Do you like me?
Yeah, I like you.
I love you.
Well, I don't love you.
We'll see.
Hey, forget it.
If there was a chance of me falling in love
with you, I wouldn't be here.
Because?
Because with you, I can't get involved.
- Because?
- Because you're a cunt.
- It was a joke.
- Where do you get off talking like that?
It was only a joke, for chrissake.
Hey, come here.
Like hell it was.
What are you standing
in front of the window like that for?
Someone might see you.
Get over here. Come on.
Go ahead. Jump out the fucking window.
Don't look.
- You really don't want me to look?
- Yeah, I really don't want you to look.
- Heh, heh, heh.
- I see what you're doing.
- I saw you.
- What? I wasn't doing nothing.
What do you want?
Ugh.
Ah!
You wild woman.
Leave me alone!
- Get your hands off me!
- Let go of me.
- You're killing me.
- Ha, ha, ha.
You should've seen it. Unbelievable.
Kid went right to the bathroom
and shot him.
Guy kept coming at him like Rasputin.
Madon. That kid was scared.
We were more scared.
It doesn't make any sense. He shot
him just because he insulted Mario?
It wasn't anything personal?
The kid's a climber, not very bright.
He kills a guy who insulted a big man,
gets a reputation, thinks he's made.
It's still sick.
Not sick, just stupid.
Which reminds me,
last night Johnny decided...
...to break into your mother's house
and get some food.
- So why didn't you let him?
- Oh, that's funny.
- Put that shit down. What are you doing?
- Ha, ha, ha.
What's the matter with you?
Hey, he doesn't know anything about us,
does he?
- Really?
- No. I don't want him to know.
Nobody knows anything.
Your reputation's safe.
Hey, come on, smile. What's the matter?
You look like you wanna kill me.
Wanna kill me? Go ahead, kill me.
Ooh.
Miss, you can make up the room now.
- I only got two hands.
- Well, use them.
- Cut that out, will you?
- I hate shit like that.
Excuse me, ma'am.
- You got some mouth, you know that?
- Kiss me.
I'll give you a zap. Wow!
- Hey, Hash, how you feeling?
- Pretty good.
- My uncle in the back?
- Yeah, I think he's busy right now.
Hey, Charlie,
play a 4-6-3 combination today.
Yeah, thanks.
What are you talking about?
There was no insult. I know the kid.
He was drunk.
He made a fool of himself, not me.
Nobody had to shoot him.
I hate the sun. Let's go inside, will you?
What else do you hate?
I hate the ocean, and I hate the beach,
and I hate the sun.
And the grass and the trees
and I hate heat.
- Charlie?
- What?
What do you like?
I like spaghetti and clam sauce.
Mountains.
- Bzzz.
- Ha, ha, ha.
Francis of Assisi.
Chicken with lemon and garlic.
And John Wayne.
You know, there aren't any mountains
in Manhattan.
Tall buildings. Same thing.
And I like you.
I like it here alone.
You know, I'm really gonna
take that apartment, the one uptown.
- Are you?
- Yeah, I'm really gonna do it.
- Why don't you do it this time?
- I'm gonna.
The hell with my parents.
I just can't take it anymore.
- I think it'd be a good move.
- I'm gonna do it.
So, what are you waiting for?
For you.
Teresa. Now, you can't wait for me now.
I'm closing in on something
in the neighborhood. I gotta stay.
What are you afraid of?
Afraid? What are you talking about, afraid?
Go on. What's stopping you?
You say you're not afraid of your parents,
so go ahead, move out.
- All I've got is the neighborhood.
- What about me?
The neighborhood and those guys.
That's all that's important to me now.
Right, guys like my cousin Johnny.
No, not exactly your cousin Johnny.
Well, I hope not, because he is crazy.
He is driving me nuts.
How can you be with him all the time?
- He's like an insane person.
- What's wrong with you?
- How can you talk that way about him?
- Oh, fuck him.
That's terrible.
Who's gonna help him if I don't?
It's supposed to matter.
Nobody tries anymore.
Tries what?
Just tries to help, that's all.
Help people.
You help yourself first.
Bullshit, Teresa.
That's where you're all wrong.
Francis of Assisi had it all down.
- He knew.
- Ha, ha. What are you talking about?
- What are you talking about?
Saint Francis didn't run numbers.
Me neither. I don't run numbers.
My darling, I'm lonely
Now that you're gone
Please come back to me
Diane, how are you feeling?
Fine. Excuse me, please.
You know, Diane, I've been wanting
to talk to you for a while now.
Excuse me.
Aside from all that joking around
that you and I do.
- You know, when you're on, I...
- Excuse me.
I really think you're a terrific performer.
Fine.
Hey, no, I'm serious.
You're really very good.
I know.
Groovy.
In a little while I'm gonna have
the opportunity of opening my own place.
Much nicer.
Much nicer than this.
Uptown, sort of a nightclub restaurant
and everything and, uh...
Uh, I was thinking you'd do much...
You'd do very nicely for the place.
Dancing?
No, as the hostess. That's nice.
Hostess?
The people come in, you greet them
and you show them to the tables.
Listen, why don't we get together later on?
We'll talk about it a little bit.
- Chinese food?
- Hey, Chinese food.
Where do you want me to drop you off?
No, don't stop.
Just pass by real slow, okay?
Hey, stop here.
Hey. What, am I crazy?
Would you take me back
to where you picked me up?
- Sorry.
- All right.
Hey, am I crazy?
That's all I need now, to get caught
in the Village with a mulignan.
Hi, Lou.
Fine, thank you. Good to see you.
- Good to see you.
- How's it going, Lou?
- Hi, Oscar.
- Giovanni.
Mario. Mario.
- Mario, how you doing? Nice to see you.
- How are you, kid?
- Giovanni, can I sit?
- Sure.
Can I talk?
- What is it?
- It's about Groppi.
I know all about it.
We'll discuss it later, huh?
Sure, I understand.
Shall I serve the tripe now?
- Anytime. Thank you, Oscar.
- You're welcome.
They are not like us.
They know where to come
when they need us.
I realized this a long time ago,
during World War ll.
Charlie Lakey was working for
the government, taking care of the docks.
- What did he do?
He was there, that's what he did.
I said the same thing to your father
20 years ago.
He didn't listen.
You're still around that kid Johnny Boy.
This Johnny Boy is named after me.
Nice, huh? Oh, sure.
But this Johnny Boy is a little bit
like your friend Groppi, half-crazy.
I understand you try to help him out
because of our family and his family.
Well, that's nice. I understand.
But watch yourself, don't spoil anything.
Honorable men go with honorable men.
Don't forget that.
His whole family has problems.
His cousin, the girl who lives
next door to you...
- Teresa.
- The one who's sick in the head.
No, she's got epilepsy.
That's what I said.
She's sick in the head.
Her mother and father came to me
for advice.
She wants her own apartment.
What am I gonna tell them? Lock her up?
You know I'm compato with them.
So I listen.
I have to take an interest.
You live next door. Keep an eye open.
But don't get involved.
Charlie, why don't you take a look
around the place if you want.
I've been in and out of this place
about 50 times already.
Well, maybe you missed something.
You should get to know the place.
All right. Yeah.
Jesus Christ, you are disgusting.
Hi, Charlie, how are you?
Hot enough for you?
Yeah, how are you doing there, Cookie?
Fine.
is it in his eyes?
Oh, no, you'll be deceived
Oh, no, he'll make believe
if you want to know
if he loves you so
it's in his kiss...
Teresa.
Psst!
Downstairs.
Meet me downstairs now. Yeah.
if you want to know
if he loves you so...
- What is it?
- Come down.
Come out here.
Shit.
Uh...
I can't make it tonight.
Okay.
All right, so is that all?
So I'll see you on Friday?
Friday, um...
I can't make it Friday either.
What do you mean?
I can't see you for a while.
Don't tell me that.
- Teresa.
- Why?
You are fucking things up!
Between you and Johnny...
- ...you're gonna ruin everything for me.
- Ruin what?
"Ruin what?"
I'm sorry, Mrs. Rucco, pardon me.
Come on inside.
Why am I ruining everything?
Keep quiet! I'll give you
a slap in the mouth, Teresa! Shut up!
Listen to me for a minute.
My uncle's got me on it
to run a restaurant,
but I gotta stay away
from you and Johnny.
- Does he know about you and me?
- No.
Does he know about Johnny
and those loans?
No. What, are you kidding me?
Of course not.
He doesn't understand Johnny. You know,
he's just a kid who needs to be...
- Answer me.
- What do you want from me?
I said, do you feel the way
he does about me?
No.
I don't feel that way.
I don't want to stop seeing you.
What are you afraid of?
I love you.
- I don't wanna say that.
- What?
- That.
- What? That you love me?
Right.
All right, all right, all right.
Let's just get out of here.
Okay. Okay, but just...
Let me get the restaurant first, all right?
Then I think things are gonna be easier.
Okay.
So where have you been?
Around.
You heard what happened
to Groppi, huh?
Who, me? No.
Well, Oscar found out
where his partner is.
It seems Groppi went
to visit his mother.
He went to her room
where she was watching television...
...and he says to her he's sorry.
That's all. Just he's sorry.
He goes into the next room, gets a gun,
puts it in his mouth.
And that's it.
How do you like that? I tell you
that Groppi was always half-crazy.
Half-crazy to say the least.
Charlie.
What is it?
Not now, huh?
Doesn't he see that we are talking?
A couple of minutes, will you? Outside.
- What does he want?
- He wants to talk to me about something.
Hey, you spit on my shoe.
Okay, Charlie,
a lot of aggravation though, you know.
Like Johnny Boy.
I figure I give him all the breaks
I can give him.
- Oh, look, Michael.
- No.
No, Charlie, it's no good, see?
He's a punk bastard, Charlie.
I call them down there at work
and I ask them...
...if Johnny Boy's there.
He doesn't even show up anymore.
- They told you that down at his place?
- Yeah.
How's he gonna pay me, Charlie?
Oh, I've talked to him
and I've talked to him.
- What more can I do?
- I don't know.
Tonight at the party,
the three of us get together...
...and we knock some sense
into his head. Okay?
All right, Charlie. You know I don't like
being taken advantage of.
I mean, you're inside there
with your uncle and all that.
It's kind of embarrassing for me.
I apologize, Michael.
We had some business.
- Private. You know what I mean?
- Yeah.
Oh. I'm late. I gotta meet somebody.
We'll settle it tonight.
- Okay.
- Ciao.
And, Michael, I appreciate
what you're doing for me.
All right.
I love you so
doo doo doo doo doo
I want you to know
I'm telling you, darling
I'll never let you go
doo doo doo doo doo
I need you, it's true
I hope you do, too
doo doo doo doo doo
I'm telling you, darling
I'll never let you go
doo doo doo doo doo
- Very intelligent too, you know?
- Yeah.
She's going to college.
She's gonna be a schoolteacher.
- Only been out with her a couple of times.
- Yeah.
Her picture.
- Michael, let me see that picture.
- Yeah, she's gonna be a teacher.
- Oh, I know this girl.
- Yeah?
Yeah. I seen her kissing a nigger
under the bridge in Jersey.
- What are you talking about? Niggers.
- Ha, ha, ha.
A nigger, as in mulignan,
as in black. A nigger.
What do you mean, kissing?
I mean kissing. Her lips on his lips.
Kissing.
- You sure?
- I'm sure.
Ew.
Nigger. I kissed her.
Don't worry about it.
It'll be all right.
love you for eternity
eternity
I spend my nights...
Hallelujah. I've come to create order.
Carl, J&B and soda, please.
May God be with you
and with your spirit.
- Let me ask you something.
- What?
Art thou the king of the Jews?
Does thou say this of thyself
or have others told thee of me?
Am I a Jew?
My kingdom's not of this world.
Jerry, hey, how you doing? Wow.
Oh, hey.
To Jerry...
...who served in Vietnam.
The immortal words of John Garfield:
"Get him in the eyes,
get him right in the eyes."
Came back with a Silver Star.
From the boys.
Hey, Carl! Drinks for everybody!
Drinks for everybody!
Hey, drinks for everybody!
- Drinks for everybody.
- Could make a shirt out of that, Jerry.
- We drink and then we bullshiting!
- We're bullshiting!
George.
- George, my man.
- Watch this.
Put your mouth down there.
- Michael.
- What?
Play only old ones tonight.
Only old ones.
All right.
Do that again
Did you ever hear of a wish sandwich?
Well, it's the kind of sandwich that you're
Supposed to take to pieces of bread
And wish you had some meat
The other day I ate a ricochet biscuit
Well, it's the kind of biscuit
That's supposed to bounce off the wall
Back in your mouth
If it don't bounce back
You go hungry
Charlie, Flash ain't here yet.
He said he'd be here.
Well, he isn't. Nice, real nice.
- He'll be here. He'll be here.
- All right.
Look...
...I'll give you 20 bucks
to hold you for now.
What, are you kidding? Twenty dollars
doesn't pay the interest for two hours.
- Now with the vig, it's almost 3000.
- Three thousand?
Shit, you charge a guy
from the neighborhood 1800 vig?
- One day he's late with his payments.
- What am I, his father?
You could have come to me
a little sooner, friend.
Charlie, this is business.
Well, then be realistic, Michael.
Where's he gonna come up with $3000, huh?
Let's work something out.
Make it 1800.
Don't hustle me.
I'm not hustling you.
Let's make it 2000.
All right, now you're being
sensible about it.
I swear to Jesus Christ
and the goddamn cross.
If he thinks he's making a jerk-off
out of me, I'll break his legs.
Michael, come on, huh?
You should have the sense
not to get involved.
- Don't tell me what to do, huh?
- I'm telling you the truth.
The fucking truth is
you're more involved than anybody.
What do I look like, a jerk?
Next payday
I'm coming down here to Tony's.
Johnny Boy better show
or I'm gonna find him...
...and I'm gonna break his fucking legs.
We understand each other?
I heard you.
Good.
Amen, I say to thee.
Thou will not come out from it
till thou hast paid the last penny.
Michael, you look tired.
You said it.
Forever my darling
Our love will be true
Jerry! Jerry, don't! Jerry!
Jerry!
Come on, Jerry! Come on! Jerry!
Easy, man!
Jerry, take it easy! Take it easy!
You're in America, Jerry!
Your love in return
May this fire in my soul
Jerry, easy! Come on, easy!
Let him go, fellas. Let him go.
I'll forever love you
For the rest of my days
I'll never part from you
And your loving ways
Dance?
My heart's at your command, dear
To keep love and to hold
Do you like this song?
Hm?
Keeping you is my goal
I'll forever love you
For the rest of my days
I'll never part from you
And your loving ways
Charlie, there's a girl here to see you.
- Charlie?
- What is it? What's the matter?
Johnny Boy is up on that building
on the corner.
He's been on the roof for half an hour.
- All right, don't get excited.
- He's got a gun.
Don't get excited.
- You stay here.
- I'm coming with you.
- Teresa, stay here.
- I don't want to...
Shh! You stay here. Tony.
Yeah, Teresa, stay here.
- Have a drink.
- I don't want a drink.
- Give Teresa a drink.
- I don't want one.
Have a drink.
- I'll have a Seven and Seven.
- Okay.
- Charlie.
- Watch out. Come here. Come here.
Crazy bastard's up on the roof.
- Johnny! It's me, Charlie!
- Hey, watch this!
I'll shoot the light out
on the Empire State Building.
Hey, cut it out, stupid. It's me.
Bobby, stop fucking around. Come on.
Hey, what do you got up there?
A .38!
- That ain't real, is it?
- Yeah.
What's the matter with him?
I'm gonna throw that fucker off the roof.
Oh, shit. Hey, lady, I'm sorry.
Lady, I didn't mean it, I swear to God.
I'm very sorry.
Are you crazy? What are you doing?
I scared the shit out of her.
Very funny. Give me that.
I hate that lady.
I tried to get her clothesline.
- What's the matter?
- What do you mean?
You have Teresa half-crazy about this.
I wasn't shooting at nobody.
Just up in the air.
I want to wake up the neighborhood.
It's dead.
I hate that woman
with a vengeance, a passion.
- You and your numbers.
- Fucking chickenshits.
- Back to Bataan.
- Heh, back to...
Now they're gonna get
a real back to Bataan.
An atom bomb,
wake up the neighborhood.
- What the fuck? Put that out.
- Put what out?
- Johnny, put that out.
- A surprise. You want to see?
- Want to see?
- Johnny, put that... Hey!
Give me... Put that... Get the fuck...
Let's hide in here for a while. Come on.
Come on with this door. Come on.
What are you kicking?
Get in there. - About time.
Remember we used to play
hide-and-seek here?
Never mind that.
What's this crap about last week?
- What? What?
- "What?"
You got some balls
not showing up for work last week.
After all we had to do
to get you on that truck, stupid.
What's the matter with you?
Charlie, come on. My hand was hurting...
Your hand was hurting.
Your mouth's gonna hurt from this kick.
For what? Hey, I swear to you,
what are you talking about?
Besides, I don't like loading crates.
You're not supposed to like it.
- What gets me is your attitude.
- My attitude?
What gets me is your attitude.
Did you ever load crates?
- You don't work.
- My attitude.
You tell me to go to work
and you do all the talking.
- What do you do?
- I'll tell you what I don't do:
I don't owe anybody 2000 clams, stupid.
I got Michael to make it 2000,
give you a break on that.
Oh, yeah?
Go to work tomorrow
or I'll break both your arms.
- We understand each other?
- Yeah.
Hey, I'm sorry, Charlie.
I really am. I mean...
...because I appreciate everything
you're doing for me. I mean, I do.
So I was figuring that the next
logical thing to do... Don't get mad.
- How?
- I know how you get.
- You know a way out of this?
- Yeah.
Oh, let me hear this one.
Talk to your uncle.
Oh, that'd be just really great for you,
wouldn't it, huh?
But not for me.
Johnny, one word out of your mouth,
my uncle hears one word about this...
All right. Hey.
I was just asking, that's all.
That's what I get for getting involved.
Look...
...on payday, at least show up
at Tony's place to meet him, okay?
This way he won't think you're trying
to make a jerk-off out of him.
- Yeah, all right.
- Hey! I'm not asking you, I'm telling you!
Yeah.
- Johnny, come on.
- What?
Come on.
- What, we going now?
- Let's go.
- Hey, Shorty!
- Fuck you, Charlie, will you?
Shorts, you must be having
illusions of grandeur.
What do you want from me? Talk to him.
Gonna see you and Johnny Boy
down here tonight, right?
Yeah, we'll be here.
I'm telling you, Charlie, that kid doesn't
show up tonight, I'll find him.
I'm gonna drag him down here.
I'll tie one of his legs
to that Cadillac bumper.
I'll tie the other to
the Ford, and boom!
We'll be here.
Better be here, Charlie.
Michael, don't you fucking threaten me.
Miss? Excuse me, miss? Miss?
What? What do you want?
I just want you to tell your cousin Johnny
he's gotta see Michael tonight.
- Then tell him yourself.
- Love to. Where can I find him?
- I don't know. He doesn't live here.
- He's here all the time.
- Fuck you.
- Fuck me?
What do I have to take
from these people?
Look what you did, you...
Here.
What am I doing?
Would you just give me
my fucking eggplant, please?
- You got some mouth, you know that?
- Get out of here.
Now just be sure and tell him
to be here tonight, all right?
You sure he didn't say anything
about tonight?
I told you before, nothing.
Charlie, will you listen to me? I can't
stay here too long at this time of night.
Now, Michael was looking for him.
- What's happening?
- Nothing.
I don't believe you.
Son of a bitch.
What? What did you just say?
Teresa, watch the hands already.
Charlie. Charlie, what do you think?
Look, why don't you realize
what this apartment means?
Maybe after a while
you could even move in yourself.
Enough with that apartment already!
I don't want to hear anymore!
I got enough on my hands
with your cousin.
You wanna move? Go on, move.
But leave me out of it!
Teresa, I didn't mean that,
but we've got a situation right now.
- Yeah, a situation.
- Come on.
Look, go and play your fucking games
with that dumb kid. I don't care.
Teresa, it's no game.
- Hey, hello.
- Where were you?
Where was I? I was around.
Answer me, son of a bitch.
Where were you?
- Charlie.
- Shut up!
Shut up, Teresa. We don't want
to get Charlie in trouble here, do we?
Don't be cute.
You had me going crazy here!
- Yeah?
- What's the matter with you?
What's the matter with you?
- About an hour and a half late.
- Oh, that's too bad.
Michael's waiting for us.
You forget or what?
Your cousin was getting sick
worrying about you.
We had to start calling up everybody!
Yeah? That's too bad.
Isn't that too bad?
Huh, Teresa?
So, kiddies,
youse make any plans yet, or what?
- When are you getting married? Engaged?
- Don't be smart.
What do you mean?
I'm stupid, remember?
- You heard me.
- I'm a stronzo.
I'm so stupid
you gotta look out for me, right?
Right? Yeah.
What's the matter? Hey, Teresa.
Look, she's upset.
Now, what are you so upset about?
You don't understand Charlie.
Charlie likes everybody,
everybody likes Charlie.
- Enough. Enough.
- Fucking politician over here.
- Watch your mouth!
- I'm going home.
Hey, no. Wait, Teresa!
Teresa, whoa, whoa!
Oh, Teresa, come on, stay here.
I don't wanna break up
a nice, happy household here.
Johnny, Johnny, stop fooling around.
I swear to God, if you open
your mouth about any of this...
About what?
- You know what I'm talking about.
- About what? You two?
Hey, who cares? I won't even say nothing
to my aunt and uncle.
The guys don't give a shit.
What do they care?
I won't even say nothing
to your uncle Giovanni.
- I'm not fooling around.
- Come here!
- As a matter of fact, I just talked
to him. - Oh, yeah? What?
What? No, I won't say nothing
to Giovanni, that's all.
I wanted to ask you something, Charlie.
I always wondered about her.
This is the God's honest truth.
I always wondered about what happens
when she comes. She get a fit?
- What's that?
- What happens when she comes? I mean...
You dirty, fucking bastard!
Don't ever hit me again!
Don't!
I will tell your uncle.
- Go ahead.
- Right now.
Go on!
I'll tear your fucking eyes
out of your head!
- I'm gonna kill you, bastard!
- Go on!
Teresa!
Teresa! What do you do?
You know about this?
Johnny!
Hey, how should I know?
She's your fucking girl.
- Teresa. Get over here.
- I gotta go.
- Come here!
- Get off me!
Teresa?
Hey, you know what to do?
I don't know. She had an attack.
You meeting my uncle? Huh?
After what I've done for you?
What do you mean what you did for me?
Why you talking to him?
You didn't do nothing for me, you fuck!
Fucking bastard.
You're a fucking bastard.
- Talk to me. What?
- You fucking bastard.
Come on, what are you doing?
What you doing for me?
Don't show up tonight.
We'll see what happens to you.
How much money you got
for Michael tonight?
- I got nothing.
- You got anything?
I got 8 fucking dollars on me.
Well, then, here. Take 20.
Take 22. At your rate,
that'll make $30 we'll give to Michael.
I'll keep 11 for the weekend.
Maybe we'll get some chinks later.
Take it, stupid, I'm doing it for you.
Come on. Come on.
Carrying on, huh? Cut it out, will you?
Come on, 30 bucks ain't nothing,
you know that.
The only way you're gonna do
is if you talk to your uncle.
- That's it.
- Forget it.
- Why not?
- I ain't gonna do it. Forget about that.
You all right? Did I hurt you?
Come on.
You're over an hour late.
Michael said he'd be back, though.
- Have a drink.
- I don't want any.
Hey, cut it out, will you?
- Where you going?
- I'm going to the bathroom.
All right, now.
Take it easy, don't get excited.
No.
Who's the girl?
Jewish.
- How do you know?
- Look at her.
She don't look Jewish.
She's in here every night with
a different guy. You know how they are.
I love you.
Ever since that first
day at the convent when
I saw you playing
volleyball with the nuns...
...I couldn't help myself.
- Let's go.
- Fuck off.
- You go. I'm staying.
It's obvious the girl doesn't want
to go with you. What do you think?
- Hey, look, fella, this is private.
- Nothing is private.
I wanna go.
Whether she wants to go or not,
she's not gonna go.
Let go of her.
- Take her away.
- You're hurting me!
Physically, you take her away from me.
Go ahead.
- All right.
- Fuck you, bastard!
Hey, Joyce.
Yeah, maybe we'll meet
at bingo some night.
Hey, Mike.
What's the story, John?
I was here earlier tonight.
You kept me waiting for an hour.
Hey, I'm sorry, Mikey, but you know...
...I had something to do.
But I got something for you.
Not much, but I got something for you.
He has about $30.
That's all he's got on him, Michael.
- Where's the rest?
- Yeah, where's the rest?
I bought a few rounds of drinks
while I was waiting. You know, I mean...
Tony says my credit
ain't no good no more.
You know, $30 is enough of an insult.
But I'd take it for Charlie here.
But 10 dollars?
John.
Ten dollars?
Hey, Mike...
You're really something, you know that?
You too good for this $10, huh?
You too good for it? It's a good $10.
You know something, Mikey?
You make me laugh, you know that?
I borrow money
all over this neighborhood...
...from everybody,
and I never paid them back.
So I can't borrow no money
from nobody no more, right?
Who does that leave me
to borrow money from but you?
I borrow money from you because
you're the only jerk-off around...
...that I could borrow money from
without paying back, right? Right?
Because that's what you are.
That's what I think of you, a jerk-off.
He's smiling. Because you're a jerk-off.
Ha, ha, ha.
You're a fucking jerk-off.
And I'll tell you something else.
Mikey, I fucked you right
where you breathe...
...because I don't give two shits
about you or nobody else.
Easy, easy!
Come on. Come on. Come on.
Come on. Come on, fuckface!
Come on. Come on.
I got something for you, motherfucker!
Come on.
Come on. Come on, motherfucker.
I'm a bigshot.
Come on. Come on.
Come on, DD, disappointed duncesky.
Right, asshole. Come on. Come on.
You don't have the...
- You don't have the guts to use it.
- I don't, huh?
I don't have the guts.
Come on, asshole. Come over here.
I'll put this up your ass.
Hey, asshole! This is for you, asshole!
Fucking asshole.
You stupid bastard,
were you gonna use that?
Were you gonna use that?
I'll fucking...
I'll fucking kill you, Johnny!
That is fucking it!
Big fucking man!
All right.
So now you did it.
No bullets in this.
Now you did it.
Get him out of here
before this blows up.
Hide the gun, Tony. Throw it away.
Listen, Tony, I gotta borrow your car.
We ought to take a ride.
We shouldn't be around here now.
Okay.
Don't drive around.
Go to a movie or something.
This is no good, all right?
You know what I mean?
- You understand?
- Maybe.
You got what you wanted.
It's really something to see
Lum-dee-lum-dee-la
This cat named Mickey
Doing that monkey
Lum-dee-lum-dee-la
Come on let's do Mickey's monkey, children
Do Mickey's monkey, children
Yeah, let's do Mickey's monkey, children
Lum-dee-lum-dee-la
Get in.
Get in the car, John!
Lum-dee-lum-dee-la
Oh, monkey see, monkey do
Virgin.
Teresa, you all right?
Yeah.
I'm sorry.
I told you I'm sorry.
- He's in trouble.
- What do you mean? What's going on?
Look, Teresa, just trouble, all right?
We gotta leave, until I get a chance
to talk to a couple of people.
I need a couple of bucks
to get to Greenwood Lake.
- Where are you going?
- To Greenwood Lake.
- I'm coming with you.
- No, you're not.
You want more trouble?
I'm coming with you.
Teresa, I got no time for this.
- So, what happened?
- Forget it.
I really think we should talk to
your uncle. That's the only way.
No.
- What happened? - It's all right,
Teresa. Will you forget it?
What are you gonna do,
hide me or what?
That's right.
I guess you could safely say
that things haven't gone so well tonight.
But I'm trying. Lord, I'm trying.
What are you, talking to yourself?
- Turn on the radio.
- Make it louder.
Oh, yeah, go ahead.
Turn on the radio, John. Yeah.
We're going to a party.
How about some fun?
Where are you going? To Brooklyn?
Why don't you make it louder? Go ahead.
- Where are we going?
- Seriously, do you know?
Where are we going?
You don't know where you're going.
We don't know Brooklyn. What's this?
- You know Brooklyn?
- Is this the right way?
Do I know Brooklyn?
Do I know the jungle?
Bing-bing.
- Watch...
- Ha, ha, ha.
- Watch where you're going!
- You're crazy.
You're out of your mind.
Didn't you see that light?
The light was red, right?
- Slow down. Will you slow down?
- What does red mean?
I wish you'd slow down
your mouth a little.
- What is that guy, crazy?
- Hey! Hey, jerk!
Now's the time.
Get down!
Johnny!
- Get down!
- Argh!
Johnny!