.::FLiCKSiCK::.
720p
It's gonna be tough.
The case wasn't easy.
You are going to see him tomorrow?
Yes, dad.
Say hi for me and
ask him to visit here.
Ah! He might not wanna visit.
Thank you.
Gift of 7th Room.
The sun and The moon!
My baby, the baby,
the fairy has visited.
What do you see?
You have wide set eyes...
you have many brothers!
Ah..I am the only child..
That's why people call you greedy.
You took all the luck from brothers
and sisters you must be lonely, right?
I'm not lonely..
The guy you are seeing now is a
bastard, he's gonna hit your back
break up, you should break up!
I don't have a boyfriend..
I told you not to get a
schedule in the morning, bad brother!
Father, money
I told you not to come in when I am in
the middle of work, listen to me! Please!
You are Bong Seon.
What is she saying?
You know my sister?
Of course, so well.
Shin Bong Seon.
What are you?
Huh?
In bible,
Then when lust hath conceived,
it bringeth forth sin: and sin,
when it is finished,
bringeth forth death.
- Amen.
Generous God, father.
- Why he has come?
Yea Seung?
- Yea Seung?
- Jesus?
It feels awkward to sit here,
I used to sit there front of the judge.
Do you also feel like that?
I did nothing wrong, why am I so nervous?
Forget about the dark pasts, brothers.
- Amen.
- Hallelujah
oh, sshiii..t..t..
Sheriff
all of you changed nothing
from now on,
Judicial Research and
Training Institute 21th,
let's get started with Pre-Jury System.
Prosecutor, defend the case.
The undertrial, Lee Dong Gu,
kidnapped young Choi Ji yoeng,
molested, smashed her with stone and
cruelly killed her.
This is already proven by
National Forensic Service.
This trial,
there is no necessity
continuing this trial in any parts.
I rest my case.
Lawyer, defend.
The obvious proof that he's talking
about, confirmed testimonies.
These are
the mistake of this trial.
Your honor,
- The lawyer is in contempt of Court..
- Mistake?
Yes
the prosecutor on this case
isn't the guy who had
been assigned to this case.
This case, unlike other cases,
he must look back the
evidences and situations on the day
but he's defending based on trumped-up
litigation records and fraudulent data
which is made by
detectives long time ago.
Oh, so the lawyer,
are you the lawyer
who had been assigned to this case?
Are you?
No
I rest my case.
But
I am sure that
I was there.
You were there?
Yes
there..
I was there.
Your honor,
statement I will be speaking from now,
is definitely
true.
Where I can meet you?
It couldn't be a fate.
Miracle sailor moon
not gonna forgive you
as a name of justice
only one left..
Yeah, Yea Seong.
We buy ..tommorrow.
Is it the salaray day?
Yeah.
Six hundred..
Ten dollors ..
Wah~ we are rich.
Yeah, we are.
- Huh?
- Huh? Yea Seong's bag..
The bag, dad!
Yeah, Yea Seong's bag..
Yea... Yea Seoung's bag..This is..
Sailor moon bag... Yea...
Yea Seoung's bag.
What's wrong with you!?
What's this!?
Huh... hello.
- Everyday..we looked at this..everyday.
- We also looked at it twice a day.
Yeah... twice a day, twice..
- Cute ~ Yea Seoung's... This is..
- Where the heck are you touching!?
This is Yea Seong's..This is..
What are you!?
This is Yea Seong's ..
- Is he crazy!?
- Why are you hitting my father??
What are you? What!?
- What's wrong with you!?
- Yea Seoung's ..This..Yea Seoung's..
I'm calling the police now!
Dad.
Why only that store
has the bag in our town?
I, dad
am going to buy... sailor moon bag.
For Yea Seong, gift for
the entrance into a school
No.
Don't push yourself.
Do not repeat what I'm saying.
Do not repeat what I'm saying
tickling, It's tickling ~
I am not afraid of you at all.
Dad.
Yeah.
Don't drink the tap water.
Tap water, NO
boiled water
don't have a bread as lunch,
eat meals
okay?
Yeah, Yea Seong you too does that
eat rice, rice!
Okay?
Yeah.
Yea..Yea Seong is cold.
Yea Seong, get back to the house
bye bye
one
two
three!
- Take care dad.
- Yeah.
Pass through, pass
wait for a while
one
two
three!
Knock, knock, knock
knock, knock, knock, knock, knock
- have you bought the bag?
- Ahhh..
The bag,
sailor moon bag
- Other store has the bag
- Must buy sailor moon bag, sailor moon bag..
I buy.
- Come with me ~
- Wait for me..
Here here
beautiful..
Sailor moon..
Why are you being funny?
Beautiful sailor moon bag..
Freaking cold
he..he..he..help
somebody help
what's wrong?
Somebody help!
Yes, chief! Crime! Crime now!
You should come now!
Shit! Commissioner is on the way now!
What a fuss here!
Go home..I need to..
Bye bye..
Sit down, face the situation.
- Yea Seong is waiting..alone..
- Okay, you are right, okay.
- Yea Seong will be scared..
- What the fuck I said okay
- Hey don't hit him.
- I need to... go home...
why are you hitting!
- Sit down now!
- Bye bye..I'm leaving now
This case is
a vindictive murder
against the commissioner...
Sir
challenge for the prosecution..
The criminal Lee will be here in a while
for a spot inspection
the citizens and
the criminal has just arrived.
They are having a spot inspection now
this spot inspection..
- Let's do it at a time.
- At once.
- You choked.
- And?
You slapped
and kissed
took off her clothes
pants..
Blood circulation..
Put it on the chest
Yes, yes.
What? What are you doing? You
also took off your clothes, right?
No more..
- No, do it.
- I am kind...
Let's make it faster so that
you can go to see your daughter.
- Ah..Yea Seong..
- Oh, okay
good, good, take off!
You bastard!!
Dad.
Daddd.
- Dad.
- Yea Seong!!
Stay in the house. See you later
go home first!!
- Dad! Where are you going!?
- Dad will be there!
- Yea Seong.
- Dad
- you might get a cold, Yea Seong!
- Dad! Where are you going!? Dad!
- Yea Seong!
- Dad!
- Son of a bitch! Stay tight!
- Wait for me! Yea Seong!
- Dad!
- Yea Seong!
- Sit properly
- You might get a cold! Go home first!
Yea Seong!
Come in.
If it's your off day, go home please.
What's this? This..
Nothing special at home
did you go?
I brought new prisoners.
Today,
4 prisoners to be transferred
among these 4 prisoners,
there is a S4 prisoner...
(S4 - lowest degree in the prison)
- S4?
- Yes
undressing?
Kidnapping a kid..
Rape..
He is a murderer..
Hello
as a prisoner here, I believe
there is no man here
without a story behind.
Anyway, all of you here made a crime.
Sins you made..
- I need to call home..
- No! no!
- Yea Seong is waiting..alone..
- No!
- City name 0317400700
- Go stand there!
City name 0317400700
I need to call home... Yea Seong.
Thank you..
Chi..chief
what the hell, this crazy guy!
What the hell are you doing!?
- I'm gonna do the laundry with pieces of soaps.
- Laundry?
- Do what? Why?
- Do blow job!
You, you, you!! You
touched my body last night!
- You touched my... You son of...
- Not last night.
It wasn't me last night
you sick, idiots
get in
turn around
do not make any fuss here
welcome him
don't worry too much
have you seen us making a fuss here?
- Don't you try.
- Yes, sir
- bye.
- Take care.
Bong Sik
- let him sing a song.
- Yeaahh
bow, bow
ehh.
Hello
Lee Yong Goo
I'm born in 1961,Jan 18.
GyeongGi city, LeaChun town
cesarean operation
my mother was painful, my head was big then
I used to fish at the stream.
My mother died when I was 5 years old
car accident, bus number 375.
WorBok town
- you know a funeral hall there?
- So what?
I never had a father.
- Uncle Jung Rae, uncle Sung Rae.
- What's wrong with him?
Cousin Min Kyeong
sister Su Jin
hey
what have you done?
I parked.
Happy, Happy, HappyMart
eh..I parked..
Ah~
I think he did a car depot
(illegal transaction).
From now on,
that's your space
take off your shoes, go there
I said go ..there.
Igonoring my...
hey, give me the book
have you ever seen me reading a book?
- Go, Chun Ho.
- Hmm, let me see..
Article 287 of Criminal Law,
kidnapping a minor, tempting..
What the hell has the trash come!?
- Son of a bitch, go on.
- Article 305 of Criminal Law, the sin of kid adultery, sexual..
- Son of bitch.
- Stop
get him, get him, get him
- you kidnnaped, you son of bitch.
- On your grandfather's face, you son of..
Bastard, you deserve it.
Article 298 of Criminal Law,
an indecent assult.
Clause 2,Article 301 of Criminal Law
rape and murder.
This son of bitch is really a trash
- 1st trial.
- Sentence of death!?
What a atmosphere here!?
What's this!?
Attention
Lee Yea Seoung, your new friend.
She will be staying with us from today
greet.
Hi, Yea Seong
how about you
- attention! Attention!
- Let's go
- oh shit, the ball got over the wall.
- Shit..
If ever somebody is there,
throw the ball back over the wall please
thank you.
- Vaseline.
- Vaseline
you pervert
double payment for the used one.
- Glue?
- That's..that's for me
not allowed, man
buy this, not glue.
That son of a bitches, want my spot?
Make sure of the payments
late payment, no deal.
- A4
- Yes, sir
- reserve a solitary confinement.
- Yes, sir.
Is this son of a bitch crazy?
That..stop drinking yogurt
bullshit on ur face.
Is this all you prepared?
What the hell??
What the hell are you guys doing?
Don't sit that way
lie down
you saved my life,
In return..
Anything you need?
It's okay, tell me
do you smoke?
Smoking is bad..
He doesn't know my bro well.
Once he speaks, he keeps. If ever he doesn't?
That's an asshole
whatevery he makes a promise,
he keeps. That's gangster.
This is the definition
you are lucky huh?
What do you need?
Yea Seong
what?
Jesus?
( Yea Seong and Jesus sounds similar )
huh?
Je..Jesus?
- Have the kids also joined the church choir?
- Sir?
Ah... It's the first time.
Aren't they cute?
Chief! Cheif!
Head of department wants to see you
you should go see him now
Go now. What's all this for!?
Hold on there, Yea Seong.
Ah, not this way, wrong way.
- Are you okay?
- Yes
I'm super fine
go first, I can take care of this
you are Jesus?
Dad!!
Without saying, you left
why!?
- I'm sorry..I did terrible.
- You know how I've been looking for you!?
Why? Where have you been!?
Sorry..
- Without telling me..
- I'm sorry.
Yea Seong got thin..
You are so light, Yea Seong
- shhh..shh..quite.
- Thank you, thank you..
- What the hell, we are so much in trouble now.
- Thank you.
This can't be happening..think about it.
If ever we get caught..
No special pardon, nothing! Not forever!
- All of us! 2 years more to stay!!
- Shut up!
Sir, look sir!
I'm good in hide and seek
nobody can find her..
Bro, bro!
Bro.
What? Why?
- Look.
- What?
Look what?
- In our room..
- Your room?
What's in your room?
What in your room!?
Hey!?
I want another bread
are you Jean Valjean?
Why the hell are you crying for a bread?
Here, eat, eat more
I'm having a tough day
and you want another bread!?
Yea Seong.
- Yea Seong, you weren't scared?
- Shhh..
- You got a brilliant daughter.
- Dad will get out soon.
- Anyway is she really your daughter?
- Yes
yes, daughter of Lee Yong Goo
Lee Yea Seong
beautiful light obstetrics
December 13
14:28
Yea Seong is born
2.2kg.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
Why are you here?
- Dad isn't a bad guy?
- Yeah.
Dad isn't a bad guy.
This is a school, school!
Not a bad place
eat, eat
this isn't a school..
This..prison, prison.
All of them, bad guys.
Dad didn't do anything bad
Shit... all shit... shit...
- why are you already here?
- The minister blacked out
high blood pressure!!
Move move!
You said 2 hours!?
- It's been only half an hour.
- Half an hour now... 2hours..
Yeah..yeah, yeah
Things don't go as you wished
- go, go see you later.
- Yeah, yeah
- bye bye.
- Not you!! Yea Seong, Yea Seong
- no.
- I don't like
- behave, good girl.
- Hey!!
Be quiet!!
If you don't leave now,
you have to be a seeker forever.
Keep being like this,
you won't see your father anymore.
- Get it?
- Lower your voice!
Dad, can't I stay here?
Nobody knows
- nobody knows, nobody..
- You need to go to school, school!
Not good to cut schooling
visit on weekends
I thought this is a school.
This isn't a school, it's a prison.
Prison, bad guys.
That's why, go to school.
You want her to be
like us? Like him?
- Like him?
- What the hell
like you idiot?
Yea Seong, school
you need to go to school, Yea Seong.
- Visit again.
- What visit again? Crazy?
Is this a playground!?
Angel (1004) will bring you back here again
(1004 pronunciation is same as Angel)
see you soon
promise
promise now
how should I buy another minister again!?
What the hell..
Shit, why me . What the heck!!
- Eat a lot.
- Yeah.
You can eat? Now with this situation?
Delicious? Dying to eat!?
Delicious..
- Good?
- Yes.
Yea Seong, eat beans, bean
- vitamin, vitamin.
- I don't like beans
you need to eat, open your mouth
Why are you here if you
don't like to eat beans?
They are not giving
enough food..
That little kid is eating all
bro, what's your plan?
That's what life is, easy to get things in
hard to get things out.
Old man, stop bullshitting
really..
Eat, eat
Bro... Let's just confess..
Huh? Let's confess.
If we confess, what do we get?
- You wanna poop?
- Yes
poop
what the fuck, eating and pooping!?
Close the door before you poop!!
Bro, let's send her out 2 days later
- What?
- A day after tomorrow.
- When, 2 days later?
- On religion event day.
He has come, He has come
friend, you're so briliant
- no doubt the swindler is a genius.
- I said I'm not a swindler.
- It's a gift!
- Gather, gather!
Get things ready
on religion event day, okay?
- Okay.
- Look at these kids!
All by chances, you guys
always gather and talk huh?
Do not gather! Get it?
Yeah
Monica, I had a tough day
Good night, see you later,
have a dream of me.
Man Bum, let's sleep
I'm sorry, dad
I asked you to buy the sailor moon bag..
Dad will buy you the sailor moon bag
when I get out of here..
Dad, speak louder and clearly to the judge,
one word at a time like a baby.
Yeah... one word at a time.
That dad isn't a bad guy.
Dad isn't a bad guy..
Wow so beautiful.
Yea Seong is beautiful
no, not me, that the star and the moon
beautiful..
Brother!
- No, Yea Seong!
- Yea Seong, Yea Seong!
Yea Seong!! What...
- Not there... Yea Seong.
- Sshh... shh...
- there there!
- Be quiet
what a surprise
- sleep, sleep, sleep.
- What's up?
- What was that sound?
- What sound?
- Sl..sle..sleeptalking?
- I heard girl's voice
what was that?
- You are freaking me out now..
- I heard it, you think I'm lying!?
- I wish to have a girl here.
- I heard "the star and the moon "!!
The..tha..t..
Answer me
what "the..tha..t"???
What the hell is this?
What?
The star the moon
you must be going crazy..really..
Lie down. Sleep
sleep
that crazy..
Hey Chun Ho, what
the hell happened to...?
- What the!!
- Monica!!!
What happened to her boob!?
This is my favorite picture, why!!
Why! Yea Seong! Why!?
I thought she might be cold
so I dressed her up
- you are driving me crazy.
- This is a violation of human rights, huh?
By the way, what is she wearing?
It's Sailor Moon
what? Sailor Moon?
I won't forgive you
with a name of Justice!
( Sailor Moon line )
- That's what Judges usually say.
- Ah... It's Judge Moon.
- Judge Moon.
- No... you don't know this song?
Don't!
Hey, sit!
What's wrong with this guy?
Hello, hi
get back in, get back!
Hallelujah!
Amen
hey son of a bitch!
You son of a bitch...
take care, bye bye
see you next time, next time, next
go
what?
Shaveling...?
You don't even know
who is Buddah and Jesus!?
You fucking swindler
- come out.
- You said I'm your right hand!!?
- Right hand?
- You shut the fuck up, you chicken!
Can you choose the picture...?
I don't think I am..
Please
- Give them to me.
- Here.
- Is the minister fine?
- Yes, he's fine now
what a relief..
That son of a bitch swindler, chicken head
bro, think about it.
They even check the room even 12 times in
a day what if they open the door and check?!
What are you gonna do then? Huh?
What will happen? Huh?
You dick
even if you needed to shave her hair
you should have sent her out!
Not allowed... No
shaving Yea Seong's hair..
- Yea Seong's hair is beautiful now..
- This son of..
- Yea Seong...
- Stay still
stay still!
Why are you guys still up?
Have you eaten?
Nothing is here.
Nobody knew about this!?
You think it makes a sense?
No, listen sir..
I definitely heard a girl's voice..
Put on emergency alert,
check all the rooms!
- Yes, sir
- Yea... Yea... Yea Seong?
I hid the kid in the furniture room.
Are you fucking crazy!?
Get her out of here right now!
- Sir...?
- Later, after the rain stops..
You wanna get fired!?
- Yes, sir!
- It's raining hard..Yea Seong might get a cold... cold..
- A cold?
- Yeah..
Are you fucking saying
a cold at this situation!?
Yea Seong doesn't have
an umbrella..umbrella..
You fucking murdered someone's daughter
but you still wanna see your daughter!?
It's not true..
9482 ( his number in the prison )
haven't killed..
Bro..
As I see so far I think if we
say nothing, we won't be in any trouble
you son of..shut up
okay..
If we reveal about this,
few of prison officers will be fired
what will they do to us, huh?
- We got nothing to lose.
- Yeah.
Yeah, those guards are also same as we are
sleeping with the enemy!
Cooperation charge
educated one is different from us
cooperation charge ~
I feel so relieved, amazing.
Yea Seong's father must have been
sent to solitary confinement, right?
Put them down
put your hands up! Your hand!!
You mother fuckers!
- I've been good to you guys!
- Listen..bro..
You fucking, "bro" only at
this kind of situations!?
Yea Seong will be scared
Yea Seong..
Yea Seong ~
who said you can be out here!?
Get back in
chief!
Fire, there's fire, fire!
Chief! There's a guy.
He set this!!
The next room, she can visit
why isn't my father visiting!?
You guys stopped him from visiting me!
Right? You motherfuckers!!
8038! we didn't let the girl in!
You can't do this!
Is my name 8038!?
Call my name!! name!
Okay, I will call you with a name
Mr. Park Sang Myen, you can't do this..
- Put..put it down.
- Hey! Am I your friend!?
How old are you!?
You son of a bitches!
Hey, Baldy! You don't wanna go
home!? Put it down for me!
Why the fuck would I put this down for you?
- Open the cells, get them to the yard.
- Yes, sir.
- You!
- Alright..put it down.
- You stopped my father from visiting me!
- I will call your father so put it down!
- I miss my father.
- Put it down, I said I will call your father.
Really? Okay...
I'm putting it down.
Thank you, chief. Thank you
you thought I bought it!?
Fuck you
I'm an orphan! You son of a bitches!
Get out now!
You wanna die there!?
Stay away from me unless you wanna die too!
What the fuck, how...
Don't come closer! Don't!!
He's dying..dying..
He's dying there.
- Dying..
- Not my business! Shit!
- What happened?
- What do you mean what happened?
What a relief.
If there wasn't a stammerer,
you are at the funeral now.
Who?
This dude has carried you on his back.
He must have inhaled a lot of gases
with tears and nasal discharge.
He said " help him, our chief
help him please".
By the way, is this guy really a kidnapper?
Is he?
He said he didn't kidnap...
hello
take care.
Yea Seong
you know how much I worried about you?
No one is there at your address
nobody was..
You moved out?
Have you been sick?
Will you tell me what happened?
Can you just ask my father instead...?
Huh?
Home counseling
- ah..coun..counseling.
- You have ID with you?
I...ID?
Dad.
Yea Seong.
- Dad.
- Yea Seong, Yea Seong!
- You got a cough?
- I'm fine now.
- Yea Seong got thinner.
- Dad also...
Dad is fine. Dad is... fine
she's my teacher
- Hello.
- Have a seat please.
- Yeah.
Nice to meet you, I'm YeaSeong's teacher
in the school
pretty.
- Yea Seong is pretty, the teacher is also pretty..
- It's nothing about special..
It's just an councelling
smart..Yea Seong
She goes to bank alone,
pays the electricity bill herself
on the first day of each month ..
In installment savings and salary $600
$140, 24 months expiration
43% 10th day of each
month, medical insurance
- Medical insurance.
- We pay $6.
- 6$?
- Yes, $6, we pay $6.
Yeah... She's the smartest
and prettiest one in the classroom.
Yeah... she's prettiest in the world.
Yea Seong is good in singing
so we are..we are planning the
the choir with her
- first floor in the refrigerator?
- Bankbook
- 2nd floor?
- Kimchi and cucumber one
- on the refrigerator?
- Cup-noodle!
3 minutes, with boiled water
with egg?
- Okay?
- Okay.
Dad, eat alo...
I can't hear.
More... Not yet... More...
Why...? Not yet!? Yea Seong.
Dad! Why!?
- Yea Seong, eat a lot!!
- You got thinner! Eat a lot!!
- Dad also... eat a lot dad!!
- Yea Seong!
Yea Seong! Dad will go out soon!
Very soon!
- Go home and wait for me!
- When are you coming!?
See you soon!
Dad will go out soon!!
Dad, 10 nights! 10 nights!
- Tomorrow dad!
- Yeah! See you later!!
- One night!!
- Just...
see you later, Yea Seong!!
Bye bye
you know, daughter of Lee Yong Goo
she's in the hospital now.
She doesn't eat anything at all.
I knew this will happen ..
We can't support and take her anymore..
Provinces are much better... government
supports provinces more than here..
Mr..
I don't wanna go far away..
Can't you just arrest me too?
Please?
This isn't right, chief
wrong, huh?
- This is insane.
- He said he will take all the responsibility.
Hey, you idiot
we all get fired!
I will be a farmer.
You guys join me.
What? Chief, chief!
Chief!
I don't like farming!
(marijuana - asshole - alcohol)
Take it easy
what the heck is alcohol?
You idiot
first initial sound law.
What? You are educated huh!?
Leader, all-in!
Let me join in Word chain game too.
Is it a special day? Why are you
offering rice cake? Unusual..
Before Chief leaves for a traning session,
he specially left it for room no.7.
Yea Seong
- rice cake, rice cake!
- It's Yea Seong, Yea Seong
Whenever you see a box, Yea Seong,
Yea Seong. Let's eat, eat, eat.
Dad!!
Yea Seong!
Stop
idiot, It's not rice cake
not rice cake..
Chief
where did he go again
did he go to get leaflets?
- Mr. Lee YongGoo, wait for a while here.
- Yeah..yeah..
What the heck are you doing?
Hello
put the picture down.
Delicious snack, snack.
Move away
I didn't bring Yea Seong for you.
Get out
get out.
Yeah
goodbye
- 5482.
- Yeah?
Why did you kill her?
You read it for me please
your voice is the best
wow, because of Yea Seong,
finally we are gonna see him reading.
Yeah, I never saw him
reading a book for 7 years
now..
Let me see..
There's a butterfly
you see? Right?
A butterfly was on my thigh
it was drawn on... before
oh there's only one butterfly, right?
Maverick, you know?
The butterfly met a rat
so..bring it on
brother, brother, brother...
what the heck is "bring it on" and "maverick"?
It's not a good words for kid
what? Are you bat-blind?
What's wrong with you ..
Brother, there's no illiterate guy
in this generation, not in 2013.
- There is no man who can't read.
- I know, go ahead!
Even a dog, monkey, dolphin, orangutan and chimpanzee
can graduate from highschool after 3 months studying
I know, who said they can't!?
Illiterate? Is that a human?
Do you know how many
percentage is illiterate!?
There is no illiterate one
here in the room, brother.
When you say something,
know the facts first.
- Okay, okay
- Where the hell is a guy who doesn't know how to read!?
That's fucking idiot!
I see! Don't be upset, it's your turn now.
- What the...
- Who the hell doesn't know how to read!?
- On cold winter, there's butterfly from the egg...
- Brother...
I want it too.
Want what?
Listen, Yea Seong also got in here
I also my want my baby here!!
What the hell..
Is it the care of a day nursery here!?
You dumb
you can't get out, the baby will be born
you must be going crazy
Look, look at this.
21 weeks, after 21 weeks, she will be out
Look, read this you son
of a bitch, I won't read.
You don't know how to read, how to
deal with a baby you know nothing.
You fucking assholes.
- Why...
- You idi...
you really wanna her here?
Then..
You also get a death sentence too
of course, I do remember
don't even mention about the day
emergency alert from the dawn.
It wasn't just a daughter of police,
It was the daughter of Commissioner!
Secretary of Interior even
ordered to close the case in a week!
- Detective Park
- Brother!
Can I see the case of Lee Yong Goo?
No, brother..
Let me see
I am a policeman of the public, brother!
Are you sure this is the
statement by Lee Yong Goo!?
I don't know, I'm not the guy who got it
I need a copy of this
brother, I can't let you copy
- then I will just take this!?
- Brother, please!
I said no..
You wanna see me getting fired!?
You are doing this again really!?
Because of that son of a bitches,
Jin Wook got kidnapped and murdered! Huh!?
Wow! It's much smaller
than my telephone in my house!
- Is that real?
- Of course, It's fake.
It's real one!
Can I touch?
Don't press "send"
what is "send"?
Mr.!! Thank you Young Woon!
Yeah, that's right
you can do it better!
- Next, Apple.
- Apple.
- He's good after all the practices.
- Good boy
"ple"
put a line down
down
down down there.
This one is "lion", LION!
Idiot
apple
"p" in "ple"!
You don't even know letter P!?
How many days are you doing this huh?
You fucking idiot
letter P.
P!!!!!
Don't you pee? Pee ~
- even he knows it.
- You don't pee? Pee?
He doesn't even pee, huh!?
- Yes!!
- Correct!
You son of a bitch
you can even study highschool stuff now.
If I just knew how to read,
I would be a prosecutor.
Don't you think they took the letter huh?
He's right
Women can't move easily when they are pregnant.
You think she has enough energy to write a letter?
Don't worry, It's fine
look
what the hell
what the!!
Where the heck did you get this!?
I borrowed it from Young Woon.
Isn't It a toy!?
This isn't allowed here..but..
- Try.
- Yes.
- Put the antenna out.
- Antenna, antenna
I think th..t..h..thi..this isn't working.
It's not working.
- It's weird.
- Why?
- YeaSeong, is this...
- Close to the window, window!
- I got a signal, signal!!
- Hello?
He..hello?
Who the hell are you?
- Hell...
- Did you call me to receive the fax!?
It works, It's working
I am on the phone.
- BongSuk.
- Honey...
I gave a birth myself
stop crying, talk
what the hell, It's not working again.
This makes me crazy. Fuck!
Work, work, work.
Why the hell isn't it working?
Hey hey hey hey!
Go away!
I got a signal! Signal!
- You hear me, honey?
- Signal, signal!
Baby's crying, baby!!
- Ask the baby to speak to dad.
- Dad?
Baby, baby!
It's me, dad
she's smiling, smile!!
- He's got all fingers and toes?
- Of course, he's a sleepy-head just like you.
- Yeah? Is it he or she?
- Daughter!
Brother, It's a daughter
daughter, she..
He's screwed up
- are you happy honey?
- Yes
where are you?
I'm so tired alone
- listen, I can't talk to you longer.
- What?
- Battery is weak now.
- Honey, what about her name!?
- Name for her.
- Name, name, name...
Name, name, name...
You got Bong in your name,
Seon in "fairy" ( Korean ).
Ah!! Bong Seon. Shin Bong Seon.
Wrong, It's too wrong
what the heck is Shin Bong Seon.
- I love you honey.
- I love you too, Seon yeo!
Done? It's off
thank you
hey, stop crying, stop
by the way, Young Woon?
Is he your boyfriend?
- Is he handsome?
- Yes, he's reliable.
You are also reliable to me.
You are most reliable to me
look at this
you can't see my hand!
That's good.
Mr. Lee Yong Goo
- hello.
- You got a schedule for the next trial
this one..
This trial is verdict
- you, be prepared.
- Yeah, prepared
hey Yong Goo.
It's not time for you to jog now
hey Lee Yong Goo
that fucking crazy man
fell down? Then what?
She just died like that!?
Even I think it over and over,
it doesn't make sense.
- Lee Yong Goo.
- Yeah.
How was she lying down?
She was just lying down
I was scared
bro
I think there's another guy
who tried to steal
- the bag and killed her.
- Bullshit!
- When you got there, she was lying down like this?
- Yeah.
- Without any reason?
- Do you feel dying?
- Shit, my arm arm arm
- it fucking hurts.
- Right?
Arm
usually when a person falls down,
they use their arm to support the body
but in her, her backhead got broken
why backhead!?
- The bag, bag! SailorMoon bag!
- Yes!!
Sailor Moon bag..
Like this.
- Yeah, it was the bag!
- When did it happen? What's the date of it!?
- Feburary 27, 1:15 lunch shift.
- Okay, okay.
- Feburary 27..
- On 27th!? It's my son-in-law's marriage!
- What the fuck.
- Water isn't coming out
what the!! fix it!!
Pipe got frozed, we weren't
able to take a shower!
- Yeah, he's right! Temp -18!
- Yes.
She slipped on ice!
Yeah! That's it!
In market, there are
full of ices
how about the scar on her forehead?
I heard there was a brick
- yeah... there was a brick.
- A brick?
Yes, yes.
If the girl fell down like this
what a crazy...
how the hell is this..
Everything is clear now
but why did you take off her pants?
First, loosen the belt
- helps blood circulation.
- Blood circulation!?
- Yes.
- Then why did you choke her?
I didn't choke her neck
second,
give a pressure on the chest
next
free airway
cover one's nose
12 times in a minute,
give the air in.
Okay, you are doing great.
Next?
Wake up, get up
wake up, are you okay?
- Wake up.
- Good
you need to shake him
so that he can wake up
so... next?
Pinch or slap
- sir, you don't need to slap him for real.
- He's alive now
- what the..
- Yes, he's alive..alive..
So... everybody, after me
repeat..
CPR!
- CPR?
- Yeah..that's right.
CPR, It's right..right..
Dead one is a daughter of the attorney general
they can't afford the long time to investigate
guys from up there will give a pressure a lot
guys from down wants a change to promote.
Who can't see this situation, poor YongGoo
went there, got suspected of a guilt
fuck, we will do help YongGoo's trial!
I have an objection
these witnesses are testifying
what hasn't been proven.
The statements they just testified,
there are no lies in there.
Is that right?
- Mr. Choi Young Ho.
- Yes, sir
what's your job?
- Hallelujah, I'm a pastor.
- I'm talking about the past.
I...I don't know when are you talking about ..
It's just like a small group, we used to play a soccer and..
- You were a member of gang, right?
- Yes..
- Your honor, he is asking things that aren't...
- How about Choi Chang Soo?
Since I was young, I had a dream about,
a treasure and a treasure chest, deep in the sea
oh you are with seven previous convictions!?
I have objection.
The presecutor is abusing the witness's past
in this trial.
Rejected.
Gangster and a guy who has seven previous convitions
do they have credibilities?
Bro, no..I mean sir?
Do we have any law in criminal law
like "don't listen and believe
whatever gangster and swindlers say?"
- None, but...
- Look.
So, gangsters
always make bullshits?
Is there any law there like this!?
None..
I'm done with examination of a witness..
It's not Examination! It's a questioning!
Am I a student!!?
- Quiet!
- Sorry sir.
Lawyer, do you have any other witness?
As the prosecutor wanted, I have
one who never commited a crime,
but served this country with honor.
I call him as a witness
in Sungnam prison, security Chief, I'm Jang Min Ha
- as you know, there is a prisoner in our...
- How have you been doing?
I believe that you have 3 meals in a day,
you will exercise everyday,
and after 9 PM,
you will go to bed.
Sir..
I can't ask you this but..
I'm asking you to investigate again.
While we are investigating again,
someday the prisoner will be released from the prison, right?
Lee Yong Goo.
He's not the criminal
have you..
Lost a son or daughter before?
I have lost..
By my favorite prisoner..
The accused,
you kidnapped the girl Choi Ji Young
to revenge on the chief of the commissioner
Is that right?
Yeah... I followed.
SailorMoon bag
papa, just read exactly what they've wrote for you
- Yeah...
- Read.
Ji Young said
she will let me know where I can buy the sailormoon bag,
so I just followed
- good!
- You are doing great
have you took off the victim's pants
for sexual molestation?
Have you? Or not!?
Loosen the belt first to help blood circulation
- yes!
I can't recall what really happened.
Have you smashed her head
to kill her?
No... Ji Young fell down...
Look, Yong Goo. What did I say.
If you can't remember what to say?
I..
- I don't remember..
- Yes. That's how you do it!
I don't..I don't remember
- Happily.
Okay, good job!
- A brick fell on her head.
- Have you seen it happening?
- I haven't...
- What's wrong with you!
- Even if you haven't seen it, you should pretend!
- Then..
I was doing CPR...
Hey... Yong Goo... Yong Goo!
Do it in the morning, morning!
Yeah...
your
honor,
I..
Am..
An intellectually handicapped person
detectives..hit me ..
Without asking..
- Try to read it.
- What's this all about?
Famous line, so famous!
I am the one who wrote!
Sign on it, sign!
Don't you get it dirty
don't eat it!
They said if I make a fingerprint on the paper,
they will send me to YeaSeong and buy me SailorMoon bag
so these statements
are forged
perfect! Ended the case!
- Great
- Good job!
Mr. Lee Yong Goo!
- Yeah?
- National lawyer is here for you
come on
anything you wanna eat?
I can do those things..
"Break time."
- Chocolate?
- Yeah. Delicious "break time".
You got a daughter, Lee Yea Seong?
Yeah, Lee Yea Seong, daughter of Lee Yong Goo
Lee Yea Seong is pretty
- you listen to me.
- Yeah..
The daughter's father is the chief of the commissioner
- yeah..
You know polices?
Yeah... police
- scary..police.
- Yeah... the head of those scary men.
He's really mad now.
He might do something to your daughter
yeah..
Fucking annoying..
Lawyer
lawyer
this is..
A petition from the prisoners
this shit doesn't help.
Even though you are a national lawyer,
isn't it too much?
You think It will change with an effort?
Try to look at this
look at this!
Lee Yong Goo isn't enough smart
to write this!
You still think he's the criminal!?
For Yea Seong..
Stay awake, focus..
Yeah..
I will go home, home..
Don't you worry, you can go home.
- Okay?
- Yeah.
Ji Young said..
She will let me know
where to buy Sailor Moon bag
- tell the prosecutor everything, okay?
- Okay..
Word at a time
the accused, Lee Yong Goo
have you kidnapped Choi Ji Young
to revenge on the chief of the commissioner who hit you?
I mean
have you kidnapped Choi Ji Young?
You sacrifice yourself for Yea Seong
You know what I mean?
You are a father!
Have you smashed her on purpose
because she resisted
from the sexual molestation?
I am asking you again
have you smashed her head with a brick?
- The accused?
- Yeah?
- Answer me.
Be purged of sin
or else
I will do the same to your daughter
answer me.
Yeah??
Is it true that you smashed Choi Ji Young
who's resisting
on purpose?
I..I'm asking you again.
Have you smashed her head with a brick?
With a brick, have you smashed!?
- The accused!
- Yeah.
- Have you smashed!?
- Yes, I have ...Yes.
Yeah, I did it. It was me
Lee Yong Goo! What the hell are you saying
wake up!
Your honor,
the accused is having a problem meantally, emotionally
quiet
lawyer! Do something!
- I killed, I did.
- Lee Yong Goo, Are you crazy!?
You killed no one!!
Because of me
because of me, she died
I'm sorry.
- I'm sorry.
- What are you sorry for!?
Nobody is saying sorry to you
what the hell are you saying for!!?
Yea Seong, help her
my Yea Seong..
I did it, Help Yea Seong.
What the heck are you doing!?
You are a lawyer
lawyer isn't for this!!
Detectives in that time
they took only witness's statements,
they completely ignored the accused's statement
even if he denied it
Lee Yong Goo's statement had been forged,
they interrogated with violence
forced, threathened him
Forged... Also
the scar on Choi Ji Young's
forehead isn't the main reason.
But the proof that the broken backhead is the
main reason why she died had been also ignored.
Lee Yong Goo's statement which is submitted by prosecutor
includes that he choked
her neck but
autopsy result that proves
nothing was found of any pressure on her neck
had also been... ignored...
lawyer, last defense.
Your honor,
I ask for favorable arrangements
please.
The prosecutor,
demand a penalty.
Since the accused had admitted..
We demand
a death sentence
for Lee Yong Goo
your honor
the investigation was focused on proving if he's guilty or not
without considering all the situations he's got.
It was defintely
a unreasonable investigation.
They ignored a basic principle
which is presumption of innocence
the fact that the accused is an intellectually handicapped person and
the fact the accused loves his daughter so much,
they abused them
to give up all the situations he had
for his... daughter
for the expediency of investigative authority,
- He is falsely accused..
- We,
the justice department,
since the accused admitted all the crimes,
we come to a definite decision
that the demand of the prosecutor,
a death sentence for Lee Yong Goo
the accused Lee Yong Goo
is given a death sentence
thank you
I did it all wrong..I..
Help Yea Seong. Yea Seong...
I'm sorry.
That's why I, the lawyer
am here to clear his name
from the false charge
from a sentence of death
to make things ..
All clear for him..
The lady will also send me in piano academy
yeah... Piano.
Mr's house, they even have a Piano.
Dad, I will play a piano for you later
Yeah... Piano is good... Piano.
Dad.
Dad, you are not a bad guy?
- Mr. Lee Yong Goo.
- Yeah.
- Bye bye.
- Bye...
I told you.
It's good to cook in the house
unlike..
Much better to buy from the restaurants
this is so annoying..
For Yea Seong,
It feels like It's a festive season today
look, this is what Yea Seong made
dark one is better, right?
You also ..
Yea Seong, Yea Seong.
Hi dad.
Dad how are you doing?
- Is it a letter from Yea Seong?
- Letter from Yea Seong..
- Boom!!!
- Wow, 100!
Yea Seong... 100..
Great job, Yea Seong!!
When she gets older
I should let her try to be a model or actress
bullshit
the baby looks so funny
- that dude is...
- Too honest.
Sorry
(can you hear me)
chi..
Ef...
C...H... I..
E...F...
How many hours more do you need!
C...H...
I heard there will be a talent show
for prisoners.
Shouldn't we prepare for it?
Who's barking here!?
If we win the first, do they let us walk away!?
Yes, they will let us walk away.
One night outing with family
really!?
- Yea Seong.
- What should we do? Sing in chorus?
Let's sing..
- SailorMoon.
- Yeah, let's try sailormoon.
So childish.
Chief, this special pardon in chirstmas,
so many of them ..
Is it because of the end of the presiden
I guess so..
We got so many ..to send..
Excuse me?
We got a schedule for 5482
December 23.
- Spider.
- Loud.
- Louder.
- Spider.
- How about this one?
What?
This one..
That's not what I can't..
Decide myself..
I need a permission first
from the principal.
This will be the last.
Yes?
Last day for Yea Seong to see her father..
Please..
Please allow..
What the fuck..
It's been only few days after the trial,
execution of a death penalty!? what the fuck..
We need to protest about this
even if the trial went that way,
This is totally against the law
what the hell ..order..
I should go first than him..
So many guys to go first
in this prison
we can't send YongGoo like this..
Hey Chun Ho.
This is to save a life
how's that sound?
Give me your area
- One.
What the heck
two
wor..wo..w..working?
Go back to work, work
you heard?
If you think a guy behind the curtain is your father,
any prisoners?
Make it work
this is to save one's life!
Yes, sir
- what happened to our dude?
- It takes longer, it's fucking big.
He isn't your father, I guarantee, right?
Why are you up here?
All of fathers in this world,
they are all my father
cheer up!
Late night, late night
there's a man from the sky...
Is everything under the control?
Brother, Yea Seong's teacher is also with me
don't worry about it.
Dad, hand.
Hold my hand.
Hold her hand now! Now!
Hold
- Go, go, go.
- Let's go.
Yong Goo, faster, faster!
Get off! Get off!
Get off right now!
- Take them out.
- Out, out, out.
Get in now, now now!
- Release the rope!
- Okay.
- Dad, we are flying.
- Flying, flying..
They look so small.
- It shouldn't cross the wall..
- Chief, that...
- we are flying like a bird.
- Yeah... flying, flying
- Bye bye.
- Get them! Get!
Block the way! Block!
Look at that dad!
They are all dancing
what the heck are you doing there?
- Hello, sir?
- Yeah..
- Bye bye.
- What a sunset! So beautiful sunset
yes, It is..
- Bye bye.
- Bye...
Look! Dad!
- Beautiful view.
- Dad, are we going home?
- Yes, we are going home.
- Yehey!
- Yea Seong.
- Yes, dad?
- Don't forget.
- Forget what?
Today
and your dad.
- Yea Seong, eat a lot... delicious?
- Yes, delicious
delicious.
- Yea Seong, eat beans, bean.
- Bong Sik, prepare.
Yes, brother..
Wow, cake!
Blow... 1, 2, 3!
Nice!
Happy Birthday!
- Gift.
- Thank you.
- Draw lots of beautiful things on it.
- Thank you
practice writing on it
this is my gift
thank you
how about Yong Goo? Gift?
- Big.
- Shit, so big.
What's in it?
- Wow! SailorMoon bag.
- Wow.
- Dad.
- Yeah...
thank you for
the birthday, dad.
What are you doing?
Say something to her
thank you
for being
born as
a daughter of Dad..
What the hell is in this soup!?
Shit..
Are you crying Mr.?
Mr. isn't crying
let me see... Yea Seong..
Look
what are you doing?
Stay still!
Tickling
see you soon
bye bye
thank you
thank you.
Dad..
Can't come with you.
Yea Seong can do it
- all alone?
- Yeah.
Dad, you can also go alone right?
Yeah.
I will visit you with so many 100 scores
I will come to see you
so go there and
don't worry about me, okay?
Yeah.
Dad, merry christmas.
Merry Christmas to Yea Seong as well
bye bye.
- Yea Seong...
- Yes.
- Goodbye dad.
- Good bye Yea Seong
bye
bye bye Yea Seong.
Yea Seong, take care!
Bye.
Yea Seong, bye bye!!
Dad.
Dad!!
Dad!!!
Yea Seong
help me
I'm sorry.
Dad, what's wrong?
Help me
I'm sorry please
save me please
- don't cry.
- Dad, you can cry here
I will come and visit you again
don't cry dad
don't say "save me" dad.
Dad.
Yea Seong!!
- I'm sorry please.
- Dad.
I'm sorry
I'm really sorry, sorry, sir.
I'm sorry, help me
I will never do it again sir.
Dad
I'm sorry.
It's my fault..
I'm sorry
- I'm really sorry.
- Dad.
- Please help me.
Today, the accused Lee Yong Goo,
no,
my father I really loved.
For my angel father.
I, lawyer
will speak the last.
With a name of justice..
Forgive..
My..
Father..
The accused Lee Yong Goo
was an intellectually handicapped person,
tricky and
violence of detectives,
we take the statements that they forget
the statements.
It also shows..
The evidences that Lee Yong Goo killed the girl and molested
is not also enough
to sentence to a death
we, court,
remand after reversal to the first trial,
demand a reinvestigation.
The jury acquit him
we find him innocent.
- Yea Seong.
- Hi...
It's dad, dad. Yea Seong.
Dad is here!
Dad?
- Hello.
- Hi, Yea Seong.
Hi dad
- Bye.
- Good bye, Yea Seong.
- Yea Seong, I love you, goodbye.
- Bye..
Yea Seong.
- Take care, eat a lot!
- Bye.
- I love you, I love you Yea Seong.
- I love you.
I love you, dad.
Bye