♪ I was busy thinking
'bout boys ♪
♪ Boys, boys ♪
♪ I was busy dreaming
'bout boys ♪
♪ Boys, boys ♪
♪ I was busy thinking 'bout ♪
♪ I was busy
thinking 'bout ♪
♪ I was busy thinking 'bout ♪
♪ I was busy
thinking 'bout ♪
♪ I was busy thinking 'bout ♪
♪ I was busy
thinking 'bout ♪
♪ I was busy thinking
'bout boys ♪
♪ I need that bad boy
to do me right on a Friday ♪
♪ And I need that good one
to wake me up on a Sunday ♪
♪ That one from work can
come over on Monday night ♪
♪ I want 'em all,
I want 'em all ♪
♪ I'm sorry that
I missed your party ♪
♪ I wish I had
a better excuse like ♪
♪ "I had to trash
the hotel lobby" ♪
♪ But I was busy thinking
'bout boys, boys, boys ♪
♪ Boys, boys ♪
♪ I was busy
dreaming 'bout... ♪
(laughter, lively chatter)
Fuck her.
- Fuck her.
- Yeah. Fuck her.
- This is how business is done, man.
I mean, this is... well, it's
just a round of fucking golf.
You'd think we were
taking clients out
- to a strip club.
- Well... well...
Which we can't even do anymore.
PAUL: Exactly.
We can't even do that anymore
- since the Christmas party last year.
- Okay.
I think it's because
the golf club
doesn't let women play there.
- So?
- (snickers)
So it means we're having
client meetings without her.
Look, she should just focus
on closing her own shit
instead of whining about how
we're doing better than her.
Jesus.
Oh, hey,
would you look at that?
- Good God Almighty.
- JIM: Yikes.
PAUL: Why don't you get
some dignity, sweetheart?
You know, they put themselves
in danger, girls like that.
If she's not careful,
someone's gonna take advantage.
Especially the kind of guys
in this club.
(groans quietly)
She's kind of hot.
PAUL:
(scoffs) A hot fucking mess.
(chuckles)
Hey. Let's talk to Brian.
I think he might be
amenable to the idea
if we all present
a very nice...
I mean, that is just
asking for it.
♪ Say you like me
'cause I'm not... ♪
PAUL:
Oh, look at that.
You know, like, you'd think
you'd learn by that age, right?
Where even are her friends?
Just kind of ran off somewhere?
Leaving her laying around
for anyone to pick up.
Sounds like a challenge, Paul.
Yeah? Maybe.
- I'll go over.
- BOTH (laughing): Oh!
- Whoa!
- PAUL: Jerry!
My God, I didn't know
- you had it in you.
- To see if she's okay.
- Yeah, no. Of course.
- JIM: Yeah, sure.
- Go for it, big fella.
- Uh-huh. Yeah. Why don't you
- go see, make sure she's okay.
- We're pulling for you.
- (slurring): Oh, my God...
- Hey.
You okay?
♪ Stay focused,
using your hypnosis... ♪
What are you looking for?
Phone.
- Uh-huh.
- It's not here.
It's got to be here.
I just had it.
JERRY:
Uh...
You think maybe you left it
in the bathroom or something?
- No.
- (sighs)
♪ Introspect, take a moment ♪
- ♪ Realize that you're not my type ♪
- (groaning)
♪ Not trying to
get noticed... ♪
You gonna be okay?
♪ Using your hypnosis,
but I think that... ♪
Oh, yeah.
How you gonna get home?
(laughing)
Ride... ride app.
Yeah. Yeah.
I think you might need
a phone for that.
- (laughing): Oh, no.
- Yeah.
I know.
Oh, no.
(sighs)
Okay, look, I'm, um...
I'm headed out anyway,
so I can drop you off.
- No.
- It's totally fine.
It's not a problem.
- Really.
- No.
What are you gonna do?
It's fine. Come on.
It's not a problem.
Let's go.
(straining):
There you go.
You got it?
All right, just hold on
to the railing.
- Yeah? You okay?
- Oh, my God. (chuckles)
♪ Candlelight
and soul forever ♪
♪ A dream of
you and me together... ♪
(inhales deeply)
(blows)
Come on.
I just had my car cleaned.
She's fine.
No, I'm not.
I'm not gonna throw up.
I don't think.
No? (chuckles)
There you have it, sir. See?
She's not...
she's not gonna throw up.
Whoo-hoo!
♪ We can achieve it ♪
♪ Come a little bit
closer, baby ♪
Uh...
♪ Get it on, get it on ♪
♪ 'Cause tonight... ♪
My apartment is
a few blocks from here.
Would you want to have a drink
before hitting the hay?
Mm...
It's literally right here.
You want to have,
like, one beer?
Yeah.
Could you take us to 242
Raleigh Drive instead, please?
It's a couple blocks.
(sighs) Just put the address
in the app.
(muttering):
Put the address in the app.
JERRY:
Kumquat liqueur.
Here we go, milady.
Hey, sorry about
my friends at the bar.
They're... they're assholes.
(slurring):
Oh, it's okay.
There you go.
You got it.
Do you live alone here?
No, but, uh, my roommate's
out of town, so don't worry.
- Right.
- Yeah.
(slurps)
- (sighs): Ah.
- Ugh, that's disgusting.
(both chuckling)
You're so beautiful.
You know what?
Do you mind if I just...
- Mm.
- You've got a little smudge.
There, right there.
Wow.
(exhales sharply)
(inhales deeply)
- I need to lie down.
- Oh.
- (sets glass on table)
- Yeah, of course.
Right this way.
- Don't go to sleep.
- What?
Gosh, you're so pretty.
- Wait.
- (shushes, chuckles)
- What are you...
- It's okay.
Hey, you're safe.
What are you...?
Hey, it's okay.
- You're safe. Shh.
- What are you doing?
Mm. My God, your body.
What are you doing?
Hmm?
(Jerry panting)
What are you doing?
Wait.
What are you...?
(kissing)
(normal voice):
Hey.
I said, what are you doing?
♪ Hi ♪
- ♪ Hi ♪
♪ We're your weather girls ♪
- ♪ Uh-huh ♪
♪ And have we got news for you ♪
♪ Humidity's rising ♪
♪ Uh, rising ♪
♪ Barometer's getting low ♪
♪ How low, girl? ♪
♪ According to all sources ♪
♪ What sources now? ♪
♪ The street's
the place to go ♪
♪ Well, you better hurry up ♪
♪ 'Cause tonight,
for the first time ♪
♪ The first time ♪
- ♪ Just about half past 10:00 ♪
- ♪ Half past 10:00 ♪
♪ For the first time
in history ♪
♪ It's gonna start raining men ♪
♪ Start raining men ♪
♪ It's raining men ♪
♪ Hallelujah ♪
♪ Amen ♪
♪ I'm gonna go out ♪
♪ To run and let myself get ♪
♪ Absolutely soaking wet ♪
MAN:
Oh, walk of shame!
(men laughing)
Good time last night,
sweetheart?
There it goes straight up!
- There you go!
- (wolf whistle)
- Uh-huh.
- Get yourself some Plan B!
- Uh-oh!
- (laughter)
- How much, baby? How much?
- Fuck that!
- What's wrong, baby?
- What's up?
Can't take a joke?
Jesus, lady, what's up?
Come on, why don't you give us
a little smile, huh?
- Stop staring.
- What the fuck you staring at?
Stop it.
You can't take a joke?
Okay. Fuck you, then.
♪ God bless Mother Nature ♪
♪ She's a single woman, too ♪
♪ She took off to Heaven ♪
♪ And did what she had to do. ♪
- (clock ticking)
- (silverware clinking quietly)
STANLEY: Didn't hear you
come in last night.
Everything all right?
(birds cawing outside)
I had to work late.
STANLEY:
Hmm.
I thought the coffee house
closed at 9:00.
We had to do inventory.
SUSAN: You have to do a lot
of inventory at that place.
You should speak to the manager.
I will.
GAIL:
You know, I was talking
to Graham earlier,
and he says there's a position
opening up at head office.
And don't freak out,
but I want you to know
I recommended you for it.
- Hi. Can...
- Why would you do that?
'Cause you're stinking up
the joint
with your sad little face.
But I like it here.
No, you don't.
No, I don't, but I like you.
And I like...
Hello? (chuckles)
...working in
a customer-facing role.
- Great. Can I get some...
- No.
- Cassie.
- Don't "Cassie" me.
I'm fine. Gail, really.
(door opens, bell jingles)
Johnny said he saw you
at The Fallout last week.
Said you were completely
hammered and on your own.
He was a little worried. I know
it's none of my business...
He must have seen someone else.
I've never been there.
Okay.
- (crowd chatter, laughter)
- (dance music playing)
MAN:
I like your pigtails.
CASSANDRA:
(chuckles) Thank you.
MAN:
Hey, you want another drink?
CASSANDRA:
Um, I don't think...
MAN: Hey, let me get you one.
Vodka cranberry
- for the lady, please.
- (Cassandra chuckling)
MAN:
Hey. How old are you?
- CASSANDRA: Um...
- MAN: Old enough, right?
- (men laughing)
- (Cassandra chuckles)
("Nothing's Gonna Hurt You
Baby" by Donna Missal playing)
♪ Whispered something
in your ear ♪
♪ It was a perverted thing... ♪
- (bell jingles)
- Can I get a coffee, please?
Mm-hmm.
♪ But I said it anyway ♪
You want milk?
♪ Made you smile
and look away... ♪
What?
Cassandra? (chuckles)
- Yeah.
- Ryan.
Cooper. We were in class
together at Forrest Med School.
Second-year neurology,
Dr. Hadid's class.
Oh. Yeah.
Ryan. Hi.
God. Why are you working here?
Or...
I didn't mean... (chuckles)
That was rude. I didn't...
You didn't mean,
what am I doing working
in a shitty coffee shop?
Yeah. No. I just meant,
you know, given...
- There's no getting out of this, is there?
- Nuh-uh.
I'm gonna leave.
Can I leave and then come back?
And I can do it...
I can do it again
- and be better next time.
- You want milk?
Pardon?
In your coffee.
No.
But, uh, you can spit in it
if you want.
I-I deserve that.
(Ryan chuckles softly)
♪ To that silly '90s R & B ♪
Thank you.
♪ When we have... ♪
Do you want to go out with me?
What?
On a... date.
Seriously?
I just spat in your coffee.
♪ A hazy shower scene ♪
♪ Nothing's gonna hurt you,
baby... ♪
And then I like
to finish always
with a little dab of gloss
just to give it
a kind of wet texture.
Just dab in the middle...
and on the top.
- And there you go.
- (electronic ding)
>- Perfect blow job lips.
- (electronic chiming)
(chuckles) So,
don't forget to like
and subscribe.
Thank you, guys, for following.
- I love you. Bye.
- (electronic chiming)
("Petite Fille Amour"
by Jacqueline Taïeb playing)
NEIL:
Seriously, you got to read it.
Consider the Lobster is
one of the fucking greats, man.
Cracked my head open
like a, uh...
like a lobster claw.
("Petite Fille Amour"
continues over speakers)
(snorting)
(sniffs, exhales)
You know, I'm actually
writing a novel.
Well, kind of,
'cause I'm such a fucking
perfectionist, you know?
It's just taking me forever.
I just keep going over it
and over it and over it
in my head,
just picking at it like a scab.
It's about, uh, I guess, like,
what it's like to be a guy
right now, you know?
Like, what it's like to be
a guy in the world.
Just this gritty,
low-life, fucked-up love story.
And it all takes place
in New York
over the course of one night.
You know what?
I'm gonna stop talking about it.
I don't want to jinx it.
You do coke, right?
- (slurring): Mm, not really.
- Oh, come on.
(inhales deeply)
I got work in the morning.
Oh, whatever. So do I.
(grunts)
Here.
Get right.
No.
Just put your nose up to this.
No, here. Maybe just...
(Cassandra groans quietly)
Okay, that didn't work.
Hey. Yum, yum, yum, yum, yum.
There you go.
Oh, my God,
you are so, so pretty.
But why are you wearing
all that makeup?
Do you mind me asking?
I never understood why women
wear so much makeup.
It's like, you guys are so much
more beautiful without it.
It's like, guys don't even like
that kind of stuff, you know?
It's just this
soul-sucking system
meant to oppress women,
and it's fucked up.
(Neil snorting)
(sniffing, exhales)
I want to see you.
- (sniffs) The real you.
- (thunder rumbling)
With all your freckles
and your imperfections.
(gags)
I don't feel good.
Could you get me
a glass of water?
Yeah. Sure.
(cabinet opens, glass clinks)
- (faucet running)
- (thunder rumbling)
(footsteps approaching)
(sighs):
Are you fucking kidding me?
Hey.
Hey, you.
Hey!
(chuckles):
Hey.
There you are.
You fell asleep.
(softly):
Good girl.
Feel better?
No.
You know, I, um...
I nearly didn't
come out tonight.
And I am so glad that I did.
I feel such a connection
to you.
Could you call me a cab?
You just got here.
- No, I need to go home.
- No.
Don't go.
Stay.
My God, you are so...
I need to go.
No, you don't want to go home.
- I need to go home.
- (thunder rumbling)
(inhales sharply)
(Neil panting quietly)
(exhales heavily)
- (normal voice): Hey, Neil.
- Yeah?
I said I need to go home.
Holy shit. Whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is this?
Are you some kind
of psycho or something?
Why do you say that?
- I just thought that you were...
- Drunk?
- Yeah.
- Really drunk?
Fuck.
Yeah.
Well, I'm not.
But that's good, isn't it?
- I think you should leave.
- Oh.
- Now you want me to leave?
- No.
I just... I'm really high.
Like, I'm really fucking high
right now.
I don't know what I'm doing.
(inhales sharply)
I think you should go.
But a second ago, you were
determined for me to stay.
You were pretty insistent,
actually.
I'm a nice guy.
Are you?
I thought we had
a connection, I guess.
A connection?
Okay.
What do I do for a living?
Sorry.
Maybe that one's too hard.
How old am I?
How long have I lived
in the city?
What are my hobbies?
What's my name?
All right.
All right, fuck,
I get your fucking point.
What do you want from me?
To say that I'm an asshole?
Fine, I'm a fucking asshole.
- Whoa.
- (thunder crashes)
Why are you so freaked out,
Neil?
You really need to calm down.
At least you didn't try
to have sex with me
while I was passed out.
You do get points for that.
A few guys, meh...
eh, they don't mind so much.
But you woke me up before
putting your fingers inside me.
- That was sweet.
- What are you trying to say?
That I'm, like,
a predator or something?
I don't know. Are you?
I am a nice guy.
You keep saying that.
You're not as rare as you think.
You know how I know?
No.
Because every week,
I go to a club,
and every week, I act like
I'm too drunk to stand.
- And every...
- (grunts, shudders)
...fucking week,
a nice guy like you
comes over to see if I'm okay.
You want to fuck me still?
(whispers):
No, thank you, ma'am.
CASSANDRA:
Hmm.
No one ever does.
Careful next time
you go out, Neil.
Your novel sounds terrible,
by the way.
(door opens, closes)
(sighs heavily)
Night, Nina.
- (birds chirping outside)
- (clock ticking)
What's this?
Mom, what's this?
What do you mean?
This gift.
It's your birthday, Cassie.
Oh.
Yeah.
What kind of...
kind of person
forgets their 30th birthday?
Oh, sweetheart, come on.
Don't...
Don't, Stanley.
You know, please, don't.
CASSANDRA:
It was just a mistake, Mom.
You know I'm terrible
with dates.
It's not a big deal.
SUSAN:
Not a big deal?
You-you just forgot
your birthday.
You don't want to have a party?
You don't want to see
your friends?
You know I don't have
any friends, Mom.
Don't joke about it. Don't.
Do you know how strange this is?
You, you're still living
here at home.
Working in that
stupid coffee shop
since you and Nina
dropped out of med school.
You're out all night long
doing God only knows what.
- STANLEY: Okay.
- SUSAN: And you...
You don't have any boyfriend.
You don't have any friends.
Mom, you should have saved
all that for my birthday card.
Why don't we just let the kid
celebrate however she wants?
- Okay?
- SUSAN: All my friends, they ask about you.
I-I-I don't know
what to tell them.
I-I don't know
what happened here.
I don't... (sobs)
(crying)
Why don't you just open
your present there, Cass?
Okay?
Go ahead.
SUSAN:
Yeah.
Oh, I hope you like it.
Thank you.
- (bell jingles)
- GAIL: Whoa.
- CASSANDRA: Yeah.
- That's direct.
A real kick in the cunt.
- Is it a nice suitcase, at least?
- Oh, yeah.
It's definitely the fanciest
"get the fuck out of our house"
metaphor I've received so far.
So, why don't you?
- What?
- Get the fuck out of their house.
- Just, I don't know, go on Zillow or...
- (door opens)
Single White Female some girl.
Get a basement room at some
weird guy's house, anything.
- (door closes)
- I can't afford it, Gail.
Not on what you pay me.
Not even a weird guy's basement.
So take this other job, then.
Take any job.
Are you firing me?
Maybe I should.
Look, you're making
the assumption
that I want any of it.
If I wanted a boyfriend
and a yoga class
and a house and kids
and a job my mom could
brag about, I'd have done it.
It would take me ten minutes.
I don't want it.
But you must want something.
- (door opens)
- RYAN: Hey.
- (Ryan clears throat)
- Oh. You.
- Hi.
- One coffee, hold the spit.
(Ryan chuckling)
She spat in my coffee last time.
I'm back because, um,
I think you gave me a...
a fake number the other day.
Mm, that doesn't sound like me.
I know.
So I spent a few hours composing
a, like, very witty,
very romantic text,
and then I sent that text to
an oil rig worker called Red.
- Was he into it?
- Surprisingly into it.
It was, like,
immediately inappropriate.
But it's not gonna work out
'cause of the oil rig,
so I thought I'd try you again.
I just heard a phone ring
in the back.
- No, you didn't.
- I most definitely heard
a phone ring in the back.
(chuckles)
She has to take a few
imaginary calls a day.
(Gail laughing)
Um, look, if you're not
into this, totally get it.
I'm not really looking to date
anyone at the moment.
Right. Yeah.
Me, neither.
Would you... be interested
in a friendship
and I'm secretly pining for you
the whole time?
(Cassandra chuckles)
Dating's horrible.
Everyone's horrible.
Okay, I went on a date
last month with a woman
who wanted to euthanize
the homeless.
You went on a date with my mom?
(laughs) Look,
I always liked you
at med school.
Okay?
I genuinely like you,
and I can't stop thinking about
you spitting in my coffee.
So go to lunch with me
this weekend.
Please. If you don't like it,
we can have a safe word
and you can leave,
no questions asked.
ROBERT MITCHUM:
Not that you mind the killings.
Your book is full of killings.
(gearbox grinding)
But there are things
you do hate, Lord.
Perfume-smelling things.
Lacy things.
- Things with curly hair.
- (Stanley snoring)
- (door opens)
- (footsteps)
Hey.
You're all dressed up.
Where you going?
I'm going out for lunch.
With who?
A friend.
STANLEY:
Cassie.
You look very pretty, honey.
Thank you, Dad.
- (door closes)
- (chuckling)
CASSANDRA (laughing):
Where... where did she get
- a skeleton's hand from?
- She got it...
It was her, uh...
it was her grandfather's.
No. It was... She got it
from the staff room,
but the worst part is
she looked me in the eye,
pulled it out
and then waved it at me.
(both laughing)
And I am done.
And I'm wondering why
I told that story.
Hey. There is nothing more
romantic than a disturbed woman
pulling a skeleton's hand
out of her vagina.
That's true.
That's very true.
No one ever pulls anything
out of anywhere where I work.
Right, so you didn't want to...
- What?
- Carry on with med school or...
No.
Really? Why not?
I wanted to do something else.
Why?
(laughs) I don't know.
You were so good, though.
You knew everything.
- You...
- I didn't know everything.
You did.
You were incredible.
I was... I was awful. I...
Remember I removed the
wrong kidney from my cadaver?
And look at you now...
operating on children.
Yes. I got better.
Thank God. But you, you were
way ahead of everybody.
You-you would have been
a great doctor.
Just didn't want it enough,
I guess.
Um...
You want to get coffee
or something?
We, um... we have some time
before the movie.
I can tell you about the guy
who got his dick
trapped in a tambourine.
- (laughing)
- Oh, my God.
(Cassandra laughing)
Do you think people think
you're my daughter from behind?
(chuckles)
'Cause of the height.
- The height, I'm saying.
- (laughs): No.
It's like a fear
I have in public,
- if I'm with a woman.
- (laughs)
My fear is that, like,
if I kiss her,
like, people will be like,
"Stop kissing that child."
- I shouldn't yell this part, but...
- (laughs): No.
I mean, try not being
so tall, maybe.
- Don't be tall.
- Maybe, yeah.
- Yeah.
- It's kind of flashy.
(Ryan chuckles)
Whoa. This is...
this is a weird coincidence.
What?
I think...
No.
Yeah, this is my apartment.
(Ryan chuckles)
What a weird, weird coincidence.
Yeah. Do you want to...
I mean, we're here.
Do you want to go up,
have a drink or...
Sure. Why not?
Too soon. Sorry. I wasn't...
No, let's go upstairs.
I don't want to go up
if you don't want to...
I-I misread things.
I'll-I'll drive you home.
You know what?
You're at your place.
I can call a cab.
- Are you sure?
- Sure.
Okay, I feel like
I fucked this up.
No, it's not you.
(birds cawing)
(sighs)
WOMAN (over P.A.): Pediatric
assistant to admitting.
- (door opens)
- (quiet chatter, phone ringing)
Need a pediatric assistant
to admitting, please.
- I'll let you know.
- Okay. Thank you.
Cassie, what...
(chuckles)
What are you...
what are you doing here?
Um...
I just came to pick up
my herpes medication.
You have herpes, too.
That saves us
an awkward conversation.
(both laugh)
WOMAN (over P.A.):
Dr. Dinkins, please dial 3751.
Dr. Dinkins, 3751.
So, I...
So, I'd like to see you again.
Oh.
- If that's cool.
- Yeah.
But we'd need to take it slow.
I understand...
Of course. Totally. I...
I can take it slow.
I can barely move,
if you'd like.
(chuckles softly)
Thank you.
Yeah. Sorry.
(chuckles softly)
I could write a poem.
- (laughs)
- This is awesome.
Uh, what are you doing? You want
to get dinner or something?
Are you working?
Well, no. Um...
(quietly):
He has leukemia, and, uh,
there's really nothing
I can do for him.
- Oh, my God.
- It's-it's over.
- I'm kidding. My shift's over.
- (laughing): Oh, my God.
- I'll grab my stuff, okay?
- Okay.
Okay.
(clears throat)
Don't leave.
- (Ryan clears throat)
- (laughs)
("Can't Help the Way I Feel"
by Lily & Madeleine playing)
- (Cassandra humming along)
- ♪ Can't help ♪
♪ The way I feel... ♪
- Oh, my God.
- What?
Are you seeing that guy?
No.
(Gail laughs)
Aw.
Good for you.
♪ Sitting pretty,
but I'm all alone... ♪
GAIL:
So, Ryan...
pediatric surgeon, huh?
Yes. Yes.
(clears throat softly)
You ever killed any children?
Uh, what? (chuckles)
While operating on them.
Have you ever killed
any children?
Uh, no. No.
Really?
- CASSANDRA: Gail.
- I...
Well, kids have passed
while I've been operating.
So that's a yes. Yes...
Gail, stop asking him
if he's killed children.
I will stop asking him
when he stops killing children.
That-that seems fair.
That seems fair.
I'll leave you two
lovebirds to it.
- Can you lock up for me, honey?
- Of course.
Now, if you two decide
to have sex on the counter,
the bleach is in the back room.
And I don't want to walk
in here tomorrow morning
and see ass prints
in the coffee grinds.
Got it?
Got it, lover boy?
Yeah.
Have fun, you two.
Oh, my God.
(Gail laughing)
(door opens)
(door closes)
She seems nice.
(both laugh)
She is. She's a good friend.
Are you... are you friends with
anyone from Forrest still or...
No.
Really? No one? No one?
Really, no one.
Oh, my God, I can't...
I can't...
I can't shake them off.
(chuckles)
You still hang out
with those guys?
They're not that bad.
They aren't, really.
Um, oh, my God.
Madison McPhee just had twins.
She's completely obsessed.
I don't remember Madison.
You...
I thought you were close.
You guys and that other girl.
No.
Huh.
Um, oh, my God.
Al Monroe is marrying
this bikini model.
He got this hideous tattoo
of her name to propose.
Amazingly, she said yes.
(chuckles)
Classic Al, you know?
Landing on his feet.
Al Monroe?
You... well,
you must remember Al.
Yeah, I thought
he moved to London.
Yeah, he was there for years,
but he just moved back
to get married.
You see him a lot?
Uh, we're not close,
but he's in the group.
We actually
see each other at work,
'cause he's a...
anesthesiologist.
Good for him.
And he's getting married?
I know. God help her.
(chuckles softly)
(quiet chatter)
Welcome to
the Hotel Saint Joan, miss.
Thank you.
One ginger ale
and one bottle of champagne.
- Don't worry. I can do that.
- Oh, but it's...
MADISON:
Cassie.
(laughs)
CASSANDRA:
Madison.
MADISON:
Oh, my God.
(both laughing)
Oh, you look amazing.
I almost didn't recognize you.
You look exactly the same.
- You're sweet. I look so old.
- No.
That's what having twins
will do to you.
It's tragic.
Do you have kids?
No.
You'll get there.
(chuckles)
Champagne?
What are we drinking to?
To old friends.
(Madison chuckles softly)
MADISON:
Mm.
(sighs):
Ah.
Honestly, I thought I'd be
bored out of my skull
watching the kids,
but it's been great, actually.
Are we out already?
Can we get another bottle?
Thanks.
I haven't been day drunk
in forever.
- So fun.
(both laughing)
TBH, I know all guys say
they want wives that work,
but it's not true.
- No?
- No.
I mean, they all want
a feminist in college,
because it's cool
to have a girlfriend
- who cares about something.
- (chuckles)
And, statistically,
feminists are more likely
to do anal.
That's a literal fact,
by the way.
Really?
You know, when it
comes down to it,
all guys want the same thing.
And what's that?
(sighs) A good girl.
I don't seem to remember
you were that much
of a good girl in med school.
Well, Fred... Thanks.
Fred didn't know me at school.
He met me when I was
working at L'Oréal.
Poor Fred.
(laughs) What he doesn't know
won't kill him, right?
I'm glad everything
has worked out
so well for you, Madison.
Thanks.
- It really has.
- Yeah.
(both chuckle)
You know, I actually
wanted to meet you today
to talk about something
in particular.
I did wonder.
No one's heard from you
in, like, forever.
(both chuckle)
I wanted to talk to you
about why I dropped out.
Okay, sure.
You remember
what happened, right?
Um, s-such a long time ago now.
I know, but you remember.
I mean, vaguely.
Do you ever think about it?
Why would I?
Right. Why would you?
So, if a friend came to you now,
into your house, and told you
that they thought something bad
had happened to them
the night before...
- Cassie...
- Something bad.
- It was years ago.
- What would you say?
It w... (scoffs)
- Ugh. I'm so...
I feel a little weird.
Would you roll your eyes
behind her back
and dismiss the whole thing
as drama?
(laughs): I don't know
why you're mad at me.
Okay, I-I'm not the only one
who didn't believe it.
If-if you have a reputation
for sleeping around,
then maybe people
aren't gonna believe you
when you say
something's happened.
I mean...
it's crying wolf.
You thought it was crying wolf?
I don't make the rules.
Look, when you get that drunk,
things happen.
Don't get blackout drunk
all the time
and then expect people
to be on your side
when you have sex
with someone you don't want to.
I mean... (scoffs)
That's a shame.
I was hoping you'd feel
differently by now.
- Sorry.
- For your sake,
I was hoping you'd feel
different by now.
(sighs)
(slurring):
Look... look, don't be mad.
Just, I'll get the check,
all right?
It's my treat.
Hello?
(Madison sighs)
Are you okay, Madison?
My head is spinning.
I just feel...
(gasps) Oh! Shit.
My God.
Sorry.
It really is so great
seeing you again.
You really haven't
changed at all.
That's great.
So?
She's over there.
Room 25.
Your money's in the envelope.
You sure about this?
I'm sure.
(door opens)
(door closes)
(cell phone vibrating)
(continues vibrating)
(line beeps)
MADISON (recorded):
Cassie, hi.
Um, wonderful to see you
for lunch yesterday.
Blast from the past.
Uh, hey.
I was pretty drunk.
I can't really, um...
Look, did you see me talking
to a guy, like, our age?
He seemed to know you.
Just trying to piece
some things together.
(line beeps)
Cassie, sorry.
Please call me back.
I-I'm freaking out a little.
I woke up in
one of the hotel rooms.
I-I think something
might have happened.
I-I don't know.
♪ Uh-oh, I did it again ♪
♪ I got a bad habit
and I can't pretend ♪
♪ Uh-oh,
if it happened to you ♪
♪ Mm, what would you do? ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
Your place, right?
(music continues faintly
over stereo)
- See you tomorrow, bitches.
- Bye, Amber.
- CASSANDRA: Excuse me.
- Bye.
CASSANDRA:
Excuse me! Hi.
- Me?
- Yeah.
(chuckles):
Hi. Sorry.
What's up?
I'm so sorry,
but my-my phone has died,
and I'm so late for work.
Do you live around here?
Do you know the area?
I guess. Why?
Would you tell me how to get
to the Castle Diner?
You know what?
I'm actually, like, really late.
Please. I'm supposed to be
shooting this music video,
- and I...
- Music video?
Uh, yeah, I'm-I'm
a makeup artist, and it's
my first time working with
these guys, and if I'm late,
- I may as well not...
- AMBER: Oh, my God.
Oh, my God.
Are you working for Wet Dreams?
You didn't see that.
I know where
the Castle Diner is.
Don't worry about it.
- I'll ask someone else.
- No way. No way.
Oh, my God, you're working
with Wet Dreams!
Oh, my God!
Are they there right now?
You need to calm down, please.
I can direct you. Please.
Sorry. No.
If I don't direct you,
how are you gonna find it?
I can't.
If you tell anyone
or you post about this,
I will never work again.
I swear I won't post anything.
I promise.
Take my phone.
Seriously, take it.
Ugh! God, okay.
Get in. Fine.
But you have to be
cool about this.
No. Of course I will.
(Amber squeals excitedly)
Whoa.
You really are a fan.
I'm obsessed.
I have a whole Insta
dedicated just to George's dog.
What a crazy coincidence.
I know.
You know what?
This... this is fate.
Sure seems like it, huh?
(engine starts)
(lock clicks)
♪ Uh-oh. ♪
(phone rings)
SECRETARY:
Yes?
Dean Walker is ready,
if you'd like to go on through.
- (door closes)
- Daisy.
- That's me.
- Dean Walker.
Please sit.
My assistant says that
you are interested
in resuming med school.
That's right.
May I ask what prompted
your desire
to get back to your studies?
I guess...
I couldn't stop thinking
about my time here.
Yeah.
It's an extraordinary place.
It's an unusual request.
Yes, but I left under
unusual circumstances.
Oh.
I left because of
what happened to Nina.
Hmm.
Nina Fisher.
You don't remember her?
Maybe you remember
Alexander Monroe?
Oh, yes. Alexander Monroe.
He actually just came back
and gave a talk here.
Oh, he's a...
he's a really nice guy.
Really smart.
- Are you a friend of his?
- No.
So, you don't remember
the accusations made
against Al Monroe?
I don't.
He took a girl, Nina Fisher,
the one you don't remember,
back to his room,
where he had sex with her
repeatedly
and in front of his friends
while she was too drunk to have
any idea what was going on.
She was covered in bruises
the next day.
Handprints,
I guess you could say.
Was it reported?
Yes.
Do you know who Nina spoke to?
You.
But you can't remember, so...
You felt there wasn't
sufficient evidence.
You said it was too much
of a "he said, she said"
situation.
Well...
you know, we get accusations
like this all the time.
One or two a week.
I'm sorry I don't remember
your friend Nina,
but I can assure you,
at that time,
that I looked into it
thoroughly.
His friends were all
watching, laughing.
It's so hard.
But, you know, also,
if she was drinking
and-and maybe couldn't
remember everything...
So, she shouldn't
have been drunk?
- I'm not saying that. I...
- I'm sorry, I don't...
(chuckles): I don't mean
to sound critical, Dean Walker.
I just want to be clear.
None of us want to admit
when we've made ourselves
vulnerable.
When we've made a bad choice.
And those choices,
those mistakes,
can be so damaging
and really regrettable.
- Regrettable?
- Yes.
I mean, because
what would you have me do?
Ruin a young man's life
every time we get
an accusation like this?
So you're happy to take
the boy's word for it?
I have to give him
the benefit of the doubt.
Of course you do.
Because innocent
until proven guilty.
No arguing with that.
No.
Thank you for your time.
- Is your friend okay?
- No.
She's not.
But Al Monroe is.
You'll be glad to hear
he's doing really well.
- He's getting married, actually, so...
- Hmm.
You know, I guess you did
the right thing.
We have to give these boys
the benefit of the doubt.
That's why I know
you won't mind that,
three hours ago, I picked your
daughter Amber up from school
and introduced her to the boys
who live in that room now.
- What?
- She is really pretty, huh?
(chuckles): She looks
a lot older than she is.
- I don't believe you.
- I noticed they had a few
bottles of vodka
in their room, too.
But I'm sure they'll take
good care of your daughter.
She seemed excited, actually.
(dialing)
- (line ringing)
- (phone vibrating)
Oh, wait.
(chuckles):
I have her phone.
She'll be wanting that later.
You're crazy.
No.
Tell me what room
my daughter is in right now.
I told you...
the same room Nina was in.
I told you
I don't remember that.
Well, that's a shame.
What are you doing?
She is a young girl.
I wonder if she looks so young
to those guys.
You better tell me
what room she's in.
Tell me what fucking room
she's in!
Now, you sociopath!
Tell me where she is!
- (muffled): Right now!
- (phone ringing)
Tell me what room she's in!
Please!
Please tell me.
You're right, okay?
Is that what you want to hear?
You're right.
Look how easy it was.
I guess you just had to think
about it in the right way.
- (whimpers)
- I guess it feels different
when it's someone you love.
Tell me where
my daughter is, please.
(laughs)
Relax.
Dean Walker,
do you really think
I would do something like that?
Luckily, I don't have as much
faith in boys as you do.
Amber is sitting in a diner,
waiting for her favorite
boy band to show up
for a music video.
It's the Castle Diner,
if you want to call and check.
Or you should probably call,
actually,
or she may never figure out
they're not coming.
She's kind of an idiot, huh?
Gorgeous, though.
Who needs brains?
They never did a girl any good.
Great to see you again,
Dean Walker.
(closing door echoes)
- (horn honking)
- (vehicle passes)
(horn honking repeatedly)
MAN (muffled):
Hey! You're blocking the road!
Get out of the fucking road!
What the fuck is wrong with you?
Hey. Hey!
You're sitting in the middle
of the intersection.
How'd you get your license?
You blow the entire DMV?
Hello.
I'm talking to you.
Look at me, you stupid cunt.
(snapping fingers)
Huh?
You want to have a face...
Okay, yeah.
Come on over. Let's do this.
Where are you going?
You're just gonna leave
your car in the intersection?
You coming over here? Huh?
Are you angry?
Holy shit!
Is that a fucking tire iron?
You psycho!
Just chill out, okay?
Why don't you calm down.
Oh! Okay.
Whoa! Stop! Stop, stop, stop!
Crazy fucking bitch.
- Excuse me?
- (sighs)
Fuck you.
(tires squealing)
(sighs):
Fuck.
Ryan, what are...?
She lives.
I'm just kidding. You weren't
answering your phone,
- so I was...
- Oh, shit. The movie.
Oh, I-I'm so sorry.
I had to work late.
Yeah, I-I went by
the coffee shop.
Gail said you took the day off.
- Um...
- Everything all right?
Yeah. (laughs)
No, I'm fine. I'm just in
the middle of something.
Totally. Got it.
We can make the movie still
if we skip dinner.
Um, I'm a little tired.
- Yeah.
- Um, do you mind if I call you tomorrow?
Sure. Great.
- Okay.
- Are you okay, though?
You seem kind of...
What?
Uh... off.
No, um, I'm fine.
I'm just...
Too-too much... too much coffee.
(chuckles):
Don't work in a coffee shop.
Okay.
All right, night.
All right, good night.
Here we go.
- Yeah, but you watch your step here.
- Whoop!
Now, when we get to the house,
you got to be quiet,
'cause I don't know if
my parents are asleep or not.
- Okay. Mm.
- We got to be respectful.
This is fucking surge prices.
1.2? That's...
I mean, it's not that far.
- You can walk, right?
- I don't know.
Let's try. Let's go.
Come on, now.
- Whoop, there we go.
- (whoops, laughs)
- You got it. That was fun.
- (laughing)
Yeah. (chuckles)
Cassie?
- (scoffing chuckle)
- Ryan.
What are you doing here?
I'm meeting friends
'cause my schedule
cleared up last minute.
Let me explain.
It's fine. It's...
PAUL:
Uh, my bad, dude.
I didn't know
the woman was taken, but...
- She's...
- She's all yours, man.
All mine? (chuckles)
Uh...
Do you know her name or...?
Claire?
- Wow.
- Pretty close.
(chuckles):
Okay. Have a good night.
Don't go, Ryan. Wait, please.
Cassie, if you didn't...
if you weren't interested,
just, you could've just told me.
(Paul chuckling)
That's ice-cold.
That was humiliating.
Why don't you just
fuck off now, okay?
Wait, are you sober?
Oh, shit.
You're that psycho
that Jerry took home.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
You know what?
Not interested, sweetheart.
Nah. Why don't you take
your crazy somewhere else.
You're not even that hot.
You're hardly dropping
panties yourself, Paul.
When was the last time
you scored in daylight?
Careful.
No, you be careful.
I'm not the only one
who does this.
And some of the other girls,
they really are crazy.
(Paul scoffs quietly)
I-I don't believe you.
There's a woman in this city
that carries a pair of scissors.
You're-you're lying.
Hmm. Try it out
next time you go out.
See what happens.
Why?
Why you guys have to ruin
everything?!
(whimpering)
(birds chirping)
Can I help you?
I really hope so.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'm no longer
practicing the law,
if that's what you've come for.
It's not about that.
I'm afraid it's
your day of reckoning.
I've been waiting.
Come in.
CASSANDRA: Your office told me
you're on sabbatical.
It was very easy
to get your address.
They just gave it to me.
I told them to give it
to anyone who asked.
That doesn't seem safe.
No use hiding from the piper.
He has to be paid.
I guess so.
You seem nervous, Mr. Green.
I came here to talk to you
about something
that happened seven years ago.
You probably
won't remember a client
named Alexander Monroe.
You helped so many boys
like him.
And you most certainly
won't remember the girl
who you threatened and bullied
till she dropped her case.
I remember her.
Nina?
Was that it?
I'm sorry, I don't remember
her full name, but...
It was Nina, though, wasn't it?
Yes.
I remember her.
Have you come here to hurt me?
Do you want me to hurt you?
I think so.
I-I had a... what I think
was a-an epiphany,
but my doctors called it
a psychotic episode.
And it was at work, so...
so now I'm on a sabbatical.
You know, I got a bonus for
every settlement out of court.
I got another bonus
for every charge dropped.
We all did.
There was a guy...
(Cassandra gasps)
His only job was to comb through
all their social media accounts
for any compromising
information.
He contacted old friends,
past sexual partners.
Oh, you'd be amazed
how much easier it is now
with the Internet
to dig up dirt.
In the old days, we'd have to
go through a girl's trash.
- Now one drunk photo at a party.
- (whimpers)
Oh, you wouldn't believe
how hostile that makes a jury.
(gasps, whimpers)
You got to help me.
I can't sleep.
I haven't slept in...
I'll never forgive myself.
I want you to know that.
I'll never forgive myself
for any of this.
- I forgive you.
- (sighs heavily)
I'm so sorry.
(shuddering breaths)
Go to sleep.
Do I go in now?
- No.
- Oh.
I'm stilling getting paid,
though, right?
Yeah.
(engine starts)
Cassie?
Do you remember
Nina's 16th birthday party?
Oh, my gosh.
How could I forget?
I was such a mess.
Nina threw up on the swing.
Mm-hmm. Certainly not
her finest moment.
And that boy
who stole your vase.
And she made him bring it
back to you and apologize.
(both laugh)
He was so scared of her.
She was holding onto his ear.
"You better say you're sorry
to my mom, you asshole."
(chuckles)
What was his name?
Simon or Steve or something.
Why are you here?
I just wanted to see you.
You need to stop this.
It isn't good for any of us.
It's no good for Nina.
It isn't good for you.
Look, I know you feel bad
that you weren't there,
but you got to let it go.
I'm just trying to fix it.
Oh, come on. You can't.
Don't be a child, Cassie.
(Mrs. Fisher sighs)
I'm so sorry
I didn't go with her.
No.
I'm sorry, too.
Cassie.
Move on.
Please.
For all of us.
(doorbell rings)
Oh, great, it's you.
Can I come in?
Yep.
Do you want something?
Do you want a coffee?
Or another dude to go home with?
Yeah, actually.
Do you have any douchebags
lying around?
(chuckles) Yeah. There's
a racist on the eighth floor.
- Yeah.
- Perfect.
What do you want, Cassie?
I came to apologize about...
Oh.
I've been trying to think
about how to explain.
(Ryan clicks tongue)
(sighs)
It's not that
I'm not interested.
- Mm.
- I really am.
I really, really am.
Okay.
Sorry if I'm confused.
It... (chuckles)
You...
Sorry, we...
we've been on a couple dates.
Um, you won't kiss me
or touch me, which is fine.
And then I see you going home
with some random creep
in a fedora.
I admit, the fedora
was unforgivable.
(chuckles)
The other night...
It's hard to explain it,
but it won't happen again.
I promise,
it'll never happen again.
Can we try again?
Can I, I mean.
I don't...
I don't know.
Are you okay?
Um...
- It's fine. I'm...
- (scoffs)
- I guess I'll see you around.
- (sighs)
(door closes)
(door opens)
- We're closed.
- (door closes)
RYAN:
Good.
Do you want to go to dinner,
you miserable asshole?
Yeah.
Shit.
("Stars Are Blind"
by Paris Hilton playing)
RYAN: First trip to
the pharmacy together.
CASSANDRA:
Yeah.
Big step.
(singing along):
♪ I don't mind... ♪
(laughing):
I'm sorry.
- Are you singing Paris Hilton?
- What? Yeah.
- Oh. Okay. Yeah.
- ♪ Just hanging here with you ♪
- (laughs): Oh, stop.
- ♪ 'Cause I don't find ♪
- (snorts) Stop it. Shh!
- ♪ Too many... ♪
It's fine. I'm fine.
It's fine, it's fine.
- No. (laughs)
- ♪ That treat me like you do ♪
- No. Stop it.
- ♪ Those other guys ♪
♪ They want to take me ♪
- ♪ For a ride ♪
- (laughing)
♪ But you can see
the real me inside ♪
- ♪ And I'm satisfied ♪
- (groans)
- ♪ Oh, no ♪
- Shh!
- ♪ Oh ♪
- (bag pops)
♪ Even though the gods
are crazy ♪
♪ Even though
the stars are blind ♪
♪ If you show me real love,
baby, I'll show you mine ♪
♪ I can make it
nice and naughty ♪
♪ Be the devil and angel, too ♪
♪ Got a heart and soul
and body ♪
♪ Let's see what
this love can do ♪
This is so much less sad
when there's someone else here.
- ♪ Maybe I'm perfect for you ♪
- (chuckles)
(chuckles): That's the cute
yogurt-wise move. This way.
♪ Oh, oh, oh, oh ♪
♪ I could be ♪
- ♪ Your confidante ♪
- (laughs): Yeah.
♪ Just one of your girlfriends ♪
♪ Why shouldn't we be with
the one we really love? ♪
♪ Now tell me, who have you
been dreaming of? ♪
♪ I and I alone ♪
♪ Oh, no, oh ♪
♪ Even though the gods
are crazy ♪
♪ Even though
the stars are blind ♪
♪ If you show me real love,
baby, I'll show you mine ♪
♪ I can make it
nice and naughty ♪
♪ Be the devil and angel, too ♪
♪ Got a heart and soul
and body... ♪
I haven't done this
in a pharmacy in weeks.
- (laughing): That's weird.
- Literally weeks.
Thank you.
Sorry.
They're okay.
(crickets chirping)
- (gentle music playing)
- Cheese?
RYAN:
Would love it.
Yeah. Thank you.
- Bread?
- Ah, yep.
Okay.
Mm. Oh. Thank you.
What a home.
It's unbelievable.
- So beautiful.
- Yeah, it's nice.
Susan works really hard.
- Yeah, it shows.
- Yeah.
Eat, eat, before it gets cold.
This looks delicious.
- Oh. (gasps) Oh.
- Thank you.
I made the sauce.
RYAN:
The sauce is...
Mm.
The sauce is really good.
- Incredible.
- SUSAN: Mm.
Ryan, I hear you're a doctor.
Your parents must be
very, very proud.
Not really.
Uh, they wanted me to be a DJ.
(chuckles awkwardly)
(laughing)
He's funny.
- (Stanley continues laughing)
- Yeah.
STANLEY:
That's funny.
You didn't say
he was funny, Cassie.
- Dad.
- You didn't say I was...
- You didn't say I was funny?
- No.
I said you were boring but rich.
I am boring. Not that rich.
- (laughter)
- No? Well, in that case,
thanks for stopping by, kid.
(laughter)
What kind of doctoring
do you do?
Uh, pediatric, so...
children.
What was your, uh...
What was that doctor's name?
Cassie's doctor.
- Gary?
- Um, no.
Dr. Katzen-something.
CASSANDRA:
Yeah. Dad, he was like 80.
Yeah, well...
You-you don't know
Dr. Katzen...?
No.
SUSAN:
Now, I'm-I'm confused.
Are there different parts
of the body on a child?
No, it's pretty much
the same thing.
You're just...
You know, different-colored
Band-Aids and things.
It's not brain surgery.
(chuckles softly)
- Well...
- (laughs)
I get it. Yeah.
- Oh.
- (chuckles)
This sauce is
absolutely unbelievable.
(laughing quietly)
SUSAN:
Night, you two.
CASSANDRA:
Night.
Thanks for
introducing us to Ryan.
I know it was hard.
You know, your mom, she's...
(chuckles): Well, I mean,
we're both so glad that, uh...
Oh, my God, Dad.
(chuckles):
He's not that nice.
(laughs):
Yeah.
Yeah, I must be tired.
(sighs):
Okay.
Honey, Nina was like
a daughter to us.
You know that.
We really miss her.
(sighs)
But, God, we have missed you.
See you tomorrow.
(sighs, chuckles)
RYAN: Your mom...
oh, your mom is hot.
- Sorry.
- (laughing)
(chuckles):
Your mom is extremely hot.
Do you want her number?
- I could hook you up.
- Really?
Ooh.
I think she likes you
more than I do.
Well, I hope that's not true.
Can I... Mm.
Can I tell you something?
Sure.
I think you're amazing. I...
- Oh, no, Ryan.
- Just shut up, you stupid bitch.
- Please don't.
- Shh. I...
- Just take this, please.
- Mm-hmm.
I think you're incredible. I...
I'm... (sighs)
I'm-I'm... I think
I'm falling in love with you.
I think I'm falling
in love with you, too.
(softly):
Yes.
- Oh, my God.
- Don't make...
- Oh, my.
- Don't make a thing of it.
- I'm gonna buy you a bicycle.
- No.
- I want to buy you a bicycle.
- Ryan, be cool.
I'm cool.
- (whispers): I'm so cool.
- (laughing)
Oh, I'm the coolest.
(humming "Stars Are Blind")
Cassie.
Shit.
Madison,
what are you doing here?
Sorry. I, um...
I tried calling.
I left messages
about, uh, that guy.
Your friend.
Um, I don't know if-if your
phone number wasn't working.
Maybe I had an old one.
I just... I mean...
I know it seems kind of crazy,
me waiting on your porch
like some kind of stalker
or something.
Madison, I'm sorry.
I should've called you back.
Nothing happened with that guy.
Please believe me.
Are you sure? I...
But it seemed like...
I know what it seemed like,
but it wasn't.
He didn't touch you.
(sighs):
Oh, thank God.
(sobs):
Oh.
(sniffles)
Oh, I was...
I was so worried that, um...
that I... that he and I, um...
He just put you in bed.
Kept an eye on you
to make sure you were okay.
I'm really sorry
I didn't call you back.
It wasn't nice.
Yeah, well...
God. Look, there...
(sighs)
I need to show you something.
Okay.
Can we go inside?
Yeah.
Do you want a glass of water
or something?
No, thank you.
Oh.
After we had lunch and...
I got so drunk and woke up
in a hotel room with that guy,
um, I thought about it.
About what you said about Nina.
And how we all
just acted like...
And I remembered something.
What?
There was a tape.
- What?
- A stupid video.
It just got sent around.
I got sent it.
Everyone did.
At the time, it was...
It was just gossip, you know?
Gossip?
So much stuff happened
back then, like, all the time.
You know what it was like.
It was just one blackout
after the next.
I-I hoped I'd imagined it.
But, um...
I always saved all my phones
for photos or whatever.
So, um...
Here.
I don't know how we all could
have watched it and, um...
What?
Thought it was funny.
You can have the phone, okay?
You don't have to watch it.
I really wouldn't watch it.
But, um, I don't know,
do whatever you want with it.
Just leave me out of it.
And...
please, will you do me a favor?
Yeah.
Never fucking contact me again.
(door opens, closes)
♪ Oh ♪
♪ Ooh ♪
♪ Ooh... ♪
(picks up phone)
- (phone beeps)
- (men hollering, laughing)
(upbeat music playing
over video)
JOE:
Al, get it!
MAN (laughing):
Come on, stop.
MAN 2:
Go on. Come on, come on.
JOE: Shh, shh, shh.
Calm down, calm down.
- RYAN: Oh, my God.
- (gasping)
Whoa. This is insane.
JOE: Ryan, holy shit.
Come look at this.
(laughing):
Man, you got to check this out.
RYAN: Yo, don't film me.
Dude, put the camera away.
What are you fucking doing?
Oh, my God.
- (Ryan laughing)
- JOE: Ryan, come on.
RYAN:
This is fucked up.
(Ryan continues laughing)
Jesus Christ.
Al, Al.
- (Ryan laughing)
- (Cassandra shuddering)
- (video stops)
- (phone drops to table)
♪ Once upon a time ♪
♪ There was a pretty fly ♪
♪ He had a pretty wife ♪
♪ This pretty fly ♪
♪ But one day she flew away ♪
♪ Flew away ♪
♪ She had two pretty children ♪
♪ But one night
these two pretty children ♪
♪ Flew away, flew away ♪
♪ Into the sky ♪
♪ Into the Moon. ♪
(elevator bell dings)
(indistinct announcement
over P.A.)
Cassie, what...
what are you doing here?
Are-are you okay or...
Can we go somewhere
to talk privately?
I'm working. (chuckles)
We need to talk right now.
Okay.
What's... what's going on?
- Everything all right or...?
- I've been such an asshole.
What happened?
I really thought for a second
it was all gonna be okay.
Cassie.
(chuckles)
Look at this.
(upbeat music playing
over video)
What are you showing me?
What is this?
- Is that Al Monroe?
- Mm.
(both laugh)
Oh, my God, it...
JOE (over video):
Shh, shh, shh.
Wait, is that... I don't...
I don't want to look
at that, Cassie.
Well, why not?
You were happy to watch
back then.
What are you talking about?
I wasn't...
RYAN (over video):
Oh, my God. Whoa.
- This is insane.
- JOE: Ryan, holy shit.
Come look at this.
Man, you got to check this out.
RYAN (sighs):
Oh, shit.
I don't... I don't remember.
Uh, I don't.
Didn't make an impact, huh?
I was a kid. I...
(video stops)
I need you to do
something for me,
and I want you to think
about it very carefully.
I have this video
ready to send to everyone
in your address book.
- (shuddering)
- Your parents.
Your colleagues.
All your old buddies
and their wives.
Cassie, come on.
So, I can send it out right now,
or you can tell me where
Al Monroe's bachelor party is.
What?
Why?
You don't need to know why.
But what are you gonna do?
Well, that depends.
On what?
You think
they'll fire you here?
- (sighs): Oh, geez.
- Dr. Ryan Cooper?
Oh, fuck.
(chuckles): I mean,
you work with kids, right?
They have to be careful.
Things have changed so much
since we were at school,
haven't they?
Think about this, please.
Please.
I cannot begin to tell you
how much I've thought about it.
- Okay.
(paper rustling)
(writing)
- All right. There. Okay?
- (rips paper)
They're gonna be there
this weekend... all of them.
You don't... you don't think
I'm a bad person.
Cassie, I-I...
I love you.
I love you, Cassie.
You got to forgive me.
Tell me you'll forgive me.
No.
(takes paper)
So, you're perfect, right?
You've never done anything
you're ashamed of?
You're... (shudders)
I can't...
Are you gonna tell everybody?
I don't know.
I don't know if I can live with
the threat of this
hanging over me.
I didn't even do anything.
(laughs):
Okay.
Poor Ryan,
just an innocent bystander.
Yeah.
Don't tell any of them
that I'm coming,
'cause I'll send the video
around just the same if you do.
And then we both
won't be doctors,
you fucking failure.
Nice.
Bye, Ryan.
(door closes)
(classical version of Britney
Spears's "Toxic" playing)
(water splashes)
(indistinct chatter)
- (laughing): Oh, shit.
- Holy shit. What?
Well, the doctor's here.
(others cheering,
whooping, laughing)
- Stripper time, baby! Let's go!
- (cheering)
- Let's go!
- Nurse, I'm feeling sick!
(laughing):
Please take my temperature.
I told you guys no strippers.
Anastasia's gonna lose her shit.
(others groaning)
All right, who ordered her?
- Joe?
- Don't look at me.
(chuckles)
No one's owning up?
All right, well, when Anastasia
finds out, it's your fucking
- funeral, you hear me?
- Get out of here.
- (laughter)
- I take it you're the groom?
Yeah.
(men whooping)
- Then sit the fuck down.
- (laughter, yelling)
Oh, shit!
Now.
I'm gonna need you all
to kneel down in front of me
like the naughty boys you are.
- MEN: Oh...
- JOE: Come on, come on.
(laughter)
Everybody here?
I don't want anyone to miss out.
Oh, yeah. All the patients
are accounted for, Nurse.
(laughter)
♪ I'm ready, come catch me ♪
♪ Tag, you're it,
come on, let's go ♪
♪ I'm ready ♪
♪ Can you catch me? ♪
♪ Play with me, I don't bite ♪
♪ Shock me and I ignite ♪
♪ Push to start, I'm on fire ♪
♪ Baby, you're my desire ♪
♪ Play with me, I don't bite ♪
♪ Shock me and I ignite ♪
♪ Push to start, I'm on fire ♪
♪ Baby, you're my desire. ♪
Time to go upstairs.
No, it's okay.
I don't, uh, w-want to.
Look, I don't
have to do anything
if you don't want me to,
but I only get paid
if I go upstairs with you.
(sighs) Okay.
- Okay, you guys.
- (cheering)
JOE: I better see her crawling
out of here in the morning!
She better not be able to walk!
Leave some for us, man!
(door opens)
(men hollering,
dance music playing downstairs)
(door closes)
Uh, so what do I, uh...
Get on the bed.
Okay.
I'm a little scared of you.
You don't need to be scared.
Get on the bed.
(grunting):
All right.
Oh! Uh, no, no, no. Sorry.
I-I'm not sure about that.
It's for my safety.
When I give private dances,
guys can get
a little handsy, so...
Oh, right. Yeah, of course.
(chuckling)
You know, you don't...
you don't need to...
I'm a gentleman.
- Are you? (laughs)
- Yeah.
You might be surprised
to hear that gentlemen
are sometimes the worst.
Ow. Oh.
Sorry, can you, uh...
can you loosen these a little?
- You'll get used to it.
- Ooh.
(chuckles)
Look, I-I don't want to sound
like a pussy,
but y-you're not... you're not
gonna do anything, are you?
It's just... I love my fiancée,
- and we're getting married.
- Aw.
- So I-I don't want any, uh...
- (chuckles)
Hey, do I look like someone
who would make you
do something
you don't want to do?
- No.
- Exactly.
(chuckles, snorts)
Ay.
So, what's your name?
Candy.
- I mean your real name.
- Nina.
Nina Fisher.
What did you say?
I said my name is Nina Fisher.
Can you let me go, please?
I'm sorry, I can't.
Did one of the guys
put you up to this?
Was it Joe?
Jesus Christ, that was dark,
even for him.
I don't follow.
- You're not Nina Fisher.
- Why not?
(sighs)
Because she's dead, okay?
Must be another Nina Fisher.
- A coincidence.
- Yeah, I don't think so.
Hey, can you let me
out of these, please?
This isn't funny.
Why would I give you
a dead girl's name?
Hey, this is fucked up, okay?
Stop.
But I'm not doing anything.
Guys! Hey, Joe?
Br-Brandon, Chip.
Hey, guys.
Can you get up here, please?
I don't think they can hear you.
And even if they could,
they're all passed out by now.
'Cause if there is one thing
I learned at Forrest,
it's how easy it is
to slip something into a drink.
You'd think they'd
remember that, especially Joe.
Do I know you?
I'm not sure
you would remember me, Al.
You were so popular.
You're Nina's friend.
Fuck!
So you did notice me after all.
I'm surprised.
I wasn't super fuckable
back then,
so I thought I kind of
slipped your attention.
Wh-Wh-Wh-Wh... (sighs)
What do you want?
Money?
You blackmailing me?
I want you to tell me
what you did.
Are y...
are you talking about...
What do you think
I'm talking about?
I didn't do anything!
W-We were kids.
Oh, if I hear that
one more time.
Look...
(stammers, sighs)
Maybe she regretted it after,
okay?
- Oh, yeah, she regretted it.
- I didn't do anything!
- Wrong!
- What the fuck...
Look, I... (chuckles)
I don't know what
you want me to say, okay,
b-b-but we-we did not...
What?
You know.
No.
She could barely
hold her head up.
She had no idea
what was going on.
It was a fucking party.
I-I mean, yeah, look,
we were all drunk,
of course,
but-but-but she was into it.
Didn't look like she was
into it on the video.
What video?
Oh, you don't remember?
Your friend Joe taped it.
Let me tell you, that party
does not look so good
in the cold light of day.
Look, I'll-I'll give you
anything, okay?
I mean, I'll-I'll do anything.
Anything.
Aw. Don't cry.
Really, don't fucking cry.
Tell me what you did.
I didn't do anything wrong,
though!
She dropped out.
Top of her class,
and she dropped out.
I did, too, to take care of her.
- The two of us gone.
- (sobs softly)
You graduated
magna cum laude, though.
Did you ever feel guilty,
or did you just feel relieved
that she'd gone?
You know, I was affected
by it, too, okay?
I mean, it's every guy's
worst nightmare,
getting accused like that.
Can you guess what every woman's
worst nightmare is?
The thing is you thought
you'd gotten away with it
because everyone had forgotten.
- Fuck.
- But I haven't.
You're out of your fucking mind!
I was so sad to leave, you know?
I wanted to be a doctor
my whole life.
But lately,
I've been feeling like...
I might want to get
back into it.
Stop.
- You know...
- Please. Please stop. Hey.
Nina was extraordinary.
So smart.
- (chuckles)
- Help!
- Weirdly smart.
- (instruments scraping)
Help! Help me!
Fuck!
- (shushing)
- Help me! (sobs)
I want you to know
what she was like, okay?
(crying):
Come on.
She's just so difficult
to explain,
'cause she was just
so completely herself.
Even when she was
four years old.
She was fully formed
from day one.
Same face. Same walk.
And funny.
Like a grown-up is funny.
- Kind of shrewd.
- (crying)
I was just in awe of her.
I couldn't believe
she wanted to be my friend.
She didn't give a fuck
what anyone else thought,
apart from me,
'cause she was just...
Nina.
And then she wasn't.
Suddenly,
she was something else.
She was yours.
(whimpers, gasps)
It wasn't her name she heard
when she was walking around.
- It was yours.
- (sobs softly)
Your name all around her.
All over her all the time.
And it just...
...squeezed her out.
(panting, sobbing)
So, when I heard
your name again...
your filthy fucking name...
I wondered, when was the last
time anyone had said hers?
Or thought it, even?
Apart from me.
And it made me so sad
because, Al...
you should be the one
with her name all over you.
No. No.
Don't worry.
I've sterilized everything.
- No.
- I really would have been a great doctor.
- You're insane.
- (laughing): You know what?
I honestly don't think I am.
I'll do this
as quick as I can, okay?
(gasping)
(grunts)
Stop. Stop!
- Get off me!
- No!
- Just stop fucking moving!
- (grunting)
- Just stop, please! Fucking...
- No!
You...
(both grunting)
(both panting, grunting)
No!
(grunts) Fuck!
(Cassandra whimpering)
(muffled screaming, sobbing)
AL:
Stop. Stop.
Shit. Shit.
(panting)
This is your fucking fault!
- (grunting)
- (muffled whimpering)
(panting frantically)
Fuck it.
Stop. Stop. Stop!
- (panting)
- (muffled grunting)
(muffled whimpering)
Fucking stop fucking moving!
Stop fucking moving!
(panting)
(grunting)
(muffled whimpering)
Stop.
(grunting, panting)
(brief, muffled whimpering)
(panting)
(bed creaking)
(quiet, shuddering breaths)
(sniffles)
(sobbing)
(sobbing continues)
(birds chirping)
(flies buzzing)
(grunts) Whoa.
What a night.
Ooh.
The fucking nurse?
Are you kidding me?
Nice.
(voice breaking):
Joe.
Al, Al, please don't freak out,
all right?
Anastasia's never
gonna find out.
What happens on tour
stays on tour.
(crying):
She's dead, Joe.
Come on.
I'm not kidding.
(laughing)
All right, I got...
y-you're being ironic.
What?
You killed the stripper
at your bachelor party?
What is this, the '90s?
Al, classic.
(laughs) Come on.
You want me to get her
out of here
so you can get some sleep?
All right.
All right, honey,
time for you to go.
- Come on.
- (Al gasps)
(laughs)
What is she doing?
Hey, honey, come on.
We got to go.
Honey, what are we doing...
Jesus fucking Chr...
- Fuck. Is she dead?
- (Al whimpering)
Al, why is
the fucking stripper dead?
I told you.
Well, how did this happen?
(sobbing):
I don't know.
Okay. Hey.
Al, this is not your fault.
I don't know.
It kind of seems like it is.
No, no, no, no.
It's not. It's not.
Am-am-am I...
- Am I gonna go to jail?
- What?
- What about the wedding and-and my job?
- No.
Anastasia's gonna be
so upset with me.
Well, no, no.
Al, Al, Al, Al,
it was an accident, right?
I mean...
Hey!
It was an accident.
I mean, of course it was
a fucking accident.
Yeah, of course
it was a fucking accident.
No one's gonna go to jail,
because no one's ever
gonna find out.
If anybody asks,
we all saw her leave last night.
She stripped, and then she left.
- She left?
- She left.
Okay. All right.
It's gonna be fine, all right?
We're gonna take care of this.
We just got to get rid
of the body
- before the others leave.
- (whimpering)
Hey, hey, hey, hey.
It's okay. Look at me.
This is not your fault, Al.
- (sobbing): Thank you.
- You did nothing wrong.
All right. All right.
You did nothing wrong.
This is not your fault.
Can you uncuff me?
Okay, come here. Come here.
♪ This is a man
who thinks with his heart ♪
♪ His heart is not always wise ♪
♪ This is a man
who stumbles and falls ♪
♪ But this is a man who tries ♪
- (water flowing)
- (fire crackling)
♪ This is a man
you'll forgive and forgive ♪
♪ And help and protect ♪
♪ As long ♪
♪ As you live ♪
♪ He will not always say ♪
♪ What you would have him say ♪
- ♪ But now and then ♪
- (Al retching)
♪ He'll say something ♪
♪ Wonderful. ♪
SUSAN:
Can't you just
do that thing where you track
her cell phone or something?
I'm sorry, ma'am.
It was turned off
before she left.
Seems like she really
didn't want anyone
to know where she was.
(sighs)
But it-it's...
it's just not like her
to disappear like this.
Well, that's not
entirely true, honey.
Stanley.
I... You know, she's...
she was getting better.
She was, really.
- She was getting better.
- STANLEY: Yes, she was.
She... Of course she was.
She'll come back.
You know how she is.
She always comes back.
Was she seeing anyone?
Did she have a boyfriend?
(knocking)
- Yes.
- (door opens)
DETECTIVE:
Are you Dr. Cooper?
Yeah.
Detective Waller.
- Yeah. Uh, come in, please.
- (door closes)
Have a seat.
Pediatric surgeon, huh?
Yeah. (chuckles)
That's very commendable.
Thank you for all that you do
for the community.
Sure. Yeah.
I'm sorry to bother you
at work, Doctor.
Do you know a Cassandra Thomas?
Yeah. Yes.
(clears throat) Yes.
- How do you know her?
- We were...
We were seeing each other.
Were seeing each other?
We broke up a few days ago.
Define "a few days."
Last Thursday.
Have you had any contact since?
No. I'm sorry,
what is this regarding?
Cassandra's parents have filed
a missing persons report.
I'm sorry, what?
Why?
Because she's missing.
Since when?
Since Friday.
She told her parents
something about a work trip,
but her colleague didn't know
anything about it.
Do you have any idea
where she might have been
going to this weekend?
She mentioned, uh,
the work trip.
- Yeah.
- Any idea where?
(sighs) N-No. No.
I'm sorry.
That's all right, Doc.
Between you and me, it, uh,
sounded like she wasn't
feeling so good.
Mentally, I mean.
Her father seemed to think
she was a little unstable.
Yeah, she was...
not in a good place.
Do you think she might have
wanted to hurt herself?
Yeah.
Uh, she could've.
She could've, yeah.
I thought that might
be the case.
Thank you for your honesty.
Well, I don't want
to bother you anymore,
but if you wouldn't mind coming
to the station tomorrow,
you know,
for an official statement.
Of course.
Anything I can do to help.
Thank you for your time,
Doctor.
- Appreciate it.
- Thank you.
(chuckles)
That's cute.
- Yeah.
- (laughs)
(door opens, closes)
(stringed instruments playing
Pachelbel's Canon)
Anastasia, you're the greatest
thing that ever happened to me.
You are my moral compass
and the love of my life.
ANASTASIA:
Al, you are my best friend
and my soul mate.
I love you.
JOE:
Al's like a brother to me.
We grew up together. We're...
We're the best of friends.
We've been through
thick and thin.
- (quiet laughter)
- And-and I just love him.
And, you know,
he's met Anastasia, who,
by all accounts, is,
you know, just a solid catch.
(Al chuckles softly)
(quiet chatter)
- PHOTOGRAPHER: That's great.
- (laughing)
(camera clicking)
- How you doing, man?
- Hey.
See that bridesmaid over there?
Whew. Just the type of girl
that makes you
go home to your wife
and say... (groans)
You know she trained
at Cirque du Soleil?
Come on her ass and her face
at the same time.
- That's nice.
- (sighs) Unbelievable.
- Everything just turned out so nice.
- Yeah.
JOE:
It's good seeing you.
Good. Yeah, you, too.
(indistinct chatter)
- Hi. How are you?
- Oh, hey, Joe. - Hey.
- Hey, it's good to see you.
- Good speech. (chuckles)
- (cell phone dings)
- I'm going to get a drink. - Cheers.
(chatter continues
indistinctly)
("Angel of the Morning"
by Juice Newton playing)
♪ There'll be no strings
to bind your hands ♪
♪ Not if my love
can't bind your heart ♪
♪ There's no need ♪
♪ To take a stand ♪
♪ For it was I
who chose to start ♪
♪ I see no need ♪
- ♪ To take me home ♪
- (sirens wailing in distance)
- (camera clicking)
- (Anastasia chuckles)
♪ I'm old enough ♪
- ♪ To face the dawn ♪
- (sirens growing closer)
♪ Just call me angel
of the morning ♪
♪ Angel ♪
♪ Just touch my cheek ♪
♪ Before you leave me, baby ♪
♪ Just call me angel
of the morning ♪
♪ Angel ♪
♪ Then slowly turn away ♪
♪ From me ♪
♪ Maybe the sun's light
will be dim ♪
♪ And it won't matter anyhow ♪
(helicopter whirring)
♪ If morning's echo
says we've sinned ♪
♪ Well, it was
what I wanted now ♪
(whistles)
♪ And if we're victims
of the night ♪
(people murmuring)
♪ I won't be blinded
by the light ♪
♪ Just call me angel
of the morning ♪
♪ Angel ♪
♪ Just touch my cheek ♪
♪ Before you leave me, baby ♪
♪ Just call me angel
of the morning... ♪
- You're Alexander Monroe?
- Uh, yeah.
You're under arrest
for the murder
- of Cassandra Thomas.
- ANASTASIA: No, no, no, no.
Officer,
please remove the bride.
- I'm sorry, this is a mistake.
- (Al stammering)
- You have the right to remain silent.
- Excuse me!
Can you explain
what's going on? Al!
(indistinct chatter)
- Sir...
- Hey, hey!
(indistinct chatter)
You have the right
to an attorney.
If you can't afford one,
one will be appointed to you.
- Understand, sir?
- Yes.
Officer, show him to the car.
♪ Of the day ♪
♪ Of the years ♪
♪ Baby ♪
♪ Just call me angel
of the morning ♪
♪ Angel ♪
♪ Just touch my cheek
before you leave me ♪
♪ Darling. ♪
♪ Cross my heart
and hope to die ♪
♪ I'm-a keep you up at night ♪
♪ Wish you never met me ♪
- ♪ Ya-ya ♪
♪ I'm the bitch, I do the most ♪
♪ Haunt you everywhere you go ♪
♪ Making you believe in ghosts ♪
- ♪ Ya-ya ♪
♪ My revenge is
sweeter than honey ♪
♪ Lick it up with your mouth ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ Never thought your jokes
were that funny ♪
♪ But ain't it funny how ♪
♪ I'm-a have the last laugh ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ 'Cause the second
you forget me ♪
♪ Is the second that
I come right back ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ Every whiskey
that you're drinking ♪
♪ You'll be thinking
how I burn like that ♪
♪ Is it a bird, is it a plane? ♪
♪ Nah, it's me in your dreams ♪
♪ Or maybe call 'em nightmares ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha, ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm-a,
I'm-a have the last laugh ♪
♪ Take an "L" and take a hit ♪
♪ Karma is a dirty snitch ♪
♪ Wish you never knew me ♪
♪ Nah-nah ♪
- ♪ Ya-ya ♪
♪ I'm crashing your party
to teach you a lesson ♪
♪ Heard you get nervous
whenever I'm mentioned ♪
♪ So if you're scared,
then go find you a priest ♪
♪ Go find a confession ♪
♪ My revenge is
sweeter than honey ♪
♪ Lick it up with your mouth ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ Never thought your jokes
were that funny ♪
♪ But ain't it funny how ♪
♪ I'm-a have the last laugh ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ 'Cause the second
you forget me ♪
♪ Is the second that
I come right back ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ Every whiskey
that you're drinking ♪
♪ You'll be thinking
how I burn like that ♪
♪ Is it a bird, is it a plane? ♪
♪ Nah, it's me in your dreams ♪
♪ Or maybe call 'em nightmares ♪
♪ Ha-ha-ha, ha-ha-ha ♪
♪ Yeah, I'm-a,
I'm-a have the last laugh ♪
I'm-a have the last laugh. ♪
(music fades)