She will fly to the sky...
She'll be a bird, a bird...
Fly.
She said she would fly.
She will.
What do we do now?
We've got to leave.
Let's go back to the village.
They'll kill us.
You'll need to be more vigilant than ever.
Don't sleep or take Chisa.
'House of Life'
It wasn't me.
Mum, how long is it
since he's been a Servant of God?
Who?
The one who works in Dad's field.
He came down from the mountain
when you were 5 summers old.
You were very little.
I want to be like him,
tall, handsome and strong.
You already are handsome.
Maybe even too much.
From the apple didn't come the first sin,
but rather the first
stupid and pointless prohibition.
It's only because the others were hungry.
Water is love.
It is word of the Divine.
And five days before this event,
the old apostle Malopse,
the One who transformed into a bird
to spy on Riva's sins
will fly five times to warn of death
for all eminent men.
It is word of the Divine.
Childhood
is the Devil's playground.
Sin takes root in your little bodies
with much ease
and contaminates others with dark thoughts.
I know about your thoughts, I know.
Because I can read your minds.
Innocence does not exist.
Only ignorance does.
Sir,
how did they discover that the Chisa
was the flower of the Devil?
We have now understoof the Truth.
We have understood the evil it brings.
It is the worst danger for men.
Even worse than deth,
because it brings about spiritual death
for those who touch the flower.
And you all know that.
Like that flower,
hat seems so innocent just like you...
But it is fed by the very blood
of the Evil One who lives beneath us.
It's there to tempt us
with its sweet taste.
It is His own blood!
Those who fell to temptation live
a life of solitude and rejection.
But... The Devil's blood is sweet?
Yes.
But the Chisa was here before us men, no?
From the creation of the world.
So it was also evil before us?
But... For hom was it bad then?
One should not even
think of these things!
But they say that with Chisa
one sees the sky...
and... the stars, and Truth.
Who said this?
The Devil Himself!
It is Evil personified!
It is the Devil in person!
You want to see Truth,
the truth of death?
well then cut open your throat
and you'll see the Truth!
But have you tried it?
How do they know if
no one has come back from death?
With your blood
the infection will be cured!
- Get to the mountain, with the other dirt!
- Dad!
- Go now!
- No!
I don't want to go!
Where will I go?
To the mountain!
I don't want to go there! Dad!
How will I live?
Along with the other filth.
Please!
You did the needful.
There was no option.
It's been a while since I saw him
on the wrong path.
Every child of this village
faces that danger.
Our only way os to educate
the remaining ones as best we can.
How was it for you?
It was the hardest moment of my life.
And the most necessary.
Out of here, village beast!
What are you stealing?!
Nothing, leave me. Just water.
Drink your own village water, you filth!
Filth yourself,
you're an Impure!
Filth yourself, look at your face!
He's been expelled, stupid.
Come in.
If you starve them to death,
you'll soon be without servants.
It's time we find a new procreator.
We also need more variety
in the House of Life.
Besides half of the women are with child.
I thought that this time
we should fetch two girls.
The agreement is unbreakable.
Per year,
one bleeding girl,
and one boy
able to carry two buckets of water.
But who would complain
since their protector has died?
We'll send another.
And who would go to that place
full of parasites?
If we break the agreement, they could flee.
And we'd be left without a place
to send out sinners.
You'll both go
soon and fetch
one male,
and one female.
It was probably a wolf.
It wasn't a wolf!
It was a lunatic.
Look,
thanks for yesterday,
but I'm not your friend.
I'm going to leave soon.
They're coming!
Which girl bled this year?
There were none this year.
You lie!
Come back next year!
That was not the agreement!
Or you hand over a girl and a boy
or you all die.
Take me!
To collect bunches of flowers?
If you don't bring us a bleeding girl,
we'll burn everything here!
Leave!
Why don't we leave?
Before they kill us all!
If we leave they kill us as well.
Where to? Here we have food!
But that was the agreement.
- A stupid agreement!
- I don't want to leave.
I'd prefer to die here.
We gain nothing that way.
I agree.
Stop shouting!
One day they see us stealing their corn
and they'll kill us.
The corn?
They all know you steal it!
They let you do it,
to make you stronger.
And later use you.
If you're witches,
why don't you defend yourselves?
I mean you have powers, right?
Or that's what they say in the village.
Yes...
No...
The thing is our teacher died recently.
We still don't know very much.
You shouldn't.
They change the course of rivers,
and the even the thoughts of men.
They consumed all the blood of their land,
and left them hollow.
They spent hundreds of years writing
guides,
laws
and rules for everyone.
They invented beliefs
to unite everyone
in the same mistake.
They filled libraries
with their convictions.
And demonstrations of their greatness.
They would spend entire lives
in this work.
But it served no purpose.
Nothing had purpose.
Everything collapsed,
like the waves clean
the beach
of detritus.
Man always goes back to what he is
and what he will always be:
An agressive and confused animal.
He's not dead, the animal.
He has a name.
He's called Kiva.
Kiva.
It's really true what they say of you
you really are witches.
Look what I found.
It's nice.
Put it with the other stuff
for my big sculpture.
I'm sorry ?
What are you doing here?
Sorry Dad.
Get back to the mountain!
Mum!
Go away!
I don't know you!
Mum, please.
You don't like me?
I've got another friend.
He's big,
and protects me.
He doesn't protect you at all.
Take it.
You'll understand everything with it.
I know.
But we're too young for that.
What is that?
They're coming to get us.
Mum!
Forgive me!
You dirtied yourself with sin.
Mum, stop!
I'm sorry?
I can clean myself.
Mum!
Leave me alone,
son of the devil!
Mum...
Look at me!
That I eat you?
But you're very little.
Why are you not scared of me?
I'm a witch.
And that spot?
That's what you do to me.
I know you think you're a witch,
but you're not,
You're good.
Is that normal, that fire?
That's not us,
it's the insects.
And the plants.
And the flowers that fly?
And what if they want to?
And the thunder?
Kila got angry.
Kila got angry?
The only thing our teacher taught us...
The more they hate us,
the stronger we get.
You mean you feed off their hate.
Where is Joaquin?
Leave it there.
So everyone can see evil.
Give us the body back!
This time we went too far,
and you know it.
What we know is that you're a hypocrite.
If he wasn't your son, you wouldn't care.
Hypocrite!
It was his own seed.
His own evil seed that came back to us!
An infected one controls us.
You
took some Chisa!
Chisa!
For you Joaquin.
For you.
We are all butteflies.
Earth is our crysalis.
Some of us eat each other.
Kila...
The storm is coming.
Siri...
Don't be angry.
Kila...
For you.
We can hear everything.
He's called
Wada.
Mum...
You killed me with shame, son.
I'm sorry mum.
I didn't want to do it.
You killed me...
There's need for forgiveness.
Forgive what?
I'm prepared
to forgive you all your evil
if you come back to the village.
If you come back altogether,
they can't harm you.
Sure, like with the other girls?!
If you don't come,
at least find a safer place.
Why protect us if we're witches?
That was only to frighten kids,
to control them.
You expelled me!
I did nothing wrong!
The village is in a state of hate.
I control them no longer.
You are the infected ones!
All of you should die!
If you come down, I'll forgive you.
Remember:
Water is Love.
It is what joins you to the village.
The Water joins us.
We've gone too far.
We're not acting properly.
It's time to forgive them.
We're not protecting anything
acting like this.
We're...
Forgetting...
of the objectives we had
to fend off evail...
Of which evil do you speak?
Of yours?
You went to the mountain
You laid with the devils.
You let them seduce you.
And you ut your evil seed into them.
You took the flower!
Everything has taken the flower!
And you know that!
Let us take off our masks.
Feel the hate!
The fountain has dried up.
He brought us this evil!
Feel the hate!
Some died
but not yet underground.
We know who
stopped the flow.
We need to go
and finish them off
once and for all.
What are they doing here?
Those witches...
Give us the water back,
and we'll leave you in peace.
We won't come again.
Let's get rid of them now.
It's Chisa!
It's lovely,
thank you.
Thank you.
They're gone.
We need to go down.
They saw us,
they judged us.
they were dogs
barking rabidly
against free and solitary wolves
that passed in front of their cages.