I open my eyes and I see nothing.
I only remember there was some accident.
Everyone ran for safety
as best they could.
As best they could.
As for what happened to me,
I just can't remember.
How strange. Where am I?
Judging by the clothes,
this must be the 1800s.
Where are they rushing off to?
What if we are denied entry?
I've never been so frightened.
Remember, the girl in white is mine.
Where are you going?
It's cold! Close the doors.
Quickly! Quickly!
Keep moving.
Those officers don't know the way.
Can it be that I'm invisible?
Or do they just not notice me?
Interesting.
Has all this been staged for me?
Am I expected to play a role?
What kind of play is this?
Let's hope it's not a tragedy.
Which way do we go?
Maybe this way.
No. We'll go this way.
That man in black,
he's wandering about too.
He nods to me, but goes away.
Pardon me for speaking before
we've been properly introduced.
What city is this?
Well, everyone speaks Russian.
I so hoped this was Chambord
during the Directory.
- What language are we speaking?
- Russian.
Russian?
How strange. I never knew Russian before.
What are they doing in there?
- Shall we go in?
- Where, in there?
Something is going on.
What on earth am I doing here?
I suddenly speak Russian.
I want to leave.
Your curiosity is not amusing.
Could all this be theater?
No, no. Farewell.
No. Our paths must part.
Farewell. You have answered all my questions.
- Farewell then.
- Where does this door lead to?
What a pity.
We may never meet again.
He was obviously a foreigner.
When will an opportunity like that
come again?
It's best not to get involved in this.
Let's not disturb them.
In any case, it's much too late.
Sir. Sir, I'm here.
My Russian cicerone. Do you know the way?
- Yes, let's go together.
- This is your country.
Yes, but not my century.
How did I come to be here?
I think I saw Peter the Great.
I hear delight in your voice.
Was it interesting?
Yes, very interesting.
Really.
In Asia, tyrants are adored.
The more terrible the tyrant,
the more his memory is cherished.
Alexander the Great, Timur
and your Peter the Great.
You're wrong about Peter.
He taught Russians to enjoy themselves.
A spiral staircase.
Where has everyone disappeared to?
I see. But why?
What's so interesting up there?
You'll see.
Peter, the man who ordered
his own son's execution.
The same man who taught the people
to enjoy life. How funny.
I thought you knew where we were going.
He built a European city upon a swamp.
He introduced order of the most primitive kind.
- Where are they going?
- But the city is still European.
To a party. But why by the back staircase?
They were taught to have fun.
So they go to parties.
And the officer and the lady?
- At the party.
- Where are they?
They've gone to the underworld.
Down, down, down!
And they are no more.
Be careful.
The stairs are steep, and it's dark.
Thank you. I can see.
Do you know where we are?
No, I don't know yet.
I don't know yet.
Sir, be careful.
Don't betray our presence.
There's no need to remind me.
Don't forget it was me
who brought you here.
Please don't be offended.
And you, don't get too close
to the actors.
Bend down.
You're beautiful.
- Stop pushing.
- Don't scratch me.
- Why is she pushing me?
- You're pushing too.
What an impressive orchestra.
They must be Europeans.
No, they're Russian musicians.
No, Europeans.
Italians.
They're Russians, for God's sake.
Well?
I say it's good.
Very good!
I need to pee!
I can't hold it in anymore.
No, no.
No. What? What?
Yes. Yes.
Sir. Sir.
Don't shout.
- Where are you?
- Here. My God, it's Catherine the Great.
Follow me.
I love the 18th century-
a time of genius and manners.
I would have to agree with you.
- Never contradict me.
- Very well.
Where's the czarina? Gone.
Russia is like a theater. A theater.
Careful.
I think I know where we are.
These petty officials.
How pretentious they are.
Don't lag behind, sir.
I'm not lagging.
I think we're speaking too loudly.
No matter. They're completely deaf.
I'm careful. I won't touch anyone.
It's all theater.
What actors. And what costumes.
Thank you, sirs. Thank you.
They don't see me.
Just like the Vatican.
Truly. It's like we're in the Vatican.
Those reliefs are painted, are they not?
What naturalism.
Look at them.
Weren't those decorations inspired
by sketches of Raphael?
Raphael, yes.
Better than the Vatican.
This is St. Petersburg.
So they're copies?
Your authorities don't have faith
in your own artists.
Russians are so talented at copying.
And why?
Because you don't have ideas of your own.
Your authorities don't want you
to have them.
In fact, they are as lazy
as all the rest of you.
Just lazy.
Lazy.
There was a gallery there for paintings.
- On the upper floor.
- 111 paintings- Italian masters.
- True, not the best masters.
- Not the best.
The czars were mainly Russophiles.
But they dreamed of Italy.
Wasn't the Hermitage created
to satisfy those dreams?
- Raphael isn't for you.
- Not for us.
For Italy.
It's warm there.
What beauty.
The small Italian gallery.
Who are these people?
From which era are they from?
Do you see that vase?
I see. I see.
Empire style is everywhere.
And those Voronikhin lamps.
Lamps, lamps, lamps.
Empire. Empire. Empire.
I have no enthusiasm for Empire style.
That style is too silly.
Don't forget it was born under Bonaparte.
Then it became fashionable here
to the point of becoming
the national style
to the detriment of its originality.
We battled Napoleon, not the Empire style.
Who are they? Who are these people?
The people of St. Petersburg,
after the city ceased being the capital.
It's better that way.
A capital city should be an ancient city,
not chimerical.
Like Moscow. Who are these people?
Should I introduce you?
- Only if it's not impolite.
- No, they are friends.
Then let's.
This is Oleg Konstantinovich,
professor of medicine.
Lev Mikhailovich, actor.
Shouldn't they rise?
This is my European friend.
He is visiting Russia.
- My pleasure.
- He's European.
Medicine is a fine profession.
I haven't spoken to anyone for a long time
aside from my new companion.
Such a long time. What is that odor?
What odor?
A curious odor.
- Have you been in St. Petersburg long?
- For an hour.
And you came straight here?
- I had my reasons.
- You must love art.
Are you interested in beauty
or just its representation?
- No, Marquis. We're here to rest.
- "Marquis"?
- This is how you rest?
- Just so.
Today, Oleg Konstantinovich
and I have come here-
It smells of formaldehyde.
Yes, formaldehyde.
Marquis, I'll show you a splendid painting.
These men are emitting a very strange odor.
Marquis, this is the
Birth of John the Baptist.
The marquis smells of formaldehyde.
I know this painting.
I saw it on my last visit here.
It comes from Paris,
from the Crozat collection.
Catherine acquired it in 1772.
One of the earliest pieces
of the Hermitage collection.
Such information, that's for specialists.
For us, the details are more interesting.
Look closely here.
See in the foreground?
A chicken and a cat.
They are symbolic figures.
The chicken represents greed, avarice.
The cat- cynicism and cruelty.
Cynicism and cruelty. The cat.
They are both calmed by the birth of John.
How interesting.
Very, very interesting.
Why is he dressed like that?
For example, the Cleopatra-
what do you know about it?
Massimo Stanzione.
The Cleopatra is on the same wall
as the Circumcision of Christ
by the pious Ludovico Cardi.
- What bothers you?
- What bothers me?
Right next to Saint Cecilia?
Can you imagine!
By Carlo Dolci.
And next to an Eastern Still Life!
- Why does that bother you?
- Don't argue, Oleg.
As a Catholic, that shocks me.
What do you think of Wagner?
Wagner? Who is Wagner?
Oleg, he doesn't know Wagner.
Wagner is that child who behaved badly
with my best friend, Meyerbeer.
I have never listened to Wagner.
- Broaden your horizons.
- That doctor is so insistent.
- But I'm not sick.
- We wish you much success.
Sir, why are they badly dressed?
My friends, how could I think
that you would get along?
One day, I'll explain everything.
I'm in a strange situation.
Sir. Sir, why quarrel with everyone?
If you do, we will never discover
why we are here.
Such clothing kills a man's creative essence.
Why do you find it necessary
to adopt European culture?
For what reason?
Why borrow also Europe's mistakes?
My God. What is all this?
What is it?
Mother!
Mother.
Canova!
What a sublime approach to art!
What feeling for the material!
How wonderful!
How wonderful. My God.
He is a true heir to the masters of antiquity.
Canova almost married my mother.
Was your mother a sculptress?
Yes, a sculptress. In Rome.
In Rome? Your mother, a sculptress.
In this Canova collection,
there are even sculptures
that Czar Alexander bought from the wife-
The wife of Napoleon?
Yes. It was 1815,
I was at the Congress of Vienna.
What were you doing there?
- I was a diplomat.
- You were a diplomat?
This collection was the object
of a serious dispute.
Look where we are now.
Is this a dream?
I don't know. I don't know.
I don't know about you,
but I'm wide awake.
It's amazing how well I speak Russian.
Yes, quite well.
Who was that small man?
Was that Pushkin?
- Good day.
Is that your great poet?
Your beloved one?
I read him in French. Nothing special.
Sir.
My God, how touchy you are.
Forgive me, please.
I'm sorry if I've offended
your nationalist sympathies.
"Nationalist sympathies." What is that?
What's that there?
- Sir. Please.
- Who is that?
Please don't be rash.
All alone, without a chaperone?
It would be wiser not to talk to that lady.
Don't bother her.
Let's move along.
Excuse me, madam.
Have you lost your guide?
Thank you for asking,
but I know this place well.
Of course. Do you work here?
Not at all. I'm here to admire
the works of the old masters.
Would you accompany me
into the next salon?
To see the Flemish masters?
With pleasure. Your slender fingers see all.
- 140 paces, straight ahead.
- 140 paces. Is that so?
How many are left?
Watch your step.
This way.
How dare you! Quiet!
- We're here.
- Yes, We're here.
Can we go closer to that painting?
Would you like me to tell you about it?
Virgin with Partridges by Van Dyck.
Catherine II acquired it.
Would you like to tell me
about this painting?
Please, tell me.
See the calm and serenity
around the Madonna and Joseph.
- Joseph, yes.
- God protects them.
There is no doubt about His unseen presence.
The apple tree represents life.
Sunflowers stand for piety.
On the upper right,
partridges symbolize frivolity.
- They're flying away.
- Partridges.
Angels dance and play.
So many other symbols
that we can only guess about.
Sir, leave her be. She's an angel.
Why have you gone quiet?
The partridges, the children, the Madonna.
Thank you, madam. Thank you.
I highly value your opinion
on the works of Van Dyck.
You'll definitely be interested
in another painting.
Be very careful.
A Rubens.
Sir, do not disturb me.
Feast in the House of Simon the Pharisee.
- Seventeen.
- I don't see it.
- Eighteen.
- Where is it?
The painting isn't here.
No, that painting isn't here.
It wasn't in the czar's collection.
Yes, it's here.
That particular Rubens is not here.
Yes. It was from Lord Walpole's collection.
Like the Virgin with Partridges.
But that Rubens isn't on exhibit.
But it's here.
- Where are you?
- What a wonderful scent.
The scent of oils.
Sir.
Sir, let's leave here now.
Let's leave.
- Where are you?
- No, let's stay a while.
What wonderful paintings.
What are those men counting?
You were right. I found it.
Let's take a closer look.
There it is.
We're almost there.
Face the painting directly.
There it is. There's the painting.
Yes, there it is.
Something to say about Rubens?
Van Dyck.
Rubens considered Van Dyck
to be his best pupil.
You know, there was a time
when all these paintings
were placed much higher
and much closer to one another.
The czar himself supervised
how they were hung.
Who are you?
I'm a sailor.
- What are those insignias?
- Navy.
The czar visited his collection every morning.
He himself saved all this during the fire.
- Which fire?
- The fire was in 1800-
Are you asking me?
Enough, let's go.
It's time for me to go.
May I accompany you?
No. No.
What a pity.
I must ask you to leave.
The museum is closing.
Please see yourself to the exit.
Quiet. Close the doors.
The museum is closing.
- How was my scene?
- I wasn't impressed.
I was joking.
Joking.
- Do you hear music?
- I hear something.
Russian music makes me break out in hives.
That has nothing to do with the music.
Why do you look at me like that?
Rags. A dog.
Eternal people.
So, live on. Live on.
- You'll outlive them all.
- Eternal people.
What are you doing?
Eavesdropping?
Are you interested in painting?
What nice small hands.
Stay away from me.
Amen. Amen.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Beautiful. Beautiful.
- Are you Catholic?
- No, I'm not Catholic.
Why do you ask?
It seemed to me that you were deep in thought
while admiring these images
of the founders of our Church.
I don't know.
I wasn't thinking about that.
You weren't thinking.
Do you know that those are
the apostles Peter and Paul?
Yes, that's what someone said.
That's what they said?
And so?
I was looking at them
because it gives me joy.
Gives you joy-
One day, all men will become like them.
Really?
How can you know what will become of people
if you don't know the Scriptures?
Why aren't you saying anything?
Look at their hands.
The hands are beautiful. So?
How can you know what will become of people
if you don't know the Scriptures?
As for you, they're just two dusty old men.
Just flesh.
They're covered with the dust of the road
as they appear in the painting.
- What happened?
- They are good and wise.
How could you know what they're like
if you have not read the Gospels?
How could you know all that?
Sir, why are you frightening him?
He was already afraid.
He's not afraid.
- These people are never afraid.
- Leave him be.
Better to appreciate the scent of the paintings.
It smells good.
Only you're not afraid of anything.
So strange to hear those words.
Now I understand. We're in the gallery.
Yes, yes, yes.
I understand.
We're in the czar's gallery
near the portrait of a medieval fanatic.
Where have we wandered to?
That music was good, after all.
- Who was the composer?
- Glinka.
Glinka? A German.
A Russian.
A German. All composers are German.
All composers are German.
El Greco.
Very nice.
Looks like a Rembrandt.
El Greco. Dust from the road.
What dust from the road?
Nice, very nice.
- Something you don't like?
- Not at all.
It's nice, very nice.
Nice, very nice.
More flesh. Very nice.
These are nice paintings.
Nice paintings.
They're getting better and better.
There's an angel.
Pardon me for addressing you
without an introduction.
- To whom was that directed?
- What?
Do tell.
- I'm speaking to the painting.
- Speaking to-
Yes. How interesting.
- I must express myself.
- Do continue.
That's how to communicate with it.
Would you like to try?
I should try? Very well.
- Like that.
- Like this?
Now like this.
Now a turn.
And like this.
Sometimes I prefer to speak alone.
This painting and I, we have a secret.
Really?
- Yes.
- Now it's over.
That's all, gentlemen.
Good-bye. Good-bye.
Where are you going, madam?
She's offended. She has left.
She's left.
- Hello.
- Hello, hello.
Good-bye. Good-bye.
Farewell, gentleman.
How charming!
She's offended. But so charming.
Where has she gone?
Marble.
White, white...
stone.
It's cold, isn't it?
When you first came here,
it must have been a disaster.
That was just after the fire.
I have been here before,
but it's as if I have not.
What luxury.
What is that?
It was under the Convention
that everything was devastated.
You don't know 20th-century Russian history.
Our Convention lasted 80 years.
A real revolution. Very sad.
What kind of system is there now?
A republic?
I don't know.
I have never believed
that a republic was suitable
for a country as large as Russia.
You Europeans are democrats
who mourn the monarchy.
You are French, is that it?
- Stop. Who are you?
- And who are you?
Excuse us. We're lost.
- Please be on your way.
- Spare us! Spare us!
- You are forbidden here.
- Help us, please.
Who forbids it? What is forbidden?
What language. Everything is forbidden.
It's better not to argue. Let's leave.
We're going, We're going.
I know where we can hide.
I suddenly feel afraid.
I don't like military uniforms.
- Don't rush.
- There's a door ahead.
Not that door, sir.
But I like it. Such a beautiful door.
No, not that one.
I have never been here.
Why is it so cold?
I told you not to enter.
What cold!
Frames. But where are-
Where are the canvases?
Let's go back, I beg you.
- Who's there?
- It's me.
- What's happening?
- Nothing. I simply entered.
- Come closer.
- I'm coming.
Maybe you need help, kind sir.
Maybe I can help.
What?
Who is the "kind sir"?
Me. You.
Not here, not there.
There is no one.
Only coffins and corpses.
Come and see.
- I'm coming.
- That's my coffin.
- Your coffin?
- Yes, I made it myself.
Why that strange tone, kind sir?
Why are there coffins in the Hermitage?
Kind sir.
- It's my coffin.
- Your coffin?
- Yours. All right.
- He looks well-fed.
- But where are the corpses?
Why do you ask where?
Don't step on the corpses.
He looks well-fed.
You stepped on the corpses!
- What happened?
- A war.
- What?
Which war? Against whom?
- Against Germany.
- Germany? What is this "Germany"?
The unified German state.
In the 20th century,
Russia was at war with Germany.
The German army surrounded the city,
but the city did not surrender.
More than one million people died.
- What? More than one million?
- More than one million.
That's a high price to pay.
Very high.
St. Petersburg and the Hermitage paid dearly.
In Russia, it is said
that freedom knows no price.
- A very high price.
- Certainly high.
But maybe not so high.
- But it's already been paid.
- All the same, I was wrong.
I was wrong
when I criticized your czars
for all this beauty and opulence.
Even if they all were... tyrants.
Please. Not so loud.
But it is beautiful, isn't it?
What do you see? Who is it?
I'm not sure. Maybe Catherine.
Nothing could be less sure.
That's enough. Lisa, bring the children.
Don't go too near her.
If it is Catherine, she has a sixth sense.
Like this.
Lower. Lower.
That will be all.
The candles. The candles.
It's stuffy in here.
- There?
- Over here.
Over here.
No, benefactress, not there.
It's much too cold.
Just so. Just so.
But it's cold.
Sir!
Where are you?
I hear your footsteps.
Mortals should not chase after royalty.
Careful not to catch up with her.
I hear your footsteps.
I hear them.
Sir, what are you doing? It's cold.
- Come this way.
- Yes, it's cold.
Come on, let's go.
- She disappeared.
- I know.
- She disappeared again.
- Move aside.
- Do you know where to go?
- Help us.
- Come on, let's go.
- Isn't he letting us in?
Let us through. We are allowed.
Where is the door? Where is it?
Greetings.
Don't be shy. Come.
We won't stay long.
Where are you taking me?
Thank you very much.
A new hairstyle is necessary.
What beautiful hair you have.
Those curls!
Thank you.
They're offering us tea.
Will you have tea?
I don't want any, but they insist.
Where is the tea?
We're in a hurry. Where is it?
- I know I'm beautiful.
- Too beautiful.
What do you want me to say?
What can I say?
No, no! I can't explain.
I have nothing to say.
What is this?
- Did you write this book?
- Not me. He did.
Neither he nor I.
But he will dedicate it.
Follow me.
Sir, what are you looking at?
Shall we continue?
What do I see?
Nothing for the moment.
Some people are obviously waiting for something.
Let's proceed with caution.
- These madmen could eat us.
- They liked your hair.
Of course. I'm a writer.
Good writers always have beautiful hair.
- Be more careful and quiet now.
- I'm following you.
- Close the doors quickly.
- The doors are closed.
When I was last received here
at the Winter Palace,
it was being renovated
after the terrible fire.
The parquet doesn't creak.
- The ambassador of Persia!
- Excuse us for being late.
Let's go, let's go.
The ambassador of His Highness the Shah.
Excuse us. Excuse us.
Prince Khozrow Mirza,
son of the future shah,
with his entourage.
- Do you know what is happening?
- No.
We're watching Nicholas I
as he receives an apology
from the Persian emissaries
regarding the murder of Russian diplomats.
Griboedov was one, I think.
Excuse us.
How interesting.
Are you able to see?
What uniforms.
Luxury. Empire.
Power.
Look over there. Up ahead.
Get up on your tiptoes.
Can you see?
Yes, I see now.
One must not trust this world.
You are right.
Beware.
Court officials are cunning.
Some of them are mediums.
They can sense your presence.
Thank you for your advice.
We Geminis are curious by nature.
I'll go ahead. Maybe I'll meet
some of my old acquaintances.
Good luck. I'll find you later.
He's so young.
"Mighty Sovereign Emperor,
the peaceful nature of Persia
and the sacred union that exists
among His Majesty and the shah
both were upset by evil.
Under the influence of this power,
a frenzied Tehran crowd
committed unheard of acts of evil.
The resulting victim was the Russian mission.
The honest heart of Fath 'Ali Shah
was horrified by the idea
that a handful of wrongdoers
might destroy our peace and union.
His Majesty the Shah has sent me, his grandson,
to request that you, Sovereign,
erase from memory this event.
Let the world know that,
despite this terrible event,
two wise monarchs, with their infinite wisdom,
speak openly and vanquish all suspicion.
With the greatest joy,
I stand before you,
Your Imperial Majesty.
I carry out my grandfather's will-
that we strengthen peace
between our two peoples."
"His Imperial Majesty
commands me to assure Your Excellence
of his pleasure at hearing your explanation,
as well as the righteous plea
of your sovereign."
I've been observing you.
Who let you in here?
- You have no business here.
- No business at all.
Then you must leave at once.
Off you go, sir. Away.
- I had no intention of staying.
- Away.
This ceremony will continue
for a few more hours still.
As a former diplomat, I'm aware of that.
A terrible boredom will set in.
A terrible boredom.
Leave me alone.
- And what is that?
- What did you say?
I adore luxury and regal splendor.
Stasov wasn't a bad architect.
He loved discipline,
but left space for breathing.
We cannot stay here.
The ceremony will finish.
Then they will all come in.
My God.
This is Svres porcelain.
My weakness.
- Beautiful.
- Yes, yes.
- It's inimitable.
- Beautiful.
This is the Cameo Service, isn't it?
Yes, it is.
Not so close, please.
What gold.
Sir, it's awkward setting the table
with you here.
You can admire it later
when you are seated.
What pure tones.
The blue and gold are enchanting.
And the wine sediment color.
Always such marvelous cooks
here in the Winter Palace.
Do you recall the taste of food?
No, I have forgotten.
You've forgotten.
Visit the other salons
while waiting for the dinner bell.
- That blue.
- Please, sir.
I beg you.
There's dancing. Come on.
I beg you. Please.
We beg you. Please.
We're getting out.
They chased us out.
It's so dark here.
Heavens.
I see you have never seen a czar.
Nor emperors, nor grand princes
in all their magnificence.
Monarchy is not eternal.
You think I don't know that?
Don't I have the right to dream a little?
We are free, you and I. Dream away.
There's someone here. Do you hear voices?
Sir, don't you hear them?
No, I don't hear anything.
Look. Someone is moving there.
Where?
Mr. Orbeli, I don't understand.
What has upset you so?
You and my father know that
no insects can harm this throne.
- It's made of silver and treated oak.
- It's not the throne.
I'm very worried.
Look at that velour from Lyon.
It's completely worn out.
- We'll restore it. Be patient.
- You don't have the time.
You're right, Boris.
We don't have time at all.
You won't ever see him again.
Speak.
He's your son.
What difficulty are they having?
They seem uncomfortable.
What do you expect?
You descend from the heavens
and no longer know how to behave yourself.
Your son is the director of the Hermitage.
Like you and I before him.
The wars ahead- terrible wars.
But we managed to preserve all this
through the catastrophes.
I can't hear anymore. Can you hear?
I can hear, but not very clearly.
What are they saying?
The elder Piotrovsky is asking
whether the director's telephone
is still under surveillance.
His son says, "Forget about that.
I'd rather talk to you
about the Hermitage cats.
The cats are still here."
There are so many people
that I wasn't able to help.
Ten years have passed.
You know what I'm referring to.
But everyone speaks well of you.
Your books are still in print.
Those of Mr. Orbeli too.
That's particularly admirable.
The dead weep with joy
when their books are reprinted.
Especially 37 years later, Mikhail.
Is something still troubling you?
Is it the authorities?
They want acorns without oak trees.
They are not interested in knowing
how to nurture the tree of culture.
But it will be their doom
if the tree falls.
Then there will be nothing left.
Can't they understand that?
Mr. Orbeli, what awaits us?
- I'm coming.
- Speak!
- Listen, Mikhail.
- Let him go.
You're completely alone.
They won't tell him anything.
I know. Ask me.
I am asking you.
I know. Everyone can see the future,
but no one remembers the past.
Look how handsome they are.
Such fine young men!
Beautiful uniforms,
even if I don't like the military.
You didn't answer my question.
You don't know. You don't know anything.
Sir. Wait. Wait.
He doesn't hear me.
I must apologize.
They were talking about all sorts of things.
I could hardly hear them.
I made it all up- about Orbeli.
About Piotrovsky too.
- Only God can judge you.
- I made it all up.
We are free, you and I.
You said it yourself.
Please, don't run.
Run. I can't keep up with you.
Little birds.
Children.
Anastasia, where are you going?
They are...
so light.
You're always watching me.
- I have a bad feeling.
- Don't be alarmed.
Pray. And I shall pray for you.
Did you hear that?
Did you hear shots?
Calm down. God is with you.
I think someone is following us.
Calm yourself, Alexandra.
- If only Alexis could run.
- Calm yourself.
Doctors are good for nothing.
There is no hope.
It's my fault.
Children.
- Children, behave yourselves.
- Sorry, excuse us.
Come here, Anastasia.
Where were you?
I looked for you all morning.
- We were playing.
- Let's go.
Where is Alexis?
- Thank you. I can manage.
- Of course.
- Are you in pain?
- I'm fine, Mother.
Move your chair forward.
You're very strong.
You're late for tea.
- What?
- Forgive me, please.
Shall we forgive her?
What do you think?
Anastasia won't do it again.
See, it's all over.
Good-bye.
Why are these doors open?
Fly away, fly away-
Fly away, my little angels.
And here's their cage.
They're all here, of course.
There haven't been so many guests
for a long time.
Good evening.
Look at that strange fellow.
But...
where has my European gone to?
Where is he?
There he is.
He doesn't see me.
I should go up to him.
Otherwise he will be offended.
Sir! He can't hear me.
But I'll see him later.
Wouldn't it be nice
to jump about like that?
You know,
Aristarkh Konstantinovich is being sent to Africa.
What a tiger. He could eat anyone.
Your mother has trained the servants well.
You're doing very well.
The thing about the mazurka is-
We had an agreement.
More! More!
The Great Nicholas Hall is ideal for dancing.
Thank you.
St. Petersburg has the best balls in Europe.
Everyone is so easygoing.
Like one big family.
There must be over 3,000 people.
Maybe less.
I've forgotten everything!
I dance so poorly.
But it's all coming back to me.
Good. Very good.
How beautiful.
Thank you. Thank you.
More! More!
Where were you? I lost you.
I'm here. Here I am.
I lost you.
Lost you.
I'm sad.
- Let's go.
- Where to?
Where to? Forward.
Forward.
What will we find there?
What's there? I don't know.
I'm staying.
Farewell, Europe.
It's over.
You might say I grew up here.
I'm not quite myself.
As if I were in someone else's house.
Listen up! Look here!
Poor man, your lady has gone away.
- Flown away like a bird.
- Gone.
In a flash.
Look around us.
The flower of Russian officers.
I have an idea. Shall we dine together?
Good.
I'll wait downstairs. Bring up the coach.
Have our coats brought up.
And don't lose them.
When we return to Kursk,
we must organize a ball.
Perhaps just before Lent.
We should invite your nephew,
as well as Vareneka.
Let him see her.
Nathalie!
It feels like we're floating.
Let me pass.
Sir.
Sir. Sir.
A pity you're not here with me.
You would understand everything.
Look.
The sea is all around.
And we are destined to sail forever,
to live forever.