Hey Sher Singh!
Hail freedom!
Get up!
No, not the country's...[CHUCKLES]
Only yours...
Follow me.
[CHAINS CLANKING]
[MARCHING ORDER]
[DOOR CLOSING SOUND]
[MARKET CHATTER]
[DOOR KNOCKING]
Clothes...
Nand Singh is here.
Send him.
All HSRA comrades
are either arrested
or shot dead.
Our movement has ended.
-Passport?
-Lahore.
I need a pistol!
You won't be able to cross the border.
It will be delivered
to you in Afghanistan.
London's details.
You're being followed.
[MARKET CHATTER]
-When did he leave?
-Last night.
Why don't you settle down?
You all want to kiss the noose, right?
Water...
Take care, cousin.
Good afternoon, Sir!
-Yes?
-Sir, Sher Singh is absconding.
Since when?
Since a week.
Come.
Putting you through now.
-Hello.
-SP Patiala, Sir.
We found an application of a new passport,
for England, Sir.
It matches the description of the suspect,
Sher Singh.
But the passport is issued
in the name of Ude Singh, Sir.
Name again?
Ude Singh, Sir!
Send through all the old
photographs you have and the aliases.
-We'll do what we can to help.
-Right, Sir!
[SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
[MAN PRAYING]
-For long, the Britishers have fooled us.
-Hmm.
Our youth has become complacent.
They say we have access to
trains, electricity, cinema halls…
Huh. The British are doing so much.
They don't realize the British
are doing this for a purpose...
They dig deep into our land to loot us...
rob us of our resources
and then, load the loot for England.
[WHISTLES]
[GRASS HUSTLING]
[FOOTSTEPS]
Bhagat!
-Get the boxes.
-How many revolvers?
Eight.
-Rounds?
-300.
He has never fired a gun but is a
master at sourcing them...[LAUGHTER]
Working, right?
Send these to Rawalpindi.
Yes.
[SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
[DOGS BARKING]
A romantic folk tale?
So, you've converted to
being a socialist![SMILES]
Love for humanity,
that's what it's all about!
If something happens to me...
you know they won't spare me.
For the organization to
function smoothly after me,
I need to share something.
In that case, we will need a third person.
Why?
Because they're not
going to spare me either.
I am destined to meet the same fate.
Hello... is anyone around?
If the turnaround is to happen...
it is now
or else forget about the revolution!
[LAUGHTER]
[SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
[SHIP HORN]
Foreign passports to immigration!
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Passport?
Go.
Passport please.
Here you go.
Uh, Oxford street?
Sure, Sir.
"The nation is finally showing
its first major signs of a recovery,
unemployment has begun to fall
and the drop in interest rates has led
to a booming construction in the South
stimulating renewed economic growth.
The two dictators, Adolf
Hitler and Benito Mussolini
have previously met in Venice.
Il Duce arrived in Munich today.
With his foreign minister Count Ciano,
to discuss immediate
plans with the Fuhrer.
Thousands cheered the Fascist leaders
who agreed on a Hands-Off-Austria policy
"in what is being termed
as a historic event."
Koppikar - Punjab restaurant.
He's not here, you can
check at the Sikh temple.
So you never returned to America…
Then you should have
been here 6 months ago?
HSRA, back home, is completely dismantled.
And you'll regroup here?
We barely have funds,
we need to spend wisely.
What's your plan?
Indians here are contented.
How will you shake up their conscience?
Under what name have you entered?
-Sher Singh.
-Change it!
By now MI5 and Scotland
Yard would have issued alerts.
Take up a job.
And as the British say,
'lie low for sometime.'
Let me introduce you
this is Abir Mukherjee.
A barrister, and our ideologue.
Dutta, Sumer Singh,
Rihana Siddiqui, a lawyer.
In-charge of women's wing.
Sameer Bandopadhyay,
and that's Surat Ali.
Associated with the Indian Workers union.
Behind you, our youth wing workers.
And you'll meet Johal at the Sikh temple.
When did you last meet Bhagat Singh?
Before being arrested.
Then, I just got his letter.
What were his last words?
To garner international support.
Can you speak English?
I can manage.
These are some contacts.
Can I have a sweet?
Mother!
Mother…
Is anyone alive?
[GUNSHOT]
"With Hitler continuing
unrestrained in his
pursuance of Nazi world domination
the writing on the wall is clear.
That world is headed for all out war.
Neville Chamberlain's appeasement
policy has clearly failed the nation
and first lord of the Admiralty,
Winston Churchill, in
his wartime broadcast
has warned the nation to
be prepared for a long conflict
"of 3 years or more."
Ladies and gentlemen,
it is a great privilege for me to
be here to talk to you on behalf
of the East India Association and
the Royal Central Asian Society.
In the war that is at our door step,
the empire will need all her fighting men.
In the last war,
I filled all the quotas
for Indian soldiers.
Over 100,000 Sikh soldiers from my Punjab
fought for the crown.
And
I made sure that the Indians
contributed generously
to the war loan.
The Empire was
and is
a force for good.
And that is why, ladies and gentlemen,
it is not only our right but our duty
to rule India.
Without us, they will return to savagery,
looting and killing one another.
It is not only Africa
ladies and gentlemen,
that is the white man's burden.
With the benefit of my
experience, I can tell you
that these reforms have been effective.
The country
is unified once more. It is peaceful.
Thank you very much.
Thank you. Thank you.
[CHEERING CONTINUES]
Great to see you.
Mister Dwyer!
-[GUN SHOTS]
-[SCREAMS]
Police!
It is all over!
All over!
It is all over.
I shot him! I shot him!
Caxton Hall!
Stretcher coming through.
It's all over, it's of no use!
It is all over!
Check his pulse.
He killed thousands.
He has killed thousands.
It is all over.
[INDISTINCT MURMUR]
[CROWD HURLING ABUSES]
-Hello...
-Lady O'Dwyer...
He shouted "Sir Dwyer."
He fired 6 shots.
[CRYING] And the shot
it hit him in the chest.
-[GASPS]
-I'm so sorry.
"Sir Michael O'Dwyer, the former
Lieutenant Governor of the Punjab
during the time of the
Amritsar affair of 1919 was
shot dead by an Indian
man in London earlier today."
Sir Michael was addressing a meeting
of the East India Association presided
over by Lord Zetland, the Secretary of
State for India, who was badly injured.
Former Governors of Punjab and Bombay.
Lord Lamington and Sir
Louis Dane were also wounded
and are now receiving
emergency treatment in hospital.
The assassin who fired
six shots in quick succession
"was immediately
apprehended by the police."
He served the British Empire dutifully
in the most turbulent
period of time in the Punjab.
Between the years 1912 and 1919.
"Germany calling!"
"This is Lord Haw Haw."
The sun finally seems to be setting
over the British empire.
Like their elephants,
the Indians never forget their enemies.
"They strike them down
even after twenty years."
-Bloody Indians!
-Who is behind this murder?
Witnesses have confirmed
that he is a man of Indian origin.
We have recovered a pistol
and live ammunition from
him, about nine rounds.
Further links are being investigated.
But we will not tolerate such violence.
Such acts of terrorism.
A cowardice within our country.
We will stand up together
and rise up against brutal crime
and we will crush
any movement
against the Empire!
I am absolutely certain
he won't name anyone.
But
he did it!
He was always stubborn.
Hats off to him.
I mean...
Such coverage by the world press
no incident has been covered so widely.
Reported across 12-15 countries.
Tell me who your other associates are?
[GRUNTS] [COUGHS]
What organization do you work for?
[COUGHS]
[GROANS]
Why did you do this?
Tell me the names of your associates?
[GROANS] Uh...
Who are your associates?...[GROANS]
Keep going.
This is the last place he lived?
Yes, Sir.
Check underneath the bed.
Sir.
Quite the collection.
Take a look at this, Sir.
Directory.
Hmm...
Caxton Hall.
Alright.
You sure he is the same man?
Yes Sir, we are certain of it, Sir!
Punjab '39...
Punjab '33 here we go, this is the one.
Well if he is our man and
he came in six years ago
what the hell has he
been doing since then?
Bring him down.
You are coming with us.
Sit down and shut up!
-Who all have come from India?
-Sir, I did.
-When did you enter England?
-In January.
Show me your passport!
What do you know about this Sher Singh?
On your feet.
Are you Surat Ali?
-Mr. Koppikar do you know this man?
-Yes.
I had nothing to do with this killing.
He did it alone.
You deny your links to
the Communist party?
[EXHALES] No.
So, he met you quite a
few times this umm...?
Yes, at the Sikh temple,
a couple of times may be.
Just a couple?
Maybe more, I don't remember.
-How did he get the gun?
-I don't know.
You don't know?
That's all?
Yes, that's all.
You will have to come with us, Sir.
He is a small time businessman
his name is Bawa.
Fond of 'laddoos'
I mean sweets.
Very passionate about
India's independence.
What else?
I told you, Sir. He used to
visit the Sikh temple sometimes.
Cut this nonsense. What else?
I don't know much about him.
Right, so what have we got?
Well, we figured out he worked
in a cotton mill in the Punjab…
In about 1919.
-Any Family?
-An orphan.
His mother died when he was six.
His father soon after that.
He and his brother, Ude,
they grew up in an orphanage.
Any other relatives?
Some cousins, but we are not sure yet.
Immigration records show he entered London
several times since 1933
using different names,
Sher Singh, Ude Singh,
Udham Singh, Azad Singh and Frank Brazil.
He first settled in a small
apartment in East London,
and constantly shifted
residences almost every 6 months,
from the East across to the
Southwest, at Bournemouth.
Yeah. While here... he tried to
organize an international network
of rebels for the Ghadr party making
contact with sources across Europe.
There is a police complaint
against him in 1937
for publicly beating another Indian
in a brawl in a bar in South London.
He obtained a local peddler's
license working odd jobs
as a stationery salesman,
also as an extra on a movie set.
I am a salesman.
Sometime later, he is spotted
at a flea market selling lingerie,
and he owns a Fiat car by now…
Our last entry in the records
show him working as a welder
in an iron factory in East London.
This was about 6 months
before the assassination.
I heard this man was under our watch!
How did he slip through?
Well, he was put under watch nine years
ago Sir, when he left prison in India,
and in that time he basically kept his
head down and we lost track of him.
Few weeks ago we had a
tip off from the passport office,
but by the time we had got
there, he had already fled.
Are there any other conspirators?
Any other associates?
There may be others waiting
to strike at high level targets.
Have a look at the Germans,
-we can't take any chances.
-Sir.
-[GROANS]
-Who are you?
What is your name?
When is the next attack gonna happen?
You thought you got them all
didn't you?
Well you didn't!
Only four bullets?
I had pumped in all six.
Zetland is also dead, right?
He said he fired six times.
Isn't Zetland dead?
Only O'Dwyer?
I am gonna ask you
one more time.
Who are your associates?
[GROANS]
[LAUGHS]
I do not feel pain...
I see death...
feel no pain.
Water...
[GRUNTING]
You have eluded us for nine years.
You must have made
some really nice friends.
Come on, tell me their names!
Tell me everything
about your collaborators.
Come on...
Tell me about the next target.
[YELLS IN PAIN]
[MUFFLED CRY]
Who...[PAINFUL SOBBING]
Is the next attack for?
Come on you can tell me.
[YELLS IN PAIN]
Just try
just try and give us one little name.
[YELLS IN PAIN]
Tell me of all the other important
figures you were following.
[SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
Are you Russian?
Are these your papers?
So.
Did he have any visitors?
An Indian man...
and a lady.
An Indian lady?
No.
British?
Yes.
-Detective Thomson, Sir.
-Yes, put him through.
Sir, he was frequently
visited by a British woman,
an active member of the communist party,
I suspect he may have established
links with other extremists through her.
[CROWD PROTESTING]
Down with imperialism!
World in peace!
Not in pieces!
Eileen
Eileen Palmer...
Eileen?
I...
I... Surat Ali... friend.
Surat Ali's friend.
You are not registered
with the party, are you?
Party? Uh... yes, yes I was...
Ah... In India... HSRA
I was... party.
H.S.R.A?
Bhagat Singh's H.S.R.A?
You know him!
-You know Bhagat Singh...?
-Yeah [SMILES]
What do you want?
I need help.
I fight for freedom of my people.
Fight for the freedom of the whole world!
World... Umm...
no...
You equal, you march for being equal
I'm not equal.
I'm not free.
When my country is free
then, I shall march as
an equal, for equality.
Hmm!
I am Detective Inspector Swain.
I am in charge of your case.
You can start by telling us your name.
What is your actual name?
Tell us your name.
No?
[YELLS IN PAIN]
[GROANS]
[COUGHS]
This is Scotland Yard.
We will dig everything
out one way or another.
So.
Who were your collaborators and
regular associates?
Who else is with you?
There is no way that a carefully planned
assassination like this can be carried out
without the support of a big organization.
Which organization is
behind this assassination?
There has to be an organization!
You first came to England in 1933.
Is that right?
Since when you were a regular at the...
Shepherd's Bush Sikh temple,
and the Punjab Restaurant?
You must have had the support of all our
regular rebels who frequent such places?
Did you meet other
extremists at the Sikh temple?
Koppikar...
S.S. Johal, Surat Ali.
You honestly expect me to
believe that they were not involved?
What about Eileen Palmer?
What's the nature of your
association with Eileen Palmer?
What is your relationship with her?
When did you meet her?
When you first came here?
This way, miss.
In you go.
So you admit that you know him?
You surely knew he was a wanted
man before he came to England.
I knew him but
he didn't talk much.
His past is a mystery to me as well.
So...
for just how long have you known him?
It's been about four years!
And you saw him throughout that period?
Frequently,
but not all the time.
You knew him
very well.
Would you say that you were
just a friend or
maybe a little more than that?
Hmm?
Don't you think that's personal?
Were you aware...
of what he was planning to do?
No!
I already told you… I didn't know.
Contact of Lewis and Connor
they work with the IRA.
Have you met them?
No.
“In a major raid on suspected
Irish Republican Army hideouts,
the police have seized
more than 3 tons of explosives
along with large amount
of propaganda material
seeking new recruits
to join the Irish rebellion.
Seven men have been
arrested and one fatally shot.”
You... Stop... Now!
[GUNSHOT]
“Intelligence agencies say
the raid was significant
in preventing the IRA
from imminent acts of
sabotage on British soil.
The call to ban the Irish
nationalist guerrilla group
has been gaining
momentum in political circles.”
So what is it that you are planning to do?
Hmm?
You are planning something
how can I stop you?
I need guns.
-Your contacts from IRA or...
-I have nothing to do with them!
I'm a prisoner, in my own country…
Under watch all the time.
I can't... I... I can't.
I have no choice…no liberty,
cannot express my voice.
Even poetry is banned, No free will
can't breathe.
I am here in exile, forced
out of my own country...
If you want the freedom of your people
you should be there, not here...
Go back...
Go home...
and fight shoulder to shoulder with them.
Shoulder to shoulder? Yes I would like to
I can't...
My party HSRA, finished
everybody shot... hanged.
So I fight in a different way.
Eileen!
Please!
-This house?
-Just through there. From the left.
-There...? thank you.
-Yeah. No problem.
Hmm!
I want the landing in India.
Balance
after delivery.
Why should I trust you?
You know of Bloody Sunday?
I have lived it, in India.
I have seen death.
Have not slept, in years...
Your revolution and mine, is the same.
Our enemy, common!
You and I both are lambs,
to the same butcher.
You see Eileen, I am finding
it increasingly hard to believe
that you were unaware
of his extremist activities.
He wasn't regular in any manner.
In fact he was erratic,
somewhat capricious.
While he was here,
he made a deal between
the IRA and the Indian rebels,
for arms
fortunately we intercepted that shipment.
Are you aware of that?
"British police have foiled an
arms conspiracy between Irish and
Indian rebels after a major
consignment containing grenades,"
"rifles and pistols was intercepted at
the port of Calcutta, in Northern India."
"Links with the banned revolutionary
group, the IRA are being investigated..."
How did this blunder happen?
Were your contacts trustworthy?
The leak was internal...
Now?
Surveillance on us has increased,
there have been raids in Ireland.
Staying here is risky.
Leave for Russia immediately.
You be safe.
And thank you, for helping.
You are not going to come back?
I will continue my fight.
There is a re-entry here
under the name of.
Ude Singh, is that you?
We have confirmation now
that you re-entered from Russia.
Who did you meet?
The Red Army?
The communist politburo?
Another arms deal perhaps?
Where was the delivery planned... hmm?
Here in London or was it Spain?
Is that why you travelled
to Spain from Russia?
To support the
communists in their civil war?
[SPEAKS RUSSIAN]
But
without the support of an
anti-colonial country like yours.
Who would listen to us?
You are a world power
it is vital that you intervene
against the imperialist British.
Our comrades don't have
weapons, how will they fight?
We need weapons.
We will discuss with the Politburo,
and I assure you that the
Soviet Union is with you.
But we are busy preparing for war
and now is not a good time for us.
So, what else were you planning then?
A little bombing campaign perhaps?
Did you go to Russia and Germany?
Who did you meet there?
Did you really think that
the Nazis and the Russians
would lend a helping hand
and we would just stand idly by?
[CHUCKLES]
You want us to believe that
you came back only for O'Dwyer?
Hmm?
Yes?
He lives near Kensington Gardens.
Visits church on Mondays.
Cinema hall on Fridays.
And the club on Saturdays.
-Sure it is him?
-I've seen him.
So Michael, I'll see you at 12 o'clock.
[LAUGHTER]
And so ladies and gentlemen,
we come to Amritsar.
And inevitably if we come to Amritsar,
we talk about General Dyer.
Now one knows the authorities' opinion
of General Dyer and so did he.
He died a broken man,
but unrepented.
And I have no hesitation in saying
that General Dyer's action that day
was the decisive factor
in crushing the rebellion.
[CROWD CLAPPING]
The seriousness, the seriousness
of which is now generally realized.
But the Hunter commission
would not hear a word of evidence
to say that the Punjab rebellion
was connected in any way whatsoever
to the Afghan invasion.
The Indian Congress
made a report that's called the
Indian Congress Report on the Punjab.
Most of it written by Gandhi.
And in that he says
that it was my intention to crush
political consciousness in India.
No Mr. Gandhi
my intention
was to crush lawlessness... and rebellion!
[CROWD CLAPPING]
[GUNSHOT]
[BREATHING HEAVILY]
Exquisite!
How much for the box?
Free, Sir.
-Free?
-For you.
-For me?
-Yes. Ah...
I
I know you, Sir. I served below you.
You were the Governor, I
I was a worker at the factory...
Railways... India!
India... ah... Thank you, Emma!
India... hmm...
That's a trait I have always
admired in the Indians.
The willingness to please.
India huh! Awful weather,
terrible food.
Never bothered to learn the language.
But I served the crown well in India.
Now, the ordinary people
the common people, the
peasants, they liked us.
Never had any trouble with us!
-But the educated...
-Sir
some of my friends...
not me, friends, students
they protested along with the commoners.
Students
communists
they incited the common people
they instigated the rebellion.
I am also educated, Sir.
But you seem rational.
You are here, in the
heart of the British Empire
making a good, honest,
lawful living like us.
You'll make a good salesman.
Thank you, Sir.
H.S.R.A.
Hindustan Socialist
Republican Association.
Is this organization still active?
HSRA... you used to be a member!
Is Koppikar or...
S.S. Johal a member? Hmm?
You were associated with
Bhagat Singh too, didn't you?
Don't talk about Bhagat Singh!
He says let's not talk about him.
I have your whole history here
you might as well tell me.
Now wake up man!
They are not going to let you
walk away from this, this time!
They are going to hang you
like they did Bhagat Singh!
They call us 'Rebels'...
If asking for your rights,
is being rebellious…
Then, yes, we are rebels!
That was earlier,
now they label us 'Terrorists!'
There is a difference between
a terrorist and a revolutionary...
A significant difference!
A revolutionary's action is symbolic
meant to register a protest.
Their motive is not to create fear.
On the contrary, they inspire
to fight for rights!
People's own rights!
Purpose of a revolutionary
is to fight for freedom.
And freedom for all!
A true revolutionary has
to follow certain tenets.
You cannot be prejudiced,
nor communal,
nor casteist.
There is no economic
or social class difference.
The only truth
is equality.
Equality!
To treat all humans as equals,
with a strong belief in humanity!
There is a significant
difference, brother!
-Yes, understood.
-Okay, Bhagat
after freedom; What first?
Oh! After freedom.
I will watch a Chaplin film,
buy an expensive British wine
and…
Ma'am -Me?
With a English lady by my side
I will do the ball dance. [LAUGHTER]
…then just eat and sleep.
[LAUGHTER]
Then get up in the morning
have a bath,
and repeat the routine...[LAUGHTER]
Ask him
what was he doing when he was 23?
He is asking what you were
doing when you were 23?
What was I doing when I was 23...
Tell me.
I was just married.
We were expecting our first born.
I was the
youngest detective constable on the force.
Happy days!
Hmm...
So don't talk about Bhagat Singh!
You know nothing about him.
"The two men responsible
for throwing bombs
at the central assembly hall in Delhi
have been identified as Bhagat
Singh and Batukeshwar Dutt,
both belonging to the Hindustan
Socialist Republican Association.
Shouting slogans like
'Long live the revolution, '
'Down with imperialism' and
'Workers of the world unite, '
Both men did not flee after the
act but willingly courted arrest.
Throwing pamphlets that cited
their rationale for the bombing,
"To make the deaf hear."
With the Labour party watching closely
the ruling Conservatives
have decided to order strict
prosecution of the members
of the revolutionary outfit,
H.S.R.A.
In a nationwide strike,
police have successfully
raided suspected hideouts
in Lahore and Saharanpur,
killing several members
and arresting some prominent ones
including Sukhdev and Rajguru,
both wanted as conspirators
in the Saunders murder case
"along with Bhagat Singh himself."
"They may"
kill me...
But cannot kill my ideas.
An ideology whose time has come
is unstoppable.
You will never earn your rights, unless
you rise up in protest
or fight the oppressors.
Independence without
a true ideology
can be worse than slavery.
Freedom is our birth right,
and therefore
we reject this oppressive regime.
And for the criticism
of resorting to violence.
We are not blood thirsty,
we do not harbour hate
toward any individual or country.
We are simply against the
exploitation of one by the other.
Most importantly
we do not want our rights in piecemeal.
Neither the illusion of semi-independence.
We want the welfare of the entire world
farmers, workers and students…
And therefore we demand
absolute independence,
"and a total revolution!"
He's been quite for some time now, Sir.
And?
Well I certainly think he is a
committed Marxist.
Very ideologically driven, Sir.
Hasn't named anyone as yet.
We need to get him to confess.
Press charges.
Get him to talk.
Do what it takes.
Sir.
So then
between you and me
what's your real name? Hmm?
Oh, there's so many passports!
And aliases.
Frank Brazil?
Is this you?
Hmm?
Yes![CHUCKLES]
Well then according to this...
[CLEARS THROAT]
Peddler's license that was
issued in Bournemouth in 1933…
You are Udham Singh.
Yes.
You haven't got a lot of time left.
It's important for your own sake
that we know what your real name is.
Hmm?
Ram Mohammed Singh Azad.
The decision of tattooing
his name on his body
specifically this name, Ram
Mohammed Singh Azad,
he definitely wanted it discovered
and for that news to be spread.
What is the meaning of this?
Uh...
Sir, it is [CLEARS THROAT]
symbolic of
Indian religious unity.
We need to control the press.
No matter what we do
there will be many who will
see his actions
as an act of revolution, Sir!
I said it at that time...
Dwyer was responsible,
for a monstrous event.
But we cannot allow that
to affect our decision making.
Yes, Prime Minister.
His defence lawyers will try and stall.
-But we should speed things up.
-Sir.
This business has to be ended here.
-I agree...
-India protests every day.
We don't get to see it thankfully.
But London must not protest anymore…
And prolonging this
trial will only ensure that.
Good morning, Sir!
Your Majesty...
There are a
lot
of Indian soldiers
fighting for us in this war.
Are there not, Prime Minister?
Yes there are.
A meek surrender
to this mad man
would be to embolden
the voices of rebellion
amongst the Indian soldiers.
We can't afford to be seen as, as weak.
I understand.
Your Majesty!
After the war...
will the crown
quit India?
Let us just say…
We will need to reinvent
a way of maintaining
our strategic presence
in the subcontinent.
We have a terrorist and a lunatic
who had no special aim or purpose.
It was a crazed violent attack,
and nothing else.
Sir, is this incident a
threat to the British Empire?
No.
This is a stray incident
by a crazed lunatic
who has no further links.
[YELLS IN PAIN]
[SIGHS]
Is anyone alive?
[FACTORY SIREN]
See you tomorrow.
What are you doing here?
You'll get me in trouble.
Come here.
How did you get here?
You want to run it?
Hey
come on.
Pull.
Hold the belt and pull upwards.
No, no... upwards.
Come here...
Hey, I was just joking...
give me your hand.
Thank you.
Support for Udham Singh.
Long live Udham.
Mr. Nihal Singh?
Yes.
So, he tried to kill your supervisor?
No, just
raised his voice.
Threatened him.
Well, it still shows
clear criminal intent.
No.
Not…
Not criminal.
You just said he threatened him.
Hmm?
He was
somewhat unpredictable
he would talk about an
Utopian world, but never...
The man is a habitual criminal
accustomed to threatening people.
Take his statement.
I did it all by myself!
Well, you must really hate the British!
-Do you hate the British?
-No.
I have many British friends too.
I don't hate them.
Then O'Dwyer?
So was it just revenge?
No.
Michael O'Dwyer
personified the evil
of British imperialism.
I am against that evil!
O'Dwyer embodied British
imperialism in my country.
You too are
working for your government,
but in your own country.
I don't hate you.
You are doing your job.
[MUFFLED CRY]
[GASPS]
[COUGHS]
[GASPING]
Sign your confession.
Write down that you helped
him purchase the guns twice.
You helped him buy the guns... Sign it!
He is a criminal. He had guns.
I'll ask you for the last time...
[GUNSHOT]
Stand up!
Stand up…
Good morning.
My name is John Hutchison.
These are my credentials.
Robert Clayton and Sons.
V.K.
Me non will also be with me in the court.
Hmm!
I was born in...
Kanpur.
I studied law after coming here.
Law?
Huh...
law…
When a country punishes a
person, you quote the law...
but when a country commits
crime against another country...
would your law call it a crime?
The British have committed a crime!
And continue to do so.
Mr. Singh, I know you think
you don't need a lawyer.
You will have to co-operate,
if you want me to present your defence.
So, let's start from the beginning.
When did you plan the assassination?
It's important that they read
back that sermon next week…
But anyway Richard, it's good
to see you, I'll see on Sunday.
-Good luck!
-See you next week, Sir Michael.
Salesman,
where's your box? Where's your pens?
Ah,
not everyone has taste like you, Sir.
Uh-huh! You ought to be selling rifles.
There's a war coming, money to be made.
Ah... I need a job, Sir.
What do you do?
I am a good carpenter…
A good electrician, I can wash clothes...
-I...
-Okay, okay.
Come around to the house.
We will see what we can do for you.
Okay?
Grateful, Sir. Thank you.
I'll be meeting Tony and Slanders
at the club this evening you know.
-I'll give them your love.
-Yes, please do.
Aren't they pretty flowers now?
They are fresh from the garden.
Got the hunt on Monday.
Ah, yes of course.
You fancy rabbits on Tuesday night, huh?
-It'll be Monday night.
-That will be lovely.
Sir.
Thank you.
Now…
Got him! Got him!
Thank you.
Now then...
Tell me, salesman
where were you in April, 1919?
I
-I was...
-I remember.
You told me.
-Working in the factory, on the railway.
-Yes, Sir.
You want something, Sir?
They deserved it.
You can't rise in rebellion
and expect a medal
you got what was coming
ungrateful!
-Something bothering you, Sir?
-No.
Nothing ever bothers me.
Would you kill a man to save ten?
If I
believe it to be true.
Ten men to save a hundred?
A thousand, lakhs…
Depends, Sir.
So, you agree.
No.
You just said it depended
on the circumstances.
Circumstance
yes
what one goes through...
I know about it.
You know nothing.
Fear is a deterrent.
Mutiny was brewing.
There would have been
another river in the Punjab.
A sixth river
a river of blood.
1857 all over again.
Fear was the key...
and fear worked.
I ended Gandhi's soul
force with brute force!
Huh...
There were women…
Children...
-wounded.
-Wounded?
Their relatives carried them away.
Carry away how, Sir?
There was curfew.
Martial law…
Shoot at sight orders.
People were afraid to
take people to the hospital…
Nonsense.
Nonsense!
When he stopped firing
that was a sign that it
was good for them to go.
So, you don't think it was brutal, Sir?
It was sufficient.
He was faced with a seditious mob.
He created fear,
and it was sufficient.
Hmm...
How can someone be so demonic?
He had absolutely no
remorse for what he did!
So you left the job?
Otherwise I would have killed him.
But that would not have
registered as a protest.
It would be construed as a
crime against an employer
and that would have tainted
the credibility of all workers.
And then?
"Just to update you on
the news from Europe
if you've just turned on your radios."
Great Britain is now at war with Germany.
Prime Minister Neville
Chamberlain announced this fact
in a broadcast at 6:15 pm New York time,
6:15 Eastern Standard time.
In a brief broadcast of about five
minutes' duration which was carried
over the CBS network,
the Prime Minister said
that I have to tell you
"we are now at war with Germany."
"A nationwide blackout has been announced
with all lights to be
extinguished during air raids."
"The government has issued a
call for up to 2 million young men..."
Why don't you finish
your flipping job, idiot!
I will cut your wages!
Hey! Stop the work...
-Stop working!
-Udham.
Stop it. This is slavery. Stop it…
Udham!
The Manager gives us an earful.
You are scared of him.
Not me.
He is scared of the Manager...
Manager, of the owner,
and the owner, of the regime.
And finally the oppressor seated
at the top, rules everyone with fear!
And they are doing the same
back home in India as well!
We are humans as well!
Don't we all deserve to be equal?
We are treated as slaves!
Disrespected, not valued at all!
What the hell are you doing?
-You are disturbing everyone!
-What the hell...
What the hell are you doing!
-I will kill you, bloody imperialists!
-What are you doing? Get out!
You get out of my country!
Stop being reckless!
We tried earlier, didn't we fail?
We did…but we have to act now!
Else we will remain under
British rule for 100 years more.
Please leave…
The world is at war we are all under
watch, we will resume after the war.
That will be too late!
The Britishers are
preoccupied with the war,
they are terrified of Hitler
this is the right time to strike.
But why here?
We have to force them out of India!
Absolutely right, but they think our
movement died with Bhagat Singh.
We should strike here,
right at the heart of
London our message
will travel across the world.
-And what do we do?
-We drop a bomb?
We'll do that back home.
Do you have a gun?
Please leave, Udham!
Free speech…
But I am not free...
Aye, Sir!
Sir!
Wake up!
Free speech!
What do I say?
Aye... drop the bomb!
No use…
Robbing people of
their freedom, is futile.
Today, you snatch one man's freedom
tomorrow, another will rob yours!
Futile!
Mother
she would talk about
no, not about independence...
about toys…
Just...[CHUCKLES]
War is most inhuman!
Nobody wins!
Nobody.
Only... hatred wins!
Hmm!
Aye Bhagat...
Bhagat Singh.
Ah, my brother!
Free speech... always!
Don't snatch.
Share.
You and me, together.
Old man, am I wrong?
No?
Swear…huh!
What would you even swear... Huh!
"Every leaf, every shrub
knows of my state..."
Only the flower remains ignorant
"the entire garden knows!"
That's it.
Free speech!
Thank you.
Share!
Please wait over there for five minutes.
[TELEPHONE RINGS]
It says "British Indian."
Yes. Right.
[PANTING]
"Germany has announced
that all British merchant ships
will now be classified as war ships.
The government has planned
to evacuate 400,000 children
from major cities to rural areas.
Meanwhile the Prime
Minister Neville Chamberlain,
"is set to meet the French
premier amid demands for a more..."
Alright, Sir.
In the war that is at our doorstep,
the empire will need all her fighting men.
In the last war,
I filled all the quotas
for Indian soldiers.
Over 100,000 Sikhs from my
Punjab fought for the crown.
And
I made sure that the Indians
contributed generously to the war loan.
The Empire was,
and is
a force for good.
And that is why, ladies and gentlemen…
It is not only our right, but our duty
to rule India.
Without us they will return to savagery,
looting and killing one another.
It is not only Africa
ladies and gentlemen,
that is the white man's burden.
Thank you.[CROWD CLAPPING AND CHEERING]
Thank you… thank you...[CROWD APPLAUDING]
Thank you!
Mr. Dwyer!
[GUNSHOTS]
I waited for 21 years!
Will this murder be considered a protest,
or this protest be considered
a murder by your British law?
Thank you.
"The trial of the Indian National charged
with the murder of Sir Michael O'Dwyer,
is set to begin at the Old Bailey, today.
The accused, represented by
Mr. St. John Hutchison KC
and Mr. V.K Krishna Me non
has also been charged
with committing violent acts
aimed at disrupting
the peace of the nation.
The trial, Crown versus Singh
will be presided over
by Mr. Justice Atkinson.
While prominent members
of the local Indian community
have condemned the vicious act,
the court witnessed an outpouring
of support by native Indians
"in favour of the accused."
[CROWD HURLING ABUSES]
Get back, please.
Quiet!
Accused to take stand.
Please take oath.
Your Lordship, he has requested
to take oath on a book of his choice.
What sort of book is it? Is it seditious?
No, it's Indian folklore, your Lordship.
A classical romance, Heer Ranjha.
He has the right to take an
oath on the book of his choice.
Proceed.
My Lord, I would like
to call on the case of
the state against the
accused Mr. Udham Singh.
The state contends that the accused is
responsible for the
criminal act of murder.
Proceed.
State your name for the record.
Shoot me.
State your name.
This proceeding is a
waste of time, just shoot me.
-State your name.
-Ram Mohammed Singh Azad!
State your real name.
This is my real name.
Accused Udham Singh, do
you plead guilty or not guilty?
I plead not guilty…
Not guilty… Dwyer was guilty.
You and your policies are guilty.
I'll ask you one more time.
-Do you plead guilty?
-I protested!
Your entire British empire is a
trading company that has turned
into an imperialistic power
ruling us illegally and forcefully!
-It's a clear admission of guilt, my Lord.
-I suggest we proceed with sentencing.
The defence has not
spoken, your Lordship.
The murderer has spoken enough!
We demand a just trial as is
laid down by the law of the land.
He has shot three people, former public
servants in front of hundreds of people.
-We have witnesses.
-But your Lordship... -Overruled.
-Have you been arrested before?
-Objection, my Lord!
-Irrelevant.
-Overruled.
Have you been arrested before?
-Yes.
-Prosecuted in a criminal case?
-How many years have you been in prison?
I was in prison for four years...
-But not for a crime.
-Why on earth would anyone be in prison
if they had not committed a crime?
No, no, no crime.
I was just fighting, fighting for freedom!
Freedom is my birth right and
fighting for freedom is no crime.
There is a complaint against you
by an Indian gentleman whose nose
you broke in a bar and yet you
say you are a freedom fighter.
Yes!
I was angry!
At such apathetic Indians,
who stay content with slavery!
This man is clearly prone to violence.
And if given a chance,
I shall do it again.
Have you possessed a weapon before the one
you acquired to kill Sir Michael O'Dwyer?
I have before me a written statement
by the man who sold
you an illegal firearm twice.
I'm telling you it was a
protest against you you, you,
Britishers have plundered
us divided us looted us,
robbed us of all dignity
finished our economy!
-That's enough!
-Yes, that is enough!
It's time you leave my country!
That is enough!
Will you stop this political ranting!
My Lordship the weapon has been
seized, and he has admitted to the crime.
The reason behind what I did was…
Do not speak in this court
unless you are asked to!
But your Lordship he has every
right to be heard. Overruled!
We are here to decide on
the quantum of sentence
based on the crime committed by this man.
Under orders of the
court the press would not
report on any statements
made by the accused.
Do you members of the
press, understand this?
Yes.
I have reached my verdict.
The accused is found guilty as charged.
The accused would be hanged till death.
[CROWD PROTESTING]
Down with British imperialism!
Down with British tyranny!
Long live revolution!
Sir...
sorry to report he is
refusing all food, Sir.
Oh, for God's sake!
Don't make him a martyr!
-It's the last thing we need.
-Sir.
We need to stop this hunger strike.
Sir.
[GRUNTS]
[BREATHES LABORIOUSLY]
[GASPS]
You won't marry, ever?
Then?
Friends forever eh?
Fine.
I won't settle down either.
Ah! [SMILES]
I have told you everything!
Nothing more to tell you, Mr. Swain.
I know you are not a killer.
You have never killed
anyone before in your life.
What happened that day?
What changed you?
-Repeal the Rowlatt Act!
-Repeal it, repeal it!
-Repeal the Black Act!
-Repeal the Rowlatt Act!
-Repeal it, repeal it!
Move them back! Charge!
[CROWD COMMOTION]
Barricade the entry.
This entry too.
Call for more battalions.
Gandhi has left Delhi for Amritsar.
Arrest Gandhi.
Yes, Sir.
No one should enter
Punjab until further orders.
Arrest all the college students.
Put them in a detention centre.
Cut all the civilian telephone
lines until further notice.
The Congress leaders,
Satyapal and Kitchlew,
keep them in detention.
Newspapers, destroy tomorrows' editions.
No more publication until further orders.
A protest has been called at Jallianwala
Bagh but it's likely to be peaceful!
Likely!
But it's going to be political, yes?
Yes, Sir!
So, it's an unlawful gathering, isn't it?
-Yes, Sir!
-Who do you have in mind for the job?
We have briefed Colonel Monago.
Hmm.
I find him to be hesitant.
-Call for General Reginald Dyer.
-Yes, Sir.
[MILITARY COMMANDS]
This here, the Golbazaar,
JP road burnt down.
Entire old city area, has witnessed
acts of rebellion and rioting.
How many dead?
The deaths of five Englishmen
have been confirmed,
and there are further
reports of a political
assembly near the Golden temple tomorrow.
Sir, Sir Michael O'Dwyer
is on the line for you.
Thank you.
-Prepare the men.
-Yes, Sir.
Good evening, Sir.
Good evening, General.
Amritsar is in the hands of the rebels.
It is your job to get it back.
I will need your permission
to proclaim Martial law, Sir.
You are the man on the ground, General.
You must act as you deem necessary.
Thank you, Sir.
Revolution is a dangerous game!
We cannot afford another mutiny.
-Sir!
-I want to set a precedent.
Punishment of itself is
not necessarily a deterrent.
But if the punishment is such
that it creates a fear of punishment
that would be of great practical value.
We need to set an example.
-Sir!
-Goodnight.
You're back again...
Almost there...
Section 144 is imposed.
Assembly of more than 2 people
will be shot at.
Section 144 is imposed.
Martial law is in force.
-If more than 2 people are...
-The curfew is on, I am leaving.
...assembled together,
they will be shot at...
No, no gathering for me.
I'm taking the day off.
No appeal, no argument, no lawyer
this Black law will not be accepted by us.
We reject the Rowlatt Act!
The arrest of Dr. Satyapal
and Kitchlew will not go in vain.
This protest will wage on!
Until both the leaders are freed...
and the Rowlatt Act is rolled back.
Soldiers, take your positions!
We are not the ones to be scared!
-Don't be afraid, sit down!
-Should we issue a warning, Sir?
Remember Shri Guru Govind Singh.
They've had their warning.
No meetings!
-Soldiers...
-Listen, sit, sit!
Take your positions.
Soldiers, take firing position.
Don't panic, sit down!
Fire!
[SCREAMING]
-[SCREAMS]
-Guard!
Fire!
This incident would have
gone unnoticed by you.
It is just a footnote in your history.
Written in fine print in some book.
But you weren't even
there when the firing started.
So why... what...?
-What did you see?
-I was late.
Very late.
[GASPS]
Balli, Balli...
Balli...? What happened?
-[CRIES IN PAIN] Ah!
-What...
What happened?
They fired at us in the gathering.
-Ah!
-Parag! Kamal, Parag!
[CRIES IN PAIN] Ah!
Balli, Balli...
-He's been shot...
-What?
What happened, Balli?
-They fired at us.
-Quick, hospital from the back lane.
-My father was shot.
-Come, come.
My father is dead! [CRIES]
-Where is Balli?
-Inside.
When you're parched with thirst...
holding on to your last few breaths...
how would a drop of water
trickle down your throat?
[MOANING]
Sister.
Wa...
-Ah!
-Oh God!
Wat...
Sister?
Water.
Water, water?
How do you hold on to...
the last breath of your soul?
Dear God.
[PANTING]
Water… -Ah!
-Ah!
-Water, water...
Sister, water.
Water, sister, water...
Reshma...
Reshma!
Resh...
Reshma.
[GROANS]
Brother, brother.
[CRIES IN PAIN]
There, it's almost done.
Almost there...
Keep your eyes open.
It's done.
Don't sleep.
Sister, sister!
[GASPS]
Keep him down.
Put him down here...!
[CRIES]
Such a young child!
There are hundreds more,
scattered all across the ground
-I am going back...
-Here, have water!
Is anyone alive?
Brother.
Brother, are you fine?
You feeling cold?
-[BREATHES LABORIOUSLY]
-Relax.
Brother...
Brother, are you okay?
-Ah!
-Brother...
Wait, Wait…
-Take me with you.
-Yes.
-Hey, some water here!
-Ah!
-Get some water here!
Trust in God[BREATHES LABORIOUSLY]
Everything is fine.
I'll be right back.
[GASPS]
Waheguru!
Are you okay?
That's it, that's it...
Just keep breathing, I'll be back.
Water… water...
It has been 5-6 hours
they have cut the water supply.
They've lost a lot of blood.
They won't survive.
We need a doctor.
Waheguru!
[CROWD MOANING]
You be here
I'll be right back.
Don't worry.
You're fine.
-How many more?
-Hundreds.
But they've not lifted the curfew.
Morphine.
Uncle...
My grand daughters are there…
-Grand-daughters?
-Yes, at the back.
Uncle...
they are... breathing...
their limbs are also moving...
Uncle, Un...
[MOANS]
[WAILS IN PAIN]
Anyone alive out there?
Sister...
Sister, are you okay?
My son...
-No!
-No, no, no.
-Do you fly kites?
-Uh...
-Huh?
-You've flown kites eh?
-Uh...
Will you fly kites with me?
Huh? You will, right?
We'll fly them together.
-[YELLS]
-It's okay…
You're fine.
It's done, well done!
Bravo!
I'll be back soon.
Mother!
Brother!
Mother...
Mother?
[MUFFLED CRYING]
God, have mercy.
Have mercy, God.
Sir, there has been a firing
upon a crowd in Amritsar!
Well, don't panic.
Hmm.
Casualties?
Don't know Sir.
-Wounded?
-Many...
Hundreds!
Section 144 and Martial Law are imposed.
Listen!
Soldiers are coming back,
they're back, run!
My husband…
My husband? [CRIES]
-My husband?
-Sister, lie down...
-My husband.
-Sister, sit down, be quiet, Shh!
[MILITARY COMMAND]
They left.
I can't find my husband.
Where are you?
-Where are you?
-Is anyone alive?
Anyone alive?
Message from Sir Michael O'Dwyer, Sir.
I have been up all night.
Haven't had any sleep.
I did my duty.
Served my country.
Your action has been approved, Sir.
Is the curfew... to be kept on?
-What time is it?
-6 am, Sir!
Keep it on.
Announce a relaxation at 8 am.
They will need to bury
and burn their dead.
Yes, Sir.
Captain!
Is it quiet out there?
Yes, Sir.
What I experienced that night...
is known only to me and the one above.
When I turned 18...
my teacher said to me...
that, "Son"
youth
is a gift of God.
It's up to you...
whether you let it wither...
"or give it meaning."
When I see him up there, I shall ask...
did I give my youth meaning?
Or did I let it go to waste?
Is there anything I can do for you?
Yes.
Let the world know, I was a revolutionary!
[MOANING AND CRYING]
Stretcher...
Saline...
Chloroform...
Clean the equipment.
Son...
he.
He is no more!
[MOANS]
I'll need more tinctures.
How are you?
Couple of months have gone now
come back.
You must ask for a pardon. You will live.
It's time to
meet my friend.
Please Udham.
That's time, miss!
Time.
-Sir...
-Yes.
They had defied section 144.
Martial law and curfew
were already in place.
Those who were assembled
in Jallianwala Bagh,
knew they had violated the law.
And you decided that you
would fire onto the crowd?
Yes!
I went with the deliberate
intention of opening fire
if I found a crowd assembled there.
Supposing the passage was
sufficient for the armoured cars to go in
would you have fired
with the machine guns?
I think probably, yes!
And in that case the casualties
would have been much higher?
Yes!
If General Dyer had not
dispersed that crowd by force
we would have had an
infinitely worse state of rebellion.
Don't you think that the
firing went on for too long?
My responsibility
was that if I fire,
I must fire with good effect.
A small amount of
firing is a criminal act!
I was going to punish them.
My idea was to make a
wide strong impression.
I was going to teach them a lesson.