For best IPTV provider, please visit: WWW.IPTV.CAT
So...
tell me about yourself.
What would you like to know?
I don't know, just the basics.
Erm...
Where are you from,
what do you do in life...
besides...
Erm...
Well, my name's Sebastian.
I'm twenty-four.
- From Edinburgh.
- Oh...
I thought I heard an accent.
Are you okay?
- Yeah.
Oh yeah.
Yeah. Good. Oh yeah. Oh yeah.
- Get on your back.
Oh yeah.
I'm getting close.
Do you want me to come?
Oh fuck, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
- Are you sure?
Yeah, yeah.
Oh yeah.
So tell me about yourself.
What would you like to know?
Oh, I don't know,
just the basics. Erm...
I must admit,
I was a bit worried
when you wouldn't
send a face pic, but...
you're very handsome.
Are you quite new to this?
Max, how is
the Marloan review coming along?
You'll have it by Friday.
Let's just say...
sophomore slump
is a kind way of putting it.
For LLF, they've
just announced Alina Casaro.
I would love to...
- There's been some indication
she might give an interview,
but we've all heard that before.
As for Easton Ellis,
his people
just confirmed this morning.
I think this one's for you.
- But didn't I ask first?
Actually, I think Max beat you
to it, but in any case,
I do think it best
that queer writers cover
queer authors.
Shouldn't anyone
be able to write about anything?
That's a very
cis-hetero response.
What does cis
have to do with it?
I thought that the priority here
was quality reporting,
not optics.
It's not about optics.
It's about sensibility,
sensitivity.
Just do me the favor and run
those questions by me, Max.
I trust that you know what
to ask, but I need to see them
because we may lead with it.
They're not that apparent to me.
I really tend not
to write about my life at all.
People point to the story in The
Informers called In the Islands,
which is about a father who
takes his son...
♪ My heart, it felt complete and ♪
♪ Everything was
Perfectly aligned [alright] ♪
♪ It happened just like that ♪
♪ We found ♪
♪ Our satellites ♪
Seriously, it's like
a religious experience,
the new one.
Reading it I really
feel changed as a person.
Sorry,
I know I sound like a twat.
She's only given one interview
in, like, eight years.
Dunno how her publisher
let her get away with it?
I think the mystique
is part of it.
Like, you actually have to read
any of her work
to understand
anything about her.
It should be out today.
Wow.
So fucking cool.
I just don't think
it stands out.
It's so unpolished.
- What?
No.
It's exactly that rawness
that makes it work so well.
The way you capture the intimacy
between the lovers and...
you know, then how
it suddenly turns to distance.
Yeah, collapsing those two
timeframes together like that
in one moment is...
fantastic.
I mean, yeah,
it's atmospheric, sure, but...
Is it really saying anything?
- Max...
Not everything needs to be
some grand statement
if it's well-observed,
if it's truthful.
This comes from the heart.
And that's why it works.
I really don't think this
could've been written by someone
who... hadn't lived it.
I can't just be stuck
writing short stories
and reviewing
other people's work
for the rest of my life, Amna.
Do you know how old
Bret Easton Ellis was
when he published
his first novel?
Twenty-one.
Zadie Smith?
I'm already late.
Hi.
Come on in.
Okay.
You're a great kisser.
Thanks.
Sorry, it's a bit messy in here.
The cleaner is coming tomorrow.
Just got back
from New York this morning.
Oh, nice. Erm...
Business or pleasure?
Business, unfortunately.
Always business.
Do you want a drink?
- Yeah, I'd love one.
Wine?
Whatever you're having is great.
Okay, kid.
You've got a beautiful place.
- Thank you.
It's just for work days.
The weekends I spend in Kent.
With the family, you know.
Oh yeah.
Are you gonna make me come?
- Yeah.
Keep going.
[Daniel] Do you
always have sex like that?
Did you like it?
You know
the answer.
Do you know...
most of the people
on that website are just awful.
Have you...
had bad experiences?
Disappointments.
- Hm.
It's so rare to find
someone like you on there.
I mean...
people lie about their age.
Or height or dick size.
It's all exaggeration.
Some of them aren't even gay.
Can't get it hard with a man.
It's so nice that
not everyone is deceptive.
"Sebastian
stood by the window over London,
looking at both the city and
himself with a new perspective.
As Daniel
casually mentioned his family,
he felt suddenly
complicit in a cliché,
acting out another role, but
one he hadn't cast himself in.
Daniel's hands found him and
pulled at his skin and flesh
as hungrily as a mouth
seeking water in the desert.
He didn't just want [pause],
he needed.
This was the relief he had
from his family,
his job, his other life.
Sebastian in that moment felt
that he was living
more authentically than Daniel."
That's good.
So good.
Did you speak to actual
prostitutes for your research?
I think Gloria
means sex workers.
Yeah. Absolutely.
What initially
drew me to the topic
was a piece I did
for Wall Magazine last year
on students who escort.
I guess I was struck by
how casually some of them
talked about the work. Erm...
They weren't
really ashamed of it at all.
They saw very little stigma
in it anymore.
And some of them had such
a sense of professionalism
in the way that they set
themselves up as entrepreneurs
or market themselves online.
There was almost
this erm... sense of pride.
Anyway, I couldn't stop
thinking about
some of the people
I interviewed
and just felt like
I had to write about it.
I thought it was all
OnlyFans now.
Yeah. People do that, too.
But a screen will
never replace touch.
Hm... It's an easier way
to earn though.
Hm,
to cultivate an audience
that'll make you
any significant money
takes a lot of work.
Yeah.
But you don't
physically need to interact.
Yeah, but some people do
just really enjoy sex though.
They might not want videos
of themselves online forever.
I know someone
that used to do it,
when they were young of course.
They didn't mind it.
And I asked her honestly
whether she didn't find
some of the men repulsive.
For her, it wasn't about them,
the clients.
It was about her.
That's just...
The idea that I'm like Patrick
Bateman because I described
a woman-hating man,
that I am that man as well,
is just a load of... bunk.
The book that I had
problems with was the first one
because everyone assumed
it was autobiographical
and my family is really nothing
like the family in that book.
So that was the one I felt
might have been the hardest
for you and Dad to take
because it was erm...
To an outsider it was
the most autobiographical.
I don't think the content
upset me.
The fact that
it was such a tremendous hit
and it affected you so much
at such an early age,
that had much more impact on me
than the content
of what you'd written.
Listen, as a writer
I guess I tend to be a bit of
a sociologist and I guess I tend
to be drawn to things that
are happening in the culture
and incorporate...
I know it's superficial,
but you are a young,
not unattractive guy
and you shouldn't be afraid
to use that.
It's just...
I'm not really big
on social media.
I find it to be a distraction.
I don't want
anything complicated,
just a couple of quality posts
every week.
I'm afraid nobody gets to say
they're above it these days.
And what about the... novel?
Did you get a chance
to look at the pages?
I have to say, I wasn't thrilled
when you said you were writing
about sex work.
You're aware there's no shortage
of treatises on the topic.
But...
I think it is alive.
Really intimate.
And you might have found
a fresh perspective on it.
I do realize it is a sort of...
stock character
of queer literature, but...
this new generation
of sex workers
are all using technology.
The digital hustler.
Yeah. Something like that.
- Hm.
Unfortunately,
I can't offer you an advance,
but it would be fantastic
if after the stories
we can get your debut novel
published already next year.
How soon do you think
you could get me a full draft?
Erm... Couple of months?
- Oh really. That soon?
Don't want to rush it.
- Yeah.
I've got to do more research.
Erm, interviews.
Yes. I understand.
Sorry.
Did you have any notes
on the pages?
Yes.
There was one bigger thing
I've been wondering about.
Have you thought about
setting it in the first person?
Almost like a memoir.
A pseudo memoir.
It's not something
I'd thought about.
I mean, it might not work.
I just think
there's something there.
♪ Dancing,
Dancing with the lights out ♪
♪ Dancing, dancing with... ♪
- Get the door. Get the door.
- I got it.
This calls for celebration.
It's just a couple
of chapters so far.
Max, it's gonna be amazing.
I have faith in you.
♪ Open to the rhythm
Like oh wah wah ♪
♪ Feel it in your bones
Like oh cha-cha-cha ♪
♪ Did you miss me? ♪
Hi.
Have we met?
Don't think so.
Where do you go to uni?
You look so familiar.
UCL, but I finished
a while ago, so...
What's your name?
Erm... Max. I'm Max.
Are you sure?
Hey. Let me just grab my jacket.
I'll come for a smoke.
Erm... Actually,
I'm gonna have to go.
I just remembered
I've got a deadline.
Oh... Grindr calls.
- It's... It's not that.
Well,
it was very nice to meet you.
So, I read your new pages.
I think the character
is really intriguing
and your prose is vivid as ever,
but I just wonder if
it gets a little repetitive.
This series of the same kinds
of erm... encounters
with generally
always older men.
I'm just wondering
what it might look like
to see him in a slightly
different situation.
Only to give it
a bit more variety
and maybe to explore how
he might react to a new context.
Also, I was just a little thrown
by the bit
about Sebastian's erm...
intermittent feelings
of shame and the erm...
how did you put it...
shame about shame,
which definitely makes sense,
but it's just
that I thought you said
you were struck by
how little shame
your interviewers felt.
I'll send you
my new chapters tonight.
Anxious to get your thoughts
before the submission.
Hey, Sebastian.
- Hi.
Glad you could make it.
Come on through.
We got friends over.
I hope you don't mind.
Oh... Nice, Sam.
Hello.
What's your name, son?
Come on in.
Can I fix you a drink?
We have vodka,
gin, wine. Erm, I think...
Or would you prefer a shot?
Actually, I think I'm gonna go.
No. No, wait.
Wait, wait, wait.
Stay. Please.
You didn't tell me it was
a group thing. I don't do that.
Why not?
Please, stay.
I'll make it
worth your while
if that's what
you're worried about.
It's late.
We'll have fun. I promise.
You didn't want it?
You put more
in yours.
Okay. I don't see well.
And after, you drink slowly.
So erm... where did you
come from tonight?
Just from home.
And where's home?
Erm... East.
Phone, please.
You get it back when you go.
We put them away
when we party. House rules.
Just so everyone can
relax. It's to protect us all.
Yeah, you know.
From any sneaky pornographers.
Or rather, it's because
our lovely hosts here
wouldn't want to be pictured
with the likes of you, Jacopo.
Fuck you.
- Hey, whoa. Careful. Come on.
Turn it off if you want.
I'm just going
to put it in a drawer.
Okay.
Want some?
What is it?
Mephedrone.
Do you notice the difference?
I didn't say.
The other one wasn't bad, but
this stuff is a lot speedier.
Are you okay?
You weren't in the meeting.
I need your piece ASAP
and your questions for Bret.
Are you not coming in
at all today?
Give me a call
when you get this, please.
So tell us, where
did you come from tonight?
Fuck him. Fuck him.
Like it, Carlo?
Oh fuck.
- It's good, right? Yeah.
I think
they enjoyed that.
You're new to this, aren't you?
So have you erm...
been here before?
Yeah, I've been over
a couple of times.
They like to get trashed
once a month or so.
Who are they?
Like, what do they do?
Both lawyers.
Hence the phones.
I have no idea what kind, but...
they can afford to be generous.
Where did he find you?
Erm...
Dreamy... guys.
Yeah, I can see
why he picked you.
We should collab, you know.
OnlyFans.
I don't think I want
to be that erm... public.
You'd do so well though.
Do you think so?
- Hm.
Yeah.
You've got that wholesome
boy-next-door thing going on.
But it's all filth underneath.
Why don't you think about it.
Hm?
What I find interesting now
is that there is this kind
of anti-sex thing going on
in a way in terms of... In a
lot of the reviews in America,
they complained about
how much sex was in the book,
which surprised me because
I don't think it was that much.
Morning.
- Hey.
Max. Good to see you.
- Hi.
Meeting's in five.
- Yeah. Thanks.
Amna is doing
the Rachel Cusk interview,
Fazel has
the Design Biennale. Max...
Erm... I've got Bret.
Change of plans.
You're going to Ecotec today
for the app launch.
Erm...
But I'm interviewing Bret.
No. James
is taking care of Bret.
But erm...
Max is like an expert.
He was here on Friday
for the LLF meeting
and has prepared for it.
But that's not even our section.
What makes the existence
of this magazine possible?
Do you think
literature pays for itself?
And please hurry up
with the Slimani review.
It should've gone up by now.
I know, it's fucked up.
But... why didn't you
come in on Friday?
I told you.
I hooked up with someone and
I fell asleep at their place.
You know, I really could've
used your feedback on my pages.
Fuck, erm...
I'm sorry. I'll look at them
tonight. I promise.
I've already submitted it.
The deadline was yesterday?
...intuitive interface,
so all you'll be doing
is swiping left or right,
which I'm sure
you can all manage.
This time the best part is
that you won't even have
to take an awkward stranger
out for a drink.
Now, we have spots
in our software
where you can share ideas,
brainstorm,
make parking lots for
your research and development...
So this is Max
from Wall Magazine.
Joan, our Head Developer.
Pleasure to meet you, Max.
- Hi.
Shall we sit down over here?
Yeah.
Where do we begin?
Has anybody demonstrated
to you how the app works?
Yeah, they have.
I can tell you more about
the development process
or how we came about our
user interface, or the design.
Actually, I think erm...
I've got enough.
Oh no, you really want
to talk to Joan about this.
She pretty much spearheaded
the project.
It's not necessary.
The presentation
covered everything, so...
I'm gonna have to be off.
Thank you so much.
No. I'm sorry.
We're not done here.
Joan needs
to be a part of this piece.
Did you find
your way here okay?
Yeah. No problems.
I know it can be a little
unintuitive from the station.
Where did you say
you live again?
In Hackney.
- Oh right, yes.
Hackney has really come up,
hasn't it?
It wasn't that long ago
no one wanted to go near it,
let alone live there.
I remember when it was just
gangs and drug dealers and...
Can I offer you a drink?
I've opened some Primitivo.
I'm grateful to have had
my career when I did.
Starting out in the seventies
was an absolute joy.
Tertiary education was free.
The pursuit of knowledge was
regarded as an end in itself.
Speaking
with post-doctorates now,
the situation seems just dire.
I don't know how they manage
to cope with all that...
uncertainty and debt.
You're erm...
studying, aren't you?
I thought
your profile mentioned that.
Yeah, erm...
I'm doing my masters.
- Oh, what in?
French literature.
That's wonderful.
I used to lecture
in comparative literature.
Do you know what you're going
to do your thesis on yet?
Yeah. I think so, erm...
But I don't want to bore you.
- Oh, you couldn't.
I live for that stuff.
I haven't...
Sorry, could we just
keep talking for now?
Are you sure?
Please.
I just want to get to know you
better first. There's no rush.
I hope you're all as excited
and as honored as I am
to welcome
onto the stage tonight
an author whose
decade-spanning body of work
has not only left
an indelible mark
on 20th
and 21st century literature,
but someone who I can also say
has had a profound influence
on the way
many writers of my generation,
myself included,
have come to view the role
of the writer in society.
Please join me
in welcoming onto the stage
the winner of both the
Goncourt and Booker Prizes,
the author of the devastatingly
brilliant Blackwater,
her 18th novel, Alina Casaro.
I mean,
you were fucking incredible.
That question
about the influence of erm...
Oh no no no.
I don't want to talk to her.
After she rejected
my manuscript. So embarrassing.
Max, hi.
- Hi.
Erm... Amna, is it?
- Yes.
Brilliant job on that Q&A.
- Oh, thank you.
You really managed
to drill down deeply.
Thanks.
I've got to ask.
How did you randle that?
Oh well...
I interviewed her for Wall
and then she asked me
to interview her here.
Max, I've got a couple of people
indoor
that I'd really love you
to meet,
if you can spare him
for a moment.
Yes, be my guest.
- Okay.
Erm... Amna, why don't you
come by the office.
We can have a chat about
whatever you're working on.
Yeah. That'd be great.
I'm always on the lookout
for a fresh voice like yours.
Brilliant.
Ready?
Just so you're aware,
Joy is on the panel
for the Polari Prize. Okay?
Hi. Can I please introduce Max.
He's one
of our latest discoveries.
Ian.
- Hi.
Charmed.
- Nice to meet you.
Ian runs the London Review.
- Wow.
Dionne
is being far too generous.
I merely oversee it nowadays.
I leave the daily business to...
well, to the younger generation.
Joy is with the Arts Council.
- Hello.
Lovely to meet you.
- Nice to meet you.
So, what are you working on?
- A couple of things
at the moment. Erm...
We're really proud
to be publishing
some of Max's short stories.
He's already had one in Granta
a few months ago
and another has been
nominated for the Bridport.
That's wonderful.
- Oh, good. Well done.
Congratulations.
- Thank you.
And currently, he's working hard
on quite a tantalizing novel
that we're hoping to publish
next year, all going well.
No doubt we'll be covering
you on our pages soon.
Certainly one for the radar.
You look awfully young
to be getting published.
How old are you, Max?
- I am twenty-five.
Oh... Well, perfection.
So, what's your novel about?
Erm, it's about a student
who erm...
who...
It's about sex work
in the digital age.
Good, good.
Max is exploring it
as perhaps just another job
amongst many other jobs
in the gig economy.
Erm... I... I just remembered
that I've left something.
I'm so sorry, I will have
to excuse myself, erm...
I'm sorry. Thanks.
...it's not very fluffy.
What can she do?
So that's Emily's idea
of a dilemma, is it?
She's got a busy life,
she wants to make
a nice cake for her party.
So in the morning,
she's bothering people
with that sponge cake.
Oh, you know...
It is true.
Hi, Mum.
Yeah, I'm good.
How are you?
You're already in bed?
All right then. Yeah, that's
fine. I can call tomorrow.
No. Nothing's the matter.
Don't worry.
Yeah. Okay.
Good night.
Love you.
Yeah, it had
almost a dystopian vibe to it.
Yeah.
I thought it was very honest.
So thank you for that, Joel.
Okay, let's move on to Max.
What do you have for us today?
"Although no one seemed
to have been able
to detect the signs
leading up to it,
they were all afterwards
in mournful apprehension
that they had been there.
Everywhere. Undetected like
an odorless, poisonous gas.
The morning had been routine.
Another identical link
in a chain of silvery
summer days at Dunbar."
There we go, guys. Cheers.
I liked your poem.
Yeah?
Yeah.
It captured that sense
of urban loneliness really well.
Did it... resonate with you?
I doubt those feelings
are entirely foreign to anyone
who's single in London.
What happened to...
what was his name? Sebastian.
I don't know. I just...
I felt like that story
wasn't going anywhere new.
I didn't know
where to take it next.
I wanted to hear more.
Do you like that?
- Yeah. Yeah, I do.
Do you like my cock?
- Yeah, fuck me.
Stop.
Please, stop.
Stop, stop. Slow down.
Sorry.
That's okay.
It's all right. Don't worry.
It's not a porno.
Did you and Dad
get round to watching that show
I told you about?
We started it, but I had to turn
it off after fifteen minutes.
I don't know why every program
nowadays has to be like that.
Just so vulgar.
Oh, Mum.
You should have stuck with it.
Do you have anything
for the wash?
No.
I read your story.
I thought it was very beautiful.
Which one do you mean?
His Breath.
The one in the magazine.
How did you...
I do know how to use
the internet, you know.
I thought it was very touching.
But...
It made me worry about you.
But it's fiction, Mum.
But it has to come
from somewhere, doesn't it?
I just worry about you
being by yourself in London.
I have friends.
Has there been
anybody else since...
You never talk
about these things.
No, because I have honestly
got to focus on work right now.
I should be staff
at the magazine soon.
They've got a new position
coming up.
Do you have to write
about such personal things?
You do have the right
to keep some things
just for yourself, you know.
Hey.
I've sent you the version
with the latest edits.
We've picked the images
and they're in Proof now.
I'll get started
with the Husmann review next.
Max, come in.
I've got some
not great news for you.
Our editorial board, now that
we have a new staff editor...
You mean James.
They are looking to shift their
emphasis away from freelancers.
So unfortunately, the pieces
that we discussed for next month
are going to be done in-house.
- Right.
So is there anything
for me to do?
I'm afraid not.
Sorry, but wasn't my piece
one of the most read last month
and the month before that too?
Max, I get the feeling
that our magazine
hasn't exactly been
your top priority of late,
so I wouldn't want us
to keep you
away from whatever it is
you'd rather be doing.
I'm sorry this didn't work out.
I get the sense
that she can't handle
having anyone with any
other prospects on the team,
like anyone with anything other
than a shitty collection
of poetry to their name.
You could ask Steven if
they've got anything at Glamour.
I know it's not exactly
Granta, but... it's money.
Do you really think that will
go down well with my publisher?
Glamour isn't exactly compatible
with being a serious writer,
is it?
Hm... Yeah.
You know what,
you should erm...
I think you should use
a pseudonym.
No one need know after all
it's by the Max Williamson.
I've got to focus
on my fiction anyway.
And live on what?
It's not like you've got
an advance or anything.
What did you see tonight?
It was The Goat by Edward Albee.
Oh yeah.
- Are you familiar?
No. I've...
not had a chance to see it yet.
I'd like to though.
But I couldn't help thinking
that for all its ingenuity
and brilliant allusion
to Greek tragedy,
the play just didn't move me.
Whereas with
Tennessee Williams, well...
I saw yet another production of
The Glass Menagerie last week.
Seeing their work
almost back-to-back
forces you to compare.
Is this a...
a Schiele?
A very lucky find back in
the day.
I like all of your pictures.
I've managed to collect
a few things over the years.
But really, it's a wealthier
person's hobby.
No, no. You...
You've got a beautiful home.
It's a bit big for one, but...
I've decided to stay.
So, you write as well then.
Or are you more of
an aficionado, like me?
I'm studying. I told you that.
I wasn't sure I'd see you again.
I mean, I had quite a shock
myself that night.
I have been offline for a bit.
- I noticed.
I hope not on my account.
And it goes without saying
that this is between us.
Nothing leaves this room,
this house. So don't worry.
To be honest erm...
I was a little surprised
to hear from you again.
That night that I was here,
erm... I'm sorry...
No. No need to apologies.
I was on edge myself.
Too tense.
I'm pretty much of a novice
in case you didn't realize.
So...
Is it poetry or prose you write?
I still do occasional work
editing textbooks.
I still get invited
to these things.
I'm only asking out of
genuine interest, you know.
I do write.
Mainly just short stories.
Anything I can read?
Not so fast.
I need to get to know you
a little better first.
Touché.
You remind me of someone. Thirty
years ago, when he was your age.
It's something
about the way you laugh.
The tenor of your voice.
Chin up a little bit.
Okay. No, not
so sultry. Thoughtful, not sexy.
It's a serious subject
you're writing about, yeah?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, that's it.
Oh, that's stunning.
I love this one.
Can we get a couple more
very close up?
Yeah, sure.
Yeah.
Max, what's your Insta?
Erm... It's @maximes.
But I've not really got many
followers or anything, so...
We're going to fix that.
We'll do a big feature
on our Instagram.
Once this comes out,
your face is gonna be
on the top of everyone's feed.
Les Nuits Fauves.
Oh, that certainly
sparked debate in my seminars.
I know some people
view him as immoral.
Or selfish.
Unlikable.
But I think it's a beautiful
account of a kind of... joy.
Even in the face of death,
against the tyranny of Aids
and homophobia...
I think there's great beauty in
his refusal to give up on life.
His continued desire
to taste everything until the...
very end.
What?
Can I ask you a question?
Why is it that you do this?
I don't imagine there are
many boys on that website
who are published in Granta or
nominated for literary prizes.
Are you saying
that I shouldn't be here?
No. No, not at all.
You know, there's not much
money in writing fiction.
Or writing full stop.
No, I don't imagine there is.
But is it really just
about the money for you?
Erm...
No.
It's not that simple.
We met in California
in the early nineties.
I still wasn't out.
The only time I plucked up
courage to meet anyone
was on work trips.
That too became a frightening
business because of Aids.
Yeah, of course.
So how did you meet?
I had the afternoon off
from my conference
and had gone to spend it
at the Getty Villa.
It really is a marvellous place.
You should go
if you haven't been.
I was looking at this sculpture,
the Victorious Youth,
lost in admiration,
when suddenly I heard,
"Cute ass, isn't it?"
Turning round,
I saw David for the first time.
Smiling his cheeky smile.
So handsome.
We got into conversation,
went for lunch, had drinks,
an unforgettable night
in my hotel.
Three days later,
I flew back to London
and David came with me,
and never left.
Until one day,
twenty-nine years later,
he was taken away.
It'll be three years
next month.
A stroke.
He went as suddenly
as he had appeared.
Oh... Our time is almost over.
I'd like to stay.
Well, you know I'd love that,
but really I can't afford...
Not him.
Me.
I've seen the proofs
from the Evening Standard piece.
Really good shots,
don't you think?
They're great. I'll see if we
can get one for the dust jacket.
The interview's good too.
I love that thing you said...
What was it?
"I carve out my existence in the
world using words. They are..."
They are the footsteps
I leave in my wake.
Beautiful.
- Yeah.
It's not too lyrical?
No, it's just what we needed.
Fingers crossed
it gets the review it deserves.
Shouldn't be a problem.
Larry is doing it.
I think he'll have a real
appreciation for your style.
So have you read the draft?
- Yes.
Ben's had a look at it too.
I'm gonna be honest because
we want to get this out
as soon as possible
after the short stories
while you're still fresh
in everybody's mind.
This erm...
whole new thread with...
Oh, what's the character's name?
The older gentleman.
Jonathan.
I'm not sure about it.
But it's the heart...
- Don't you think it's...
somehow too romantic in a way?
Is Sebastian, who has been
so consumed by sex until now,
really about to become all
Harold and Maude with this guy?
I'm trying to show that
he's moved beyond that initial,
more superficial interest
in sex work to... to this deeper
appreciation of its meaning.
I can see
that's what you're trying to do.
But you spend so much time now
on this one relationship,
I fear it's losing focus.
Don't get me wrong.
It started off brilliantly.
Really exciting stuff.
I'd just like you
to continue in that vein.
It's just, I really feel
like I'm discovering...
something deeper here.
These exchanges between
escorts and their clients.
They are really important,
connecting generations
of gay men
that might have not had
much to do with each other
and thus they're transmitting
queer history and culture and...
That's something
I want to talk about.
But that's not what we
discussed originally, is it?
You've veered
from your proposal.
An authentic portrait
of contemporary sex work.
The reality
of what life is like...
But it's grounded in reality.
It's all based on research.
From my interviews.
I'm sorry. I just don't think
our audiences will like it.
You need to bring
something more to it, Max.
Find a way to raise the stakes.
- I don't want it to be
just another tragic
sex worker's story. Not at all.
And nobody is asking you
to do that.
Look, we already know that
you've mastered the short story.
But this is a novel.
You have to remember that.
It is a different beast
entirely.
As it is,
I'm afraid it's not working.
It scares me. I don't know...
It's as if I have a cold heart.
Have you never fallen
in love with a boy?
Yes.
Then why aren't you with him?
I don't know. It's my fault.
I didn't know what I was doing.
Think of him a lot?
Sometimes.
I don't want to talk about it.
If I were you,
I'd listen to the people
who've done this
100 times before
and are giving you
this opportunity.
Yeah, but I don't think
that she actually gets it.
They're drawn
to totally different aspects,
to this more
superficial version.
Sure, but it really
doesn't matter
how amazing your version is
if no one gets to read it.
That'll be 28 pounds
when you're ready.
Sorry.
Thanks.
There's something
I really think we should see,
erm...
The week after next
it's coming on.
I think it...
The inside pocket
of your jacket.
I'll see you again
next Thursday.
Next week erm...
may be a bit tricky.
I've got a lot of work on at the
moment with the writing, so...
Of course.
But I'll let you know though.
Whenever it suits.
Welcome
aboard the 10:45 Eurostar
to Brussels Midi.
The restaurant-bar
is located in carriage 4.
We will arrive
at our destination
at 1:45 p.m.
We wish you a pleasant journey.
It's really good to see you.
Ah, Mr Larson.
Nice to see you again.
Just follow me, please.
How are you?
- Very good. Thank you.
So they all know you here.
Yeah.
I like to come here
whenever I'm in town.
Yeah, I love their food.
Though I always seem
to have the same meal. Yeah.
But never the same company.
No, erm...
Well...
If I find something I like,
I want to have it again.
So what are your family doing
this weekend?
Just...
keeping themselves company,
I suppose.
Have they ever been to Brussels?
Well...
I don't think
they're very interested.
Would you like some more wine?
Yes, please.
Thank you.
Perhaps another bottle?
Erm...
Why not.
Sorry, I'm not feeling too well.
I think I had
a bit too much to drink.
Go get
some water then.
I'm tired.
It's okay. It's okay.
Can we just wait until morning?
Do I have to remind
you who is paying for this?
Can you at least get a condom?
Please.
Max?
Max!
We haven't got all day.
Can you at least get a condom?
What the fuck is this?
Oh fuck. Erm...
"And in that moment,
Sebastian realised
that to try to fight back
would have been fruitless,
or dangerous even."
That is not what happened!
What the fuck is this?
It's just for myself.
It's nothing.
I should have known.
Never trust a whore.
Sorry. Give my laptop.
- Get out.
It's nothing.
- Please. Get out.
Give my laptop back.
- Get the fuck out.
Can I have my laptop?
Just give it.
- Now!
- Get... out!
Give me my stuff.
- I'll give you your stuff.
- Out. Now.
Fucking whore!
Fuck.
Do you have my wallet?
I need it.
Daniel!
Sir? Sir, please.
You need to stop.
You are disturbing the guests.
I left my wallet.
- Sir, please.
I want you to leave.
Reception can sort it out.
I need to get in...
Good afternoon, Mr Larson.
I'm sorry to disturb you.
I have a young man
in front of me
who wants access to your room.
He's looking for his wallet.
He says his name is Sebastian.
Do you know him?
No?
No, he's lying.
- Okay. Thank you very much.
I'm so sorry to have
disturbed you. Thank you. Bye.
There's nothing more I can do.
- He's a liar.
Your colleagues have literally
seen me here before.
I'm sorry.
If you're not booking a room,
I have to ask you to leave.
Are you kidding?
That's fucking ridiculous.
I've been here before!
- Please, sir, calm down.
Sorry. I can't do anything.
- Call him again.
I can't do that. I'm sorry.
Hi, Mum.
Hi, Max.
Why are you not picking up?
I've been trying
to get through to you.
I was just in the cinema.
Why am I getting
a strange dialling tone?
Where are you?
Erm...
I'm in Brussels, with Amna.
In Brussels?
Sorry, I didn't get the chance
to tell you.
It was so last minute. Erm...
Amna got a deal on
Eurostar tickets, so... erm...
She took me here
for the weekend.
A late birthday present.
That was really nice of her.
Listen, your dad and I
were just calling to say
that we had read that piece
in the Evening Standard.
You came across
really, really well.
I am so proud of you, Max.
Yeah.
That's great.
You spoke so beautifully.
Bye.
- Bye, darling.
Closing time.
Get going. We are closing up.
Move along. We're closing.
♪ How much longer can you last? ♪
♪ Push it to the limit
Over in a minute ♪
♪ Burning up until you crash ♪
♪ Oh, oh ♪
♪ How much longer can you last? ♪
♪ Burning up until you crash ♪
♪ Make you sweat
Dripping down your neck ♪
♪ Let's get together
Gonna make you sweat ♪
♪ My silhouette
Running round your head ♪
♪ Let's get together
Gonna make you sweat ♪
Thank you.
- No problem.
A handsome guy like you
should never be thirsty.
Are you here on holiday?
Yes. Something like that.
♪ Everything was mine [alright] ♪
♪ I knew it
When I saw you that night ♪
♪ My heart, it felt complete and ♪
♪ Everything was
Perfectly aligned [alright] ♪
♪ It happened just like that ♪
Want to go to my place?
It's not far.
Yes. I'd like that.
But that'll be 200.
What?
It's 200.
Hey, this is Amna.
I can't pick up now,
but please leave a message
and I'll get back to you
as soon as I can. Thanks.
Hello?
Sebastian?
Are you there?
Is everything all right?
I've always been rather
fond of the name Jonathan.
I'm going to tell my publisher
that I'm scrapping
the whole project.
They never even liked
that section anyway.
Do you not hate me?
For using you like that?
No, I don't.
You need to carry on
and finish it.
What I would hate you for
is not publishing it.
And...
if I can help in any way,
and heaven forbid,
be an inspiration to you,
I couldn't be more thrilled.
It's good.
There are fresh towels
in the bathroom.
Really nice to meet you, Max.
- You too.
Have a good rest of the day.
I'm really excited
about our conversation.
Your book is one of
my favorites of this year.
Thank you.
I'll begin by introducing
and welcoming everyone
and then if you just want
to follow out after me
and get seated
once I introduce you.
- Yeah.
Did you get a chance
to look at the questions?
I did, yeah.
- And did they all seem okay?
I mean, if there is anything
you don't feel
comfortable discussing...
or if anything feels
too personal, please tell me.
You can ask me anything.
♪ I work all night ♪
♪ I do my thing ♪
♪ Just killin' time ♪
♪ Need a friend ♪
♪ Is this my life? ♪
♪ Beginning or end? ♪
♪ Can I start again? ♪
♪ Can we start again? ♪
♪ There's a new moon on the rise ♪
♪ Turn the tide, turn the tide ♪
♪ I've been walking a thin line ♪
♪ Between the Earth and the sky ♪
♪ Why do my realities take over
All my dreams? ♪
♪ Why does all the purest love
Get filtered through machines? ♪
♪ Gimme something good
That's even better than it seems ♪
♪ Why does all the purest love
Get filtered through machines?♪
♪ I work all night
♪ I do my thing [I do my thing] ♪
♪ Just killin' time
♪ Need a friend [a friend] ♪
♪ Is this my life?♪
♪ Beginning or end?
♪ Can I start again?
♪ Can we start again?
♪ There's a new sun
In the sky ♪
♪ Where are you?
Where am I?♪
♪ Have you been looking, ♪
♪ Like I've been looking
For a reason or a sign? ♪
♪ Oh, why? Oh, why? ♪
♪ Why do my realities take over
All my dreams? ♪
♪ Why does all the purest love
Get filtered through machines?♪
♪ Gimme something good
That's even better than it seems ♪
♪ Why does all the purest love
Get filtered through machines? ♪
♪ I work all night
♪ I do my thing
♪ Just killin' time
♪
♪ Need a friend
♪ Is this my life? ♪
♪ Beginning or end?
♪ Can I start again?
♪ Can we start again?
♪ Can we begin again? ♪