Hiya, Stel.
Hello.
Hello, Stella.
Stella's got a fella!
Only
he don't know it.
Who?
You, that's who.
My own sister, standing
out here every night making
a sap out of herself over a
guy who don't even know she's
on Earth.
- You mind your own business!
Anyways, you don't know
what you're talking about.
Oh, I don't, huh?
I suppose you doll
up every night
and wait out here
to welcome me home.
Why, of course.
Oh, gee, thanks.
I must give you a
kiss for that one.
Now stop it!
Take your dirty hands off of me!
Ah, you're
just like all the rest.
There's fingers nearly chopped
off at the mill every time
he passes.
But he don't look
at none of 'em.
Why should he?
Mill hands.
Hey, wait a minute.
There's some nice girls
that's mill hands.
Where do you get off?
What's the matter
with a mill hand?
I work in the mill.
I'm a mill hand, and your
father's a mill hand!
All right, all
right, don't yell.
The neighbors know it.
- Yeah?
Well, maybe he don't,
so I'll tell him!
Hey!
- Stop that!
Here, stop this!
What's the matter with you two?
You used to get along.
Yeah, but that was before
she started taking a business
course to improve herself.
It's done her a lot
of good, all right.
She ain't satisfied
with none of us anymore.
Supper!
What'd you say, Mom?
Supper's ready!
Yeah, so am I. Come on, Pop.
Come on, Stel.
I'll be in in a minute.
The childhood sweetheart
of young Stephen Dallas,
a sweetheart until
that tragic hour
when his millionaire father,
bankrupt and ill, committed
suicide.
Two days later Stephen Dallas
disappeared, leaving behind him
a note saying that he was trying
to make a life somewhere else.
Harvard graduate and crewman
disappeared immediately
after his father's death.
Millionaire playboy
left without a penny.
Don't be late, Charlie.
What is it?
Your lunch.
Oh, that's
right, get funny.
You know what I mean.
What's in it?
Oh, just a little
turkey and dressing.
That's all I had today.
Wait a minute.
Baloney again.
And apple butter.
Baloney and apple
butter, apple butter
and baloney, that's all I get.
Well, I ain't going
to take it no more.
It's all right with me,
you can do without it.
Oh, I can, huh?
Charlie, I'll
fix you something.
Oh, don't baby him, Mom.
Baby me?
I'm old enough to
earn money, ain't I?
A man could have a home of
his own on what I'm making!
Charlie, wait a minute.
Oh, what do you want to
egg him on for, Stella?
You know that Jenkins girl's
just dying to get him.
Well, let her, then.
If that's the only
ambition he's got,
there's nothing you
can do about it.
I don't know what
we'd do without him.
I'm going to fix up
something for him to eat
and you can leave it for
him on your way down.
He'll starve first.
Maybe you're right, Mom.
I'll take it down to him.
I'll run over to
the delicatessen
after and get him
something nice.
Will you?
Yeah.
Hey, the boss just phoned.
He's in Millhampton Junction.
He just got in.
He said to tell you the
contract with Parker Company's
right in his vest pocket.
He's chirping over
the phone like a bird.
He says he'll be
here in a few minutes
but just wanted to tell you.
Hey, ain't you interested?
Yes, yes, I'm--
I'm glad Mr. Beamer
got the contract.
Well, you ought to be.
He was chirping like a bird.
Like a bird, you know the
way he does on the telephone.
Yes, sir, he said to put you
down for a raise this week.
And you could have
that vacation now.
How's that?
I don't need a vacation now.
I've no place to go.
Huh?
Oh, oh, nothing.
Nothing.
I beg your pardon.
Could you tell me where I
could find Charlie Martin?
Charlie Martin?
Yes, he works on
the carding machine.
Oh, yes.
The-- the carding machines.
Well, why, they're
closed down just now.
He'd be out in the
yard most likely.
I'll tell you what you do.
You go right back through the
corridor the way you came in,
and instead of coming
up those stairs,
there's a big gate down there.
And if you go right through
that gate, and the path
leads right down past
that first big building.
And just as you turn
around the corner,
the men usually have their--
Yes?
Well, er-- it's sort
of dirty down there.
Maybe I'd better send for him.
Won't you sit down?
Thank you.
McCarthy!
Yes, sir.
Find Charlie Martin
and send him in.
Yes, sir.
Right away.
He'll be right in.
Thank you.
Good morning,
Dallas, good morning.
Mr. Beamer, congratulations
on that contract.
How do you do, Mr. Beamer?
How do you do?
Stella Martin?
Martin's girl?
You're all grown
up, and so pretty.
Isn't she, Dallas?
Yes.
Say, how long have you
two known each other?
Well, we, ah,
haven't really met.
Oh, excuse me.
Mr. Dallas, this is Miss Martin.
Miss Martin, Mr. Dallas.
How do you do?
My brother forgot
his lunch and I
didn't want him to go without,
so I brought it to him.
That's a nice girl.
Good to your brother.
Good to your father,
too, I'll bet.
I wish I had somebody thinking
so much of me, eh, Dallas?
He ain't there, Mr. Dallas.
They said he went out to eat.
Oh, thank you.
Oh, that's too bad,
after all your trouble.
Oh, I suppose it was
all my fault. I was late.
Well, it wouldn't do him
any harm to wait, would it?
I'll bet sometimes he's late.
Never mind, don't you worry.
Let's see what you've got.
Maybe we can make believe
that you brought it to us.
Eh, Dallas?
Well, it isn't anything much.
Oh!
Mm!
Make this yourself?
Mm-hm.
Dallas?
Thank you.
You do.
I hope they're not too dry.
I forgot to bring
anything to drink.
I have some milk here.
Oh, fine.
I'll
get some glasses.
Can I help you?
Thank you.
Say, you're some
cook, aren't you?
Oh, wait, please.
I hate glasses that don't shine.
Don't you?
Mm.
Mm-hm.
Care to go?
You ready?
Hello, Stella.
Hello.
Hello, Steve.
Hiya, Ned.
Don't forget, the
missus will be expecting
you over for that good meal.
You bet.
Very soon.
You going there for dinner?
Gee, you who could
be at the River Club.
Look, look.
Hmm, that's the
second time this week.
I saw them in the drugstore
together the other night.
You mind your own business.
Do you mind our being
talked about, Stella?
Mind?
I mind?
Oh, no.
It's just that-- well, I can't
believe you like seeing me,
when you could be out
with all the swells.
I want to be with you.
I like being with you.
Um, could I--
could I take your arm?
I mean, is that all right?
Is that considered--
I want to be like all the
people you've been around.
Educated, you know,
and speaking nice.
Don't be like anyone else.
I like you the way you are.
No, I don't want
to be like me.
Not like the people
in this place,
but like the people
in the movie.
You know, doing everything
well-bred and refined.
And dull.
Stay as you are.
Don't pretend, Stella.
Anyway, it isn't
really well-bred
to act the way you aren't.
But I've wanted to be
different ever since I met you.
And if I was around you
long enough, I could be.
Why, I could learn
to talk like you
and act like you,
and pretty soon I--
well, you know, you've
done a lot for me
even in these couple of weeks.
You've done a lot for me, too.
I was very lonely the day
you walked in the office.
Oh, no, I--
no thanks.
I don't smoke.
And I don't drink, either.
I was lonely and unhappy and--
and then you--
Yes?
Oh, I-- I shouldn't have.
You won't have any
respect for me.
Not for girls who let men
kiss them whenever they want.
I-- I mean, I don't let--
I mean-- well, girls
shouldn't, unless they--
well, unless they
know a man is serious.
Hiya, Mom.
Ain't she got home yet?
No.
Does the old man know?
Hello, Pop.
What time did Stella get home?
Huh?
Oh, oh that was about--
well, that was around,
oh, I don't know.
But she woke me up.
Hey, Mom, how about
the coffee, huh?
And Pop's, too.
Tell Stella I want to see her.
Gee, Pop, it was
kind of late, you know.
Let her sleep.
Tell Stella I want to see her.
Yes.
Why-- why, she ain't here.
I wonder where she
could have gone so early.
She ain't slept there!
I guess she spent the
night with Carrie Jenkins.
It was raining kind
of hard, you know.
She didn't go out
with Carrie Jenkins, why
should stay the night with her?
When she gets home, you
tell her to take her things
and be out of here before
I get back, I mean it.
Oh, now, listen,
Pop, you can't.
You got to give her
a chance to explain.
You shut up!
Tell her what I said.
All right, then, I guess
that goes for me, too.
Charlie, finish your coffee.
I'll talk to your pa.
I don't want any coffee,
or any part of this dump
from now on.
I'm through!
I'll tell you later.
Oh, gee, Stella,
where you been?
You know, the old
man's been all--
Look, Charlie, look!
- Married?
- Uh-huh!
Oh, Stel!
Oh, my gosh.
Aw, gee, Mr. Dallas,
that's swell.
Hey, Ma!
Hey, Ma, she's here.
She's married.
Hey, Ma!
Hey, Pop, it's OK now.
She's here.
We're here, Agnes.
My, oh, my, you sure is!
And there it is!
Yes, ma'am.
Who do it look like?
Let me
see who you look
like, your pappy or your mammy.
Go ahead, Agnes,
and open the door.
You'll have plenty of
time for that later on.
Yes'm.
Yes, ma'am.
I know who's gonna be boss
'round here from now on.
Oh, gosh, home never
looked so good to me.
Poor Stella.
Oh, I didn't mind.
It was just the hospital
got on my nerves.
And that darn doctor, trying
to make me stay another week.
Well, but Stella, he just
thought it would be better--
Better for who?
It was just to get your money.
I felt as good the
next day as I ever did,
and maybe better than
I had for a while.
Oh, Stephen, why didn't
you bring him to me?
The days wouldn't have
seemed half so long.
Gosh, I thought everybody
had forgotten me.
Now, Mrs. Dallas, I
think we'll get you to bed.
Bed?
I just got up.
Haven't you seen enough of me
in bed for the past three weeks?
Seems like three years to me.
You'll soon find you're not
as strong as you think you are.
You must remember I've had
a great deal of experience
in these maternity cases.
Experience?
What do you think I had?
Tell me, why is it doctors
and nurses and husbands
always seem to
think they know more
about this maternity business?
Don't you think a mother learns
anything in that little room
they wheel them into?
Or is that just a
kindergarten class?
Oh, Mrs. Dallas.
Let me tell you something,
I picked up quite a
little experience in that room.
And it wasn't out
of books, either.
Experience.
Stephen!
Yes, dear?
A dance at the River
Club tomorrow night.
I think I can wear
my blue dress.
I'll let it out a
little at the top.
But Stella, you don't
want to go dancing already.
Before I went
to the hospital, I
was stuck in this house
for four solid months
without going anywheres.
And we just got
into the River Club.
All my life I've just about
died to go to the real places
and get in with the right
crowd, and when I got a chance
and get started, I
have to give it all up.
Oh, we'll go next time.
Well, I
don't want to go next time,
I want to go this time.
Aw, Stephen, I won't
dance much, I promise.
Gee, I just want to get
a wave and a manicure
and get all dressed up
again, and go hear some music
and forget all about doctors
and hospitals and nurses.
And babies?
Mm, aw.
Aw, but Steven, please.
Well, you're a
wonderful dancer, Mr. Munn!
Well, if I'm any
judge of horseflesh,
you don't shake a
mean leg yourself.
Hello!
Hello.
Who's that she's dancing with?
He's pretty good, too.
I-- I really don't know.
His name is Munn.
He has something to
do with horse races.
The girls invite him
over for golf, and he--
he gives them tips!
How'd you come to get hooked
up to a table like that?
Oh, they're some business
friends of my husband's.
Business friends?
What is he, an undertaker?
Oh, why don't you get him to
ditch that bunch of moss bags
and come over and join us?
Spencer Chandler's table?
Well, we don't even know him.
Well, that won't take long.
You know what he said
after our first dance?
No, what?
He said, Ed-- he
always calls me Ed.
He said, Ed, you can pick
winners on a dance floor
better than you
can on a racetrack.
Yeah?
Aw, go on, don't red-apple me.
No, on the level.
Come on, I'll prove it to you.
Well, I'd, um, I have
to ask Stephen first.
Stephen?
Yes?
Come here.
Excuse me.
Yes?
Stephen, this is Mr. Munn.
Howya?
Mr. Chandler,
Spencer Chandler,
wants us to come
over to his table.
I'm sorry, we're just leaving.
Leaving?
Why, it's only quarter after.
I know, but
that's late for us.
Aw, come just for a nightcap.
Oh, yes, Stephen, please.
I'm afraid we
can't, thank you.
Good night.
Hm.
I'll get the things.
He dug down in his
pocket, got his last cent,
and the horse came in
and paid 20 to one!
- 20 to one!
- What do you think of that?
Oh, dear, I--
I--
Did you lose something?
Well, yes, I--
What was it?
May I help you?
Oh, I remember.
I gave it to Mr., uh, pardon me.
What do you think of that?
What a story.
Say, Ed.
Did you give me back
my handkerchief?
You never gave it to me.
Oh, I must have lost it.
Well, here.
Take mine.
Oh, no, no, didn't mean I--
Well, wait a minute.
I want you to meet a
friend of mine, Stella.
Mr. Chandler, this
is Mrs. Dallas.
How do you do?
Say, Spence, I want you to
prove something to her for me.
Didn't you say I could
pick 'em on a dance floor
as good as on the track?
- Mm-hm.
But I wouldn't
feel too flattered.
Munn hasn't given me a
winner in over a month.
Will you sit down?
Oh, thank you.
Mrs. Dallas, I'd like
you to meet Miss Terry.
Oh, I believe your
wife lost something
and she thought maybe Mr.--
Mr. Munn.
Mr. Munn might know.
Well, thank you.
Oh, Stephen.
Stephen, this is Mr. Chandler.
Mr. Chandler, my husband.
- How do you do?
Mr. Chandler just
asked me to dance.
You don't mind.
I'm sorry, my wife's
just out of the hospital.
She should be home in bed.
Oh, well, we'll hurry then.
Come on.
Mr. Dallas, you wouldn't
like to sit down and have
a little snifter, would you?
No, thank you.
Thank you.
What have I done this time?
All right, I'll
take my usual lecture.
Go ahead, begin.
Stella, I asked you not
to wear those earrings.
That cheap imitation necklace.
You took them off, you agreed,
then after we got there you
came out of the dressing room--
Now, Stephen.
I'm perfectly willing to
let you tell me how to talk
and how to act, but
please don't give
me pointers on how to dress.
Allow me at least to know more
about one thing than you do.
After all, I've always been
known to have stacks of style.
You should have heard Ed Munn,
and he's been around a bit,
too.
He's traveled further and he--
all right then, farther,
whichever it is.
I don't care.
Gosh, I have to think twice
every time I open my mouth.
And Spencer Chandler
didn't seem to have
to turn the other way, either.
And he only happens to
be one of The Chandlers.
Stella, please.
Don't say things like that.
Remember you're my wife now.
Oh, and can't
look at another man!
That isn't the point at all.
Oh-ho, that's a laugh.
An affair between Spencer
Chandler and I. Well,
I am coming up in the world!
Stella, can't you, won't
you try to understand?
Please listen to me
this time, please.
The fake jewelry's
not important.
Chandler's not important.
None of these things
matter in themselves.
But what's to become of us?
That is important.
Yes, dear.
Stella, why did you marry me?
Because I was crazy
about you, silly.
And I-- I still am, only--
only you just don't
seem to ever--
Once, a long time ago, you
said you were crazy to learn
everything, become someone.
Didn't you?
Yes, Stephen.
Please listen to me.
I'm only telling you
this because I love you.
Beamer wants to
send me to New York
to handle the sales
department there.
I want to go.
And I want to take you with me.
But I want you to
make an effort.
I want you to try to be
what you wanted to be.
Give up a few things for me,
and try to adapt yourself--
Adapt myself?
Give up a few things?
What have I been doing
ever since I met you?
And I'm getting a
little sick of it, too.
How would it be for you to do
a little adapting for a change?
I don't see you
giving up anything.
And I'll tell you
one more thing.
I'm not going to New York.
I'm certainly not
going to leave here
just when I'm beginning to
get in with the right people.
Now, Stella.
You-- you go on
and go to New York.
I want to stay here.
Well, can you beat that?
Laying here wide awake,
waiting for her dinner
and not a squawk out of her.
Gosh, Carrie.
You know, I used to think
girls at the mill were crazy
when they got married and
right off the bat started
having kids.
But honest, Stella,
would you want any more?
Sure, if I could have
another one like her.
She's been a regular pal to me.
Since Stephen's been
away in New York so much,
I hardly know I have a husband.
Why, he's only been here
three times this summer,
and then it was
only account of her.
He's crazy about her.
And who wouldn't be?
Oh, look at her!
Wiping it up at her
age, can you beat that?
She's the spit of her old man!
Now, who is that?
Agnes?
Well, is this all
the welcome I get?
Ed!
Of all people!
Oh gosh, I'm glad to see you!
And I you.
I haven't seen you for ages.
Get a load of that kid.
Has she grown or am I crazy?
Come on.
Oh gee, Stella, she looks
more like you every time.
You remember Uncle
Ed, don't you, darling?
Well, I remember you.
Oh!
Ed!
How's that?
Oh, Ed, you shouldn't
have done this!
Oh, don't she look
like a little queen?
All in gold and turquoise.
Edna!
You want a drink, don't you?
Sure.
And if you don't mind,
I'll peel this coat.
Oh, sure, go ahead.
What'll it be?
Well, you know me, Stella,
I ain't partic', so long as it
don't jump up and bite me.
But I've been drinking bourbon.
What have you been drinking?
Oh, nothing.
But I'll take bourbon.
Aw, gee, Stel, you
oughta been along.
Or maybe you've been
having too much fun here.
Gosh, Ed, I haven't been out
of the house for two months.
Been sick?
No, but-- I don't know.
I don't seem to get any fun
out of a good time anymore.
All the time I'm out,
I'm thinking of her
and what she's doing and how
soon I can get back to her.
Well, here's
hoping I'll always
be around at the right time.
What are you drinking?
Sarsaparilla.
Stealing
the kids' drinks, huh?
Did you ever catch her
sneaking your oatmeal?
Hey, can I pick her up?
Sure, go ahead!
Come on to your uncle Ed.
Gotcha, girl.
Come on.
Ain't you got a big
smile for your uncle Ed?
Of course she has.
Come on, darlin'.
Smile for uncle Ed.
Edna?
Edna!
I'll get it.
If I could only see her
open that door just once.
Come on, darlin'.
Come on, darling.
STELLA AND ED COAXING
Stella?
Oh, um-- oh, you
remember Mr. Munn.
How do you do?
And Carrie Jenkins.
Yes, how do you do.
How do you do?
I think I'll be getting along.
Yes, darling.
That's a fine baby you've
got there, Mr. Dallas.
Thank you.
I think so.
I gotta be going too, Ed.
Oh, me, too.
Yeah, just a minute,
I'll see you to the door.
Listen, Stella,
you call me soon, will you?
Yeah.
All right.
Thanks for a good time.
Bye.
Stella, I can't have
our child living this way.
What's wrong this time?
It's not just this time.
It's every time I--
What do you mean, because
there was a couple of drinks?
Well, what's wrong with that?
Coming in here with that
icebergy way of yours.
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to be rude.
But she's my child, too.
And I won't have this.
I hadn't wanted to take
Laurel away from you, but--
if you--
Take her away from me?
What are you talking about?
How dare you say such a thing?
Give her to me!
Now, Stella.
- Give her to me, I say!
- Stella, please.
You mustn't do this, now.
- Give her to me!
Stella!
Watch out, you're hurting her!
Stella.
Get off.
Did he frighten
Mummy's little girl?
Oh, don't you cry.
Mummy's right here.
Mummy won't let
anybody hurt you.
There, there.
You're here with Mummy, and
nobody in the whole world
is ever going to take you away.
Nobody.
Thank you.
Boy.
The whole thing.
Would you like to
include one of those, too?
No, she's a little too grown
up for that now, I'm afraid.
Come on fellas,
Mother's ready.
Come on, boys.
Mother, he rows it himself!
Aw, can't we wait
until he winds it again?
I want you to see how it goes.
Thank you, Mr. Dallas.
You'll send those
right away, won't you?
Yes.
Stephen?
Helen.
Oh, Stephen!
Oh, I'm so glad to see you.
Oh, and you.
Oh, boys, come.
Come here, please.
Stephen, these are my sons.
How do you do,
young gentlemen?
How do you do?
Oh, this is Mr.
Dallas, whom your mother
has known for such a long time.
John.
- John.
How do you do?
Lee.
- How do you do?
And Cornelius.
Cornelius.
- How do you do?
- Con.
He doesn't like to
be called Cornelius.
I do, too.
It was my father's name.
Was?
Con's the man
of the family now.
And he looks after us
all so beautifully,
his father would be very proud.
That's splendid.
Nothing but the finest
care in the world
would be good enough
for your mother.
Oh, but Stephen,
tell us about you.
Oh, I gave up all
thought of ever seeing
you again such a long time ago.
What are you doing here?
Well, if you mean New
York, I'm in business here.
If you mean the store,
I'm here buying birthday
presents for my daughter.
Your daughter?
Oh, Stephen!
There she is.
Ooh, pretty!
Oh, she's lovely.
Thank you.
Oh, when may we meet her?
And her mother?
They're not here.
You see, Laurel goes to
school up near Boston
and her mother spends
all of her time with her.
Oh.
Oh, I have so many things
to hear, and to tell.
Can you lunch with us?
Well, I should be back
at the office by now.
We'd be glad to have you,
Mr. Dallas, if you don't
mind carrying your own tray.
John's been saving
up for a whole month
in order to take us for lunch.
It's his treat.
That's all right.
I got enough for one more,
if you don't eat too much.
How about it, Mr. Dallas?
Well, I guess I can't
refuse an offer like that.
Oh, good.
If you run short,
I'll lend you a couple dollars.
Gee, thanks.
Oh, books again.
Sometimes I've got a good
mind to write and tell him
she can get books
from the library,
but there's no place where you
can get a fur coat for nothing.
Boy, what I wouldn't
give to see her in one.
Oh, well.
Here.
Hide them with the rest and
let me get on with this,
or it won't be
ready for Christmas,
let alone her birthday.
Hello, Gladys.
Where's Mother?
Now, let me see.
Uh, she's-- um, she's--
Hello, Mother.
Hello darling.
Mother, Miss Phillibrown,
my teacher, came home with me.
She wants to see you.
Oh, Lolly, if I'd only known,
I could have fixed up a little.
Look at me, I'm a sight!
But you look fine!
Oh, no, look at the
things all-- oh, dear.
Mother, this is
Miss Phillibrown.
Oh.
How do you do, Mrs. Dallas?
Pleased to meet you.
Won't you sit down?
Oh, really, I haven't
a minute, but thank you.
Laurel, my dear, I wonder if
I might have a glass of water.
- Oh, of course.
- You too, Mother?
No.
Maybe she'd rather
have some sarsaparilla.
I have some on ice.
- No, thank you.
All right.
She's such a darling.
You know, I didn't want
to talk in front of her
in case she might
be disappointed.
I spend the weekends in Boston,
and I wonder if you would let
me borrow Laurel for this one.
I, um, I couldn't get
her ready this time,
but if you'd ask her again--
oh, Lolly thinks the world and
all of you, Miss Phillibrown.
I know she'd have
a wonderful time.
Seeing some decent shows,
I mean, not just movies.
Well, I had in mind the
galleries and museums.
She seemed so interested.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, she's crazy
about that stuff.
She gets that stuff
from her father.
Her father?
You see, I've only
heard about you.
Oh.
Well, of course, she don't
see as much of her father.
Mr. Dallas's business
keeps him in New York.
Oh, really?
But I always spend his
vacation with him, don't I,
Mother?
- Uh-huh.
Up in Maine, in the woods.
Have you ever been there?
No.
Oh, it's beautiful!
Your mother has just given
her permission for you to spend
a weekend with me in Boston.
When?
Very soon.
Oh, thank you
Miss Phillibrown!
Well, I really must go.
Oh, must you?
Goodbye, Mrs. Dallas.
Goodbye.
Come again, won't you?
Thank you.
Goodbye, Laurel, dear.
Goodbye, Miss Phillibrown.
Oh, Mother, isn't
she the nicest?
Yes, darling.
Did you ask her to the party?
No.
Do you think she'd come?
Of course.
Why not?
Mother!
For the party?
Lolly!
What did you do that for?
You're always sticking your--
Oh, Mother, I'm sorry.
Oh, come here, darling.
I didn't mean it.
You know how I always
fly off, and well, I
wanted it to be a surprise.
Well, now that
you've seen it, you
may as well slip
it on and let me
fit you instead of this thing.
Dummy.
Oh, it's blue!
Mm-hm.
There.
Oh, Mother, it's beautiful!
Careful, don't
mash the ruffles.
Now, oh, yeah, I forgot.
This goes here.
Oh, no.
Oh yes, it gives it some snap.
No, please.
Oh, for heaven's sake,
you're just like your father.
You want everything as
plain as an old shoe.
Plain?
With all these beautiful
handmade ruffles?
Now turn around.
Yes, the length's all right,
it's just the sleeves.
All right, take it off
and let me get on with it.
Yoo-hoo!
What's going on there?
Come on in, Ed!
No, Mother, wait
till I get out!
What is this, a
Follies dressing room?
Mother please!
Oh, what's the matter?
He shouldn't see me like this!
For heaven's sake, Ed's known
you since you were knee high
and seen you with
hardly anything on.
Yes, and even less than that.
Now, what have you got
to hide from your uncle?
You've got nothing to
hide, come on, let me see.
Mother, make him stop, please!
Oh, Ed, stop!
Lolly, don't be a little fool.
- Come on, let me--
- No!
Oh, Ed, I wish you
wouldn't tease her like that.
You know she don't like it.
I know, but I get a
kick out of a young one
being so finicky.
Well.
Your car downstairs?
- No.
No, it's in the shop, why?
Oh.
Well, I wanted to go to town.
I wanted to get the
decorations for the party.
Well, why not go
in on the train?
I'll tell you, we'll
take the kids, see a show
and have dinner.
No, I don't want her
to know what I'm getting.
Oh, I see.
I guess I could show you
a better time without her.
Ed!
How long will you be?
I gotta run down to the corner.
I won't be long.
Well, unless you've
got a drink here.
I've got sarsaparilla.
I'll meet you at the corner.
Sarsaparilla.
Honest, Stel, some of
the things I do for you.
You'll like it when
you get used to it.
And it's good for you, too.
What's that?
Well, you can read, can't you?
Itch powder?
Shh!
Things are just a little
too quiet around here.
Oh, Ed, you're not--
Hey, can I see that?
Great jumpin' catfish, what's
the name of that horse?
- What's the matter?
- Nothing's the matter.
I got a ticket on it.
Oh, ho!
Kokomo wins!
I'm rich!
Well, let me shake your hand.
- Thank you!
Congratulations!
Thank you.
I'm awfully glad.
Why, listen, I stand to
win $20,000 or $30,000.
- Good.
- No fooling.
What's the matter?
Have a cigar.
Oh, what happened?
Sir!
Oh, I beg your
pardon, you want gum.
Here, we got all parts here.
Thank you very much.
Thank you, lady.
Say, that was great luck.
Why, did you
see what happened?
Yeah!
He won $30,000
on a horse race!
You're kidding.
Really?
Watch 'em commence.
I can't stand it!
Another one of 'em
just bit the dust.
Stop, you're killing me!
Look at the old girls.
They're doing a sister act.
They must have rehearsed.
Hey, Stella.
Stella!
What's so funny?
Oh, come on, look.
There are two down there.
Gee, Ed, you're a card.
I don't see how you can
keep such a straight face.
Oh, well, what's a little
kidding among friends?
- He's that the father?
- No.
No, it can't be.
She particularly said her
husband was in New York.
Such women don't
deserve to have children.
Well, there's only one
way to drink sarsaparilla,
and that's so it don't
taste like sarsaparilla.
Do you mind?
No.
Want some?
Uh-uh.
Laurel's such a lovely child.
I don't know what to think.
Why, Mary Ann's been
asked to her party.
Ah, Stel.
Why don't you scratch
that first entry of yours
and give somebody else a chance?
Honest, I'd do anything for you.
Please don't, Ed.
It's like I told you.
It's not personal,
only, well, I don't
think there's a man living that
could get me going anymore.
Oh, I don't know, I
guess Lolly just uses up
all the feelings I've got
and I don't seem to have
any left for anybody else.
You got plenty for me, Stel.
Why can't we go on as we are?
Gosh, I don't know
what I'd have done
without you some
of the times when
Lolly was back with Stephen.
You're such a good sport
and such a lot of fun.
Well, I guess you
know what you're doing.
What's the matter?
Say, do you know what?
I think I got some
of that stuff on me.
Now, would that be a hit?
I have!
Oh!
Oh, Stel, it's all over.
Here.
Gladys, You nearly ready?
I'll just have to let her in.
I'm ready.
Mm-mm!
Mrs. Dallas!
Do I look all right?
You know, none of
them have ever seen me
and she's always telling all
of them how beautiful I am.
Honey, you sure
can live up to it.
Yeah, but if I live
through this day,
I'm going to get
me another corset.
Mother?
- Yeah, coming, dear.
Mother!
However did you do it?
Oh, and you, Mother.
You look beautiful!
Do I?
And look, favors!
Oh, now, don't
pull them, they pop
and have little hats inside.
And the little baskets!
And I put candies
in with the nuts.
And the placecards,
Mother, they're beautiful.
Where did you get them?
Oh, I sit there
and you sit here.
And Miss Phillibrown
next to me,
and Flo Bell, and Alice May.
Uh-huh.
Mother?
Mother, could I see the cake?
Oh, all right, go ahead.
Oh, look!
One, two, three,
four, five, six--
Here somebody is!
Lolly!
Lolly, let Gladys go.
All right.
Gladys.
Now remember what I told you.
Yeah.
Lolly, no, no.
Is this the
Dallas residence?
Yes.
Sign here, please.
Thank you.
It's for you, Lolly.
Don't you forget to say Miss
Laurel in front of people.
Yes, ma'am.
What is it?
It's from Miss Phillibrown.
She can't come.
Well, what does she say?
"Laurel, dear, I'm sorry
it is impossible for me
to come to your party, but I'm
thinking of you this afternoon
and I hope you will
not be disappointed.
Sincerely, your friend
Margaret Phillibrown."
Oh, that's too bad.
Oh, I do you
wish she could have
come just to see everything.
And you.
Oh, well, I'll fix up
again for her sometime.
Most likely the girls will
have a better time without her.
I guess they see enough
of her in school.
I know I did my teachers.
Oh, but everyone
loves Miss Phillibrown.
Gladys, take these, please.
Well, anyway, it'll
make an even number.
Sure!
Come on, we'll wait
in the other room.
You sit over there.
No!
No, let Gladys go.
Remember what I told you?
Miss Dallas' residence?
That's right.
Miss Dallas' residence.
OK, I'll tell her.
Who was it?
It was Miss Cheeny and she
says Alice May can't come.
Who?
Alice May Cheeny.
She sits next to me in school.
Oh.
Uh, it'll make the
table look better.
It won't be so crowded.
I'll fix it.
I think I better make
some more biscuits,
don't you, Miss Dallas?
The others is all dried up.
Yes.
Yes, let's do that.
That's a very good idea.
You know, Mother, they're
not coming or they'd be here.
Oh, Lolly, you
don't think that--
We'll go in together.
I never know what to look for,
you change so much each time.
Do I look older?
Older?
You're a young lady.
Evidently your
wardrobe's going up, too.
Oh, I have a costume
for everything.
Fine.
Because we have a
wonderful invitation
to spend our whole time
together in the most
beautiful place in the world.
- Better than Maine?
- Mm-hm.
Where?
Mm-hm.
You'll see.
Hello.
Martha, this
is my daughter, Laurel.
How do you do?
Oh, Daddy, it's so beautiful.
Hello, Laurel.
This is Mrs. Morrison, Laurel.
How do you do?
So glad to see you.
I'm so glad to see you, too.
Michael, this is Laurel.
We've been waiting
and waiting to meet.
Now, don't overdo it.
Oh, he's such a nice dog.
Where are the boys?
I believe they're still down
at the stables, Mrs. Morrison.
Ah, well, tell them
their surprise is here.
You don't mind being
a surprise, do you?
No.
Come on, Mike,
we'll go fetch 'em.
Come on, boy.
I'll show Laurel her room.
Oh.
It's lovely.
How sweet.
Now, if you let
me have your keys,
I'll have Martha unpack you.
Oh, I can do it.
I'll take your coat.
Yes, thank you.
And your hat?
Oh, everything!
Oh, I like nice closets, too.
We'll hang this here.
There.
Oh, I'm so glad you
brought your riding clothes.
It was one of the things on my
list, to ride in Central Park.
Well, we'll be
using them here, too.
Oh, and so many
pretty dresses.
What fun your mother must
have choosing them for you.
She makes them all.
She does?
Uh-huh.
Oh, how clever!
Oh, what a lucky girl you are.
And how lucky she is, too.
All boys want to
wear are overalls.
Ah, well, I suppose
you want to freshen up.
But don't change.
I'll run down and see that your
father has his tea, because he
has to get right back to town.
You come down when
you're ready, and don't
keep the boys waiting too long.
Thank you.
PARTY MUSIC,
INDISTINCT CONVERSATION
They won't acknowledge
that they like you yet, they
haven't got as far as that.
But have you noticed the
hair brushing and collar
wearing that's been going on?
I have.
Mother!
Am I too little to
dance with Laurel?
Did she say so?
No, but Con did.
Well, if I wanted
to dance with Laurel,
I think I'd ask her, not Con.
I will.
Big intrigue.
Let me have it.
You'll drop it.
I will not.
I'm carrying it.
I want to carry it.
Goodbye, Laurel.
It's been fun, hasn't it?
Oh, yes.
Oh, we look forward
to the next time.
I've had such a lovely time,
I don't know how to thank you.
Bye!
Goodbye!
Oh, aren't they the nicest boys?
I think so.
How did you like Mrs. Morrison?
I think she's the
loveliest lady I ever knew.
Do you, Laurel?
Do you really?
Oh, I mean--
I mean-- of course, I
mean except my mother.
Mother, how nice!
It's a little stuffy,
I'm going to open a window!
All right.
You happy?
Mm.
Well, I guess I'll shove off.
You two got lots to
talk about, and-- say,
where are you going to eat, Ed?
Me?
Oh, I don't know, I
ain't very hungry.
I thought maybe I'd
stop in at, uh--
Well, uh, why don't you come
back and have dinner with us?
You only bought two chops.
Sure, one for you
and one for Lolly.
Oh, say, I'm so happy I
couldn't even look at a meal.
Fine.
About what time?
Oh, an hour.
Good.
So long, Lollipops.
I'll come back and tie
on the nose bag with you.
Want me to bring anything?
No.
No thanks, Ed.
Oh, Mother, why did you?
I thought we were going to
have a nice, quiet time alone.
Oh, so did I, Lolly, darling,
but things haven't been going
so good for poor Ed
lately, not that you
never know it to hear him talk.
But you remember that bit watch
and chain he used to wear?
Well, they're-- they're
just not there anymore.
I'm sorry.
Gladys!
Oh, she's not here anymore.
I let her go.
Mother!
Oh, well, what did I
need with anybody around?
Oh Mother, you shouldn't have.
Besides, I was glad
to have something to do
to help pass the time away.
You know what I did?
What?
I saved enough
money out of her wages
to pay a deposit on
a fur coat for you.
Mother, you didn't.
Mm-hm.
Well, you're just going
to get it right back.
I don't want a fur
coat now, Mother.
Besides, none of the girls I
met at Mrs. Morrison's were
allowed to have them yet.
Oh no?
No.
Oh.
Here.
Mother, you know what
I've been thinking?
Would it cost too
awfully much for us
to have a house with
our own front door,
and a little garden and flowers
and a room for each of us?
Oh, just in case
sometimes we wanted
somebody to stay all night.
Oh, Mother, not a great
big expensive house
like Mrs. Morrison's, but
just a little, tiny place.
Say, tell me about
this Mrs. Morrison.
What's she like?
Oh, Mother, she's lovely.
She's sort of-- well, she
reminds me of a flower
that grows up in Maine.
All pale and delicate,
but strong, too.
I don't know what you call it.
Oh, gracious, Lolly, I don't
care what kind of a flower
she looks like!
Is she tall or short, dark
or light, fat or thin?
How old is she?
Well, she doesn't seem
to be any special age.
You know, she's like
one of those goddesses
in my mythology book that way.
Oh, come now.
You can tell whether
she's 20 or 40.
Oh, she's not 40, no.
Well, I'd guess
maybe she's about 25.
And how did your father
happen to meet this goddess?
Mother, it's like a story.
Con told me all about it.
- Con?
Mm-hm.
Is that her husband?
Oh, no, he's dead.
Didn't I write you?
Dead, is he?
Well, that's convenient.
Oh no, it isn't.
It isn't a bit convenient.
Because when Mr. Morrison died,
he left a whole lot of houses
and horses and money and things,
and Mrs. Morrison has to look
out for them all by herself.
You know, she said she wouldn't
know what to do without Father
to help her and advise her.
Yeah.
I can just imagine.
Oh, I just remembered.
I've got some snapshots of her.
Aw, no, Lolly, I--
I just want to look at you.
Oh, but Mother, I want you
to see her, she's beautiful.
No--
You'll be crazy about her!
The funny thing about her
is she's not only beautiful
when she's all
dressed, but even when
she wakes up in the morning.
She spends hardly
any time on her face.
Once I saw her put soap
and water right on it.
Well, all I can say is there
are different kinds of skin.
And besides, with
her money, she don't
have to worry about her looks.
Say, are those real pearls
she's got slung around her neck?
Mother, look
what you're doing!
What?
You're getting cold
cream all over her picture!
Oh, I didn't mean it, Lolly.
Oh, give it to me!
I'm sorry!
I'll do it.
Oh,
jingle bells, jingle bells.
Jingle all the--
Hello, Lollipops!
Merry Christmas.
Here
is your mistletoe,
now where's the kiss?
Where's the kish?
Mother!
Ed!
Stella!
Go on, run along, go inside.
No, no, no, no.
Ed Munn, what do
you mean by showing up
around here in this condition?
You get out of here!
Shh, Stella, Stella,
I got something for you.
I-- I've been robbed.
Why, if I thought that
anybody would take--
Oh.
Oh!
Here you are, my dear, and
a very Merry Christmas.
No thanks, Ed.
I can't take it.
I wouldn't know
what to do with it.
Huh?
Oh.
What to do with it.
Cook it!
No, you run along.
Give it to somebody else.
What, me give my
chicken to somebody else?
You think I'm going to do that?
I'm gonna take it, I'm gonna
stick it, I'm gonna take it
and I'm gonna put it in--
Ed Munn, you
come out of there!
Ed!
What are you trying to
do, set the place on fire?
No.
Well, you're, uh--
cookin' a turkey.
Ed!
Get that thing out of here.
I say no.
I say yes.
Now, Stella, listen, don't
tell me how to cook a turkey.
I know how to cook a turkey.
Oh, Ed, no.
Now, come on.
Stel!
Stel, no!
Now, listen.
I know how the curkey should
be tooked, and so there.
Now, of course the feet
won't be very well done,
but then I don't care
for feet much anyway.
Oh, Ed, now, be reasonable.
Merry Christmas.
Father!
Oh, I'm so glad to see you!
Oh, and am I glad to see you.
What a nice surprise.
You should see the way I've
been running to the door.
I never dreamed of
anything so wonderful
as your bringing them yourself.
Ooh, what a lovely tree!
Here you are.
Oh, thank you, Daddy.
I'll put them right here
while I go call Mother.
I'll take your coat and hat.
This
is a fine Christmas spirit,
that you don't have
anything in the house.
Ha!
Strawberry, now, there
you are, strawberry.
And lemon.
Ha!
Lemon and peach.
Ho, ho, ho!
What is this?
Ohh, this is more sarsaparilla.
Well, of all the
places I ever saw
where a man can't have any--
You go
inside and keep him company,
and I'll get dressed and
come in as fast as I can.
All right.
Hey, Stel!
What is all the
whispering over there?
You've got to go.
I've got company.
- Oh, company?
- Yes, come on.
- Having company?
Who's the company?
Never you mind, you just go.
Well, I'd like to
see the company--
No-- Ed!
Oh, Stella, now, listen.
Come on.
Oh, I'll tell you, Stella.
No, sir, I'm going to
sit right here until I
find out who the company is.
Ed, shh!
No you're not, you're gonna go.
Pushin' and shovin'!
ED
I think the company
would like the turkey, too.
It was the biggest
turkey I could find.
One of the finest
turks that the man had.
I never saw such a big
turkey in all my life.
Daddy, a
wristwatch, how lovely!
Do you
like it, darling?
Oh, yes!
You're
getting so grown up,
I hardly know what
to buy for you.
Mother copied it from one
we saw in the window of a shop
in Boston.
You can hardly tell
the difference.
It is pretty, isn't it?
It was my best
present till you came.
Oh, you darling.
Stephen?
Well!
Merry Christmas, Stella.
Merry Christmas
to you, Stephen.
It's good to see you again.
Well, it's good to see you.
Sit down.
Thank you.
Place looks
awfully nice, Stella.
You'll go to dinner with us?
Well, darling, I--
I came to ask your
mother a favor.
Stella, I was wondering if
you'd let me have Laurel
for the holidays this time.
I've never had a
place for her before.
This time we have an invitation
to spend with the Morrisons.
Oh.
Well.
Would you like to go, Lolly?
Yes.
Oh, that is, if--
Oh, I-- I think
it would be lovely.
When would you
want her, Stephen?
Well, my train leaves
in an hour, Stella.
I was hoping I could
take her back with me.
Today?
Oh, no, no.
Not today, I couldn't, Father.
Mother and I had
something all planned.
Well, yes, we did, but--
well, we-- we could
do that anytime.
All right, come on,
we'll have to hurry.
You have to have your new coat,
and you want these things.
I'll just get her started.
Excuse us.
Hurry.
There's your case there.
Will this do for the train?
Yes, that's fine.
Just pack what you
need now, and I'll
send your trunk on tonight.
All right, Mother.
She won't be very long.
This is for you, Stella.
Oh, thank you.
Stella, I'm awfully sorry.
When I see all you've done
here, and you did have plans,
I didn't realize--
Oh, it wasn't
anything, really.
We were just going to a show
and dinner at the Bontonne.
This will be a
real treat for her.
It's been so long
since I've seen you.
How have you been?
Well, thank you.
And you?
Oh, fine.
That's good.
It's too bad your
train leaves so early.
Stella, I--
I've been thinking.
I don't know why didn't
occur to me before.
But there's no earthly reason in
the world why you should spend
the day all alone
just because I've
been selfish and thoughtless.
There must be a later train.
Where's the telephone?
Shall we call and see?
Oh, yes.
Please.
Here.
Beacon Hill 3700, please.
Ooh!
Fooled you, didn't I?
You put me out the back
door and I went all the way
around and came right in here!
Say, listen, just where
is all this company that I'm
being kicked out because of?
Because I'm gonna tell you this.
You're not gonna
feed 'em my turkey.
No sir.
Not to--
Oh.
I beg your pardon.
I guess-- aw.
I'm sorry, Stella.
I didn't mean to--
I guess I'll go now.
Mr. Dallas.
He had a little too
much Christmas, I guess.
He was here a
while ago and brought a turkey,
and I had a terrible
time getting rid of him.
What did you find
out about the train?
Well, I'm afraid it
would be too late, Stella.
I'm sorry.
I'm all ready.
Was I very long?
Not at all, darling.
Goodbye, Stella.
I'll take good care of her.
Goodbye, Stephen.
Goodbye, Mother.
Goodbye, Stella.
Thank you for letting me go.
Bye.
Mrs. Dallas, Mr. Morley.
How do
you do, Mrs. Dallas?
Won't you sit down, please?
Mrs. Dallas, I wrote you a
letter, and in it I stated--
You don't have to
tell me what you stated,
just tell me what you meant.
Mrs. Dallas, it's only natural
to suppose that you should
wish to legalize your position.
Legalize my position?
Well, I've got our
marriage license.
Look here, Mr. Morley, what
are you trying to give me?
Your freedom.
A divorce.
Mr. Dallas feels, and I
can readily understand why,
that you might wish to remarry.
Remarry?
Listen, Mr. Morley, let's
get down to brass tacks.
I haven't the slightest
idea of ever remarrying.
Now, it don't happen by
any chance to be Mr. Dallas
who wishes to remarry, does it?
Well, assuming for the
moment that it does, surely
you could have no objection?
Your allowance
would be the same.
As a matter of fact, Mr. Dallas
might even be able to increase
the amount he's sending you.
I don't want any increases.
Let him keep it and let
me keep my daughter.
Mrs. Dallas, Mr. Dallas has
no intention of any change
regarding your daughter.
Oh, he hasn't?
Then what's he been trying
to win her away for?
Taking her to fine hotels,
country places, townhouses!
Making her dissatisfied
with the kind of things
I've been giving her.
Does he think I don't
see what he's after?
Well, he'll never get away
with it and I'll tell you why.
Because I'm going to
give her the same things!
Everything her
heart's been set on.
Fine hotels, fancy friends,
she's going to have 'em all.
And I'm gonna give 'em to her
and he's gonna pay for 'em.
If he's got any extra increases,
he can just hand 'em over.
And if he don't, maybe
I'll get a lawyer
and bring in the name of
that highfalutin' widow!
But Mrs. Dallas--
I won't keep you any
longer, Mr. Morley,
thank you very much.
Just see the check is
mailed to the same place.
That all the benefits I want.
No.
Mm-mm.
This one'll do.
Look, put some more lace on it.
Nice one!
You're wonderful, Laurel!
Dick, you threw
me that last game.
Threw it?
The last one came
over like a bullet.
Is that any way to
treat your teacher?
That's the way to
take him over, Laurel!
What's the matter, Dick,
you losing your edge?
Laurel, this is Mrs. Clews.
I'm glad to know you.
How do you do, my dear?
You're improving rapidly.
My teacher.
Say, Laurel.
We're going to have Dad's
box for the polo game.
Won't you come with us?
Oh, I'd love to!
But I should spend the
afternoon with my mother.
See you dinner, then.
Fine.
Bye-bye.
How is your
mother today, dear?
Oh, she's much
better, thank you.
Couldn't Mrs. Clews and I
visit with her this afternoon
while you go to the polo?
Oh, yes.
That's an idea, mother.
You know, I've been looking
forward to meeting her.
It's unfortunate that
she's been ill all the time.
What do you say, Laurel?
I'll have to ask Mother.
Come on.
All right.
I'll call you.
Mother!
Hello, darling.
Did you have a good time?
Oh, heavenly.
Mother, Richard's mother
and a Mrs. Clews I just met
want to go to the polo game.
And they want to spend
the afternoon with you.
Oh, and see me for the
first time in my nightgown?
Huh!
I should say not.
Me with a trunk
full of new clothes
my skin is just
itching to get next to.
Goodness gracious.
Oh, but you go along
and say I was asleep.
Oh, no, I won't
leave you alone again.
Oh, don't be silly.
There's no sense of the two
of us being cooped up here.
I'll be all right in a few days,
and then I'll get all fixed up
and meet your friends right.
You know what I was thinking?
The first night I'm able to
go down in the dining room,
we'll have this Richard and
his mother to dinner with us.
Would you like that?
Lolly?
Oh!
I knew you would.
Oh, now run along.
You mustn't keep him waiting.
Wear your blue jacket.
I love you in that.
All right.
Boy!
Oh, boy.
Listen, will you tell me which
lady is Mrs. Richard Grosvenor?
Mrs. Grosvenor's
not here, ma'am.
Oh, then please direct
me to the tennis court.
Maybe she's there.
You go just across the
lawn and down that path.
You mean sort of over
that way and down there?
Yes, ma'am.
Oh.
Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Here you are, young fellow.
Oh, that's all right.
Oh!
Don't be sill'.
Thank you.
Here goes a birdie.
Did I say birdie?
Well, whew!
Trying to cover it up, huh?
No, I'll wear it everywhere.
Did you see
the makeup on her?
And those shoes!
Why, I thought
she was wearing stilts!
Hello, there.
Hi, Dick, how are you?
Come on, move on.
Move down one seat.
Say, whatever
happened to you two?
We've been back hours.
Oh, we took a shortcut.
Yeah.
Say, Paul, you
sure missed the show.
What'll it be, Mr. Grosvenor?
What show?
Oh, that woman
on the tennis court.
Well, I'll have a
chocolate ice cream
soda with chocolate ice cream
and lots of whipped cream
on top.
What about her?
Make mine the same, only
make it with vanilla ice cream
and leave off the goo.
OK.
I didn't know they
let that kind of woman loose
anymore.
- Happy?
You should
have seen the getup.
What a woman!
Say, maybe
Dick knows her.
Dick, she was looking
for your mother.
Yeah?
Weren't she a panic when
Pete lobbed one over the fence
and she started
chasing after it?
I never saw
her before, did you?
Who is she?
- I don't know.
I'd sure like to know where
she got that paint job.
Just
needs a new coat.
Shh!
That's not a woman,
it's a Christmas tree.
And it walks!
Does it talk?
And how!
Good?
Mm, delicious.
That's the one there.
I heard her say to
Jimmy, "you ought to see
my little girl play tennis."
She must have
some little girl.
No, I don't like it.
Well, it is rather heavy.
Oh, let me see that one.
- This one?
- Yeah.
She's an ad!
An ad for what?
We'll see in a minute.
Wait'll her hat lights up.
You're all wrong.
It's a trailer.
Do you think that one
really suits my personality?
Yes, ma'am.
Decidedly.
You do?
I'll take that.
Send it up to Room 214.
214.
Mm-hm.
Thank you.
Personality.
Hey, Pete.
Get her.
What's the matter?
I-- I must have lost my watch!
Wait a minute,
Laurel, you can't
go all the way back there now.
When did you see it
last, do you remember?
I-- I want to go,
please let me go!
Don't worry about it.
Let's finish our sodas first.
We'll find it.
There you are!
I've been looking
all over for you, I--
well, Lolly, what on earth--
Mother, we're going home.
Home?
What are you talking--
well, what's the matter?
What's happened?
Nothing.
Oh, I know.
My little Lolly's had a
quarrel with her young man.
Mother, please!
Oh, Lolly, don't
be a little goose.
I tell you what you do.
I'll call him up and
invite him to dinner,
make believe I don't
know anything about it.
I'll pretend you're not back
yet What's their number?
Mother!
I want to go home.
You want to go home?
Well- well, what about me?
Paying for two rooms all this
time and using only a bed.
Don't you think
I'd like a little
of the fun you've been having?
I should think you'd think of
somebody else besides yourself.
You know, I like nice people
and a little fun myself.
I'm sorry.
I don't see how your
pride would let you
show him you cared that much.
If it was me, I'd stay on
just to show him that there's
other fish in the sea.
Oh, Lolly.
It's only for you.
Well, you said yourself
this morning you'd never
been so happy in all your life.
And so was I, too.
Oh, dear.
Here.
Here you are, miss.
Thank you.
All aboard!
She said that as
sure as she lives--
Well, she's got my bag.
Oh, there she is.
Lynn!
Oh good heavens.
Did you have a blowout?
No, but just as I was
leaving, I met Ethel.
Oh, I can't get my breath.
Here, sit down.
But I want to tell you
what Ethel told me.
Do you remember that
funny-looking woman
parading around the
grounds this afternoon?
No, I didn't see her.
But Joan was--
I bet you didn't see her.
She can't be described.
You wouldn't believe it.
I'll tell you, she was quite
a number, dresses up to here,
and paint an inch thick,
and bells on her shoes
that tinkled all the time.
Oh, not bells.
And bracelets up
to here, that clanked.
You never saw such a sight.
Anyway, do you know who she was?
Who?
Laurel Dallas' mother.
Laurel Dallas?
No!
Boy, I can't believe it.
You mean that
pretty little girl
Dick Grosvenor's been rushing?
Yes.
Didn't you know that?
But are you sure?
She seems so lovely and sweet.
I know it.
Isn't it weird?
To have such a common-looking
creature for a mother.
Poor thing.
Poor nothing.
She's wearing Dick
Grosvenor's fraternity pin.
She won't be
wearing it long, I bet.
Not when Mrs.
Grosvenor hears about it.
Your bags
is ready, ladies.
Oh, all right.
Thank you.
I want to tell you about it--
Lollie?
It's lonely up there, mother.
I want to come down here
and cuddle with you.
I'd-- I--
I'd like to see Mrs. Morrison.
Was it in reference to--
I-- I couldn't say.
It's private.
And I-- I have to
see Mrs. Morrison.
What was the name, please?
Mrs. Dallas, Mrs.
Stephen Dallas.
Yes.
I will see if Mrs.
Morrison is at home.
Come with me, please.
Just wait in there, please.
Yeah.
Mrs. Dallas?
Are--
are you Mrs. Morrison?
Yes.
Oh, I, um--
I'm-- I'm sorry to bother
you in your home, but I--
Won't you sit down?
No.
What I have to say
won't take very long.
It's just that I--
Oh, well, we may as
well be comfortable.
It's so very warm.
Won't you take off your coat?
I-- I know you must
think it's funny,
me coming here like this.
I'm not going to beat around the
bush, but what I want to know
is, if--
if Stephen was free, if I got a
divorce like his lawyer wanted,
would--
would you two get married?
Yes, we would.
I'm sorry if it's unpleasant.
But I'd rather that
you knew the truth.
Yeah.
Um, well, what I wanted to
know is if you and Stephen did
get married, um--
well, what about Laurel?
Would you take her too?
Oh no, Mrs. Dallas.
I'm a mother.
Do you think I could ever
deprive another mother
of her only little girl?
Yeah, but if the
mother didn't want her--
I mean, if she couldn't
very well have her, well,
if it was inconvenient?
Inconvenient?
Yeah.
You see, Lollie's
growing up now.
And she-- well, she's
quite a responsibility.
Well, I don't understand.
Well, you see, it's this way.
From now on, there's
lots of things
Lollie ought to begin having.
Oh, I don't mean money.
But dances and parties,
you know, good times.
And really, I--
I've never been much
at that sort of thing.
So I-- I feel that I've done
about all I can for her.
So I-- I thought that you being
so crazy about her father,
and she taking after him
so much, that well, if uh--
you and Stephen got
married, why, Lollie could
come and live with you and--
your name being Mrs.
Dallas, you see,
well, everybody would naturally
think she was your little girl.
And then when you went
places, you see, well--
you see, you're the kind
of a mother that any girl
would be proud of.
I didn't know anyone
could be so unselfish.
And I'll say one
thing, Mrs. Morrison,
you'd never be ashamed
of Lollie either.
Oh.
Everybody's just
crazy about her.
She-- well, she makes
a wonderful impression.
She's so refined and
elegant in her ways.
But oh, you already know that.
Anyway, she's--
well, anyway, she's--
well, she's crazy
about you already.
She don't talk as
much as she used to.
But that's because she thinks
I'm jealous or something.
And oh, I guess I was a little.
But I'm not anymore.
And you'll see.
In a little while, she'll--
well, in a little while she'll--
she'll forget all about me.
And it-- why, it won't
be any time before
she'll she'll love you just--
just you were her real mother.
And oh, Mrs. Morrison,
she's so wonderful.
You don't know.
I do know.
And I know that it hasn't
come only from her father.
I have to go.
Lollie doesn't know
I've come here and I--
I don't want her to yet.
She-- she's awfully
funny underneath
and I've thought it all out.
It'll be better to just let her
come for the visit like always.
And-- and by that time
it'll all be over.
The-- divorce, I mean.
And-- and you can
break it to her.
It'll be easier that way.
Aboard!
Goodbye, darling.
- Goodbye.
- Go on.
Get inside.
Goodbye, mother.
Goodbye, dear.
Goodbye.
You'll write to me, won't you?
Oh, yes I will!
Now, have a nice time
and don't think about me!
Wear your new blue
dress tonight!
I want to see you
in my mind's eye.
All right!
Bye!
I love you!
Goodbye!
Goodbye, mother!
It's a lot of fun, isn't it?
Yes.
Haven't you really
ever played it before?
No, honestly, I haven't.
John wouldn't go to bed until
I promised to bring these in,
so you'd still have some
members of the family
to keep you company tonight.
Oh, how sweet.
Oh, that John.
And here's their breakfast.
Gosh, you sure
stand high with John.
Why, he won't let Lee and me
see him, let alone, feed him.
Well, I suppose it's
time young gentleman
removed themselves from
ladies boudoirs, eh, Con?
OK, dad.
Goodnight, sweetheart.
Goodnight, father.
Goodnight, darling,
and sleep well.
Goodnight dear, I will.
Thank you.
- Goodnight, Laurel.
I'll see you in the morning.
Right, Con.
Uh-huh.
Goodnight, mother.
I'll put these
in a safe place.
Oh, I never saw
father so happy before.
And you, dear, are you happy?
So very, for you both.
But I've been worrying and
worrying about something.
Why, what could
possibly be worrying you?
Well, I don't know
what to call you.
Oh, if that's all,
oh, I'm so glad.
Because I have something
to tell you which I hope
will make you just as
happy as it has me.
From now on, you're going to
be one of us reality, dear.
You're going to be a
member of this family
like Con and Lee and John.
They're your brothers.
And this is going to be your
home as much as it is theirs.
This, my home?
Yes, dear.
You're going to live with us.
Live here?
Here, the townhouse,
wherever we are.
Does it make you happy, Laurel?
Oh yes, it makes
me very happy.
To know-- to know that
you want me, and I--
I do love you all so very much.
But-- but I couldn't
leave my mother.
Oh, you won't be leaving her.
Your mother will
always be your mother.
I could never expect
or even want to take
her place in your heart.
You will visit her
whenever you like.
No, no, I couldn't.
Oh thank you ever and
ever so much, Mrs--
Laurel, your mother, your
father, all of us who love you,
feel it now that
you're getting older,
there are-- there
are many advantages
that we can give you.
I know.
I-- I know.
And I do thank you.
But I-- I'm sorry.
Goodnight, Con.
Goodnight, dad.
Father?
Yes, dear?
What is it, dear?
Father, you-- you don't mean
you thought that I could live
anywhere ever without mother?
Well, you've lived without me.
Your mother and I
are just changing
places for a while, that's all.
Isn't it fair for me to
have a little of what
she's had all these years?
But that's different, father.
You know it is.
I've been with mother all these
years because I needed her.
Now she needs me and-- and
you need me less than ever.
Oh, Laurel, don't say that.
I'm sorry, Laurel, if
you don't see that what
we've planned is for your good.
We thought it would
make you happy.
Your mother and I
have decided upon what
we think is best for you.
My mother, does she know?
Certainly.
We have your interests
equally at heart, haven't we?
We both feel that this
should be your home
for at least a few years.
I'm sorry, father.
But please understand, my
home will be with my mother
as long as I live.
Now, Laurel--
Oh, Stephen.
Laurel, you don't
understand, dear.
This was all your mother's
idea, her wish for you.
She planned it all herself.
Your father had
nothing to do with it.
She came to see me and
we talked it all over.
My mother came to see you?
Yes, dear we felt--
When did she come?
Well, I don't know--
Was it just after we
got back from the Mirador?
Well, I believe it was.
But--
Oh, oh my poor mother.
My wonderful mother.
Oh, she wasn't asleep.
She wasn't.
She heard what they said.
Oh, I must go to her!
I must go to her at once!
Darling, tell us about it.
Now, now, sweetie--
Oh, oh, please daddy, help me.
I can't make my visit here.
I must go to my mother.
Don't, sweetheart.
Sure, you can see him.
That ain't meanin'
that he can see you.
Hey, Munn!
Somebody to see ya!
Ed?
Ed, wake up.
It's Stella.
Ed, it's me, Stella Dallas.
Hello, Stell.
Look, I still live
in the same old flat.
Oh yeah?
And I want you to take this,
get a Turkish bath and a shave
and come right over.
Do you understand?
Ed, do you understand?
Sure.
I got it.
Mother?
Mommy!
Mother.
Oh, mother.
Oh, Lollie, when
did you-- well,
whatever brought you back?
Mother, how could you think?
As if I could ever live
anywhere else but with you?
Oh, well, I thought
you'd like it for a while.
No, really.
You-- you always
seemed to have such
a good time with your father.
Yes, but-- but
good times, oh, they
aren't what make you belong.
It's-- it's the
other kind of times.
It's when you've
cried together and--
and when you've been
through things together.
Oh, that's when you
seem to love the most.
It-- it's different when you--
didn't they send the telegram?
they said they would.
Oh, most likely they tried
to deliver it and I was out.
I've been on the go
ever since you went.
Put those in water
for me, will you?
Oh, they're lovely.
Yeah, from an old admirer.
Ed Munn blew into town
and I've been stepping
out with him for a change.
Ed Munn?
Yeah.
Now, put 'em in water.
I want 'em all fixed
nice when he gets here.
Mother, you don't
mean that you and--
Lollie, haven't
you fixed them yet?
Give them to me.
Get some water.
That'll tickle him.
Lollie!
Mother, don't you remember a
long time ago, when he said--
and-- and you promised
about him that--
Oh, Lollie, I know
what you're driving at.
Now, let me tell you something.
I-- I've spent the best
years of my life on you.
A woman wants to be something
else besides a mother,
you know.
Well, you will know
when you get grown up.
You can't explain
everything to a child.
Now, go on.
Run along.
I'll come back
to stay if you still want me.
Still want you?
Laurel, my dear.
Don't.
Oh.
Father!
Tell me, dear,
what is it, angel?
What is it, darling?
Oh, daddy!
What is it, dear?
What is it, sweetheart?
I-- I thought it
was my sake she wanted
me to come and live with you.
And I was so glad and so proud.
But it wasn't.
It was for him.
She wanted to marry him!
Please don't cry, darling.
You knew him!
You knew?
Yes, I--
And she chose him!
Come, Laurel, come
upstairs with me, dear.
All right.
So long!
Thanks a lot!
Well, hello.
You back?
Gee, that's great.
Hello, Con.
Say, who do you
think brought me home?
Dick Grosvenor.
We were just talking about you.
Say, you wait here.
I'll go get him.
He's still in the driveway.
Oh, no, Con!
No, no!
Oh, i don't want to see him.
- It's fine.
Not now.
No, darling.
Oh, no, no, not yet.
You go on upstairs, dear.
We'll take of Dick.
Hey, Dick!
What?
Come on back!
Laurel's here!
- When did she get back?
- I don't know.
She was here when I got here.
How do
you do, Mrs. Dallas?
Good, how do you do?
- How do you do, Mr. Dallas.
I'm glad to see you again.
Oh, glad to see you, Dick.
Con
told me Laurel was here.
All right, fella'.
That's one on me.
No, she's here.
Hey mother, Laurel's
here, isn't she?
Yes, she's here.
Won't you stay for dinner?
Why, if I'm allowed as I am.
Of course.
If you don't mind, I'd
like to wash up too, please.
Sure.
Boy, come on up to my room, huh?
- Thank you, Con.
- Now, hurry up, will ya?
OK, dad.
Stephen.
Laurel is here.
She's here to stay.
Who's accomplished it?
Couldn't you read between
those pitiful lines?
Rugs.
I told you, those curtains
weren't to be drawn.
Open them, please.
Yes, madam.
Yes.
Now you must light the
candles, and we must hurry.
Yes, madam.
Come dear, it's
nearly time for our cue.
What's this?
Oh, my darling.
I was just thinking, I never
really thought that my mother--
I thought that she would
read about the wedding.
And even though she was
too far away to come,
at least she would write to me.
Oh my dear, do you
think if she knew,
any distance in the world
could keep her away?
Then you think she
just doesn't know?
Sorry, bu you
can't stand here.
We have to keep this clear.
Move along, please.
Break up the group here.
You too, lady.
Oh, please, let me see
her face when he kisses her,
please.
All right, well,
you've seen enough.
Come along.
Move along please, now.
Come on, clear the sidewalk.