[Pietro in a low voice] Shh, slowly.
[Pietro in a low voice] Come here.
- [Totò] Uncle!
- Shut up.
[Nino] Totò.
[in Sicilian] Here it is, take it.
Here she is.
Bitch of misery! She ran away.
- Uncle...
- You have to shut up, you mute!
- [Pietro] Did you hear it?
- [Nino] Yes.
Piano.
[Peter] She hid.
It's there, uncle! I saw her.
- [Totò] Uncle...
- Shut up!
Get up.
Here she is.
[in Sicilian] You got it, uncle!
[in Sicilian] You got it!
What do you guys say, huh? Let's go.
Or.
Totò, do you have balls or are you a girl?
Go get the hare.
- No, I'm scared.
-She's dead, go!
- Do not be afraid.
- It makes sense to me.
You are useless!
Next time you get it, though.
Look what's here! Ah!
- Let's go, come on.
- Go.
[Pietro] Watch out for the thorns, Totò.
[Nino laughing] Run away!
Nino!
[eco]
Uncle, there's an echo!
- Nino!
- [eco]
[Emanuele in Sicilian] Really?
They don't even let us touch the ball.
- [reporter] Out of the game.
- [Emanuele] How poor!
[reporter] He came on with a quarter of an hour
to go instead of Ivan.
[rock music from tape recorder]
Oh!
[indistinct voices]
[in Sicilian] Cousin Palermo,
turn off the radio.
- Meow!
- Get out!
[man] And go away!
- [reporter] Conti, Rossi on the right.
- [Emanuele] Go, shoot!
Pull! But fuck you!
- [Sucabenzine] Giannuzzo.
- Appears.
- [Emanuele] Giannuzzo.
- [in an effeminate voice] Giannuzzo.
[Emanuele] Have you become deaf?
- [Emanuele] Giannuzzo?
[Emanuele] Come and have
a coffee with friends.
Dai!
[reporter] Rossi, short.
He recovered Matysik.
[Emanuele] Oh! I'm talking to you.
Come here!
[Sucabenzina in Sicilian] Can't you hear
him talking to you?
[chronicler] La partita finisce zero a zero.
Can't you hear him talking to you?
Come on, we'll offer you coffee.
Come, don't be afraid.
Do you no longer greet friends?
Do you have to go home to mommy?
He has to go home to his mommy!
[Emanuele] Come on, I'll buy you a coffee.
Giannuzzo!
It's a one minute thing.
Come on, that's how it's done, Giannuzzo.
Come and have coffee with friends.
[reporter] Closing
this scoreless...
- Enter.
- [Giuseppina] What are you looking for?
- [Giuseppina] Enough!
- [Emanuele] Oh, walk!
Sergio, a coffee for our friend.
Don't you even say thank you?
[laughs]
- Do you like it, do not you?
- [laughs]
Say you like it, don't be afraid.
Or maybe you don't like it?
[man] Fuck!
Yes you like.
Everyone knows what you like,
everyone knows what you want.
Oh, there it is!
So beautiful.
- That looks nice.
- Come on, will you come and dance with me tonight?
[Emanuele] How beautiful!
Beautiful, beautiful Giannuzza!
[laughs]
[Sucabenzine] How beautiful you are!
[Emanuele] You are beautiful, yes.
[man] You're driving me crazy!
[Sucabenzine] Yes, you're tasty. Come here!
- [Emanuele] Here it is.
- [laughs]
- [Sucabenzine] Beautiful!
- [Emanuele] Stop, where are you going?
[Turns] Oh!
At that time? As?
[in Sicilian] Leave this boy alone , come on!
If you tell me, I have to obey.
[in Sicilian] Come on, let's go.
Give me the rifle.
[Totò] Grandpa!
[horn]
- Hello grandfather!
- Totò, be careful.
- Come on!
- HI.
[Nino] Hello, dad.
- Alfredo.
- Peter.
- [Alfredo in Sicilian] How's it going?
- Everything is fine.
- [Pietro] How did it go for you?
- Well.
Did they cause you any problems?
Let's hope for the fires in Santa Venerina.
- Sure, everything's fine.
- What does the councilor say?
- Did you tell him that you are my brother?
- There was not.
- I'll call him in case. Let's go?
- I knew it.
- I should have talked to him.
- There's no need, I'll handle it.
You always get your feet wet.
Peter, stop. There are the boys.
You take it,
my wife doesn't know how to cook anyway.
- Thanks, see you.
- HI.
[Alfredo] Totò, what are you doing?
- Come here!
- Ninuzzo, come.
This was your grandfather's.
Second.
You were promoted and you deserved it.
- Good boy.
- Thank you.
- [Pietro] Hello.
- [Nino] Hi.
- [Nino] Did you see, dad?
- Yes.
Aren't they going to shoot us in Santa Venerina tonight ?
What do you say? They're bullshit!
Now I'll sort everything out.
Here is a list of things
we need to buy for tonight.
- "Twine, lead rope, rubber bands..."
- Can you tell me what I should buy?
I've been shooting fires
since I was younger than you.
Alright, I'll leave it here for you.
Totò, how is he?
[voices in the distance]
Gianni, oh!
I am sorry.
I'm sorry they don't give you peace,
but what can I do?
- [in Sicilian] Those are like that.
- Do you realize what you're saying?
[in Sicilian] Well done, shut up,
when you talk you only cause damage.
I didn't want to say it.
They insisted and then...
It's your fault.
- My?
- Yes.
Because you never worried
about what they could do to you.
You told him what
made you happy!
Get out!
[groans]
[the door slams]
[Lina] Gianni is here, wait.
[Lina] Wait.
Stop it?
[in Sicilian] You can't fuck in peace even at home !
[Franco] Tell him not to drink
from the bottle as usual!
'This is nothing.
Shall we add some lemon?
[voices in the distance]
What's up?
Eh?
They don't give you peace, do they?
- What's new?
- We'd like to know.
- To do what?
- We both have the right to it.
He doesn't give a damn.
He just wants people not to gossip.
- Don't disrespect him.
- Respect. Should I kiss his hands?
- Huh? Should I kiss his hands too?
- Shut up.
It's your fault,
because you wanted to take him home.
If it were up to me,
he could have stayed in reform school.
But since I love his mother
and I had no alternative,
I make it work in my workshop,
even if it's of no use to me.
But now things have to change. Oh!
Oh, look, I'm talking to you!
That's my workshop, not a circus
where people pass by, watch and laugh.
Did you understand?
What do you do? You do not talk?
What am I saying?
Does it seem easy to you growing up here
without a father?
So why doesn't he kill himself?
[horn]
Hello Uncle.
- [Ciccio] Hello.
- Grandmother!
Uncle Pietro caught a rabbit.
[in Sicilian] A rabbit?
Good! I cook it well.
Look, the saint who doesn't sweat.
- You don't know how much I sweated last night.
- Ciccio, shut up, there's the baby.
[in Sicilian] Do we have to teach
these kids a little about life, or not?
- [Alfredo] Yes.
- [Ciccio] Nino, come here!
[Nino] What is it, uncle?
Do you know what I did last night?
What have you done?
- I won't tell you.
- Come on!
What are you doing?
- Pasta with sauce.
- Good.
Yesterday I didn't bet on just any female,
I chose the most beautiful one in the place.
Do you know what I said?
"Do you know that one eye is
more beautiful than the other?"
- What did you answer?
-[Alfredo] “Fuck you,” she told him.
What does your father know?
You'll ruin your appetite!
Ugh!
- Put out the cigarette.
- [Isabella in Sicilian] Leave me alone.
- Oh, look.
- The rabbit? Put it there.
- Let's have lunch?
- [Carmela] Nino, come here!
Hello Mom.
Look what Uncle Pietro gave me.
Take bread, salt and oil.
- Isabella!
- Hey!
[Carmela] Come here!
[Carmela] Totò, stop!
[Carmela] Isabella, cut the bread.
I'll get some bread.
[in Sicilian] Are you stupid?
Salt is disgrace!
The misfortune is you.
- [Ciccio] What's happening?
- Ouch!
Is this how you respond to your mother?
Come on, clean everything up!
What are you laughing at, Nino? Give us a hand.
What have you done?
- Totò, come here.
- What's up?
You and I need to get together.
Truly? What does it mean?
That we will always be together.
- Really?
- Certain.
[Ciccio] So? I'm hungry.
[Alfredo] Eat, eat.
When will you give the scooter to Uncle Nino?
Did you actually buy it?
It was supposed to be a surprise, Totò!
- She said to say it.
- What do you say?
- He tells what he feels.
-Where is he? I go walking.
- Stay here, let's finish eating.
- [Carmela] Eat first.
I knew it.
Come on, he's right!
He is curious and so am I. Let's go!
This son is always right.
At that time? Do you like it?
It's for the end of school.
- You deserved it.
- Thanks Mom.
- Do you like it? Is it how you wanted it?
- It's beautiful.
What are you waiting for? Try it!
I go.
- Slow down!
- Yes.
You could have bought it new,
this one looks like it was in the war.
- Oh, let's go and see the scooter?
- Go.
[Totò] Uncle!
- It's beautiful! Can you show me around?
- Wait, Totò. Let me try it.
- C'mon, please!
- Nino, bring your nephew!
- Grandma, will you tell her?
- Totò, wait.
- A moment.
- Come on!
Get up, Totò!
Don't be late,
we have to leave at 6pm!
- [Totò] You promised me.
- One second, Totò.
- Come on, uncle, please!
- A moment!
What's up?
[plays "Luntanu"
by Giovanni Caccamo and Leonardo Milani]
I don't know, give me 50,000 lire.
Consider that we are already there, Mr. Sciacca.
All right.
Best wishes to your son. Until we meet again.
Sciacca's son's scooter.
They can't come and get him.
Bring it to him.
But that's far away!
How do I get back?
You take a nice walk.
In the evening the air is fresh.
I'm going home, you close here.
Yes.
Gianni!
- As?
- HI.
Have you finished working?
No, I have to deliver the scooter.
- Where?
- Distant.
- I'll take you.
- No, it's not necessary.
Why?
Then we'll stop for a beer, eh?
Like old times.
No, I don't like it.
Don't like it today?
- What do you have?
- Nothing.
Leave them alone, they're stupid.
You do not have to worry.
I'll think of you.
Leave me alone, I have to go.
Why?
- You're beautiful, you know?
- Please.
- Come here.
- No, Turi.
- Relax.
- Let me go.
- Come here.
- Turi.
- No, Turi, leave me alone.
- Come here!
Ahi!
Son of a bitch!
Now I'll kill you, I swear I'll kill you!
Emanuele!
Emmanuel! Come on, come with me.
- What's up?
- Come on, get in!
[rock music from tape recorder]
Oh!
- Leave me alone!
- Come here.
Cow!
Oh!
- Let me go, please!
- But what? Oh!
Cow!
Racing.
[Gianni] Leave me alone!
- [Gianni] Oh!
- [Emanuele] We won't do anything to you.
Come on, brake!
- Oh!
- Brake!
Let's go.
Oh!
Damn, I'm sorry.
It's my fault, I didn't see you.
Breathe!
Breathe! Come on, breathe!
- [coughs]
- How are you? Oh!
Senti.
For everything I am Nino Scalia.
I live in the Triona district,
my father is called Alfredo Scalia.
Let's shoot off fireworks,
everyone knows us.
Second.
Goes better?
Everything is fine?
[engine roar]
Sorry, dad, you're right.
- Where have you been?
- I had an accident.
- With the scooter?
- What did you do to yourself?
- Nothing.
- Nothing was done.
Hurry up, they're not giving us the money.
Or.
- Mr. Sciacca!
- [Luca] I'm coming!
[Luca] Here I am.
- HI. How is it going?
- Everything OK.
- Is the engine ok? Is there petrol?
- Yes.
- Where do I put it?
- Leave it here, it's a surprise.
Thank your boss and tell him
that men like him can't be found anymore.
- [wife] Luca, the cake is ready.
- I come.
- HI.
- [Luca] ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
[in chorus] ♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Many happy wishes ♪
♪ Tanti auguri a te ♪
[applause]
[Alfredo coughs]
- Bring me the fuse.
- [Nino] Yes.
Oh!
- Ready?
- Yes.
- Go.
- [coughs]
- Come on, the first round is over.
- Check the second one.
- Again, huh?
- Yes.
Still.
[Alfredo] Come here.
- [coughs]
- What's wrong, dad?
Nothing.
Don't worry, fix everything.
- Nice sweat.
- [coughs]
Continue.
- [Alfredo] You do it.
- [Nino] Yes, but are you okay?
Dad!
Light on!
Where did I put it? Nino, turn on!
- [gasping]
- Dad!
[crack of fireworks]
- Where's the spray?
- In the jacket, look for it.
Here, dad. Breathe, slowly.
Breathe.
Goes better?
[laughs]
- [woman 1] Does the Abbot have to come?
- [woman 2] Abbot? To me?
- [woman 1] Beautiful, I'll tell you.
-[woman 2] You have to see how she responds.
Your love isn't coming tonight anyway.
If Italy wins,
I'll show you how to celebrate.
- Dude, do you want to have fun?
- [woman 1] Leave it alone.
- What did you put in your pocket?
- Why? What's up?
[a prostitute sings a dirge]
Do you want to make me die?
I want to make you die?
- What have you done?
- He wants you to die.
You left the workshop open.
He had to get out.
Tomorrow you apologize to him,
otherwise he'll kill you.
Who were you with?
Go further, go.
[Lina sings a girl]
[bell tolls]
Dad, don't smoke.
If mom sees you, it ends badly.
Don't start too
, these are already making me dizzy.
They don't even answer me!
[coughs]
How are you?
Bene.
- I am fine. How should I feel?
- No, because I got scared last night.
Nothing happened.
And since nothing happened,
no one has to know anything.
Did you understand?
- Yes.
- Go to work.
[music from the radio]
Who is this?
Who are you looking for?
[Gianni] I was looking for Mr. Scalia.
- What do you want?
- I wanted to talk to him about work.
Wait here.
- Dad, there's someone looking for you.
- Nino, you go, please.
Finally! I've been calling you since this morning.
- HI.
- Have you had problems with the scooter?
- No.
- It was my fault, I didn't see you.
- Don't worry.
- I wanted to apologize, but you ran away.
- You're the one in the accident!
[Gianni] Yes.
- We are good people. If necessary, we pay.
- Come on!
No, I don't want money,
the scooter is fine.
I had to deliver it to a customer
by the principal.
- I work in a workshop.
- Did he make you walk back?
Eh, in fact I don't want to go back there again.
Looking for a job?
- Ah, well, hello!
- Yes.
Is that why you wore the good shirt?
What is your name?
Gianni, nice to meet you.
Anyway, I like this shirt. You come.
- I can?
- Yes.
All right. Yes, let's see how it ends.
Until we meet again.
Dad, he's the boy from the accident.
- He asks if we have a job for him.
- Good morning.
Salve.
My son told me everything.
He knows he made a mistake.
- No, but...
- What?
- Apologize to him now.
- Come on...
- Before me.
- Excuse me.
Good, like that.
- Grandpa, I'm hungry. Let's go to eat.
- You're right, Totò.
I don't know about you,
but when I'm fasting and with my balls turned around,
I can't even talk about females,
let alone work.
Let's go come on.
- [Alfredo] His mother is beautiful.
- What are you doing with this thing?
- I have to do something afterwards.
-[Alfredo] I liked her straight away.
- It's ready? I am hungry.
- Yes.
I made the decision
one evening at his house.
[Alfredo] We were still engaged.
His parents, his mother,
they invited me to eat
her homemade pizza.
- As soon as I saw her...
- Stop it!
Carmela!
She's turned all red, look at her!
Carmela, you were beautiful, refined, elegant.
- Seriously.
- We have a guest for lunch.
I know. It's ready.
Let's go. The cigarette!
- Which is?
- Shh!
- [Alfredo] Let's go. Eat, come on!
- Straight on, Totò.
Rabbit is eaten with your hands.
Gianni, what does your father do?
My father left.
A few years ago he went to Germany.
- Eats.
- Work there.
I haven't seen him in a long time.
He works well.
He does whatever comes his way.
I would like to be like him.
[Alfredo] Have you heard
how he talks about his father?
This is how we talk about a father.
You have understood?
Well done, Gianni.
You're a good boy, especially
what you say about your father.
Listen.
You must always go with your head held high.
You have to be proud of who you are
and the family you have.
- Now that we're eating...
- [Carmela] The salad!
Let's talk about work.
Obviously you're a good boy,
but I can't give you work.
- I can't afford an employee.
- Who wants salad with onion?
Carmela,
we are discussing important things
and you come out with the onion? I do not know!
I was thinking of asking my brother tomorrow
if he has a job as a laborer at the quarry.
- What do you say?
- Okay, yes.
- Have you ever broken stones?
- No, but I can learn.
If they give you fifth grade,
go and work at the quarry too.
- I do not want.
- Do you want to be a scientist?
- No, the footballer.
- Now let's think about the exam, then we'll see.
Have you studied poetry?
Can you really help me?
- Certain.
- I thought you were only helping him now.
- [Totò] What's your name?
- Gianni.
This one has been standing still for a lifetime.
It's definitely the candle, don't worry.
- Hand me a rag and some sandpaper.
- Yes.
- Isabella?
-What is it?
Help me close the bottles.
- [Nino] Are you seeing the match tomorrow?
- [Gianni] Which match?
- Like which match?
- Ah, the Italy match..
Yes.
[Isabella] Do you want to make pasta
with tomato sauce for breakfast too?
Because your mom put
the spoon in her mouth.
It's a trick to keep from crying
while chopping the onion.
I knew it.
Try now.
[engine starts]
Of course you know how to clean a candle,
that's your job.
It was my job.
However I don't have the money.
- I'll take you home, so we're even.
- No, I'll take the bus. There's no need.
- Come on, it won't be half an hour until you get home.
- There's no need.
Dai!
- [Ciccio] Is there food for us too?
- [Isabella] Good morning, huh?
Thanks anyway,
it was a wonderful lunch.
I had too good a time with you.
You have a beautiful family.
Say hello to your father,
I don't want to disturb him.
- Hi Gianni! Come back whenever you want.
- All right.
- Until we meet again.
- [Ciccio] Totò! Buy me cigarettes!
- HI.
[Carmela] But do you know what time it is?
- [together] First.
- [together] Eh!
[man] Go!
Oh!
[together] Eh!
[together] Three, four, five, six, seven
eight nine...
[yell out]
[inaudible voices]
Look who's here!
- Enzo, come here!
- [together] Enzo!
[together] Come here!
[together] Enzo, come here!
Enzo, show the kids
how you lift the car.
Alone.
[Emanuele] What's up.
[man] A thousand lire who can do it.
That's it, 100 lire.
what's up
[together] Enzo! Enzo!
[together] Two, three,
four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, ten.
[shouts of exultation]
Oh, you broke my ass.
The car is mine.
- Crazy things!
- [indistinct voices]
[Emanuele] Shh, look who's here.
What is this bitch?
- Just like Miss Italy!
- [laughs]
[Gianni] Sergio, a coffee.
[Turi] Did you see?
Today he wants to get hurt.
What do you want to do?
Eh?
Tell me what do you want to do?
Why are you provoking them like this?
Do you want to understand that those ruin you?
Did you want a coffee?
Bring him a coffee too,
since he's very busy!
- [Turi] Franco!
- [Sucabenzina] Yes, it sticks a lot.
- [laughter]
- [Emanuele] Franco sticks it.
[laughs]
Franco!
[Turi] Shut up and go away, it's better.
[Sucagasoline] Go home!
Mamma.
You are completely crazy!
You are crazy!
- Everything's fine.
- What?
- He's kicking us out of the house.
- Let me talk.
Do you remember how you and I were?
Now you apologize to him
because money is sacred and...
I got a job, mom.
I'm taking you away from here,
we're going somewhere else.
- What do you say?
- Let's get another house, I'll pay for everything.
We don't need him! Did you understand?
- We don't need anyone.
- Where? Come here.
Wait, Franco...
You will never enter my workshop again.
- Leave him, Franco.
- Get up!
- Leave him!
- You have to leave.
Yes.
- Otherwise you will regret being born.
- Leave him alone!
Get out!
What should we do here?
[Franco] This is my house, understand?
- I make the rules!
- [the door slams]
- [Pietro] Pasquale, give me the list.
- [Pasquale] Here.
- [Peter] How many are there? You?
- Salvatore Massone.
[Pietro] Salvatore, we know each other. Go.
- Antonino, still here?
- Yes.
- Grab the digger and get started.
- All right.
- This is the first time I've seen you.
- You are wrong.
- What is your name?
- Michele Mannino.
Michele Mannino, yes.
- Do you want to work?
- I'm a family man.
Grab a tool and get started
before I think about it again.
Thank you.
- Pasquale, continue.
- All right.
- [Nino] Good morning.
- [together] Good morning.
I heard
that Giacomo Agostini put you under control.
- Leave him alone, he thinks he's nice.
- Look here.
No, but it's not his fault.
Gianni Accordino, pleasure.
Pleasure.
- Alfredo, how are you?
- I am fine.
- Tonight I'm going to Santa Venerina.
- No never mind.
No, I won't let it go.
They have to tell me
what they said to you.
- Why are you doing so?
- Alfredo.
They must show you respect
because you are a good Christian.
- Gianni, let's get started.
- Let's go to work too.
- Thank you, Mr. Scalia.
- Hi handsome!
- Good work, Gianni. Hello Uncle.
- [Pietro] Hello, Nino.
[Alfredo] Let's go.
- Pasquale!
- Yes?
Mark Gianni Accordino on the list.
So, Gianni.
My brother brought you
and you didn't wait in line,
but when you work, you are the same as others.
- Understood?
- Certain.
Pasquale, explain the basics to this guy.
Alone.
See those branches?
[Pasquale] Now I'll explain what you have to do.
All right. Thanks, Fabio. HI.
[worker] Slowly, come in.
Piano.
Goes into.
Or.
Stop!
[worker] Attention, stop! Switch off!
What are you doing?
Mr. Scalia, I'm sorry.
- I was smoking...
- Go home.
- How are you going home? I have a family.
- I already told you.
When the truck unloads
no one has to stay here,
and do you smoke cigarettes?
Oh, I'm talking to you!
Are you going away or will I come get you?
What should we do?
I have family.
You did well, it wasn't the first time
he did something stupid.
Pasquale, that's why I'm here.
[Pasquale] Of course.
[Peter] What is there to look at?
Nothing happened.
Come on, start working again!
- [man 1] Did you see yesterday?
- [man 2] Don't be cheap.
[indistinct voices]
- [man 1] Cheers, kids!
- [together] Cheers!
Did you see the match?
Paolo Rossi, two to zero. Here!
[indistinct voices]
- Hello, Gioacchino.
- We will see each other.
[Pietro] Gianni, come here.
Until we meet again.
I looked at you, you know?
I saw how you move.
Bravo.
This is hard work,
you learn little by little like all things.
For the first day
I liked you, you work hard.
Thank you.
- HI.
- Until we meet again.
Now that you've become a pilot,
won't you come hunting with me anymore?
- No, uncle.
- HI.
Ciao.
What are you doing here? Don't see the game?
No, I want to be outdoors for a bit.
- Come with me!
- No, take me to the bus.
No, I want to take you somewhere.
Dove?
A place that only I know, mount.
- All right.
- Come on, come on! Go!
In here is the
gunpowder charge.
When the bomb enters the mortar,
the first blast puts pressure,
the gases expand,
the bomb shoots into the air and flies.
When it's high, really high, it explodes
and see all the colors
you chose in the mix.
Blue, red, green,
yellow, purple and all things.
You didn't understand anything, did you?
I understood that when it explodes,
you can see the colored stars.
Alright, let's leave it at that.
Look what I'll show you.
My grandfather drew these.
I did this.
So,
just a little warning to start with.
Alarm!
People look up
and you have their attention.
Now you have to figure out what you mean.
If you want to talk about love,
you need the most delicate colors.
If you've argued with someone,
you want to show everyone that you're pissed off.
If you want to scare them,
what's the problem?
You have a war army at your disposal.
What are you doing?
Then there's the grand finale.
Boom! Boom! Boom!
Because every story has to end, right?
What's up?
Did you kiss me last time?
To the accident.
What do you say? Kissed?
You weren't breathing anymore, I saved you.
Go wash yourself, you're all dirty.
No, do you think I should wash here?
The water is frozen.
Come on, come on!
Nino!
- Come on!
- I'm here, stupid.
Damn, you scared me!
Someone like you drowns in three seconds.
There's current there, it's dangerous.
We come here every day
and he still hasn't figured it out.
How long until the last bus leaves?
Soon, come on.
If we don't hurry, will we lose him?
I've been telling you for half an hour, hurry up!
- Come on!
- A moment.
Fast!
- Wait a moment!
- I'll leave you here. HI.
Where are you going? My scooter.
- Bye see you tomorrow.
- Until tomorrow.
Dude, you fell for it!
Come on, come on.
- Did you work here?
- Yes.
- Is he the one who fired you?
He's got a really fucking face.
Just a lot.
- HI.
- Oh, this is Nino.
- He's my boss' nephew.
- Good evening.
They were late and I accompanied him.
My uncle says he's very good.
Thank you.
- Come on, come on.
- Yes.
Okay, I'm going.
Why don't you ever want me to accompany you?
- Because I don't want to disturb.
- Stop it! See you tomorrow.
- HI.
What is this thing?
It's a trick, so you don't cry anymore.
Where did you learn this trick?
Works.
Are you seeing?
Have you made a new friend?
Bravo.
[radio] we'll meet you tomorrow
always at the same time.
- We greet you with a song.
- Which one do you want?
Let's Dance.
- What do you say?
- Come here.
♪ My day began in you ♪
♪ My night will come to me from you ♪
♪ a smile and I will smile ♪
♪ One gesture from you and I will cry ♪
♪ La mia forza me l'hai data tu ♪
♪ Every time you believed in me ♪
♪ You gave me what ♪
♪ The world never gave me ♪
♪ My world began in you ♪
♪ My world will end with you ♪
♪ What if you leave me ♪
♪ In a moment I will die ♪
♪ You gave me what ♪
♪ The world never gave me ♪
♪ My world began in you ♪
♪ My world will end with you ♪
♪ What if you leave me ♪
♪ In un momento così ♪
♪ Tutto per me ♪
♪ Finirà con te ♪
- [worker 1] Thank you.
- [worker 2] Thank you, Mr. Scalia.
[indistinct voices]
Grab your pickaxe and get started, go!
- Who are you?
- Rosario Puglisi.
[Pietro] Rosario Puglisi?
- Is it your first day at work?
- Yes.
Today you cut the grass down there.
Oh, young man!
- What are you doing? You rest?
- No.
- Come on!
- Yes.
Sorry, Mr. Scalia,
but I don't feel so good.
I would like to go home.
- What do you have?
- I don't know, I feel like I have a fever.
Ah, you have a fever.
Oh well, go home, but come back soon
because there's a lot of work to do here.
- Understood?
- Yes.
Or.
[Pasquale] Mr. Scalia, I'll carry it.
- [Pietro] Be careful, it's delicate.
- Hello Uncle.
Look who's there.
Punctual like clockwork.
- Gianni?
She-she Went home this morning.
Why?
He says he was unwell, he had a fever.
Do you know what the truth is?
You guys are fucking limp.
- Who are you?
- You young people.
- Then admit that you are old, uncle.
- Go away, go!
Oh!
- Hello, kids, see you.
- Until we meet again.
Yes?
- HI.
- Greetings miss. Is Gianni there?
- No, he's at work.
- It is true.
- Has something happened?
- No, I thought it was later.
- I'll get over it now. Until we meet again.
- HI.
[Emanuele] Hey, you!
Who are you looking for?
- I?
- [Emanuele] You. Come here.
[Emanuele] Come!
Alone.
At that time?
I was looking for a boy
who lives in this house.
Let me guess.
- You were looking for Giannuzza, right?
- [laughs]
Oh, will you shut up? I'm watching the game
and you screw my dick.
- Come on, let us have fun.
- Hi, what did you want from Gianni?
Well done Giuseppina.
This is how you welcome a stranger?
I came to say hello, but he's at work.
- What work?
- [Emanuele] So he didn't show up.
Work with my uncle.
- Okay, I'm leaving.
- Wait, where are you going? A second.
Did he also lie to you
that his father works in Germany?
I think you don't know many things about him.
Now Giuseppina tells you
a beautiful story about him.
She acts shy.
- Turi.
- Stop it, I'm watching the game.
- I don't want to disturb you, I'm leaving.
- You don't bother at all.
Do you know that your friend is a puppu?
Giuseppina saw him
while he was sucking one.
Does it suck for you too?
Enough, you have to stay silent, do you understand?
Otherwise I'll kill you.
Eh?
[reporter] One to zero for France.
Are you still here? Get out! Run, baby!
- You got scared, huh?
- [laughs]
What's up?
Nothing!
Oh!
What do you want?
Uncle said you had a fever,
and I stopped by
to see how you were.
Nino, you must not come to my house
unless I tell you. Did you understand?
However, everything is fine.
I am fine thank you.
Why are you talking to me like that?
Gianni, I'm talking to you.
You have to answer me.
Do you think you can escape like this?
Besides not having a fever, you
don't even have a father.
You only tell lies,
and I don't want a friend
who tells lies.
We don't see each other anymore anyway.
What do you mean we don't see each other anymore?
I don't come to the quarry anymore.
They took someone from my country
who I don't want to see.
He's one of the guys
at that shitty bar, right?
What do you know about it?
They took it out on me too.
I am sorry.
- Are the things they told me true?
- What did they tell you?
No, bullshit.
Bullshit, like the ones you tell.
Oh, I don't want to lose you.
Me niether.
Then a solution can be found, trust me.
Shall we go down?
[in English] This is my land.
Il pummarolo.
- [in English] Do you know the tomato?
- No.
Oh well, how do you say it?
[in English] I'll take you now
in an important place in my family.
[in English] She is...
Forget it.
[Ciccio in English] Oh, this is
my family!
Nail.
[in English] You're welcome.
[Totò] Italy! Italy!
- [in English] This is Carmela.
- Good evening.
- Ninuzzo.
- HI.
Italia!
♪ Italy has woken up! ♪
- Grandpa, when does the game start?
- Good, Totò.
- Go and call Uncle Nino.
- Yes!
Paolo Rossi! Paolo Rossi!
- Uncle, grandfather wants you.
- Eat.
[Totò] Forza Italia!
Here, dad. The panels.
So you told
your mother about the other night?
I? Who do you think I am?
Nino, the doctor says
that my cough doesn't convince him,
and your mother doesn't want me to work.
Do you know what pisses me off?
You are right.
Bitch the misery, I work too hard.
- So I...
- What? What do you?
We have twenty fairs up until August,
and that's quite a few.
I know, dad, but I can take care of it.
You know I'm good at it, right?
At 16? Alone?
No, maybe you're right, but...
That I know...
I can take Gianni with me.
Why not? She wants to work.
Uncle Pietro says
he was one of the best at the quarry.
Let's take the Ape that no one uses anymore
and we've solved it.
After a week off,
you settle back.
In the meantime, you watch
all the matches until the final.
Get me another one.
We'll talk about it again after
I talk to the doctor. All right?
All right.
♪ Cuccurucucu paloma ♪
♪ It burns cantava ♪
♪ The serenades at the teaching institute ♪
♪ During Gymnastics or Religion ♪
♪ For Carnival I played
Above the masked floats ♪
♪ I already had the Moon and Uranus in Leo ♪
♪ "Il mare nel cassetto"
"Le mille bolle blu" ♪
♪ Since you left
I no longer exist ♪
♪ "The world is gray, the world is blue" ♪
♪ Cuccurucucu paloma ♪
♪ It burns cantava ♪
♪ "Lady Madonna" ♪
♪ I can try
With a little help from my friends ♪
♪ Oh, oh, ciao, "Ruby Tuesday" ♪
♪ Come on, baby, let's spin again ♪
♪ Mi piacciono i Rolling Stone ♪
- [man] Are we all dumb?
- [together] Let's bring Sebastiano!
- Are we all silent?
- [man] Are we all dumb?
- [together] Let's bring Sebastiano!
[Nino] Sorry.
- Excuse me, can we pass?
- Can not be done.
Everything is closed here, the saint is passing by.
- Are you the ones with the fires?
- Yes.
They are those of the fires.
- What time were you supposed to come?
- [Nino] I know, there was traffic.
- It's closed now, you can't go through.
- But we have to shoot.
Don't insist, you can't pass.
So I call my uncle Pietro.
Then you explain it to the councilor.
Colleague! They are those of the fires.
They have to pass. What do I do?
Shall I pass?
- Come on, come on.
- Thank you.
[child] Do you see it?
[Nino] Good, put the cartoons close together.
Not really attached, close.
- [Nino] Get a fuse, helper.
- [Gianni] Don't be a commander.
- [Nino] Come on!
- [Gianni] Am I the helper?
- Sure, you're helping me.
- Stop it!
- Go away! Come here.
- Would you like to win?
- Come here.
- Come here how?
[Gianni] Oh, you don't scare me.
Say it, I give up.
[Nino] I give up, I give up.
Enough, I give up.
- You can't win with me.
- [child] They are kissing.
- Did you understand?
- Go away!
- You can't win.
- Enough.
At our
first fair together, commander.
Look how beautiful they are.
[bell tolls]
Let me enjoy, little ones.
[Nino] Did you see?
- [Alfredo] Nino!
- What's up?
- You come.
- Wait here.
- [Nino] What is it?
- Do you like fires?
Beautiful.
They told me everything.
Where is your friend?
- But what did they tell you?
- Call him.
Gianni, come.
At that time?
- Good morning.
The show went well.
- Totò!
- [Totò] Yes?
- Come here.
- Grandpa, I'm shitting.
[Alfredo] The councilor called.
He said everyone had
their heads held high and their mouths open.
Well done.
What's up?
- Let them accompany you.
- Where?
Don't have to dye your hair?
I dreamed that if I didn't win the tricolour,
Italy would lose.
Take money.
It must be the most beautiful tricolor.
- All right.
- Hello Mom.
- Hello Mom. Hello grandmother.
- Where are you going?
Damn, you look like two mummies!
So, are you ready? One, two, three, go!
[Nino] Go!
[Totò] Come on, uncle! Come on!
Go, uncle!
[Nino] Come here.
- Totò, come here!
- You come!
No, I'm scared, I don't know how to swim.
[Nino] What are you doing?
- Totò, stay still.
- Leave him alone.
[in Sicilian] Totò,
I'll cut this ball off for you.
Totò! I'll cut it for you.
Toto?
- I'll cut it for you.
- [Alfredo] You have to go to the center.
- Totò! Stop with this ball.
- Good.
- Dad, shut up, I can't hear.
- You put.
[reporter] Header
in a corner.
- Pass, pass. Stand on the right.
- Come on!
- [together] Come on!
- The defense needs to be more aggressive.
These are good,
they recover from two to two.
- [chronicler] From the flag...
- Oh, dumb!
- Accounts.
- Pass!
Conti is ready, he takes the shot.
- Accounts.
- Tardelli, dad.
[together] Goal!
My love!
[together] Yes! Goal!
[together] Goal!
Damn, I'm out of breath.
- Come on!
- Nino!
[Alfredo] Nino!
It wasn't needed.
What do you do in these cases?
He waits for it to pass and as it comes, it comes.
- Do you want a beer?
- Yes.
[Nino] A beer, thanks.
[woman softly] Yesterday I was at the party
to see the fireworks with my daughter.
Maybe I'm wrong, but I had the impression
that they were kissing.
- What do you say?
- I don't know, maybe I'm wrong.
- So you're making me worry.
- They were so close.
This seems strange to me.
A beautiful thing happened to me.
They promoted me, now I do trade fairs.
Nino's father is not well,
he cannot follow the fires for a while.
- Why didn't you tell me before?
- I'm telling you now.
- What do you know about fireworks?
- It's not difficult, then I'll help Nino.
Mom, they are beautiful.
You have to see them, you can say a lot of things with fires .
Are you two alone?
Yes.
What is it, mom?
Nothing.
- [Pietro] Do you like it? Carmela cooks well.
- [Alfredo] Where is he?
- [Pietro] Totò, this pasta?
- Good.
- [Pietro] You have to take Gianni hunting.
- Certain.
- Whenever you want.
- I'll teach you how to shoot.
The other time Nino caught
a hare like this, huge.
- Mom!
- [Pietro] You didn't see it, it was like that.
- [Isabella] Mom!
- [Ciccio] In Taormina I can take...
[Carmela] Yes.
[Alfredo] Take it, but don't do anything stupid.
- Sorry, I got distracted.
- Help your aunt.
No.
Nobody makes Carmela's pasta like it .
I can't do it.
With everything
I drank last night, I'm good.
- How beautiful my sister-in-law!
- Ciccio, hands off. It's a rare commodity.
- Thank you, Mrs. Scalia.
- [together] Best wishes, Alfredo!
- [together] Best wishes!
- Happy birthday to my brother, happy birthday.
Carmela, is everything okay? Eat something.
- You're right, I'm coming now.
- I'm always right.
We agree with you
because it's your birthday.
[Pietro] Leave him alone,
can't you see how he is?
[Ciccio] For being 99 years old you are perfect.
- [Totò] He's 49!
- [Alfredo] Let's eat.
The other night everyone was speechless
when you set off the fires.
- Good boy.
- [Alfredo] It's the truth and for this reason...
Carmela, bring the wine.
Guys, uncle has to give the speech
like every year.
Please let me talk, come on.
So, we all know it.
My son is a great artist.
- I'll be right there.
- Yes.
Today I want to make a toast
to those who accompanied him and work with him.
[Nino] Smoke, smoke!
[Alfredo] Just two words for the boy
who entered this house
almost by chance and on tiptoe.
Well done, Gianni.
And who then took my place
next to the person dearest to me.
Not only!
It also took my place
in the thing dearest to me, my work.
Yes, you took away a laborer from me
who ran like a train.
Come on, you get it.
This year we make
the first toast for Gianni.
Or.
[together] Thank you, Gianni. Welcome!
[Totò] Well done, Gianni!
[Alfredo] Carmela, what happened?
Nino, go and see
what your mother has done.
Mamma.
Mom, what happened here?
I had them for the second one,
they slipped and they broke.
- Don't worry, these things happen.
- No, Nino.
These are oddities that shouldn't happen,
you have to be careful.
Don't get hurt.
- HI.
- What is this concern?
The fair is far away, let's leave immediately.
I'm here to change,
Nino is waiting for me downstairs.
Good morning.
Ciao.
I did it, bye.
- Watch it! You look handsome in this shirt.
- Did you see?
Look at them, they look like two boyfriends.
[Gianni] You're talking to me. Look.
[Franco] Our Lady sent this work to the fairs .
If the pay is good,
he can get his own apartment.
You know what?
I'll call my friend
from public housing tomorrow.
He puts in a good word.
Oh, Lina! Where are you going?
Gianni! Gianni!
Gianni!
[phone rings]
[Carmela] Hello?
[Lina] I am Gianni's mother.
[Carmela] Ah.
[Lina] I wanted to thank you
for what you did for my son.
[Lina] Precisely for this reason...
it is right that you should know.
My son is the victim
of gossip, of malice.
Voices that perhaps are said
for a laugh...
but which then boil forever,
especially
to those who are too sensitive to react.
Your child can save himself
from this chatter.
He has a life full of joy,
of satisfaction ahead of him.
Gianni, on the other hand, has the life he has.
[gasping]
[coughs]
Go away, otherwise I'll kill you.
- You knew it?
- What questions! In your opinion?
- Did you know it or not?
- I knew it.
- [Isabella] That's bullshit!
- Shut up!
No, he was with my son, alone,
and who knows what he showed him!
- Is it true, Nino?
- Get out of here!
- [Alfredo] Go home!
- No, mom.
- The devil has arrived here. Come here.
- Go away!
- No!
- I said you have to leave!
- [Alfredo] Go away!
- [Carmela] No!
- Nino...
- Go away! Come on, move!
Bitch the misery!
Move!
Sit down!
- Sorry...
- Nino, tell the truth.
Only if you tell us what happened
can we help you.
We still have time to fix everything.
Can you tell what must have happened?
Today really think...
I didn't want to think about anything,
but these are the facts!
That disgusting thing is what it is,
I don't even want to repeat what,
and you spent too much time together,
in front of everyone, you and him, alone!
Really, Dad, I don't know what to say.
Gianni puppu?
Every girl who passed turned around...
- What the fuck are you doing?
- Don't bullshit me!
- Dad, I'm not kidding you!
- Oh! Calm down, calm down.
Oh my God!
- Have you calmed down?
- You have to tell me.
Did something happen or not?
What do we want to do, Nino?
Come on, answer your father.
Uncle, if I knew,
I wouldn't even let him in.
People like him disgust me,
more than all of you!
Don't let me see him here again
because I'll beat his broken ass!
All right?
Are you happy now?
Is the trial over?
No, because I'm tired.
[sobs]
Dad...
[Nino crying] Dad...
What do you want to know?
[Nino crying] Why?
[sound of footsteps]
Go to sleep,
tomorrow Franco will be waiting for you in the workshop.
You had something to do
with what happened, right?
I'm your mother.
You already ruined another guy's life .
Now do you want to ruin it for your friend too?
If you don't like what I decided,
you can go back to juvie.
You only want to protect yourself
because if people talk
behind our backs, they will chase us away.
And
who's going to buy this cheap dressing gown for you?
Who gives you the house?
This shitty house that disgusts me,
and you too,
who don't even know how to stand.
- Where are you going?
- My damn.
But what do you think? That
they're joking at your friend's house now?
You're off track, my life.
If you think you love him,
disappearing is the best gift
you can give him.
[a door slams]
LICENSED RICCHIONE
[Emanuele] Come on!
[Emanuele] Come on,
this time I made you win!
♪ I know, I know everything, don't talk anymore ♪
♪ I know maybe it's better ♪
♪ But I don't want to believe it ♪
♪ Non c'ero preparato ♪
♪ It takes my breath to say goodbye ♪
- [Pasquale] Permission?
- We are closing.
We want to buy the guy a coffee,
a one-minute thing.
The boy is working.
Didn't he say he was closing?
No, it's for me. Good morning.
Come on, shall we have this coffee?
Yes.
Gianni, Gianni.
Gianni...
At that time?
Shall we take this coffee?
[man] Come and see
what's going on outside.
Do we take it or not?
- [Gianni] No.
- Eh? What are you saying?
Shall we offer a coffee to your friend?
Gianni.
At that time?
[sounds of pain]
How much sugar do you want in your coffee?
Oh, fermi!
You bastards, get out!
Bastards, go away! Street!
You have to go! Go away, go away! Street!
Away, you bastards!
- Gianni!
- [sounds of pain]
What the fuck are you doing standing there? Give me a hand!
Oh!
Give me a hand!
[sounds of pain]
♪ Ma è vero ♪
♪ That your breath is shaking ♪
♪ But yes, it's really true ♪
♪ Come mai ♪
♪ Your eyes are crying now ♪
Is escaped.
You have to be more careful, Nino.
If you make too much noise,
the hare hears you and tricks you.
What do you want to do with that thing?
- Do you want to shoot, Totò?
- I'm scared.
What scares you? Come here, I'll teach you.
A hand here.
Good boy. The other one here.
Do you see the hare?
- Yes.
- Go.
I got it! I got it!
- Good boy.
- [Pietro] Did you understand Totò?
I got it!
Uncle, did you see? I got it!
Look, I got it.
Now everything is as before.
- Shall we go back to playing?
- Certain.
[priest] Gianni?
Gianni!
Come on, let's pray together.
"In the name of the Father, of the Son
and of the Holy Spirit. Amen.
Our Father in heaven,
hallowed be your name.
Come your kingdom,
Thy will be done on Earth
as it is in heaven.
Give us today our daily bread,
and forgive us our debts
as we forgive our debtors
and do not lead us into temptation,
but deliver us from evil. Amen."
Nino! Come on, tonight is the final.
Let's prepare everything.
Isabella, give me a hand.
Arrange the chairs.
[Totò] Forza Italia!
Yes!
[Isabella] Like this?
[Totò] ♪ Brothers... ♪
Oh, come on, get up! Grab some chairs.
- [Isabella] Totò, come here!
- [Totò] Yes!
[Alfredo] Nino, come on!
This...
The table.
Take this table.
Via.
Totò, what are you doing there? Come here.
We place the flag on top of the table.
Put it on the table.
As.
Shoot well. Attention...
- [Alfredo] What should we do today?
- [Totò] Winning!
Yes, come here. Forza Italia!
[inaudible voices]
[together] Oh!
- Gentlemen.
- Thank you.
[chronist] Launch of Tardelli on Rossi.
- Come on, Rossi!
- [reporter] Rossi stopped by Breitner.
[reporter] Breitner advances.
Shot from afar. Deviation by Rummenigge.
- Where is Nino?
- I do not know.
[reporter] And he's out. Forster shot.
- [in English] One moment.
- [Alfredo in English] Italy is strong.
- [Totò] Grandpa, do you think we win?
- [Alfredo] Of course, we win.
- [Alfredo] Oh, move!
- [Totò] Come on! Damn, take pictures!
- [Alfredo] Like this!
- [Totò] Come on!
[Alfredo] Lance! Oh, come on!
- Nino, what are you doing? Don't see the game?
- No.
You don't have to be afraid of me.
- I'm not afraid of anything.
- And you're wrong.
He who is not afraid of anything
goes nowhere,
or ends up under the train.
They think they know everything about me.
Your father,
your mother, Isabella.
Uncle Pietro!
Instead they know nothing.
What I do at night.
The females, the friends, the Americans.
What I don't do.
They can imagine it, yes.
But they must remain in doubt...
and that alone is not enough.
Nino, what is done in secret...
it can be done for 100 years.
Ciao.
[chronist] Bergomi, Gentile. It's over!
World Champions! World champions!
Italy won the final
beating Germany three to one.
- [shouts of celebration]
- [together] Italy! Italy!
[together] Italy! Italy!
Yes!
- [together] Italy! Italy!
- Gianni!
[Nino] Gianni!
- [Gianni] Nino!
- Come on, get down.
Come here, come on! Get off!
- [Nino] Come on, come on!
- You're not going anywhere.
Yes, that's right, mom.
I'm not going anywhere.
[inaudible voices]
What's up?
[two shots]
to Toni and Giorgio who were killed in
Silicia,1980 because they loved each other
the first arcigay club was formed in Palermo
on 9 December 1980 also on the emotional wave of
the demonstrations organized by "FUORI"
following the death of the two young Sicilians