Good afternoon and welcome to the
Phase II press conference of the
upcoming mission of the
Global Precipitation Measurement.
To discuss the mission, we
have with us John Stockton,
GPM Project Formulation
Manager from NASA Headquarters;
Mohan Bhargav,
Project Manager and Spacecraft
Mission Director from Goddard.
Over to you, John.
- Thank you, George.
The Office of Management and Budget
released the President's 2004
fiscal year budget plan in early February,
flagging off the GPM launch.
We have in the Formulation phase
of GPM taken steps to reduce risks
to ensure a mission confirmation review.
And that's where Mohan Bhargava,
our Project Manager, comes in.
Thank you, John.
Good afternoon, everybody.
Before I get into Phase II, a quick
update on the recently concluded Phase I.
In the Phase I, we focused on
the Definition of Mission Scope,
Systematic Measurement Approach,
and Technology Roadmaps.
Will you roll the tape, please?
Thank you.
The core satellite is designed
like a TRMM spacecraft,
and it'll be launched in a non-sun-sync
orbit at an inclination of 65 degrees
and an altitude of 400 kilometers.
The constellation satellites would be
pre-existing operational, experimental, and
dedicated satellites, with PMW radiometers.
They would operate both in
non-sun-sync and sync orbits
at an altitude of 600 to 900 kilometers.
You are welcome to
throw any questions.
What are the objectives of the Global
Precipitation Measurement program?
Last question.
- Is this budget justified?
Globally, there is a danger of
water recession in the near future.
It will not be unreal to imagine that
in the 21st century, cities like...
Beijing, Amman, New Delhi, Santiago,
Jakarta, Mexico City, Lima...
and many others, will drink up, use up,
their surrounding waters and perish.
Water is going to be rare. Is it not a
reason enough to justify any budget?
Are there any more questions?
Thank you for being here.
- Thank you very much.
I've never seen John Stockton smile so much.
He is really happy with us.
The press conference went off well.
And your presentation - excellent!
This is really a quantum leap for us.
Well, we can now let our hair down.
Now that Phase I is finally over.
Hey, you're very quiet.
What's the matter?
I'd like a cup of coffee.
Do you want some?
Yeah. Make me a strong one.
- Sure.
Two new messages.
Hi Mohan, this is Paul. I tried
calling you at work and your cell.
You seem to be in a meeting.
Call me back.
Good afternoon, Mr. Bhargava.
This is Stephen Carter from the BCIS.
Your request for citizenship has been accepted.
Congratulations. Please call me in my office on Monday. Bye.
Congratulations! Your request for
American citizenship has been accepted.
You seem lost.
- Not really.
I get it.
Work pressures are stressing you out,
and you have no other interests...
No pubbing, no partying.
Take my advice - you should get married.
You need a life partner.
As they say, happiness
doubles when it's shared.
Look at me!
That's not it, Vinod.
Then what is it?
What's the matter?
Today is the anniversary of my parents' deaths.
Oh. I'm sorry.
It's okay.
I still remember it clearly. I was in my
last year at the University of Pennsylvania
when I heard about the car accident.
Now I understand why
you've been so down all day.
You know, Vinod...
There's something else which has been
bothering my conscience for a while.
Do you remember Kaveriamma?
Kaveriamma? Your old nanny, right?
Please don't call her a nanny.
She was like a mother to me.
I'm sorry. I had no idea.
What about her?
As you know, I was an only child.
My parents brought me up with a lot of
love - they provided me with everything.
But along with them, Kaveriamma
had a special place in my life.
My mom would make my breakfast,
then Kaveriamma would feed me.
While my mom tucked me into bed,
Kaveriamma would sing a lullaby.
From the age of two to seventeen,
she looked after me completely.
One could call her a second mother,
Kaveriamma was that dear to me.
So... when was the last time you met her?
At my parents' funeral.
I cried like a baby in Kaveriamma's arms.
It was a very tough time for me.
Then I came back here and
began to find my footing in life.
Kaveriamma wrote letters to me
often, and I would send her replies.
But later on, I became so immersed
in my work that I just lost touch.
All this is so out of the blue, Mohan.
Why did you suddenly think of her today?
It's not sudden, Vinod.
I've been thinking about
Kaveriamma for months.
I've been having recurring nightmares of her...
...being old, feeble, and helpless.
I've made a mistake, Vinod.
I feel so guilty now, having
forgotten and neglected her...
Not cared about her.
I had become selfish, Vinod.
She is the only thread capable of
piecing together the memory of my parents.
I was thinking of going to Delhi...
and bringing her here.
Absolutely! Brilliant idea.
But I don't think John will agree.
There's no better time for you
to ask for a vacation than now.
We are 28 weeks away from
the GPM launch. John won't refuse.
You think so?
- Yeah. Sure.
Promise to bring him back
an elephant or something.
Yeah. Sure.
Thank you very much.
So, it's of the utmost importance
to get the time pressure on the
stabilization unit.
Thank you very much, gentlemen.
Excuse me, John.
- Sure, tell me.
I have a request for two weeks off.
Need to go to India - is it possible?
Is everything okay back home?
Oh yeah, everything is all right.
Just a pending matter.
When do you have to leave?
Actually, as soon as possible.
28 weeks to launch?
You realize you'll have to
delegate some of this to others.
Oh, yes, yes. I'll have a detailed
meeting with the team and
I'll be in constant touch
with Vinod from there.
All right, then. Have a good trip.
Thank you very much, John.
Amazing. John agreed very quickly.
I should've asked for a vacation myself.
Thank God you didn't. If you had,
mine would've been canceled as well.
May I clear your tray, please?
- Yes, thank you.
Can I get you anything else?
- No, thank you.
This is your captain here.
Good morning, everyone.
We have now started our descent,
and in a short time we'll be landing
at the Indira Gandhi
International Airport in Delhi.
I hope you had a comfortable flight.
Thank you for flying Air India.
Your attention, please.
Announcing the arrival of
flight AI-112 from New York.
Good to see you.
-Good to see you, too.
How was the flight?
- Connecting flight was delayed. Otherwise, first class.
Did you get anything for me?
- Yeah, everything's for you, kid.
So, Kaveriamma... is she still
living in an old folks' home?
Did you speak with her?
No, I want to surprise her.
She'll be so glad to see you.
I'm sure she'll have forgotten me.
Obviously!
Excuse me.
- What is it? May I help you?
I've come to see Kaveriamma.
Kaveriamma?
- Yes.
Oh yes, Kaveri!
She doesn't live with us anymore.
Doesn't live here?
- Yes. She stayed with us for about a year...
...until a lady came, looking for her.
Kaveri left with her.
But where did she go?
One minute.
I'll have to check the register.
Bharati ji, this gentleman
is looking for Kaveri.
Do you know where she is now?
Bharati used to share
a room with Kaveri.
I remember her mentioning
a village before leaving.
Now, what was it?
Charanpur.
- Yeah, Charanpur.
Where is this Charanpur?
- Never heard of it.
We'll find out.
Kaveri was a good woman.
We all miss her.
Here's the address.
Thank you.
Kaveri is very fortunate.
There was someone who came
for her then, and now once again.
Otherwise, who cares
about old people like us?
Come on.
Excuse me.
Here's the map.
You'll find Charanpur in here.
That'll be 150 rupees.
- No, buddy. You don't need to pay me.
Do me a favor. Watch the counter
for me while I nip to the bank.
Get me a loan, too.
- No way. You'll manage the counter, right?
I'll just sit behind.
That's good.
- Come back soon.
Excuse me - you've no respect?
What's wrong?
You can see I am picking up books,
and still you're walking all over them.
I didn't mean to do anything.
Sir, books are a source
of knowledge and culture.
If you don't know how to
appreciate them, then why are you here?
Well... I'm sorry.
- Thanks.
I'm sorry, I was looking at this map.
Do you want to buy these books?
No. I want to sell them.
Oh! Stupid question. I'm sorry.
- No, I'm sorry.
I'm just a little irritated.
- No, I saw what happened.
You handled it well.
Some people simply don't
have any manners. Really stupid.
Oh, yeah... I'll do this for you.
Lots of books.
I will need a...
- There.
Of course. Thank you.
That's 13 books of mathematics into 17...
...is equal to 221... plus 22
language books into 12...
485.
8 geography books into
19 is 152... and 485 is...
637.
Yeah? 637?
Thanks.
And these 8 notebooks into 113.
And the total is...
750.
Must be right.
Your math is pretty good!
Actually, I should be
giving you a concession.
You selected the books,
you did the totaling.
You should be in my chair!
Then, give me a concession?
I can't.
My name is actually Mohan Bhargav.
I'm Rahul's friend.
He's the owner of this shop -
he had to go to the bank.
He needed some money... he'd ran out.
I'm just filling in for him.
Oh.
I'll pack this for you.
But I need...
Bags.
I've been looking for
Charanpur on this map.
It's a small village.
Do you know where Charanpur can be found?
Yeah, I do know where it is.
Go down National Highway No. 6 for
110 kilometers until you reach Charoti.
From there, take a left.
And then keep going for
80 kilometers, until you reach Azamgarh.
After 20 kilometers on a dirt
track, you'll reach Charanpur.
Wow! Your geography seems pretty good as well!
Here you...
Hello! Excuse me.
Please look after the counter. Hello!
What happened?
Are you sick of the job already?
No - a girl came in, bought a lot
of books... but forgot her change.
Hey! Not bad!
You made a profit for the company on
the very first day. You've got the job!
She was amazing!
She even told me the way to Charanpur.
Great. Where is Charapur?
About 200 kilometers from here.
Spare me, Mohan. Don't expect me to
leave the store and drive you there.
No worries, man! I'll need a car though.
Take my car!
- No, no. I meant.. could I get a caravan?
Caravan? Caravan - why?
I don't know what conditions
I'll have to face in the village.
Okay, okay, Mr. NRI.
(Non-Resident Indian)
You'll have your caravan. Don't worry.
Can you tell me which of
these paths leads to Charanpur?
You have strayed from the path.
Strayed? No, no...
I've been following directions.
Maybe I took a wrong turn somewhere.
It was your destiny to take that wrong turn.
Charanpur is pretty far from here.
I'm headed in that direction.
If you want, I can show you the right way.
Keep going, traveler!
How beautiful is this world?
Forget every burden,
let the flowers pull you in
How vibrant this world is!
Wow!
Encore!
Sing.
These roads call out to me:
Somewhere, someone's waiting for you!
Why does the heart anxiously beat?
Who is it about to meet?
Perhaps what it most desires is about to happen
Keep going, traveler!
Life's a car; time's the wheel
There's a flood of tears and a garden of joys
All wait along this path for you, brother!
Keep going, traveler!
How beautiful is this world?
Forget every burden,
let the flowers pull you in
How vibrant this world is!
Wherever I look along these paths,
colors stream in my glance
The breeze is cool, the shade cool, too
Far, over there, I wonder whose hamlet stands
What cloud has spread over me?
Where has the heart brought me?
What dreams has it shown me?
Every dream comes true if the fires of love are lit,
if the path you travel is of your heart!
You will pick pearls from every oyster of time
but only if you always listen to your heart!
Keep going, traveler!
How beautiful is this world?
Forget every burden,
let the flowers pull you in
How vibrant this world is!
The heart experiences such ease
As though a load has been
lifted from the shoulders
As though the innocence
of childhood has returned
As though, at long last, one
has bathed in the river Ganga
The heart is pure,
bonds are now strengthened
Life feels fresh and new
There's love in my living,
a song upon my lips
This is your victory, oh traveler!
Wherever you go, may you always find love
and leave a blazing trail, oh traveler!
Keep going, traveler!
Who calls out to me?
The river, the mountains,
the lakes and streams, the woods and valleys
Whose beckoning hand do I see there?
Keep going, traveler!
How beautiful is this world?
Excuse me.
Do you know where Kaveri ji lives?
Hey, Chikku!
Take this man to Kaveri ji.
Sorry.
- Watch it!
Amma!
Wait a while.
She needs to be massaged like this
in the morning and evening, Maithili!
She'll cry a little, but ignore it.
Understood?
Now talk.
Amma, someone has come
to meet you in a very big car.
A very big car?
Come on, now! It's parked outside.
I am coming.
Chikku, I hope this isn't one of your pranks!
Look at that.
It's big, isn't it?
What's going on?
Who is this?
Go on... take a guess.
No. No, I can't. Who are you?
Come on, let go! Let go!
Atkan batkan dahi chatokan,
(Krishna's childhood couplet)
Tu Yashoda, main hoon?
Mohan!
Kaveriamma.
Mohan... my Mohan!
I can't believe my eyes!
Do you know who this is?
This is my Mohan.
The one I keep telling you about.
Come.
Stop! Wait right here.
Don't step a foot inside. I'll be back.
Now you can come in.
Kaveriamma.
- Yes?
What are you doing?
I can't tell you how
happy I am to see you.
Wait until Gita comes home.
I'll announce that I've won the bet.
Bet? What bet?
Gita always said,
"Your Mohan has forgotten you."
Really?
But I would always retort,
"No, he will come to see me."
So we made a bet.
If you did come, she'd have
to treat me to an ice cream!
Ice cream? Kaveriamma.
Why...?
- Because you haven't changed a bit!
You haven't lost your
appetite for ice cream.
Why not?
Is ice cream meant only for kids?
Can't us old-timers enjoy it?
Sit!
All right, you win.
And by the way, who says you're old?
So... who is this Gita?
Don't you remember?
You often played with her as a child.
She used to visit our
Delhi house with her mother.
Gita...
Are you referring to that
'Gitli' by any chance?
Yes! You called her that.
And this is Nandan, Gita's younger brother.
We lovingly call him 'Chikku.'
- Chikku! Hey, Chikku!
He faked a tummy ache today
so that he could miss school.
How old are you?
- Eight.
Which school do you go to?
I study at Navjeevan Paathshala.
My roll number is 6 and
I am in the fourth standard.
The motto of our school is:
"Books are a source of knowledge,
and knowledge is strength."
Your school seems to be a good one.
So, why haven't you gone today?
- I had a stomach ache.
Really?
Was the pain here?
Or here?
Would you like to see my school?
- No, not now.
I want to talk to Amma.
- No! Let's go to the school right now.
All right, Chikku.
Mohan, why don't you go
visit the school with Chikku?
You can meet Gita as well.
She teaches there.
But... I thought Chikku
had a stomach ache.
Ache? Oh, yes.
It was there, but it just went away.
Let's go to my school now!
That's Uncle Postman!
Not just postman!
I'm the plough and the bull, the field
and the seed, the crop and the grains.
I am everything here!
I sort the letters, seal them,
and distribute them, as well.
When on my bicycle, I'm the postman;
and in my chair, postmaster.
The name is Nivaaran Dayal Shrivastava.
How can I help you?
Can I call America from here?
There is no ISD here, but you can
connect through Mizwa village's line.
By the way, there is
no bank, no bond, no registry.
I apologize for the trouble earlier today.
That's okay. You live abroad, right?
- Yes.
I too happen to know some English.
What can I do for you?
Very good!
Mohan bhaiyya! Look - this is my school!
It's very nice, Chikku.
It was in 1942 that...
...the slogans of the 'Quit India Movement'
were first heard in Bombay.
From Bombay to Lahore,
Lahore to Peshawari...
...the Indian revolutionaries and the
British soldiers were locked in conflict.
Blows were dealt in succession,
bullets were whizzing and ricocheting.
But through it all, we protested,
not once raising our hands against others.
I was even hit by a bullet in the shoulder.
They arrested us and threw us in jail.
We kept protesting - Inquilab zindabad!
(Long live the revolution)
Dada ji, did you have a beard then?
- I wish I did.
Then the bullet would've gotten
stuck in my beard and become lost.
I... am... going!
We both... are... going!
We all... are... going!
Well done! Kamala, now you repeat...
I... am... going!
It's you!
I must have misunderstood
your directions and gotten lost.
Excuse me. This is a school,
and a class is in progress.
I'm sorry.
Mohan bhaiyya, this is Gita didi.
And didi didi, this is Mohan bhaiyya.
He has come from Aamkarica!
- Not Aamkarica, Chikku. America.
Chikku, what are you doing here?
I thought you had a stomach ache!
Amma asked me to show
Mohan bhaiyya the school, so I just...
So you are Gita! Remember me?
I used to call you 'Gitli' when we were kids.
The children are supposed
to be studying. Now will you go?
I'm sorry.
Now I understand.
Mathematics, geography...
Oh yeah, by the way...
You forgot your 50 rupees at the bookstore.
Thank you. Now will you go?
Yes. I'm very sorry.
I... am... going!
Very good.
What's this?
Foot massager.
It'll take care of your aching feet.
There's no electricity at the moment.
- Why?
We have power failures quite often.
- Oh? When will it return?
Nothing can be said for sure.
This happens three or four times a week.
Who are they?
Gita's parents, Shanta and Jagmohan ji.
They started the school in Charanpur.
When Chikku was only five,
Jagmohan ji passed away.
Gita was studying at a
college in Delhi at that time.
As soon as she graduated, she came here...
...to help her mother with
the running of the school.
But Shanta's health was on the decline,
and it came to her sending Gita
to the retirement home to find me.
Before dying, Shanta entrusted
me with the care of her children.
Thanks.
It took you a while.
- Yes. I had to correct a few test papers.
I thought I might as well finish them here.
Didi, didi - look what
Mohan bhaiyya got for me!
Guess what I'm going to
cook for you, Mohan?
Very nice.
Your favorite tadka dal,
aloo ki sabzi and kheer!
Wow!
Gita! Now you will have
to treat me to an ice cream.
You lost the bet!
Kaveriamma, I've missed your food.
The kheer was especially good.
I knew you would like it.
Enough about me.
Now tell us about yourself...
and your work in America.
Everything's fine in America.
I have all the comforts.
I have all that I could ask for.
I'm glad to hear that.
And how is your nasha going?
(nasha - drugs)
Nasha?
Yeah. Why? Have you quit?
NASA? NASA...
That's what I meant.
My work at nasha -
I mean, NASA - is going very well.
You're an astronaut?
No.
I'm a Project Manager for
Global Precipitation Measurement.
Very good.
Mohan bhaiyya! Look at this.
Wow! Very good. You are a great artist.
Chikku, you skipped school today.
You have to catch up with work. Come on.
Good night, Chikku.
- Say good night.
I owe you an apology.
Apology? For what?
I'm sorry...
...that I wasn't there to take care of you.
What are you talking about?
Let me talk, Kaveriamma.
I'm sorry... that I wasn't
there to take care of you.
I'm sorry that I was not there
when you needed me the most.
I'm sorry that you had
to go to an old-age home.
Not another word now.
Son...
...these are all matters of destiny.
I have everything...
Everything, but you.
I miss you very much, Kaveriamma.
Will you come with me?
Where?
America.
No, I'm fine here.
Just come with me, you'll love it there.
You'll get a lot of rest and peace.
It's a much better life there.
Let me think about this.
Now, come on.
You should go to sleep here.
Here?
If you don't mind,
I will sleep in the caravan.
Now what new machine is this?
One that puts you to sleep?
Something like that.
Good night.
- Good night.
Yes?
Sir, I am Mela Ram.
Hello. What do you want?
Sir, I have brought you breakfast.
Please try my breakfast.
- Breakfast? Not now.
Sir, please - I made it especially for you.
I am a very good cook.
Got it... I mean, I understand.
You are a good cook! I'm impressed.
- Thank you, sir.
You have come from America, sir?
One question, sir.
In America, are there a lot of highways?
Yes, there are. But they're
called freeways there.
Got it!
I mean, I understand.
One more question, sir.
Be comfortable.
Do they have dhabas on these freeways?
(dhaba - an Indian fast food joint)
Dhaba?
- Yes.
Yeah, there are. Why?
What do you think?
Would an Indian dhaba
work on those freeways?
I think it'll work.
- Will it work?
I think, maybe...
Thanks for the dhaba - I mean, the breakfast.
Now if you'll excuse me,
I have to get ready. Please?
Why not, sir?
I'll meet you again, sir.
Thank you, Thela Ram.
Sir, it's Mela Ram!
- Sorry, Mela Ram.
Sir, last question.
Sir, I'll give you a very good offer, sir.
We'll open a dhaba in partnership.
I will give you 50% - yes, half of all
the money I make, sir, I'll give you!
I have even thought of
a name for this dhaba.
It will be called...
...Mela Ram Dhaba. Okay?
- Okay.
Happy?
- Very happy.
It's a deal, sir.
Jai Ram ji ki!
(Lord Ram be praised)
So this is your caravan!
It's not mine. It belongs to a friend of Rahul's.
It's nice! Isn't it, Gita?
Chikku was right.
Really, this car is exactly like a house.
There's a kitchen here.
A TV.
A bathroom.
A bed, too.
Wow! This car is like a house on wheels!
Absolutely.
It's very comfortable.
Now we should be going.
We don't want to miss the panchayat.
(governance assembly)
Come on. Let's go.
Come on, quickly.
The dstrict council is deliberating
upon all the demands...
...made in the last village panchayat meeting.
The decision will be made soon.
Sadanand ji, please tell us when the
remaining electric wires will be put up.
We plan to start work as soon as possible.
The Gram Panchayat ha...
- Just a moment, Sadanand Bajpei saab.
I've never seen a panchayat before.
Whenever you are asked,
all you say is: "We plan to start work."
You are the Block Development Officer.
You are well aware that we have been
dealing with this problem for a long time.
75% of the village is constantly
plagued by electricity failures,
and the remaining
one-fourth still lives in darkness.
This is like covering your
back while your front's open.
Then, what's the point
of these electric wires?
Dada ji, the Government Surveyor
has recorded his observations.
It's now just a matter of a few days.
A few days?
In a few days, I'll be at heaven's door.
Then you can come light a bulb on my shrine.
Dada ji, don't say that -
may you live a long life!
If you don't mind, Dada ji, I also
have a complaint against the village.
What's that?
- One hears that Dukhi, Santram and their boys...
...steal electricity from the poles.
It's not us. It's Santram who's the culprit!
Shut your mouth!
When did we steal electricity?
Now I understand why there
was no power last evening.
Calm down everyone!
- All right, all right.
Sadanand ji, this job should be done soon.
- Yes.
Otherwise, we'll take the
matter to higher authorities.
Sangam, what is the next case?
Case number 35 - the school!
Well, Gita ji?
I wish to continue teaching the
children using the existing premises.
The new alternate
place you are suggesting...
...is much too small,
and it's also too far.
Children can't walk that distance every day.
But why do you need such
a big space for the school?
You don't even have enough
children to fill up the classes.
More children will come
to study in the school.
That's what you've been
saying for a year now!
She has been trying.
We've all been trying.
Look, Dada ji, we need the
school space for the panchayat.
And the tehsildars also want to
establish their office in the school.
And the village needs a
spare room for the granary.
It will be the economic center of the village.
And the place we are offering
you is good enough for teaching.
No, it won't be enough.
I want to start a few
more classes in the school.
I want to reinstate those children
who have left the school
in the past couple of years.
There also are many villagers who
do not send their children to school.
Today, I appeal to all of them to
start sending their children to school.
All right, Gita ji.
If you can manage to enroll more
children in the next three months,
then we'll be ready to reconsider.
But if there are no new admissions,
then you must agree to move
from the current premises.
This month's panchayat is adjourned!
Come, Mohan, let me introduce
you to the members of the panch.
This is my Mohan.
He has just come from America.
Mohan... this is the head of
our village - Vishnudutt ji.
Hello.
Namaste.
- My blessings, son.
Munishwar ji.
God bless you, my son.
Gungadin ji.
- Namaste.
Fatimabi...
- May you live long, my son.
...and Narayan ji.
God bless you, son.
May Lord Ram protect you.
What do you do in America?
I work for a company called NASA.
So, what does this
company manufacture?
We make satellites.
What's that?
Oh, come on, Fatima...
...you know those things in the sky.
Satellites...
- Let me explain.
Satellites are like
the moon, orbiting earth.
They help us to know when,
where and how much it will rain,
and they predict atmospheric changes.
They send us information
about all these things.
That's it!
- Isn't this what you had told me?
Wow, Kaveri - I'm impressed!
I had no idea you knew so much...
...about these things.
All this work that you have described
is done by our Sahdev out here...
...without rotating himself, believe me!
Hey Sahdev, speak to us!
The sky is clear.
There will be no clouds in
evidence for the next two days.
Very good! That's precisely what I do.
Mohan bhaiyya! Look!
That's the temple!
Beautiful!
Beautiful! What's this?
This is the specialty of our village.
These are the footprints
of Lord Ram and Sita.
What?
Ram and Sita's footprints!
Charanpur. Okay.
That explains the name of the village - Charanpur.
(Charan - feet)
How are you?
- I'm all right.
And Kaveriamma? How is she?
- She's fine.
I've been trying your cell phone.
Yeah. There's no phone network coverage here.
Vinod, I'm no longer in Delhi.
I'm in a village called Charanpur.
Oh. Anyway, now what about
the GPM instrument concept
and risk reduction study
that needs to be initialized?
I'll e-mail you the graphics right away.
You do that. But the internet
connection here is weak.
I don't think I'll be able to download them.
Why don't you send by Fed-Ex the
CD to Rahul in Delhi? He'll give it to me.
Okay.
Come fast.
One more thing! The week
will pass by very quickly.
All right.
I am going to be here a
little longer than I thought.
Kaveriamma has some work here,
so she can't leave right away.
Okay. Fine.
Can I have a word with John
regarding this? Is he there?
Don't worry about that.
I will take care of that.
See you then.
- Bye.
Jai Ram ji ki.
Well, well... the village lingo's getting
a hold on you. Jai Ram ji ki! Bye.
One minute.
How much was that?
518 rupees?
518 rupees, sir.
One second, sir.
You just mentioned the word "internet."
I've heard the word "international."
But "internet"? What is that?
I think I've heard it somewhere.
Internet... Internet is a medium
through which we can...
...connect and communicate
with people in any part of the world.
No post office needed!
This is called e-mail.
E-mail! Really?
Fantastic!
If this e-mail is somehow
installed in this village,
I'll be in seventh heaven!
- How so?
Because then I wouldn't
have to deliver any little letters.
I would just sit here and e-mail them all!
E-mail is indeed the summum bonum,
it breaks the walls that...
...separate home and the world!
Thank you, sir.
- Okay.
Time to get up!
Kaveriamma, don't wake me up!
I haven't slept like this in years.
Get up. We have a lot of work to do now.
The guests will be here at eleven.
The house needs to be cleaned.
What's going on? Who are the guests?
A potential groom is coming
to see Gita with his parents.
What?
They are from Azamgarh.
- Gita's marriage?
Yes!
- Yes?
Gita's marriage.
I forgot to tell you last night.
About two months ago, Vishwas ji,
the boy's father, wrote to me.
Now, finally, they're coming here today.
But what's the need for all this?
- What do you mean?
I mean... I mean, what's the rush?
She's just a child!
What a strange thing to say!
Come on, get ready.
Why should I get ready?
As if they're coming to see me.
This is Gita.
- Namaste.
This is Raghunath.
Please sit.
Excuse me, I'll just be back.
I've heard... you run a school here.
- Yes.
We have a chemicals business.
Really?
The demand that you're
making is not acceptable to me.
Teaching at this school is
my profession and my passion.
And I'd like to continue
this work after marriage.
A woman's hands are full
just with household chores.
I disagree. I'd take care of my
house in addition to my work.
But we don't like the women
of our home to work outside.
Besides, I fail to see why you would
want to keep working after marriage.
What if I say the same to your son?
My parents brought me
up with love and respect.
And they expected me to live my life with...
...self-esteem, independence and self-reliance.
If your son has a desire to be
something in life and to have a part in society,
then why can't women
have the same desire?
Be it in any field, women
are making their mark equally.
There's more to a woman
than just wearing bangles.
And after marriage, aren't the
house and the children as much...
...a responsibility of the man as the woman?
Why can't the husband
and wife work as a team?
Why should one of them
sacrifice more than the other?
I don't accept the demand that
I must not work after marriage.
You mean... are you rejecting this proposal?
I have nothing else to say.
This is how the new generation thinks.
We should not carry this matter any further.
I'm sorry, Sharda ji... Vishwas ji.
It's all right.
I'm upset with what happened today.
- But I felt I was right.
I don't think you should have
expressed your views in that way.
Whatever they wanted
was against my principles.
Kaveriamma, Gita is right.
But Mohan, he was a nice boy.
You can change people's views
about life over a period of time.
Yeah, you do have a point there.
- No. I couldn't have changed him.
Habits can be altered over time, but
narrow opinions and beliefs cannot be.
I'm absolutely certain...
...that their next demand
would be the dowry amount.
Quite possible. I completely agree with you.
This thinking is embedded in our culture
and traditions, and it hampers the nation.
Excuse me?
Without culture and traditions, the
country would be left with no soul.
But Mohan, we are not
talking about the country.
I know, Kaveriamma.
But it's all connected, isn't it?
What is this soul you talk of, Gita?
We are plagued with problems.
I mean, you and I both
know that illiteracy is rampant,
that we have administrative problems,
and we are yet underdeveloped.
Yes. Illiteracy and poverty are hand in glove.
Kaveriamma, your village has
not even gotten electricity yet.
Caste discrimination, overpopulation,
unemployment, corruption...
I mean... our state of affairs is dismal.
It's pathetic. Pass me the salt.
You have drifted from our topic. But since
you've brought this up, let me tell you,
the government is trying to
find solutions for these problems.
Yeah, yeah, yeah! We'll see how
much good their solutions bring.
The infrastructure that the
government has is not enough to...
...cope with even one fourth
of the existing population.
The government has always failed
to satisfy the needs of the population.
The government is making
policies, making efforts.
What do you mean by "efforts"?
Just to make resolutions and collect funds for them?
Is that where the government's work ends?
Whether this money is implemented in the
first place to reach the grassroot level or not...
...whether the common man
benefits or not from their resolutions...
...are they not responsible
for these things, as well?
Yes, they are.
- Then...?
But what do you think the
government is, after all?
The government is a system, of
which the public is also a part.
Us, you, this village...
we all are involved in this system.
Now, if the system is lacking
in certain things, then...
...to remedy its weaknesses
is our responsibility, as well.
God helps only those who help themselves.
Yes, Kaveriamma, but things
are not going to change here.
Because no one wants to change.
It's easy for you to criticize.
But are you doing anything about it? No.
Excuse me.
At least I am not defending
the government like you.
I'm building satellites to
help technology advance.
For everyone - mankind!
Some more curry?
- No.
But you are doing it all there.
I'm doing all that I can here,
at the village grassroot level.
I'm trying to make this a better place!
Gita... you are a typical Indian.
You Indians can't take criticism.
You Indians?
Sorry, I mean... we Indians.
Anyway, we are aware that not
much has changed in a long time.
But I still want to try to make a difference.
You have given up all hope!
Not at all!
Yes, you have.
- No, I haven't.
She's really a fighter, isn't she?
You're no less one yourself.
Now what is to become of this girl?
He was such a nice boy.
There are other boys.
- Yes, there are.
But it's not easy to please Gita.
She has too many expectations.
To top all this, there's the school case.
And until both of these problems are solved,
you won't be able to leave with me.
I have a plan... let's split up the work.
I'm the boy... I mean...
You find a boy, and I will
find children for the school.
We'll solve Gita's problems.
What did you say?
Nothing.
Hail the Lord of Strength!
This is the first lesson in wrestling.
Remember it.
There's no letter for you, Mohan babu.
You're a wrestler as well?
I've been wrestling since I was a child,
and it's my favorite hobby.
- Very good.
Just out of curiosity, until
what grade have you studied?
I mean, you must have worked
very hard to gain this post.
I am a graduate.
How fortunate you are.
- Fortunate... yes.
But I've also studied very
hard to attain this post.
I'm sure you studied hard,
but at least you had the
opportunity to go to high school.
I feel very sorry for the village children.
Why is that?
- I'll explain.
What are your views on the school case?
The school case? It's very simple.
The school must move from here.
That space is needed for the panchayat.
That is why I feel bad for
the children of the village.
Look... the panchayat is not allowing
a high school to be started here.
And what good will it do children
to study only until the 4th standard?
If they want to succeed in life like you,
then they must go to high school!
True.
Look!
It's here the high school will stand.
The children will study here.
Then they can start writing
letters for their parents themselves.
Think about the work it will save you.
I think the school
should not shift from here.
I will talk to people in the village.
You must!
- Definitely.
Praise the Lord of Might.
- Praise the Lord of Might.
Mohan babu...
Yes?
Why don't you drop by our
wrestling ring sometime?
Yeah. Sure, I will!
How about a wrestling session?
Sure!
Mohan babu, I have a surprise for you.
Here... have some pakodas
with shimla mirch tandoori.
Try it, sir. I've made it especially for you.
Is this all you can make?
- No, sir. I can cook whatever you desire.
I understand. Sorry, Mela Ram...
Please don't say a word.
I know what you have on your mind.
- What?
Actually, I was thinking...
you must have felt bad.
I'll give you 60%.
I'll give you 60% in partnership.
Okay.
Your lunch and dinner
will be on the house!
I have changed the name of our dhaba.
We can call it Mohan's Mela Ram Dhaba,
or Mela Ram's Mohan Dhaba.
You decide. Then we'll finalize it.
The first one sounds okay.
Mohan's Mela Ram Dhaba.
Okay then. So, deal done, sir?
But before that, you'll have to help me.
Help? How?
- I'd like to send the kids from...
...your community to the school.
To do this, I'll need your help.
Understood.
But it's little difficult.
Well, then your going to America...
...also looks little "difficult."
It is easy, sir.
I'm ready. Just tell me what I need to do.
Our children and their
kids in the same school?
Lions and sheep never drink water
from the same pool, Mohan babu.
So...
...what is your background?
I mean...
...what caste are you?
I'm a Brahmin.
Then learn to behave like one.
So what am I expected to do?
We've heard that you eat
food cooked by Mela Ram.
Are you aware of what caste he is?
What difference does that make?
What age are you living in?
Don't you dare degrade our piety!
You've fallen - are you out to drag us down, too?
And you, Nivaaran ji, it seems as
though you've switched sides already!
I am only doing what I think is right.
If you have any objections,
you don't have to accept this.
Hey, Birsa! This is Mohan babu.
He wants to have a word with you.
What has happened, sir?
Have we done anything wrong?
No, no.
I just came to ask...
...if you would like to enroll
your children in the school.
Huzoor, those villagers do not
allow us to work in the village.
Do you think they'd agree
to educate our children?
Don't worry.
Your kids will go to school.
But of what use is studying now
that they are of marriageable age?
My daughter Lajwa is going to be engaged.
Child marriage.
Can you not see our situation?
We barely manage to fill our stomachs.
How could their school fees be paid?
Gita ji doesn't run the school for profit.
Teaching is her passion... her life.
If we speak with her,
we can assure you that she will help you.
The village's people don't
want to see us around.
Look...
Let it be, sir.
Education is not in their destiny.
Not in my children's destiny.
What have you decided, Vishno ji?
Studies are not going to
fill an empty stomach, babu!
Since pottery will be their livelihood,
why waste time studying?
Have you made these?
They're very beautiful.
Tell me - how much do you sell this pot for?
Thirty rupees.
- What?
We have a contractor in
the city who buys it from us.
Sometimes we even get an
extra five or ten rupees.
We won't sell it for less than thirty, babu ji!
The price of this pot wouldn't be
less than a hundred rupees in the city.
Maybe if you people were educated,
you wouldn't be fooled like this!
Nivaaran ji. I know that this art has
been passed down through the generations.
I agree that your kids
should carry on this tradition.
But in this day and age, it is
imperative that they be educated.
Is it not, Nivaaran ji?
- Absolutely.
Because education will help them take
this art to its deserving end...
...and earn appropriate prices.
You are selling us a dream!
Don't show us these dreams.
Namaste, Sarpanch ji.
Namaste, Nivaaran ji.
Welcome, Mohan ji.
Mohan babu wanted to
discuss the school with you.
I know, I know.
Bhai, both my grandsons...
...are enrolled in the school.
We have great respect
for education in this house!
But I have heard that you have
two granddaughters as well...
...and that both of them
have dropped out of school.
Oh, yes - Kusum and Suman.
They have both studied
until the fourth grade.
Now, how much more can they study?
It's time for them to learn household work,
cooking and such things.
After all, that's what will help
them once they get married.
How can you say such things?
Education instills confidence in girls.
Don't you want to see
them study and live their lives...
...with self-respect,
independence, and self-reliance?
There's more to a woman
than just wearing bangles.
Agreed, Mohan ji!
But the village doesn't have a high school...
...that they can attend.
But Mizwa village does.
You could have sent them there.
But now you don't need
to worry about that,
because Gita ji is planning to
open a high school in Charanpur.
If she has your support, that is.
Do support us.
Not possible.
But how much longer are you going to control
the children's lives with caste and community?
Who are you to tell us
what we should be doing, bhai?
How much do you know about the
ways and problems of this village?
I accept that you were
born in this country,
but that doesn't mean you
can go around giving sermons.
We understand quite well what we
need to do for the progress of our village.
Yes. But the ones who stand
to lose are the children, right?
Enough arguing!
Father.
For heaven's sake, stay out
of the village matters. Understand?
Anyway, Mohan babu,
you are just a visitor here.
Roam around, enjoy the village...
why get involved in all this?
Attention!
A movie is to be screened in Charanpur.
Tonight, the panchayat has
organized a movie screening in the village.
You must come and watch... you'll enjoy it!
Get down.
Okay, sir. We'll meet later.
Why? Won't you see the movie?
I'll be sitting on this side
and watching the movie.
Okay.
By the way, which film are they showing?
Yaadon ki Baaraat. (Union of Memories)
- Whose union?
Union of Memories.
- Oh. I heard, "our union."
Shut up.
Just kidding. Actually, it's one of my favorite films.
Please turn off your lanterns.
The film is about to begin.
Dear people, kind patrons, and art lovers!
Here's an important announcement:
Parents must keep a watchful eye
on their children during the screening!
And please don't disturb your neighbor.
So, presenting the separation
and union of three brothers!
Todays' movie is...
Yaadon ki Baaraat!
Will you sing the song you do every year?
- Yes.
What happened?
What happened to the movie?
Not a power failure again!
Chikku, it's just temporary.
No, it won't come back! I know it won't.
How much time will this take?
It will take twenty minutes
to start the generator.
Hurry up.
Now don't cry, children!
Everyone quiet!
Sit down.
All the children on the other side, quiet!
Don't cry. Now, listen to me carefully.
Everybody, now look up at the
sky and tell me what you see.
The stars!
Now, tell me... can you see
the stars forming a plough?
Plough?
Yes, a plough.
Do you see it?
No.
- I'll help you.
There...
Can you see the brightest star in the sky?
Can you see it?
- Yes.
Along that star on the right
are three stars in a line.
Yes.
Can you see them?
- Yes.
Now below the third star,
five stars form a curve to the left.
Can you see them?
- Yes.
Now look at them as one.
Look closely. You will see
the plough taking shape.
I can see it!
Yes, plough!
So what we must understand is this:
By observing these stars,
we can make anything we want.
Yet if we look at just one star,
though it may be beautiful...
...it is only a shimmering, solitary star.
This star, that star, every star
Whichever one you see looks lovely
When all these gather together in the night,
the whole sky shimmers!
Twinkling stars, two stars, nine stars,
a hundred stars!
They glitter as one,
but each is a fiery spark!
If you have seen a rainbow,
then tell me, how many colors are there in it?
There are seven colors to speak of,
yet how many shades does the company keep?
Just think, if each of these colors were alone,
how would a rainbow ever form?
Likewise, if we couldn't
manage to unite to fight injustice,
then there would be no community
So don't ask why we are so weak and defeated!
Hmmm... stars, stars!
This star, that star, every star
Whichever one you see looks lovely
When all these gather together in the night,
the whole sky shimmers!
Twinkling stars, two stars, nine stars, a hundred stars!
They glitter as one,
but each is a fiery spark!
Individual drops, joining together,
make a river
Every drop makes the sea;
otherwise, what is this sea?
Understand this puzzle:
A drop existing on its own, just as a drop,
is hardly anything
Were we to forsake others,
turn our backs on everyone,
we would end up feeling incredibly lonely
Why not join together and become a current?
Hmmm... stars, stars
This star, that star, every star
Whichever one you see looks lovely
When all these gather together in the night,
the whole sky shimmers!
Twinkling stars, two stars,
nine stars, a hundred stars!
They glitter as one,
but each star's a fiery spark!
The farmer who ploughs the land
brings forth gold from the earth
The cowherd who raises the cattle
is rewarded with a river of milk
The blacksmith who shapes the iron
makes every tool of his shine
The potter who holds the mud
molds clay into a pot
All these are faces of labor,
desiring to do something
No one has enmity with anyone else
All have the same dreams, all are the same
No one is a stranger to another
This is a simple matter; understand, my friends
Hmmm... stars, stars
This star, that star, every star
Whichever one you see looks lovely
When all these gather together in the night,
the whole sky shimmers!
Twinkling stars, two stars,
nine stars, a hundred stars!
They glitter as one,
but each is a fiery spark!
Gita?
I want to talk to you
about something important.
I can't hold it back any longer.
Go on.
I had recognized you at the bookstore in Delhi.
And I had guessed that you had
come to take Kaveriamma away.
You did not make a mistake
on the way to Charanpur.
I had deliberately given
you the wrong directions.
Really? Why?
Call me childish,
but I did not want you to come here...
...and meet Kaveriamma.
For all that you're doing for the
school, I'd like to thank you.
But I cannot let you take Kaveriamma away.
Why?
You want her so that...
...she can take care of your
house and do all the chores.
How dare you say that?
How can you accuse me of such a motive?
I've traveled 12,000 miles
only out of concern for...
...Kaveriamma's well being.
If you were so concerned,
then where were you when
she was put in an old-age home?
It was I who traced her and brought her here.
Maybe that's because...
...you needed someone to take
care of Chikku and your house.
Why did you come back?
Why did you have to come back?
We were so happy.
And you have everything you need, right?
We only have Kaveriamma.
You are not the only one who loves her.
I know she is like a mother to you...
...and you like a son to her.
But she is a mother to me, too.
And I don't want to become an orphan again.
I understand, Gita.
I will not allow you to take
Kaveriamma away from me.
Kaveriamma will come with me to America.
Whether you like it... or not.
I stuck between a rock and a hard place, Fatima.
Mohan is asking me to go with him,
while Gita expects me to be here.
I just don't know what to do.
Allah knows that when Mohan arrived,
I was so happy for you.
But I never thought things
would get into such a tangle.
You'll have to disappoint
one or the other.
I'm not sure whether I should
go to America with Mohan or not.
I don't understand why he
wants to take you to America.
To work there? Did you ask him?
No, Fatima. He loves me.
He'd take good care of me.
Allah, I hope you are right, Kaveri.
Otherwise, who is to know
what tomorrow has in store?
Kaveri, why don't you ask Mohan to stay here?
No, he won't agree.
Remember one thing...
...every piece of ice inevitably melts in its own water.
Make him understand this perfectly.
We played a lot.
Kaveriamma!
You can stop looking for a groom for me!
I have decided not to get
married at this point.
What did you say?
Yes. I want to focus all my time on
the children and the school's progress.
That's all right, but...
Furthermore, I'm not
yet prepared for marriage.
Well done!
That was a good move
to stall Kaveriamma from leaving.
Though, who'd want to marry you, anyway?
Now, don't get me wrong!
I'm not saying you're not beautiful.
But that attitude, all those
ideals and principles...
Who'd suffer through it?
It's a good thing you've
decided to opt yourself out.
But there is one crazy guy
who might want to marry you.
Yes, Mohan, the precipitation
measurement list has been drawn up.
You understand what I'm saying?
- Yes, Vinod. Yeah.
Okay - we've tested the dual frequency radar,
and the horizontal and vertical resolution is just fine.
Yeah, but the waveforms need to
match with the longitudinal parabolas.
Of course, of course.
They work in alignment.
Nivaaran ji...
Here, speak to Steve.
- Hi, Mohan.
Steve, what about the
geometrical axis function?
Yeah, that's been calibrated.
The baseline parameter's been optimized.
See, the sun-sync orbit needs to be in
alignment with the radiometers of the TRMM.
Okay, I'll make the remaining readings,
and call you in a couple of days?
Okay. Thanks.
Hey, Mohan. So, how's everything else?
Everything is fine. All is well.
So, have you found yourself a village belle?
Actually, you could say I have.
What?
You're kidding me, right?
- No.
Who's she? What's her name?
Her name is Gita.
Kaveriamma lives with her.
I don't believe this.
Except she's no village belle.
She studied in Delhi,
and now she runs a school here.
Anyway...
Have you told her?
Does she know?
How can I tell her?
- What do you mean?
I mean...
I mean she's got a different set
of ideals and all. I like a simple girl.
Come on! You can't make that mistake.
You have to tell her how you feel.
All right. If you say so.
Listen, I'll catch up with you later.
I gotta go now.
Hey... your two weeks are almost up!
Yeah, I know.
I'll be back soon.
You should have been back already.
- Well, let me propose to her first.
I'll be leaving soon.
Catch up with you later. Bye.
Bye.
Gurnaam ji, how much was that?
32 minutes. Is it okay if I pay tomorrow?
- Yes.
My apologies, Mohan babu.
The electricity is problematic here.
Why are you trying to
corrupt Chikku's mind?
What are you talking about?
I don't understand.
Oh, really? Haven't you been talking to
him and his friends about going to America?
No, Gita, I was just explaining...
Am I teaching these kids so that they can go
abroad, settle down, and never come back, like you?
You NRI! Non-Returning Indian.
Hand me the pitcher, please.
You don't even know how to take a bath.
You should learn from Chikku.
Gita, I think you need a change.
Why don't you come back
with me for a vacation?
You are very mischievous, Gita.
Where's the bucket?
Listen...
- No. You listen to me first.
What is it?
- I like you very much... Gitli!
What?
- Yes, Gitli.
I liked the way you disciplined
that man in the bookstore.
Don't try to sweet talk me.
Kaveriamma will stay here... with me!
You're misunderstanding.
I really like you.
Shut up! And don't you try
to corrupt the kids again, okay?
I'm not corrupting anyone.
I'm just bathing.
More than the kids, you're the
one who needs an education!
You can continue calling out
to your Kaveriamma now.
All right now, remove your notebooks.
The topic is general knowledge.
So, who will tell me...
...the names of five of the most
important rivers in the country?
I'm sorry to be late, teacher.
Look ahead.
Today, he'll be taking your class.
First question.
What are the names of five main rivers in India?
You.
Tell me!
Let me think.
Ganga, Jamuna, Narmada...
...Bharati...
...Panchgani...
Bharati? Panchgani?
Are they rivers?
Vidya, you tell me.
Ganga, Jamuna, Narmada...
Godavari and Brahmaputra.
Excellent, Vidya!
Second question.
What is the name of the new state that
has been formed in northwest India?
I know this one.
It was a part of Uttar Pradesh, right?
Yes Chikku. You tell us!
It's Uttaranchal!
- Oh yes, Uttaranchal!
How could I have missed it?
I forgot!
Well done, Chikku!
Now the last question.
If our new student does
not know the answer,
we'll have to demote him to a lower class.
How many lion heads does
the Ashoka pillar have?
This one is easy.
Three.
No! Four!
Excellent, children!
The lesson of the day is...
...before gaining knowledge about foreign lands,
it is important for one to
know one's own country.
Don't forget to do your homework.
The rivers Ganga and Jamuna have
their confluence point in Allahabad.
The new state Uttaranchal...
...is the 27th state of India,
with Dehradun as its capital -
and this is the land where
the Mahabharata was written.
The Ashoka pillar rests
on a circular abacus,
which is guarded by four animals.
The bull by the west side, the elephant by
the east, the horse by the south, and...
...the lion by the north.
Gita, the blackboard is clean.
Gita, I am...
Gita!
But all my answers were correct.
This is Natthu, the potter,
and this is Shankar...
...he makes baskets.
Both of them want us to
admit their children to the school.
What Mohan babu said to us
the other day touched our hearts.
We don't want our
children to suffer like us.
On the morning of Dussehra,
(Indian festival)
you can come and enroll
your children in the school.
Yes, okay.
The tides have begun
to change direction.
Haven't they?
I'm sorry.
Mohan!
- Yes?
Mohan, I have some work for you.
- What work?
There's a place called Kodi
a few miles from here.
Gita has some family property there...
...which has been leased to a
farmer called Haridas.
He has not paid his rent for some months.
I want you to go and collect the money.
Me?
But why do you want me to go?
Can't you send someone else?
If you go and ask, he just might pay up.
Oh! So you want me to be a collector now!
Okay, when should I leave?
I have to fuel up the caravan.
You have to leave now.
- Now?
Yes, and you can't take the caravan there.
- Then?
You will have to take the train
for three hours to Narsinga...
...then a boatjourney across
the river to Maangaon...
...and finally three hours by bus...
and then you'll have reached Kodi!
Sure, that's pretty close by.
- Yes. You'll return by tomorrow evening.
And Mela Ram will go with you.
He knows the way.
Kaveriamma.
- Yes?
My vacation is nearing its end.
What have you decided?
You finish this work first.
Come on, collector saheb.
Why are you sending Mohan?
I sent Haridas a message
only a few days ago.
I know what I'm doing.
Good morning, sir!
- Good morning, Mela Ram.
I'm all set to take you on a
sightseeing trip of the village.
Okay, we're going now.
Mohan bhaiyya, you'll bring
me back a toy, won't you?
Of course. Gimme five... yes!
And what shall I bring back for you?
Nothing.
I know you don't want me to leave,
but I have to go for Kaveriamma.
Now look, don't think about me too much.
I mean, don't miss me too much.
Now what makes you think that I'll miss you?
Your eyes.
They give everything away.
My love, my love
I have become crazy
You have won me over
Oh, my love...
My love, my love
I have become crazy
You have won me over
Oh, my love...
This heart is in turmoil
This body is left to smolder
It's raining dreams
The eyes have found a home
The heart spills over
Oh, my love...
Now that you have come close to me,
now that you have invaded my heart,
how can I express what has happened?
Somewhere, there are blossoming heartbeats
Somewhere, there are paths of dreams
How can I express the joy in my heart?
You've made me lose control
Oftentimes I'm embarrassed
It seems I have forgotten my way
ever since I have seen the city of love
City of love
My love...
I have become crazy
You have won me over
Oh, my love
Now that I have found you,
this whole atmosphere has changed
Flowers have begun to trouble my path
I feel as though the earth is renewed
and a new sky has been formed from our love
The wanton breeze sings a melody
The flowing river narrates a tale
Since our eyes met, my sweetheart,
I have lost my senses
My love...
Haridas ji!
Yes?
I'm Mela Ram and this is
Mohan Bhargav ji.
Tell me what's going on.
Kaveri ji and Gita ji have sent me.
It's about the rent.
I understand.
Come in.
You have traveled a long way.
You must be tired. Please rest.
I think they could do with some bread.
Run along now.
Please come in.
You really shouldn't have bothered.
How is that possible?
A guest is like God.
We've served what we have;
you eat and then we'll talk.
Okay.
If I had the capacity to pay,
I would have come to Charanpur myself.
Sir, I was a weaver before I took up farming.
Since the advent of machine
woven fabrics in the market,
weaving has ceased to
be a lucrative business.
So I became a farmer.
I took Gita ji's land on lease.
I imagined once the crops flourished,
the children's lives would improve.
But it was not to be.
How do you mean?
By taking up farming,
I had changed my profession.
The village elders did not accept this,
and looked upon me as an outcast.
They felt a weaver should remain a weaver,
even if it meant he had to go hungry.
I cried, pleaded...
but no one listened.
Nobody offered a drop of
water to irrigate my land.
The entire crop dried up...
...and whatever survived,
the villagers refused to buy.
It is because of this I've not
been able to pay Gita ji's rent.
But this is wrong.
It's unfair. It's an outrage.
It is the way things work here.
Not enough food to fill our stomachs,
no clothes to wear,
no roof above our heads,
no education for children, no land.
The thirst in my heart alone
knows the taste of my tears.
So what did you do?
What could I do?
I thought about migrating to the city,
hoping life would be better there.
Those who had been there spoke of the anguish.
A laborer goes there to work
and falls into the grip of contractors.
He either returns hungry or never returns.
And soon, his wife has to
sell the little land she has.
No, sir. No.
I couldn't feed my children in this life...
...what is to happen after me?
And about Gita ji's money,
I have nothing to offer
but helplessness and shame.
Nothing...
Thank you for the food, Haridas ji.
Haridas ji, good bye.
Please don't mind. Here's
some money. Keep it.
Mohan babu, it's very kind of you,
but I can't accept it.
Please Haridas ji, I want you to keep it.
When you want, you
can return it to me.
But I don't know when
I will be able repay it.
Don't worry about it.
Here chotu, this is for you.
Share it with your sisters.
Please give Gita ji
and Kaveri ji my respects.
Water for sale... water for sale...
25 paise for a glass...
25 paise for a glass of water...
Saheb, please have a glass of water.
You're back, Mohan.
How was your journey?
Okay.
- Did you meet Haridas?
Yes. But I couldn't get the money.
His situation is pathetic.
He can't pay the rent.
Instead, sir gave him money
from his own pocket before leaving.
I couldn't bear to see Haridas' situation.
I don't think you should
expect any rent from him.
Did you get me my toy, Mohan bhaiyya?
I couldn't get anything.
Come on, Chikku.
Mohan, this is the general state of affairs.
What is money when compared
to the value of human life?
I'm glad you gave him money.
Now, don't be upset, son.
Rest a little.
Kaveriamma!
How do I wrap this around?
Kaveriamma has left for school.
For the decorations.
I don't know why she
wants me to wear this dhoti.
What's wrong with my jeans, anyway?
It is the appropriate thing
to wear on Dussehra.
If you want, I can tie it for you.
How do you know?
Have you ever worn one?
It's not a saree, okay?
Fine, then. Do it yourself.
No! You can tie it.
Just do it quickly, please.
Come here...
Give...
Hold it.
What the...
There, it's done.
Sure, it's done.
But I hope it doesn't
unravel in a crowd. Or else...
Shut up.
Today is the auspicious day of Dussehra.
It was on this day that Lord Rama...
slayed Ravana and marked
the triumph of good over evil.
I am very happy that on this day,
we initiate new students into the school.
May the Goddess of Knowledge be with you.
It's Lajwa.
This is our little granddaughter, Kusum!
Now, go and play!
Hey, Mohan ji, where are you off to?
Why don't you spend some time with us?
I'm impressed. How well you've tied your dhoti!
How did you manage to learn so quickly?
It's pretty easy. It was tied in seconds.
You're looking like a bridegroom.
Thank you.
So, Mohan babu, how long
have you been living abroad?
It's been almost twelve years now.
You must have adapted yourself
completely to their way of living.
Bhai, we would like to know
a thing or two about America.
What can I tell you?
Well, America is a big country...
We've heard that it's also very rich?
It is rich. But there are
several reasons for that.
One among them is that the land
is rich, especially in minerals...
Our land is rich as well, but in crops.
Our strength... lies in our fields.
Do they have problems of rain?
Are they affected by drought and famine like us?
And what about electricity?
They've set up an infrastructure that
provides many resources to the average person.
Electricity, housing, healthy
food, free education, water...
But we have one thing they
don't have and will never have.
What?
Culture and tradition.
Yes, bhai, yes.
And as long as we have them,
no one or thing can destroy us.
Ours is the greatest country in the world!
Yes, bhai!
Culture and tradition is our strong point,
don't you think so?
Munishwar...
I don't think... that Mohan agrees.
Do you, Mohan ji?
You're right.
I don't agree that ours is the
greatest country in the world.
But I do believe that we have the
potential and strength to become great.
Look, these two countries are
politically and culturally very different.
Maybe I shouldn't say this, but since you
have broached the subject, let me tell you that...
...whenever we suspect losing in comparison,
we clutch on to our favorite refuge:
Culture...
...and tradition.
America has progressed
on its own strengths.
They have their own culture
and their own traditions.
It's silly to claim that their culture,
their traditions, and their beliefs are
inferior and ours are commendable.
It's wrong.
But I have heard, son,
that there, they discriminate
against members of certain ethnicities.
Look, sometimes there are clashes.
Where are there not?
But the important part is this:
We also create rifts - based on caste.
You talk as if we have created the
caste, class, religious and social systems.
This hierarchy of caste is
ancient, as is culture and religion.
And color and creed.
And listen, one's caste is
a thing that can never die!
Just because a custom is
ancient does not mean it is right.
Why are you imposing your
views on us, Mohan babu?
I'm not imposing any views.
I am only expressing myself, speaking of
things I've noticed while living here.
I've realized that we keep
fighting amongst ourselves...
...when we should be fighting against
illiteracy, overpopulation, and corruption.
Every day, in our streets and homes,
every one of us keeps saying that...
...that this country has gone to the dogs.
That this country is on the path to destruction.
And if we keep saying just this,
we will actually end up there one day.
You'll need to do something to stop this.
You too.
Not just the members of the
panchayat, but everyone in the village.
You are blaming the members of
the panchayat for your problems.
But if you stepped into their shoes, you'd
do the same thing. This applies to me, too.
The dalits blame the brahmins,
and brahmins claim that their
piety is spoiled by the dalits.
The blacksmith and potter blame the moneylender.
The landowners blame the tenants,
but they don't give them their rights.
In what way are we great, then?
If we have problems in the village,
we point our finger at the state...
...and the state at someone else.
We all are finding fault with each other!
The fact is that we're all to be blamed.
Because the problem... is us.
Me... you...
...all of us.
Have you lost your head?
What are you saying?
All I know is that...
...a weaver who changed his
occupation by becoming a farmer...
...cannot feed his family...
...or give his children an education.
He can only watch them die of starvation.
Every moment weighs terribly,
we're struck by a calamity
Save me, oh king of the Raghu race
Come, oh hero of the Raghu race;
Lord Ram, please come!
Lord of my heart,
my Sriram, please come!
I keep repeating the name of the Lord,
hear it and come
I chant your name;
please listen, Ram!
Let the truth ring out loud
Burn Lanka of its sins
Come at once and liberate me;
listen to my woes
Every moment weighs terribly,
we're struck by a calamity
Save me, oh king of the Raghu race
Forget Ram, look!
Raavan has come
His mighty shadow is found in all creation
Why do you chant the name of Ram?
Why do you take the name of Ram?
This "Ram, Ram" you've started...
Sita!
What have you found so worthy in Ram?
How can one count all his virtues?
Where are there so many words?
Who can reach the summits
where my Ram sits?
In the whole world,
he is the highest being, the supreme spirit
Stronger than all and yet patient
But now his patience has reached its limit
Raavan, there's still time - ask for forgiveness!
Let the truth ring out loud
Burn Lanka of sins
When King Ram arrives, we will bow down to him;
with him will come his devoted brother, Lakshman!
Every moment weighs terribly,
we're struck by a calamity
Save me, oh king of the Raghu race
If Ram holds strength,
if Ram possesses courage,
why has he not come yet to protect you?
He whose descriptions
you never tire of giving -
tell me, where is your
Ram at this very minute?
Ram is in my every heartbeat
Ram is in my soul, Ram is in my life itself
Ram is in every moment of mine,
Ram is in my every breath
Ram is in every hope of mine; Ram is what I long for
Ram is in compassion, Ram is in peace
Ram is in unity, Ram is in progress
Ram lives in the minds of
followers and enemies alike
Forsake sin, Raavan, Ram is in your heart
Ram in your heart, Ram is in my heart
Ram is in every home, Ram is in every courtyard
Whoever removes Raavan from
their heart will find Ram there
Every moment weighs terribly,
we're struck by a calamity
Save me, oh king of the Raghu race
Listen, Ram is coming
My Ram is coming
King Ramchandra is coming;
Lord Ramchandra is coming
Look Lord Ram has come,
Mine Lord Ram has come
Ram is coming, my Ram is coming
Siyavar Ramchandra Ki... Jai!
(Glory to Lord Ramchandra)
The burning Raavan is looking
prettier in the darkness.
Every moment weighs terribly, we're struck by a calamity!
Save me, oh king of the Raghu race!
Listen. Quiet! Be quiet, please. Please.
Why is it I feel...
...that you all have started
to enjoy living in this darkness?
You've adjusted to it, no?
For how long are you going to
take your problems lying down?
But what else can we do, Mohan ji?
Will you do as I ask?
Have you once again come up
with some strange solution?
Please, have mercy on us, bhai!
Wait, Munishwar.
What do you want us to do?
There's a spring on
that nearby mountain, right?
Yes, there is. So?
So I need a hundred men.
A hundred men?
You will have them.
You will have a hundred men.
Thank you, Dada ji.
Sir, one hears lightning struck
this spot several years ago.
Since then, there has
been this gush of water.
I wonder what he's up to!
Look at this. This is point A1.
We'll build a reservoir here.
I mean, a water tank.
The water will accumulate here.
From here, there will be a
pipe that leads to point A3.
A3 will have a shed with a
turbine - I mean, machine.
When the pipe's water falls on the
turbine, it will rotate with great speed.
And if everything goes well,
electricity will be generated.
We'll form four groups.
The blacksmiths will cast the molds for the pipes.
The second and third groups will do
the digging work for the tank and so on.
Now, let's form the groups.
Fast!
This boy looks promising!
Surely seems like it.
The reservoir will be made here.
Five meters long and one meter wide.
I mean, five arms' lengths by one arm's length.
For this, we will have to clear
out all the stones and bushes.
Is that clear?
-Yes.
It's seven feet and six inches.
May I try it?
Where's Mela Ram?
What is this?
- From boot to suit - total American, sir!
But why?
Now that we are going
to do business together,
I thought that I should
look like a 40% partner!
This is my passport and this is
my VISA form, fully filled out!
Once it's stamped...
Baloo, show him an
alternator powered 24 watts.
Please come in, sir.
Here's your water, Dada ji.
- Thank you, Santaram.
How's work progressing on the hill?
It's going well.
How long will it take?
- It will be completed very soon.
You take a rest.
I'll leave you now.
Jai Ram ji ki.
By the way, Vinod, will the turbine
principle work in power generation?
Yeah. Why do you ask?
You know what? I am trying
to generate electricity here.
Electricity? What the hell
are you talking about?
No, no, Vinod. I'm lighting a bulb here.
John is beginning to lose it by the day.
Speak to John, and
buy me some more time.
We've started working nights.
- Come on, Vinod - handle it for me!
I'll talk to you later. Okay?
Bye.
- Bye.
25 into 75 is equal to...
- 1875.
23.3 into 33.9.
789.87... 790.
Yeah, just a moment...
I'm about to finish this.
I've fallen in love with you.
What did you say? Come again.
See! Just see!
It's you and me, and long solitude!
How delicate these shadows are!
Listen, just listen! Listen to the heartbeats
Listen, just listen! Listen to the song of silence
Listen, just listen! Listen to what the night says!
Night's come
with desires nameless and many
She tells so many stories - I listen
Night is stretching her limbs
Some unusual words are said;
like strewn pearls, I pick them up
What you just said
has made my eyes light up with flames
has taken away the darkness from my nights
Mela Ram, ready?
- Ready, sir!
Release the valve!
Release the value further!
Good!
The water will gush to this
turbine through this pipe.
The turbine will rotate with the force of water.
With this steering wheel,
we can control the water flow.
We need to release enough water
to make this pulley rotate,
and make this alternator spin
at the speed of 1,500 RPM.
And if this happens,
electricity will be generated.
Without you, the days and nights were lonely
Life was overcast with desolation
Now the days shine and the nights are sweet
for you are my companion
Without you I was incomplete; now I am whole
In you, I discovered my world,
yet I have lost myself
Now we both realize what living is all about
What life was like and what it's like now
Now we both realize how wonderful the world is
We have so much happiness
What are you all doing?
There will be electricity in
your house, Dadi Setu!
The wires are up.
Now, all that we have to do is wait.
Ready?
- Ready, sir!
Nivaaran ji, okay?
Yes, Mohan babu.
Mela Ram, release the water!
- Okay, sir!
Nivaaran ji?
Open the valve... slowly.
Electricity will be generated at 230 volts.
Come on...
Nivaaran ji. The valve is fully open, right?
- Yes, Mohan babu.
Mela Ram! Is the valve fully open?
Fully open, sir! Totally open!
Sure?
- Sure!
Gita, come here.
Hold this state.
Hold it.
If the valve is fully open,
how come there's no pressure?
Has the pressure increased?
Yes!
Jafar bhai, how many RPM?
800, sir.
I say, how long now for the electricity?
Have patience, Munishwar - patience.
Electricity.
Bhai Mohan ji, we have done it!
Electricity for our own village.
Generated with our toil and sweat.
Just like this project, we must
think of newer, innovative ways...
...to solve our village's problems.
Sarpanch ji, come quickly!
Dada ji's health has deteriorated.
Dada ji...
Electricity? Is it here?
Yes.
The day...
...I saw you...
...I felt...
...something special about you.
Now that you're here...
...I can...
...die in peace.
But Mohan, you've already been away
for five weeks. This really isn't right.
I'm extremely sorry, John. I've just been
caught up with some personal work and...
We are in Phase II of core design here.
There can't be any further delays.
I understand, John. I've just finished
with what I needed to do here, and...
...and I'll be back in three days.
Three days it is.
- Of course, John. Yes... I will.
What surprises me is how
you can think of going...
...after all that you have seen and learnt here.
It's true, Gita.
I have learnt so much here, gained so much here.
Felt the problems here...
...but I cannot live here.
And I cannot live elsewhere.
I want to marry you...
...but I won't go to America.
You're not going to come with me. Right?
Mohan, I've given it lot of thought.
At this age, I wouldn't be able to adopt
the ways and customs of another place.
I am happy here.
Now that you are leaving...
...I will miss you very much.
If you stayed here, our family
would have been complete.
Goodbye.
Live long.
Mohan ji,
we had forgotten that you were a guest.
A visitor must leave one day.
We'll miss you very much, Mohan babu.
When you come back, bhai,
you'll be sure to find Internet
in the Charanpur Post Office.
Every kid will e-mail you!
We just need to have our wrestling match.
I am sorry, Mela Ram, that
I have to leave suddenly.
But I'll definitely send you
the sponsorship papers.
No, sir.
I don't need them anymore. I'm fine here.
Mohan babu, your presence in the
village has changed things around here.
Some things have clearly changed.
But... have you forgotten about
your plan to immigrate to America?
When the vine crawling along your
wall crosses onto another's property,
individual homes are lost.
It's like a lamp on your porch,
giving light to neighbor's house.
All the best, sir.
Thank you, Mela Ram.
Mohan bhaiyya, this is for you.
I will put this up in my house.
Look, study hard. Right?
Where is Gita?
I haven't seen her around since morning.
I have to leave now...
...or else I'll miss my flight.
- Okay.
Please explain to her.
Go, son. My love and
blessings are always with you.
Don't worry.
Bye, Mohan bhaiyya.
You're impossible, Gita.
You're here, and I...
...I've been looking for you all over.
I did not want to talk to
you in front of everyone else.
I'm upset with your decision,
but I can understand your predicament.
I can understand.
Gita, I can understand how you feel, too...
...but please don't mistake
my helplessness for betrayal.
I did not mean to hurt you...
- Mohan.
I love you.
I want you to be happy wherever you are.
This is for you.
What is this?
Open it.
What's all this?
A collection of our culture and traditions.
Little flowers of our faith.
Our fields...
...greenery...
...rivers...
...our customs.
All these will keep reminding you of us.
And maybe...
...maybe persuade you to return.
Don't go. Please, don't go.
And as we can see, we have some
points here that the satellite travels...
...along the way to capture
data of the Global Precipitation.
Next we're going to see the
trajectory of the GPM instrument,
as it goes from Australia...
India... and the United States.
This land of yours
is your motherland
She calls out to you
This is a bond that can never be broken
The scent of the soil:
How can you forget it?
No matter where you wander,
you'll always come back
In new paths,
in every sigh,
to your lost heart
someone will say:
"This land of yours
is your motherland
She calls out to you
This is a bond that
can never be broken"
Life itself
is telling you, traveler:
"You have accomplished everything;
what's left now?"
Happiness has been showered upon you
but you're far from your home
Come back now, fool,
to where someone would
consider you their own
and call out to you!
This country...
this land of yours
is your motherland
She calls out to you!
This is a bond that can never be broken
Now that you're here...
I can... die in peace.
It's like a lamp on your porch,
giving light to neighbor's house.
I've made up my mind, Vinod.
I must go back.
Not again.
How can you go all the way back for the girl?
Just persuade her to come here.
It's not like that, Vinod.
It's not only about Gita and Kaveriamma.
This moment
conceals within it
a whole century
of life
Don't you dare ask why the road
forks into two diverging paths
You are the one to choose which path,
you are the one to choose which direction you take
This land
This land of yours
is your motherland!
She calls out to you!
This is a bond that can never be broken
I understand.
Just because you lit a bulb,
you now have delusions of sparking
a revolution throughout the country.
You're being foolishly romantic!
Let's leave aside sentiments.
Have you figured out what
you are going to do there?
I have a few ideas.
- Like?
I could be a Project Manager for
Vikram Sarabhai Space Center.
I can... I can work in
tandem with NASA from there.
There's a lot to be done there.
You're impossible!
I can't understand you.
If you can't understand
after hearing all this, then...
...then maybe it's pointless
explaining anything to you.
You'll have to go there
and see things for yourself.
Otherwise, you'll never understand.
We're just a few minutes away now
from the launch of the GPM spacecraft,
on an important scientific mission to...
...better understand the
global water cycle here on earth.
GPM will allow improvements in
predicting precipitation forecasts,
and better predict flood hazards.
We are not tracking any
technical problems at this time.
All systems are "go" on the launch vehicle.
Weather forecast is very good for today.
Just a few minutes away from
launching the GPM spacecraft.
This spacecraft will be
able to give us information...
...that will help us better predict precipitation.
It also will help us in understanding the...
...global water cycles and fresh water availability.
In addition, we can better predict flood hazards.
T minus 20 seconds.
T minus 15 seconds.
T minus 10... 9... 8... 7... 6...
We have a "go" for main engine start.
3... 2... booster ignition...
...and liftoff!
John, I tried to knock
some sense into his head.
I tried to convince
him not to leave, but...
Mohan, you do realize
what you are going to lose.
John, I know what I'm going to gain.
But you're aware you
could have gone places.
I am going places.
All right, Mohan.
Go light your bulb.
Nobody has ever thrown me like this.
Where did you learn those
wrestling tricks, Mohan babu?
Where there is a will, there is a way.
After all, a coward changes his attitude
in the company of another coward.
Do you understand now?
Excellent match, Mohan babu!