My father died suddenly.
I only found out last night.
The mayor called to tell me.
I couldn't believe it.
My hometown is in the mountains...
a village called Sanhetun.
I left to work in the city.
So busy I haven't been home in years.
My father was
the village schoolteacher.
He taught there all his life.
I am an only child.
The only one from our village
who went to college.
I am very worried about my mother.
Come in and rest a while.
I've got to get back.
Thank your boss again for me.
- Thank you.
- Good-bye.
Mother?
- Mother?
- Yusheng.
Mayor, Uncle Xia.
I saw the car and
knew you were back.
Come in.
It's warmer inside.
Please. Sit down.
I couldn't tell you much
over the phone.
Now you're here
I can explain everything.
It's the schoolhouse.
For many years your father
has wanted to rebuild it...
but there were always
reasons we couldn't.
He brought it up
again recently...
and the village agreed.
We have the materials we need
but not enough money.
Your father's mind was set.
He was determined to find the money.
He began traveling around,
trying to borrow the money.
He went all over the county.
If he thought there was a chance,
he'd go after it.
On the last trip,
on his way home...
he ran into a snowstorm,
a big blizzard.
He was stuck in the storm,
and he got sick.
He was too sick to be moved.
That made him more anxious.
He was in bad shape
when he got back...
so we took him to the hospital.
They examined him,
said he had a heart problem.
We've known your dad
all these years.
Who knew he had
a heart condition?
They tried treating him,
but it was no use.
He fought,
but he didn't make it.
Where is my father now?
At the provincial hospital,
in the morgue.
That's why we wanted
you to return.
To tell you all this.
Last time I spoke with him
he seemed fine.
It was a bad storm.
At his age,
it was too much for him.
It would have been
hard on anyone.
The village wants
to arrange a car...
to bring your father back.
Bring him back here to bury him.
That's what we planned.
That's fine. Go ahead.
But there is a problem.
Your mother doesn't
want to use a car.
She wants your father
to be carried back.
What do you mean?
She wants the coffin
brought back on foot...
so your father
won't forget his way home.
It's an old tradition,
a superstition.
And she wants to walk with us.
- So let's do it.
- We want to.
He was our village teacher.
Everyone respects him.
But our young people
have all left for the city.
They've gone away to work.
Only old people
and children are left.
We thought of using a tractor.
We could make the trip
in half a day.
You must help
your mother decide.
I appreciate your concern.
I will talk it over with her.
- Good.
- Where is she?
Probably at the schoolhouse.
She's there every day
since he died.
- She won't listen to anyone.
- She just sits there.
- Is she okay?
- I think so.
I am only afraid...
- The old schoolhouse?
- Yes.
I'll go to her.
Mother.
It's so cold.
Let's go home, okay?
Your father is dead.
Let's go home.
You will never see him again.
Get on the bed
where it's warm.
Bring me my loom.
What for?
- I want to weave something.
- Weave what?
A cloth for your father's coffin.
Don't trouble yourself.
Why don't we go buy one instead?
I don't want to buy one.
That loom is so old.
It's been broken for years.
Why can't we fix it?
You need rest, Mother.
You must be so tired.
I have to make this cloth.
Can't I just buy one?
No! Just bring me the loom.
The only loom
left in the village...
is this one of your mother's.
She's guarded it like a treasure.
Looks like she's
determined to use it.
Just like the funeral procession.
Carrying the dead is an old custom.
Over the mountains...
across the river,
past the crossroads.
And we shout at him along the way.
What do we say?
We tell him
this is the road home.
Everyone yells at him,
so that he remembers his way home.
It's an old tradition.
Is it really so difficult...
to do as my mother wishes?
It is a problem, yes.
We don't have the manpower.
All our young people have left.
No one has followed this custom...
since the Cultural Revolution.
I don't want her
to work like this...
but I don't know
how to stop her.
The funeral procession...
seems all that matters to her now.
I know about your wishes
for the funeral.
Yes.
Is there some other way
to arrange it?
I know it won't be easy.
But your father
lived here for 40 years.
He taught many
generations of kids.
He worked very hard.
Long, long hours.
The town should give him
something back.
The mayor agrees with you.
How about this?
We can walk alongside...
with the coffin
pulled by a tractor.
We'd still be with him, right?
It's not the same.
I want your father
carried back by the men.
If they won't help...
we'll get someone who will.
Please don't work anymore.
I have to.
I have to finish it.
You are tired.
Get some rest, okay?
You sleep in
your father's study.
I have to finish this.
This picture was taken the year
my parents married.
My father was not
from the village.
He came here to teach.
The story of
my parents'courtship...
is well known in the village.
Practically everyone here
has heard about it.
My mother had just
turned eighteen.
My father was twenty.
My mother told me
my father arrived by horse cart.
This is our new teacher.
His name is Luo,
Luo Changyu.
Is that Di?
What's all the racket for?
Nothing.
Has the teacher arrived?
Yes.
It's about time
we got our own teacher.
What does he look like?
He's a young man.
A young teacher?
He must be talented.
- Where is he staying?
- At the village council office.
That's good.
Where will he eat?
He'll eat with
a different family each day.
When it's our turn,
we'll have to make a good meal.
What are you doing?
Nothing.
Seeing a teacher
has you changing clothes?
My grandmother
was already blind by then.
Mother says when
Grandfather died...
Grandmother cried
until she went blind.
After Grandfather died...
there was only Mother
to look after Grandmother.
Grandmother's only wish
was to find a good husband for Mother.
She had many proposals...
but my mother
didn't like any of them.
The schoolhouse was not yet built
when my father arrived.
The mayor enlisted
all the men's help.
According to our village custom...
a red cloth must be hung
in a new building.
It's hung on the ceiling beam
for good luck.
The cloth is called
the lucky red banner.
It must be woven by the village's
most beautiful maiden.
This task, of course,
fell to my mother.
Perhaps she was already
a little in love...
because the cloth she made
was especially fine.
The village had
two wells back then.
The old well was
called the "front well."
The newer well was
called the "back well."
The new well was nearer the village,
so more people used that one.
After my father arrived...
Mother started
to use the old well.
She had to pass
the schoolhouse to get to it.
The village had another custom.
When putting up a new building...
each family prepared a dish
for the workers'lunch.
Everyone contributed.
Mother prepared
all her best dishes...
hoping Father
would eat what she made.
Back then when
something was built...
women were not
allowed to participate.
Superstition said
they would bring bad luck.
When they put up the school,
the village women could only watch...
from a distance.
- What did you make today?
- Steamed bread.
- What about you, Di?
- I made onion cakes.
I brought rice
steamed in lotus leaves.
Onion cakes are better.
Did you save some
for your boyfriend?
Shut up!
Look at them.
They just pick up the first dish
they see. They don't know who made what.
I don't know who's eating mine.
Must be your husband!
Put them here.
You're already done
with the banner?
I was going to come get it from you.
Give it to me.
Okay.
You'll save me a further trip.
This is a beautiful banner.
The school is almost finished.
Chinese study will be
the first lesson.
- Is the teacher happy with the food?
- Yes.
- Does he eat what we make?
- He eats together with you?
- No.
He's a city gentleman.
It's not proper for him
to eat with us.
So, how does it work?
We give him first pick
of the dishes.
"In life..." Follow me.
"In life..."
"You must make goals."
Start from the beginning.
"One must learn to write."
"One must learn arithmetic."
"Keep a journal faithfully."
"Know the present, know the past."
When I was young,
my mother told me...
my father had a beautiful voice.
My mother never learned to write,
was never interested in school.
But she couldn't resist the sound
of my father's voice.
She went by the school
every day after that.
For most, the novelty of the new school
wore off after a while...
but not for my mother.
For 40 years,
she came to listen...
and it became part of her life.
"Know respect for your elders."
Each day after school...
my father walked
some of his students home.
Knowing this,
my mother waited along the way.
The birds sing
with the beautiful sun
Their songs wake
the beautiful flowers
Hey!
- Who is she?
- That's Zhao Di.
Is she from Sanhetun?
Yes.
Di, the teacher
is asking about you!
- You need water?
- Yes.
- Let me get it for you.
- No, that's okay.
- Let me do it.
- I can do it. Thanks.
No, let me. Let me help you!
You're the teacher.
You shouldn't bother.
- Let me do it.
- No, no.
Come on.
Di, you're fetching
water as well?
Tomorrow it's our turn
to have you over.
I know.
My father told me...
the first time
he went to my mother's house...
she stood in the doorway.
Leaning against the door frame...
she looked like
a figure in a painting...
an image he would never forget.
- Is the teacher here?
- Yes.
Your heavy footsteps
gave you away.
Come in. Come here.
My mother's eyesight
is not good.
This teacher is very tall.
Sit down.
Can't think when we last
had a man home for dinner.
The food must taste good to you.
You sound like you're enjoying it.
How long have you been here?
About a month.
Have you gotten used to it?
- It's okay.
- That's good.
- You're from the city?
- Yes, from East Gate.
How did you choose Sanhetun?
After graduation,
I couldn't find work.
One day in the street
a man was signing people up.
I didn't know what for,
but I signed up anyway.
And I ended up here.
- Do you regret it?
- No.
Why?
I like it here.
Are you married?
No.
Are you engaged?
Di will do it.
Sit for a while.
Do you remember this bowl?
This design?
No, I don't remember.
Did you eat the food
brought to the site?
Yes.
Looks like Di's hard work
was wasted.
You know...
when you were
building the school...
she made all her best dishes.
She always used that bowl...
hoping you would choose her dish.
Even I wasn't allowed to help.
I remember now.
You do?
The bowl and your cooking
are familiar.
- So you ate from it before?
- Yes.
You did? What did you eat?
On the first day
I made onion cakes.
On the second,
scrambled eggs and onions on rice.
On the third day,
mushroom dumplings.
What a shame.
Three delicious meals.
And I love mushroom dumplings.
I'll make you some
this afternoon.
- That is too much to ask.
- No.
You've hardly finished lunch,
and you're planning the next meal.
Di, show the teacher out.
He must be very busy.
Yes, I should go.
That red jacket of yours
is pretty on you.
I remember it
from the day I arrived.
Don't forget to come back
for dumplings.
You shouldn't make the dumplings.
- Why not?
- You may regret it.
- Why?
- You don't understand.
This teacher is a nice man...
but he's out of our class.
What are you talking about?
It's only dumplings.
Don't play dumb.
I'm just being honest.
You'd best forget about him.
I will not go back!
You've got no choice!
I came to say good-bye.
- Where are you going?
- Back to the city.
- What's happened?
- Nothing.
I saw you argue with someone.
Was that what it was about?
Who was he?
Why do you have to go back?
It's no big deal. They just want
to ask me some questions. That's all.
- Can't they ask you questions here?
- He says it's not up to him.
Will you come back?
Of course!
I have classes to teach.
When will you be back?
By the 27 th at the latest.
On the 28th the school holiday starts.
I have to be back before that.
- Come in and eat something.
- I can't.
I have things to do before I go.
I really do.
That man is waiting for me.
Tell him to come too.
You have to eat in any case.
Okay, I'll be back.
I'll wait for you.
This is for you.
To go with your red jacket.
I'll be waiting.
What is going on?
No more class?
- He's in some political trouble.
- Political trouble?
I don't understand it either.
But maybe it's nothing.
Said he might be back
in a day or two.
The teacher's left.
- The teacher's left?
- Yes.
- Just left?
- Just left with the mayor.
My mother retraced her steps
every day...
searching back and forth.
She had to find the clip
my father had given her.
Pottery repairs!
Please come in.
I charge for the nails I use.
This will cost you
more than buying a new bowl.
Just tell me how much
and I'll pay you.
Is it a family heirloom?
No.
It belonged to someone special?
You could say that.
Who?
It's for my daughter.
The man who used it left...
and took my daughter's heart
with him.
I've put it back together again.
I hope she'll be happy.
Pottery repairs!
Di, what are you doing?
Nothing. Just getting
a drink of water.
1 times 8 equals 8.
1 times 9 equals 9.
2 times 2 equals 4.
2 times 3 equals 6.
2 times 4 equals 8.
2 times 5 equals 10.
2 times 6 equals 12.
2 times 7 equals 14.
2 times 8 equals 16.
2 times 9 equals 18.
Good.
3 times 3 equals 9.
3 times 4 equals 12.
3 times 5 equals 15.
3 times 6 equals 18.
3 times 7 equals 21.
3 times 8 equals 24.
3 times 9 equals 27.
My father told my mother...
when he was teaching the kids...
he could always look up
and see the red banner.
When he saw that banner...
it reminded him of Mother
and her red jacket.
The mayor kept insisting...
that the ceiling
needed proper insulation...
but my father never let him.
That's why the school ceiling
was never completed.
Mother sat in the classroom
for hours that day.
The door was open,
and the mayor saw her there.
He understood what that meant.
Once he knew...
the news got round
the village quickly.
Back then, arranged matches
were the rule.
The freedom of falling in love
was unfamiliar.
This was a first for our village.
On the day my father
promised to return...
my mother was waiting
from first light.
She remembered his promise...
that he would return on the 27th.
School vacation
began on the 28th.
He had to be back before that.
It's so cold out. Where have you been?
Gone all day. Get warm on the bed.
You're burning up!
I know you went
to wait for the teacher.
Everyone says he's in trouble
and won't be back.
You've got to let go.
I'm going to the city
to find him.
Are you crazy? You're ill!
Di! Come back!
My mother didn't make it
to the city.
She fainted by the road.
Someone saw her,
and they got word to the mayor.
The mayor and my uncle
brought her home on a cart.
The mayor said that day
my mother's hands were like ice.
While on the cart,
they wrapped her in a heavy blanket...
but they couldn't
get her hands warm.
I don't think it's too serious.
It's a bad chill,
but she is strong.
Mayor, is the teacher coming back?
I don't know the answer.
He should have been back by now.
Maybe someone can write to him.
I don't know how to help her...
if he doesn't come back.
"Spring is here."
"It melts the snow."
"The grass turns green."
"The farmers sow."
"The ox plow the field."
"The wild geese return."
"The frogs begin to hop."
Di, you're awake.
You've been sleeping
for two days.
Di, the teacher is back.
He came back yesterday.
He came straight here.
He sat with you for a long time.
Isn't it good news?
He came back for you.
"Full of energy."
"Our spirit comes alive."
"It carries our wishes."
"Full of hope."
"Spring is here."
"It melts the snow."
"The grass turns green."
"The farmers sow."
"The ox plow the field."
"The wild geese return."
"The frogs begin to hop."
"Swallows start to sing."
"Spring is the season to sow."
"All starts to grow again."
"The world is full of life again."
Mr. Luo!
Mr. Luo, Di is here to see you!
Sir!
Di is here!
That evening,
my father had to leave again.
When he heard about my mother,
he left the city without permission.
He couldn't stand it any longer,
so he sneaked back.
For this disobedience...
my parents were kept apart
for another two years.
Someone told me...
that on the day my father
finally returned...
my mother put on her red jacket,
my father's favorite...
and stood by the road
to wait for him.
From that day on,
my father never left my mother again.
This is the story
of my father and my mother.
This road is part
of their love story...
this road that leads
from the city to our village.
Maybe because of the hope
it held for her...
as she waited for
my father to return...
she wants to walk this way
with him one last time.
Mr. Mayor?
- Who is it?
- It's me, Yusheng.
- You need to see me?
- Yes.
Come in. Come in.
It's cold out there.
How can I help you?
I've thought it through.
- I want to do as my mother wishes.
- To carry him back?
It's still a problem though.
The problem is
not enough men, right?
How about this?
We'll hire men from the next village.
That's a good idea.
But how do we pay them?
Just tell me how many men we need.
For a short distance, only ten...
but this is a long trip.
I think we need about 16.
We will need two shifts.
That's 32 men.
And we'll need others
to carry chairs...
so people can rest along the way.
That comes to about 35, 36 men.
How much per person?
100 Yuan each should do.
That will do.
35, 36 people.
How much in total?
That's 3,500 or 3,600 Yuan.
We need to buy cigarettes.
And wine too.
Got to ward off the cold.
We'll also want a little extra
for emergency use.
Altogether, around 4,000 Yuan.
Here's 5,000 Yuan.
Is that enough?
It's more than enough.
Mrs. Luo, come and see Mr. Luo.
Please don't cry.
Don't let tears fall on him.
Mr. Luo, we are
going back to the village.
That day over 100 people
came to the ceremony.
The mayor told me
they were my father's students.
They heard about his death,
and they all came back.
Many came from other towns.
Some drove from the city.
The mayor said some came
from as far as Guangzhou.
Some tried but didn't make it in time
because of the snowstorm.
I didn't recognize many of them.
Many were older than me.
I don't know when
my father taught them.
I didn't know
how to address them.
Anyway, as the mayor said,
they are all my father's students.
Take this money back.
Why? Didn't you pay the men?
They won't take it, not even the ones
we hired. No one wants the money.
Take it back.
At my mother's request...
my father was buried
next to the old well.
The village has running water now,
so no one needs a well.
No one draws water from it now.
My mother says from this hill
my father can look down on the school.
She asks to be buried next to him
when the time comes.
After my father's funeral,
the mayor came...
to talk about
rebuilding the school.
The city has granted funds...
and the village families
have donated money.
He says we must fulfill
my father's wishes.
Your money. Give it to me.
Mayor, we've saved
over the years.
Take it to rebuild the school.
I can't take it.
With my husband gone,
you have to take it.
All right. I'll take it then.
You are the first
but surely not the last to help.
I am leaving tomorrow.
Mother has asked me to go
to the schoolhouse one last time.
My mother says
the next time I come back...
the school we know will be gone.
Your father helped
build this school.
He taught here so many years.
Spent as much time
here as at home.
Changyu, can you hear me?
The mayor will
rebuild the school.
They'll build a tall...
and wonderful school...
just as you wished.
They will start
building next spring.
You won't have
to worry anymore.
When the school is completed...
I will hang
a lucky red banner there.
You can rest easy now.
You know, your father
was a sincere man.
He always wanted you
to become a teacher...
to take over for him.
You went to
the teachers' college...
but you never taught
a day of class.
If you could teach
for one day...
I think it would
make him happy.
Then you can go back
to your life.
Look, there's no teacher now...
no sound of children
reciting their lessons.
The mayor said a new teacher
was on the way.
Not many teachers...
would sound as good
as your father.
After 40 years
I still love that voice.
I can still hear it.
Mother, I've been thinking.
Why don't you come
to the city with me?
No, thank you.
I won't leave your father.
How can I leave you here alone?
Don't worry about me.
I can take care of myself.
Are you doing
all right in the city?
Yes. Don't worry about me.
Do you have a girlfriend?
Let's not talk about it.
You're not young anymore.
Don't be so picky.
Listen to me.
Find yourself a nice girl...
and bring her home to meet me.
Your father's gone.
He used to worry about you.
Our children must leave home.
We can't keep you here forever.
As parents...
we let you go...
but we never stopped worrying.
Your father...
missed you so.
Please don't cry.
With your father gone,
it's hard not to feel lonely.
I know.
You must work hard
and make a good life.
"One must learn to read and write."
"Keep a journal faithfully."
"Know the present, know the past."
"Spring, summer, fall, winter.
Four seasons in a year."
"East, west, south, north."
"In everything there is a purpose."
I gathered the students
early that morning.
I told them I would teach them
for one day.
The mayor asked me why.
I said it was for my mother
and for my father too.
I stood in my father's place...
where he stood for so many years.
I felt sure he could hear my voice
and those of the students.
The book I am using
is the same one he used that first day.
It is not a textbook.
It is a book he wrote himself.
"One must learn to read and write."
"Keep a journal faithfully."
"Know the present, know the past."
"Spring, summer, fall, winter.
Four seasons in a year."
"East, west, south, north."
"In everything there is a purpose."
"Know respect for your elders."