♪
Come on in, son.
Come on.
Go on, close the door.
That book I gave you, kevin,
have you finished it yet?
Not yet, brother
mac, almost though.
What do you think,
do you like it?
Yeah, I likes it a lot.
Like, kevin, like.
I like it a lot.
Not I likes.
You know when we goes
to confession, I mean go,
well, I was wondering, do the
brothers go to confession too?
Indeed we do, my boy.
We confess our sins,
ask the lord
for his forgiveness,
we say our hail marys,
just like everybody else.
It was a dark, dark night.
And there was
a bit of a wind up,
just enough
to rustle the leaves.
Can we make that sound,
rustling leaves? Come on.
How does that sound?
That's it, that's it.
Now, uncle jim
was afraid of no man,
but there was something about
that night that made him uneasy.
When he came around the bend,
he saw a light in the middle
of a bridge he had to cross.
And the closer he got, the
brighter the light shone out.
When uncle jim put one foot
on that bridge,
he froze like a pillar, because
the light was coming toward him.
It was just...
suspended in the air
and coming closer and closer.
So moved to one side
and the light moved with him.
Then he moved to the other side,
and the light moved as well.
Then that light
came rushing at him,
and uncle jim,
the same uncle jim
who was afraid of no man,
was so scared
that he ran off the bridge
and took shelter underneath it.
What's this?
Someone come to help me?
Come on, my son, you're no
good to me in there.
I need you out here
to hold this wrench for me.
Come on.
There's no need of me
coming down at all
if there's someone already
here to do the work.
Seeing as we're both here,
let's do it together.
Here you go.
Stand up on there.
Are you tall enough?
Now.
Hold that tight.
It's no good if you let it slip.
What are you doing
down here on your own?
What's your name anyway?
Kevin.
Kevin reevey.
Yeah, ok, and, uh...
and what?
What are you doing
down here on your own?
Nothing.
Nothing?
That's not a lot,
to be doing nothing.
You're not afraid of the dark?
No.
I like it down here.
What do you think of that?
Good or what?
Yeah, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Come down here often?
Just before the sun came up...
the light was gone.
Was it the devil, bro'?
It may well have been, child.
But you know
what protected him, don't you?
All of you together now.
What protected uncle jim...
that night under the bridge?
The rosary.
That's right, saying the rosary.
In the name of the father,
and the son and the holy ghost.
Amen.
Good.
Did you hear the one about the
sheep and the lonely shepherd?
Mr. finn, I'd rather hear the
one about the broken door.
No, bro', you'd rather hear
the one about the sheep.
I called a couple of stores, and
the part is going to cost $150.
I thought you said you could
repair anything
that needs fixing, mr. Finn.
Well, there are things in life
broken that can't be fixed.
This is one of those things.
Ha, ha, ha, I see.
You're a philosopher, mr. Finn.
Indeed I am, brother lavin,
indeed I am.
Now, there was this fellow
who was trying to fix
his poor old broken arm.
I've promised
a slide show, gentlemen,
which will be presented after
the 100th anniversary dinner.
And brother glackin, I want
you to take charge of it.
Oh, great.
I don't have enough to do
already, I suppose.
It's already been decided.
I don't want to hear
any more about it.
Now, as for the hockey team,
I'm planning... to...
play mike... at centre.
All right, that's it!
Lights out, come on!
Everybody in your pyjamas!
Five more minutes, bro'.
You say your prayers, please.
Put all your toys in here.
Come on! Hurry up!
Not yet.
Come on.
Hey, eddie, get him.
Eddie, you could have got him.
No more bathroom.
That should all be done by now.
Come on, please.
Put on your pyjamas.
Kneel down ald
we say our prayers.
Kevin?
Brother lavin would like to see
you in the office, please.
But I'm real tired, bro'.
And I'm getting ready for bed.
Can't it wait till the morning?
What did I say?
Did I say brother lavin would
like to see you in the morning?
No, bro'.
I din't say that, did I?
So go on now.
There you go.
And you cleaned your ear, huh?
Good morning, gentlemen.
Paws out!
Good, good, good.
If you washed them
that wouldn't happen.
Good, good.
Good, good, good.
Flip.
Good.
That shirt belongs
in the laundry.
Get another one.
Good. Do up the button. Good.
Good.
It's good.
And what about you, young man?
Is your little split pea brain
functioning enough this day
to know which foot goes where?
I'm not sure, bro.
Let me see.
That's about
the size of it, my son.
Back in line.
Tuck that shirt in.
Good.
Good, good, good, good, good.
Get moving.
And for god's sake, watch
your language out there.
Remember, you carry the good
name of st. Vincent with you.
Got any clothes
for the orphanage, missis?
We're collecting clothes
for st. Vincent.
Hang on a moment, my love,
and I'll see what I got.
What do you think?
Where did you get that?
I made it myself.
Kevin, you must learn
how to take care
of yourself in this
mean old world... watch.
Here you go, sweethearts.
Thank you.
Thanks, missis.
I almost forgot.
You wouldn't have
any spare change
for the christmas turkey?
I'm quite sure we'll find
something around here for that.
Just a minute now.
Now, will that do you, boys?
That's great, missis.
Thanks a lot.
You're welcome, boys.
I just wish my own youngsters
were as polite as ye.
Thanks again.
Got to run.
Bye.
See what I mean, kevin?
She gave us a lot, buddy.
Yeah?
You know, when we goes
to confession,
are you going
to tell them about this?
No, boy... don't have nothing
to do with them priests,
my son, can't trust them.
Oh, whoa, yeah!
Hey, hey, hey!
Ring the alarm.
We've got a lady
in the orphanage.
Yeah!
Ah, these aren't for ladies,
these are for men.
Yeah, boxing.
Boxing, I'm real good at boxing.
I'll beat you up,
I'll beat you up.
You're no good.
I'll kick it out of you.
Ok, who's going to fight me?
Come on.
Come on, let's go!
Get your older brother, steven.
Come on, come on, come on!
Go, steven, go!
You'll be beating up
on your brother.
Heh, come on!
Kevin, you have to go
to brother lavin's office now.
Now?
Hey, come on!
Hey, watch me, oof, oof, oof!
Yeah! Yeah!
Hey, come on.
Hey, steven!
Yeah!
All-time champion!
Kevin reevey!
Hey, hey!
Hey.
No!
Please, no!
Leave me alone.
Don't take me back
there, please.
Ain't no place else
you can go, lad.
Kevin?
Could you wait
in the office, please?
Take off the hat.
Thank you very much
for bringing the child
home, gentlemen.
It's too cold to be out.
Well, brother lavin,
he certainly didn't
want to come back.
He kicked up some racket.
No doubt.
One thing these youngsters
have in common
is an insatiable need
for attention.
Good evening.
Good night.
Come here.
First of all...
let's take off your jacket.
Come here.
Kevin...
it's ok, kevin.
You're home now, child.
Mama loves you.
She loves you.
Oh, god, she loves you.
My mother's dead
and always will be.
What?
You're not my mother.
Ah!
If you choose to behave
like the other boys,
then you will be punished
like the other boys.
Ah!
Ugh!
Shh.
Let's go, gentlemen!
Everybody up, let's go, go, go!
Move, let's go!
Let's go, come on, it's time!
When I said everybody up,
I think I meant
everybody up, let's go!
Come on, move your carcasses!
Let's go, let's go!
Come on, move!
Up, up, up, up!
Come on! Sun's
been up for hours!
You, up! I said up!
Let's go!
Get your carcass up!
Move it, move it!
Come on, move, move,
move, go, go, go, go.
Out! Move, move!
I said move!
It's ok, kevin.
You can stay in bed today.
Ok?
Ok, let's move.
Let's move over to the teeth.
Brush your teeth, come on.
Come on, go, go, go.
Who made the world?
God.
Who is god?
The creator and son
and the lord of heaven
and earth and all things.
How many gods are there?
There is but one god
who will reward the good
and punish the wicked.
Where is god?
God is everywhere,
but is said to be in heaven
with his angels and saints.
Now, we can do better
than that, boys.
Where is god?
God is everywhere,
but is said to be in heaven
with his angels and saints.
Very good.
Now, let's see. Jimmy.
Yes?
What is heaven?
The kingdom of god's glory
and of his angels and saints.
Very good, very good.
Come on, I'm real starved.
Come on, bud, you got to eat,
get your strength back.
Keep it under the blankets, ok?
Got to go.
See you later.
How you doing, mike?
Not bad, son.
Yourself?
Fine. I'll stay that way if you
don't tell anybody you seen me.
Never get it out of me.
I never been here,
know what I mean?
They could pull
out my fingernails,
and I'll never sell you
down the river, how's that?
Thanks, mike.
Got to go.
See you.
How come you're not up, kevin?
You sick or what?
Come on, you got
to say something.
What's wrong with you?
Come on, let me see that
smiling face of yours.
What happened to you?
I'm telling you, brother,
he doesn't look very good.
A day in bed is all
the boy needs,
mr. Finn.
Jesus, brother,
have you seen him?
I think he needs
some ice or something.
Why don't you go up and
take a look at him yourself?
Just hold on,
mr. Finn.
How long have you been here?
A couple of weeks?
Boys are a tough lot.
They recover quickly.
Not trying to say
anything, brother,
but that boy needs
to see a doctor.
And what in god's name
could the boy have done
to get beaten like that?
Just who in hell
do you think you are?
How do you know
the boy was beaten?
Do you know the boy
was beaten? Do you?
Are you a doctor?
No, you're a janitor, mr. Finn.
That is your job here.
Now, you go and do it and
let me get on with my work.
Or do I find myself
another janitor?
Don't.
I don't want to go.
Well, my son, you're going
whether you like to or not,
'cause this is not good enough.
What seems to be
the problem, young man?
He's been beaten, doc,
that's the problem.
Go on, kevin,
tell him what happened.
I'm going to have
to examine the boy.
Would you mind
waiting outside, please?
I'll be outside the
door, kevin, ok?
Hi, kevin.
Good.
Can I help you, brother?
Yes, I hope so.
I am brother lavin
from st. Vincent.
Apparently one of our boys was
brought in, a kevin reevey.
He's with the doctor... down the
hall, second door to your left.
Thank you.
You stupid, stupid
son of a bitch.
What do you think you're doing?
He had to see a doctor.
He had to see a doctor?
You don't even know
the trouble you're in.
I could have you
charged with abducting
a child, you stupid imbecile.
You don't have to be
getting on with that.
I don't have to?
I'll get on with
whatever I choose.
And you are no longer welcome
in st. Vincent, mr. Finn.
What?
You're fired,
you meddling moron.
Just the sight of
you makes me sick.
You brought pain
and chaos to our home,
and the boys hate you
for it, they've told me.
That is not true,
and you know it.
You're a goddamn nutcase,
that's what you are.
You get out of here.
Don't let me see you again,
or I'll have you arrested.
You might call me
a stupid imbecile,
and you might call me a moron,
but let me tell you
something right now, bro'.
Those boys have a friend in me.
And in you, they have nothing.
You can take him with you.
Poor child.
Brother, I have
no idea who did what.
But I think you have a problem
with somebody down there.
He didn't say who it was?
No, he wouldn't
tell us anything.
Perhaps you can, uh,
find out more from the boy.
But the child is
terrorized, I'm convinced.
I had no idea.
No doubt, it's one
of the older boys.
They can be very brutal
to the younger ones.
The nurse here will give
you the papers to sign,
and, uh, I'll bring
the boy down in a minute.
Fine.
Thank you.
Kevin.
Come here.
That is for being a good boy.
A few days rest, and you're
going to be as good as new.
Go on.
Well?
Thank you, bro'.
You're welcome.
Kevin, if I punish you,
it's only to help you learn
what is right and what is wrong.
I'll always be
here to protect you.
And you are very special to me.
Understand?
Let's go get something to eat.
Come on.
It's past your bedtime.
It's past my bedtime.
Shh, close your your eyes.
That's it. Keep out the light.
It's time for bed.
Everybody else is asleep.
Please, bro'.
Get up early in the morning.
It's past your bedtime now.
Come on, now, steven.
Close your eyes and go to sleep.
Have nice dreams.
You're supposed to be asleep.
Not supposed to be awake.
Are you ok?
Has he been at you?
Has he?
Get your hands off me!
Back to your seat.
You know that.
Iunny, get back!
Get back here!
What are you all looking at?
What are you looking at?
I've got no parking
spaces in the back.
That pervert glackin's been
after my brother again.
If he touches him again, I'm
going to knock out his teeth
and shove them up his holy arse.
Hey, you watch your
language, young man.
Foul mouth,
threatening a brother,
disrespectful of god at mass
and god knows what else.
10 of the best on each, brother.
No tears, mr. Lunny?
Perhaps you haven't yet
learned your lesson.
Hands out again, please.
Who did this to you?
Glynn. I swear I'm going
to kill one of them bastards.
Lay your hands on there
till I get some ice.
Now, this will freeze them and
keep the swelling down for it.
Bunch of goddamned perverts.
Ok, let me wrap this up.
Now, are you going to tell me
what's going on around here?
Stevie.
Glackin's after him.
I tried to do something
about it, and look.
Look, I got fired, ok,
for taking young kevin
to the hospital.
And now this?
I want you
to tell me exactly what you
mean by perverts, brian.
They're after us,
especially the young ones,
in their beds at
night, you know?
No, I don't know.
Oh, Jesus christ almighty.
Are you saying what
I think you're saying?
I'm not lying, mike.
Jesus, brian.
Yes, sir, can I help you?
Who's the person in charge
here? maybe I can help you.
Are you in charge?
No, but I can probably...
Well, you can't help me then.
Sir, if you tell me
what it is, maybe I can.
Listen, my love, there's
a manager or director
or some goddamned thing in here,
I don't care what he's called.
That's who I want to see.
My name is mike finn.
I wasthe janitor
at st. Vincent.
You go, and you find him
now!
'Cause I ain't leaving
till I talk to the fella.
Well, we have our procedures
to investigate
complaints, mr. Finn.
And this is not the way
to go about it.
What the hell
are you talking about?
I'm telling you they're
beating the living daylights
out of them boys
and going around at night,
bothering them in their beds.
Now, what I want to know is
how are you going
to put a stop to it?
As I've already told you,
mr. Finn, we cannot do anything
until you go to the proper
district office to fill out
a complaint form.
Now, once that is done,
the form will be evaluated
by our review panel.
I'm supposed to go
and fill out a form?
That's what you're
going to do about it?
Well, you just can't come
barging in here, making wild
statements about things you
haven't even seen yourself.
Spreading rumours
about one of the most
hallowed institutions
of this city.
Now, I'm sorry, I must insist
that you follow the rules.
They, they have been
developed for very...
Mr. finn, where are you going?
I tell you where I'm not going.
That's to your district office
to fill out no goddamned form.
No, sir.
Ha, ha, I said to her, I said,
"lady, what are you
giving it to me for?"
"Don't forget the surgeon!"
Ah, here it is.
Here it is.
Look how beautiful.
The all new and very
accommodating st.
Vincent orphanage.
Excellent, excellent.
And just how much is
this going to cost me?
Ah, well, minister, the
renovations are budgeted
at 450,000, and the rink
at half a million, so the total
government grant will have
to be in the neighbourhood
of $1 million.
Is that all?
St. vincent has always had one
of the finest teams in the city.
Now that they'll finally
have their own rink,
they may be just unbeatable.
And learn to skate.
And speaking of those
whose path to heaven is assured,
we all know our esteemed
chief kennedy.
Nay, not a blemish
resides in his soul,
nor has a drop
ever passed his lips.
Certainly not.
Pour the man a drink.
Please do, ha, ha.
Chief kennedy is another
of our respected citizens
who got training
with the brothers.
And I have the bruises
to prove it.
Now, now, chief,
let's have a toast.
Hear, hear.
Gentlemen, to brother
lavin's renovation plans.
Salute grazie dio.
Salute.
God bless.
Have a spin for a quarter.
Step right up.
Get your tickets inside.
Every spin is a prize.
Merry christmas.
That's it. Come on in.
You look like you need
the turkey. Come on in.
Come on in. Merry christmas,
merry christmas.
Come one, come all.
Two for a nickel,
four for a dime,
10 for a quarter.
How you doing, ma'am?
Step right up.
Hey!
Are they all gone?
Yes, they're almost all gone.
We've got two more here.
Quick, quick.
Are they all gone?
All gone! They're all gone!
All right, mr. Premier,
spin the wheel, please!
Yes, brother, I will!
I'll spin the wheel.
Here we go!
And where she stops,
nobody knows!
Ha, ha, ha!
Number...
one!
Number one!
You won!
Two for a nickel!
Well, if it isn't
detective noseworthy
of the royal frigging
newfoundland frigging
constabulary.
How are you doing, mike?
Not so bloody good.
Come on in. Have a drink.
Is that why you called me, mike?
To have a drink with you?
Look, marty, I know
you're not catholic,
but Jesus, mary and Joseph, man,
those bastards are
at them young fellas,
and something's got
to be done about it,
church or no goddamned church.
Have you ever seen
anything yourself?
Have I seen anything?
I've seen a young fella's
hands so smashed up,
they looked like hamburger meat.
Brian lunny, talk to him.
He'll tell you plenty of stuff.
Now, uh, this boy you took to
the hospital, kevin reevey.
What was the doctor's name?
That's another thing.
Why would lavin have me fired
just for taking a young
kid to the hospital?
The doctor, mike?
Do you remember his name?
Jesus, I don't know.
He threw me out of the room,
looking at me like
I done something.
Then that high and mighty
fella from the government
asking me to fill out
forms for christ's sake.
You got to be able
to read and write
to know what's right and wrong?
My god, we can't use that.
We look like a
crowd of refugees.
Like prisoners of war.
I can tell you one thing.
You can plan some party.
Can you imagine?
A hundred years of good works.
I vow and promise
to protect every living thing
that god has put on this earth.
I'll protect, uh,
butterflies and flowers,
children, rich and poor.
I'll even protect
crab lice, ha, ha.
Any and every living
and non-living thing.
I'll protect the
bones of dead relatives
and the, the insects
that feed on them.
I vow, I vow
I vow, I vow, I vow.
Bravo!
Ok, eddie, we're here.
Now, if you hears
or sees anything,
flick this switch here,
and that'll let us know.
And always keep a lookout.
That's the wine.
You idiot, I know where that is.
The bottles, where's
the bottles, boy?
Come on, hurry up.
Take it easy, will you...
I'll get 'em all.
Hurry, hurry.
Let's go.
Come on, come on.
Oh!
Thank you.
You will say the grace,
brother maclaverty.
Bless us, oh, lord, and these
thy gifts which from thy bounty
we are about to receive
through christ, our lord.
Amen.
And, and forgive us,
lord, for the
wrong we do, and be merciful for
the path we've chosen.
We at this table ask
your forgiveness, amen.
What was that all about?
Have you taken it upon yourself
to change our regular
grace, or is there some
dark spot on your soul
you wish to discuss
at the breakfast table?
Just rambling, brother.
Here you go.
I think he's in trouble.
Come on, lunny, you little
frigger, fill it up, boy.
What do you think this is, my
son, a garden party, do you?
That's how much you get
for what you paid.
That's it, boys, put it
in the bag, that's right.
If you want some more,
come back, eh?
Yeah, yeah.
That's it, boys.
Anybody for seconds?
Anybody for seconds, come on.
Drink up, drink up.
Now, a globe is simply a ball
with a picture of
the earth on it.
Ok, now, on the picture of
the globe in your book,
find the line that runs around
the middle of the earth.
Everyone see it?
Yes.
Kevin reevey
to the office.
Kevin reevey to the office.
Kevin reevey.
Come on, kevin, let's go.
Hurry up.
Now, this line is
called the equator.
It divides the earth in half.
The upper half is called?
There's a policeman in my office
who wants to talk to
you about the hospital.
Anything you tell him,
I will know about it.
Do you understand?
Kevin reevey?
Brian?
Can I, uh, have a talk with you?
In private, please.
Come on, it's all right.
What did he ask you?
He told me I'm a part of
a police investigation,
and I'm not supposed to tell
anyone what we talked about.
I said, what did he ask you,
and what did you say?
He told me that if anyone
so much as touches me,
to contact him.
So, you want to touch me?
You want to hit me, hey?
Is that what you want to do?
'Cause I'm not telling
you nothing!
What was done to you
is a crime, kevin.
Whoever did that can
be put in jail.
Jail?
Yeah, if you tell me who did it.
Were you beaten because you
ran away from the orphanage?
Who told you I ran away?
I talked to the officers who
brought you back here, kevin.
All right?
Now, the last thing they saw
was brother lavin telling
you to wait in his office.
The next day, you were
taken to the hospital.
Can I go now?
It's ok, kevin.
Just take it easy,
now, all right?
Things are going to be ok.
Thank you, kevin.
Run along now.
Straight back to
class, now, kevin.
No detours.
If I have any more questions,
I'll be in touch.
Detective, if there's something
going on with these boys,
I think I should know about it.
As I've told you, I'm
following up some leads.
I'm afraid I can't
go beyond that.
I hope you got what you wanted
and that will be the end.
I'm afraid I cannot have this
kind of thing going on here.
Now, on that, I agree with you.
This is no place to
conduct police interviews.
I'm telling you,
that's what the cop said.
They're all going
to jail, if, and only if,
you guys tell them what's
been happening around here.
I don't know, brian.
You shouldn't have
given them names.
Christ, lavin will
take the skin right off of us.
Chicken, chicken.
Do you mind if I
take a look at that?
No.
Thank you.
Kevin had a hard life before
he came to the orphanage.
He was brought up with alcohol
and fighting, and then there
was the fire which absolutely
destroyed the child.
Watching his parents
being carried out dead.
Now, the doctor who saw kevin
filed an official report
of suspected abuse.
Yes, I know.
What are you going
to do with it?
It's already been dealt with.
Everything having to
do with the orphanage
gets sent to the director.
This is not the first
report, you know.
Reports having to
do with beatings?
Beatings and...
they go upstairs, and that's
the last we ever hear of them.
Have you ever had any reports
of brothers touching boys?
There have been rumours.
Look, I'm the social worker
assigned to the boys in the
orphanage, and I can't even get
in there to see the boys.
Brother lavin says it would
disrupt their routine.
Really?
There's nothing I can do.
Have you ever tried to go
over the catholic church
in newfoundland?
This brian lunny has been making
some serious
allegations, brother.
Do you know of
anything going on?
No.
I don't believe a word of it.
What I do believe is he's
a sullen and resentful
young delinquent.
What if it is true?
What then?
Then glackin will have
to be dealt with.
But I tell you he
is simply making up
a story about his little brother
to hide his own
incipient criminality.
I don't think you
fully understand
what is going on here.
This is a copy of
the witness statement
which the police department has
been kind enough to send over.
Peter, do you realize
what happens when
a police investigation
gets underway?
Word of it starts
getting around.
All sorts of rumours start up.
I am getting calls.
Now the police want
to interview more boys.
And not at
the orphanage, you see?
I will deal with it.
That's not good enough, peter.
The monsignor will be looking
into this matter on my behalf.
He'll keep you informed.
Have a good night's rest, peter.
I have the feeling
you're going to need it.
Your grace.
Peter, please.
Sit a moment.
I'd like to read some
of the words from this...
this boy's statement.
"I have been beaten lots
of times by brother glynn."
"He smashes lots of boys,"
"and he's after some
of the little ones."
"I saw him rubbing mike
sproule's private parts."
"Brother glackin is after
my little brother, stevie."
Everybody up please,
immediately!
Down to the gymnasium
right now, come on!
Up, up, up, come on!
You, get up, you, get up!
Come on!
Down to the gymnasium,
quickly, please.
Forget your slippers.
Down to the gym!
Go, go, come on!
There are rumours
being spread around
by certain people.
Anyone who is spreading
these rumours
is a traitor to the orphanage,
a traitor to you
and a traitor to god.
Whatever happens inside the
walls of this orphanage
is to stay inside the
walls of this orphanage.
That is a sacred rule,
a rule more sacred than
any rule you will ever hear.
Understand this.
There are people outside
who want to see
this orphanage close.
These...
these rumours are
the way to do it.
If these
hellish fantasies are believed
by the devils outside,
people will stop donating money.
People will stop
donating clothing.
You will be forced out
onto the street,
and you will have nowhere
to go but into the gutter.
If I hear or hear of anyone who
is spreading these evil lies
from hell or talking to anyone
outside, I can assure you
that by god...
by god, they will be punished.
Now, mike,
what about brother glynn?
Has he ever touched you?
Yes.
What has he done?
He took me to my dorm, put me
on his knee and spanked me.
And then?
And then he rubbed me all
over and all over my bum.
What else?
Sometimes he even does
it on my private part.
What does he do on
your private part?
He rubs me.
What else does he do?
Sometimes he takes me into his
bed and puts me on top of him
and says rub me
on his private part.
Does he do this often?
Yes.
Now, what about brother mac?
No, he never done
any of that stuff.
Sometimes I wake up in
the middle of the night
and he's in bed with me...
rubbing and trying, you know.
Kissing, trying to... trying
to stick it up me bum.
Anything else about glackin?
You sure?
Yes, sir, he comes to my bed
and he leans right in over me.
So I knows it's him.
I can see his face.
Sometimes he wants me to look
at him when he's doing it.
And brother glynn?
Yeah.
Brother maclaverty?
No, not brother mac.
What about brother nichol?
Yeah, he's got a stick.
Does he hit you with it?
All over.
Even your face?
Yeah.
And brother white?
Not me, but some of the others.
What about brother loomy?
No.
And, uh, what
about brother lavin?
No.
You're sure.
There's no need
to be scared, you know.
Let's talk about
some of the others.
No, it's not ok.
You can't say I said anything.
I never saw him do anything.
I never opened me mouth
about brother lavin, right?
It's fine.
I understand.
No more about it, ok?
Now, let's talk about
brother maclaverty.
Listen here.
Brother mac's number one.
Him, brother porter and brother
quinlan are the best kind.
They've always been good to us.
So no one's been
at you, is that right?
Not glynn, not glackin?
That's right.
I'd let them have it
if they tried anything on me.
Mm-hmm.
You're sure.
Yes, I'm sure...
I told you already.
I don't let them.
It's unbelievable.
I've never seen
anything like it.
Noseworthy, I want
to see evidence.
I've got enough to make arrests.
As soon as I...
Hold on a second
there, noseworthy.
You're not going
off half-cocked.
You know what we're up against.
I want a report
on what you've got.
How can I write a report
when I haven't finished
my investigation?
I've got to interview every lad.
Those boys came from two dorms.
There are other dorms and other
brothers in charge
of those dorms.
Then there's brother lavin.
I'm convinced the
boys are terrified.
What is all this istuff?
Ineed to arrest,
ineed to interview.
This is sensitive
stuff, noseworthy.
I can't have the police force
look like we're out to crucify
catholics, now can I?
You're catholic sir.
Do you think I'm crucifying you?
Don't get smart
with me, noseworthy.
There's no use talking to you.
Get me a report of
what you've got.
Now, justice and social
services are waiting for it,
and I'm waiting for it.
And in the meantime,
I want to see
a copy of those
witness statements.
Glackin, glackin, glackin!
That's enough, boys.
That's enough, come on.
Get to your beds,
it's time for prayers.
Awww!
Do we have to?
Yes, you have to.
Where's brother glackin, bro'?
Brother glackin has been
relieved of his duties.
I'll be replacing him
for the time being.
Yeah!
Boys.
Boys, that's enough.
I can assure you it is
a very fine facility.
These men are sick.
They need proper
medical treatment
in a spiritual setting.
They have acknowledged
breaking their vows.
It's the first step towards what
we hope will be a full recovery.
Good day, gentlemen.
Thank you very much.
Giancarlo.
Monsignor.
You know, it stinks.
They should be facing
criminal charges.
But the grant's already
been announced.
We can't be seen giving
a million dollars
to a bunch of perverts.
They should be in jail, ed.
This is your official
release form
from st. Vincent.
You are to report to the social
welfare office on harvey road.
And I want you off the premises
before the day is out.
I was gettin' out
of here, anyways.
And I'm not going to any
goddamn welfare office.
I'm going to get a job.
And I'm going to get my brother
out of this hell hole.
The only mark
you'll make, lunny,
is with your fingerprints,
stealing something.
Oh, yeah, well,
wherever the hell I'm going,
I'm going to tell them about
you goddamn perverts
and what you've
been doing in here.
Oh, no, you're not.
You see, you got
a big mouth, lunny,
and you're going
to have to learn
to keep it shut tight.
Your younger brother is going
to be with us for
a good many years,
and if I hear about you saying
so much as one word...
do I have to spell it out?
You miserable bastard.
Can't wait to go to toronto.
Don't get too excited yet.
It's going to take a while.
Yeah, I know,
but I'm going sometime, right?
What do you think,
I'm going to leave you
in this goddamn place?
No way. As soon as I get
straightened away, you're gone.
You'll be all right.
Just stay away from them.
That's all.
I can look after myself.
I'll kick the bastards in
the nuts if they comes near me.
I knows what to do.
Yeah, you're tough, stevie.
Hey, how much money you got?
I don't know. I'm ok.
Here. You gotta eat, boy.
It's a long bus ride.
Don't be foolish. Put that away.
Look, there's a lot more
where that came from.
Take care of yourself, huh?
Ok, here we go.
The speech ends,
and you've taken places
in the back of the hall.
Now, I will be up front,
over here on the side.
Ok, now don't forget,
you're holding
a million-dollar cheque, ok?
So hold it proudly. That's it.
Now, keep your eyes on me.
Ready?
Slowly.
Slower.
That's it.
Want everybody
to have a good look.
Ok, come right ahead,
right up here on the stage.
That's it. Watch your step.
Ok, now...
you turn around.
Ok, so we can get
a good picture. That's it.
Excuse me, brother.
Yes, brother?
A small addition, brother.
A gift will be given
to the premier.
What a lovely idea.
Well, well, well, well, well,
let's see, now.
We'll need a boy to step forward
and present the gift.
Oh, me, me, me...
how about kevin?
An excellent idea.
Ok, kevin, uh...
brother, would you mind
standing in for the premier?
Certainly not.
Ok, you stand right there,
just ahead a little bit.
There you go,
ok, right there, fine.
Now, kevin,
you come out around.
You have your gift
for the premier in your hands.
Go forward, and you present
your gift to the premier.
That's it.
Now, mr. Premier,
you shake hands with kevin.
Kevin, shake hands.
Kevin?
Yeah, there, yes.
Oh, that's a very nice picture.
Now, uh,
you return to your place.
Brother, would you mind bringing
kevin back to his place?
You come forward
to the edge of the stage.
That's it. Stop there.
Now, the archbishop
will rise, go forward,
and you will present him
with the cheque
for $1 million, ok?
Now, he may want to ask you
a few questions
from your catechism text.
Uh, eddie, who is god?
The creator and sovereign
lord of heaven and earth
and all things.
And, mikey, what is heaven?
The kingdom of god's glory
and of his angels and saints.
Exactly.
Then you move back the stage.
Ok.
You stop there. Fine.
Ok, now, you come forward.
Just come forward a little bit.
Ok.
Everything ok?
Anything wrong?
I think he was
coming after me again.
Who?
Brother lavin.
Want to tell me about it?
What did you say?
Did you say anything at all?
I told him
that he wasn't my mother.
What did he do after that?
Did he say anything?
He picked me up
and he threw me on the wall.
Did he hit you?
Did he hit you with his hands?
With a belt.
What end of the belt?
The buckle.
Uh, does brother lavin...
Has he ever done this with
any other boys that you know of?
No, he says that I'm his boy.
Has this kind of thing
been going on for a long time?
Do you remember the first time
it ever happened?
Great.
Do I have to go back
to the orphanage?
Yeah, I'm afraid so.
You know,
when your parents died,
the court put you
in the custody of the brothers.
But it's going to stop, kevin.
We'll put an end to this stuff,
I promise you.
I can't give you
your family back, but trust me.
It's all over.
You got my word.
All right?
You're going to come back
and see me, right?
I promised you, didn't I?
Let's go.
Yes, oh, yes, he's here now,
as a matter of fact.
Yes, I'll call you.
Thank you.
Bye-bye.
Now, I don't know
everything that's
been going on
in here, but I will.
You can count on that.
I want to make sure
that you understand that
you and every
other person in here
are the subject
of a police investigation
into very serious
criminal matters.
Such as?
Gross indecency,
physical assault,
indecent assault.
Shall we start with that?
Don't be absurd, detective.
Now, you listen here.
I have brought this boy
back here personally
to make sure that
nothing more happens to him.
It is over!
That boy is under
my very personal protection.
Don't you come in here
threatening me.
You have no authority here.
You know it, and I know it.
So if you would quickly remove
yourself from the premises,
we can get on with
the job of repairing
some of the damage
you people have caused.
Is that right?
That is right.
Well, let me tell you something.
I have some paperwork to do,
and then I will come back here
with all the authority I need.
Now, this is not it, lavin.
If you touch that boy
before I get back here,
I'll rip that Jesus throat
right out of your neck.
Here you go.
Joseph...
and his walking stick.
Have you seen kevin?
No, bro'.
Me neither.
Lying little thieves.
Ye shall not enter
the kingdom of god.
Do you hear me!
Your punishment will be eternal!
Move, move!
Kevin!
You foolish... foolish child.
Foolish, foolish child!
Why?
Why, why, why, huh?
Why, why?
Please, bro',
don't hit me, bro'.
I'll do whatever you wants, mom.
Please, mom, I'll be good, mom.
Please, mom, please, mom.
I love you.
Peter.
What in the name of god
are you doing?
Come here, child.
Let him go.
Come here.
Come here. Let him go.
Go up to your dorm, kevin.
Go on. Go on, boys.
You're a sick, evil man, peter,
and a disgrace to the order.
By the authority invested in me
as superintendent...
Don't speak to me
about authority.
You will have nothing more
to do with these children ever.
Ready?
Ready, ready, ready? Let's go.
Let's go, ok, ready?
Here we go.
Watch your sticks, now,
watch your sticks.
Go, steve, go, steve!
Come on steve.
Get up, steve, get up, get up.
Nice goal!
Oops, beg your pardon.
Nice to see you again.
How are you?
Mary, hold all the calls,
would you?
He's wating for you in here.
My uncle's coming over.
He's going over to happy's.
Is he? My uncle's coming over.
He's really nice...
What?
My name is brother davitt.
I'm going to be
your new superintendent.
These are brothers bilton
and brother graham,
who will be taking over
dorm duties
from brothers glackin and glynn,
who have been transferred.
This institution has been put
into the gravest of danger.
And it is going to be
my mission to rectify
the good name of st. Vincent.
And I can assure you all,
I intend to do just that.
There will be no more visits
from the police.
It is time to put
the past behind us.
This is your home...
and will be treated
with the reverence
its history deserves.
Gentlemen, my office, please.
Come on, eat up, gentlemen.
We haven't got all day.
"He made me put his bird
in my mouth"?
You will rewrite
this piece of pornography.
I can't send out
something like this.
You'll take out all references
to sexual matters.
Now, is that clear?
I didn't make up
this stuff, chief.
Those are sworn statements
made by the boys.
You get orders, I get orders.
The case is closed.
Oh, no, I don't believe it.
This comes straight
from the department of justice.
There will be no arrests.
Apparently, the brothers
involved will be sent
somewhere for treatment.
What about the boys?
Noseworthy, I need a nice
clean report for the files.
And you're going to write it up,
or you're out on the street,
out of a job.
Is that clear?
I told the little kid he
wouldn't be buggered any more.
What the hell do I tell him now,
that the high holy church
and a bunch
of criminal politicians
don't give a damn about him?
And what about the other
brothers we didn't get yet
'cause you closed
this investigation
just when it was
getting started?
You are this close
to being charged
with insubordination right now.
And that goes
for the rest of you.
If I hear one more word
about this case,
I'll have the person responsible
charged under the police act.
We all carry scars
of one kind or another.
I can only pray
that ours will be
less visible than others.
But we do have them,
and your understanding
of our problem is...
but all I can say is that I'm...
I'm deeply, deeply grateful.
Enough said.
Another drink.
I'm going to sleep now, bro'.
Yes, will you go
to sleep now, steven?
Don't do that, bro'.
I don't like it.
Shhh, you go to sleep now.
...kevin, this is mr. Premier.
Hello, kevin.
A humble gift
from the boys of st. Vincent.
Thank you very much.
Captions provided by
telefilm canada
captions performed by
the national captioning centre