Subtitles optimized by flitze
She's not coming today.
Tomorrow, either.
Hello, miss Polly-o.
Thank you, Hannah.
Wow, cousin Jessica.
Your first this week.
Mom would have been very proud.
Hi, chicken.
Hey.
- I can clean it up.
- Go in the house.
Bring them eggs with you.
Miss Blodgett said you
should fix the front step.
How was your day?
It was fine.
How's your supper?
It's good.
"How was your day, Duncan?"
Good.
"Did you tell your father
about old red hen?"
"I had to bury another one
of my chickens today, Edgar...
old age."
"Duncan played the minister.
- You should've seen him throw the Bible."
- Just don't.
"Now, Edgar, death's just as
much a part of life as living is."
Stop! Stop it! Stop it!
I'm going to have a smoke.
That it?
That's all of it.
Look at that.
Follows him like
a little puppy dog.
That chicken belongs
with the others.
Nacnud Egdum.
This is my last name backwards.
Duncan Mudge is Nacnud Egdum.
You go...
M-U-D-G-E, E-G-D-U-M.
Egdum.
Egg dumb, huh?
Yeah, it's kind of funny.
You can do anything.
Juster Pelkey is, um...
How about taking a couple
of chickens home with you?
That'd be great.
Yeah.
Go grab him two good ones.
They're not yours to give.
You mind your manners
and get the man his chickens.
Hey.
You hear me?
- I don't want to cause trouble with you.
- You ain't trouble.
Sorry, Juster.
It's ok, Duncan.
How come Duncan don't help you?
He helps out.
Cousin Jessica, you're gonna go
live at Juster's house now.
It's ok, it's ok.
Marilla the Gorilla
is going with you.
I know.
I'll miss you too.
Just make sure you lay
lots of eggs for him, ok?
He's nice.
I didn't know women had
heart attacks like that, huh?
Heard it knocked
her right off her bike.
- Is that true?
- Yeah, yeah.
Oi! Those are big ones, Duncan.
They're good layers.
Them are beauties.
Give them to me.
Hey, not like that!
You'll hurt them.
Poor little things.
They'll be good eating.
He's a funny kid, Edgar.
You better get these home.
Hey, girl.
What the hell you doing?
I was just petting her.
She'll suck your dick
if you let her.
Well, I wouldn't let her.
I'm just kidding you, Duncan.
I know.
Hey!
She ain't gonna milk herself.
No shit. Really?
I'm just talking to
my friend over here.
You're a god damn
smart ass, ain't you?
What are you waiting for?
Let's go.
He's just mad because
he lost his license.
Nice chicken.
Do you want to hold her?
No.
I gotta go in.
Come on.
Come on!
Do you need any eggs?
We're leaving shortly.
I'm almost ready.
on a hill far away
stood an old rugged cross
the emblem of
suffering and shame
and I love that old cross
where the dearest and best
for a world of lost
sinners was slain
so, I'll cherish the
old rugged cross
till the moment,
at last I lay down
I will cling to the
old rugged cross
and exchange it
some day for a crown
Where's my eggs, young man?
Oh, I forgot. Um...
I'll bring them by after church.
Duncan's it.
I just can't get over it.
He's the spitting image of Lydia.
You must see it, Edgar.
Yeah, I see it.
More and more like her
every time I see him.
Good morning. How are you?
Tracey!
Where's your brother?
We're leaving.
Oh, he went off downstairs.
- Oh, I'll go get him.
- Thanks.
Come on, let's go.
God, you got beautiful tits.
You're sexy as hell.
- Are you being serious?
- Yeah.
Take off your panties.
Oh, God, Perry,
you're all sweaty.
Fuck!
Oh, my god. Are you kidding me?
Why?
Perry?
- Perry.
- What?
Your mom's leaving.
Oh, Jesus, Perry.
Hi, Duncan.
Hi.
Where are you going?
Yeah...
your mom is leaving.
Tell her I'll be right there.
I've got to shit.
Ok.
Hop in, Scotty.
Come on, boys.
He'll be right out.
He was just down there, um...
by himself.
Thanks, Duncan.
Bye, Duncan.
Edgar...
glad you're here.
Morning, Reverend.
How are you boys making out?
Uh, we're fine, Reverend.
We're doing just fine.
Good.
What'd I tell you
about that chicken?
Hey, chicken boy!
- Look, it's the egg lady.
- You're just an asshole, Travis.
- "I'll have a dozen."
- "You're an asshole, Travis."
We need more beer.
Right, Travis, 'fess up.
I told you, I'm broke
till Monday, man.
What, are you kidding me?
Scotty, you never
have any money.
When's the last time
you bought the beer?
Hmm, let me see.
Never?
Fuck! Hey!
- Take it easy on my wheels, big fella.
- I'm trying.
What do you want me to do?
Turn him upside down and shake him?
I got money.
How much?
That'll do.
- I want some gum.
- Get some chips. I'm starving.
Nice turd, Duncan.
Hey, Travis, check out his turd!
Oh, that's a nice one, pumpkin.
Duncan, bring your
chicken over here.
Oh, my God. She is so cute.
Can I hold her?
Sure.
Hey, who cuts your hair, Duncan?
Your grandma?
No.
My dad.
Right, ok.
Ok.
Aww, she's sweet.
What's her name?
Chicken.
Me and my mom
ordered a box of baby chicks in the
mail, and they were all supposed to be...
Rhode Island Reds and girls, but
one of them turned
out to be a rooster,
and one of them
turned out to be white.
Hmm.
She was my mom's favorite.
Your mom was so pretty.
Yeah.
Gross, Tonya.
Shut up, April.
Uh, chickens are filthy.
God, you're such a girl.
They have diseases.
It's kind of skeevy.
Eww...
Put the tailgate up.
Later, chicken boy.
You should come with us.
Ok.
Hold on. Duncan's
coming with us.
No way.
Fuck you, Travis.
He bought the beer.
- Brent...
- Help him with his bike.
Jesus Christ.
Give me the fucking bike.
Come on.
Let's go!
What the fuck is that about?
Whoo!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Yeah!
Ugh!
Stop it!
Hey, lay off the beer!
Scotty, you need a beer?
- You bought it.
- Whoo!
- Drink it up, brother.
- Yeah!
Hey, Duncan?
How's the beer?
Good.
Hey, that hat is
fucking cool, man.
It was my mom's.
Fuckin' geek.
Look at him, look.
Chicken boy!
Oof... fuck.
Spell joke.
J-O-K-E.
Spell smoke.
S-M-O-K-E.
What do you call the
white part of an egg?
Weirdo.
The yolk.
Nope... albumen.
The white part!
The white part... right.
Come on.
Yes I do, I smell cowshit,
how about you?
I smell cowplop, yes I do.
I smell cowplop, how about you?
I smell cowshit, yes I do.
I smell cowshit, how about you?
Scotty, let me sit up front.
My hair's getting all
tangled in my face.
I smell cowplop, yes I do.
I smell cowplop, how about you?
Gimme that hat.
Gimme it.
Put this on.
There you go.
- That better?
- Pff, get off me.
What's the matter with you?
You're a fuckin' bitch.
Oh, my god!
It's Perry!
Perry smells like cowshit.
You do smell like cowshit, man.
Ow!
Ass!
- Can we go get it?
- Brent!
Let me out. I'm going home.
What's the matter, Perry?
Your vagina sore?
I'm serious. Let me out of
the fucking car. I'm leaving.
Alright.
Take it easy.
I want to go get it.
Hey, Scotty, is there
any more beer up there?
Whoo!
That's why they make
fun of you, you know?
That and the chicken.
I want to go find it.
Forget it.
It's gone.
How come you have to act
like that in front of people?
I don't know.
My mom died.
Yeah, I know.
It's big, huh?
Yeah.
A lot of girls won't let me fuck them
when they first see the size of it.
You have to get them nice
and wet so you don't hurt them.
Yeah.
You ever fuck a girl, Duncan?
No.
I did it with this girl once.
She wouldn't let
me put it in her.
So I just kept
rubbing down there,
playing with her nipples.
She had these
big nipples, man.
Stuck out like that.
Big, hard ones.
Big cow nipples.
I rub one between my fingers...
and whisper "let me fuck you."
"No, I can't."
So, I'd pinch them real
hard when she said that.
Hard, so she'd moan.
Just to punish her a little.
But you could tell she was loving it,
because her pussy was sopping wet.
And I just kept licking
on those nipples.
Flicking my tongue on them.
Pulling 'em.
Just teasing the
hell out of her.
She started grabbing
on that big dick.
I was sliding two fingers
in and out of her.
"Let me fuck you."
But she didn't say nothing.
Just kept moaning
and moving her ass.
So I slide in another finger.
"Fuck me! Fuck me!"
She said it that time.
"Fuck me, Perry."
I like to look them
right in the eyes
the first time they feel
that dick going up in there.
Pretty soon, I could
feel her underneath me...
sliding her ass
down on that big dick.
It's funny.
First, they don't
let you fuck them...
and then they're fucking
themselves on your own cock.
Yeah.
People do weird stuff sometimes.
Fuck!
- Perry!
- My dad.
I better go before he comes out.
Perry!
Bye, Perry.
Where you been?
I was out...
riding around with my friends.
I've been thinking
that I want you to...
to help me out more around here.
There's no reason to pay Juster
when I got a good,
strong boy like you.
How you feeling?
You had supper?
I'm fine.
Alright.
Well...
we gotta bale the rest
of that first cut tomorrow.
Yes, sir.
Uh...
I think your mother would
want you to have this.
Thank you.
No more, alright?
We gotta get up at 5:00.
Dad...
you're not throwing
it out, are you?
I'm just putting some
things in storage.
We gotta get an
early start tomorrow.
We gotta get all this in
the barn before it rains.
Hey.
No, thank you.
Why don't you go get cleaned up?
You can go see
those friends of yours.
What about dinner?
I'll fix my own.
Hey, Perry.
What's up?
They're cute, aren't they?
Want some help?
I got it.
Why aren't you helping your dad?
What'd you do to your lip?
Nothing.
It's fucked up, you know?
You have this idea that...
your life will automatically
be different when you grow up.
Then you start getting older and you
realize it's all gonna be the same shit.
You know what I mean?
Sort of.
It's a fucking joke.
Yeah.
I know what you mean.
That chicken know any tricks?
No.
Then you should teach her some.
Like what?
I don't know.
Roll over, sit...
it's your chicken.
Give me your bike.
Take your clothes off.
Aren't you going in?
I'm waiting till I'm more sweaty.
I'm going in.
That's far.
Is it deep?
Deep enough.
Hey, help!
Are you crazy?
You almost killed me!
You're ok. You can swim, right?
Yeah.
Duncan!
Oh, it's fucking cold!
It's freezing.
That was kind of fun.
That wasn't so bad, was it?
Whoo!
It's neat.
This is my hideout.
Really?
Wow.
Nobody but me.
Did you ever bring
a girl up here?
- Fuck, no.
- Duncan?
Duncan!
He's gotta be here.
His bike's here.
Duncan, buddy?
Where are you?
Duncan?
Come out, come out,
wherever you are!
- Fudge boy!
- Dude, dude, dude, dude,
put it on the tracks.
Wait, wait, no, wait.
I got a better idea.
Throw it in. Throw it in.
- Oh, shit!
- My bike!
I'll get it.
Oops, sorry, man.
Dinky, where are you?
Dude, he's gotta be down there.
Fuck!
Oh, shit!
Scotty, you're supposed
to watch out for trains.
Fuck, man, I didn't hear it.
Run, you stupid fucks!
It's like a rock, huh?
Yeah.
I'd better get your bike.
Me and my mom made a little cemetery
for them when they get old.
She won't let my dad eat 'em.
She doesn't believe in it.
And he listens to her?
He used to.
You guys gave
them a lot of names.
Yeah.
I never knew anyone
that died before.
Are your grandparents
still alive?
My mom's are.
I never met my dad's.
Probably dead.
I always thought...
if you're a good person...
when you died,
you'd just go straight to heaven.
Like a reward or something.
But then they just...
put you in the ground...
and bugs and worms eat you.
There's definitely a heaven.
There has to be.
Were they in love?
Who?
Your parents.
I guess so.
Want to know a secret?
Yeah.
Never mind.
Tell me.
I'm not gonna tell anybody.
You can calm a chicken...
by putting its
head in your mouth.
My mom showed me.
Your mom was a weirdo, too, huh?
No.
I didn't mean that.
You think I'm weird?
Yeah.
A little. Don't you?
I don't know.
Wanna try it?
See, that's what I'm
talking about, Duncan.
That's weird.
Duncan!
Coming.
- Is that it?
- That's it.
Today was kind of fun.
Hey, Mr. Mudge. Hey, Duncan.
Hey, Duncan,
you wanna do something?
We're just cruising around.
Come with us, Duncan.
Where's Perry?
We're going to pick him up.
Can I?
Yeah. Go ahead.
Let me get ready.
How you been, Mr. Mudge?
Just fine.
It's good.
Good to hear.
Duncan!
- Bye, dad.
- Ok.
Hey, you got money, right?
- Hold on a minute.
- Shit.
Buy something for
your friends there.
Wow!
- Thank you.
- Scotty, get the fuck out.
Please.
Yeah, right.
Hop in, buddy.
Hey, Duncan,
where's your chicken?
- I don't know.
- Bummer.
She's probably around somewhere.
Bye, dad.
Careful, now.
Take a pull, Duncan.
Drink, drink,
drink, drink, drink...
drink, drink,
Pumpkin!
Dandelion wine.
- How you feel, buddy?
- How are you feeling?
How you feeling, Duncan?
- Tingly.
- Tingly!
Tingly, huh?
Hey! Hey, Duncan.
Do it again, man.
Yeah, do it. Come on.
I shouldn't have done it.
- Come on, do it.
- Do it again.
- Do it.
Come on, do it.
Come on, man, do it.
Took an awful spill
off my bike today.
I need you to fix
those tires, Edgar.
They're awful wobbly.
Shit.
Hey!
Who is that guy?
Leave him alone.
He's a freak.
Freak!
Hold on...
to Duncan.
To Drunken!
- Drunken Mudge!
To the chicken boy!
Chicken boy!
- Chicken boy!
Hey!
- Drunken boy!
To the chicken boy!
Chicken boy!
Moo!
Fuck off!
Ahh! Oh, Jesus.
Perry, stop it!
Shit!
Get him, Perry!
Perry, that's enough!
Hurry, do something!
- Perry, that's enough!
- Perry, no!
Don't talk like that to a lady,
you fucking faggot!
Perry!
You fucking kicked his ass.
Perry, you beat
the shit out of him.
Motherfucker!
Teach that boy some manners.
You see that, Scotty?
Fuck, yeah, I saw it.
You're insane, Peraldo.
I'm cold.
Help!
Brent, take me home.
It's time to hook up
or pass out.
Guess which one you're doing.
Come on, Brent.
I'm getting all bitten up.
You're gonna have
to wait till I sober up.
I already fucked up
one truck like that.
Are you kidding me?
Perry, make him take me home.
I'm freezing.
Perry, I'm talking to you!
Come here, baby.
I'll warm you up.
Get over here.
April!
Get off of me!
You like that?
What's the matter with you?
You're taking forever.
Nothing.
Keep doing it.
April?
Let's go.
We're leaving.
I gotta go.
Let's go!
- You're kidding me.
- No. Sorry. I gotta go.
April, come on. I got us a ride.
You're a fucking bitch.
Fuck you!
Pervert.
Fucking tease!
You're in the shithouse
with me, man.
No, I know. I'm sorry, Perry.
I didn't, I didn't mean to.
Forget it.
I'm, I'm sorry, Perry.
I know something we could do.
- Hurry the fuck...
- Dude, Duncan was watching.
Shut up. I'm tired.
- They're gonna fucking leave.
- Ok, ok.
My dad put all
her stuff out here.
Why?
He wants to forget her, I guess.
She sure had a lot of shit.
Yeah.
Hey, thanks, Perry.
For what?
Being nice.
My knuckle is bleeding.
You see me hit that guy?
The fucker cut me.
Here.
Fix your hairdo.
Pew! Oh, it stinks.
My mom could play that.
- Yee-haw!
- Shh! My dad.
Oops.
Check this out.
Try it on.
What else is there?
Come on. It's funny.
Uh, I'm not supposed to.
Just try it on.
Alright. Let's get out of here if
you don't want to have any fun.
But you don't think it's weird?
Uh-uh.
It's just the two of us.
Who cares?
You really want me to?
I don't want you to.
I just thought it'd be funny.
Like Halloween or something.
Me and my mom used
to go trick-or-treating.
This old lady, miss McGee,
who lived up the road from us...
Not over your clothes.
It won't look right.
And, uh, ha...
well...
everyone...
used to think she
was a witch, 'cause...
her house,
it did look kind of haunted.
But, um, so, one
year we go up there...
and we go on her porch...
and she just comes...
running out of there,
waving her broomstick at us...
and yelling and saying that...
if we didn't get out...
she'd call the constable.
Turn around.
Looks good.
- Yeah.
- Mm...
don't take it off.
You gotta do the back up.
It was weird, 'cause
she really did look like a witch, but...
we just felt kind of
bad for her, though.
Even though she
didn't give us any candy.
I remember that old lady.
She was a fucking bitch.
You sure swear a lot, Perry.
What? Bitch?
Perry.
- Are you a bitch?
- No.
- Quit it!
- Bitch.
- Huh?
- Quit it, Perry.
Huh? What?
Say it.
Say it!
I'm a bitch.
Take it out.
Take it out!
Go on.
Tastes like pee.
Keep doing it.
Ow!
Fuck, that hurt.
Perry.
- What the fuck is the matter with you?
- I'm sorry.
Would you stop fucking
saying that? Alright?
- I'm not mad at you.
- What are you doing?
What are you doing?
Perry, what are you doing?
Shh.
Perry?
Hold still.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
- Alright?
- Perry.
Spread your legs.
Further.
That's it.
Shh.
I'm just gonna put it in a little.
Perry.
Ah!
That's not so bad, right?
You ok?
Yeah.
God, you're fucking tight.
It feels just like a pussy.
My dad says we might
be getting a new car.
It's about time.
Have you seen our old one?
My mom can hardly drive it
'cause the steering wheel shakes so bad.
You hear it coming
from a mile away...
'cause the muffler fell off.
It's fucking embarrassing.
Don't tell my dad, ok?
That's why she drives the truck.
Can you undo it?
I was trying to take it off.
I couldn't get it off.
You go on home, Perry.
Go in the house.
And take that thing off.
- I can't...
- I said, take it off!
I can't undo it.
- I'm sorry.
- Don't talk to me.
Get up.
I'm up.
Hey!
Wash up before you sit down.
You hear me?
Get up.
Move it.
Not so easy, is it?
Hmm?
I do it every goddamn day.
You're weak.
How you ever going to
take care of yourself, huh?
Hmm?
Get up.
Goddamn it, Duncan, get your
filthy ass off your mother's sofa.
Now!
In case you haven't noticed,
she's dead.
What's the matter with you?
Huh?
You can't even get into
trouble like a normal boy.
Alright.
Goddamn, alright. Alright.
Dad!
You can't!
Dad, you can't.
You can't. You can't.
- Go!
- You can't.
Go on!
Put them down.
Do it.
- Please!
- Put it down.
Please, dad.
I should have done
this from the start.
Perry.
Perry?
What the fuck are you doing?
I need to talk to you.
Jesus, Duncan.
You smell like shit.
What did your dad say?
Nothing.
Nothing?
He burned all my mom's stuff.
He didn't say anything about me?
No.
Are you sure?
He's only mad at me, you know.
I didn't tell him what you did.
We can't do nothing no more.
It ain't right.
- I didn't tell him, Perry.
- We can't do nothing no more.
It's queer.
I ain't no queer.
I know.
I'm sorry, Perry.
You're always sorry.
What are you sorry about?
You act like a goddamn
girl sometimes, Duncan.
Shit.
Perry.
What?
Did you ever...
Did you ever think
about kissing me?
You're crazy, Duncan.
No.
No way.
Is that what you want? Huh?
No.
You're a fucking faggot, Duncan.
Stay the fuck away from me.
Where the hell you been, Perry?
Just out smoking.
Just out smoking, huh?
Yeah.
What does "lights out"
mean, Perry?
I know I, I know I...
I know I've said it,
but I just...
just can't seem to remember.
Out wandering around time?
Out raising hell time?
Just out smoking time?
Bedtime.
Yeah, I guess that's it.
Jump!
Good girl.
Thank you.
One dollar.
Oh, I thought they were 75.
Thank you.
Chicken?
Chick, chick.
What are you doing?
Hey, chicken boy.
I like your chicken.
Don't you guys like his chicken?
Hell, yeah.
Let me see her?
Sure, Duncan, buddy.
I'm just kidding.
- Let me see her.
- Give her to me, Travis.
You want her?
Are we hanging out
tonight, Duncan?
It ain't a party without you.
Please?
Scotty, let me see her?
How you doing?
It's good to see you.
- Scotty, give her to me.
- How you doing?
Scotty, please.
I think something's
wrong with her, Duncan.
- Scotty, please.
- She doesn't look too good.
- Is she sick, Scotty?
- I think she might be.
- Scotty, please.
- Aw, chicken boy lost his chick.
Take her, Perry. You want her?
Trav...
What the fuck you looking at?
Perry, what happened?
What are you, a moron?
What do you think happened?
Happy now?
Perry, put your shirt down, man.
Faggot!
I'm not a faggot.
Oh...
truth hurts.
Doesn't it, ass humper?
I'm not!
Scotty, Scotty, Scotty, no!
Scotty!
Scotty? Scotty, don't!
What's wrong, chicken?
We're just fucking with you.
No!
- No, Perry!
- Fuck, yeah! Break its neck!
- Kill it, Perry!
- Kill it, fucking kill it!
- Kill it!
- Perry, kill it!
Fuck, yeah! Kill it!
Perry... Perry...
Perry!
Perry, no.
Let him go.
What the fuck are
you talking about, man?
What?
Let him go.
Brent, what the fuck, Brent?
Whoa.
- What the fuck are you doing, Perry?
- Shh, shh, it's ok.
You ain't no fucking fun
any more, Peraldo.
Yeah, dude, you're such a wet
noodle or wet blanket or whatever.
- Fucking wet something.
- Wet something, man.
Let's get out of here.
I'm not a faggot, Perry.
Why don't you show us
how you suck it, fudge boy?
Woo, yeah!
Why don't you suck it like
your mother showed you?
Excuse me, Mrs. Mudge,
can you teach me
how to suck a dick?
Oh, shit, he did it!
Motherfuck!
Tastes like chicken.
You weren't kidding, Perry.
Hey, Duncan, what are you doing later?
You got any plans?
Faggot.
Oh, shit!
Shit.
Oh, god.
Fucking!
Oh, Jesus Christ.
You are cold-blooded,
chicken boy.
What did you go and do?
Huh?
What happened?
I gotta go deal with it.
Let me go.
- Let me go.
- No.
Let me go. Let me go!
No.
Let me go.
- Let me go.
- No.
I love you.
Subtitles optimized by flitze
Original captions performed by
The National Captioning Centre