Showbox presents.
A hive media corp /
gemstone pictures production
the film depicts 40 days leading up to
the president's assassination
on oct. 26, 1979.
Although based on the story “kcia chiefs,”
which was serially published in the dong-a ilbo,
for 26 months starting from 1990, we have
taken creative liberties for certain settings.
October 26, 1979
presidential safehouse.
Moving to b wing.
Vip and 2 envoy cars confirmed.
When the nation
goes haywire, we all die.
Brace yourself.
Will you include the president?
We kill him tonight.
The castle has rundown,
only the tall grass remain...
On may 16, 1961, an army began
military coup d'etat.
The third Republic was established
and Korea's first intelligence agency
was founded.
Korean central intelligence agency
utilized its absolute power
fo ensure president park's 18-year rule.
Based in namsan, Seoul,
mere existence of kcia was a threat.
So-called 'directors of namsan, '
the kcia directors
were park's right-hand men.
The man standing next
40 days ago, Washington D.C.
Do you swear to tell the truth
and nothing but the truth?
Former director of kcia yong-gak park
chairman Fraser,
and the honorable representatives,
thank you for giving me
the opportunity
to speak to the subcommittee
on international organizations
of international relations
that boasts tradition and authority.
I no longer have the ambition
to be a politician in Korea.
I'm here only for the sake
of my beloved country,
where human rights are violated
and justice is nowhere to be found,
and for the sake of its democracy.
I was the head of Korea's
greatest intelligence agency.
I was rotten with power too,
and the reason why
I'm here to confess everything
is to accuse a man on top,
on top of that rotten power.
That man is president park!
He's the one who's making
democracy a tragedy in Korea!
Is the president inside?
He's getting a trim, sir.
My men tried to stop him
director of kcia gyu-pyeong Kim
from appearing at the hearing but...
Come on now.
Chief of presidential security
sang-cheon gwak
the north Korean leader wouldn't say that,
but our ex-kcia director said it!
What were you doing
while park sold our country off!
What's this about a memoir?
He's been spilling it
to the media and FBI.
Park believes that getting attention
is his only way to survive.
What should we do
with that traitor?
We must grab him and use him
as fertilizer in the back.
I will...
Take care of it quietly in America.
Can this be solved that way?
Did you not hear what he said?
Which is why we must
keep it under wraps.
America is watching this
very closely.
Goddamn yanks...
Gwak, you may go.
I need to speak to
director Kim alone.
How dare hel
proclaim that I am the man
who must vanish
from Korea before anyone else!
What will you do with him?
I'll first bring back his memoir.
What if he doesn't hand it over?
I'll bring it.
- Director Kim.
- Yes, Mr. president.
Do you also wish
for me to step down?
I held this seat
quite a while, no?
I will...
Always stay by your side.
September 18, Washington D.C.
Kcia agent dae-yong ham.
Deborah shim was the broker.
- Ms. shim?
- Yes.
Park is going around
telling everyone that
we can't kill him
because of the Americans.
I must return to Seoul
with park's manuscript.
Yes, sir.
Gosh...
It's me.
You're a director now.
Do you even know what
that position entails?
I hear gwak is head of security.
You got your plates full
competing with an idiot.
Let's head back.
You know why I sought asylum.
Are you really that angry?
You'll suffer the same fate.
Writing a book, huh?
Churchill won nobel literature prize.
I found my talent in writing.
I'll give you the prize money
for the manuscript.
Did I write it to make money?
Am I after money?
Even if the world thinks that way,
you of all people can't do that.
Give it to me.
Then beg the president
for forgiveness.
If I give it to you,
I'm a dead man.
You'll die if you don't.
Is that a threat?
I'm flying out tomorrow.
Decide.
Stay for a while,
don't leave so soon.
Until tomorrow.
Park made a grave
mistake he couldn't have
without your help, Ms. shim.
I'm the victim here.
Lobbyist Deborah shim
you know how I worked
to become a lobbyist here.
I suffered racism for
coming from a poor country,
no one here can even tell
North Korea from south.
I endured all that
in service of our country.
But when koreagate blew up,
you all shunned me,
and FBI threatens me to jail me
if I don't cooperate.
What am I to do?
So you sold Korea
with park as a front?
A good girl goes to heaven
but a bad one goes anywhere.
Can't return home.
Even a bad girl can't go
anywhere without money.
You're now responsible
for ex-dir. Park.
Give my agent every detail.
Your family back home
wants you to call them.
Are you threatening me?
It's peaceful.
So peaceful...
Gyu-pyeong,
why did you want the revolution?
And why did you?
I only did it because
you wanted to.
I did?
It wasn't you?
Me?
Goddammit.
- I don't know...
- Did you bring it?
Wait for this thing to blow over,
then return home quietly.
Director Kim.
Do you know why
I'm giving this to you?
Even if I die,
I won't die in your hands.
Let's walk.
Ever heard of 'lago'?
Iago from othello?
A pen suits you better
than a gun.
What do you want to say?
President park has a 'personal
intelligence agency, '
and that's what CIA's
calling the man behind it.
Iago.
I'm saying there's someone
with higher authority over us.
Give me a reliable source.
CIA has been digging into
the president's money trail,
they found out that
he's been funneling money
into Swiss accounts and slush
funds behind kcia's back.
He's trusting his personal
agency with it, not kcia.
Who is that?
- That I don't know.
- Since when?
I believe it's since the revolution.
To the revolutionary comrades!
To the comrades!
He will be one of us.
The president only trusts
those he knows intimately.
I'm sure it was no big deal then.
He did our background checks,
and did things the president
was embarrassed of making us do.
Then the president's power grew,
so did his rivals,
and the money piled up.
He couldn't lose any of it,
but couldn't trust anyone.
Congratulations, sir.
The world thought we were
second in command,
but no.
The real deal was someone else.
He had another man sucking
on his tits beside me.
You and I were just errand boys!
Director Kim,
how long do you think
the Americans will let him be?
It'll be over in a year.
He's making preparations.
He'll step down slowly,
and I'll be helping him.
You believe that bullshit?
Look at it.
This is like the Greek temple.
But Lincoln is like god here.
He still got shot and died.
Gyu-pyeond.
Why did we go through
with the revolution?
Why did we risk our lives for it?
September 20, presidential safehouse
park's book title is
'traitor of the revolution.'
so I betrayed the revolution?
'In the battlefield
called “revolution”,
president park led us valiantly
like a flag at the front.
But the war is over.
He alone remains
on the battlefield.
A flag tattered
and covered in blood,
as it dances in the wind,
he is the evidence of defeat.'
so many beasts
waiting to tear me apart.
I gotta leave them something.
They're all waiting for me to die.
What did park say?
Does he want me dead?
No, sir.
He has come around
and regrets deeply.
Please forgive him for my sake.
He should've taken
a break and waited.
Mr. president.
Have you heard of 'lago'?
What is it?
Shall we have rice wine cocktail?
The ratio is very important.
Here.
It's not like the old days.
Weren't you the 36th
regimental commander?
Yes.
The drink we had back then...
Was the greatest.
Those were...
The days.
Those days
were great.
September 21, blue house
pull that out.
Rip them apart!
Take out all the books
and check them out!
Find every piece of yank's hair!
Rip the bottom of sofa
and look there too.
Find it thoroughly!
Plunder of sovereignty!
Do you see?
What?
How could the kcia not know
when the yanks wiretapped
our president's office!
I'm appalled!
They're gunning for us!
Who are they?
We confirmed it's CIA,
we are scanning everything!
Get them out. Call our guys.
How could I trust someone
so incompetent?
- Your excellency is entering.
- Get them out right...
Goddamn ignorant bastards!
They're taking us for fools,
how dare they bug
the president's desk!
What the hell were you doing?
I'll look into it, sir.
You must send an envoy
and make a strong objection.
The un should know about this!
Am I right, Mr. secretary?
Chief secretary gye-hoon Kim
get me the ambassador!
Have him kneel before our flag!
Korea's pride is on the line!
Us ambassador Robert.
Goddammit!
Kcia assistant secretary
Chang-su kang
sir, I looked into those guys
gwak brought in for bugs.
Strangely, there was
a professor among them.
A professor?
Educated in America, he's training
the security division's wiretap team.
Find out more about him.
Yes, sir.
Gwak must've brought in
tanks to protect the president.
I told you not to do this!
That son of a bitch!
Are we on a cursed land?
Why are all security chiefs
so moronic?
Why are tanks guarding here?
Does it elevate
the president's authority?
Seniors in the area
had heart attacks,
thinking it was a commie invasion.
Gwak even kicked assemblymen
in the knees at national assembly.
Can't you do something?
There's a rumor that the president
only cares for gwak lately.
He has to look after the idiot.
Congratulations
from chief executive gwak
security commander du-hyeok chun
thank you, sir.
It'll come in handy.
By the way, general chun,
are you in bad terms
with director Kim?
What do you mean, sir?
When I recommended you
for security commander,
Kim objected heavily.
Is that right?
Director of kcia is here.
What? Director Kim?
Tell him I'm not here.
Director Kim.
I actually wanted to talk to you.
Please sit down.
I'm told you played soldier
at national assembly yesterday.
I heard the opposition party
was on a hunger strike,
so I went there to feed them.
Isn't this your duty?
Kcia doesn't do that now.
Then what does kcia do?
You didn't even know
CIA bugged the president!
Men have personalities,
and nations have dignity.
This is the blue house.
It's where personality
and dignity come together.
Send in the tanks again,
and I'll bulldoze your office first.
Stop acting out and
protect the president!
Got that, it. Col. Gwak?
Director Kim.
He is the country.
It is my duty to
protect the country.
You're the one who doesn't
know what your duty is.
You know that saying,
work in the shade and
face the sun or something.
Think of yourself
as a mushroom or moss
and stay in the dark
and moist room.
You disgusting cockroach!
Why are you here
pretending to be a man?
This is not the place
for you to mess around!
The president and others
should see this!
Why are you so titillated?!
I hope others don't think
we did anything explicit!
So embarrassing!
Son of a bitch!
I'll bury you in the backyard!
Stupid asshole!
- Goddamn cockroach!
- Son of a bitch!
- Shithead!
- You bastard!
- Director!
- Sirl
you're just a damn Minion!
This is a mutiny!
Goddamn cockroach!
Court martial him right away!
How dare he point his gun
at chief of security!
Director, you better go.
- He should be shot!
- Director Kim!
It's a coup! A coup!
Who'd you think you're
pointing a gun at?
He calls himself my senior!
Let's barge into their hq
in namsan!
And see if they can
still take us down!
September 22, myeong-dong, Seoul.
A New York times reporter
is staying at the Plaza hotel,
so see if he conducts
an interview with governor Kim.
Traitor of the revolution
by yong-gak park.
Governor Kim had an interview
with a New York times reporter.
- What did he say?
- He demanded that usa use official and
direct pressure to control you.
What?
It'll be on the front page
of New York times tomorrow.
- Did you know?
- Yes, sir.
What should we do?
This is a clear act of hostility.
You must expel the governor at once.
If you did that for
doing an interview,
usa won't stay put.
Are you a kcia director
or a CIA director?
If you like usa that much,
go and join CIA.
If you expel governor Kim,
the public will not remain calm.
Security commander is requesting
an immediate audience.
Let him in.
Ex-kcia director's memoir unveiled,
debunking president park's myths
am I insane?!
Why'd I dig my own grave?!
You should've buried
or burned the memoir!
Why didn't you?!
I got rid of it!
Only FBI and kcia dir. Kim
have a copy...
Is Kim screwing me over?
Why'd he do such a thing?
Secret is your upper hand,
how could you just open up?
There's no secret in that book.
I'm a bad guy,
they're bad too, everyone's bad.
There's no secrel.
There's only one message
to that memoir,
let's all die,
I'm not going down alone,
let's all diel
no secret in it!
Goddammit! There is no secret.
When will I ever go back home?
When will the days of
those bastards end?
Will the world change?
Only in its name.
Speaking of that,
If the president's pushed out,
who'd have America's back?
They won't trust a soldier again.
But they have a relationship
with gyu-pyeong.
And gwak is a useless prick.
At least they can
talk civilly with him.
Will he do well?
About what?
You're up to something.
You think it's a bad idea?
Gyu-pyeong won't last long,
he has to wake up.
The president doesn't
let his number two alive.
There is only one sun.
Councilor Kim opposes the third
constitutional amendment?
Yes, sir.
A considerable number
of councilors are backing him.
What do you recommend?
I'll only follow your order.
You have my full support.
Do as you please.
Good work with
the third amendment.
Thank you, sir.
Why don't you take a break?
It looks bad in the media.
Both parties are going nuts.
You should've gone easy.
Sir, but councilor Kim...
Why?
Why are you making me
look like a bad guy again?
Did you think you'd be safe
after beating a man like that?
Sir, I did my best for you.
Are you buying up lands?
Pardon?
I heard you're buying up lands
in this small country.
Leave the moneybag and go home.
Stay home until I call you.
Mr. president!
I, yong-gak park, have
never had any money issue.
I swear I wasn't blinded
by selfish interests!
Cough it all out.
Don't get yourself killed
for being greedy.
Mr. president! Sir!
Your excellency!
Sirl
sirl.
September 26, kcia hq in namsan.
Sir, the professor who trained
wiretapping to security division,
he was in Washington.
He wiretapped director park there.
He's downstairs.
You studied at a good school,
prof. Lim.
I'm just a freelancer.
I was told you wiretapped
kcia ex-dir. Park in Washington.
This is the kcia.
All right,
consider yourself dead,
and spill everything you know.
I met a kcia agent there.
James ryu was posing
as an exporter.
I found him visiting
the embassy often.
And this kcia agent ryu
hired you to wiretap park?
Yes.
When I returned, I got a call
from the security division.
I was hired to wiretap you.
Me?
Bug me?
I found out who scouted
prof. Lim in America.
James ryu,
Korean name is dong-hoon yoo.
He's at the Paris embassy now.
A kcia agent acted without my order.
Who gave him an order?
When yoo was in the airborne,
he was gwak's aide.
Dong-hoon yoo
gwak was the one who
recommended him to kcia.
Send agent ham to Paris.
September 29, Paris, France
then in the hotel?
Best thing is to bring him
to koreaq.
Ambassador tae-ho yoon
it's a little difficult here.
Kcia agent dong-hoon yoo.
He'll drag me down?
He's in close contact
with the Americans.
Is park so desperate to die?
Mr. president.
Should we eliminate him?
Sir, I have something to tell you.
Idiot...
October 1, Korean embassy in Paris
- have you had lunch?
- Yes.
Sir, ambassador yoon has
invited park to Paris.
Tell yoon to carry out the plan.
October 2, speaker of the house
welcome party.
Director, good to see you.
General chun!
Come greet him.
This is...
Us embassy is on
the best site in Korea.
Just feel that air.
Right?
Park heard from a feng shui
friend in Hong Kong,
the blue house is on the
most omnious site in Korea.
Which is why the owner
can't get out of there alive.
Dragging him out
is best for the owner too.
Park says he can't
wait any longer.
What does he mean?
He wants to do it.
He says it's time
for a new owner.
Are you nuts?
You already know,
it's just a matter of time.
No one in this room
has not thought about it.
Who'll pull out the sword first,
who'll cross han river first?
Who'll plant the flag first?
You have a nice dream.
It may be a dream to park,
but not to you.
Do you think I'd send you
to the lion den on your own?
The ambassador has
invited park to Paris.
Yoon?
Yes.
He has also invited the former
prime minister hwang in Tokyo.
Hwang's coming?
Yes.
He and yoo are taking orders
from gwak.
Watch closely and see what
yoo and yoon are conspiring.
I will, sir.
October 4, place vendome, Paris.
Director park!
It's been too long!
You look tired.
Let's catch up for
the lost time, come on.
Hwang is flying in
from Tokyo for you,
it's best to resolve this
through him.
So I should kneel
and beg to hwang?!
The president said to hwang,
“I gave up!
I don't wanna fight with park
anymore, just bring him in.”
He'll forgive you
if you return his money.
What money?
What money did I take?
Did he really say that?
Do this right.
The president listens to hwang,
you know that.
You sure director Kim
is getting fired?
Yes.
He's barely holding on
because of you.
He couldn't even attend
the morning assembly.
Gwak pushed him out!
The one managing president's
Swiss bank account is lago.
This man blindsided us, kcia
and got on top.
Give me a reliable source.
CIA has been digging into
the president's money trail,
they found out that
he's been funneling
money into Swiss accounts,
and slush funds without kcia.
Sir, yoo obtained guns
through his Israeli contact.
As you said, gwak may be
planning to assassinate park.
How should I proceed?
Director?
Yeah...
Mr. president.
You and I are the only ones
working late.
I'm feeling lonesome, a drink?
Gyu-pyeond.
Yes, sir.
When do you think I'm done?
It's not like I'll live
thousands of years.
Who should be my successor?
You should be it.
Why? Not feeling it?
I will always stand by you.
What will you do with park?
Sir,
what would you like me to do?
You have my full support.
Do as you please.
Traitor of the revolution
by yong-gak park.
Sir, I got 3 Algerian killers
on standby.
Where's park?
He's at the hotel.
Deborah shim is arriving soon.
What's your order, sir?
October 7, Paris
Charles de gaulle airport.
Where's park?
He's in the casino.
It's good for park that
Kim's on his side.
18-year dictatorship is over.
You want me to lure park?
Kim wanted me to tell park
that I got his full support.
What the hell is he doing?
Kim is an asshole.
Watch your mouth.
You should've told me earlier
this is how it's gonna play out.
This isn't funny.
Kcia's bad at their job?
Would you have come
to Paris then?
I don't know why
I agreed to this.
You can go back to D.C. now,
but you'll never return to Seoul.
Are you threatening me?!
It's your choice,
but you must choose one.
Goddammit!
Seoul arts theatre
17th anniversary performance of
children's dance company.
Yoon will bring park
to suite 407.
Where's prime minister hwang?
His flight got delayed
due to strong wind.
We'll meet here when he arrives.
- Here?
- Upstairs, suite 407.
I'll go to the front desk
and see if hwang checked in.
I told you not to bet it all.
I'm getting great hands.
I might go big today.
What brings you here to France?
I came with Johnson.
Take park to suite 407.
Director Kim wants you to wait.
Gyu-pyeong?
Heard he's been abandoned.
What?
Us councilors I went with
all had meetings only with him.
Ambassador yoon, you bastard...
What?
Gyu-pyeong will do it?
A few councilors and Johnson
are at a nearby diner.
What?
Let's go say hello,
we need our own plan.
And change your reputation.
The councilors really hate you.
Korean politicians hate me too.
Excuse us.
How did you know I was here?
Director Kim told me.
How did he know?
Aren't we walking?
I got high heels on.
I'm sorry, we lost him.
I think someone else intervened.
- Oh no, my hat!
- What is it?
Such a strong wind.
What the hell?!
My nose, my nose!
He bit my nose!
The operation is complete.
October 18, blue house
director Kim, your thoughts?
You must reinstate governor Kim,
make amend with
the opposition party.
Director Kim!
The rioters lit up police station,
screaming to overthrow us!
That's a declaration of war!
Sir, they're not citizens anymore,
they're rioters.
Declare martial law in busan.
If you do that, the riot could
spread to nearby cities.
Run them over with tanks,
it's all over.
Disturbance in busan, fire linked to riot
army chief of staff, thoughts?
Army chief of staff seung-ho Chang.
What am I supposed to do?
If we send in an airborne brigade,
we can suppress it immediately.
Sir, you can't declare martial law.
Let's control it with the airborne.
Declare martial law.
Park went missing?
He will not be found.
I'll go meet governor Kim.
Please lift the martial law.
If we can't find him,
what about the money he took?
Pardon?
I don't care if he's missing or not.
He's a traitor anyway.
I buried him a long time ago,
just bring back
the money he took.
Aside from some he embezzled,
there's nothing much...
Sir, it'll get messy from now on.
Usa will not stay put.
I'll make this go away,
but I need your cooperation.
Cooperation?
Kim,
are you threatening me?
If you want to threaten me,
do so with something enticing.
What's with you lately?
Just get me what I asked for.
Where's gwak?
Yes, Mr. president.
Director, there's an event
tonight at our safe house.
Head there then.
The president only invited gwak.
He didn't invite me?
No, sir.
The pressure to supply
color TV is immense.
Do you want our people
to see me in color?
I like black and white.
You look better
in black and white!
They say Kim is next in line, and
he communicates well in english.
Any news from busan?
I took care of the evidence
for the connection with
the north and the opposition party.
What is the matter with Kim?
Did you see him glare at me
at the mention of airborne?
It's a state of emergency.
Why is he so foolish?
Sir, Kim is done.
Yes?
Okay.
The rioters in busan
are going mad.
They even lit up a TV station.
I'll go make a call.
Only moonlight shines
on the land
of the fallen kingdom
it expresses futility
of this world.
Oh, you poor thing
as I search aimlessly.
For...
Yes.
What?
What did they say?
I'm over?
Did that yank really say that?
What did Kim say?
That bastard is the same!
What can he do by
siding with the Americans?
If he loves democracy so much,
tell him to go and live in usa.
He even killed his own friend.
How can I trust him
to be by my side?
Son of a bitch...
What do you think
I should do with Kim?
You have my full support.
Do as you please.
He even killed his own friend.
How can I trust him
to be by my side?
Son of a bitch...
What do you think
I should do with Kim?
You have my full support.
Do as you please.
Director.
Your attention is needed
in busan, sir.
The situation is grave.
October 24, busan
the rioters have taken over
the TV station!
The riot is quickly
spreading out to masan,
from students and regular citizens,
it's like the uprising that
toppled president Lee's regime.
It may be a dream to park,
but not to you.
Why did we go through
with the revolution?
Why did we risk our lives?
You were in busan? How was it?
They were just students
and citizens, sir.
They burned down a station,
they're no regular citizens.
Intimidation will not work.
Intimidation?
Reinstate the governor,
and work things out
with the congress.
Did I threaten the citizens?
Mr. president.
Take a broad outlook
in the politics.
Busan and masan aren't islands.
The situation could spread to Seoul.
I put you in your position
to stop that.
How can we stop a forest fire?
The forest must
burn down for it to die.
Hey you!
How come a kcia director
cannot even contain a small riot?!
Before the commies spread,
we must take special measures!
You know, in Cambodia
they sacrificed 3 million people,
killing a million or 2
with tanks is nothing!
Gwak is right.
In the days of liberals,
generals got executed
for opening fire to the rioters.
But if I order to open fire,
who will execute me?
- So?
- Sirl you are absolutely right!
Isn't that right, general chun?
Absolutely.
All settled, let's move to
the sapgyo river ceremony.
He wants you to stay put!
There's no room for you!
We should cancel the unveiling
ceremony of sir an jung-geun statue.
Why?
There's a crack in the statue.
Blue house
yes, Mr. president.
There's an event tonight at 6,
so you should attend.
Grab some commies and
tie them to the busan riot.
We'll run them over with tanks.
Do it right!
Get the chief of staff.
Right away, sir.
October 26, 1979
presidential safehouse.
Moving to b wing.
Vip and 2 envoy cars confirmed.
Director Kim makes
the best cocktails.
Indeed, sir.
I'm good at being a bartender.
Despite his vices,
he's good with drinks.
Director Kim.
Yes, sir.
I organized this night for you.
Have a drink.
Did you feel neglected?
Come in.
Wipe away that frown.
Don't be so proud.
Here.
Chief of staff, I'm sorry.
The president dropped by
all of sudden.
Let's meet another day.
No, not at all.
I'll wrap it up quickly,
go have dinner first.
When the nation
goes haywire, we all die.
Brace yourself.
Chief of staff is present.
Once this is over, we take him
to namsan and take over the army.
Will you include the president?
We kill him tonight.
The security is too tight tonight.
- We should postpone.
- Nol!
There will be a leak.
Have a couple of
smart ones on standby.
The castle has rundown,
only the tall grass remain,
depicting how futile
our lives are
a lonesome stranger
cannot fall asleep alone
he Wells up al the sound of
mournful crickets
- good evening, sir.
- Hey.
Did you have dinner?
Yeah, go on, I had it already.
Okay.
The president doesn't eat much.
It's so comfy coming here,
kcia does all the security,
nothing to worry about.
Sir, allow me
to pour you a drink.
Sure.
Do you remember
the night of revolution?
You and I were half way
across the han river,
and we saw mp police line.
I followed you off the Jeep
and walked across the bridge...
A bullet came flying.
It was too dark to see anything.
But we heard the bullet whiz by.
You asked me then,
“gen. Kim, what should we do?”
“A man's path isn't
always filled with laughs,
but a storm cannot stop a man
with determination.
Sir, let's go!”
That's what you said.
He had balls back then,
but all shriveled up lately...
Had we not crossed
that bridge...
None of us would be here.
Let's all drink for park,
who is not here today.
You know the drill.
We drink and become
one with the ghost.
Park was one of us, no?
Isn't that right, sir?
You got a death wish?
How could you govern with
this cockroach by your side?
The country is in ruins.
Kim, stop it!
- What are you doing?
- Mr. president!
You must step down at once.
- Enough!
- Step down!
You bastard!
Sit down!
Director Kim.
Do you know why
I put you in your position?
Trying to be almighty
after killing his friend?
Do your damn job.
Mr. president.
Why did you carry out
the revolution?
Why did we risk our lives!
For revolution?
Kill one or two million
citizens with tanks?
Please, sir!
Get it together!
You're out of your mind!
Know your place!
What the hell?
What are you doing?
- You should die too!
- No, Kim!
Nol
sirl.
Mr. president!
Blood...
Help!
- Don't move!
- What are you doing?!
Sirl
help! Someone help!
Bring me a gun! Now!
Col. Kang!
Where are you?!
Right here, sir!
Gun! Give me a gun!
- Guards?
- All dead.
Why did the lights go off?!
Security!
I'm okay...
You're executed for being
a traitor of the revolution.
Director!
Sir, what do we do now?
It's all over.
I'll bring the chief of staff,
we're going back to namsan.
C... clean it up.
It's all over.
What's going on?
The president was assassinated.
What... how did it happen?
Well...
Did you see my shoes?
I'm missing my shoes.
Director, let's go to the army hq.
Why go to namsan?
We must declare martial law
at the army hq,
and figure out
the north's movement.
Go to the army hq.
Director, where should we go?
What?
Kcia or army headquarters?
Kim ultimately went to the army hq
and was arrested upon arrival.
The military court sentenced him
to death by hanging.
Swiss bank account transactions
47 days after the assassination,
a new military coup took place,
leading to another military dictatorship.
According to
the joint investigation committee,
Kim was discontent as he believed
that the president distrusted him,
and only favored the chief of security.
He feared his potential dismissal,
relating to the disturbance
in busan and masan,
and becoming delusional,
committed the murder
of the president and the chief of security.
This is a crime to create a disturbance,
driven by the vain desire
of becoming the president.
The goal of October 26 revolt
was to restore democracy of Korea,
and to prevent even more sacrifices.
I did not start the revolution
to become a president.
I am a soldier and a revolutionist.
I am not testifying here today
for any leniency.
I wish for your honor to judge me
fairly with just sentence.
This concludes my statement.
Thank you.
Subtitle By: MARSH-MARIE.
Directed by woo min-ho.
Lee byung-hun.
Lee sung-min
kwak do-won.
Lee hee-jun.
Kim so-Jin
produced by
Kim won-kuk, kang Sarah
executive producers
Kim do-soo, hwang soon-il