It's raining today.
Not playing in the yard.
There will be plenty of mud.
If you slip, you shall hurt you.
-- Play inside.
-- Okay.
And do not walk under the trees.
A tree fell yesterday
a bridge collapsed,
it was on the news.
But it stopped raining.
It can resume.
Here it is.
Wait!
A minute!
Thou hast put all the spices?
No Auntie, I forgot one.
I felt, the whistling!
Want.
Thank you, Auntie.
Just a pinch.
Okay.
This new recipe will work.
Are you sure?
You doubt,
but you'll see.
Yum ... perfect!
A mouthful,
and he will build you a Taj Mahal.
The Taj Mahal is a tomb.
I know!
Retrieves them.
Fernandes.
I present Shaikh.
Shaikh, Mr Fernandes.
He was chief accountant
in a small Saudi company.
He will take your notes to your departure
in one month.
It has very good references.
Delighted.
Mr. Shroff fill you with praise.
I did come early
for you to truly form.
Good luck.
Mr. Shroff said it 35 years
you're here.
Your colleagues will miss you.
What does it do?
This is the beginning of your golden age,
how do you feel?
Beautifully.
Awesome!
Can we start training?
Course.
But it's lunchtime.
Return to 16 h 45.
Well, at any hour.
Thank you!
Today
the recipe for one of my favorite dishes:
"paneer pyaza do."
Auntie!
-- Do you sleep?
-- What happened?
The lunchbox is back.
Then?
It is empty.
Is that true?
Completely!
It all sauced!
What did I tell you?
And this is just the beginning!
Stops the tape,
Rajeev is back.
Okay.
You're home early, the better.
Did you like your breakfast?
It was good.
Well ... no more?
As everyday.
The lunchbox was empty,
then I thought ...
Cauliflower was very good.
It was very good.
I just got back.
I was expecting your call.
It was so boring?
I left early too.
A problem, sir?
I retire.
I would like to stop delivery.
Okay, I take note.
I will pay you at the end of the month.
No problem.
And. .. who cooked today?
Us, why?
It was good!
-- What?
-- It was very good.
Continue on this path.
What has?
Cauliflower liked him.
Do it again tomorrow.
Like, serve it.
What do you do?
Mr. Fernandes, our ball fell
at home. It can recover?
Please!
-- I look like a maid?
-- No.
It will no longer play here.
We'll go to the other side.
If you replay here, I hunt you.
Please!
We'll play somewhere else!
I'm here, Auntie.
You called me just now?
Yes.
I changed diapers Tonton.
Rajeev has said?
Nothing.
What?
The lunchbox was delivered elsewhere.
I do not think Rajeev has received it.
Someone else ate the meal.
But they are never wrong,
impossible.
What does he?
Hello, how are you?
Good morning.
When I returned,
you were not there.
-- You were late.
-- I came to 16 h 45 accurate.
I was there, you were late.
No problem.
These are the claims?
It is the claims service here.
When do we start my training?
Let's go.
Now?
After lunch.
-- I'll be back after then?
-- Yes, come.
-- Are you sure?
-- Yes.
You will be right there?
Thank you.
Thank you all ate yesterday.
I cooked this dish for my husband.
Seeing the empty box,
I thought it welcome me
coming back.
I thought,
Within a few hours
that satisfy the stomach,
it was to seduce the heart.
thank you
here paneer.
favorite dish of my husband.
Auntie, this letter is weird.
Ila, you should thank him.
And if it is Rajeev who receives?
Better.
He eats meals someone else.
His noticing today!
I do not write anything else?
No, it should remain short!
You sleep?
Then?
The lunchbox is back.
Empty yet. With a reply.
-- A response?
-- Yes.
Read it to me.
This is not writing Rajeev.
And what does it say then?
"Dear Ila. Food
today was very salty. "
And what else?
"The food
today was very salty. "
What? No "thank you", no?
"The food
today was very salty. "
Who does it?
It swallows everything and he complains?
A minute.
Here, put--in.
No, it bothers me.
I say to the driver
there was an error.
It should thank you!
No, I really do not like it.
Why? You do not know.
Good morning. How are you?
Property.
You were not at your desk,
I came here.
You read in the canteen,
I do not want to bother.
Your meal exhales a delicious aroma.
I tasted the food
just by feeling!
Your wife ...
has magic in his hands.
My wife is dead.
Dear Ila, salt,
it was this time.
It was perhaps a little spicy ...
but I ate two bananas for dessert,
they extinguished the fire.
And it's good for my circulation.
So many people
simply a banana or two
at noon.
It's cheap and it fills.
Hello.
My husband came home late last night.
He did not say a word.
This morning, he went to work,
and my daughter to school.
And I cooked with Auntie Deshpande.
This is our upstairs neighbor.
Her husband is immersed
in a coma for 15 years.
One day he woke up
and began to fix the fan.
fixed all day
and falls asleep at night.
Upon awakening, he went back to fix it.
He said nothing.
For 15 years.
Even doctors have lost all hope.
This is an old model fan.
It is never extinguished.
Auntie  think it keeps him alive.
One day, there was
a power outage.
He stopped
and his pulse slowed.
Fortunately, the electricity came back.
since Auntie installed a generator.
Her husband continues
attach the fan.
mine fixed his phone.
as if nothing else existed.
This may be the case.
What do we live?
Dear Ila,
Your husband seems to be busy.
Today
people are very busy.
There are too many people,
and everyone wants
that the other features.
Before, you could
sit in the train,
but nowadays, it's hard.
If Mr. Deshpande was waking up,
it probably prefer
his fan.
When my wife died,
she had a horizontal fall.
I wanted to buy one for me,
but they had
as vertical.
I spent my whole life standing.
It will be the same in my death.
Why do not you
another child?
It can sometimes help a marriage.
Rajeev?
What do you say?
It's pretty.
You forgot?
I reach
during our honeymoon.
I wanted to see
if she needed alterations.
But it suits me very well,
-- Right?
-- Yes.
It is a little wide.
Yes ...
On our return, we did not know
Yashvi that happened.
It was known much later.
Two months later!
We did not have much
at the time.
When she was born,
luck smiled on us.
Everything is so expensive today,
luck is not enough.
Why you prepare me
cauliflower every day?
You have a stock to sell?
Rajeev.
And if Yashvi had a little brother
or sister?
You had a brother you.
And ...
I pray thee, over cauliflower,
it gives me gas.
Cars, buses, airplanes:
all trapped in Mumbai we are.
This road is bottled
since this morning.
You see this tower?
A woman jumped this morning
with his little girl.
She jumped?
What was it?
I do not know.
Surely domestic problems.
You know someone
who lives there?
She did not survive?
Hello.
this morning
my husband went to the office ...
Hello, sir.
How are you?
I'm busy.
And my training?
It's lunchtime.
Check back later.
I was told to expect nothing
on your part.
I'm Aslam Shaikh.
I'm an orphan.
I gave myself that name.
All I know
I taught myself.
And I also teach this work.
I finished. Thank you.
Listen.
Come on.
Go to my office.
There are records
of Ahmedabad sector.
Calculate the amounts
and prepare payment orders
for accounting.
Thank you very much.
I'll be right back.
No, do not come back, go to work.
Yes sir, thank you very much.
This morning my husband went to the office
and Yashvi school.
I listened to the news on the radio.
the death of my brother,
everyone said:
he should be brave.
He missed his exams, so what?
He should be brave.
What  thought this woman?
Maybe she has removed her jewelry ...
Bracelets, earrings,
wedding necklace ...
What  asked his daughter?
We play what, Mom?
It must have been difficult
reaching to the roof.
Must we not courage
to jump as well?
Dear Ila,
do not see it that way.
They never go
as bad as you think.
One day on the train
taking me to work,
I suddenly felt something.
Someone touched me ...
down ...
You laugh?
Yes, Auntie.
A joke.
Tell!
I forgot.
-- You forgot?
-- Yes.
Soak almonds 5 am every night.
And eat them in the morning.
It strengthens memory.
Noted.
How are you?
-- You go to the station?
-- Yes.
I get off at Central Station
Bombay.
I live in Dongri.
And you?
At Bandra.
Can I ask you a question?
Yes.
At the office, it is said that walking ...
you gave a kick
a cat.
A bus has crashed and you have continued
your way, nonchalantly.
Is that true?
It was not a cat.
But a blind man.
He asked his way,
so I pushed
and a coach ran into him.
So be careful.
Thank you.
Give me a cigarette.
I'll pay later.
This is a joke, right?
Have you always lived in Bandra?
Yes, always.
I move constantly.
At first, I was way Muhammad Ali.
Then I went to Dubai,
then in Saudi Arabia.
I was commuting
between there and here.
But after meeting Meherunissa,
I stayed.
I cut vegetables here
and I cook when I get home.
Where did you learn to do that?
Before I worked in a hotel.
A hotel?
Kitchen, room service,
accounting ...
All in one.
It is dry in Saudi Arabia.
No entertainment:
work--prayer, prayer--work ...
Here I have free time.
I cook for Meherunissa,
we eat when she gets home.
-- And then we walk.
-- Very well.
I love her more than anything.
That evening you doing?
I watch TV sometimes.
Come to me.
-- Where?
-- My house.
I will make you a "Pasanda".
-- A what?
-- "Pasanda".
-- What is it?
-- A dish made with lamb.
You cut it like that.
-- From the lamb?
-- Yes.
My specialty.
I will come.
-- Now.
-- Right now?
Yes, please!
No, I work another time.
Next time promised?
I can wait ...
Next time.
-- See you soon.
-- Goodbye.
Hello.
My husband came home late yesterday.
He returned to work
after a call.
Yashvi asleep.
my marriage, I took business
without telling my mother.
I found an old book.
It contains recipes
my grandmother.
I found an apple.
Tis the season.
I think you'll like it.
Excellent!
How are you?
I can sit?
Please.
Thank you.
Want a taste?
Are you sure?
Yes.
What does he?
Where does this meal?
A restaurant near me.
Why?
It is delicious.
Book a meal for me.
They close soon.
With food so delicious?
The talent is not rewarded
in this country.
You are right, sir.
It must be magic
in his hands.
Everyone can cook,
but it must be magic.
Dear Ila,
this recipe was very good.
Better than my favorite dish,
eggplant.
Yesterday, I also
found something.
old emissions
my wife recorded.
You probably were
not yet born at the time.
My wife loved them.
I wanted to watch,
who knows why.
I have watched for hours.
Episode after episode.
After spending the night
I understood what I was looking for.
Every Sunday
while she watched,
I stood outside,
fix my bike or smoke.
I threw him a glance
from time to time.
And I saw his reflection on the screen,
still laughing at the jokes ...
she knew by heart.
If only I had continued
to look at the time ...
I forwarded
all payment orders.
An apple and a banana for you.
Go ahead.
No, sir.
I insist.
Okay.
What is that?
A leaf.
Can I have some water,
please?
Then, right?
I love it.
Thank you.
Today, we no longer send
letters. As emails.
More letters?
This is the era of emails.
Hello.
My mother loves
old serials.
Small , I watched
for hours.
I wanted to tell you something.
Each cigarette smoke,
it is 5 min of life and less.
My father has lung cancer.
When he suffers too,
he said he would have to smoke more
for not
to deal with this pain.
Do not blame me.
Yes, Auntie?
You have my carrots?
They are there.
Here!
They cost only 10 rupees.
What have you taken other?
As usual.
What other food can you cook
based eggplant?
can fry them, stuff them,
bake ...
It follows a new treatment.
It helps,
but he sleeps all day.
Mom? Where's the TV?
There are currently more good emissions
nowadays.
You need money?
It comes out.
This treatment is very expensive.
It's OK, I got it.
But how?
Where do you find the money?
If my son was there,
I would not have to beg.
I'll talk to Rajeev.
It's no go.
I ask 5000.
It is the family of the bride.
What was the air
to ask all this money?
You can pay little by little.
No.
I have money.
I got it.
Well, okay.
But do not tell your father.
The 5000 should be sufficient
for this month.
Next month
else be found.
You wanna see it?
I wake up?
It's late, we must go back.
Okay.
Dear Ila,
You will not believe
what happened to me yesterday.
the evening, on my way to the station
with Shaikh,
my colleague,
the urge took me
look at the paintings of an artist.
They are all identical.
But if you look closer,
we note that each
is slightly different.
Here  a car and more
there a man who dreams in a bus.
Or a dog crossing the street.
What caught the attention of the painter.
And on one of them,
I saw.
At least I think that's me.
Then I offered
a "rickshaw."
houses of my childhood friends
all disappeared.
My old school too.
But some things have remained.
old post,
and the hospital where I was born
and where my parents are dead,
and my wife.
I think we forget things
if there is nobody to tell them.
Pardon, sir?
-- What?
-- You told me?
No.
What do you play?
In Blind Man's Bluff.
-- You know what I was playing at your age?
-- What?
Let's remove it first.
I do?
I got it.
We played at home.
That was the baby.
I was the father.
And your uncle was the mother, wife.
Hello.
I want to tell you something.
I think my husband is having an affair.
At first I thought  confront.
But I have not had the courage.
Where would I go?
There is one place ...
My daughter has learned in Bhutan,
everyone is happy.
They do not have  GNP
but Gross National Happiness.
Would not it be wonderful
to have it here?
Madame.
if I came to Bhutan with you?
You seem distracted.
-- I made a mistake?
-- No.
Tell me, Shaikh ...
Yes?
-- Have you ever been to Bhutan?
-- Bhutan?
I thought ... rather than Nasik,
I could move there.
I have been in Saudi Arabia.
Bhutan, that's fine too.
It has advantages:
1 rupee is 5 there.
It's worth going there.
My mother said ... she always says:
"The wrong train
can take you to the right station. "
Your mother?
You told me that you were an orphan.
This is true,
but when I say:
"My mother always says ..."
people take me seriously.
It feels good.
That is correct.
You're listening to Radio  Bhutan ...
How could we go together
Bhutan?
I do not even know your name.
How are you?
A banana and an apple.
Try this.
You are radiant today.
Whether he comes?
You lost 10 years.
Your mother said that the wrong train
can take you to the right station ...
-- My mother is always right.
-- So?
I love it.
Variety.
Variety, sir.
Auntie!
What does he?
Would you have the cassette of this film,
"Saajan"?
So, why?
The songs were good, right?
Not bad.
We can hear it?
Now?
Yes.
You can put it?
I put it.
Hello,
Yesterday Auntie put the cassette
Film "Saajan". Funny coincidence.
She tapes
of all Indian movies,
but no CD or MP3.
It keeps the industry alive
alone!
I crossed
few lines of this letter ...
It's weird
to continue to write, right?
can write everything in a letter,
it's easy.
But what I erased,
I must tell you in the face.
It is time we meet.
Do you know the coffee Kooler
in Matunga?
It seems they are
a very good "kheema pao",
my favorite dish.
What say you of an appointment
tomorrow at 13 am?
Mr. Saajan ...
What?
The boss wants to see you.
-- Yes, I will go after lunch.
-- This is urgent.
I'm coming.
Can I enter?
I just had a meeting
with accounting.
I've never been
so embarrassed in my life.
Do you know what they said?
It is as if our service
claims did not exist.
All payment orders are wrong!
Shaikh initials are everywhere.
The idea that I would leave
replace you!
Should you review all of this.
Spend the night if necessary,
but correct me that.
In your case, Shaikh,
out of my sight.
It's my fault, sir.
It is I who
payment orders.
He has initialed
because we work together.
It's my fault.
Fernandes,
you do not have to defend it.
I am not defending anyone, sir.
35 years of service,
and you have never done
the slightest mistake.
It's not my type
defend anyone.
Anyway,
I take care of the accounting.
Okay, sir.
One last thing.
Why these files
they have the smell of vegetables?
Onions, potatoes, even garlic!
Really?
Feel!
I do not know.
Pardon, sir.
Thank you.
You saved me.
Do not cut ever
those pesky vegetables on folders.
Forgiveness.
I put a plastic bag,
next time.
Okay, no vegetables. Nothing. Forgiveness.
This is not the accounts
a shabby little restaurant!
These public accounts!
If you do not do that, go!
From?
No.
You teach me everything.
I'm sorry,
but you teach me everything.
Your mother told you
to make fake degrees
to get a job?
It must have been mistaken ...
What kind of person are you?
And if you come home for lunch?
I prepared a "Pasanda".
Amazing! Mr. Shaikh.
Amazing ...
A "Pasanda" he said.
You come from, is not it?
-- Take--in.
-- No.
This is very good.
This is my recipe.
My father warned me:
"Do not marry this guy,
it will chain you to the stove. "
His father is a very dangerous man.
He did not smile
since the World Cup 1984.
Or maybe just a little.
Still grinning.
What does your wife?
Shh.
I'm sorry, she did not know.
Okay.
My wife is dead.
But I have a girlfriend.
You?
Yes.
How is it called?
Ila.
I knew it!
Meals, notes ...
When were you married?
Marriage ... it sometimes seems
it's been 35 years.
Or 25 or 10, but I sometimes
feel like it was yesterday.
You back for seconds.
This is my recipe.
You do not eat anything at all.
I wanted to ask you something.
Go ahead.
About our marriage ...
In fact, his father refused.
He said: "He is an orphan, small,
he skinned. "
Meherunissa then fled.
But she wants the blessing
his father.
I will not tell anyone.
No, that's not it.
He agreed.
We're getting married.
There will be a whole army on his side:
brothers and sisters, uncles and aunts ...
everyone will be there.
But there will be no one on my side.
I am alone.
I wanted to know if you would ...
to be my witness.
Me?
Yes. And if Ms. Ila could come too.
Course.
We will come.
His father wants to offer me a scooter.
A gift for my promotion.
But I'm not leaving.
I thought refuse
early departure retirement.
I ask the boss
you become my assistant.
So your promotion ...
This is very good news,
Sir!
But not a word to my father,
otherwise no scooter.
I'll tell Meherunissa.
Sir, you want to sit?
Me?
Yes, take my place.
No.
Please.
I go down to the next.
-- Fernandes.
-- Yes?
You wanted to talk to me?
No.
My secretary told me ...
It was about payment orders.
What is it?
This is resolved.
-- Are you sure?
-- Yes.
Okay. See you later.
Want to Buy?
Dear Ila,
I got the lunchbox today
but it was empty.
It was deserved.
Yesterday you me long
waited at the restaurant ...
But before that, in the morning,
I forgot something
in the bathroom.
I went back ...
and the room had the same smell
that my grandfather left there
after his shower.
It was like he had been there.
But that was not the case.
That was me.
Me and the smell of an old man.
I do not know
when I became old.
It was perhaps this morning.
Or before.
And maybe if I'd forgotten
something earlier,
I would then noticed.
Sir, you want to sit?
No.
life rocked me languidly,
forward, back ...
And before I knew it ...
Nobody buys
a lottery ticket expired, Ila.
I came to the restaurant.
And you were there,
fiddling with your purse,
to drink all that water ...
I wanted to come
tell you all this in the face,
but I only look at you.
You were lovely.
You are young.
You still have dreams.
You have greeted me some time.
And I want to thank you.
The two ladies behind
come forward, please.
Smile, please.
One, two, three.
Now a photo
with everyone!
The family of the bride to the right.
The spouse left.
You leave, sir?
-- This is the new scooter?
-- I will drop you somewhere?
If you stay,
I will go to my father.
Taxi!
It's weird, it is very dry ...
Goodbye, Shaikh.
You know,
when I took the train for the 1st time
with you, 1st class.
That day, I had no ticket.
I was anxious throughout the journey.
I prayed that the controller
does not come.
What would you think of me?
The next day, I got to
a 1st class pass.
You make a good husband, Shaikh.
Thank you.
A moment.
Come see me at Nasik, on occasion.
I'm coming, Mom.
80 rupees.
Rajeev comes.
It is in a meeting.
It will go directly to the crematorium.
I have one of these hungers.
A desire to "parathas".
I have not eaten this morning.
I prepared his breakfast it.
Mom ...
I always apprehended
what would happen to me after his death.
-- Do not worry.
-- But now ...
I'm hungry, that's all.
It was loved at first
when you were born.
But for years,
it disgusted me.
Every morning, I prepared something to eat.
Drugs. Bath.
Breakfast. Drugs.
Bath.
When your brother is dead,
this old ambulance came.
Do you remember?
These old Matador models.
Which came today?
What color?
White with blue light.
Yes.
Sir.
The lunchbox comes
to the wrong address.
It is impossible.
-- We never make mistakes.
-- Yes, I understand.
But my meals are poorly delivered.
-- It is delivered to the right address.
-- I tell you no.
People came to Harvard.
Listen to what I tell you.
Try to understand.
This lunchbox is not delivered to my husband.
It comes also
it is someone else who receives it.
People Harvard
came to study our system.
They say that there is no error.
But it's not going to the right place.
You think I'm a liar?
The King of England in person
came to observe our system.
But this meal goes somewhere
someone eats it.
He goes to the right place.
I want the address!
Office Saajan Fernandes?
Two rows away.
Is the office Saajan Fernandes?
I remember you.
Saajan Fernandes?
He is gone.
He left the company.
Where can I find it?
He went to Nasik.
Then you go to Nasik?
Yes.
You move?
This is final?
Yes.
I'm retired there for years.
I return to Mumbai from time to time
to see my son.
I'm sorry, Mrs. Ila.
Good evening, Mr. Fernandes.
We thought you were gone.
Yes, but I came back.
Why?
Well, you can play here.
But do not break windows,
understood?
Hold.
Thank you, Mr. Fernandes.
I've been calling you all the time.
Where were you?
I had to adjust something.
I got worried.
I have more layers to Tonton.
I asked the guard to search.
I washed the fan today.
While he was running!
You're probably Nasik.
You had to get up this morning
make a tea.
And maybe a walk then.
This morning I woke up,
and I sold all my jewelry.
My bracelets, my earrings,
my wedding necklace.
It is not much.
But they told me:
1 rupee is worth 5 in Bhutan.
So we should
get away for some time.
And more ...
we'll see.
return Yashvi,
luggage will be ready.
We take the train this afternoon.
I may send you this letter
and your new factor
you bring.
Or maybe I should keep it,
and read in a few years ...
I read somewhere that sometimes,
the wrong train
can lead you to the right station.
We'll see ...