Cait!
Where are you?
Mam is looking for you!
Cait!
Cait, I'm warning you!
Girls! Did you find her?
No!
There's muck on your shoes.
The Quiet Girl
Mam said the calf will be born
the same week as the baby.
They will be twins!
We'll have to pick a name for it.
How does the calf
get into the mammy's belly?
The bull pushes the calf into her.
Everyone knows that.
Grainne, that's not how it happens.
It is!
Fiona Geraghty saw their bull..!
-Fiona Geraghty is an idiot.
-She's not an idiot!
Fuck sake...
She hasn't made the lunches.
Dad! Mom didn't make the lunches!
You know what?
Pick a bread or something.
It really pisses me off!
"There was a sadness...
"..upon the...
People.
"..people...
"..who were...
Left.
"left."
Siobhan, continue reading.
"..but the king said
they were most welcome.
"The prince was overjoyed.
"They were travelling
on a great ship..."
-Pick one.
-Green.
Your sister is such a weirdo.
My mother and your mother
were hanging out their clothes!
My mother came to your mother
and punch in the nose!
What color was the blood?
How's it going?
What?
Which one is she?
That's the wonder.
Have you anything to say for yourself?
Don't stop at me on the street either.
It's enough from here to your home.
Would you prefer if I let you off?
Don't be fucking like that.
I can let you off, if you want.
Help yourself.
Dan.
Huh?
Dan, did you hear me?
What?
Could you put your horses down
for one minute?
Alright then. What do you want?
How long should they keep her?
Till after the baby?
She can take her
for as long as they like.
Is that what I'll say?
They are your people, aren't it?
You are some help of a man.
Do you know that?
Say whatever you want to say so.
Isn't that what you always do?
Just the one today.
Letter for you.
Leave it on the table.
Cait.
Yes?
Come here.
Where are they?
Look further in the field. There.
Girls!
Cait is leaving!
Wait for us! We're coming!
Let's go, in the name of God.
Waterford, 3:1.
That's where we're going.
Aye, sure in that way I put a bet on them.
My dear, that's in it.
Fuck yeah, I knew it!
Useless showy bastards.
Oh, shit.
Dan, what way are you?
- Sean.
- Get out of here.
How was the drive down?
As it should happen.
Three hours in a car is no joke, mate.
We've got a power of sunshine
these past weeks.
Priest had us praying
for rain this morning.
That'd be good if you do.
How's the farm?
Well, look at this girl!
Stand out so I can
have a proper look at you.
The last time I saw you,
you were in the pram.
Did you know that?
-The pram is broken.
-What happened to it at all?
My sisters used it as a wheelbarrow
and one of the wheels fell off.
Come on in, child.
Sit down if you'd like, pet.
Make yourself at home.
How is your mammy?
She won ten pounds
on the Prize Bonds.
She did not.
She did. We had jelly.
Wasn't that a treat?
I'd say she's busy.
Your mother?
She's waiting for the men
to come and cut the hay.
Have you not cut the hay yet?
You're late.
Are there any children here?
There's only myself and Sean
in the house, pet.
They are in here, aren't they?
Hello, Missus.
Dan.
There's a scorcher of a day, huh?
’Tis hot, surely.
No fields be glad of a sip of rain.
That would've rain long enough.
Aren't you saying hello to our guest?
Here's herself, then?
"Herself" has a name.
Great year for the hay all the same.
Jeez, I've never seen the like of it.
Loft is full to capacity.
Near clipped me head off
on the rafters pitching in the hay.
Now. How bad!
What way is Mary?
She's nearing her time.
I suppose,
the last puppy is getting hardy?
Aye.
It's the feeding them that's the trouble.
There’s no appetite like a child’s
and, believe you me,
this one here is no different.
Well, we all eat in spurts,
the same as we grow.
She’ll ate but you can work her.
There's no need for any of that.
We keep the child gladly.
She's more than welcome.
She’ll ate you out of your house and home.
But I don't suppose there'll be a word
about that this time twelve months.
I have to pee.
Now.
I’d better hit the road.
What hurry is on you?
Long drive back.
The spuds to spray yet.
There's no fear of blight these evenings.
Back in a minute.
Give this to Mary.
I'm snowed under with rhubarb
whatever kind of year it is.
Now.
Good luck to you now.
Try not to fall into the fire, you.
Are you all right, love?
Lord God, he left with
the poor girl's suitcase in the car.
In you go.
-It's hot.
-You'll get used to it.
Now, your clothes.
I don't have any clothes.
Would some of our old things
do you for now?
-I don't mind.
-Good girl.
Now.
My mam says
I have to change my pants every day.
What else does your mother say?
That you can keep me
for as long as you like.
Now, will you come down
to the well with me?
Now?
Does now not suit you?
Is it a secret?
What?
Am I not supposed to tell?
There are no secrets in this house.
Do you hear me?
-Yes.
-Yes, what?
Yes, there are no secrets
in this house.
If there are secrets in a house,
there is shame in that house.
We don't want any shame here.
OK.
You're too young to understand.
Come on.
Look at that.
You wouldn't think
we've had no rain all month.
Drink some.
Now, be careful.
It's deep.
Now, do you want to bring
a cup of hot milk up with you?
Mam doesn't let me drink anything
before bed.
Well...
..we'll stick with Mammy's way so.
Sean, Cait is going to bed.
Good night.
We'll go up.
Oh, pardon me.
Would you prefer I left it open?
Are you afraid of the dark?
Don't mind me.
Are you OK?
Is your mammy OK?
What do you mean?
Your mammy, is she OK?
She'd been throwing up until
recently, but she's stopped now.
Why isn't the hay in?
She doesn't have enough
to pay the man.
God help her.
Would she be offended
if I sent her some money?
-Offended?
-Would she be cross?
She wouldn't, but Dad would.
Your father.
Goodnight, pet.
God help you.
If you were mine...
..I would never leave you
in a house with strangers.
Did you sleep well, love?
Lord God Almighty.
Look at that.
These old mattresses.
They're always weeping.
What was I thinking
putting you on one of these?
Take off the pyjamas, good girl.
It's time.
Do you want to bring Cait
with you today?
Show her the farm?
The work will be
a little difficult this week.
-Will it?
-Another time, maybe.
Well.
If so...
..we'll begin.
You need to be careful with it.
Twenty-three...
..twenty-four...
twenty-five...
twenty-six...
twenty-seven...
..twenty-eight.
It's a secret.
Not many people know about it,
but it does wonders for the skin.
Look at me, I haven't so much
as a pimple.
I thought there were no secrets
in this house.
Well...
..this is different.
More like a secret recipe.
Forty-three...
...forty-four...
. forty-five...
. forty-six...
..forty-seven.
-Perishables?
-Food that doesn't last very long.
You put them in here
and they stay as they are.
-They don't grow old?
-Exactly.
Like The Land of Youth?
Like The Land of Youth!
You're getting the hang of it.
Careful of your hand.
Excuse me.
Hello? 72599...
Ninety-four...
..ninety-five...
..ninety-six...
..ninety-seven...
..ninety-eight...
..ninety-nine...
..one hundred.
Your complexion is better already.
All you needed was some minding.
This game is crooked, girl.
I've been saying it for years.
Quiet, you!
Easy knowing whose purse
is running low!
Is it any wonder?
After twenty years
of being swindled by you lot!
O Cathasaigh,
haven't I said it before,
misfortune followed you
from the cradle!
Did your mother never tell you?
"The Ass" O Cathasaigh.
The name well-earned.
This girl must think that everyone
around here is mad, does she?
-Who's winning? "The Ass" I bet.
-Who else?
And pigs might fly!
You're after our pennies, are you?
Selling tickets for the raffle.
There's a new roof
going on the school.
I wasn't sure...
You don't have to have
children of your own
to give shelter
to other people's children, do you?
-You'll have a drink?
-I'll have a cup of tea.
I'll get it.
And who is this?
Excuse me.
Hello? 72599...
Ah, hello Sinéad.
You don't say! Your poor father!
Of course, I'll head over to you now.
There's ham and coleslaw in
the fridge for lunch if I'm not back.
We won't die of the hunger anyway.
My mam says I'll get pneumonia
if I don't wear my jumper.
Now.
Maybe the old man
wasn't wearing his jumper.
Maybe.
Why is Mrs Kinsella
looking after him?
She's helping his daughter.
It's the daughter
who's looking after him.
Don't you help your neighbours out
now and then?
I don't know.
Cait!
You can't go wandering off like that,
do you hear me?
Do you hear me?
Sean.
Cait is going to bed.
Good night.
How are you getting on, love?
-Is that the mother's milk?
-No.
-What is it then?
-Powdered milk.
Why don't you give him
his mother's milk?
We sell that milk.
-Why doesn't the calf get any?
-He does, in the beginning.
For how long?
Long enough!
Why don't we drink the powdered milk
and leave the cows
to drink their own?
Here, you do it.
-Can you run?
-What?
You have long legs.
Are you fast?
Sometimes.
Run down the lane
to the box and back.
-What box?
-The post box.
I forgot it this morning.
See if there's anything in it.
Off you go. I'll time you.
Off you go!
You've never had red gooseberry jam?
I haven't.
You're in for a treat so.
Good girl.
It's past time
we did something about this.
What's wrong with her?
Tomorrow is Sunday and I won't let
her go to Mass like that again.
Isn't she clean and neat?
You know what I'm talking about,
Eibhlin.
Run upstairs, get yourself ready
and I'll bring us into town.
You should wash your hands and face
before going into town.
Didn't your father bother
to teach you that much even?
One minute.
Sorry to have kept you.
It will be nice
to have your own clothes.
And the town is nice.
I don't know why I didn't think
of taking you in before now.
You can buy a Choc Ice for yourself.
She could buy
half a dozen Choc Ices with that.
What good is it having her here
if we can't spoil her?
What do you say?
-Thank you.
-You're welcome.
We'll go.
Isn't she tall!
We're all tall.
You look beautiful, pet! Beautiful!
Try this one.
Isn't your mammy good to you?
Nine pounds, ten ounces.
-She was big in the end.
-You can say that again!
She's beautiful.
Your mother must be mad about her.
She's very taken with her.
What about Cian?
Is he good with her?
He's getting used to her!
It takes time, I suppose.
And who's this girl? Whose is she?
This is Cait.
She's my cousin's daughter.
She's staying with us for the summer.
Can she be put to work?
She'll put her hand to anything.
Well, isn't she company for you
all the same, God help you.
Sinéad, is everything OK?
It's Dad, he's gone.
Oh Sinéad, I'm so sorry.
Very sorry for your loss, Sinéad.
If there's anything we can do.
-Where's he gone?
-Sean?
He's helping the family.
Were you ever at a wake?
I don't think so.
Well, there will be a dead man
in a coffin.
You probably never saw
a dead person before, did you?
I did, on the news.
You probably did, God help you.
But it's a different thing
having them there in front of you.
Don't be afraid.
He's praying.
We have to say a prayer for him too.
Bye for now, Sean.
-There she is, the long-legged girl.
-Eibhlin, love!
Come here.
Isn't that a lovely dress?
You got that today, did you?
Do you want a sip?
-Do you like it?
-No.
Don't get a taste for it either or
you'll end up like these drunkards.
Now.
She's getting restless,
the poor creature.
I can bring her home with me
if you'd like?
I'll be leaving now.
Oh, I don't know.
My gang can play with her.
Maybe. What harm?
-If you don't mind.
-It's nothing.
They're looking after you well,
I suppose.
Yes.
Tell me,
what room did they put you in?
The one beside the toilet.
Does he give you pocket money?
Kinsella?
-He gave me money today.
-Weren't you lucky?
-How much?
-A pound.
Is herself allowed to spend?
-Who?
-Eibhlin, you dope!
She is.
And she's still drinking, I suppose?
When visitors come.
-Do they have many visitors?
-They had a card game last week.
Who was there?
Two men. And another man
who came selling lines.
-Lines?
-To put a roof on the school.
Do you say the Rosary?
No.
-She's baking the whole time, is she?
-She is.
-Butter or margarine?
-What?
-In her pastry!
-Butter.
Does she have the freezer
packed to the brim?
Yes.
-Where does the dog sleep?
-In the shed.
-Not in the house?
-I've never seen him there.
And are the child's clothes
still hanging in the wardrobe?
-The child's clothes?
-Yes.
If you're sleeping in his room,
you must know.
Didn't you look?
Well, she had clothes for me
but we went into town
and bought new ones.
-This rig-out you're wearing?
-I like them.
The shop lady
said they were flattering.
'Flattering', is it?
Well..!
Well, I suppose, after wearing the
dead's clothes for the past month.
You didn't know?
About what?
The Kinsellas' boy, you dope.
It must have been some
head of cabbage they found you under.
What happened to him?
Didn't he follow the dog
into the slurry pit...
..and didn't he drown, the poor boy.
That's what they say anyway.
They say Sean got the gun
and took the dog down the field
to kill it...
..but he hadn't the heart
to shoot it, the soft-hearted fool.
Do you know poor Eibhlin's hair
turned white overnight afterwards?
-But her hair is brown.
-Brown?!
Out of the dye-pot,
you can be sure!
There weren't many there.
A mound of sandwiches still
on the table when I was leaving.
They had raisin scones
and some sort
of an attempt at a trifle.
And poor Gearéid
lying crooked in the coffin
without a proper shave even.
Shameful!
And plastic rosary beads
in his hands,
the poor wretch.
Shut your traps in there!
I'm trying to talk to your granny!
-Hello all.
-Sean, you were quick.
We're only in the door.
Aren't we, girl?
Thank you, Una.
It was good of you to take her home.
A quiet girl, this one.
She says as much as she needs to say.
May there be many like her.
Are you ready, pet?
Were you OK in there?
Yes.
Did she ask you any questions?
A few things, not much.
What did she ask you?
She asked me if you used
butter or margarine in your pastry.
Did she ask you anything else?
What did she tell you?
Girl.
She told me that you had a little boy
who followed the dog
into the slurry pit...
..and died.
And that I was wearing his clothes
for the past month.
We'll go out.
Someone's horse is missing tonight.
It's a stable door.
Do you know, fishermen sometimes
find horses out at sea?
I know a man
who towed a colt in one time.
And the horse lay on the strand
for a long, long time...
.like he was fit to die.
Until he suddenly stood up, revived.
He was OK?
Good as new.
Perfect.
Strange things happen sometimes,
don't they?
Something strange
happened to you tonight.
But Eibhlin didn't mean any harm.
She wants to find
the good in other people...
..hoping she won't be disappointed...
..but sometimes she is.
You don't have to say anything.
Always remember that.
Many's the person missed
the opportunity to say nothing...
..and lost much because of it.
Cait?
Look!
There are three lights now.
"Heidi," - she answered in a clear, ringing voice.
"That's no Ch..."
Christian.
"...Christian..."
Keep your finger under the words.
"...Christian name for a child."
I'm coming!
I'm going to win!
"And now open!
After extensive renovation,
broad department store "Don Garben"
is back in business!
Except all for your home needs,
we're also the one-stop shop
for the latest fabrics and fashions.
And with Back-to-School Time
just around the corner
we've got you covered for school uniforms,
lunch boxes, copybooks, mathematical sets
and a wide range of pencil cases
and colouring pencils!
Professional service and easy marking.
Look no further, dear housewives...
Ten seconds faster
than the first time you did that.
Like a gust of wind you are, girl.
Now, do you think there's any money
in any of these?
I don't know.
A wedding invite maybe.
Will you marry someday, do you think?
Mam says men
aren't worth bothering with.
Maybe she's right.
That being said,
we're not all the same.
But this is certain, whatever fella's
to catch you, he'll have to be fast.
My mam?
It's addressed to Eibhlin.
Well, you have a new brother.
Eight pounds, six ounces.
-Great.
-Don't be like that.
And school is starting again
on Monday.
Your mam wants us to bring you home
so she can get you ready.
I have to go back then?
Yes.
But you knew that, didn't you?
You couldn't stay here
with old fogies like us, could you?
Come here, child.
I have not being in a hurry.
This quilt has taken some years.
It is already promised to a daughter.
It'll be alright, love.
And I hope will become a family heirloom.
-You'll have a glass of orange, pet?
-Please.
The water is low.
I'll have to go down to the well
when you're gone.
-Where's himself?
-He's milking the cows below.
-What hurry is on himself?
-He needs help pulling a calf.
Do you mind finishing down below?
I have the herd out.
-Of course.
-I'll be back as soon as I can.
Go.
I won't be long, dear.
Cait?
Oh Christ!
Oh, my love!
You're frozen.
-What will we say to her mother?
-We won't say a word to her mother.
-It's just a little cold she has.
-She's expecting her at home.
What harm if we hang on to her
for another day or two?
When I think
of what could have happened.
If you've said that once,
you've said it a hundred times!
-But..!
-But nothing happened, she's fine.
We'll bring her home at the weekend
and that's the end of it.
I don't know if I had those potatoes
boiled right at all.
I wouldn't find any fault with them.
That's where Dad lost our red heifer
in a game of cards.
You don't say?
Wasn't that some wager?
Mam didn't speak to him
for a month afterwards.
You've grown.
I have.
Now, watch that.
Eibhlin.
-Sean.
-Maire, my love.
-How are you?
-It's a long time since I saw you.
Come in and have a seat
if you can find a chair.
-You'll have a cup of tea?
-We will.
I brought some jam. Don't let me
leave without giving it to you.
I made this from the rhubarb
you sent down to me.
That's the last of it.
I should have brought more rhubarb
with me, I wasn't thinking.
Where's the new baby?
He's up in the room.
You'll hear him soon enough.
How is he sleeping?
He could crow at any hour.
You never know.
Speak of the angels
and you'll hear their wings.
Hello, girls.
He's sturdy, isn't he?
He's a pet!
No sign of himself?
He went out earlier.
Wherever he's gone.
Speak of the angels.
- Evening, all.
- Dan.
There's the prodigal child. Huh?
Coming back to us, did you?
I did.
- Did she give you any trouble?
- Trouble?
Good as gold, she was, the same girl.
Is that so?
Well, isn't that a relief?
You'll want to sit in
and have your supper.
I had liquid supper.
Any news from home?
Not much.
All quiet really.
-Have you caught a cold?
-No.
You haven't?
Nothing happened.
What does that mean?
I haven't caught a cold.
The poor girl was in bed
for a few days.
Didn't she catch herself a wee chill.
Aye.
She couldn't mind them.
You know yourself.
Dan.
You know, I think it's getting to us time
that we were making tracks.
It's a long road.
-What hurry is on you?
-No hurry, the usual.
The cows don't give you any let up.
Jesus!
That’s a right dose
you came home with, huh?
It’s nothing she hasn’t caught before
and won’t catch again.
Sure, isn’t it going around?
Are you ready for home?
Are you sure everything is OK?
Yes.
These are nice and floury.
They're Queens.
There was no need, Sean.
It was a nice thing you did,
minding her.
Thank you, both.
She was welcome,
and is welcome again any time.
She is a credit to you.
Take care, my love.
Goodbye, my love.
What happened at all?
Tell me.
Daddy.