0
00:00:05,365 --> 00:00:10,991
Encoded by Judas
Enjoy!

2
00:01:18,328 --> 00:01:20,246
-Go, go.
-We're going right.

3
00:01:20,330 --> 00:01:22,248
Stop traffic up there. Let's go!

4
00:01:52,446 --> 00:01:53,780
Approaching.

5
00:02:01,455 --> 00:02:04,248
l think we have touchdown.

6
00:02:09,296 --> 00:02:12,131
THOMPSON: A little to the right.
SANBORN: Going to the right.

7
00:02:33,237 --> 00:02:34,862
Oh, hello, mamma.

8
00:02:39,076 --> 00:02:40,701
Now push it in.

9
00:02:43,997 --> 00:02:45,498
-l can't.
-What do you mean, you can't?

10
00:02:45,582 --> 00:02:49,001
-Pretend it's your dick, man.
-How about l pretend it's your dick?

11
00:02:49,086 --> 00:02:50,169
You'd never get in if you did that.

13
00:02:51,505 --> 00:02:53,589
-Here. Let me have a shot.
-All right, give me a sec.

14
00:02:53,674 --> 00:02:55,550
No, come on. Time's up. lt's my dick, man.

15
00:02:55,634 --> 00:02:56,717
Go.

16
00:03:01,932 --> 00:03:03,307
You fucker.

17
00:03:06,603 --> 00:03:08,187
SANBORN: Got that?
THOMPSON: Yeah.

18
00:03:10,983 --> 00:03:12,358
There we go.

19
00:03:15,612 --> 00:03:19,740
-Oh, look at that.
-Nice 1 55, huh?

20
00:03:19,825 --> 00:03:21,534
-Yeah.
-1 55?

21
00:03:21,618 --> 00:03:24,579
lt's going to do some fucking damage.
Okay.

22
00:03:24,663 --> 00:03:27,874
SANBORN: Hey, Eldridge,
looks like we're going to need a charge.

23
00:03:27,958 --> 00:03:29,500
ELDRlDGE: Oh, l got that.

24
00:03:29,585 --> 00:03:33,129
l figured four blocks, that'll give us
about 20 pounds of bang, total.

25
00:03:33,213 --> 00:03:36,132
That blast is going to roll straight out there.

26
00:03:36,216 --> 00:03:38,134
The shell will probably kick out there,
and most of the shrapnel

27
00:03:38,218 --> 00:03:40,761
is going to shoot straight up
in a beautiful umbrella pattern.

28
00:03:40,846 --> 00:03:41,929
Yeah.

29
00:03:42,598 --> 00:03:44,932
We're gonna get some smaller pieces
and shell fragments this way,

30
00:03:45,017 --> 00:03:47,018
but we'll be okay
if we're behind the Humvee.

31
00:03:47,102 --> 00:03:50,146
-Bring the bot back. We'll load it up.
-No problem.

32
00:03:52,274 --> 00:03:53,774
Bot is moving.

33
00:04:08,874 --> 00:04:10,875
SANBORN:
Let me know what you got, Eldridge.

34
00:04:10,959 --> 00:04:14,420
-Good to go.
-All right. Wagon's set up. Bot moves.

35
00:04:16,632 --> 00:04:19,842
-Uh-oh. We got goats, guys.
-Heads up. Goats.

36
00:04:19,927 --> 00:04:23,220
-Watch out.
-SANBORN: Blow them little bastards up.

37
00:04:39,738 --> 00:04:41,280
-Oh, shit.
-Shit.

38
00:04:43,367 --> 00:04:46,702
-Oh, fuck.
-Wagon's having a bad day, boys.

39
00:04:46,787 --> 00:04:49,038
-Did you build that?
-ELDRlDGE: No, the U.S. Army did.

40
00:04:49,122 --> 00:04:51,290
All right. Looks like l'm going down there.

41
00:04:51,375 --> 00:04:53,125
You don't like waiting around
this beautiful neighborhood?

42
00:04:53,210 --> 00:04:54,710
Oh, l love it.

43
00:05:04,262 --> 00:05:05,805
So, if everything looks okay
when l get down there,

44
00:05:05,889 --> 00:05:08,891
l'm just going to set it up and we'll BlP it.

45
00:05:09,476 --> 00:05:11,644
Give these people
something to think about.

46
00:05:11,728 --> 00:05:13,062
Want them to know
if they're going to leave a bomb

47
00:05:13,146 --> 00:05:14,480
on the side of the road for us,
we're just going to

48
00:05:14,564 --> 00:05:17,733
-blow up their little fucking road.
-Sounds good.

49
00:05:18,360 --> 00:05:20,486
-Craving a burger, is that strange?
-Not for you.

50
00:05:20,570 --> 00:05:21,862
No, okay.

51
00:05:22,364 --> 00:05:25,324
-Helmet on.
-Happy trails.

52
00:05:33,709 --> 00:05:35,876
-Fans on.
-Blaster One. Can you read me?

53
00:05:35,961 --> 00:05:38,879
Roger that, Blaster One. You're good to go.

54
00:05:43,885 --> 00:05:46,262
You're looking good, Blaster One.

56
00:06:05,741 --> 00:06:07,783
lt's nice and hot in here.

57
00:06:14,249 --> 00:06:15,666
THOMPSON: 150.

58
00:06:15,751 --> 00:06:17,626
Roger that, 1 50 meters.

59
00:06:31,641 --> 00:06:33,726
Hi. Where are you from?

60
00:06:33,810 --> 00:06:34,810
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.

61
00:06:34,895 --> 00:06:36,729
Where are you from?

62
00:06:36,813 --> 00:06:38,481
-California?
-Hey, get out of here, man.

63
00:06:38,565 --> 00:06:40,608
-Where?
-Hey, this ain't a fucking meet and greet.

64
00:06:40,692 --> 00:06:43,027
Now get out of here. Now.

65
00:06:46,740 --> 00:06:47,823
Go.

66
00:06:56,708 --> 00:06:59,919
-You making friends again, Sanborn?
-All day long.

68
00:07:07,177 --> 00:07:09,303
-Twenty-five.
-Twenty-five meters.

69
00:07:09,387 --> 00:07:12,181
Roger that. You are now in the kill zone.

70
00:07:13,725 --> 00:07:17,394
-Thanks for reminding me.
-That's what l'm here for, baby.

71
00:07:18,855 --> 00:07:20,022
THOMPSON: Okay.

72
00:07:28,490 --> 00:07:31,992
-Okay, the dets are good.
-Roger that.

73
00:08:02,190 --> 00:08:06,026
Okay, l'm laying on the charge.
Nice and sweet.

74
00:08:08,238 --> 00:08:11,198
l'm good to go. l'm coming back.

75
00:08:13,743 --> 00:08:16,829
-Five meters out.
-Five meters. Roger that.

76
00:08:17,330 --> 00:08:20,291
Hey, Sanborn.
You know what this place needs?

77
00:08:21,168 --> 00:08:23,294
-l'm listening.
-lt needs grass.

78
00:08:25,589 --> 00:08:28,674
-We gonna start our grass business?
-That's right, man.

79
00:08:28,758 --> 00:08:32,094
l'm going to sell the grass,
and you're going to cut it.

80
00:08:33,638 --> 00:08:35,431
lt's going to be called Sanborn and Sons.

82
00:08:37,559 --> 00:08:39,059
We'll be rich.

83
00:08:40,270 --> 00:08:45,524
l like that. Crabgrass, St. Augustine, man.
l'm a scholar on this shit.

84
00:08:46,234 --> 00:08:48,694
How about this? You sell it, l fertilize it.

86
00:08:51,448 --> 00:08:54,533
THOMPSON: Twenty-five.
SANBORN: Twenty-five meters. Roger that.

87
00:08:54,618 --> 00:08:58,662
Sanborn! Butcher shop, two o'clock,
dude has a phone!

88
00:08:59,080 --> 00:09:01,874
-Why is Eldridge running?
-Make him put it down!

89
00:09:01,958 --> 00:09:05,085
-Put down the phone!
-Come on, guys. Talk to me.

90
00:09:05,462 --> 00:09:07,963
-Drop the phone! Drop your phone!
-Shit!

91
00:09:08,048 --> 00:09:11,550
-Hey, burn him, Eldridge. Burn him!
-Put down the cell phone!

92
00:09:11,635 --> 00:09:13,802
Eldridge, burn him! Get out of the way!

93
00:09:13,887 --> 00:09:15,721
-Drop your phone!
-Tell him to put it down!

94
00:09:15,805 --> 00:09:18,807
Go get it! Stop him, Eldridge!

95
00:09:18,892 --> 00:09:20,226
l can't get a shot.

96
00:09:36,618 --> 00:09:38,160
Thompson!

97
00:10:07,065 --> 00:10:08,691
Anywhere's good.

98
00:10:30,088 --> 00:10:32,131
-MAN: ls that everything?
-Yeah.

101
00:11:08,084 --> 00:11:09,209
Yeah?

103
00:11:13,423 --> 00:11:14,631
Come in.

104
00:11:16,801 --> 00:11:18,344
Sergeant James.

106
00:11:22,098 --> 00:11:25,434
-J.T. Sanborn, my man.
-Oh, hey. Hi. How are you? Will. Call me Will.

107
00:11:25,518 --> 00:11:27,770
Welcome to Bravo Company.
Welcome to Camp Victory.

108
00:11:27,854 --> 00:11:30,272
Camp Victory?
l thought this was Camp Liberty.

109
00:11:30,357 --> 00:11:33,025
Oh, no. They changed that about a week ago.

110
00:11:33,109 --> 00:11:34,985
Victory sounds better.

111
00:11:35,445 --> 00:11:37,654
All right. Well, good.
At least l'm in the right place, right?

112
00:11:37,739 --> 00:11:39,031
-Yeah.
-Well, while you're here, can you

113
00:11:39,115 --> 00:11:41,241
-help me move this thing real quick?
-Oh, yeah, yeah, no problem.

114
00:11:41,326 --> 00:11:44,703
Maybe you shouldn't take this down.
You know, we get a lot of mortars at night.

115
00:11:44,788 --> 00:11:48,082
You know, the plywood on the windows
help with the lateral fray coming through.

116
00:11:48,166 --> 00:11:50,876
-That's why it's up there.
-Yeah, well,

117
00:11:50,960 --> 00:11:53,837
it's not going to stop a mortar round
from coming in through the roof, you know.

118
00:11:53,922 --> 00:11:56,632
Besides, l like the sunshine.

119
00:11:58,134 --> 00:12:00,552
Hey, uh, l'm sorry to hear about Thompson.

120
00:12:00,637 --> 00:12:03,472
-l know he was a good tech.
-Yeah, he was.

121
00:12:03,723 --> 00:12:05,391
He was a great team leader, too.

122
00:12:05,475 --> 00:12:07,643
Yeah, l'm not trying to
fill his shoes or anything.

123
00:12:07,727 --> 00:12:10,813
You know, l'm just going to do my best.

124
00:12:10,897 --> 00:12:12,439
Appreciate it.

125
00:12:12,524 --> 00:12:14,149
All right. Cool.

126
00:12:15,652 --> 00:12:19,113
Well, home sweet home, right?

128
00:12:26,996 --> 00:12:29,748
ELDRlDGE: Aren't you glad the Army has
all these tanks parked here?

129
00:12:29,833 --> 00:12:32,709
Just in case the Russians come,
we have to have a big tank battle.

130
00:12:32,794 --> 00:12:36,630
l'd rather be on the side with the tanks,
just in case, than not have them.

131
00:12:36,714 --> 00:12:38,382
Yeah, but they don't do anything.

132
00:12:38,466 --> 00:12:41,635
l mean, anyone comes alongside a Humvee,
we're dead.

133
00:12:41,719 --> 00:12:43,720
Anybody even looks at you funny,
we're dead.

134
00:12:43,805 --> 00:12:46,682
Pretty much the bottom line is,
if you're in lraq, you're dead.

135
00:12:46,766 --> 00:12:48,267
How's a fucking tank
supposed to stop that?

136
00:12:48,351 --> 00:12:50,561
Would you shut the fuck up,
Owen? Please?

137
00:12:50,645 --> 00:12:53,355
Sorry. Just trying to scare the new guy.

138
00:12:54,023 --> 00:12:56,733
l saw a little bit in Afghanistan, too.

139
00:13:05,452 --> 00:13:07,035
Should get your eyes on the road, Eldridge.

140
00:13:07,120 --> 00:13:08,495
Copy that.

143
00:13:15,712 --> 00:13:16,837
Move.

147
00:13:53,791 --> 00:13:55,542
MAN ON RADlO: Blaster One,
this is Victory Main.

148
00:13:55,627 --> 00:13:58,295
Have you reached your 20, yet? Over.

149
00:14:08,223 --> 00:14:10,974
Where the hell are the guys
that called this in?

151
00:14:26,366 --> 00:14:29,409
Victory Main, Victory Main,
this is Blaster Mike.

152
00:14:29,494 --> 00:14:33,205
lnterrogative, do you have
an update on position? Over.

153
00:14:34,916 --> 00:14:36,542
MAN ON RADlO: Victory Main.
Figures to follow.

154
00:14:36,626 --> 00:14:40,629
3-4-5-3 is your grid. Over.

155
00:14:47,303 --> 00:14:50,514
Well, that's exactly where the hell l am,
and l don't see anybody in fatigues.

156
00:14:50,598 --> 00:14:53,308
MAN ON RADlO: Give us a second
to confirm grid. Over.

157
00:14:54,018 --> 00:14:57,896
-Watch your feet.
-MAN ON RADlO: Set visual is 3-4-5-3, grid.

158
00:14:57,981 --> 00:14:59,147
Over.

159
00:14:59,232 --> 00:15:00,816
Got the Humvee.

160
00:15:03,820 --> 00:15:09,491
Friendly!

161
00:15:26,968 --> 00:15:28,343
Ah, here we go.

162
00:15:30,013 --> 00:15:33,932
-They abandoned their vehicle.
-We got an empty Humvee over here, James.

163
00:15:34,017 --> 00:15:35,559
Yeah. Yeah, l got it.

164
00:15:38,896 --> 00:15:40,314
Let's move.

165
00:15:42,400 --> 00:15:43,692
Friendly.

166
00:15:48,364 --> 00:15:50,198
-Morning, boys.
-Sir.

167
00:15:50,742 --> 00:15:52,284
Don't tell me the bomb's in here
with you guys.

169
00:15:53,494 --> 00:15:55,078
Let's step out,
and l'll show you what's going on.

170
00:15:55,163 --> 00:15:58,081
-All right.
-Down on that block 20 meters,

171
00:15:58,166 --> 00:16:00,959
this side of the mosque,
east side of the street, our informant says

172
00:16:01,044 --> 00:16:03,670
he saw a pair of wires
going into a rubble pile.

173
00:16:03,755 --> 00:16:05,797
-lt's a possible lED.
-Yeah.

174
00:16:05,882 --> 00:16:08,342
-l trust this guy. l know him.
-Okay. l'll handle it.

175
00:16:08,426 --> 00:16:10,927
-Do you want to talk to him or...
-No. Good. Keep your boys back.

176
00:16:11,012 --> 00:16:13,722
We'll be good. Thank you. Specialist,

177
00:16:13,806 --> 00:16:15,641
-bring up the Humvee.
-What's going on?

178
00:16:15,725 --> 00:16:18,060
l'm going to break out the suit.

179
00:16:18,144 --> 00:16:20,395
-What about the bot?
-l'll take care of it.

180
00:16:20,480 --> 00:16:21,730
Well, don't you want us
to get the bot down there,

181
00:16:21,814 --> 00:16:22,814
see what it looks like?

182
00:16:22,899 --> 00:16:26,443
-l'll handle it.
-lt's kind of tight down here, James.

183
00:16:39,248 --> 00:16:41,333
All right, here we go.

184
00:16:41,751 --> 00:16:42,918
Ready?

185
00:16:46,589 --> 00:16:47,756
Good?

186
00:16:57,684 --> 00:16:59,059
You know,
you don't have to go down there, man.

187
00:16:59,143 --> 00:17:02,688
-We already have the bot halfway out.
-l'll be all right.

188
00:17:12,782 --> 00:17:15,992
First day, figure you want to
take it easy, right?

189
00:17:22,709 --> 00:17:24,418
-How's it looking, Eldridge?
-Good to go.

190
00:17:24,502 --> 00:17:25,919
Let's do it.

191
00:17:35,972 --> 00:17:37,556
-Got tools?
-Got tools.

192
00:17:37,640 --> 00:17:40,142
All right. Let's rock and roll, man.

194
00:17:58,244 --> 00:18:00,662
-He's a rowdy boy.
-He's reckless.

195
00:18:13,885 --> 00:18:15,177
Blaster One, what's going on?

196
00:18:16,554 --> 00:18:18,889
Blaster One! What are you doing?

197
00:18:20,516 --> 00:18:21,975
Blaster One, this is Blaster Mike.

198
00:18:22,059 --> 00:18:25,395
What's with the smoke
on the side of the road? Over.

199
00:18:26,397 --> 00:18:28,231
SANBORN: Hey, James, can you hear me?

200
00:18:28,316 --> 00:18:32,152
What's going on with the smoke
on the side of the road? Over.

201
00:18:33,029 --> 00:18:36,364
-JAMES: Creating a diversion.
-From what? ls there a threat?

202
00:18:36,783 --> 00:18:39,284
Eldridge, get up on the wall. Move!

203
00:18:41,078 --> 00:18:43,538
Tell me what you see, Specialist.

204
00:18:44,457 --> 00:18:47,334
All right. l got him.
He's walking down range.

205
00:18:47,418 --> 00:18:51,963
James, the smoke is killing my visibility.
Where are you in relationship to the lED?

206
00:18:52,048 --> 00:18:54,257
Are you within 1 00 meters yet?

207
00:18:54,342 --> 00:18:57,677
Hell, l don't know, Sanborn. l'll tell you
when l'm standing over it, cowboy.

209
00:19:35,007 --> 00:19:36,424
Take cover!

210
00:19:42,223 --> 00:19:44,933
ELDRlDGE: Oh, no.
A car stopped in front of him, Sanborn.

211
00:19:45,017 --> 00:19:47,894
Shit. James! James, come back, now.

212
00:19:47,979 --> 00:19:50,730
EOD just pulled a nine on a haji in a car.

213
00:19:52,900 --> 00:19:55,569
-Do you want me to send backup?
-JAMES: l got it.

214
00:19:56,112 --> 00:19:58,697
-Sanchez, Harris.
-Negative! Negative!

215
00:19:58,781 --> 00:20:01,825
Stand down.
The blast will come up the block.

216
00:20:01,909 --> 00:20:06,621
Stay clear around the corner.
EOD has the situation under control. Over.

217
00:20:07,665 --> 00:20:10,792
JAMES: Where you going?
SOLDlER: Hold your fire, on my command.

218
00:20:11,294 --> 00:20:12,961
Want to back up?

219
00:20:17,842 --> 00:20:19,593
SOLDlER: Get out of the car!

220
00:20:20,803 --> 00:20:22,012
Get out of the car!

221
00:20:25,975 --> 00:20:28,143
What the fuck are you doing?

222
00:20:31,272 --> 00:20:32,480
Back up.

223
00:20:36,485 --> 00:20:37,652
Hello?

225
00:20:52,793 --> 00:20:54,419
Want to get back?

226
00:21:13,022 --> 00:21:14,189
Shit.

227
00:21:15,775 --> 00:21:17,275
lt's that way.

228
00:21:21,948 --> 00:21:23,031
Back.

229
00:21:24,158 --> 00:21:28,119
SOLDlER: Three, four rounds fired. The nine
is now pressing into the haji's forehead.

230
00:21:43,219 --> 00:21:45,804
-Taxi's moving.
-Eldridge, get him out of here. Come on.

231
00:21:45,888 --> 00:21:48,682
-Get him out of the car!
-Stop! Stop the car!

232
00:21:49,558 --> 00:21:51,643
Get out of the fucking car!

233
00:21:51,727 --> 00:21:54,354
Get on the ground! On the ground!

234
00:21:54,438 --> 00:21:56,564
-Get down there.
-Stay down.

235
00:21:58,651 --> 00:22:01,319
Well, if he wasn't an insurgent,
he sure the hell is now.

237
00:22:02,488 --> 00:22:04,739
Roger that. That's real funny.

238
00:22:59,462 --> 00:23:01,087
Found something.

239
00:23:12,266 --> 00:23:13,516
Hello, baby.

240
00:23:45,341 --> 00:23:46,341
Got you.

241
00:24:01,023 --> 00:24:02,315
All right.

242
00:24:07,655 --> 00:24:11,491
All right. We're done. Good to go.

243
00:24:13,077 --> 00:24:15,537
-Good to go.
-Come down, Specialist.

244
00:24:16,997 --> 00:24:18,164
Roger.

246
00:24:32,054 --> 00:24:35,723
Uh, got a wire. Hang on.

247
00:24:41,897 --> 00:24:43,898
Where are you going?

248
00:24:58,622 --> 00:25:00,832
-Secondary.
-Shit.

249
00:25:00,916 --> 00:25:03,835
Take cover. Get in the wall. Get in the wall.

250
00:25:19,059 --> 00:25:20,310
Oh, boy.

252
00:26:47,690 --> 00:26:49,482
That wasn't so bad.
First time working together.

253
00:26:49,566 --> 00:26:50,566
What do you think?

254
00:26:50,651 --> 00:26:56,364
Hmm, l think us working together
means l talk to you

255
00:26:56,448 --> 00:27:00,201
-and you talk to me.
-We going on a date, Sanborn?

256
00:27:00,536 --> 00:27:04,372
No. We're going on a mission,
and my job is to keep you safe,

257
00:27:04,456 --> 00:27:07,917
-so we can keep going on missions.
-lt's combat, buddy.

258
00:27:15,759 --> 00:27:17,885
Hey. lt's just 39 days.

259
00:27:18,262 --> 00:27:20,179
Thirty-eight if we survive today.

260
00:27:38,240 --> 00:27:40,575
Hey, it's Mr. Be All You Can Be.

261
00:27:41,076 --> 00:27:43,786
-What's up, Doc?
-Not much. How are you?

262
00:27:44,705 --> 00:27:48,958
l'm good.
Got a question about that song, though,

263
00:27:49,752 --> 00:27:51,461
Be All You Can Be.

264
00:27:51,879 --> 00:27:55,006
What if all l can be is dead
on the side of an lraqi road?

265
00:27:55,090 --> 00:27:58,051
l mean, l think it's logical. This is a war.

266
00:27:59,136 --> 00:28:01,679
People die all the time. Why not me?

267
00:28:03,098 --> 00:28:04,349
You got to change the record in your head.

268
00:28:04,433 --> 00:28:06,184
You gotta start thinking about other things.

269
00:28:06,268 --> 00:28:10,355
Okay. Stop obsessing.
Right now, what are you thinking about?

270
00:28:10,439 --> 00:28:11,814
You want to know
what l'm thinking about, Doc?

271
00:28:11,899 --> 00:28:14,817
-Yeah.
-This is what l'm thinking about, Doc.

272
00:28:16,362 --> 00:28:18,780
Here's Thompson, okay. He's dead.

274
00:28:20,199 --> 00:28:21,199
He's alive.

275
00:28:21,784 --> 00:28:24,494
Here's Thompson. He's dead. He's alive.

276
00:28:25,788 --> 00:28:27,663
He's dead. He's alive.

277
00:28:33,420 --> 00:28:35,171
Yo, what's up, my nigger? What's up, man?
What's up?

278
00:28:35,255 --> 00:28:37,173
You cool? Come on.
You want the cool shit?

279
00:28:37,257 --> 00:28:39,217
Man, come on, come on.
lt's the tight shit, man. Come on.

280
00:28:39,301 --> 00:28:43,721
Wanna buy DVDs? Wanna buy DVD?
Fuck you. Come, come, please, please.

281
00:28:43,806 --> 00:28:45,306
New releases. Look.

282
00:28:45,391 --> 00:28:48,267
Hey. Hello, hello. Want to buy DVDs?
Very good. Very good.

283
00:28:48,352 --> 00:28:50,269
-How much?
-One for 5 and two for 9.

284
00:28:50,354 --> 00:28:53,689
-Three for 1 2.
-Three for 1 3, and l don't give you tax.

285
00:28:53,774 --> 00:28:56,692
-Very good, man. Look.
-No tax?

286
00:28:56,777 --> 00:28:58,194
All right. What do you got?
What do you got?

287
00:28:58,278 --> 00:29:01,572
You know, you smart shit.
You not like those stupid fuck-face...

288
00:29:01,657 --> 00:29:03,574
Yeah, l'm a smart guy, huh?

289
00:29:04,118 --> 00:29:07,412
You're a smart kid.
Give me your best one, okay?

290
00:29:07,496 --> 00:29:09,914
-Here, this the best one.
-This is a good one?

291
00:29:09,998 --> 00:29:14,043
-Yes. The best shit, man.
-Okay. Here you go. l'll take one.

292
00:29:14,128 --> 00:29:15,628
-Keep the change.
-Thank you.

293
00:29:15,712 --> 00:29:19,173
Want a cigarette? Get out of here.
You shouldn't smoke.

294
00:29:21,260 --> 00:29:23,219
Thank you. Take it easy.

295
00:29:28,809 --> 00:29:32,728
l need to talk to you about something
before we go out again.

296
00:29:32,813 --> 00:29:34,188
What's that?

297
00:29:35,649 --> 00:29:37,400
-Yesterday.
-Mmm-hmm.

298
00:29:38,986 --> 00:29:40,361
Wasn't cool.

299
00:29:41,613 --> 00:29:44,866
Yeah, l know. You'll get it, though.
You'll get it.

300
00:29:47,578 --> 00:29:50,204
-So, you're a ranger, huh?
-Yeah.

301
00:29:50,998 --> 00:29:54,417
l was in lntelligence seven years
before l joined EOD.

302
00:29:55,627 --> 00:29:59,755
We ran missions in every shithole
that you could possibly imagine.

303
00:30:02,009 --> 00:30:06,762
So, l'm pretty sure l can figure out
a redneck piece of trailer trash like you.

304
00:30:07,890 --> 00:30:10,516
Looks like you're on the right track.

305
00:30:11,768 --> 00:30:13,895
See you out there, man.

307
00:30:23,989 --> 00:30:25,364
Come on, let's go. Move it. Move it.

309
00:30:31,955 --> 00:30:34,624
SANBORN: Shit. Get out of the way. Move.

310
00:30:39,004 --> 00:30:40,213
Hello.

311
00:30:41,298 --> 00:30:43,758
-Where is it?
-lt's behind the wall.

312
00:30:43,842 --> 00:30:47,178
-All right. See any wires? Any smoke?
-No. l didn't look.

313
00:30:47,262 --> 00:30:50,556
-All right, so how do you know it's a bomb?
-The car has been parked illegally.

314
00:30:50,641 --> 00:30:51,891
The suspension is sagging.

315
00:30:51,975 --> 00:30:53,851
There's definitely something heavy
in the trunk.

316
00:30:53,936 --> 00:30:56,437
Right. So, why don't you walk over there
and peek inside

317
00:30:56,522 --> 00:30:58,648
and tell me what you see?

318
00:30:58,732 --> 00:31:00,942
You want me to go close to it?

319
00:31:01,360 --> 00:31:03,444
Yeah. No. l don't. No, l'm kidding.
l'm kidding.

321
00:31:56,456 --> 00:31:59,041
ELDRlDGE: Shit. lt's coming from over here!

322
00:32:05,757 --> 00:32:08,134
Blaster One, you there?

323
00:32:13,015 --> 00:32:15,224
Blaster One, you hear me?

324
00:32:16,143 --> 00:32:17,893
Here. Go!

325
00:32:24,693 --> 00:32:25,818
Shit.

326
00:32:28,280 --> 00:32:29,822
Let's go, guys.

327
00:32:30,824 --> 00:32:31,907
-Sarge.
-Yeah?

328
00:32:31,992 --> 00:32:34,493
-Let it go.
-ELDRlDGE: l got top cover.

329
00:32:34,578 --> 00:32:37,496
That's a negative, Specialist.
Eldridge, you stay with me.

330
00:32:37,581 --> 00:32:40,082
-Sanborn, you take top cover.
-Shit.

331
00:33:20,082 --> 00:33:22,083
Blaster Mike in position.

332
00:33:47,109 --> 00:33:48,234
What do you got?

333
00:33:48,318 --> 00:33:51,696
l got a through and through to the chest,
but l got him stable.

334
00:33:51,780 --> 00:33:55,157
-He's not going to make it.
-lf we leave here in 1 5 minutes,

335
00:33:55,242 --> 00:33:59,078
-he's got a survivable wound, sir.
-He's not going to make it.

337
00:34:28,150 --> 00:34:29,400
Oh, God.

338
00:34:40,245 --> 00:34:42,580
-What's he doing?
-l don't know.

339
00:34:46,543 --> 00:34:47,543
What are you doing?

340
00:34:47,627 --> 00:34:50,296
There's enough bang in there
to send us all to Jesus.

341
00:34:50,380 --> 00:34:52,590
lf l'm going to die,

342
00:34:52,674 --> 00:34:56,260
l wanna die comfortable.
l need my kit and my cans, yeah.

343
00:34:56,344 --> 00:34:59,764
-What's going on down there, Eldridge?
-l'm getting his kit and his cans.

344
00:34:59,848 --> 00:35:01,515
Cover me, please.

345
00:35:11,610 --> 00:35:13,110
Kit and cans.

346
00:35:29,961 --> 00:35:34,048
Got a lot of det cord, electrical.

347
00:35:52,484 --> 00:35:55,194
All right, l'm gonna look
for the initiating system.

348
00:36:22,055 --> 00:36:24,390
Well, it's not in the back seat.

349
00:36:26,434 --> 00:36:27,977
l don't think.

350
00:36:41,741 --> 00:36:43,742
All right. lt's not in the back seat.

351
00:36:52,377 --> 00:36:55,671
Got a young man on the roof,
your nine o'clock, keep an eye on him.

352
00:36:55,755 --> 00:36:57,131
Roger that.

353
00:37:04,973 --> 00:37:07,099
lt's not in the front seat.

354
00:37:12,647 --> 00:37:14,440
lt's not in the door.

355
00:37:20,405 --> 00:37:22,072
Not on the floors.

356
00:37:26,119 --> 00:37:27,661
Not in the glove box.

357
00:37:27,746 --> 00:37:30,247
lf you haven't found it yet,
it's probably under the car.

358
00:37:30,332 --> 00:37:34,168
Yeah. No wire leads under the car.
lt's all in here somewhere.

359
00:37:41,092 --> 00:37:42,843
-Hey, Sanborn.
-Yeah.

360
00:37:42,928 --> 00:37:45,930
You got eyes on some guy
with a video camera?

361
00:37:46,014 --> 00:37:49,099
-No. Where?
-He's right at my 1 2 o'clock. You see him?

362
00:37:49,184 --> 00:37:52,186
He's pointing the fucking thing right at me.

363
00:38:01,696 --> 00:38:04,073
Shit. Negative. l don't see him.

364
00:38:04,366 --> 00:38:08,118
Hey, Sanborn. He's right at my 12 o'clock.
Look, 12 o'clock!

365
00:38:08,995 --> 00:38:10,871
Roger that. l got him.

366
00:38:15,085 --> 00:38:17,586
ELDRlDGE: Getting ready
to put me on YouTube.

367
00:38:18,046 --> 00:38:19,630
-Little shady.
-Yeah, he looks shady.

368
00:38:19,714 --> 00:38:22,883
-Keep an eye on him.
-Okay. So, what's the play?

369
00:38:24,052 --> 00:38:26,679
Be smart. Make a good decision, over.

371
00:38:33,228 --> 00:38:35,646
Got more wire that

372
00:38:39,484 --> 00:38:41,652
leads fucking nowhere.

373
00:38:43,780 --> 00:38:44,905
Fuck!

374
00:38:45,907 --> 00:38:50,244
-SANBORN: Hey, James, how you doing?
-l'm wonderful. How are you?

375
00:38:50,912 --> 00:38:53,330
You know, we've been here a while.

376
00:38:54,082 --> 00:38:56,917
-We need to get out of here soon.
-Uh-huh.

377
00:39:01,506 --> 00:39:05,342
We got a lot of eyes on us, James.
We need to get out of here.

378
00:39:06,052 --> 00:39:08,846
Roger that. l'm going to figure this out.

379
00:39:10,390 --> 00:39:12,808
SANBORN: James,
we need to get out of here.

380
00:39:13,810 --> 00:39:17,688
-James, do you copy?
-Fuck it. l get it.

381
00:39:19,816 --> 00:39:21,066
Fuck me.

384
00:39:29,534 --> 00:39:32,911
-Hey, how's it looking in there, soldier?
-All clear.

385
00:39:33,455 --> 00:39:37,041
James, the evac is complete. We can leave.
Let the engineers handle this mess.

386
00:39:37,125 --> 00:39:39,460
-We moving?
-That's affirmative.

388
00:39:53,641 --> 00:39:55,559
-lnteresting.
-What's up with James?

389
00:39:55,643 --> 00:39:59,688
-He's not answering me.
-Yeah. l think he removed his headset.

390
00:40:01,316 --> 00:40:04,485
Will you tell him to
put his radio back on, please?

391
00:40:04,569 --> 00:40:09,990
Hey, James! Sergeant Sanborn is asking
if you'll please put your headset back on.

392
00:40:16,664 --> 00:40:18,749
Uh, that's a negative.

393
00:40:18,833 --> 00:40:20,417
That, yeah, that's not going to happen.

394
00:40:20,502 --> 00:40:21,585
Shit.

395
00:40:37,018 --> 00:40:40,104
l got eyes on three guys
at the minaret at six o'clock.

396
00:40:58,623 --> 00:41:01,834
-SANBORN: What the hell is he doing?
-l don't know what the fuck he's doing.

397
00:41:01,918 --> 00:41:04,378
Looks like he's checking the oil.

398
00:41:41,624 --> 00:41:43,959
They're communicating
with your cameraman.

399
00:41:44,043 --> 00:41:47,504
-This is real bad, man.
-Get behind the Jersey barrier.

400
00:41:51,843 --> 00:41:54,761
-l can't see James from here.
-Get down now!

401
00:42:00,268 --> 00:42:01,602
We can go!

402
00:42:08,443 --> 00:42:09,651
Bastard.

405
00:42:33,718 --> 00:42:35,135
We're done.

406
00:42:36,846 --> 00:42:39,723
Sanborn, let's get out of here.

407
00:42:55,073 --> 00:42:56,490
JAMES: Whoo!

408
00:43:08,836 --> 00:43:10,337
That was good.

409
00:43:20,682 --> 00:43:22,683
-Hey, James?
-Yeah, yeah.

410
00:43:24,519 --> 00:43:26,979
Never turn your headset off again.

411
00:43:52,714 --> 00:43:56,466
-You the guy in the bomb suit?
-No, sir. Sir, that's Sergeant James.

412
00:43:56,551 --> 00:43:58,510
-He's right here.
-Hey, James.

413
00:43:58,594 --> 00:44:00,929
-Yep.
-Someone's here to see you.

414
00:44:01,222 --> 00:44:02,389
Oh!

415
00:44:02,807 --> 00:44:04,766
You the guy with the flaming car,
Sergeant James?

416
00:44:04,851 --> 00:44:06,810
Afternoon, sir. Uh, yes, sir.

417
00:44:07,770 --> 00:44:12,399
Well, that's just hot shit.
You're a wild man, you know that?

418
00:44:13,735 --> 00:44:16,570
-Uh, yes, sir.
-He's a wild man. You know that?

419
00:44:17,447 --> 00:44:19,990
-l want to shake your hand.
-Thank you, sir.

420
00:44:20,074 --> 00:44:22,993
Yeah. How many bombs
have you disarmed?

421
00:44:24,162 --> 00:44:25,912
-Uh, l'm not quite sure, sir.
-Sergeant?

422
00:44:25,997 --> 00:44:28,415
-Yes, sir.
-l asked you a question.

423
00:44:30,084 --> 00:44:33,337
-Eight hundred and seventy-three, sir.
-Eight hundred and seventy-three.

424
00:44:33,421 --> 00:44:37,883
Eight hundred and seventy-three!
That's just hot shit.

425
00:44:37,967 --> 00:44:41,178
-Eight hundred and seventy-three.
-Counting today, sir, yes.

426
00:44:41,262 --> 00:44:43,263
That's gotta be a record.

427
00:44:44,932 --> 00:44:49,227
What's the best way to go about
disarming one of these things?

428
00:44:50,813 --> 00:44:52,939
The way you don't die, sir.

429
00:44:54,108 --> 00:44:57,944
That's a good one.
That's spoken like a wild man. That's good.

430
00:45:14,879 --> 00:45:16,046
Hey, what's up, man?

431
00:45:16,130 --> 00:45:18,840
Hey, wait a minute. Look who it is.

432
00:45:20,426 --> 00:45:21,885
l want my 5 bucks back, buddy.

433
00:45:21,969 --> 00:45:23,970
$5 for what, man? You crazy now?

434
00:45:24,055 --> 00:45:25,889
Yeah. The DVD you sold me was crap.

435
00:45:25,973 --> 00:45:29,017
You crazy, man. That's impossible.
lt's Hollywood special effects.

436
00:45:29,102 --> 00:45:30,977
No. lt was shaky.
lt was out of focus, buddy.

437
00:45:31,062 --> 00:45:32,396
-What, you want donkey porn?
-lt's crap.

438
00:45:32,480 --> 00:45:34,398
Girls on dog? Gay sex?

439
00:45:34,482 --> 00:45:38,276
Man, anything you want. You're gay?
l hook you up, man. Come on.

440
00:45:38,736 --> 00:45:41,154
-All right. What's your name?
-Beckham.

441
00:45:41,406 --> 00:45:43,907
-Beckham, like the soccer player?
-Yeah, man. lt's like the soccer player.

442
00:45:43,991 --> 00:45:45,659
-Now give me my ball.
-Are you a soccer player?

443
00:45:45,743 --> 00:45:48,578
Yeah, man. l'm best of the best.
l'm better than Becks.

444
00:45:48,663 --> 00:45:50,747
-You play goalie?
-Yes. l play goalie.

445
00:45:50,832 --> 00:45:52,416
Good. l'll make you a deal.

446
00:45:52,500 --> 00:45:56,253
lf you can stop the ball,
l'm going to give you 5 bucks.

447
00:45:56,337 --> 00:45:58,130
-But if you can't...
-$5, man? What about 1 0, 20?

448
00:45:58,214 --> 00:46:01,800
lf l score... Listen to me.
lf l score, l'm going to keep your ball.

449
00:46:01,884 --> 00:46:03,343
-Deal?
-Deal.

450
00:46:05,096 --> 00:46:07,681
Get up there. Go on.

452
00:46:12,937 --> 00:46:15,355
-Let's see what you got, hot stuff. Come on.
-Are you ready?

453
00:46:15,440 --> 00:46:19,192
-On three. Ready? One, two, three.
-Yeah.

455
00:46:23,531 --> 00:46:24,531
Shit.

456
00:46:24,615 --> 00:46:26,491
Come on. Where's the $5? Man, come on.

457
00:46:26,576 --> 00:46:29,202
All right. l got you. Good job, dude.

458
00:46:30,163 --> 00:46:32,414
-There's 1 0.
-You're an EOD?

460
00:46:33,749 --> 00:46:37,335
-That's right.
-lt's fun, no? lt's cool? lt's gangster.

461
00:46:38,212 --> 00:46:39,296
Yeah?

462
00:46:40,214 --> 00:46:43,341
Yeah, l think so. Tell you what.

463
00:46:43,634 --> 00:46:47,888
l'm going to buy... Let me see
if l have enough money, yeah, 5.

464
00:46:48,556 --> 00:46:51,141
l'm going to buy another DVD, okay?

465
00:46:51,434 --> 00:46:58,064
But if it's shaky, look at me,
or out of focus, or any way not 1 00%,

466
00:46:58,983 --> 00:47:01,693
l'm going to chop off your goddamn head
with a dull knife.

467
00:47:01,777 --> 00:47:04,613
How do you feel about...
l'm just kidding. l'm just kidding. Here.

469
00:47:05,907 --> 00:47:08,408
You're a good kid, man.
You're a good kid, aren't you?

470
00:47:09,994 --> 00:47:13,330
CAMBRlDGE: Owen. Hi.

471
00:47:13,414 --> 00:47:14,873
-Hey, sir.
-How are you?

472
00:47:15,458 --> 00:47:17,083
-l'm good.
-Good.

473
00:47:17,168 --> 00:47:19,711
-What's wrong?
-Brakes are squeaking.

474
00:47:20,254 --> 00:47:23,423
Don't trust the mechanics around here,
you know?

475
00:47:23,508 --> 00:47:27,177
-So, how you doing?
-l'm good. l just want to check the oil.

476
00:47:28,304 --> 00:47:33,725
Yeah, it's good to sleep, eating well.
Feeling pretty squared away, actually, Doc.

477
00:47:34,268 --> 00:47:36,019
Well, l'm glad to hear it.

478
00:47:36,103 --> 00:47:38,730
So, you getting along
with the other soldiers in your unit?

479
00:47:40,316 --> 00:47:45,237
Yeah. My team's great.
My team leader is inspiring.

480
00:47:45,863 --> 00:47:48,949
-You being sarcastic, soldier?
-No.

481
00:47:49,617 --> 00:47:52,911
He's going to get me killed,
almost died yesterday.

482
00:47:53,955 --> 00:47:57,749
At least l'll die in the line of duty,
proud and strong.

483
00:47:58,292 --> 00:48:00,961
You know, this doesn't have to be
a bad time in your life.

484
00:48:01,045 --> 00:48:04,130
Going to war is
a once-in-a-lifetime experience.

485
00:48:04,632 --> 00:48:06,007
lt could be fun.

486
00:48:06,092 --> 00:48:08,760
And you know this
from your extensive work in the field, right?

487
00:48:08,844 --> 00:48:12,597
-l've done my field duty.
-Where was that? Yale?

488
00:48:14,475 --> 00:48:17,227
Look, you don't want me to come around,
l won't come around.

489
00:48:17,311 --> 00:48:19,229
These talks are voluntary.

490
00:48:19,313 --> 00:48:23,733
Look, l'm sorry.
l appreciate what you're saying. l do.

491
00:48:23,818 --> 00:48:25,235
l appreciate our sessions together,

492
00:48:25,319 --> 00:48:30,156
but you need to come out
from behind the wire and see what we do.

493
00:48:31,158 --> 00:48:35,954
Well, if the circumstance calls for it, l will.
Just like every other soldier.

494
00:48:41,127 --> 00:48:44,462
Fire in the hole! Fire in the hole!
Fire in the hole!

495
00:48:44,547 --> 00:48:45,755
Firing now.

497
00:48:52,680 --> 00:48:54,514
-Ready for second det?
-Ready.

498
00:48:55,016 --> 00:48:57,851
Fire in the hole! Fire in the hole!
Fire in the hole!

499
00:48:58,019 --> 00:48:59,019
JAMES: Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!

500
00:48:59,103 --> 00:49:00,770
Hold on a second.

501
00:49:00,855 --> 00:49:02,105
God damn it.

502
00:49:02,189 --> 00:49:04,899
-l think l forgot my gloves down there.
-What?

503
00:49:04,984 --> 00:49:07,110
l forgot my gloves. Hang on.

505
00:49:41,896 --> 00:49:44,981
SANBORN: You know, these detonators
misfire all the time.

506
00:49:45,900 --> 00:49:47,651
What are you doing?

507
00:49:48,027 --> 00:49:50,862
l'm just saying shit happens, they misfire.

508
00:49:53,532 --> 00:49:55,825
He'd be obliterated to nothing.

509
00:49:57,161 --> 00:49:59,579
SANBORN: His helmet would be left.
You could have that.

510
00:49:59,664 --> 00:50:02,624
Little specks of hair charred on the inside.

511
00:50:03,459 --> 00:50:07,253
ELDRlDGE: Yeah. There'd be
half a helmet somewhere, bits of hair.

512
00:50:09,590 --> 00:50:11,925
Have to ask for a change
in technique and protocol,

513
00:50:12,009 --> 00:50:15,136
and make sure this type of accident
never happen again, you know?

514
00:50:18,182 --> 00:50:20,475
You'd have to write the report.

515
00:50:22,436 --> 00:50:24,938
-Are you serious?
-l can't write it.

516
00:50:26,232 --> 00:50:29,150
No. l mean,
are you serious about killing him?

517
00:51:08,482 --> 00:51:12,110
ELDRlDGE: Twelve o'clock, l see an SUV.
SANBORN: Roger that.

518
00:51:12,194 --> 00:51:15,488
ELDRlDGE: l got four armed men.
They're in haji gear.

519
00:51:17,366 --> 00:51:19,242
JAMES: All right. Go slow and easy, man.

520
00:51:26,959 --> 00:51:28,501
We're in it now.

521
00:51:32,047 --> 00:51:34,340
SANBORN: All right.
Careful now, guys. Careful.

522
00:51:34,425 --> 00:51:36,384
-Eldridge, you stay on that 50.
-l got them.

524
00:51:39,305 --> 00:51:41,347
Put your gun down. On your knees.

525
00:51:42,183 --> 00:51:44,350
Down. Put the gun down, now!

527
00:51:46,187 --> 00:51:48,772
-Put up your hands.
-Get down, motherfucker.

529
00:51:49,940 --> 00:51:52,192
Put your gun down now!

530
00:51:58,032 --> 00:51:59,699
Put your gun down!

531
00:52:03,871 --> 00:52:05,538
Advance, advance.

532
00:52:25,810 --> 00:52:27,185
Hands high!

533
00:52:27,895 --> 00:52:30,230
-Eldridge, cover!
-l got you.

534
00:52:31,398 --> 00:52:33,399
Pistol off your hip, now.

535
00:52:33,901 --> 00:52:36,820
What you want me to do?
Keep my hands up or take off the pistol?

536
00:52:38,989 --> 00:52:41,074
-Keep your hands up.
-Okay.

537
00:52:46,163 --> 00:52:47,539
Easy, easy.

538
00:52:48,415 --> 00:52:49,624
Got it!

539
00:52:51,627 --> 00:52:54,003
Can l touch my fucking head now?

540
00:52:55,089 --> 00:52:56,256
Slowly.

541
00:53:03,722 --> 00:53:06,307
We're on the same fucking side, guys.

542
00:53:06,433 --> 00:53:07,851
Oh, Jesus.

543
00:53:09,186 --> 00:53:10,895
TEAM LEADER: You guys are
wired fucking tight, you know that?

544
00:53:10,980 --> 00:53:12,939
JAMES: Right. Well, this is no place
for a picnic, right?

545
00:53:13,023 --> 00:53:15,942
-What are you guys doing here?
-We have a flat tire. Can you help us?

546
00:53:16,026 --> 00:53:17,569
Sure, yeah. You got any spares?

547
00:53:17,653 --> 00:53:19,654
We have spares,
but we used up our wrench.

548
00:53:19,738 --> 00:53:21,281
How do you use up a wrench?

549
00:53:21,365 --> 00:53:24,993
Well, the guy over there with the red thing
on his head, he threw it at someone.

551
00:53:26,287 --> 00:53:27,620
-All right.
-Thank you.

552
00:53:32,042 --> 00:53:35,962
-This is Chris. This is the wrench man.
-Hello, wrench man.

553
00:53:36,046 --> 00:53:38,339
-That's Jimmy.
-You know, you can shoot people here.

554
00:53:38,424 --> 00:53:40,592
-You don't have to throw a wrench.
-Fuck off.

555
00:53:50,436 --> 00:53:54,397
Take a look at this.
l picked these guys up in Najaf.

556
00:53:56,358 --> 00:54:01,487
Nine of hearts, that's one.
And the other, Al Rawi, jack of clubs.

557
00:54:06,827 --> 00:54:08,578
-The same guys?
-TEAM LEADER: Yeah. That's them.

558
00:54:12,124 --> 00:54:13,917
Does he need a little help there?

559
00:54:14,001 --> 00:54:15,668
What's the problem with the tire? Come on.

560
00:54:18,297 --> 00:54:20,757
No good, boss. This wrench is too small.

561
00:54:20,841 --> 00:54:22,091
All right, solutions? Anyone?

562
00:54:22,176 --> 00:54:24,802
l think there's another wrench in the back
of the Humvee, if you wanna check.

563
00:54:24,887 --> 00:54:27,180
-l'll give it a try.
-All right. Let's do it.

564
00:54:27,973 --> 00:54:29,807
TEAM LEADER: How long you guys out here?

565
00:54:29,892 --> 00:54:33,019
JAMES: l don't know, Specialist,
what do we got?

566
00:54:33,145 --> 00:54:36,105
ELDRlDGE: We have, uh, 23 more days.
SANBORN: Oh, God.

567
00:54:36,190 --> 00:54:38,524
We have 22 days after today, sir.

568
00:54:39,109 --> 00:54:40,818
But no one's counting, right?

569
00:54:40,903 --> 00:54:42,570
This trip never finishes.

570
00:54:45,741 --> 00:54:46,741
Contact left.

571
00:54:51,956 --> 00:54:53,873
Sniper!

572
00:54:58,420 --> 00:54:59,963
MAN: Take cover.

573
00:55:00,047 --> 00:55:02,298
TEAM LEADER: Chris, take the 50.
Jimmy, head back into the...

574
00:55:02,383 --> 00:55:03,549
You got it.

575
00:55:05,719 --> 00:55:06,928
Nice covering.

576
00:55:08,222 --> 00:55:10,014
Lay it down! Lay it down!

577
00:55:18,315 --> 00:55:21,818
Charlie, go! Go, go, go, go, go!

578
00:55:27,783 --> 00:55:30,159
-Shit!
-SANBORN: Rock and mortar.

579
00:55:30,244 --> 00:55:31,869
TEAM LEADER: They're on the sides, Charlie.
Take this one.

580
00:55:31,954 --> 00:55:33,746
-Get the van and the go bags, Jimmy.
-Got it.

581
00:55:36,500 --> 00:55:39,502
-What are we shooting at?
-l don't know.

582
00:55:39,586 --> 00:55:42,213
-Fuck. The packages are gone!
-MAN: They won't get far on foot.

583
00:55:42,297 --> 00:55:45,675
Bring them in, Sergeant, those fuckers.
l'm out 500,000 fucking quid.

585
00:55:58,939 --> 00:56:02,108
l forgot, it's 500,000 dead or alive.

586
00:56:05,904 --> 00:56:08,740
Okay. Jimmy, give me the Barrett.

587
00:56:10,784 --> 00:56:11,951
Can't see a thing.

588
00:56:13,954 --> 00:56:14,954
Come on!

589
00:56:20,544 --> 00:56:22,879
Chris is shooting wild.
Gotta conserve the ammo.

590
00:56:22,963 --> 00:56:24,672
OLDER MAN: Hey, Chris, can you hear me?

591
00:56:24,757 --> 00:56:29,385
Hey, Chris! Can you hear me?
Chill out on the 50.

592
00:56:29,470 --> 00:56:30,803
Roger that.

593
00:56:32,806 --> 00:56:34,932
-Fifty's down.
-He shot Chris.

594
00:56:46,361 --> 00:56:47,612
OLDER MAN: lt must be coming
from that building.

595
00:56:47,696 --> 00:56:48,988
l can't see anything.

596
00:56:54,161 --> 00:56:55,953
Movement on the roof.

597
00:57:09,593 --> 00:57:11,803
-Yeah?
-Three meters higher.

598
00:57:12,262 --> 00:57:13,763
l'm going to adjust.

599
00:57:14,515 --> 00:57:16,099
My anchor fell out.

600
00:57:44,795 --> 00:57:48,840
-Fuck, fuck. We need some help.
-He's dead.

601
00:57:49,091 --> 00:57:50,967
-We gotta get out of here now.
-Damn it.

602
00:57:51,051 --> 00:57:52,760
This is Alpha Nine. We're in deep shit.

603
00:57:52,845 --> 00:57:54,804
-l'll get on the Barrett.
-Go, go, go, go.

604
00:57:54,888 --> 00:57:57,640
-Yeah, we're taking incoming fire.
-JAMES: Go, go, go, go.

605
00:57:57,724 --> 00:57:59,475
No, Sanborn. Sanborn don't go up there.

606
00:57:59,560 --> 00:58:01,310
JAMES: Go, buddy. Stay low!
Stay low! Stay low!

607
00:58:01,395 --> 00:58:06,983
l have two KlA... Correction, three KlA.
Our grid last lock stat...

608
00:58:07,860 --> 00:58:09,735
-JAMES: Stay low!
-Can you get me some help?

609
00:58:09,820 --> 00:58:11,988
MAN ON RADlO: Roger that, Alpha Nine.
Give me your post. Over.

610
00:58:12,114 --> 00:58:13,197
-Behind you.
-Yeah.

611
00:58:13,282 --> 00:58:16,033
OLDER MAN: MGRF 5-5-4-2-9-7-3-4-2-0.

612
00:58:20,581 --> 00:58:22,165
MAN ON RADlO: Alpha Nine,
this is Big Dog Seven.

613
00:58:22,249 --> 00:58:24,792
You're gonna have to sit tight. Over.

614
00:58:30,174 --> 00:58:31,799
Just breathe easy.

615
00:58:34,011 --> 00:58:36,012
JAMES: l've got movement.
SANBORN: Yeah.

616
00:58:36,096 --> 00:58:38,139
On the ridge of that house.

617
00:58:42,060 --> 00:58:44,770
-About 850 meters.
-See it.

618
00:58:45,230 --> 00:58:48,149
By the window. You got target?

619
00:58:50,068 --> 00:58:51,277
Got it.

620
00:58:57,534 --> 00:59:01,913
All right, you're a little left.
Just breathe easy.

622
00:59:09,880 --> 00:59:11,464
l'm out of ammo.

623
00:59:12,132 --> 00:59:13,216
Hmm?

624
00:59:13,759 --> 00:59:14,884
l'm out of ammo.

625
00:59:14,968 --> 00:59:17,637
Eldridge, we need ammo.

626
00:59:21,975 --> 00:59:25,728
-Where is it?
-JAMES: Check on the dead guy, man.

627
00:59:25,812 --> 00:59:27,605
lt's on the dead man.

628
00:59:33,362 --> 00:59:35,696
-Eldridge!
-l'm looking.

629
00:59:39,159 --> 00:59:41,911
-We need that ammo, man.
-All right, man.

630
00:59:43,664 --> 00:59:44,830
Here.

631
00:59:48,001 --> 00:59:49,210
Thanks.

632
00:59:56,343 --> 00:59:57,343
Here.

633
01:00:02,516 --> 01:00:05,184
-All right. Same target.
-Got it.

634
01:00:08,647 --> 01:00:11,857
-Fucking jammed.
-Let me see.

636
01:00:14,027 --> 01:00:15,027
Fuck.

637
01:00:15,529 --> 01:00:18,698
Shit. The blood's making it jam.

638
01:00:18,782 --> 01:00:20,992
Eldridge, shit.

639
01:00:21,243 --> 01:00:23,703
You gotta clean the blood off, man.
lt's making them jam.

640
01:00:23,787 --> 01:00:25,162
Specialist!

641
01:00:26,832 --> 01:00:29,458
-Clean the blood off.
-Okay.

642
01:00:35,799 --> 01:00:37,591
Clean it. Clean it.

643
01:00:38,302 --> 01:00:39,844
-You gotta clean it, man.
-How?

644
01:00:39,928 --> 01:00:41,387
Spit and rub.

645
01:00:44,599 --> 01:00:48,894
-All right.
-Spit and rub, buddy. Spit and rub.

646
01:00:51,523 --> 01:00:54,942
lt's not working. lt's not coming off.

647
01:00:58,780 --> 01:01:02,575
Just spit and rub. Spit and rub, man.
Here, take it out. Take it out.

648
01:01:05,037 --> 01:01:08,622
Use your Camel. Use your Camel.
Where is it? You all right?

649
01:01:08,707 --> 01:01:10,249
Here, use that.

650
01:01:13,837 --> 01:01:16,589
Just breathe, buddy. Come on.
Just breathe in.

651
01:01:17,257 --> 01:01:20,593
You got it. You're doing good.
Here, just squeeze. Got it?

652
01:01:23,055 --> 01:01:25,681
Rub that ogive baby.
Come on, you got it. Here.

653
01:01:35,484 --> 01:01:38,569
You're doing good, man.
You're doing real good.

654
01:01:39,654 --> 01:01:40,738
-Got them?
-Yeah.

655
01:01:40,822 --> 01:01:44,700
Hey, l'm going to keep you safe, buddy,
all right? Now let's get these bastards.

656
01:01:44,785 --> 01:01:46,994
Scan your sectors. Scan your sectors.

657
01:01:55,253 --> 01:01:57,296
Kill that fucking asshole.

658
01:01:59,132 --> 01:02:00,716
Son of a bitch.

659
01:02:11,603 --> 01:02:14,647
Nice, he's down.
Second one is out of range.

660
01:02:15,941 --> 01:02:17,817
Twenty meters to the right of the building.

661
01:02:23,115 --> 01:02:27,910
-l got him.
-Fire when ready.

662
01:02:36,253 --> 01:02:39,880
He's moving. He's moving. He's moving.
To the building. Follow him. You got him?

663
01:02:40,382 --> 01:02:41,674
Got him.

664
01:02:45,720 --> 01:02:47,054
JAMES: He's down.

665
01:02:49,182 --> 01:02:51,517
Good night. Thanks for playing.

666
01:03:02,362 --> 01:03:03,946
Window, at the window, at the window.

667
01:03:09,578 --> 01:03:11,203
He's still there.

668
01:03:26,553 --> 01:03:28,929
Left window, left window. Got him?

669
01:03:29,222 --> 01:03:30,473
Got him.

670
01:03:49,659 --> 01:03:50,993
He's down.

673
01:04:47,759 --> 01:04:50,761
-JAMES: Hey, Owen.
-Yeah.

674
01:04:51,638 --> 01:04:54,348
Can you grab a juice
out of the pack, please?

675
01:04:54,432 --> 01:04:55,516
Sure.

676
01:05:07,904 --> 01:05:09,655
SOLDlER: l think we're out.

677
01:05:10,323 --> 01:05:13,158
-Got anything left to drink?
-You could try that one.

678
01:05:28,717 --> 01:05:29,842
Here.

679
01:05:33,805 --> 01:05:35,139
Thank you.

681
01:06:01,374 --> 01:06:03,792
Drink. Drink it.

682
01:07:07,816 --> 01:07:11,026
JAMES: Things are real quiet.
SANBORN: Yeah.

683
01:07:11,111 --> 01:07:12,111
JAMES: l don't like it.

684
01:07:32,674 --> 01:07:35,634
-Hey, Will.
-Yeah?

685
01:07:36,636 --> 01:07:40,472
At your six o'clock,
l see movement on the bridge.

686
01:07:40,932 --> 01:07:45,185
-Right on the tracks.
-Well, handle it.

687
01:07:49,983 --> 01:07:53,861
-Should l fire?
-lt's your call, buddy.

688
01:08:23,475 --> 01:08:24,767
Good job.

689
01:08:55,215 --> 01:08:56,715
Hey, Sanborn.

690
01:09:01,221 --> 01:09:02,971
l think we're done.

694
01:09:15,485 --> 01:09:18,237
-Okay? You all right?
-Yeah.

695
01:09:21,157 --> 01:09:23,700
That's what you get for hitting
your fucking team leader, motherfucker.

696
01:09:26,246 --> 01:09:29,164
-Come on, man.
-l'll be right back. l gotta piss.

697
01:09:29,249 --> 01:09:33,085
Owen. Another round, boy. That's an order.

698
01:09:33,169 --> 01:09:35,504
Well, yes, sir, Sergeant James, sir.

699
01:09:35,588 --> 01:09:36,839
You're not very good with people,
are you, sir?

700
01:09:36,923 --> 01:09:38,674
But you're a good warrior.
Give me your mug.

701
01:09:40,260 --> 01:09:42,010
-There you go, sir.
-You acquitted yourself well

702
01:09:42,095 --> 01:09:44,680
on the field of battle today, Specialist.

703
01:09:44,764 --> 01:09:45,931
Cheers.

704
01:09:54,065 --> 01:09:55,440
l'm too old for this shit.

705
01:10:01,114 --> 01:10:03,657
-l was scared.
-Yeah?

706
01:10:04,367 --> 01:10:07,661
Well, everyone's a coward
about something, you know.

707
01:10:10,290 --> 01:10:12,749
You're good. You're real good.

708
01:10:12,834 --> 01:10:14,376
SANBORN: Just what do we have here?

709
01:10:15,628 --> 01:10:18,213
Will has possessions.

710
01:10:19,215 --> 01:10:23,135
-l didn't know you owned anything, Will.
-Let's see what you got here, Will.

711
01:10:25,638 --> 01:10:28,307
-Who's that?
-That's my son.

713
01:10:29,767 --> 01:10:33,020
He's a tough little bastard. Nothing like me.

714
01:10:33,271 --> 01:10:35,606
You mean to tell me you married?

715
01:10:37,317 --> 01:10:43,405
Well, you know, l had a girlfriend,
and she got pregnant, so we got married.

716
01:10:44,490 --> 01:10:46,074
We got divorced.

717
01:10:48,494 --> 01:10:52,456
Or, you know, l thought we got divorced.
l mean, she's still living in the house,

718
01:10:52,540 --> 01:10:55,959
and she says we're still together,
so l don't know.

719
01:10:56,044 --> 01:10:57,669
What does that make her? l don't know.

720
01:10:57,754 --> 01:11:01,381
Dumb for still being with your ass.

722
01:11:03,301 --> 01:11:07,512
Hey. She ain't fucking dumb, all right?
She's just loyal.

723
01:11:09,307 --> 01:11:12,768
She's just loyal. That's all.
How about you guys? You got...

724
01:11:12,852 --> 01:11:15,896
You got a girl? What do you got?

725
01:11:16,522 --> 01:11:23,028
My only problem is the girl l do like, l can't
stop her from talking about babies, man.

726
01:11:23,613 --> 01:11:25,656
Give her your sperm, stud.

727
01:11:26,366 --> 01:11:28,033
Go on. Do it.

728
01:11:28,117 --> 01:11:30,035
Come on, chicken shit.
Just give it to her, man.

729
01:11:30,119 --> 01:11:31,203
-No. Hell, no.
-Make babies.

730
01:11:31,287 --> 01:11:35,082
l know when l'm ready.
l ain't ready for that yet. l know that.

731
01:11:35,166 --> 01:11:36,625
Well, well...

732
01:11:37,418 --> 01:11:42,214
-What do we have here?
-Components.

733
01:11:43,549 --> 01:11:45,467
They're, you know, bomb parts, signatures.

734
01:11:45,551 --> 01:11:47,803
Yeah, l see that,
but what are they doing under your bed?

735
01:11:50,932 --> 01:11:51,932
Well...

736
01:11:58,856 --> 01:11:59,856
Ah-ha!

737
01:11:59,941 --> 01:12:02,192
Here we are. This one.

738
01:12:02,276 --> 01:12:05,737
This one is from the U.N. building.

739
01:12:06,072 --> 01:12:10,033
Flaming car. Dead man's switch. Boom.

740
01:12:10,118 --> 01:12:11,743
This guy was good. l like him.

741
01:12:12,912 --> 01:12:14,746
Relay... Ah! lt's this guy.

742
01:12:15,832 --> 01:12:20,085
This one, y'all,
is from our first call together.

743
01:12:21,546 --> 01:12:25,382
This box is full of stuff
that almost killed me.

744
01:12:25,842 --> 01:12:28,677
And what about this one?
Where's this one from, Will?

745
01:12:28,761 --> 01:12:32,681
lt's my wedding ring.
Like l said, stuff that almost killed me.

747
01:12:34,058 --> 01:12:38,437
You know, l just think it's really interesting,
you know, to hold something in your hand

748
01:12:38,521 --> 01:12:40,856
that could have killed any one of us.

749
01:12:40,940 --> 01:12:43,775
Damn that. lt's all shit from RadioShack.

750
01:12:46,237 --> 01:12:49,489
-ELDRlDGE: lt's interesting.
-l think it's interesting, too.

751
01:12:49,574 --> 01:12:52,367
Well, l think you hit me harder
than l hit you, motherfucker,

752
01:12:52,452 --> 01:12:54,578
therefore l owe you a punch.

753
01:12:54,662 --> 01:12:57,789
-Now get your ass up. Come on.
-You know what? He's right.

754
01:12:57,874 --> 01:12:59,624
Let's go. Come on.

755
01:13:00,793 --> 01:13:01,793
Come on.

756
01:13:01,878 --> 01:13:04,129
All right, hold on, boys.
We need some rules.

757
01:13:04,213 --> 01:13:05,714
Sanborn, no face shots.

758
01:13:05,798 --> 01:13:08,550
-There's gonna be a face shot.
-Sergeant James, take off your shirt.

759
01:13:09,635 --> 01:13:12,763
-Yes, sir.
-What happened?

760
01:13:12,847 --> 01:13:16,600
-My momma dropped me when l was a baby.
-Looks like frag scars.

761
01:13:16,684 --> 01:13:18,143
Let it go, Eldridge.

762
01:13:19,228 --> 01:13:21,063
-Come on.
-All right.

763
01:13:21,147 --> 01:13:22,481
Nice and big.

767
01:13:36,621 --> 01:13:39,331
-You like that, huh?
-That's all you got?

768
01:13:40,166 --> 01:13:41,416
Come on.

769
01:13:44,170 --> 01:13:45,504
Bring some. Come on.

773
01:13:53,429 --> 01:13:54,930
God damn!

774
01:13:55,598 --> 01:13:57,265
That's gotta hurt.

776
01:14:00,520 --> 01:14:02,646
-You all right, man?
-Yeah.

777
01:14:04,690 --> 01:14:06,983
-He's all right.
-Get up, bitch.

778
01:14:08,528 --> 01:14:10,028
Get up, bitch.

780
01:14:12,824 --> 01:14:14,199
-What do you got now?
-Get the fuck off me!

781
01:14:14,283 --> 01:14:15,951
-What do you got?
-Get off me, you motherfucker.

782
01:14:16,035 --> 01:14:20,163
What do you got? Come on, Sanborn.
What do you got? He's a wild one.

783
01:14:20,248 --> 01:14:21,289
We got a wild one.

784
01:14:21,374 --> 01:14:22,457
-Let go.
-That's right.

785
01:14:22,542 --> 01:14:24,543
-Come on, Sanborn.
-You get off me, you shit.

786
01:14:24,627 --> 01:14:25,877
-Ride on him!
-Get off me.

787
01:14:25,962 --> 01:14:28,130
l'm riding him. Whoo!

788
01:14:28,214 --> 01:14:30,674
-Come on, guys.
-Come on, Sanborn.

789
01:14:31,717 --> 01:14:34,136
-Get off me!
-Hey, hey, hey.

791
01:14:44,856 --> 01:14:47,315
l'm just kidding, motherfucker. Shit.

792
01:14:49,235 --> 01:14:51,862
You're all right, Sanborn.
You're all right, man.

793
01:14:51,946 --> 01:14:54,364
Owen, get this guy a drink. Come on.

794
01:14:56,075 --> 01:14:57,409
-You got him?
-Yeah, l got him.

795
01:14:57,493 --> 01:14:58,577
-Right here.
-All right.

796
01:14:58,661 --> 01:15:00,745
-l'll see you later, man.
-Get home safe. All right.

797
01:15:00,830 --> 01:15:03,915
Come on, big boy.
Damn, boy, you need to get on a diet.

798
01:15:04,584 --> 01:15:06,751
He hurt his knee. Carry on.

799
01:15:08,337 --> 01:15:09,754
Come on, man. Steps.

800
01:15:10,673 --> 01:15:14,759
Come on. Step, step.

801
01:15:16,596 --> 01:15:17,762
Jesus.

802
01:15:19,807 --> 01:15:22,350
All right, lay down. Lay down.

803
01:15:24,061 --> 01:15:26,980
-Get some rest.
-Hey, James,

804
01:15:27,064 --> 01:15:30,734
you think l got what it takes
to put on the suit?

805
01:15:32,904 --> 01:15:33,904
Hell, no.

806
01:15:35,990 --> 01:15:37,532
Good night, boy.

808
01:16:31,462 --> 01:16:32,545
Whoa.

809
01:16:36,759 --> 01:16:40,512
-Morning, Colonel.
-Morning. Mind if l ride along?

810
01:16:41,180 --> 01:16:43,515
l'm sick to death of sitting
behind a desk all the time.

811
01:16:46,269 --> 01:16:48,853
lt'd be a privilege. Hop in, Colonel.

812
01:16:52,984 --> 01:16:54,025
Hey, Doc.

813
01:16:54,944 --> 01:16:57,821
Not to insult your intelligence, sir,
but if the shit hits the fan,

814
01:16:57,905 --> 01:16:59,864
please don't fire out the Humvee.

815
01:16:59,949 --> 01:17:02,701
The round will just bounce around
and someone might get shot.

816
01:17:03,369 --> 01:17:05,036
l don't like getting shot.

817
01:17:05,121 --> 01:17:06,913
Understood, Sergeant.

818
01:17:19,135 --> 01:17:20,343
ELDRlDGE: lt's a pretty standard mission.

819
01:17:20,428 --> 01:17:23,054
We're just here to pick up
some unexploded ordnance.

820
01:17:23,139 --> 01:17:25,140
Sergeant James is gonna
go see what the deal is...

821
01:17:25,224 --> 01:17:26,349
All right, guys.

822
01:17:26,434 --> 01:17:28,977
...and hopefully we're gone
in a couple of minutes.

823
01:17:29,061 --> 01:17:30,687
-We've gotta gear up.
-For what?

824
01:17:30,771 --> 01:17:34,482
Security hasn't gone in.
We'll just go in quiet. Radios off.

825
01:17:34,567 --> 01:17:35,734
-Roger.
-Roger that.

826
01:17:36,402 --> 01:17:38,528
-l'm glad you came.
-Stay safe. All right.

828
01:20:31,619 --> 01:20:32,994
Psst. Psst.

829
01:20:43,339 --> 01:20:48,426
-Clear.
-Hey, cigarette's still smoking.

830
01:20:52,306 --> 01:20:53,973
lt's all our shit.

831
01:20:57,311 --> 01:20:59,229
Motherfucking goldmine.

832
01:21:00,814 --> 01:21:02,273
Watch out for trips.

833
01:21:26,507 --> 01:21:28,132
l got something.

834
01:21:41,188 --> 01:21:45,984
l know this kid. His name's Beckham.
He sells DVDs.

835
01:21:46,777 --> 01:21:49,362
You ever see a body bomb before, man?

836
01:21:51,323 --> 01:21:54,701
lt's fucking disgusting, man.
Let's get out of here.

837
01:21:56,745 --> 01:22:01,791
Eldridge, why don't you grab all the C4 and
det cord you can get your hands on, okay?

838
01:22:04,920 --> 01:22:06,588
Let's get all this ordnance out of here.

839
01:22:06,672 --> 01:22:09,924
And we're just gonna...
We are gonna blow the place, got it?

840
01:22:10,009 --> 01:22:12,010
-Roger that.
-Let's blow it.

842
01:22:20,185 --> 01:22:21,269
What are you doing?

844
01:22:22,688 --> 01:22:25,189
Yeah? Putting the stones in to move?

845
01:22:26,275 --> 01:22:30,361
Yeah. That's really wonderful,
but it's a little unsafe today.

847
01:22:32,364 --> 01:22:35,908
Yeah, it's a little unsafe.
So, maybe... l don't know,

848
01:22:35,993 --> 01:22:39,203
l'm thinking maybe we should move?

849
01:22:39,705 --> 01:22:40,455
No?

851
01:22:57,431 --> 01:22:58,431
Fuck.

852
01:23:03,562 --> 01:23:05,104
-You all right?
-Yeah. You?

853
01:23:05,189 --> 01:23:06,189
Yeah.

855
01:23:12,071 --> 01:23:14,322
-ELDRlDGE: You all right, man?
-Yeah.

856
01:23:15,282 --> 01:23:17,200
No one in or out, okay?

857
01:23:59,034 --> 01:24:01,369
Cancel the det. Cancel the det.

858
01:24:23,142 --> 01:24:25,727
-Fuck is he doing?
-l don't know, man.

859
01:24:27,521 --> 01:24:28,980
l don't know.

861
01:25:57,152 --> 01:26:00,279
-l'm coming out.
-SANBORN: Roger that.

862
01:26:17,631 --> 01:26:18,756
Hi.

864
01:26:20,968 --> 01:26:23,052
-Where are you from?
-New York.

865
01:26:23,136 --> 01:26:26,514
-The Big Apple.
-l'm from lraq.

866
01:26:26,598 --> 01:26:28,683
CAMBRlDGE: l love it here.
This is a beautiful place.

867
01:26:28,767 --> 01:26:34,856
But it's not too safe here, okay?
So l think we need to move, please?

868
01:26:59,089 --> 01:27:01,007
ELDRlDGE: You think it's that little base rat?

869
01:27:01,091 --> 01:27:04,218
-SANBORN: No, l don't.
-You positive?

870
01:27:04,678 --> 01:27:08,431
Sure. Hey, l don't know, man.
They all look the same, right?

871
01:27:08,891 --> 01:27:12,059
l don't know. Will seemed sure.
That was weird.

872
01:27:12,519 --> 01:27:13,895
Very weird.

873
01:27:15,814 --> 01:27:18,065
Please, just move.

875
01:27:19,484 --> 01:27:20,776
Move. Move.

877
01:27:22,154 --> 01:27:23,654
Thank you. Move on.

878
01:27:23,739 --> 01:27:25,698
Move on. Thank you.

880
01:27:28,994 --> 01:27:30,036
l'm sorry.

881
01:27:30,662 --> 01:27:32,455
Will's very weird.

882
01:27:32,539 --> 01:27:34,790
l mean, he keeps bomb parts under his bed.

883
01:27:34,875 --> 01:27:38,336
l bet you he won't keep
any of these parts under his bed.

884
01:27:40,005 --> 01:27:41,047
Bye-bye.

886
01:27:42,716 --> 01:27:45,217
Yeah, bye-bye. Bye. Thank you.

887
01:27:46,136 --> 01:27:48,804
Hey, Colonel. Let's go.

888
01:27:48,889 --> 01:27:51,557
So long. Thank you.

889
01:27:58,523 --> 01:27:59,649
ELDRlDGE: lED.

890
01:28:00,275 --> 01:28:02,985
-lED, lED. Fuck.
-Cambridge!

891
01:28:03,904 --> 01:28:05,947
-What happened here?
-Clear it.

892
01:28:06,031 --> 01:28:09,450
-Jesus!
-JAMES: Get back! Get down!

893
01:28:09,534 --> 01:28:10,618
SANBORN: Stay back.

894
01:28:10,702 --> 01:28:13,120
Stay back, Sanborn. Keep them back.

895
01:28:13,205 --> 01:28:14,246
ls anyone hurt?

896
01:28:14,331 --> 01:28:17,792
Cambridge! Fuck. Fuck.

897
01:28:17,876 --> 01:28:19,585
Where's Cambridge?

898
01:28:19,920 --> 01:28:23,089
-Cambridge, come on. We gotta go.
-Shit. l think he's dead.

899
01:28:24,007 --> 01:28:26,842
We got to find Cambridge. Doc!

900
01:28:26,927 --> 01:28:30,054
-Eldridge. Eldridge.
-Doc!

901
01:28:30,263 --> 01:28:31,305
-Eldridge!
-Doc!

902
01:28:31,390 --> 01:28:32,848
-Eldridge, come on, man. Come on.
-Doc!

903
01:28:32,933 --> 01:28:35,142
l just saw him. He was walking right here.

904
01:28:35,227 --> 01:28:37,979
He's dead, okay? He's dead. Okay?

905
01:28:52,327 --> 01:28:55,579
lt's all right, man. You're all right, buddy.
You're all right.

907
01:29:19,271 --> 01:29:23,607
Hello?

908
01:29:24,693 --> 01:29:25,818
Will?

910
01:29:27,988 --> 01:29:33,367
Hello?

912
01:30:25,378 --> 01:30:26,879
Hey, let me ask you a question.

913
01:30:26,963 --> 01:30:29,924
What happened to the little kid
that used to work here?

914
01:30:30,008 --> 01:30:33,094
Sorry, man. English... l, no English.

915
01:30:33,178 --> 01:30:35,387
No English. You no speak English now.

916
01:30:35,472 --> 01:30:39,642
Okay. Little kid. Beckham is his name.
He sells DVDs.

917
01:30:39,726 --> 01:30:42,520
DVD. One DVD, $5.

918
01:30:42,604 --> 01:30:44,271
Jesus Christ.

919
01:30:44,356 --> 01:30:46,107
-$5.
-Excuse me, soldier.

920
01:30:46,191 --> 01:30:48,359
-You in charge of this area here?
-What's up?

921
01:30:48,443 --> 01:30:50,277
You know this guy?

922
01:30:50,362 --> 01:30:52,822
How do we know that
he's not giving intel to insurgents,

923
01:30:52,906 --> 01:30:54,281
telling them where to drop mortars?

924
01:30:54,366 --> 01:30:56,575
-l think he's just selling DVDs.
-Well, he's a security risk.

925
01:30:56,660 --> 01:30:59,495
We should get rid of him.
What are you looking at?

926
01:30:59,579 --> 01:31:01,205
He's just selling DVDs, man.

927
01:31:01,289 --> 01:31:02,414
All the merchants are clear.

928
01:31:02,499 --> 01:31:03,541
-By who?
-l couldn't do anything with him

929
01:31:03,625 --> 01:31:05,835
without the say-so from my CO.

930
01:31:07,587 --> 01:31:08,963
All right. Fuck.

931
01:31:11,091 --> 01:31:12,216
Fuck.

933
01:31:48,712 --> 01:31:50,296
Change anything?

934
01:31:50,714 --> 01:31:53,174
You speak English now, don't you?

935
01:31:53,258 --> 01:31:54,717
-Okay.
-Drive.

936
01:32:16,907 --> 01:32:18,324
-Okay.
-This is his house?

937
01:32:18,867 --> 01:32:20,451
Beckham's house?

938
01:32:29,127 --> 01:32:30,461
Wait here.

939
01:32:39,888 --> 01:32:40,971
Fuck.

942
01:33:40,657 --> 01:33:41,699
Shh!

943
01:33:43,118 --> 01:33:44,410
You speak English?

944
01:33:44,494 --> 01:33:46,078
English, French, Arabic.

945
01:33:46,162 --> 01:33:47,913
Good. Open your vest.

946
01:33:48,957 --> 01:33:50,582
Stay there. Stay.

947
01:33:51,459 --> 01:33:53,377
Tell me what you know about Beckham.

948
01:33:53,461 --> 01:33:56,880
-For whom?
-Beckham, 1 2-year-old boy, body bomb.

949
01:33:56,965 --> 01:33:58,590
Stay right there.

950
01:33:58,675 --> 01:34:00,676
-l don't know.
-You don't know.

951
01:34:00,760 --> 01:34:04,305
But please, sit down. l am Professor Nabil.

952
01:34:04,389 --> 01:34:06,140
-This is my home.
-Mmm-hmm.

953
01:34:06,224 --> 01:34:09,059
You are a guest. Please, sit down.

954
01:34:11,730 --> 01:34:16,650
l'm a guest. l'm just...

955
01:34:16,735 --> 01:34:22,614
l'm looking for the people
responsible for Beckham.

956
01:34:23,408 --> 01:34:25,451
You are ClA. No?

957
01:34:26,911 --> 01:34:29,955
l am very pleased to see ClA in my home.

958
01:34:30,040 --> 01:34:31,415
Please, sit.

959
01:34:39,424 --> 01:34:40,424
Look...

961
01:34:45,221 --> 01:34:46,930
Be careful. The gun can go off.

964
01:35:43,988 --> 01:35:45,948
-U.S.A. friendly coming in.
-GUARD 1 : Stop.

965
01:35:46,032 --> 01:35:48,492
-GUARD 2: Get the fuck down!
-GUARD 1 : Stop right there.

966
01:35:48,576 --> 01:35:50,244
-U.S.A. friendly.
-GUARD 1 : Halt.

967
01:35:50,328 --> 01:35:52,287
GUARD 2: On your knees.
GUARD 3: Get down on your knees, now.

968
01:35:52,372 --> 01:35:53,539
You will be shot.

969
01:35:53,623 --> 01:35:55,124
-Don't move.
-Don't fucking move.

970
01:35:55,208 --> 01:35:57,459
-Get the fuck down!
-On your knees!

971
01:35:57,544 --> 01:36:00,504
-Down now!
-Open yourjacket!

972
01:36:00,588 --> 01:36:03,924
-Opening my jacket.
-Cover. Get him down.

973
01:36:04,008 --> 01:36:05,217
-On the ground.
-l have a weapon.

974
01:36:05,301 --> 01:36:07,636
-Don't fucking move.
-Get him down.

975
01:36:07,720 --> 01:36:09,555
-Tower, hold cover. Searching.
-l have a weapon.

976
01:36:09,639 --> 01:36:11,890
-Hands where l can see them.
-Gun.

977
01:36:11,975 --> 01:36:15,227
-Like l said.
-Weapons clear.

978
01:36:15,728 --> 01:36:17,271
lD?

979
01:36:17,355 --> 01:36:20,149
-What the fuck are you doing?
-l was at a whorehouse.

980
01:36:21,401 --> 01:36:26,196
All right. lf l let you in,
will you tell me where it is exactly?

981
01:36:28,116 --> 01:36:29,366
Yeah.

982
01:36:31,494 --> 01:36:33,203
SANBORN: James, do you copy?

983
01:36:42,797 --> 01:36:45,132
James, do you have your ears on?

984
01:36:48,261 --> 01:36:49,428
James!

985
01:36:51,222 --> 01:36:52,389
Yes, it's James. What's up?

986
01:37:08,323 --> 01:37:10,574
-Hey.
-What's up, man?

987
01:37:12,744 --> 01:37:15,537
Look, we have a tank explosion
in the Green Zone.

988
01:37:15,622 --> 01:37:18,874
We have to do a post-blast assessment.
See if it was a suicide bombing,

989
01:37:18,958 --> 01:37:21,585
and if so, how the fuck did he do it?

990
01:37:21,669 --> 01:37:23,003
Okay.

991
01:37:23,087 --> 01:37:24,838
Where'd you say you were again?

992
01:37:24,923 --> 01:37:26,590
l didn't, Sergeant. Let's go.

993
01:37:28,927 --> 01:37:31,345
What happened to your head, James?

994
01:37:38,353 --> 01:37:41,563
You ready? Game face, buddy. Let's go.

995
01:37:46,694 --> 01:37:48,654
-SANBORN: You ready?
-Let's do this.

996
01:37:48,738 --> 01:37:50,614
-Rock and roll.
-Moving out.

997
01:37:52,242 --> 01:37:53,408
Good night.

1000
01:38:04,587 --> 01:38:06,964
U.S.A. friendlies coming through.

1002
01:38:27,277 --> 01:38:28,986
Make room, guys. Make room.

1003
01:38:41,583 --> 01:38:44,001
Hey, Sanborn. Look.

1004
01:38:48,089 --> 01:38:49,506
Grab the other arm. Grab the other arm.

1005
01:38:49,591 --> 01:38:52,426
-Grab the other arm.
-Sir, can l get a medic? Need a medic!

1008
01:39:11,863 --> 01:39:13,655
JAMES: An oil tanker?
SANBORN: Yeah.

1009
01:39:17,035 --> 01:39:19,077
SANBORN: Pretty long flight, huh?
JAMES: Yeah.

1013
01:41:26,539 --> 01:41:29,166
JAMES: This is the edge of the blast radius.

1014
01:41:34,172 --> 01:41:35,338
Jesus.

1015
01:41:36,591 --> 01:41:40,469
-So, where's our triggerman?
-Burnt up in the flames, man.

1016
01:41:40,553 --> 01:41:44,723
Suicide bomber.
We'll never find a body in that shit.

1017
01:41:44,807 --> 01:41:49,186
What if there was no body?
What if it was a remote det?

1018
01:41:54,233 --> 01:41:57,110
A really good bad guy
hides out in the dark, right?

1019
01:41:57,195 --> 01:41:58,445
Mmm-hmm.

1020
01:41:59,864 --> 01:42:01,281
Right here.

1021
01:42:01,949 --> 01:42:05,410
The perfect vantage point
outside the blast radius

1022
01:42:05,495 --> 01:42:08,413
to sit back
and watch us clean up their mess.

1023
01:42:11,167 --> 01:42:13,460
ELDRlDGE: Wanna go out there?
JAMES: Yes, l do.

1024
01:42:15,379 --> 01:42:19,466
-l could stand to get in a little trouble.
-SANBORN: No, man. This is bullshit.

1025
01:42:19,550 --> 01:42:22,052
Look, you got three infantry platoons
behind you

1026
01:42:22,136 --> 01:42:25,138
whose job it is to go haji hunting.
That ain't our fucking job.

1027
01:42:25,223 --> 01:42:28,141
JAMES: You don't say no to me, Sanborn.
l say no to you, okay?

1028
01:42:28,226 --> 01:42:30,268
You know there are guys watching us
right now.

1029
01:42:30,353 --> 01:42:34,064
They're laughing at this.
Okay, and l'm not okay with that.

1030
01:42:34,649 --> 01:42:38,068
Now, turn off your goddamn torch,
because we're going.

1031
01:42:49,580 --> 01:42:51,248
Fucking shit.

1033
01:43:46,929 --> 01:43:48,555
JAMES: Now we know
where their oil tanker came from.

1034
01:43:48,639 --> 01:43:50,181
SANBORN: No shit. Same kind.

1035
01:43:50,266 --> 01:43:52,309
-We're close.
-Yeah.

1036
01:43:52,393 --> 01:43:54,144
All right, these alleyways
are probably set up in a grid.

1037
01:43:54,228 --> 01:43:57,397
We're going to need to split up,
flush them out.

1038
01:43:57,481 --> 01:44:00,901
Sanborn, you take one.
Eldridge take two, l got three.

1039
01:44:00,985 --> 01:44:03,403
Rally point at your intersection.
Ready, move.

1040
01:44:03,487 --> 01:44:05,405
SANBORN: Wait, rally point when?

1041
01:44:05,489 --> 01:44:06,615
Fuck.

1046
01:45:20,064 --> 01:45:21,147
Shit.

1048
01:45:28,572 --> 01:45:30,198
-Shit!
-You got contact?

1049
01:45:30,282 --> 01:45:31,992
Who was it? What's going on?

1050
01:45:32,076 --> 01:45:34,285
-What do you got?
-lt's Eldridge.

1051
01:45:35,371 --> 01:45:37,664
JAMES: Go, go. Man down. Man down.

1052
01:45:39,000 --> 01:45:41,418
-Shit. Shit.
-All right. No, no.

1053
01:45:41,502 --> 01:45:42,752
-Negative, negative. lt's not him.
-Shit.

1054
01:45:42,837 --> 01:45:44,004
-He's gone.
-lt's not him.

1055
01:45:44,088 --> 01:45:45,505
Where'd they go? Where'd they go?

1056
01:45:45,589 --> 01:45:47,424
Tankers and troops are that way.

1057
01:45:47,508 --> 01:45:49,509
-Let's go this way.
-Fuck!

1058
01:45:56,934 --> 01:45:58,059
Fuck.

1059
01:46:11,907 --> 01:46:13,950
Use your torch. On three.

1060
01:46:16,537 --> 01:46:20,206
Ready? One, two, three.

1061
01:46:22,793 --> 01:46:24,210
-Fuck.
-Shit.

1062
01:46:29,550 --> 01:46:31,468
Softly, softly, softly.

1063
01:46:42,730 --> 01:46:45,648
On three. One, two, three.

1065
01:46:50,029 --> 01:46:52,072
JAMES: Now, now, now. Go, go, go.

1066
01:46:54,658 --> 01:46:56,409
Eldridge, you okay?

1067
01:46:56,494 --> 01:46:57,911
-Fuck, dude, l'm hit.
-Shit, he's hit, man.

1068
01:46:57,995 --> 01:47:01,581
They hit him in the fucking leg.
Shit. Come on, come on, come on.

1069
01:47:01,665 --> 01:47:03,917
-Am l dead? Am l dead?
-No, you're fine, man. You're fine.

1070
01:47:04,001 --> 01:47:06,211
-You're fine, man.
-That's right. Just breathe.

1071
01:47:06,295 --> 01:47:07,587
Hang on, buddy.

1072
01:47:07,671 --> 01:47:08,963
-Okay, l got it, got it, got it.
-You got it?

1073
01:47:09,048 --> 01:47:11,758
l'm gonna put some pressure now, come on.
You're all right.

1075
01:47:12,968 --> 01:47:15,970
You're all right. Look at me, look at me.
You're all right, okay? You're all right.

1076
01:47:16,055 --> 01:47:17,430
All right, buddy. You ready to get up?

1077
01:47:17,515 --> 01:47:19,933
On three, ready? One, two, three.

1078
01:48:42,766 --> 01:48:46,144
Hey, what's up, man? Hey, man.
What's up, man?

1079
01:48:46,228 --> 01:48:49,355
Wanna buy some DVDs?
Wanna play some soccer?

1080
01:48:49,440 --> 01:48:52,525
Wait. What's up? Come on, man.
Wanna play some...

1081
01:49:09,585 --> 01:49:11,502
Hey, wait a minute!

1082
01:49:11,587 --> 01:49:12,712
Fuck.

1084
01:49:16,884 --> 01:49:18,968
-Hey.
-JAMES: How you doing, buddy?

1085
01:49:19,553 --> 01:49:21,179
Doc says you're going to be okay.

1086
01:49:21,263 --> 01:49:24,182
My fucking femur is shattered
in nine places.

1087
01:49:25,100 --> 01:49:27,936
He said l'll be walking in six months,
if l'm fucking lucky.

1088
01:49:28,020 --> 01:49:32,273
-Six months ain't bad, huh?
-lt's not bad? Fucking sucks, man.

1090
01:49:33,484 --> 01:49:35,235
Take it easy, buddy.

1091
01:49:36,820 --> 01:49:39,906
You see that? You fucking see that?

1092
01:49:39,990 --> 01:49:43,618
That's what happens when you fucking
shoot someone, you motherfucker.

1093
01:49:43,702 --> 01:49:46,412
Sorry. Sorry, Owen.

1094
01:49:46,497 --> 01:49:50,208
Fuck you, Will. Really. Fuck you.

1095
01:49:50,292 --> 01:49:52,877
Thanks for saving my life,
but we didn't have to go out

1096
01:49:52,962 --> 01:49:56,965
looking for trouble to
get your fucking adrenaline fix, you fuck.

1097
01:49:58,842 --> 01:50:00,635
Hey, take care of yourself, Owen.

1098
01:50:00,719 --> 01:50:02,303
Come home safe, man.

1099
01:50:02,388 --> 01:50:05,306
-See you on the other side, man.
-All right.

1100
01:50:05,391 --> 01:50:08,017
Let's get out of this fucking desert!

1101
01:50:13,774 --> 01:50:14,857
SOLDlER: Don't move.

1102
01:50:14,942 --> 01:50:17,652
lf you keep walking, we will shoot you.

1103
01:50:18,529 --> 01:50:19,612
Move him back.

1105
01:50:20,864 --> 01:50:22,073
Keep that translator back.

1106
01:50:22,157 --> 01:50:24,367
-But the bomb was forced on him.
-Get back!

1107
01:50:24,451 --> 01:50:26,536
Don't move! Stay still!

1109
01:50:28,372 --> 01:50:30,206
lf you keep walking, we will shoot you.

1110
01:50:30,291 --> 01:50:32,500
lf you keep walking, we will shoot.

1111
01:50:32,584 --> 01:50:34,794
Get that translator back, now.

1113
01:50:38,257 --> 01:50:40,717
-TRANSLATOR: He's not a bad man.
-Clear.

1114
01:50:40,801 --> 01:50:42,969
Give him room. Give him room.

1116
01:50:49,560 --> 01:50:51,019
Hey, what do you got?

1117
01:50:51,103 --> 01:50:53,730
He came walking up to our checkpoint,
said he had a bomb strapped to him.

1118
01:50:53,814 --> 01:50:55,690
But he's sorry. He doesn't want it to go off.

1119
01:50:55,774 --> 01:50:57,400
Then he starts begging us
to take it off of him.

1120
01:50:57,484 --> 01:50:59,319
-Right.
-Help this man. He's not a bad man.

1121
01:50:59,403 --> 01:51:02,822
SANBORN: He's not a bad man?
He got a bomb strapped to him.

1122
01:51:02,906 --> 01:51:04,824
This is a joke. He's trying to pull us closer.

1123
01:51:04,908 --> 01:51:11,122
Yeah, l got it. l got it. All right.
Look, tell him to open his shirt slowly

1124
01:51:11,206 --> 01:51:12,707
and see what's inside.

1126
01:51:16,545 --> 01:51:18,129
Slowly. Slowly.

1127
01:51:18,213 --> 01:51:19,422
Slowly!

1129
01:51:30,184 --> 01:51:31,351
Jesus.

1130
01:51:32,436 --> 01:51:34,896
All right, Sergeant, l need
a 75-meter perimeter. Get these guys back.

1131
01:51:34,980 --> 01:51:37,940
-Get them back.
-Give me 75 meters. Get back!

1132
01:51:38,484 --> 01:51:40,985
You tell him to get on his knees
and touch the sky, okay?

1134
01:51:42,154 --> 01:51:44,113
Slowly!

1135
01:51:44,198 --> 01:51:45,198
Get down!

1137
01:51:49,495 --> 01:51:51,579
Okay. l need your radio.

1138
01:51:51,663 --> 01:51:52,747
Can't we just shoot him?

1139
01:51:52,831 --> 01:51:53,831
-TRANSLATOR: No, no, no.
-No.

1140
01:51:53,916 --> 01:51:57,543
He's a family man. He's not a bad man.
He's just asking for help, only help.

1141
01:51:57,628 --> 01:51:58,878
-Yeah, all right. Look. You get back.
-Only help!

1142
01:51:58,962 --> 01:52:00,004
-Like everybody else.
-He's asking for help!

1143
01:52:00,089 --> 01:52:01,297
You don't want to die, get back!

1144
01:52:01,382 --> 01:52:02,632
l got it.

1146
01:52:05,636 --> 01:52:08,513
-Listen. l know we've had our differences.
-Yeah.

1147
01:52:08,597 --> 01:52:13,101
Eldridge... Look, it happened, all right?
lt's water under the bridge.

1148
01:52:14,103 --> 01:52:16,229
James, this is suicide, man.

1149
01:52:17,481 --> 01:52:19,232
That's why they call it
a suicide bomb, right?

1151
01:52:23,445 --> 01:52:24,404
Let's do this.

1152
01:52:24,488 --> 01:52:25,905
TRANSLATOR: He says
the bomb may have a timer,

1153
01:52:25,989 --> 01:52:26,989
please hurry.

1154
01:52:27,449 --> 01:52:28,699
-We're good.
-You all right now?

1155
01:52:28,784 --> 01:52:29,867
Yeah.

1156
01:52:35,290 --> 01:52:37,083
-Go get them.
-Let's do it.

1157
01:52:37,167 --> 01:52:38,167
-See you.
-Watch for snipers.

1158
01:52:38,252 --> 01:52:39,377
Yeah.

1160
01:52:50,139 --> 01:52:51,806
JAMES: Get your hands up.

1162
01:52:55,018 --> 01:52:55,977
TRANSLATOR: He says he has a family.

1164
01:52:57,938 --> 01:52:58,938
TRANSLATOR: Please help.

1166
01:53:05,154 --> 01:53:06,529
Now, listen.

1167
01:53:06,613 --> 01:53:07,947
-TRANSLATOR: Please.
-Look.

1168
01:53:08,031 --> 01:53:12,076
lt'd be a lot easier for me to disarm this
if l just shoot you. Do you understand?

1170
01:53:16,665 --> 01:53:17,790
All right. What's he saying?

1171
01:53:17,875 --> 01:53:20,418
He says, "l don't wish to die. l have a family.

1172
01:53:20,502 --> 01:53:22,503
"Please take this off me."

1173
01:53:22,588 --> 01:53:25,339
All right.
Tell him to put his hands behind his head

1174
01:53:25,424 --> 01:53:27,133
or l'll be very happy to shoot him.

1178
01:53:33,223 --> 01:53:36,726
Look, that's not what l said.
Tell him to put his hands behind his head

1179
01:53:36,810 --> 01:53:38,394
or l will shoot him.

1181
01:53:40,939 --> 01:53:41,939
Listen.

1183
01:53:44,359 --> 01:53:45,735
Listen, listen.

1184
01:53:46,904 --> 01:53:47,904
Yes? Yes?

1185
01:53:48,572 --> 01:53:50,490
Yes? You understand?

1187
01:53:52,743 --> 01:53:53,868
Okay.

1188
01:53:57,247 --> 01:53:58,581
What do you got here?

1190
01:54:00,042 --> 01:54:01,834
TRANSLATOR: He has four children.

1191
01:54:06,465 --> 01:54:07,590
Shit.

1193
01:54:12,554 --> 01:54:15,848
All right, Sanborn, we got a timer,
and we got a lot of wires, man.

1194
01:54:15,933 --> 01:54:18,100
l'm going to need a little help on this.

1195
01:54:18,185 --> 01:54:20,436
Roger that. Tell me what you need.

1196
01:54:20,521 --> 01:54:23,022
Bolt cutters. But you gotta get down here
in two minutes,

1197
01:54:23,106 --> 01:54:26,442
-or we're all fucked.
-Roger that. l'll be there in 30 seconds.

1199
01:54:29,905 --> 01:54:32,323
TRANSLATOR: He says,
"Please, l have a family."

1201
01:54:35,619 --> 01:54:37,662
l know. l know. Just...

1202
01:54:38,121 --> 01:54:40,122
lt's okay, you're all right. You're all right.

1204
01:54:43,710 --> 01:54:45,211
TRANSLATOR: Says, "Please don't leave me."

1206
01:54:50,884 --> 01:54:53,886
-You weren't fucking kidding.
-Nope.

1207
01:54:53,971 --> 01:54:55,888
What's this made out of?

1209
01:54:57,474 --> 01:54:58,474
Shit.

1210
01:55:00,894 --> 01:55:03,688
SANBORN: Oh, man.
That's case-hardened steel.

1212
01:55:05,482 --> 01:55:06,524
Shit.

1213
01:55:06,608 --> 01:55:08,276
-What's our time?
-We got two minutes.

1214
01:55:08,360 --> 01:55:11,654
-Shit.
-We're gonna need a torch to get this off.

1215
01:55:11,780 --> 01:55:13,739
Well, we don't have one of those
in the fucking truck, man.

1216
01:55:13,824 --> 01:55:15,157
-He's dead, man.
-Hold on. Let me think.

1217
01:55:15,242 --> 01:55:17,410
Just let me think. Let's handle this.
We're gonna...

1218
01:55:17,494 --> 01:55:20,997
lt's okay. We got this. We got this.
Just... Shh! Okay?

1219
01:55:22,583 --> 01:55:24,500
l'm gonna look at the back.

1220
01:55:26,503 --> 01:55:30,506
lt's just... We don't got enough time,
Sanborn. We don't have time.

1221
01:55:30,591 --> 01:55:33,718
l just gotta... l gotta get these bolts off.

1222
01:55:33,802 --> 01:55:37,263
No. We got a minute and a half, man.
We gotta get out of here.

1223
01:55:37,347 --> 01:55:39,682
-l'll handle this. Just go.
-Look, Will, come on, man.

1224
01:55:39,766 --> 01:55:41,601
Look, l'm right behind you. Just go.

1225
01:55:41,685 --> 01:55:43,269
Fuck him! Come on. Let's go.

1226
01:55:43,353 --> 01:55:46,147
-Sanborn, l got the suit. Just go.
-James.

1227
01:55:46,231 --> 01:55:50,276
Sanborn, you have 45 seconds.
You have 45 seconds, Sanborn, leave!

1228
01:55:50,360 --> 01:55:53,321
-He's a fucking dead man, Will!
-Go!

1229
01:55:54,239 --> 01:55:56,907
-Everybody get back!
-Go, go, go!

1231
01:56:02,497 --> 01:56:03,873
We got one.

1232
01:56:04,374 --> 01:56:06,917
Go! Get back! Get back!

1233
01:56:09,504 --> 01:56:10,546
Shit, l can't!

1234
01:56:11,465 --> 01:56:14,759
There's too many locks.
There's too many. l can't do it.

1235
01:56:14,843 --> 01:56:19,221
l can't get it off. l'm sorry. Okay?
You understand? l'm sorry.

1236
01:56:19,306 --> 01:56:22,099
You hear me? l'm sorry. l'm sorry!

1237
01:56:22,184 --> 01:56:23,267
Get down now!

1238
01:56:23,352 --> 01:56:24,977
l can't help him.

1239
01:56:27,189 --> 01:56:30,483
Everybody stay down! Stay down!

1241
01:56:53,507 --> 01:56:56,842
James! Everybody up and out. James!

1243
01:57:40,429 --> 01:57:41,971
You all right?

1244
01:57:44,725 --> 01:57:50,396
No, man. l fucking hate this place.

1245
01:57:53,608 --> 01:57:55,484
Here, man. Have a hit.

1246
01:58:07,164 --> 01:58:09,331
l'm not ready to die, James.

1247
01:58:11,376 --> 01:58:14,253
Well, you're not going to die out here, bro.

1248
01:58:14,796 --> 01:58:16,505
Another two inches.

1249
01:58:19,342 --> 01:58:21,969
Shrapnel zings by, slices my throat.

1250
01:58:23,597 --> 01:58:26,098
l bleed out like a pig in the sand.

1251
01:58:29,019 --> 01:58:30,895
Nobody will give a shit.

1252
01:58:33,565 --> 01:58:36,817
l mean, my parents will care,
but they don't count, man. Who else?

1253
01:58:44,451 --> 01:58:46,410
l don't even have a son.

1254
01:58:49,539 --> 01:58:52,917
Well, you're going to have
plenty of time for that, amigo.

1255
01:58:53,001 --> 01:58:54,752
-No, man.
-You know.

1256
01:58:57,005 --> 01:58:58,255
l'm done.

1257
01:59:02,552 --> 01:59:04,053
l want a son.

1258
01:59:07,724 --> 01:59:09,767
l want a little boy, Will.

1259
01:59:16,858 --> 01:59:19,401
l mean, how do you do it, you know?

1260
01:59:20,570 --> 01:59:22,071
Take the risk.

1261
01:59:29,746 --> 01:59:35,751
l don't know. l just...
l guess l don't think about it.

1262
01:59:38,755 --> 01:59:43,634
Every time we go out, it's life or death.
You roll the dice.

1263
01:59:47,430 --> 01:59:49,682
You recognize that, don't you?

1264
01:59:51,184 --> 01:59:52,601
Yeah. Yeah.

1265
02:00:02,612 --> 02:00:03,946
Yeah, l do.

1266
02:00:05,615 --> 02:00:07,950
But l don't know why, you know.

1268
02:00:20,088 --> 02:00:22,047
l don't know, J.T.

1269
02:00:22,132 --> 02:00:24,341
Do you know why l am the way l am?

1270
02:00:30,098 --> 02:00:31,473
No, l don't.

1271
02:01:06,176 --> 02:01:09,345
Pizza. Pizza.

1273
02:01:31,409 --> 02:01:34,745
-Wow. You did some shopping.
-Yeah.

1274
02:01:35,580 --> 02:01:37,581
l got some soda. We done?

1275
02:01:39,125 --> 02:01:42,461
You want to go get us some cereal
and l'll meet you at the checkout?

1276
02:01:42,545 --> 02:01:44,546
Okay. Cereal.

1277
02:01:48,885 --> 02:01:50,052
Where...

1278
02:02:49,362 --> 02:02:52,990
Some guy drove his truck
to the middle of an lraqi market,

1279
02:02:53,616 --> 02:02:55,701
starts passing out free candies.

1280
02:02:55,785 --> 02:02:59,121
All the kids come running up,
the families and stuff.

1281
02:03:00,457 --> 02:03:01,957
He detonates.

1282
02:03:04,294 --> 02:03:06,420
They're saying 59 are dead.

1283
02:03:16,306 --> 02:03:18,807
You know they need more bomb techs.

1284
02:03:21,978 --> 02:03:24,396
You want to chop those up for me?

1285
02:03:25,315 --> 02:03:26,607
Boing! Boing!

1290
02:03:34,741 --> 02:03:35,824
Yeah.

1291
02:03:38,036 --> 02:03:40,454
You love playing with that.

1292
02:03:40,538 --> 02:03:43,916
You love playing
with all your stuffed animals.

1293
02:03:44,000 --> 02:03:49,338
You love your mommy, your daddy,
your nature pajamas.

1294
02:03:49,881 --> 02:03:51,757
You love everything, don't you?

1295
02:03:51,841 --> 02:03:52,841
Yeah.

1297
02:03:54,094 --> 02:03:57,846
But you know what, buddy?
As you get older,

1298
02:03:58,848 --> 02:04:03,936
some of the things that you love might
not seem so special anymore, you know.

1299
02:04:05,105 --> 02:04:07,147
Like yourjack-in-the-box.

1300
02:04:09,901 --> 02:04:14,363
Maybe you realize
it's just a piece of tin and a stuffed animal.

1301
02:04:16,449 --> 02:04:20,953
As you get older,
there are fewer things you really love.

1302
02:04:24,290 --> 02:04:28,460
And by the time you get to my age,
maybe it's only one or two things.

1303
02:04:36,553 --> 02:04:38,595
With me, l think it's one.

1304
02:05:15,216 --> 02:05:17,759
-Welcome to Delta Company.
-Sergeant.