A "MASTERPIECE APPRECIATION
SERIES" SPECIAL SELECTION
GRANDSCOPE
A SHOCHIKU FILM
THE HUMAN CONDITION
Developed by BUNGEI PRODUCTION
and NINJIN CLUB
Produced by
SHIGERU WAKATSUKI
Based on the Novel by
JUNPEI GOMIKAWA
Screenplay by ZENZO MATSUYAMA
and MASAKI KOBAYASHI
Director of Photography
YOSHIO MIYAJIMA
Production Design KAZUE HIRATAKA
Sound Recording HIDEO NISHIZAKI
Music CHUJI KINOSHITA
Lighting TAKASHI KATO
Editing KEIICHI URAOKA
1st Ass't Director YUGORO IMAI
Ass't. Director KOICHI INAGAKI
Ass't Camera TOSHITADA NAGUMO
Ass't Production Design JUSHO TODA
Set Decoration KYOJI SASAKI
Set Design
YOJI MURO
Production Manager
TATSUO OSAWA
Starring
TATSUYA NAKADAI
as Kaji
MICHIYO ARATAMA
as Michiko
CHIKAGE AWASHIMA as Jin Tung Fu
INEKO ARIMA as Yang Chun Lan
KEIJI SADA as Kageyama
SO YAMAMURA as Okishima
AKIRA ISHIHAMA as Chen
SHINJI NANBARA as Kao
SEIJI MIYAGUCHI as Wang Heng Li
TORU ABE as Sergeant Watai
MASAO MISHIMA as Kuroki
EITARO OZAWA as Okazaki
KOJI MITSUI as Furuya
AKITAKE KONO as Captain Kono
NOBUO NAKAMURA as Head Office Chief
KYU SAZANKA as Cho Meisan
Directed by
MASAKI KOBAYASHI
SOUTHERN GATE OF PEACE
This isn't like you.
- Why?
- You're running away.
Don't you want me?
Of course I do.
And I want you too.
Yet we can't marry -
How many times
must I explain?
Because you might be
called up?
I wouldn't care
if it was the day after.
Of course I'd cry.
I'd cry bitterly.
But happiness only lies
in marrying the one you love.
All right.
I'll take you back
to my dormitory.
You'll stay with me tonight.
All right?
Yes... I'll go.
No, you better go back
to your own dormitory.
I can't take you to mine.
You were just testing me.
You shouldn't have done that.
You're a coward
and a weakling!
Now I see that!
SOUTH MANCHURIA STEEL CO.
RESEARCH DEPARTMENT
Hey.
Well, what a surprise.
I came to say good-bye,
as sentimental as that may sound.
You got called up?
When do you leave?
- Tomorrow morning.
The papers came five days ago.
I've been drinking ever since.
Oh, yes.
I ran into Michiko last night.
Aren't you going to marry her?
It's you today.
Tomorrow it could be me.
Being called up
isn't a death sentence.
I'm a born optimist.
Unlike you, I've had
my share of earthly pleasures.
My only regret
is not having left the seed of life
in the womb of a woman I love.
I'll probably regret it too,
but I can't be
as optimistic as you.
The manager wants me.
Wait for me inside.
No, I'll see you tonight.
Tonight? All right.
Kaji looked a bit angry.
Is anything wrong?
Are you going to be
platonic friends forever?
You had the spunk to come
out here to Manchuria alone.
Throw yourself at him!
I did.
He rejected you?
No. 12 and 13,
stop your chatter...
or I'll report you.
THE SUPERVISION
OF COLONIAL LABOR
I read it twice.
Very interesting,
though it does smell
of leftist tendencies.
What are you trying to say?
That men should be treated as men -
I suppose that's the gist.
But in colonial territories it's -
- A challenge?
Yes, sir.
We profit by exploiting
Chinese labor - isn't that the idea?
That's right.
And that goes
against your thesis.
Yes, it does.
Mind if I take a cigarette?
- Help yourself.
So how about it?
Without that contradiction,
there'd be nothing to write about.
So it contradicts your thesis,
but there are still ways
to improve performance,
is that it?
Yes, perhaps there are.
Listen, I want you to take over
at the Loh Hu Liong mines.
Any objections to being sent off
to the hinterlands?
I'm not trying to force you.
You've analyzed the local
situation quite well on paper.
Would you want it
to end up only on paper?
No.
When you're ready to put
your theories into practice,
I'll help you get
a fair chance
at exemption
from military service.
An exemption
from military service?
You're not the only one
to get an exemption.
There are dozens of others.
But it's the idea
of accepting an exemption
in exchange
for the Loh Hu Liong job.
You always complicate things.
It's a bad habit.
The war is escalating,
and there's only one way to oppose it:
A life sentence in prison.
Neither you nor I have
the courage for that. Am I right?
Yes... you're right.
I humbly accept your kind gift.
Not even the commander of the
Kwangtung Army ever dared slap me.
Take Michiko
and go to Loh Hu Liong.
Michiko... his sweetheart?
Is pretty?
The most beautiful girl
in the world.
But you're the most beautiful
girl in my world.
Listen.
So you think you'd just be
a shepherd's dog.
What's wrong with that?
A good dog can lead the sheep
to greener pastures
and earn their gratitude.
If such things are possible.
As for me,
I'll take this one.
My little Manon,
your hair smells like dried grass.
Michiko-san!
Kageyama-san, take care.
Michiko-san, go with Kaji
to Loh Hu Liong.
Let this damn war
go to the dogs.
If you let happiness
slip through your fingers...
He may never return.
I won't be called up.
Loh Hu Liong
is a tiny Manchurian village.
All we'll find there are iron ore
and labor camps.
Would you go with me
to a place like that?
I'd follow you anywhere.
This will affect your whole life.
Think it over carefully.
Even if you were called up...
I'd still want
to have your child.
Is that crazy?
What a honeymoon!
What did you say?
It's all this wind and dust.
I don't care! It's wonderful!
It feels like gravel
in my mouth.
LOH HU LIONG
Step up.
All right.
Bastard!
Why, you!
Think I'm blind?
Trick me into giving you
special rations?
Oh no, you don't!
Come here.
- Kaji from the head office?
- Yes.
I'm Okishima.
We'll be working together.
We can dispense
with the formalities.
What ever made you
come out to the boonies?
Following Kaji-san
through thick and thin?
Nice to meet you.
This way.
Hey, take their bags
to their new quarters.
I read your report on the supervision
of colonial labor.
Lots of fancy words.
Please, ma'am.
The men here are plain speakers.
You'll be fundamentally incompatible.
- Thanks for the advice.
- What's so funny?
Sorry, but your own fancy words
sound out of place.
Anyway, it's very well-written.
Touches the core of the matter.
Touches...
but doesn't quite grasp it.
Why?
If I knew, I'd write it myself.
I'll show your wife around.
You go see the boss.
Furuya, show him the way.
I know this is
nothing new, sir,
but our first shift
requested 2,500 men.
Only 1,500 turned up
this morning.
We can never meet
our production goal that way.
We're at war, Okazaki.
We must expect such shortages.
You can't do your work
unless all conditions are perfect?
I didn't mean that,
but if Labor would do something -
MEETING IN PROGRESS
I'm Kaji. I just arrived.
So you're Kaji?
I'll introduce you.
Mr. Higuchi,
supervisor of Pit No. 2.
His foreman, Mr. Kawashima.
Mr. Koike,
supervisor of Pit No. 1.
And his foreman, Mr. Okazaki.
The head office sent Mr. Kaji here
as labor supervisor.
Pleased to meet you.
You're just in time.
Please sit down.
We're discussing labor problems.
Any good ideas?
I'd like to speak
with Mr. Okishima first...
and find out how many men
are available.
If labor conditions
are improved,
all available men
will report for work.
And in more concrete terms?
Our employment system
must be radically revised.
The labor boss must be replaced
by a direct employment system.
Ridiculous!
You'd be throttling the mines.
Right, Kawashima?
Why is that?
Because -
Kaji's the name, right?
Think about it.
We have
200 labor groups here.
You think a single one
has no system of skimming
or doesn't cheat
on food rations?
I doubt it,
but the matter under discussion
is how to improve
the work attendance rate.
Laborers lose the desire to work
because labor conditions
are basically no good.
Regardless of
how things are "basically,"
workers aren't what
you make them out to be in theory.
They squander any surplus
in idleness or gambling
or pour it
into women's crotches.
We have a difference of opinion.
Mistreating the men
won't yield good results.
You know, Kaji,
theory may be correct
and yet not always apply in reality.
Then either
the theory was wrong
or it was incorrectly applied.
Never mind.
Do what you think is right.
I respect revolutionary ideas.
Now, your work here
won't just be a desk job.
It will cover all aspects
of the men's lives.
Rationing food, disposing
of excrement from 10,000 men,
handling menstrual cases
among the women.
The women?
We have comfort quarters
for our men.
Okishima will show you.
There are about 60 Manchu women.
Starting today,
you're their boss.
I'm relieved
you're not a bachelor.
Go home now and do your duty
by your wife -
but don't overdo it, eh?
But why must our group
be disbanded?
Poor yields.
You've been raking off too much.
Are you kidding?
What's this all about?
Shall I show you the evidence?
Why should the company make trouble
over our contracts with the men?
The company's money
is meant for the workers.
But Mr. Okazaki says
our men work very hard.
Yes, but your rolls
have been padded.
But Mr. Okazaki -
I'm not Mr. Okazaki!
Mr. Okishima,
put in a good word for us.
We've been associates
a long time.
And it's made me moldy.
Kaji's been scraping away the mold
until I'm practically raw.
Mr. Supervisor,
it's the poor living quarters
and poor food
that make our men sickly.
I know.
Bad quarters, poor food.
Men can't work on beans alone.
But there's a still greater evil.
You know what that is?
You men.
Now get this:
I give the men my word.
The food situation
will definitely improve.
Better quarters
will be considered.
But it's no use
as long as you exploit them.
You lend money
to transient laborers
to bind them for life.
And that's not the worst.
You try to squeeze even more
from your investment.
You hire slave-drivers to practically
murder those who try to escape.
I won't allow such methods.
Allow them?
What do you mean?
You're just an employee yourself!
You have no right!
Won't allow it, eh?
Try and stop us!
Hey!
Any more threats
and I'll kick your nuts in!
The gentlemen
seem to be having a bad day.
We'll come back.
Mr. Muta.
I'm returning this.
Your other gifts have been
returned to your home.
Sons of bitches
left too peacefully.
They must be up to something.
Making a tour of inspection?
Much obliged.
Mr. Okishima, please see
that we get the men we need.
I have to face
the old man.
You'll get 'em.
Just don't kill 'em off too fast!
Son of a bitch!
What's going on?
The dog refused to work!
Beating him won't help.
They're not horses.
Get up, scum!
Beating them
only lowers productivity.
I take orders from Okazaki...
not you.
What goes on here
doesn't concern Labor.
- So you'll keep beating them?
- That's right!
Fine. Then tomorrow
you'll have no men to beat.
What?
You're in the pit now.
You can't pull rank
down here.
You men don't want to work?
Then don't!
But you needn't
come back tomorrow.
Stay by the cozy fireplace
in your barracks.
But remember:
You'll get no food!
Just getting home?
You want something?
Just one question.
Did you threaten
to shut off our supply of labor?
Well? Say something.
Can we talk about work
in the morning?
In the morning?
I can see why you'd prefer that.
Can't have your loving wife
seeing your weaknesses.
- Do I have any?
- Answer my question!
What have you got
to be so proud of?
You may brutally beat
your laborers,
but it doesn't mean
others will be intimidated.
I just warned your assistant.
Mr. Kaji, you know how
important that ore is to us.
What's wrong
with slapping a cheek or two
if it keeps the ore coming out
and helps the war effort?
What's more important:
The ore or the workers?
I don't think
in those terms.
It's ridiculous
to compare men with ore.
Take care of your men
and the ore will come out.
Let me make it very clear
that Okazaki of Loh Hu Liong
won't be changed
by any of
your half-baked theories.
I'll stick to my own ways.
Remember that.
I will. And I'll stick
to my ways too.
Son of a...
KENPEITAI - MILITARY POLICE
These gentlemen
from the Kenpeitai
are offering us 600 special
laborers to achieve our goals.
Special laborers?
War prisoners from North China.
All you need do is keep them fed.
With the labor shortages,
it's a heaven-sent blessing.
A stroke of good fortune.
Yes! Our head office
will certainly be pleased.
Kaji, discuss the matter
with Okishima.
Discuss what exactly?
I'll tell you what.
I never repeat my instructions.
Got that?
First: Special laborers must not
mingle with ordinary laborers.
Second: Their quarters
must be enclosed by barbed wire...
electrified barbed wire.
Understand?
You'll handle matters
of food and labor,
but they must not escape!
What voltage can you supply
for the fence?
About 3,000 volts.
Good enough.
The laborers will be delivered
one week from today.
The exact time will be
specified later. Understand?
We may not be ready
in a week.
What?
You don't seem terribly grateful.
Kaji!
Why should civilians
take over POWs -
Make preparations immediately!
Wait!
I haven't heard your answer.
We understand.
We'll be ready.
It could take an armed platoon
to return safely with these men.
I want to be neither aggressive
nor defensive with them.
You go on if you want.
Don't waste
your heroism on me.
Someday you'll appreciate me.
Chen, how's your mother?
She says she's sick.
She lies in bed all day.
Sick, huh?
Take good care of her.
Mr. Kaji, I have a request.
May I have some flour
from the storeroom?
For your mother?
I wish I could help,
but I can't make any exceptions.
Here they come.
Chen, how do you feel
about all this?
These are your fellow countrymen
who lived in anti-Japanese areas.
Your mother's from Shantung.
Her friends might be among them.
My mother raised me
not to be anti-Japanese.
In a battle zone,
you'd be killed as a sympathizer.
The key!
We don't have it yet.
- You in charge from Loh Hu Liong?
- Yes.
- Your name?
- Kaji.
Oh, right.
I never forget a name.
Very well. I hereby transfer
the special laborers to you.
Never forget that these men
are prisoners of war.
You must deal with them
like a soldier.
Civilian negligence will not be
tolerated. You understand?
I do.
No, you don't!
You think your seven men
can handle 600 prisoners?
What if they try to escape?
We received no special instructions
about the transfer,
so we anticipated
no special danger.
You're a bold one.
How old are you?
I'm 28.
You married?
May I please have the key?
You don't back down.
I like that.
Will you witness the transfer?
Don't be ridiculous.
I'm now on leave.
You seem to believe
that the army can make mistakes.
Don't worry.
When the army says 604, it's 604.
Submit a transfer receipt
immediately.
Let those who die, die,
but they must not escape!
Filthy bastard!
Get up!
What a mess to unload on us!
Open the other cars!
Out! Everyone out!
Hurry up! Everyone out!
Everyone out!
Line up! Double file!
Mr. Kaji!
This is bad.
What is it?
Hurry!
Line up quickly!
They baked to death.
Help!
Don't let them eat
all of a sudden!
Stop them!
If you gorge yourselves now,
you'll die!
Kaji!
Get back!
Don't eat that!
You'll all die!
Throw me the whip!
Kaji, the whip!
The special laborers
are unfit for work.
Please give them a month's rest.
They're half dead.
These anti-Japanese elements
should be fed without working?
If you'd witnessed the scene,
I'm sure you'd agree, sir.
Twelve of them were allowed
to bake to death.
If you want to kill them, stuff them
with raw beans - they'll die for sure!
Listen here.
Be careful what you say.
What you're saying amounts
to denouncing the military.
I'll defer to your opinion
one last time.
- One last time?
- That's right.
One last time.
May I ask why?
You really want to know?
You're a man
of strong convictions,
but I just got a report
from Furuya.
150 men under your supervision
were just snatched away.
But I'll overlook
the matter this once.
Everyone up!
I give you all warning.
I know you all want to escape.
But you cannot.
If you even try...
you'll meet the same fate
as this dog.
Chen, show them.
Tomorrow begins a month
of still higher production goals.
The directors have even discussed
replacing all the top men here.
I'll accept this disgrace
if we cannot increase production.
However, we have not yet
done our utmost.
Until we attain the 20% increase
demanded of us,
I will extend the higher
production goal every month.
If there are dissenting
opinions, air them now.
In the name of final victory,
I refuse to listen
to any excuses hereafter.
Mr. Koike,
tell him we'll see it through.
I, Okazaki, vow that Pit No. 1
will achieve the new goal.
I'm sure you'll permit me
to use any means necessary.
Use all means available.
Increased production
is the main thing.
Listen here:
Lash them on
with all you've got.
If any Chinaman balks,
kill the scum!
Push them! Whip them!
We need that extra 20%.
Those of you who top your quota
will be amply rewarded.
Remember: We're at war here.
If anyone feels he can't do this,
let him step forward!
Good. I have your word.
I'll assume all responsibility.
Don't worry... and do your best!
You will start work tomorrow.
Your rations will be
sorghum wine and soy pulp,
same as the regular laborers.
You don't smoke?
I used to.
You stopped?
When we run out of tobacco,
we suffer again.
The Japanese
won't keep us supplied.
We restored your health,
yet you still hate us?
We are not soldiers.
We have the right
to be released.
I don't have the authority
to release you,
only to detain you.
Master, when we be free?
We all not soldier.
We don't fight.
Japan soldiers come...
do bad things to Chinese women.
Take away all men... bring here.
Nothing to eat... many die.
Not die... killed.
I can't set you free,
but I can promise
that you will not be killed.
The Japanese
say pretty words...
and write pretty words...
but never keep their promises!
Your name was Kao?
Remember this:
You've been placed
under our supervision.
Whether that barbed wire
stays up or not depends on you.
Faster!
Move it!
Step along there!
Come on!
Move!
You'll be in trouble
if any men escape, won't you?
Why should they escape?
They used to work
in their own villages.
Why would they want
to work here?
Here they have no mother,
no wife, no children.
Kaji, why are so many
special laborers left in camp?
They're the sick ones.
Make sure
they're not just malingerers.
I didn't come to find fault.
I'd like to see their camp.
Certainly.
No danger of escape?
I don't think so.
We must give them
some incentive to work.
I think so too.
What does a man in a cage
dream of most?
Freedom, I suppose.
Freedom?
You must be a poet!
It's women.
Men dream of women.
Women dream of men.
What did you dream of
as a bachelor?
The ways of the empire?
I doubt it.
The way to make
caged men work
is to satisfy
70% of their bodily lust.
With what women?
It's very simple.
You're in charge of the comfort women.
Send them in here.
Is that necessary?
Do you want a woman?
See that?
Just the word brings
joy to their hearts.
What is a man?
Not poetry or morality.
He's a mass of lust and greed
that absorbs and excretes.
I'll ask their leaders' opinion.
Who gives you orders?
POWs or me?
I'm more concerned
about escapes than you are.
Carry out my orders.
Stop loafing!
Hurry up!
Son of a bitch!
Get up!
You dog!
Master!
This man sick!
He maybe die.
Have mercy... he sick man!
Save your whining for Kaji.
I don't care if I kill
a few of you dogs.
Here he comes!
Ah, Kaji-san!
No want to see?
Sister Jin!
Mr. Kaji... welcome!
Mr. Kaji, wanna have some fun?
I won't charge you.
I'm sorry...
but I need 30 girls
for the special laborers.
The Labor Office will pay.
They go inside barbed wire?
Just like dogs... sleep together...
everybody watch?
If you don't wish to,
just say so.
You don't, do you?
We no have choice.
It's our job.
I send 30 girls tomorrow.
Don't be crazy!
We can't work
with everyone watching.
Know how many men
are in that compound?
If you don't wish to go.
Then don't.
Even if the others go,
I refuse.
Think you can get out
of working?
What do you mean?
I was speaking for all of you.
You talk real big.
If you want to go, then go.
Don't act so big!
What about you?
Stop arguing.
You don't make the decisions here.
I'll decide what to do.
Thirty girls will go tonight.
All right?
Yes, please do that.
- What happened?
- The foreman let him have it.
- Where?
- Pit No. 3.
Okazaki!
Get him to first aid quickly.
If this is ignored,
supervision will be impossible!
I'll charge Okazaki
with manslaughter.
Come now! Relax!
It wasn't wise to use force,
but he was only following orders
to increase production.
So he actually acted
out of patriotism.
Listen here.
Okazaki may be a brute,
but his brutality
lets him run that large pit.
We need him just like
we need you and Okishima
to keep our 10,000 men in line.
Understand?
We're at war.
To achieve the greater goal,
we must overlook the small mistakes.
Small mistakes?
A human being was murdered!
Kaji, I'll tell you just once more:
Calm down!
Think it over.
I'm sure you'll see.
Can we exchange a good,
hard-working Japanese man
for the life
of one mere prisoner?
That's not the point.
If you insist on pressing charges,
include me as an accomplice.
I'll see that the suit
goes unfavorably for you.
I can do it, you know.
You'd dare distort the truth?
Sir, will you see
that this never happens again?
How should we report it?
As an accidental death.
Say he fell off a ledge.
It does happen, you know.
Sir!
You think I'll falsify the report?
What else can we do?
- Well, I won't!
- Yes, you will!
Then I become
Okazaki's accomplice.
What will you do?
I'll get Okazaki!
You fool!
Why play the hero?
Fight so hard
and you'll just run out of steam.
You're a fool to ruin
your future with his.
Mr. Kaji.
One of our men was mistreated.
What became of him?
He died.
I assume the culprit
was arrested.
- He's still working.
- Will there be no trial?
I suppose not.
If that's why you're here,
come inside and explain to all of us.
No, I came to wait
for some women.
You promised not to kill!
You're like all the other Japanese!
If you treat me like a murderer
just because I'm Japanese,
you'll be losing
the only friend you have.
Friend?
You don't have to believe me!
Wait.
Does this man's death
mean others may also die?
I won't allow it.
Women!
Open the gate.
Let the women in.
Ten girls to a barrack.
Have them out by 10:00.
Look! Women!
I'm coming!
Women!
We're here,
just like I promised.
Why do you send us women?
Think as you please.
I'm just obeying orders.
You send whores
to sleep with us like dogs
so we'll work harder?
Is that it?
What's that about whores?
I wouldn't talk so big!
You wouldn't understand!
Oh, I understand.
You're no better off than us.
Look at your friends
over there.
Have you no shame?
You think I like coming here?
I told him I refused!
Aren't you the same, beaten down
by the Japanese every day?
Then why so cocky?
You love it here so much?
I'm sorry.
We all suffer
the same misfortune.
Welcome home!
You must be tired.
Look at this!
Isn't it wonderful?
Her first egg!
She cackled so loud
I thought a dog had gotten inside.
But right there
was this great big egg!
What is it?
Are you in a bad mood?
No, it's nothing.
It's like you hate
coming home.
Is something wrong?
Why won't you
tell me about it?
Would you want a husband
who runs a whorehouse?
What does that mean?
You'd vomit if I told you!
What happens to 30 women
in a camp of 600 men?
And now I'm
an accomplice to murder too.
That can't be.
The workers
don't believe a word I say.
With time
you'll gain their trust.
Could you just be quiet
for a while?
It's a shame.
What is?
Since those prisoners came,
you seem so far away.
I guess I do.
I hate feeling
like I'm fighting a Ione battle.
You leave early
every morning
and return late at night.
During that time, you work.
Meanwhile,
I clean the house,
putter around the kitchen,
and do the shopping...
but it's like doing nothing.
Still I try to convince myself
that the little things I do
help keep you going.
Otherwise, there's no difference
between a housewife and a housekeeper.
I'm sorry. Forgive me.
I'll letting my work
get the best of me.
Let's stop worrying about it...
just for now.
It was nice talking to you.
Locked up in here,
we lose touch
with the outside world.
Thank you.
Don't you want to have a good time?
I came here for business.
I'm sorry to take your time.
I just wanted to talk.
You plan to escape,
don't you?
It's impossible
with all that barbed wire.
It's charged with electricity,
that's all.
It's men who run
the electricity through it.
Don't talk like that.
Human beings are weak creatures.
Go where you're told to go.
Do what you're told to do.
That's the only way to survive.
You're wrong.
Man can become
as strong as he wishes.
He need only find
the cause of his unhappiness.
Want to make
some easy money?
You mean selling
my girls elsewhere?
I don't go
for that kind of deal.
This isn't about women.
Laborers?
I have something else
in mind this time.
You mean
behind the barbed wire?
Too dangerous.
If anything goes wrong,
it's my neck.
It's not like the others.
Escaped prisoners mean big profit.
Help make arrangements
and I'll split it with you.
It's easy money.
What kind of arrangements?
The easiest way... is like this.
You just flick off
the electric switch.
Did someone
put you up to this?
My buddy Muta, the Japanese
assistant who was just fired.
How sad,
selling men like that.
Don't expect
any sympathy from me.
I'm just a Korean. The Japanese
and Chinese both look down on me.
Hurry it up!
Mr. Wang!
I just heard the Japanese say
that the Italians have surrendered.
Defeat for Germany
can't be far off.
Our time is coming.
When?
Six months, maybe a year.
We must be patient.
What's going on there?
You scum!
Thank you.
This'll really invigorate my man
and the young folk.
If Okazaki gets
any more invigorated, ma'am,
you'll be in trouble.
Didn't you know?
We women prefer
our men that way.
Ma'am, I'm sure
you've seen to everything,
but it might be wise to send
some of that flour to Kaji's wife.
A very good idea!
I'll do just that.
Your food.
Good day, sir.
Ah, it's you.
You want dumplings?
Can you loan me
a bag of white flour?
I'd like to make my mother happy.
She hasn't long to live.
One bag?
Why don't you go
get some yourself?
The Japanese steal the flour
they ration to us...
and eat their fill.
I can't do that.
But Mr. Kaji trusts you.
This flour was stolen
from the warehouse
by the warehouse guard
with the big mole.
It's stolen property.
You still want
to buy some of it?
Let him have half a bag.
No, I won't.
Young man, don't forget
you were born of a Chinese mother,
of Chinese seed.
Go ask the man
with the big mole!
Try not to be so obvious.
About what?
Okazaki's wife just left here
with a big sack.
I hate to interfere,
but you're making a mistake.
People around here
appreciate my mistakes.
It's an old custom.
Well, it's one
that should be abolished.
Unpleasant as it may seem,
that's my job.
If it happens again,
I'll have to order an inventory.
Mr. Kaji...
the men in the pits
wonder if you're one of us
or just a puppet
of the Chinese.
And?
That's all.
But I do think your acute sense
of justice is inflamed by the fact
that you can't take
some extra flour to your own wife.
Take your filthy feet
off your desk when speaking to me!
Or do you need my help?
You fool!
They'll see your light!
Go easy tonight.
Hurry!
It's the night watchman!
What's taking so long?
Get going!
I like you a lot.
You did very well
for your first time.
You'll do it for me,
won't you, Chen?
Talk to Sai
at the power station.
Just have him shut off
the current for three minutes.
I'll see that
you're well-rewarded.
Then you can buy
all the flour you want
without playing the thief.
Still can't make up your mind?
Hey, Big Mole!
Well, Chen, how'd it go?
Did you get a good price?
Or did you eat it yourself?
Free white flour
must taste good.
What's going on, Matsuda?
What indeed.
Seems even saints
have thieves for underlings.
Flour thieves.
Mr. Kaji...
I'm willing
to overlook it this time.
But just for future reference,
I'd like to see how you handle this.
Chen, stand up.
Look at me.
You didn't do it, did you?
I did.
Alone?
Matsuda,
I hope you're satisfied now.
Now get out before I expose
all your dirty doings!
Chen, what's the matter?
I stole something...
and Mr. Kaji struck me.
Kaji struck you?
But no matter.
Mr. Kaji is Japanese,
and I'm Chinese.
It's that simple!
Sister Jin is busy now.
I think he's Korean.
Korean?
Hi, cutie.
Get in a fight?
Yang, let me use
your room awhile.
What's wrong?
I don't understand it myself.
Foolish girl,
acting like an amateur
in love for the first time.
I can't seem to forget Kao.
Love at first sight...
with a man behind barbed wire.
Why not use your room?
It's such a mess.
Why do you ask?
The Japanese are all the same.
They don't consider us human beings.
Chen...
go to the power station
and work it out
with your friend.
I'm not Korean.
I won't betray my friend
for money.
I know that.
You're a good man.
But those men in there
are prisoners.
The Japanese will exploit them
and then kill them.
Can they really be saved?
Of course.
But the only one
who can do it...
is you.
This can wait, Chen.
First go do as I ask.
I understand.
I'm Chinese too.
I'm ready to do my part.
At exactly 1:00 a.m.
When the siren sounds,
I'll cut the current.
But only for two minutes.
That's the best I can do.
Two minutes?
Watch out!
That's 3,300 volts!
Be careful.
Don't let them see you.
Sai!
Go now,
and don't let them see you.
My regards to our brothers
behind barbed wire.
They're in love.
This isn't business.
In that case, we don't pay.
Stop kidding around.
A prisoner and a prostitute in love -
it's like a novel.
But what will come of it?
Nothing can come of it
while there's a war going on.
They have their love today.
That's all.
Can't you let them marry?
I would if I could.
I'm sure you'd want
to help them.
I do, but it ends right there.
Have some.
They're delicious.
What are they?
A rare treat.
They were given to us.
By whom?
Try and guess.
Mrs. Okazaki.
Send them back!
But...
I can't send them back now.
Return them!
Tell her I was furious.
But why?
Why?
Why do you glare at me
like that?
She wanted to make up
for earlier.
The murderer stole that flour!
It's time you showed more sense.
Can't you understand
my position
and what I'm trying
to do at this mine?
No, I can't.
How could I,
when you never tell me anything?
Of course, even I can guess
where the flour and sugar came from.
But women can't always live
by unbending rules.
I didn't accept them
for myself.
So you accepted them for me?
I don't need
that kind of thoughtfulness.
Because it was the Okazakis?
What if it had been
Mrs. Okishima?
I'd still refuse.
Yes, you're just
the kind who would!
You struck Chen, didn't you?
I know you didn't want to,
yet you did.
Why?
Because he did
something wrong?
That's not why.
You could have forgiven him
for such a minor matter.
It was because you lost face
in front of others.
For a man who aspires to great things,
you have a small mind!
You wouldn't understand.
But I do!
I know what people think of you.
It's reached my ears too.
What do they think?
That you try to look better
than everyone else.
I didn't believe them.
I thought it was just spite,
but now -
- Think what you want!
- Where are you going?
I've kept 30 women waiting.
Marriage?
Impossible!
We can marry
after the war is over.
Is the war going to end?
It won't be much longer.
But they'll take you
away again.
No, Chun Lan.
It will end in victory for China.
We'll be free.
I...
I can only hope
that things stay as they are.
Why, Chun Lan?
When that day comes,
I'll never see you again.
But I'm asking you
to marry me.
There are plans
to escape from here,
but I will not run away
as long as you're here.
You won't run away?
You promise?
I'm sorry.
I went too far.
You brute!
I'm thinking of letting
those two get married.
Hello.
What? Escaped?
I'll be right there!
- How many?
Eleven men!
I won't bother
asking for information.
We'll soon know
who planned the break.
I won't ask for details.
But you must understand
one thing.
We've tried our best
to help you.
If you cannot trust us,
and if you continue
to try to escape,
those who remain behind
will face reprisals
and even more hard labor.
And I will not raise a finger
to protect you.
You think we can't bring you
before a firing squad.
But if Kaji and I decide to,
we can always pack you
into those freight cars
and send you back
to the army!
They acted on their own.
We only serve as liaisons
for the prisoners.
We couldn't stop them
even if we knew of their plot.
I see through your lies!
What if I said that
Wang Heng Li plotted this break?
It no lie... we don't know.
I no run away.
You fools!
You think we'd take
your word for it?
Why don't you all
run off somewhere!
I will not run.
I'll walk out of here
with dignity.
And just where will you go?
Don't think all Japanese
are as forgiving as me.
If you want to die,
just try to escape.
Wang, the safety of your men
depends on all of you.
I'm the one who has
to answer to the Kenpeitai -
not you!
Investigate the situation
and take adequate measures.
Oh, and think up a good story
for the Kenpeitai.
Where's Kaji?
You stood by
while those men escaped?
We didn't stand by.
So you took
all precautionary measures?
Let me remind you once more:
Those prisoners are spoils of war,
obtained at great sacrifice.
You allowed them to damage
the prestige of our Imperial Forces.
I demand an explanation.
- I have none.
The only explanation
is their desire to escape.
Why did you stand by and let them?
Answer me!
I can hear you.
You don't have to shout.
We have
10,000 other laborers here,
but these special prisoners
have taken all our attention.
No matter what, they'll manage to escape.
What are we supposed to do?
One question!
Go ahead.
We reported the truth.
I could have reported them dead
and avoided trouble.
Does the Kenpeitai
not want the truth?
I acknowledge your honesty.
But shortage of personnel
is not an acceptable excuse.
Though your negligence
is inexcusable,
I shall overlook it
just this once.
No more men must escape.
Tell them that if they do,
I will personally kill their leader.
Understand?
I understand.
How about it?
Want me to scare them a little?
That won't be necessary.
You must be quite sure of yourself
to refuse aid from the military.
Very well.
I'll hold you personally
responsible from now on.
I never go back on my word.
- I understand.
And you?
Do you understand?
I understand.
That will be all.
No! Wait!
Wait!
Let me go!
- Don't take it out on the men.
- What about you?
You lost your temper and struck Chen,
and now you lecture me?
Don't pull your humanism on me.
I struck Chen, and I regret it.
But should you do the same?
Don't let your feelings
ruin my work.
Your work?
Yes, my work.
You've kept in step so far,
but now you're going your own way.
Can't you see?
Force has meaning
only when overcoming tyranny.
I know that.
I've had enough of your lectures.
You intend to let them
do as they wish?
I'll talk to them.
I won't mince words.
I don't want
your men trying to escape.
As far as you men
are concerned,
I am your friendliest enemy.
I pride myself on supervising you
without hostility.
Despite the conflicts
of interest
that result
from our being at war,
I've tried
to protect your interests.
What you say is difficult.
I see.
Eat your fill.
We can talk at our leisure.
When one of your comrades
was killed,
we didn't take adequate
measures to protect you.
Therefore
you no longer trust us.
That's only natural.
However...
I shall do my utmost
to correct this mistake.
It may take time...
but I hope you'll trust me
and be patient.
No one wants to risk
the danger of escaping.
Let me speak
for my friend Kaji.
Since he arrived here,
the regular laborers' conditions
have greatly improved.
This also applies to you.
However, if there's
another escape,
I cannot say
what the Kenpeitai might do.
I don't know how Kaji feels,
but the only way
to save my own neck
is to send you back
to the Kenpeitai.
It's true what he says.
We can reach
an understanding by talking.
How about you, Kao?
If you can marry
Yang Chun Lan,
will you stay
until the war ends?
I don't like propositions
that start...
with the word "if."
Can't you understand?
We're talking things over.
Bootlicker!
It's the same old
Japanese trick.
They always promise
to do this and do that...
but they never
keep their word.
Stand up!
You dog! You wouldn't
understand what men say.
Go to Yang Chun Lan
and learn the ways of human beings!
By the way, Wang, if I -
There's the "if" again.
If I gain the freedom for you
enjoyed by the regular laborers,
will you trust me?
To wait seems to be
the only safe liberty.
You promise?
Wang, you must trust me.
I wonder if they trust me.
You want to believe they do,
don't you?
I want to believe Wang
when he says he'll wait.
You plan to continue sending
the women inside. Why?
Just a hunch.
I also plan to take 50 of them
for outside labor.
- Under armed guard?
- No, just by myself.
These strange hunches
aren't like you.
Why not be honest?
- About what?
You'd let them escape
if you could.
That's nonsense.
When that happens,
I stand to lose my neck.
Remember that.
On days they come out here,
they seem happy.
Is your mother still ill?
I suppose she still longs
for some white flour.
She's given up hope.
I'm sorry I struck you
that day.
I'm hardheaded
in some ways, I know.
It's all right.
Is Sai at the power station
a friend of yours?
Somebody shut off
the current.
Sai was on duty that night.
If he did it,
tell him not to do it again.
Well, back to work.
They could escape
whenever they want.
Maybe they're starting
to trust you.
No, they're just wary
of a trap.
Then you'll stop
taking them out?
No, I'll keep doing it.
Isn't it dangerous?
They might kill you and escape.
I doubt that.
This bath feels good.
Why don't you come in?
I think I will.
If the workers settle down,
let's go into town on vacation.
Let's do it!
How many days
can you take off?
Three at the most.
That would be wonderful!
Well, if they really
settle down...
Someday you'll be
a great supervisor,
but by then our youth
will have vanished.
That's not for me.
I'll take that vacation.
You're probably right.
Please do, all right?
I will.
See to it, Cho.
We need a break in that barbed wire.
Kaji will be off
on a three-day leave.
Okishima will be busy.
We'll do it then.
Releasing prisoners is more profitable,
but more dangerous too.
With things going smoothly,
Kaji has let down his guard...
but watch out for Okishima.
The timing is ideal.
Let's pull another fast one
and then make ourselves scarce.
That's right. Getting away clean
is the important thing.
Is Jin Tung Fu in?
She's in bed
with the cute boy.
How about you?
There's a problem.
Chen won't help anymore.
Won't help?
Once is as bad
as 100 times.
He doesn't want that risk
with you and me.
But he'll risk
sleeping with you.
He wants me
to break away too.
Has that dog squealed on us?
- He'd never do that.
- You never know.
Don't let him spend the night.
Send him home.
Jin Tung Fu is some woman, eh?
How was it?
I hear Kaji will be away
starting Saturday.
Have the power cut off
while he's gone.
Sai isn't on duty those nights.
Then when is he?
Friday night.
Then make it Friday night.
He can't!
They already suspect him!
Who does?
Mr. Kaji.
What can he do
without evidence?
Listen carefully, punk.
Play it straight and I'll fix it
so Jin Tung Fu will be yours alone.
You little scum!
You'll do it, won't you?
Be a good boy.
If you refuse,
you and Sai will die.
END OF PART 1
GRANDSCOPE
A SHOCHIKU FILM
THE HUMAN CONDITION
Developed by BUNGEl PRODUCTION
and NINJIN CLUB
Presented by
KABUKI PRODUCTION
Produced by
SHIGERU WAKATSUKI
Based on the Novel by
JUNPEl GOMIKAWA
Screenplay by ZENZO MATSUYAMA
and MASAKI KOBAYASHI
Director of Photography
YOSHIO MIYAJIMA
Production Design KAZUE HIRATAKA
Sound Recording HIDEO NISHIZAKI
Music CHUJI KINOSHITA
Lighting TAKASHI KATO
Editing KEIICHI URAOKA
1st Ass't Director YUGORO IMAI
Ass't. Director KOICHI INAGAKI
Ass't Camera TOSHITADA NAGUMO
Ass't Production Design JUSHO TODA
Set Decoration KYOJI SASAKI
Set Design
YOJI MURO
Production Manager
TATSUO OSAWA
Starring
TATSUYA NAKADAI
as Kaji
MICHIYO ARATAMA
as Michiko
CHIKAGE AWASHIMA as Jin Tung Fu
INEKO ARIMA as Yang Chun Lan
SO YAMAMURA as Okishima
AKIRA ISHIHAMA as Chen
SHINJI NANBARA as Kao
SEIJI MIYAGUCHI as Wang Heng Li
TORU ABE as Sergeant Watai
MASAO MISHIMA as Kuroki
EITARO OZAWA as Okazaki
KOJI MITSUI as Furuya
AKITAKE KONO as Captain Kono
NOBUO NAKAMURA as Head Office Chief
KYU SAZANKA as Cho Meisan
Directed by
MASAKI KOBAYASHI
PART 2
I feel wonderful!
We arrived in a whirl of dust,
but it's so nice today.
Worried about work?
- No.
Just wondering
why I didn't do this before.
- Really?
- I mean it.
I'll phone Yasuko first thing
and tell her to take the day off.
Would you mind?
And then what?
We'll have lunch together
and then go to the apple orchard.
It's so wonderful!
I feel as light as a balloon!
Allow me just one thing.
What?
Let me go
for just one hour?
What for?
With our increased production,
I'd like to talk to the main office
about treating the special laborers
like the ordinary laborers.
Just one hour?
- The rest of my time is all yours.
- All right.
I'll give you two hours,
but not a minute more.
Mr. Kaji!
- They broke out again.
- What?
Where's Okishima?
- At their camp.
All right.
I'll be right there.
I don't want you to go.
I have no choice.
You go have
a good time with Yasuko.
Yasuko isn't you.
- But this is my job...
- I don't care!
You're officially on vacation.
They can't make you go back.
Leave it to Okishima.
I'll wait till after lunch, okay?
I'll never finish by then.
You just don't want to go.
Don't be foolish!
Your work's important,
but don't you see
how important this is for us?
I'll make up for it next time.
You needn't bother!
Why so angry
over such a small thing?
Such a small thing?
You don't seem
to care how I feel.
At any rate,
I can't just leave now.
I see.
Then I'll go on alone.
Stop it!
From now on,
I do things my way!
- And ruin everything?
- They'll understand my fist!
Hitting them
won't bring back the others!
Do you realize
how many got away?
Eighteen men,
led by Hwang and Sung!
Still think words will help?
- I'll assume all responsibility.
- You fool!
If you don't like my methods,
you can quit.
You won't be dragged
before the Kenpeitai.
Fine!
Wang!
Stand up!
I've given up on all of you.
You said you'd wait.
You might think I'm a fool,
but even a fool has limits!
Another escape and you'll all
go without food for three days.
I'll turn your men against you
and break your authority in this camp!
You Japanese
are all the same!
Fine!
Then I'll act accordingly.
All promises are hereby retracted.
Now I realize there can be
no trust between us.
Mr. Okishima!
How will you report
this to the Kenpeitai?
They won't let us off
easy this time.
- I won't report the incident.
- What?
If it leaks out,
I'll assume all responsibility.
I don't think
it was all your responsibility.
You think someone
shut off the power?
I couldn't say.
Shall I put only Japanese
on night duty there?
You can't do that
without evidence.
Shall I increase the night watch
around the fence?
I'd have to check
that they're at their posts.
Eighteen men...
that's a big loss!
I've achieved
the 20% increase in production.
I don't want trouble now
over something like this.
I forgot: Okishima
is hereby relieved
of all responsibility
for the special prisoners.
I don't know!
Damned Chinaman!
Son of a bitch!
Tell me!
Who paid you?
Okishima favors drastic measures,
but Kaji always stops him.
Meaning he gives
tacit consent to the runaways?
I wouldn't say that,
but it does all seem
rather suspicious.
There is one way
to teach them a lesson.
How?
We let them plan another break
and then foil them.
With your permission,
I'd like to try.
Sounds intriguing.
I'll try anything
that brings results.
Give it a try.
Boss's orders.
We're distributing flour and oil.
Only to the Japanese, of course.
I'm sure you don't approve.
I do not.
Unfortunately,
you're not the manager.
I'm sure you're happy I'm not.
Mr. Kaji, it's Mr. Okishima!
Filthy scum!
Son of a bitch!
Kill the rat!
Let him have it!
Mr. Okishima,
let us handle that Korean dog!
Stay out of this!
Filthy dog!
Swipe men from
under my nose, eh?
Bastard!
Not stopping me today?
You want me to?
Don't look so disapproving.
Should I go easy
on the regular workers too?
Your clumsy humanism kills good men
and lets scoundrels run wild.
Chen, take him
to the medical ward.
Do no such thing!
His boss will pick him up.
Take him!
Go call Furuya.
Don't worry, young one.
I won't talk.
Chen, it seems I know more about you
than you do about me.
Go back and tell Kaji
his wounds aren't serious.
It's better if Kaji doesn't
come around here.
Well? How is he?
He seems all right.
Mr. Furuya is with him.
Furuya?
Furuya, send
a telegram to Muta.
That rat Okishima!
He says he's going
to sue Okishima.
Help him arrange it.
You two seem friendly enough.
Don't bother explaining!
Think I'm that stupid?
Was it the money?
Or just to make trouble for me?
Don't worry.
I won't tell the boss.
See that your buddy
is hospitalized.
But you're paying for him...
not Labor!
You probably made plenty.
Where you been hidin'
What's wrong with you?
Drunk, I see.
Think I got drunk
and came to make trouble?
I had a drink with the boss,
but I'm not drunk.
I have some hot news.
They're issuing commendations
for the increased production.
Okazaki will surely
be included.
I told the boss
you were the only one in Labor
who deserved a commendation.
The boss felt the same way,
but he feared that this old-timer
might feel slighted.
You don't think
I'd feel slighted, do you?
Why have you suddenly
turned to brute force?
The boss asked the same thing.
I was born a brute...
good enough?
How long do you plan
to keep on like this?
Meaning what?
Straddling a fundamental contradiction
and trying to justify it.
I'm out of breath.
If I'm being a nuisance,
just say so and I'll back off.
Kao!
Chun Lan!
I was afraid
you might have escaped.
That's all I could buy today.
Thank you.
Thank you!
We can't meet
for the time being.
We can't come here.
If you run off by yourself...
I'll kill myself.
I'll take you with me
when I escape.
When?
After I learn
how the others have fared.
I can't take any chances
if I take you along.
Stay here.
They might let us marry.
Don't believe them!
Wang says
the war will end soon.
Japan will be defeated.
Now that I have you...
I'm willing to bear anything.
Kao!
I wish we could meet
like this every night.
But if they start suspecting us...
then it's all over.
This cursed wire!
Careful!
Why do the gods
torment us like this?
Chun Lan...
I love you!
And I love you!
Can't you sleep?
Kaji would have been happier
married to a girl like you.
You're too much
the wife, Michi.
You're forgetting
to be a woman.
What do you mean?
Being a wife
is a kind of profession,
but it's the woman
that men love.
When you typed Kaji's reports,
you studied them like one possessed.
I never understood a word.
And now? Do you ask him
about his work?
He doesn't like me
asking questions.
If I were you, I'd pester him
until he told me everything.
Then I'd ask
even more questions.
What's wrong?
Did I go too far?
I'm sorry about yesterday.
I failed as a wife
and as a woman.
I couldn't sleep.
This is your home.
You can sleep soundly here.
Promise you'll share
both your joys and sorrows with me.
Sorrow for one is enough.
It's not!
I'm walking down
the same path you are.
It's okay if I lose my way.
Just tell me we might get lost
and take me along.
I'll follow you...
and do my best to keep up.
I understand.
If I don't walk fast enough,
will you wait
just a tiny bit for me?
Just a very tiny bit?
Of course.
I'll never ask you
the same question twice.
"Through fitting leadership
in the pit,
you have helped achieve
a 20% increase in ore production.
At this hour
of dire national emergency,
you've rendered a valuable service
to our armed forces
and set a fitting example
for other employees.
You are hereby
officially commended.
September 23, 1943.
Chairman of the board
Jushiro Kitada.
Read in proxy
by Junichi Kuroki."
Looks like we'll have rain.
Rainy nights are ideal
for escape attempts.
When you deliver their dinner,
tell them arrangements have been made.
They can break out tonight.
Tonight?
Then go to the power station
and tell them Kaji says
to cut the power.
But Mr. Kaji would never...
I'm acting under direct orders
from the boss.
You want me to tell
the Kenpeitai about you?
About how you and Jin Tung Fu
aided the plotters,
and how Kaji knew
but pretended not to see?
It's the only way
to save your neck.
As ships at sea
part the great white waves
So do I part
my loved one's thighs
Mr. Kaji, I look forward
to your continued favor.
You're young,
but you're quite a fellow!
No, a great fellow!
The day you arrived
it was snowing...
No, it was windy.
Really? Windy?
That day I thought
a young squirt like you
could never handle this mine.
But things really did
work out as you said.
You're really something!
But Mr. Kaji...
I've been watching.
You haven't been drinking.
Give me a hand?
If you want to try,
tonight is your last chance.
Why the sudden rush?
If the timing's no good,
just forget it.
But my friend's being moved
to the day shift tomorrow.
You sure about this?
On behalf
of the men in the pit
and in the spirit of friendship,
I challenge Mr. Kaji
to a friendly drinking bout.
Hear! Hear!
I concede defeat.
No, you can't!
We haven't even started yet!
No, I really do.
Mr. Kaji...
do you only show spirit
when you're snarling at me?
Come on. Be a man!
All right! I'm ready!
Use this.
Get drunk and let down
your guard for once.
That's right!
Okay, let's begin.
Show 'em, Mr. Kaji!
- That's the way!
- More!
Those boys in Labor are used
to being wined and dined by the bosses.
They get the women too!
They run the whorehouse
and have their pick.
So we're wined and dined, eh?
And the whores are ours
for the taking?
Fine! Bring on your wine and women!
I'll take 'em on!
Chen.
All done delivering their meals?
This is a special ration ticket
for Japanese only.
You're welcome to mine.
- But your wife...
- She's given up hope.
Mr. Kaji.
No, nothing.
I just wanted to say thank you.
It's me who should thank you.
I was afraid
you wouldn't accept it now.
There's a nice ass!
Hey, lady-killer!
Tops in Japan!
Back off!
Still in heat at your age?
What if I am?
Go sow your seed
in your own rice paddies!
I wouldn't act so big,
Okishima.
If you and Kaji
would mind your own business,
I could have topped
our production goal long ago.
And you'd have 10 murders
on your record now.
You'd be having dinner in jail!
Bastard!
If you want trouble, come on.
Chen, what's the matter?
What should I do?
I won't be able
to see you again.
I've fallen into a trap!
Go to the station
and have him cut off the power.
If I do that...
and the men are captured...
they'll kill me!
This is a Japanese plot.
No matter what happens,
you won't be killed.
You speak as if
this didn't concern you.
If I'm caught,
I might confess everything.
Don't threaten me.
You dragged me into this!
- Where are you going?
- To warn them.
You'll never get word to them.
I can try.
Wait! I have a better idea.
Chun Lan.
Kao is breaking out tonight.
Kao is breaking out?
Go tell him
it's too dangerous.
I won't let him escape alone!
Drink. It'll relax you.
I couldn't contact him.
Are you sure he plans to escape?
You met no one?
With this downpour,
I couldn't see a thing.
Not a soul?
Is he really breaking out?
What'll we do now?
If he runs off by himself...
I'll kill myself!
The power must be cut off!
We mustn't anger the Japanese.
What should we do?
The best way is to confess
the whole thing to Mr. Kaji.
No! He's the worst
of them all!
Where are you going?
Go to the power station!
You little punk!
I expected as much.
Did you do as I told you?
Yes.
You didn't mention
the matter to Kaji, did you?
No.
We'll find out in a moment...
whether you did as ordered.
If you betrayed us,
it's a bullet in your head.
We'll report that we caught you
helping the men escape.
It'll even mean a reward.
They're coming!
Mr. Furuya.
The power... I didn't...
What?
Son of a bitch!
Bastard! You want to die?
I never dreamt that Chen
might plot something like this.
I've been blind.
Furuya!
Blind because I never thought you
capable of such a diabolical plot!
Go brag to the boss
of your brave deed!
Wang!
You're not always right either.
Your failed leadership
caused this.
You refused to trust us.
The result is charred human flesh.
It serves you right!
Kao!
Why did you do it?
It was so foolish!
Kao!
You're alive!
Chun Lan!
Look at the man whose mistake
killed his own friends!
Okishima came
to tell me about it.
Why didn't Chen come to me?
He was probably afraid to.
Because I hit him?
Okishima told me
you'd take it really hard.
It's not my fault
that I'm Japanese...
yet it's my worst crime
that I am!
Chen was kind to you
even though I struck him.
He understood how I felt.
Yet look what happened.
That son a bitch Furuya!
The boss put him up to this.
They'll never meddle
in Labor affairs again!
Let's go home.
Some nice hot soup
will help you feel better.
Yes, let's.
Let's go home.
I wish you'd ask the main office
about getting the Kenpeitai
to let us treat these prisoners
like ordinary laborers.
But I know I asked you
to stay out of my affairs.
Don't worry. I'll do it.
My trip will cool us both off.
It'll be my present to you.
Seems the boss considers Okazaki
more indispensable than me.
I'm boarding
this run-down truck,
but you're trying to catch the train
of humanism before it's too late.
I won't stop you.
You seem willing to pay the fare,
no matter how high.
Am I making trouble
by coming here?
I already offered
my apologies.
Leave us alone.
From now on, we'll have
to escape from the work areas.
Wang wants us
to lie low for a while.
And there's been
no news from the others.
What's going on here?
Run!
Bastards!
You dare resist?
Get back here!
Come back!
Escape attempt!
How about it?
They're offering us
500 more prisoners.
We lack accommodations.
Accommodations?
Don't you mean supervision?
We just caught seven prisoners
trying to escape!
You caught them?
Good work!
- Did they resist?
- The bastards almost got away.
- From the pit?
- The ore dump.
That's strange.
You were eating Chinese food here.
How would you know?
How could they escape
in broad daylight?
Look at this. Only desperate men
would throw ore at me.
That makes it a break?
I'm not the only witness.
It took 15 men to capture them.
Inside the compound? Running
inside the compound is a break?
- Why do you defend the chinks?
- I'll investigate this.
You needn't bother!
- Where are they?
- The guard house.
Good.
Captain, what are
your instructions?
Well, let's see.
Shall we try the method
you've been suggesting?
He's a master swordsman.
How many men
did you slay in China?
Wait! How can you be sure
it was a break?
Silence! We have a witness.
Any more objections?
Yes! An impassioned witness
can't be trusted.
All those men want to escape.
Would you execute them all?
- Why you...
- Enough!
Whether it was or wasn't
an escape attempt isn't the point.
All that matters
is that we say it was!
Arguments will not be tolerated.
Sergeant!
They're to be executed tomorrow.
You decide how.
They will be executed
tomorrow, sir!
I assume you approve.
You shall officially witness
the execution!
You'll save seven men's lives
if you testify
they weren't trying to escape.
They were trying to escape.
They ran.
They should have stayed
and taken their beating.
What's going to happen to us?
If injuring Okazaki was a crime,
why not just investigate me?
Listen to me.
You're all guilty
of attempted escape.
- Lies!
- You're wronging the innocent!
Quiet!
Dog!
An investigation
will reveal the truth.
Investigate it!
Immediately!
The investigation is over.
But I don't believe
you tried to escape.
You're turning us over
to the Kenpeitai?
I don't intend to.
But you never
had faith in me before.
Perhaps it's best
to doubt me now as well.
Those men have all the power!
I have none!
I'll do everything I can
until tomorrow evening.
Sir, if you ask them,
the Kenpeitai will listen to reason.
This is an object lesson, Kaji.
Personally I don't approve,
but the head office says
to leave it to the Kenpeitai.
Why?
Must there be a reason?
Please wait! You're about
to chop off men's heads!
If the company
protested strongly...
This is wartime.
Peacetime reasoning doesn't apply.
That's no reason!
You may not think so, but I do.
You're wasting your breath.
If you're not satisfied,
speak to the head office.
I will!
There's no answer.
He's in a conference.
Shouting like a madman!
Hello? One moment, please.
Someone else
will take your call.
Okishima?
We're in real trouble.
You've heard?
Hello? Hello?
I can't hear you!
Speak louder!
I can't hear you at all.
What's that?
Give up?
That's ridiculous!
Okishima,
please talk to them again.
Please try again.
I'll be waiting.
I'll be honest. There's only
one chance in a hundred.
This does not
concern us alone.
Just as my companions
stand between life and death,
so do you now stand
at an important crossroads.
You're right.
If you fail now,
no one will ever trust you again,
and you too will lose
faith in yourself.
It's true.
Yet you would do nothing?
What can I do?
Must a man outside this barbed wire
ask me such a question?
Not all the Japanese working here
are murderous devils.
Their combined opinion
objecting to this execution
will be more effective
than one individual alone.
If I'd always acted
as you wanted me to,
there'd be no Kaji here today.
I'd like to see
what you'd do in my position.
You and I will both make
minor mistakes.
Such things can be forgiven.
But an error made at a crucial
moment is an unforgivable crime.
Your life has been
a series of errors
stemming from the conflict
between your work and yourself.
Such errors can possibly
be corrected.
But this one cannot.
Meaning?
You'll either be revealed as a murderer
wearing the mask of humanism
or as one worthy
of the beautiful name..."man."
I know that.
You have less faith in man
than you try to believe.
Regardless of how
you might feel,
true men will always find
kindred spirits!
What will happen to Kao?
I wish I knew myself.
When will you release him?
You won't kill Kao, will you?
You won't, will you?
Hello? Okishima?
What's the decision?
Calm down and listen.
The manager is no help,
the old fool.
Wait until morning.
I'll talk to the chairman.
The chairman?
Yes, the chairman!
I'll make him listen to me.
Please go away.
I want to be alone.
Mr. Kaji!
Please save him!
Save him!
He wouldn't try to escape!
We planned to be married
after the war ended.
You won't kill him, will you?
You're a good man.
Go to sleep
and stop worrying.
I won't do anything.
There's nothing I can do.
Can I really set
my mind at ease?
Really?
Go to sleep
and don't worry.
I'll try to sleep too.
Where are you going?
To free those men.
You can't!
Think what might happen to you!
I don't care!
You did everything you could.
Don't you care
what happens to you?
Well, I do!
Michiko, don't torment me!
I'll call for help!
I won't let you do it.
You always go your own way,
and perhaps you're right.
But if you free those men,
they'll kill you for sure!
Please don't go!
I'll follow you!
I'll shout for help!
Michiko, if I don't,
I'm no longer a human being!
How can you ignore me
like some stray dog?
Even you don't want
to give up this life, do you?
Remember: You promised!
I'm sorry.
Go and do as you see fit.
Perhaps it's me who's wrong.
I can't have you feeling
I stood in your way.
I don't want you hating me,
not loving me anymore.
There's no hope for me!
- All ready!
- Good work.
Spare us!
It's best to wet the blade.
Keeps off the fat.
Kaji!
Stay right there.
Thanks for being my witness.
Get up!
On your knees!
Kaji...
you can tell them all later:
If they want to die,
they can run all they like.
Next!
Spare me!
Want to try?
Next!
I don't want it!
I demand an explanation!
Why are we being executed?
Son of a bitch!
Japanese devils!
Stand up!
I'll go by myself!
Inhuman wretch!
This is your true form!
The face of a man...
but the heart of a beast!
Good! You show some grit.
Stay calm! Slash him!
The Chinese nation...
will live forever!
Don't think of it
as a human head.
Take a rest and try again.
Next!
Spare my life!
Wait!
No more!
What?
Please stop!
Stay out of this
or I'll kill you too!
I'm not afraid any longer.
Kill me if you dare!
I'll be happy to oblige.
Enemy sympathizers
deserve to be killed.
We won't let them kill
our countrymen!
Stop them!
You're killing innocent men!
Murderers! Murderers!
Private!
Very well.
The execution is called off.
Go back and join
the others, quickly!
Take them back!
Kaji!
We're taking you
to headquarters.
Pvt. Tanaka, take special care
of our honored guest.
I'll return later. Go.
Kaji won't be
coming home today.
Did something happen?
He refused to let me
behead those enemy dogs.
He may not be back for a while.
It all depends.
Did he hide anything?
No.
No wonder.
Books by damn Westerners.
Open the desk drawers.
Place everything
on top of the desk.
Son of a bitch!
How about it?
Wouldn't it be smarter
to confess everything?
I only regret that I let you
behead the first three.
You don't say!
You're a hopeless case.
Pvt. Tanaka...
you should show
our guest more courtesy.
Kaji, don't you miss your wife?
She was crying. She'll have
no one to ride her at night.
What have I done?
I'm no monster.
I'd like to put you back
on top of your wife tonight,
but for that I'd need
more cooperation from you.
What's so funny?
I don't pick pockets. I don't steal.
I have nothing to confess.
Very interesting.
Then don't confess
until I make you.
Show off your bravado
while you can.
You let 18 POWs escape
and failed to report it, didn't you?
Is it so funny
you can't even answer?
I didn't report it,
but I never let them escape.
You used that chink Chen
to contact the prisoners.
Show me evidence. Or will you
lose face if you can't prove it?
Son of a bitch!
Did you want something?
No.
I just didn't expect things
to come to this.
Quarrels over work
are one thing.
I didn't intend for others
to do my fighting for me.
So I came to...
I understand.
I never thought
Kaji would do such a thing.
Do what?
Oh... nothing.
I don't know
what other people think,
but I know that whatever Kaji did,
he alone could do.
I see. If that's how you feel,
you can do as you please.
I just dropped by to see
if I could help in any way.
I won't be asking
for your help.
What you can do
is admit that those men
were not trying to escape.
Admit it! You and Wang Heng Li
plotted their escape.
Didn't you?
Why don't you answer?
Wang Heng Li was arrested.
He confessed everything.
Wang was arrested?
Only his execution remains.
When will it be?
Worried?
He was your friend, wasn't he?
He instigated the uprising
at your suggestion, didn't he?
When is he to die?
Why don't you answer?
Very well.
Today I'll make you
weep like a woman.
That'll be something
for your wife to hear!
WANG HENG LI
In Memoriam
Wang...
in the end you died
without seeing the dawn.
But your countrymen...
will surely bury you
by the light of the newborn day.
Get out here.
Come on.
Go inside.
Kiss her.
Don't let me stop you.
Michiko,
you mustn't come here.
Don't worry. Go home.
I brought some sushi.
May I give it to him?
Go ahead.
Won't you have some?
Michiko...
if you ever need help,
talk to Okishima.
Okishima,
I'm counting on you.
Mr. Okishima...
is being transferred.
I came to say good-bye.
I see.
I'm sorry I wasn't
any help on the phone.
I argued with the manager.
I'm being shipped out to a smaller mine.
So that's how it is.
I'd have liked to stick around
and fight with you some more.
Furuya's taking over my spot.
We're back to square one.
Is there anything you'd like?
Nothing.
So... I won't be seeing you again?
I learned so much from you.
No, it's me
who learned from you.
Though you've paid
a bitter price,
you finally caught
the humanism train.
Oh, yes. Wang Heng Li...
No unauthorized conversation!
Your time is up.
Private!
Michiko!
You're hereby released
by special permission.
But don't think
you're out of the woods.
Remember:
I'll always be watching you.
Wherever you go,
I'll be there first.
Reporting back, sir.
It arrived, Kaji.
EMERGENCY SUMMONS
TO MILITARY SERVICE
I knew something was up.
So you use me up
and then throw me out.
I can't afford to lose you,
but there's nothing I can do.
Forget the smooth talk!
Nice way to get rid
of those you don't want.
There's nothing I can do.
Now I see the light.
I should have trusted the whores
instead of the managers here!
I know you're tired,
but turn your duties over to Furuya.
He needs to find a new leader
among the special laborers.
Since Wang Heng Li escaped,
no one wants to lead them.
Escaped?
Wang Heng Li escaped?
Thirty of them got away.
So he made it after all!
Good for you, Wang!
I hope they all get away!
Sir, please inform Furuya
that he's been spared a thorough
beating thanks to Wang's escape.
I was going over there to thrash him,
not hand over my duties.
But I've suddenly
changed my mind.
I guess a man finds
kindred spirits after all.
Japanese devil!
Kill me...
like you murdered Kao!
Why don't you kill me,
Japanese devil?
He murdered
an innocent man!
Mr. Kaji.
Don't be angry.
I know you have a good heart...
but you weren't able
to save Kao's life.
Michiko, you'll fall!
Welcome back!
I heard you'd come back
in terrible shape.
But it's not true.
You look well.
I'm so happy!
So very happy!
What's this?
They wouldn't!
No, it's not fair!
They promised you
an exemption.
This is a dirty trick!
This is too much.
It's not fair.
Nothing can be done now.
What did you do to deserve this?
Nothing.
But I'd hoped to accomplish things
with you when I returned.
Why must these terrible
things happen to you?
What have you done
to deserve this?
You're so thin,
so covered with scars.
And now they're dragging you
off to war.
You mustn't die.
We must live again.
When will we meet again?
You'll come back.
I know you will.
Japanese devil!
I hope you die!
Michiko, let's go home.
We still have
24 hours together.
Japanese devil!
END