For best IPTV provider, please visit: www.IPTV.CAT
Ficus Religiosa
is a tree with an unusual life cycle.
Its seeds, contained in bird
droppings, fall on other trees.
Aerial roots spring up
and grow down to the floor.
Then, the branches wrap around
the host tree and strangle it.
Finally, the sacred fig
stands on its own.
THE SEED OF THE SACRED FIG
Thank you so much,
I was going to bed.
You haven't eaten since yesterday.
Have your breakfast first.
Your prayer was finally answered.
I'm so proud of you.
I wish your father could see this.
May he rest in peace.
Iman...
Will we be given
a three-bedroom apartment?
- It'll be a while.
- We'll wait.
The girls are too big
to share their bedroom.
It's going to change our lives
to move.
I was given this for self-defense.
Why?
To protect us.
Try it.
Hold it.
No, I don't like it.
Don't be scared, the safety is on.
I'm not scared.
It's heavy.
Shall we tell the girls?
Not yet.
But it's the perfect moment.
They'll be so proud to find out
their father has become a judge.
Not a judge, an investigator.
It doesn't matter.
You'll be a judge soon.
We'll see.
It's important for them
to know these things.
It will build their character.
You know about
the revolutionary courts.
They're unpopular.
Yes, but it's been too long.
You were waiting for an opportunity
to tell them about your work.
This is the best one.
We can go to a restaurant
to celebrate your promotion.
And we'll both talk to the girls.
I'm not sure.
Let me take care of this.
- OK?
- OK.
Sana, quiet, Dad's sleeping.
It's no big deal if I'm not there.
Impossible.
It's important.
The four of us need to talk about it.
So tell us now.
I'm telling you
your father has to be present.
It's both
a celebration and a meeting.
- What celebration?
- You'll see.
Please don't ruin my gathering.
See your friends another day.
Another day? It's her birthday.
Then ask her to be born another day!
Seriously.
I can't postpone it,
we've been planning it for a while.
Family must be your priority.
What's this meeting-celebration
anyway?
For the 20 years I've known your dad,
he's been dreaming of this.
Stop the suspense!
Tell us what's happened.
What if I told you
you'll each have your own bedroom?
No kidding? Seriously?
Hush, I said.
Let's run to the restaurant.
Bye!
Thank you very much.
A judge cannot rule
without first gathering
information and evidence.
Your job was
to gather that information?
Yes.
And why couldn't we know that?
You could have told us sooner.
They must stay anonymous
for their own safety
and that of their families.
In each case,
there's a winner and a loser.
The loser can always consider
he's been convicted unjustly
and seek revenge.
Now you're an investigating judge,
it's still dangerous.
That's right, honey.
But now you're big enough
to understand his position
and be careful.
Careful about what?
You mean, to take revenge on him,
they might hurt us?
It's possible.
But we're going to move to a place
where the neighbors are like us.
And they have kids.
We'll be safe,
the neighborhood is watched.
You should respect certain things
so as not to harm your father.
Like what?
Like the hijab.
No photos of you on social media.
You must be irreproachable.
Anything you do
would be immediately denounced.
You must watch your attitude,
your clothes, the places you go to,
your friends, your words.
Can you do your spoon trick?
Sure.
What's this?
It's written on it.
A five-volume case file.
It takes time to investigate.
I haven't even started.
Don't bother, write down
the indictment and sign.
It's the prosecutor's order.
I can't.
I've been working honorably
for 20 years.
I took an oath.
WIRETAPPED.
I suggest you read the text
of the judges' oath again.
Especially the last part.
Lunchtime.
Why do you think
you became an investigator?
The boss doesn't like you.
He was against your promotion.
He wanted to have one of his guys.
I was the one who insisted.
He's watching for
the slightest misstep on your part.
Do you want me to be challenged?
Or compromise your own success
and your family's serenity?
Do you know how many people
wanted this position?
Iman...
Here, you have to fight,
you have to earn your stripes.
Especially on a case
with an order from the prosecutor.
I haven't even read the file.
How can I indict him
of offense against God
and ask for a death sentence?
How's that?
It's great.
The shoulders fit badly.
And it's loose in the front.
- Shall I tell her?
- Sure.
- Madam...
- Yes?
Thank you, it's very nice,
but the shoulders fit badly.
And the front is loose,
it hides her chest.
One, this isn't the chest,
it's boobs.
Two, her shoulders
will be hidden by the veil.
It's true
but can you please fix this?
Young lady,
this is a uniform,
not an evening gown.
Why wouldn't a uniform look good?
OK, take if off.
Can you also tighten the front?
OK, but if they bug her at school,
don't complain to me.
Sadaf, forget it.
No! I hate loose clothes.
OK, then, please tighten it a bit.
OK, I'll see to it.
When will it be ready?
Call me next week.
School is starting next week!
What can I do? I'm busy.
Hello?
Hi, Mom.
Isn't it hard to be away?
It's a bit hard
to be in a college dorm,
but at the same time, it's cool.
You make new friends,
meet all kinds of people.
You become more independent.
Your mom's brave to let you go.
That was delicious.
- Anything else?
- No, thanks.
- You had enough?
- Yes.
At the beginning,
my mom was a bit worried
but now that I'm settled, she's OK.
- How many are you in a dorm?
- Eight.
So cool, I wanna go there too.
Then Amir called and a red heart
appeared on the screen.
I added it to his contact.
My mom said: who's that?
I said: a classmate.
She said: do you put red hearts
for all your classmates?
I didn't know what to say.
And then, she said:
let me see what he's like.
I said...
She wanted to see him?
She's so laid-back.
- Rezvan?
- Yes?
- Come here.
- OK.
- I'll be right back.
Sana, go help.
You should have put a white heart,
she wouldn't have suspected you.
Yes, Mom?
Your friend had lunch,
serve her tea and off she goes.
What do you mean?
I told you about her situation.
The dorm is not ready.
She knows nobody in Tehran.
You want to kick her out?
If she didn't know you,
what would she do?
She knows me.
This is what I meant.
Our life has changed,
we have to be very careful.
About what?
Our entourage.
What danger would Sadaf
represent for us?
Why do you think
my problem is Sadaf?
I'm telling you
we have to change our lifestyle.
If it's hard for you to tell her,
I'll talk to her.
I'll talk to Dad.
I'll ask him to let Sadaf stay.
Your father doesn't even know
who she is.
He's very busy, don't disturb him.
He's left all this up to me.
Let her spend the afternoon here.
I'll tell her in the meantime
that she has to leave.
OK?
OK, if it's just for the afternoon.
- Rezvan...
- Yes?
Why is it so important to you?
She's my friend, I promised her.
She's very lonely here.
What if you put her up tonight
and then again,
her dorm is not ready?
It will be ready tomorrow.
It's planned, I promise you.
I really didn't think you'd mind
having her one night.
That's why I offered.
She can stay on two conditions.
Which ones?
First, never ask me
this kind of favor again.
Second, make sure
between the time Dad comes home
tonight and when he leaves tomorrow,
Sadaf doesn't come out
of the bedroom.
I can't lock her in!
She can't see your father.
OK.
Mom, my eyebrows are still too thick.
Can you make the end thinner?
So you look like a slut?
I have thin eyebrows
but I'm a good girl!
I'm sorry,
that's not what I meant!
Rezvan has to respect
her family's rules.
When she gets married,
she'll see with her husband.
Sure, she'll respect his rules.
- When will I live for myself?
- Don't move.
Mind you,
natural eyebrows are fashionable.
Are you really plucking them?
I can't feel anything.
Of course I'm plucking them.
Did you see the photo I sent you?
Yeah, it was beautiful.
Mom, can I get some highlights soon?
What's next?
With this beautiful hair you have...
Sadaf is saying
natural is fashionable.
For eyebrows.
I'll dye my hair blue this summer.
Go ahead, and I'll blacklist you.
Remove your nail polish
before your dad comes.
I don't want problems.
What's wrong with you?
You dye your hair
and paint your nails.
Being a young girl
and a married woman
are different things.
What?
Nothing, I'm showing her my nails.
Is that so funny?
They look good.
It's Dad.
Yes, Iman?
Doesn't your mom like me?
Whatever.
She's constantly teasing me.
She's worrying
about this little pest.
Who's the hottest one here?
Ready, girls?
Why are you home so late?
You OK?
Iman...
Have some of this,
it'll do you good.
Why don't you say anything?
They think
they can make me do anything.
Who?
My predecessor was fired
because he refused to sign
a death indictment.
Did they ask you to do something?
To sign the same indictment.
Is it unjust?
I don't know.
Do not sign.
It's the prosecutor's order.
I have to obey to it.
If the prosecutor has given an order,
it's not in your hands, is it?
It's his responsibility.
That's what Ghaderi says.
That's a first instance judgment,
it can be contested.
There can be an appeal
or a plea procedure.
So why are you upset?
I'll get you something
that helps with sleep.
Hello?
Hi, are you feeling better?
Sorry I didn't wake up
to prepare your breakfast.
I'm glad.
I couldn't sleep last night.
I fell asleep at dawn.
Yes.
I missed my prayer.
Where?
Why?
I wanted to go shopping
with the girls.
Rezvan needs
some clothes for college
and Sana some stationery.
Then, we're not going.
If you say it's risky,
we'll stay home.
Don't worry.
OK, my love.
Sure, bye.
If they have stationery
from previous years,
they shouldn't buy more.
They'd better avoid wasting.
Two days before school starts,
parents flock
to school supplies shops
for their children.
Maryam Jafari for National TV
at Tehran's bazar.
Last night,
several neighborhoods
were the scene of protests
turned into riots by some individuals
who disturbed the peace
for a few hours.
Last night's incidents
caused widespread damage
to public property
as well as businesses.
The protests that took place
in some places in Tehran
quickly degenerated.
The rioters damaged
public and private property.
It's 8:55 pm
on Ghods square,
in front of the City Hall,
a car is burning...
They're getting beaten up!
And those lies on TV!
Has Sadaf arrived at her dorm?
Haven't heard from her yet.
Who do you think
you are?
You're coming on my land
to beat me?
Down with the dictator!
Sadaf, are they shouting slogans
there too?
Yes.
- The neighbors!
- Let me see!
In the dorm?
Can't you hear? Listen.
Down with theocracy!
Did you shout too?
Yes and I took off my veil!
- Really?
- Awesome!
Down with the dictator!
You're crazy! What are you doing?
I sent you videos. Check them out.
It's all filtered,
I can't see anything.
I'll send you a VPN.
To me too!
Shut up!
You don't have to imitate me!
I wanna go on the net.
Send it, bye.
Little pest.
In the name of Mahsa Amini,
some fringe groups
called for rallies
that turned into riots.
We could have gone out for a pizza.
Staying one day at home
is more than you can take?
Don't you see this chaos?
What chaos?
People are living their lives.
You two think you know better
than your parents?
Setting fires and breaking glass
is living one's life?
They're not letting them protest.
Go ahead,
defend the rioters in court.
It's impossible to talk to you.
Quiet, I'm listening to the news.
Speculation about the cause of death
is circulating in the media,
from different sources.
She died as a result
of police violence.
Traces of blows were observed.
Traces of blows.
The security police
have released CCTV footage.
Here are the first images
to be released by the police.
From Uzbekistan, the President
ordered an emergency procedure.
The Minister of the Interior
has asked
his Security Officer
to quickly
and accurately determine
the causes of the incident
and report back.
On social media, some maintain
that Mahsa Amini died
as a result of police brutality.
She has visible injuries.
Widespread calls for rallies
were published on social media.
Among them...
Was she really killed for her hijab?
Not at all, she was sick.
She had a stroke.
How do you know?
It's what TV said.
The TV is always right?
No, you're always right.
She had heart issues
and had a stroke at the station.
She must have been so scared
that she had a stroke.
People have strokes every day.
Is it the regime's fault?
They don't all die
from fear of the police!
What if it was your daughter?
My daughter had better not be seen
in an outfit like that!
Why should people get arrested
for their outfit?
That's God's order,
the law of the country.
What if the law of the country
is wrong?
God's law cannot be wrong.
What makes you so sure
this is God's law?
What's the matter with you?
Go out and shout slogans!
Go dance on the streets bareheaded!
If your father knew
what's going on here!
Move it!
What's the matter with her?
What do I know?
The girls have grown.
They have opinions, questions.
They need you.
I'm not asking for anything.
But at this age,
a girl needs her father.
They're getting bored.
If I bug them too much,
they dig their heels in
and don't listen to me.
It's gonna be all right.
It's a phase.
The school and the college
are opening soon.
That will keep them busy.
Be patient.
Iman...
Did you sign the death indictment?
Did I have the choice?
"I submit to the one
who submits to You.
"I fight him who fights You.
Until the Last Day."
Iman...
I know you want to sleep.
But you remember you promised
you'd buy a dishwasher?
My hands and the girls'
are getting damaged.
Next week.
Remember not to take
your phone out of your bag.
I won't, Mom.
I'll pick you up at 1.
Bye.
Rezvan honey,
weren't you supposed
to distance yourself from her?
Sadaf is my only friend.
There's nothing wrong with that.
But be careful because of Dad's job.
I don't know
what you're talking about.
What does Dad do?
A sensitive job, like my brother's.
He's travelling all the time
and nobody knows where he is.
Do you know what he does?
I'm his sister and all I know
is that he's a military man.
But Dad, is he a judge,
an investigator, a military man?
I'm telling you
he has a sensitive job.
We have to be discreet.
When you get close to people,
you must always be careful
to avoid leaks.
What were you thinking
offering to pick up Sadaf?
Her dorm is on our way.
You don't want her in our home.
I'm 21 and you're controlling
all my relationships.
I'm not controlling,
I'm watching over my family.
You'll understand
when you're a mother.
Sadaf is here.
- Hello!
- Hi, how are you?
You're OK? Your parents too?
Yes, thank you.
I just talked to my mom.
She says hi.
That's nice of her.
Last night, it was crazy at the dorm.
Why?
They were all out chanting slogans.
You too?
Did your mom say
how it was in their city?
Yeah, people are very angry
everywhere.
They're not people
but a bunch of thugs.
Be careful not to mingle with them.
- Hello?
- Mom...
What's going on?
Come pick me up. The school's closed.
Why?
The girls are demonstrating.
At the school?
Yes, it's quite tense.
I'll turn around, I'm coming.
- Keep your distance, I'm coming.
- OK.
We are receiving messages
that the principals
are no longer noting absences.
We can officially skip school!
Before, we felt bad doing it.
Now, it's official.
Don't bother coming,
they won't let you in the door.
Basically, in the colleges
and in the highschools,
it's a free-for-all.
Bye.
Hi.
What's going on?
They were shouting slogans.
What slogans?
Women, life, freedom.
I can't reach Rezvan.
Let me try.
Maybe she's out of battery.
I think they cut the coverage
during the demonstrations.
Let's go pick her up.
Can't reach her.
What's he saying?
He says not this way, the other way.
But I can't go from there...
Rezvan...
Rezvan!
Iman...
What's new? Since what time?
No one knows
what time the college closed?
In that case,
she should be home by now!
How will I find my girl?
OK, I'll wait to hear from you.
Iman, call me, don't forget.
Hello?
Rezvan, where are you?
We're at home.
Don't come, Mom's here.
How is she?
Poor thing.
No, I've got this.
Stay close, I'll call you.
See you in a minute.
Mom...
I'm out of sanitary pads.
You got scared, honey?
I'll give you some of mine.
Sorry, but I need thin ones.
If you can't go, I'll buy some.
You've got a nerve!
You want to go out?
Certainly not, I'll go.
Thanks a lot.
Hello?
She's leaving the building now.
I'm coming down.
Go get painkillers.
Sadaf...
Take this.
Drink some water, sweetie.
It's OK, my love.
You'll get better.
Lean back.
Rezvan...
- What?
- Her face...
What should we do?
I have no idea.
Shouldn't we take her to a hospital?
- She says she'd be arrested.
- So what?
What if something happens?
If they arrest her, they won't
let her stay in the hospital.
They'd hurt her.
We have to find a safe doctor.
But how?
Mom...
Rezvan!
You're here?
Why didn't you call me?
I was worried sick.
What's going on?
There's nothing more I can do.
If something happens to her,
who will answer to her family?
She doesn't want her family to know.
It's none of our business.
It's my business.
Why doesn't she want them to know?
I don't know.
All I know is she's in danger
and we need to help her.
I can't allow you to.
It's too much responsibility.
Mom!
You saw her face.
Is it my fault?
She shouldn't have gone.
Gone where?
It was at college,
we got caught in the crowd.
I don't want this in this home.
Have you thought of your father?
You're responsible for him too.
Sadaf, what are you doing?
Sadaf!
I want to go.
You're not well.
You have to call your mom.
- OK.
- I'll take you.
- Mom!
- Don't bother.
Tell her I don't want her to take me.
Stay, we'll take you to a doctor.
Let me talk to her.
I'll call her a taxi.
Put her veil on.
Mom, let her stay, please.
The neighbors mustn't see her face.
Sorry, my love.
- I'll call you.
- OK.
Let's go.
By changing jobs,
you have also changed?
Why don't you answer my calls?
I was in a meeting.
And after the meeting?
I called several times.
Lots of times.
Let me in.
Today,
I had a complicated case.
It preoccupied me.
Complicated enough
to make you forget about your family?
A twenty-year-old boy.
No matter how strong you are,
how unfailing your faith is,
death sentences are overwhelming.
Out of bad luck,
the protests coincided
with my arrival at this position.
There are countless arrests.
From 14-year-olds
to 70-year-old men and women.
More of them every day.
Police stations are saturated.
We're asked to rush through them.
I have a few minutes
to make a decision.
100, 200, 300 cases a day.
What can I do?
Work is work.
Do you know how long it's been
since you had a meal with the girls?
Explain, reassure them.
Who reassures me?
Tomorrow morning, before leaving,
take the time to talk to them.
I can't.
I have to be in court very early.
I promise to be back for dinner.
Mom...
Hi, Dad.
Can you come?
Go, darling, I'm coming.
What is it?
They must have argued.
It looks great on you.
I'll be back.
Look what they're doing to her,
poor thing.
It's at the dorm?
Her friends filmed them secretly.
I told you she should have stayed.
On the contrary,
I was right.
They would come for her here.
What about your father?
I'll talk to him.
Stay here. What are you doing?
- I'll talk to him.
- About what?
I want to know where she is.
Nobody knows who took her.
Sadaf did nothing.
You father doesn't know about that.
Who does, then?
None of your business, you brat.
- Mom...
- You two listen to me.
The agents have her phone.
Do not call or text her.
Same goes for you, Sana.
She must have done something
to get arrested this way.
Mom, listen.
Sadaf did nothing.
I was with her.
I beg you, help her.
Never say again
that you were with her.
You were nowhere with her, got it?
I know someone who can help us.
I'll find her by tomorrow morning.
Now go to bed, phones off.
Go!
What did he say?
He got hit by buckshot.
Gosh! They're breaking in.
Oh no...
God.
They've pulled
her jacket over her head.
They've covered her head.
They're taking the kid...
Hello.
- How are you?
- Thanks.
How are the kids?
Fine, thank you.
How's Alireza?
Good, thanks.
He said Iman has become
an investigator, congratulations.
For now, it's mostly problems.
He's swamped.
Don't be ungrateful.
He'll have a big pay raise,
you'll be given official housing.
After a couple of years
in this position,
he'll be promoted
to the revolutionary court.
Then, you'll be all set.
Being a judge's wife is the best.
I wish the same for you.
We're not so lucky.
Alireza too should have be promoted
to an investigator, but...
it didn't happen.
It's God's will.
For now, they're arresting
so many people.
Night and day, it never stops.
I know. Actually, I'm here
for a friend's daughter.
She got arrested
and her family hasn't heard from her.
When did it happen?
Last night, at her dorm.
Who arrested her?
Plainclothes cops?
Or special forces?
Plainclothes, I think.
Then it will take a while
before they know anything.
I've come to ask you
to do a good deed.
If you could search her name
in your base.
No promises, but send me her name
and also her identification number.
Sure.
I have to go. You see it's endless.
Thank you for taking the time.
No problem.
I don't want to interfere,
but these friends of yours
who ask you a favor
let their children
take part in riots.
- And then...
- Yes, I know.
These days, some unscrupulous people
have posted the addresses
and phone numbers
of judges, investigators,
or whoever works for the government.
They have found them
and put them on social media.
No, seriously?
Imagine, when they circulate
on the hostile media...
You need to choose
your acquaintances wisely.
We will, for sure.
Say hi to your family.
Thank you, Fatemeh.
Please, don't tell Alireza
about my request.
If he tells Iman,
he wouldn't like it.
Don't even say you saw me,
it's between us.
OK, no worries.
Take care. See you soon.
- See you.
- Bye.
Hi, Mom.
- What's new?
- Take these.
We need her identification number.
How are we gonna find that?
No idea.
You're talking like it's my fault.
She must have broken windows
or burnt tires.
That will teach her a lesson.
Call her family.
I told you she didn't do anything.
They were together.
Rezvan could have been
shot in the eye too.
What were you doing
with those rioters?
These loose women
in the streets, undressed.
Hello?
Hi, any news?
She needs the identification number.
Can you find it?
OK, try to find it
as soon as possible.
I'll wait for your call.
What the hell are you doing?
Who were you talking to?
What's wrong with you?
To a classmate.
Did you tell anyone we can help her?
Did you mention your father?
In what way?
Stop playing dumb.
How do your friends think
you're searching for her?
I didn't mention Dad.
- How then?
- I said my uncle knows someone.
How dare you mention your uncle?
If I ever hear you mention
your father or your uncle...
I didn't say anything, Mom!
I know what I can and can't say!
Stop threatening me
or I'm moving out!
Moving out, congrats!
What do you think this is? A hotel?
You're shameless!
- Don't close the door!
- Leave her alone!
Not like this, set it down.
Take another one.
Move these aside, my hands are dirty.
- How should I cut it?
- In slices, the other way round.
Put it here.
The other way round.
Now cut it in slices.
Set it down.
- It's OK.
- You'll get burnt.
Turn them with this.
Down with theocracy!
Each person killed
Is replaced by a thousand more
What's going on?
You're here?
I thought you forgot.
I rushed out of court.
My phone was off.
They're shouting in our building too.
The bastards.
We'll get rid of them.
They take advantage of the system
and they insult it.
There are more of them every night.
What if something happened?
Like what?
Don't you think of it?
If something happens,
what would they do to us?
Nothing will happen.
How can you be so sure?
We'll stop them.
Whoever confronts God
does it at their own risk.
There's agitation everywhere,
in colleges, schools.
Let them agitate.
Even schoolgirls
are in the streets bareheaded
chanting slogans.
Where are the girls?
In their bedroom.
They're upset.
Some of Rezvan's friends
have been arrested.
Rezvan wasn't in the commotion,
was she?
No, she wasn't.
But one of her close friends
was arrested.
She's very worried about her.
Why does she have
that kind of friend?
I can't make their friends
undergo a merit test.
They met at college and became close.
Poor kid came to Tehran for college
and ends up in jail.
But she hasn't done anything.
All the families say
the indictees did nothing.
I'm telling you,
she really did nothing.
She found herself
in the middle of the rally.
There we go.
Being in a rally
is a five-year sentence.
OK, fine.
All I want to know
is if you can find
her whereabouts for her family.
How?
God knows where she is.
They'll have to wait.
- They're so many of them.
- How long?
Until she talks.
She'll be kept
in solitary confinement
until she confesses
in front of a camera.
Confess? She's done nothing.
How do you know she's done nothing?
Anyway.
Can you try to find out how she is?
Just that.
No. Even if I wanted to, I couldn't.
At this stage, it's out of my hands.
Nothing but lies. Turn it off.
What'd you say, honey?
Nothing.
You said something.
I said we should turn off the TV
during dinner.
Before.
I said it was nothing but lies.
Sweet Lord.
How do you know?
I live in this country.
I've got eyes.
Are you sure? It could be the enemy
that's persuading you.
What enemy, Dad?
My friends were beaten and arrested
before my eyes.
Listen,
I know there's room for improvement.
But you guys don't realize
that the whole world is against us.
This is all an enemy plot.
What plot?
I don't care about the enemy
or some conspiracy theory.
A girl my age
was killed because of her hijab.
Why?
See, your facts aren't straight.
She had a stroke.
But through the media,
the enemy brainwashed you
into believing she was killed.
So why do they refuse to investigate?
Why don't they let an independent
commission take action?
They're killing all these people
simply to deny killing her?
You're going too far.
Me and thousands of others,
are slaving away
to preserve this country for whom?
For you!
You are defending
a bunch of sluts who just want
to walk the street naked!
Who wants to walk naked?
The people in the streets!
Who, Dad?
I happened to be
in the crowd yesterday.
You had no right to!
It was a coincidence.
I was leaving the college
with my friend.
They shot her in the face
with buckshot.
And then they arrested her
at her dorm.
Even if she lives,
she'll lose an eye.
Her beauty is gone,
her bright future too.
Why?
Listen, every day,
I interrogate
thousands of people like her.
- I know who they're involved with.
- Who?
They're just normal people
who want a normal life and freedom.
Just like anywhere else.
Good God.
Stop arguing with your father!
If not as a father,
as an expert who's been serving
this regime for 20 years,
don't you think I know better?
No.
You don't, Dad.
Because you're on the inside.
You believe in it.
You want to preserve it at all cost.
Iman...
For once we were having
a family dinner, you ruined it.
Iman...
Iman.
Here, have some water.
You OK?
Najmeh...
Najmeh dear.
Yes?
Where have you put my gun?
Your gun?
I don't know.
I didn't touch it.
My God...
Are you sure you had it
when you came home?
- I came in, you were at the window.
- Yes.
I took off my jacket,
threw it on the bed.
I put the gun...
in the drawer and then...
I sat down here.
I didn't mention it,
but the other evening,
you left it in the bathroom.
I found it there
when I picked up the laundry.
I put it away in this drawer.
You'll find it.
The kids!
Where are you going?
They may have taken it.
Take your gun?
Can you ask them?
You want me to wake them up
to ask them about your gun?
Yes, I do!
Rezvan...
Sweetheart...
Wake up, please.
What's going on?
Your Dad's gun is not in its place.
Do you know where it is?
What?
A gun?
Dad has a gun?
No, nothing.
Go back to sleep.
- So?
- I told you, it scared her.
They didn't even know you have a gun.
God...
Iman...
Maybe you've left it in court.
Go check.
Six months to three years in jail.
Worse than the sentence,
is the discredit.
You've been here
less than two weeks.
Such an embarrassment.
There'd be talk.
They'll say you were incapable
of keeping your gun for a few days.
Your merits will be questioned.
They'll lose faith in you.
Prevent you from moving up.
I'll find it.
You have to find it.
For now, don't report it,
don't say anything to anyone.
Based on what you're saying,
it's in your house, without a doubt.
Maybe if you just wait a few days,
the one who's taken it
will put it back.
Don't repeat yourself.
Where would I have left it?
Najmeh, think back
to what she said last night,
it just has to be at home.
Yes.
Keep me up to date.
Put them properly on the desk.
- And the top one?
- It's empty!
These are my underwear!
In my own home,
I don't feel safe.
Be patient, my love.
These things happen in every family.
Next month,
it will be 21 years, right?
21 years.
Up in smoke.
All my professional credibility.
You can't lose your credibility
because of something
that's out of your hands.
Don't be so worried.
Yes.
I can.
But I won't let it happen.
Dad is about to have a stroke.
If something happens to him,
it's your fault.
Really, Mom?
You said people had strokes every day
and it was no one's fault,
just bad luck.
But if it's Dad, it's our fault?
You've got some nerve.
If this damn gun is not found,
your dad will do 3 years of jail.
3 years.
Why do you assume it's us?
We could point the finger at her.
Don't know.
Sana, what's going on with her?
Mom, aren't you eating?
No.
Why?
Mom...
Mom!
You don't realize
what you're doing to him.
What are we doing?
If you'd grown up like me
with a father who only cared about
gambling and partying,
you'd be more grateful.
You'd honor your father.
I understand, Mom.
I know you suffered as a child.
But why do you always think
Dad is right?
Why would Sana and I
take the gun?
So it just flew away?
Maybe Dad is lying...
Mind what you say about your father!
OK, the gun was in the drawer
of his nightstand.
Do you really think Sana and I
would dare come in
while you're asleep
and take it from the drawer?
What are we talking about anyway?
Dad is so spaced out these days,
he's left it somewhere
and he's taking it out on us.
She's right, Mom.
Think about it.
Here, eat.
Mom...
You shouldn't have told your family
about your work.
I should have hidden it?
Of course.
Until when?
To the grave.
I'm in deep shit.
It's normal.
In our training, they don't teach
an investigator
how to interrogate their family.
Don't you suspect any of them?
I can't believe my daughters did it.
And your wife?
I have absolute confidence in her.
Really?
There's only one way
to find out who did it.
What?
Alireza.
Take them to him.
- To Alireza?
- Yes.
He's the best interrogator there is.
He has psychological tricks,
he'll figure it out quickly.
How could I?
He comes over often.
Our wives are friends.
Our kids are friends.
How can he interrogate my family?
Why interrogate?
He uses psychology
and body language techniques.
He'll tell you who's got it.
Isn't that worth it?
You want to be let go?
You want us both to be on the hook?
Make this go away.
I won't take them to him.
Do you know anyone safer?
Any better way?
Tell yourself it's a therapy session.
Alireza and Fatemeh are our friends.
They don't need to know about
our personal problems.
I told him not to mention it
to his family.
They're a couple.
They tell each other everything.
How dare you have your children
interrogated by your friend?
Why interrogate?
It's a psychotherapy session.
He'll make sure
they don't recognize him.
After this,
who can the girls confide in?
You?
Me?
Their friends?
What can I do?
If they find out at court,
do you know what will happen?
If they discover
the gun was taken from my home?
We'll see him for half an hour,
he'll do the interviews
and make his diagnosis.
We'll be done with it.
He's a specialist.
Is it filmed?
What?
You said interrogations are filmed.
Of course not,
what are you talking about?
What will we tell the girls?
That it's a therapy session.
It's here.
It won't take long.
I'll wait for you.
OK.
Let's go, girls.
Hello.
Hello, come in.
Come in.
Arms up.
Come on.
The other one too.
You have something on you?
Go sit.
Come on, quick.
Arms up, legs spread.
Go sit there too.
- What do you have on you?
- Nothing.
- A phone in your bag?
- Yes.
Let me see.
Arms up.
Legs spread.
Go wait there.
Mom...
Yes, honey?
Come here.
Girls, this way.
Get up.
Let's go.
It's on your right.
You're here and you're there.
Hello.
- How are you?
- Fine, thank you.
- Fatemeh is fine?
- Thank God.
Reyhaneh and Amir Mahdi too?
Yes, thank you.
Follow me.
You want to talk to me too?
I have a few small questions.
Iman said it's just the girls.
Please, this way.
Don't turn, face the wall.
- Can you see here?
- Where?
Down here.
Could you write?
No, I can't see.
- And now?
- Yes.
Don't move, I'll be back.
I cannot believe
the girls would have taken the gun.
In general, the criminal
is not the one you imagine.
What crime are we talking about?
I'm sure Iman has left it somewhere.
You know how it's been lately.
You are all under pressure
due to all of the arrests.
Iman is really perturbed.
He's had to sign a few indictments
that have deeply troubled him.
I see.
But Iman is sure he put it away
in its place at home.
He told me the same thing,
but it's unlikely.
The other night, he came home
very upset and went for a shower.
Then I found the gun
in the bathroom.
Just by chance.
I put it in its place.
So you think
the gun is not at your home.
Yes.
And you?
What about me?
Might you know where it is?
What do you mean?
I would have taken it?
You just said
you're sure it's not in your home.
Well, thank you.
Thank Iman.
Don't take it badly.
Iman told me
he has absolute confidence in you.
But everyone knows
sometimes between
mother and daughters,
there are secrets.
Absolutely not.
Why would I hide this
from my husband?
God as my witness,
I've always been transparent
with Iman.
Yet I know
there are things
that Iman doesn't know.
Stay seated, please.
You're speaking in an offending way.
Sit down.
I'm speaking to you
very respectfully.
Never has a person sitting there
been treated with such respect.
Be reassured,
all this will remain between us.
I'm the keeper of secrets.
I thought perhaps this issue
might be one of those
that you have decided
to hide from Iman.
I can't understand this disaster
taking over my life.
Be precise and thorough.
Especially concerning the young girl
you were looking for.
You, go to your room.
No, stay.
We have nothing to hide.
Do you realize what you're doing?
What am I doing?
Playing with your dad's reputation.
The family's reputation.
Sweetheart,
this issue has the potential
to ruin my career.
I'll be put in jail.
Don't you care?
- It's not me...
- Who, then?
Rezvan,
honey,
don't be scared.
No harm will come to you.
Just give me the gun back.
What gun?
Why won't you believe me?
You accuse me
because of what a stranger says!
Where's the gun then?
Did it vanish into thin air?
Where is it?
I have no idea!
Maybe you have it!
Calm down, sweetie.
All you've been given
is love and respect.
The best house, everything you need,
a car, money...
What have you been missing?
I didn't take it, Dad.
I swear I didn't.
I swear on whatever you want.
Why won't you believe me?
I didn't even know you had a gun.
Leave me alone.
You won't believe me.
Leave me alone!
I'll find it.
Mom...
Mom, wait...
What are you doing?
Please, don't start again.
You've already searched everywhere.
Mom!
Calm down, you're not well.
Did she tell you anything?
It's my turn?
Don't you want to have blue hair?
Your father will promise you can.
Go ahead, Iman.
Sweetie,
Rezvan isn't in her right mind.
If you know something, say so,
you'll do her a favor.
And I'll let you dye your hair,
paint your nails.
She didn't tell me anything.
Sana knows something.
I can see it in her eyes.
She's a child.
This isn't the court, it's your home.
A mistake has been made,
but as you said,
one shouldn't burn bridges.
What curse has fallen upon me.
You have us.
They'll call me incompetent.
Who?
I've always said
you built this life from nothing.
With no support, on your own,
with no help.
Iman...
your dream is coming true.
You're only a few steps away
from the judge's chair.
Yes.
A few steps.
But fate has changed.
Your name is Iman.
How can you lose faith?
You'll make it right.
I'd like to hug Rezvan.
Kiss Sana.
Go ahead, hug them, kiss them.
Now?
Najmeh...
Yes, my love?
Sana wants to have blue hair?
Painted nails?
Why?
The world has changed.
Kids think differently.
The world has changed,
but God has not.
Nor his laws.
We have to teach them.
We always have.
Sana is going through puberty.
She's influenced by her friends.
She shouldn't see them.
You must spend more time with them.
So that you get closer,
become more intimate.
You have to help shape their ideas.
Yes.
Najmeh.
Yes, my love?
Come close to me.
Mom!
- What's that?
- Dad's contact info was posted.
Even our address.
Good God...
My Goodness.
Let me see.
I told you to be careful.
They wanna do away with me.
You have to report it all.
Write a letter to the boss now.
Say your personal info
has been revealed online
and that you're in danger.
Ask for secure official housing.
Drop the letter off and rush home.
Take your family
and go to a safe place for a while.
Until things settle down.
I have two of them.
Keep one for now.
Thank you so much.
Yes?
Who is it?
Nobody rang.
Iman... you're OK?
Yes... I'm OK.
What shall we do?
Give me your phone.
My phone? Here.
Hi, Dad.
Hi.
Your phone.
Cut the music.
Your code.
2003.
Iman?
Sana.
Your code.
Give it to me.
Najmeh, your code.
You know it.
Everyone at the table in 10 minutes.
I'm worried.
Strange things have been happening.
We'll leave Tehran for a few days.
We'll go to my birthplace.
You loved going there
when you were little.
I haven't had time
to take you there lately.
It's the right moment.
Over there we will become
the family we were.
And try to work things out.
Get ready, we're leaving in an hour.
Dad, can I have my phone back?
Rezvan, drop it.
- I want to check on my friend.
- Get in the car.
Come on, get in.
- Anything wrong?
- No.
You seem weird.
Did someone recognize you?
They took photos and videos of us.
What are you going to do?
Masks on.
Girls, masks.
Sana, wake up,
put a mask on.
What's going on?
Dad and the car were filmed.
By who?
Iman, please, let's go.
You said it would be all over.
I won't let anyone hurt us.
Please, drop it.
Please, Dad, let's just go.
Are you sure he filmed us?
The glove box.
Take out your phone.
When I tell you,
film his car with the license plate.
She's also filming us.
You're going too fast.
Don't you see the girls are scared?
Careful, Dad!
Dad!
We'll crash!
Please, drop it!
Stay in the car.
So, investigator, you're scared?
Afraid your family
will find out what you do?
Your father is an executioner!
Drop your phone.
Go ahead, shoot, if you dare!
His gun!
He didn't tell us he found it.
It's another one.
What have you done, Sana?
- Give it to me.
- I'll keep it.
Leave it!
Dad's lost it.
Grab the phones.
Let's call Uncle Assad.
Shut up, you whore!
Do you know how many death
sentence requests he's signed?
There's no signal!
Have you read about him?
- Sana, quick!
- I have no signal!
I'm better than you
who feeds on the blood of the people.
- Call Assad...
- There's no signal.
I'm streaming this live to the world
to put you to shame.
She's lying, there's no signal.
She can't send anything.
Throw your phone.
I swear I'll shoot!
Throw it, he may really shoot!
Tie her up.
ID and phone.
- Hands behind your back.
- Quick!
- Not you!
- Here we are!
It's a couple's photo.
I've got you.
Daddy!
- Yes?
- Sing.
What song?
"From my heart"
No, another one.
Please, Daddy.
No, I said!
- Yes, sir!
- Good boy.
So you found the gun?
No, I didn't.
This is Ghaderi's. He lent it to me.
So the nightmare is not over.
Soon.
Shit.
It must be the fuses.
I'll check.
Sana...
Thanks.
- I put it here?
- Yes, thanks.
It's so nice of you.
My pleasure.
A feast of a breakfast.
It's only normal.
Thank you.
Dad, when will we have
our phones back? It's boring here.
Be patient, you'll have them.
You think it's which one?
The one with the plaid shirt.
That's Uncle Ali, for sure.
I think he's the other one.
Dad!
- Is it you?
- Yes.
It's at the Imam Reza shrine.
Why are you doing this?
It's a gesture of submission,
faith, absolute obedience.
I see, what Dad expects from us.
It's not for me,
it's for God.
Why are you interfering
in our relationship with God?
- Sana!
- Let her talk.
That's no way to talk.
I'm just asking a question.
In faith, there are no questions.
You have to feel it in your bones.
Woe to him who loses his faith.
What's undermining our family
is lies.
I don't care about the gun anymore.
I want the liar.
I want my family back.
You have one hour
to hand over the liar.
It shouldn't have come to this.
Why does he get to do
whatever he wants?
He's the first liar.
For years he hid his job from us.
We're up against the wall.
I know your father well.
- Whoever's done it needs to give in.
- Mom...
I'm begging you.
No matter who did it,
just stop playing around.
Give it to me.
I stole it, I'm the liar.
You always give in to him.
I've always made sure you never see
your father's true colors.
Which of you has the gun?
We don't know anything.
Is that your final word?
Fine.
Sit down.
So,
I've been living with a liar
for 20 years.
Can the girls go out?
Why?
Let them see.
What else did you lie about?
I didn't lie about anything else.
From the start, you were excited
to have this gun at home.
But I was scared.
Where's the gun?
I threw it into the canal
near our house.
One lie
after the other.
Are you taking the blame
for the girls?
I'm not lying.
I made a mistake, I apologize.
Please forgive me.
Let's go back home
and I'll show you where I threw it.
We might find it.
Explain when and how
you stole the gun.
The night you had a nightmare,
I woke you up
and gave you some water.
Remember?
You went to the living room.
I took it then.
Where did you hide it?
When did you throw it?
I hid it
in the freezer,
between pieces of meat.
Then,
in the morning, when you left,
I went to throw it into the canal.
You didn't think
of your husband's reputation?
Iman, please, that's enough,
let's go back to Tehran.
I'll tell everyone it was me.
I won't let you be harmed.
The girls are really scared.
I'll come to any court
to confess I took the gun.
You'll be off the hook,
don't be afraid.
I'm not afraid of anybody!
So what do you want the gun for?
Enough, Mom, get up.
Stop it, I don't want you
to be involved in this.
We've been involved
since the beginning.
I have your gun.
It's here.
Ask Uncle Assad to come and pick up
Mom and Sana.
Then, I'll give it to you.
Are you making conditions for me?
Sit down in front of the camera.
I won't sit.
You will.
Rezvan sweetheart,
come sit for a minute.
We'll talk.
Come, my love.
Let your father calm down.
When and how you stole the gun,
for what motive?
I won't answer.
Don't get smart with me!
Answer him.
I told you,
I have it here, in the garden.
Let Mom and Sana leave
and I'll give it to you.
Don't make conditions!
Rezvan, honey,
since you're saying
you have it here,
why don't you give it back to him?
It's not here.
You're all liars.
I swear I left it here.
You're hurting me!
Open the door!
Open!
Mom!
Iman!
Are you out of your mind?
You've gone crazy!
Mom, you're OK?
Rezvan, honey, I'm here.
Don't be scared, my love, I'm here.
Take this.
Open it!
Open the door!
Iman, where's Sana?
It's cold, she'll get sick.
It's not safe out there.
There are wild animals.
Let's go find her.
I don't want this!
What are you doing?
We're your family!
My baby will get scared!
If something happens to her,
I'll never forgive you!
Iman!
My baby's all alone!
She'll get lost!
Iman!
Where are you?
Can you hear me?
Come open this door!
Iman,
she needs to go to the bathroom!
Open up!
- I need to go!
- Open up, I'm telling you!
If you shout next time,
I won't open up.
Tap gently on the door...
- Mom!
- Let's go, quiet.
Go in, I'll put the power back on.
I'm going to the toilet!
You brute!
- Iman, take only me.
- Sure.
If they let me.
- Daddy!
- Wait.
Let's do a selfie.
Daddy!
Yes, honey?
Stop saying Daddy for a second!
Dad, take one alone and then...
Sana!
Open the door!
Open up!
Damn it!
Sana, you're OK?
Where's your father?
He can't reach us!
The car key!
The gate is closed.
He'll be here soon!
No, this way!
Come on!
Run!
Faster!
Come on, girls.
Let's separate!
Mom...
Sana...
- Rezvan!
- Mom!
What the hell are you doing?
- Run!
- Najmeh!
Get out of my way.
Quiet, sit down.
I won't sit, I'm talking.
What are you going to do?
You've already done it all.
You haven't shot me yet.
Go ahead.
Girls, he's here!
Mom!
I won't sit!
Sana!
Mom!
Enough, let her go!
Sana, my love.
You're finally back.
Let her go. Get up, Mom!
Give him the gun.
Don't hurt my girls.
- You know to shoot, kid?
- Yes.
First, you have to pull this.
I know, it's armed.
Where have you learnt?
Stay back!
I'm a nervous wreck, I'll shoot.
Shoot your father?
Yes.
With what I've seen of you,
I'll definitely shoot.
Go ahead, honey.
Iman, if she gives it to you,
it will be all over, right?
It won't be over.
It's always been this way.
You've always given in.
You gave him everything.
If I give it back, nothing changes.
Please, Sana, sweetheart.
Mom!
Rezvan, tell him to stay back!
Don't!
THE SEED OF THE SACRED FIG
Adaptation: Massoumeh Lahidji
Subtitling TITRAFILM