Sonny, hit me up with some syrup.
- Ma'am?
- Yeah, I'll be right with you.
Here you go. You got the sausage,
and pancakes for you.
And here's your syrup.
He's over there.
- Decaf or regular?
- Regular, please.
You girls are kinda young to be smoking,
don't you think?
Ruins your sex drive.
I'll get it!
I got it!
Hello?
Hey, how you doing, little housewife?
You all packed?
We're out of here tonight.
Well, wait now.
I still have to ask Darryl if I can go.
You mean you haven't asked him yet?
Thelma, for Christ's sake!
Thelma, is he your husband or your father?
It is just two days, for God's sake.
Don't be a child.
Tell him you're going with me.
Tell him I'm having a nervous breakdown.
That don't carry much weight with Darryl.
He already thinks you're out of your mind.
- Are you at work?
- No, I'm calling from the Playboy Mansion.
Call you right back.
Darryl?
Darryl!
Honey, you better hurry up!
Goddamn it, Thelma.
Don't holler like that.
Shit.
Haven't I told you I can't stand it
when you holler in the morning?
I'm sorry, doll.
I just didn't want you to be late.
Thank you.
- Hon?
- What?
Have a good day at work today.
- Jesus.
- Here.
Thank you, no.
- Hon?
- What?
You want anything special
for dinner tonight?
No, Thelma, I don't give a shit
what we have for dinner.
I may not even make it home for dinner.
You know how Fridays are.
Yeah, funny how so many people
want to buy a carpet on a Friday night.
You'd almost think they'd want to
forget about it for the weekend.
Well, then it's a good thing
you're not regional manager
and I am.
Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
For Christ's sake,
I got to get the hell out of here.
Jesus!
Goddamn it, Homer!
Christ, I gotta get to work!
Don't need this bullshit in the morning!
Just leave 'em. I'll get 'em.
Thank you.
For Christ's sakes.
And I want you out of here by 5:00.
No, 3:00. Get out of here by 3:00 today.
Good morning.
- Morning. Is Louise there?
- Why, yes, she is.
Is this Thelma?
When are you gonna run away with me?
Not this weekend.
She's running away with me.
Hey, what did he say?
What time are you picking me up?
All right!
I'll be there around 2:00 or 3:00.
Okay.
Hey, say, what kind of stuff do I bring?
Oh, I don't know. Warm stuff, I guess.
It's the mountains. It gets cold at night.
I'm just gonna bring everything.
Okay. I will too then.
- And steal Darryl's fishing stuff.
- Louise, I don't know how to fish.
Neither do I, Thelma, but Darryl does it.
How hard can it be?
- All right, I'll see you in a bit.
- Okay.
Okay, bye.
Hi, this is Jimmy.
I'm not here right now.
- Hey.
No, Thelma, we don't need the lantern.
The place has electricity.
Okay. No, I want to take it anyway.
- Just in case.
- In case of what?
In case there's some escaped
psycho killer on the loose
who cuts the electricity off
and tries to come in and kill us.
Sure, Thelma. Well, then
that lantern'll come in real handy.
Maybe we should
just tow your car behind too
in case he steals the spark plugs.
We'd have to. That thing barely makes it
down the driveway.
- Careful. Careful.
- Okay.
- All right. Everything in?
- Yeah.
Careful. Here you go.
- Be careful!
- All right.
Smile.
Yeah! See you later!
Sit down!
Oh, Louise?
- Will you take care of this gun?
- What in hell did you bring that for?
Oh, come on.
Psycho killers or bears or snakes.
I just don't know how to use it.
Will you take care of it?
Put it awa...
Just... Here. Put it in my purse.
Thelma, good Lord.
- So whose place is this again?
- It's Bob's, the day manager's.
He's gettin' a divorce.
His wife's gettin' this place.
So he's lettin' all his friends use it
till he's gotta turn over the keys.
I've never been out of town
without Darryl.
How come Darryl let you go?
'Cause I didn't ask him.
Shit, Thelma.
Why... He's gon' kill you!
Well, he'd never let me go.
He never lets me do one goddamn thing
that's any fun.
All he wants me to do is
hang around the house the whole time
while he's out doing God only knows what.
Well, you get what you settle for.
I left him a note.
I left him stuff to microwave.
- Thelma.
- What?
- Thelma, what are you doin'?
- Smoking.
Hey. I'm Louise.
I'll never make it.
Can't we just stop somewhere for a minute?
Thelma, we're not gonna get to the cabin
till after dark as it is.
Then what difference would it make
if we stopped?
Come on.
I never get to do stuff like this.
- Okay. But it's gonna be a quick stop.
- Fine. Okay.
I haven't seen a place like this
since I left Texas.
Isn't this fun?
- Y'all want a drink?
- No, thanks.
I'll have a Wild Turkey straight up
and a Coke back, please.
Thelma!
Oh, what? Tell me something.
Is this my vacation or isn't it?
I mean, God, you're as bad as Darryl.
I'm sorry. It's just I'm not used to
seeing you this way.
I haven't seen you this way in a while.
You're usually so sedate.
Well, I've had it up to my ass
with sedate.
You said you and me
was gonna get out of town
and, for once,
just really let our hair down.
Well, darlin', look out,
'cause my hair is coming down.
All right. I've changed my mind.
I'm gonna have a margarita
and a shot of Cuervo on the side.
- Okay.
- All right! Get me another one.
Hey.
Now, what are a couple of Kewpie dolls
like you doin' in a place like this?
- We left town for the weekend...
- Minding our business. Why don't you try?
To have some fun.
And 'cause Louise here is mad
at her boyfriend 'cause...
- We just wanted to get something to eat.
- Well, you've come to the right place.
Do you like chili? They got good chili.
Harlan, you botherin' these poor girls?
Hell, no. I was just bein' friendly.
Well, it's a good thing
they're not all as friendly as you.
Hey, your name's Harlan?
I got an uncle named Harlan.
You do?
Is he a funny uncle?
'Cause if he is,
then he and I got something in common.
I don't mean to be rude,
but I got something I got
to talk to my friend about in private.
I understand.
I didn't mean to bother you.
It's just hard not to notice
two such pretty ladies as yourselves.
You better dance with me before you leave,
or I will never forgive you.
Sure, that'd be fun.
Geez, Louise. That wasn't very nice.
Can't you tell
when somebody's hittin' on you?
Oh, so what if he was?
It's all your years of waiting tables
that's made you jaded, that's all.
Maybe.
Well, just relax, will you?
- You're making me nervous.
- All right!
I woke up in a hotel,
I didn't know what to do
I turned the TV on
and wrote a letter to you...
That's a good band.
The news was talkin' 'bout a dragnet
up on the interstate
Seems they were looking for a Cadillac
with Tennessee plates...
- Wonder if Darryl's home yet.
- Wonder if Jimmy's got back.
Why don't you just tell him to get lost
once and for all?
Why don't you ditch
that no-good husband of yours?
This one's on Harlan.
Thanks.
Well, look.
Jimmy will come in off the road
and you won't be there.
He'll freak out and call you like
a hundred thousand times.
Sunday night, you'll call him back,
and by Monday,
he'll be kissin' the ground you walk on.
Exactly.
In the meantime,
you said we was gonna have some fun,
so let's have some!
- All right.
- Okay.
All right.
Okay.
- Let's dance.
- All right.
I woke up in a hotel,
I didn't know what to do
I turned the TV on,
and wrote a letter to you
The news was talkin' 'bout a dragnet
up on the interstate...
Thelma. That's your name? Thelma?
That's a lovely name.
I don't know what I'm doing.
Follow me, Thelma.
- Ma'am, you wanna dance a little?
- Sure.
Since I left California, baby,
things have gotten worse
Seems the land of opportunity,
for me is just a curse
Tell that judge in Bakersfield
my trial'll have to wait
Down here, they're looking
for a Cadillac with Tennessee plates
She saw him singing once
when she was 17...
You got some great moves, honey.
Anyway, he wouldn't care,
hell, he gave them to his friends...
All right! Here we go!
Here we go! Here we go!
Hey now, baby,
you lookin' so fine
Toolin' around in your Mercury '49
Crazy about a Mercury
Lord, I'm crazy about a Mercury
I'm gonna buy me a Mercury
and cruise it on down the road
Hey, hey! Thelma!
- Oh, Louise.
- I'm hittin' the little girls' room.
And then we're out of here.
I'm ready when you are.
Wait, Louise, I want to come with you.
Come on there.
Turn around. Turn around.
- What?
- I don't feel so good.
What's wrong?
Come on.
- Shit. Stop!
- What for?
I'm spinning.
Oopsy-doopsy.
We need to get you some fresh air,
little lady.
Look, have you seen my friend?
Your friend? Yeah. Yeah.
She was out there dancing.
Dancing.
How you feeling now, darling?
Oh, thanks.
I think I'm starting
to feel a little better.
You're starting to feel pretty good
to me too.
- Hey.
- You know that?
I think I need to keep walking.
Wait a minute. Wait a minute.
Wait a minute.
- Where do you think you're going, huh?
- I'm going back inside.
Oh, no, no.
- Harlan.
- What?
Hey, quit it. Stop it. Stop it. Stop.
Thelma, Thelma, listen to me.
Listen to me.
I'm not gonna hurt you, okay?
I just wanna kiss you. All right?
- No. No.
- Come on. Come on. Come on.
- Goddamn, you are gorgeous.
- Let me go now. Come on.
- You're gorgeous.
- Let me go! I mean, I'm married!
- Come on.
- That's okay. I'm married too.
I don't feel good. I've been sick.
Listen to me.
I said I'm not gonna hurt you.
All right?
- Relax.
- Harlan, stop it, please! I mean it!
Wait, don't! I mean it!
Louise is gonna wonder where I am!
Fuck Louise! Fuck...
Hey!
Don't ever fuckin' hit me!
Fucking bitch!
- Harlan, please! Harlan, please!
- Do you hear me?
- Don't hurt me, Harlan, please!
- Shut up!
Shut the fuck up! You hear me?
Shut up!
Please. Please don't hurt me, Harlan!
Goddamn bitch!
Don't hurt me, Harlan!
- Let her go!
- Louise!
Get the fuck out of here.
Louise!
You let her go,
you fucking asshole,
or I'm gonna splatter your ugly face
all over this nice car.
All right.
Hey, hey, hey, just calm down.
We were just having a little fun,
that's all.
Looks like you got
a real fucked-up idea of fun.
Come on. Come on.
Turn around.
In the future,
when a woman's crying like that,
she isn't having any fun!
Come on.
- It's okay.
- Bitch!
I should've gone ahead and fucked her!
What did you say?
I said, suck my cock.
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
- Get the car.
- Oh, Jesus Christ.
Louise, you shot him.
- Oh, my God.
- Get the car.
You watch your mouth, buddy.
Louise, come on!
Watch it, you fucking asshole!
Louise?
Louise, where are we going?
I don't know. I don't know.
Just shut up so I can think.
Shouldn't we go to the cops?
I mean, I think we oughta tell the police.
Tell 'em what?
What do you think we should tell 'em?
I don't know.
Just tell 'em what happened.
Which part?
All of it.
That... That... That he was raping me.
A hundred goddamn people saw you dancin'
cheek to cheek with him all night!
Who's gonna believe that?
We don't live in that kind of a world!
Goddamn it, pull over!
All right.
Thelma.
Thelma?
Thelma, I'm gonna... I'm gonna...
I'm gonna stop someplace
for a cup of coffee and then...
just for a second...
and then I'm gonna get it together.
And we'll figure out then what to do.
And everything's gonna be fine,
all right?
Everything's gonna be...
All right?
Now is not the time to panic.
If we panic now, we're done for.
- Nobody saw it. Nobody knows it was us.
- Okay.
So we're still okay.
We just have to figure out
what we're gonna do next.
We just have to figure out...
what we're gonna do.
I'll say one thing.
This is some vacation.
I sure am having a good time.
This is real fun.
If you weren't concerned
with having so much fun,
we wouldn't be here right now.
- Just what is that supposed to mean?
- It just means shut up, Thelma.
So this is all my fault, is it?
I have to go to the bathroom.
Sorry.
- Can I get you anything else?
- Just the check, please.
Thanks. I'll try again later.
Move back, people.
Stand away from the line, please.
No, it's secured until further notice.
Could you identify 'em
if you saw 'em again?
Oh, hell, I told you 50 times,
yeah, I could identify 'em.
But neither one of those two
was the type to pull somethin' like this.
Well, you're not exactly
an expert witness,
but what makes you so sure?
Oh, well, if waiting tables in a bar
don't make you an expert on human nature,
nothin' will.
I could've told you Harlan Puckett was
gonna end up buyin' it in a parking lot.
I'm just surprised
it didn't happen sooner than this.
- Who do you think did it?
- Has anybody asked his wife?
She's the one I hope did it.
Lena, do you have any ideas or don't you?
Well, if I had to guess,
I'd say it was some old gal,
some old gal's husband.
But it wasn't neither one of those two.
The smaller one,
the one with the tidy hairdo,
she left me a huge tip.
- Well...
- What?
You didn't happen to notice what kind
of car they were driving, did you?
It's a nightclub, Hal, not a drive-in.
I don't follow the customers
out to the parking lot.
- All right.
Lena, go on home.
You kept me here all night
to ask me the same old question
over and over again?
Ain't you gonna offer me some teeny-eeny,
witty-bitty little drink?
Behave yourself.
Neither of those two
was the murdering type, Hal.
Hi, this is Jimmy.
Thelma, you in there?
Thelma, come on.
We're out of here, Thelma! Come on.
The Dow Jones dropped over 12 points
today, closing at 18...
We're gonna need money.
Thelma, how much money you have on you?
What?
I'm gonna stop at the next town.
We'll get a motel room.
I can rest for a little bit
and then I'll figure out what to do.
Okay. Wait. I'm looking.
Sixty-one dollars.
Shit.
Forty-one dollars.
We're gonna need more money.
What are you doing?
Why are you unpacking?
You said we was just gonna take a nap.
Well, I'm trying to figure out what to do.
Well...
When you figure it out, just wake me up.
What the hell's wrong with you?
What's that supposed to mean?
- I mean, why are you acting like this?
- Acting like what?
How am I supposed to act?
Excuse me for not knowin' how to act
when you blow somebody away!
You could help me try
to figure out what to do.
I'm trying to figure out what to do.
But you could try...
Try? I did! I had a suggestion
that we go to the police.
But you didn't like that,
so frankly, Louise, I'm out of ideas.
Well, what's the big rush, Thelma?
I mean, we give 'em enough time
they'll come to us.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
I'm just not ready to go to jail yet,
okay?
Why don't you...
Why don't you go out to the pool
and take a swim or something, all right?
Now, I'll figure out what to do.
Jimmy, this is Louise.
Look, I've been trying to call you.
- Louise? Hey, baby.
- Hey.
Now, where the hell are you at?
- Are you all right?
- Yeah, I'm fine. How are you?
Long time no see.
- You sound kind of funny, Louise.
- I am funny. I'm real funny.
Are you in town?
It sounds long-distance.
No, I'm out of town. I'm in...
I'm in deep shit, Jimmy.
Deep Shit, Arkansas.
Louise, now you just tell me
what the hell's going on here.
I come back, nobody knows where you are.
- Is Thelma with you?
- Listen, Jimmy.
I have about $6,700 in the bank.
Now, I know you can't get it out...
but I need that money.
Can you wire me the $6,700
and I'll pay you back?
What the fuck is going on here, Louise?
Listen...
Something real bad has happened.
And I can't tell you what.
Just that I did it and I can't undo it.
Will you help me, please?
Yeah, yeah, yeah, baby, of course I can.
But where?
Why can't I bring it to you?
Jimmy.
Do you love me?
Yeah.
- Never mind. Never mind. Never mind.
- Yeah, yeah.
Look, just...
Just wire it to Western Union
in Oklahoma City, okay?
Oh, so that's where you're at.
Oklahoma, huh?
Not yet.
You call me back
and I'll tell you which office to go to.
All right. All right.
You call... I'll call you back in an hour.
Thelma!
Thelma! Thelma!
- What?
- Get in the car.
Okay.
Even if they didn't do it, it times out
they most likely witnessed it,
so somebody better talk to them.
Put out an APB and see what we get back.
All right.
Any reason to believe
they've left the state?
That's certainly possible.
Well, why don't we go ahead
and let the Bureau in on this?
Louise, don't get mad, okay,
but where are we going?
Oklahoma City.
Jimmy's gonna wire me some money
and then we're gonna...
Jimmy?
You talked to him? Did you tell him?
What did he say? Is he mad?
No, I didn't tell him.
That's what we gotta get straight.
Darryl's been calling, mad as a hornet,
making all kinds of noise.
And when you call him,
you gotta not tell him anything
about this.
You gotta just make sure
everything sounds real normal.
You know, I called the asshole
at four o'clock in the morning.
He wasn't even home.
I don't know what he's got
to be mad about.
I'm the one that should be mad.
Thelma.
I'm going to Mexico.
Now, I figure I can make it
in two and a half days,
but I'm gonna have to haul ass.
Are you up to this?
I mean, I gotta know.
This isn't a game.
I'm in deep shit,
and I gotta know what you're gonna do.
I don't know. I don't know, Louise.
I mean,
I don't know what you're asking.
Now, don't you start flaking out on me!
Goddamn it, Thelma.
Every time that we get in trouble,
you just get blank or...
or plead insanity or some such shit.
Not this time.
I mean, this time things have changed.
Everything's changed.
But I'm goin' to Mexico.
I'm goin'.
Louise?
Is that the way you answer the phone?
I was afraid I missed you.
I... I... I got it.
I was afraid I couldn't get a check cashed
on Saturday.
Who did it?
A friend of mine who owns a club.
Doug Randall.
- You didn't tell him what for, did you?
- No, I didn't say what it was for.
- I told him I was buyin' a car.
- Good. That's real good.
Listen, where do I go?
It's a place called the Vagabond Motel.
It's at 1921 North East 23rd.
It's under Peaches.
What?
That's the code word.
I miss you, Peaches.
Thanks, Jimmy. I appreciate it.
Ma'am, you sure you wouldn't rather
have a large, economy size?
No, no, that's okay.
What are you lookin' at?
- Hey.
I want you to call Darryl.
Call him?
Tell him you're having a wonderful time
and you'll be home tomorrow night.
- Will I be?
- I don't know.
I won't.
The newspaper.
And Witherspoon had a great play.
Watch this right here.
This is Darryl.
I have a collect call from Thelma.
Will you accept?
Why, yes, I will, operator.
Thelma, where in the Sam Hill are you?
I'm with Louise.
We're...
We're in the mountains. We're fishin'.
Have you lost your mind? Is that it?
Now, I leave for work, and you
take complete leave of your senses?
Darryl, calm down, please.
Don't get so mad. I can explain, okay?
- See, Louise...
- Hold on! Hold on!
Oh, come on, Kurt, pick it.
- Kurt knocks the ball loose.
- Pick it!
- Chad Williams's got it.
- Shit! God!
We end up with the ball...
Christ.
We're just gonna stay there and,
you know, fish and hang out and stuff.
We'll just be gone one more day.
We'll be home tomorrow night.
No, you won't. You'll be back today.
You get your butt back here, Thelma, now.
Goddamn it!
Darryl.
Darryl, you're my husband, not my father.
Oh, now, that does it.
That Louise is nothin'
but a bad influence.
If you're not back here by tonight...
Thelma,
well, then I just don't wanna say.
Darryl.
Thelma.
Go fuck yourself.
Oh, that's good. That's just sweet.
- Shit!
- Sorry.
- Darling, you all right?
- Yeah.
- Are you okay? Did I cause that?
- No, I'm sorry.
No? You're okay?
All right.
Is there something I can do for you?
No, it's okay.
Crazy.
Excuse me, ma'am.
May I ask
which direction you're heading?
See, I'm trying to get back to school,
my ride fell through,
and, well, I'm kind of stuck here
like stink on stink.
So I was thinkin' that...
if you're goin' my way
or if I'm going your way...
- I think we're going to Oklahoma City...
- Perfect.
But I'm not sure.
Yeah, well, I'd appreciate it much.
Well, see, it's really not up to me.
It's not my car...
We'd have to ask my friend.
But I... She would probably say no.
She's a little bit uptight.
Maybe it's not such a good idea.
But I tell you what.
I thank you for your time.
But, I mean, I can ask, you know.
It wouldn't hurt nothing.
Well, no, it wouldn't hurt.
Hey.
Louise. Hey, Louise.
This young man here
is on his way back to school,
and I thought since
we're going the same direction,
you know, we could give him a ride, huh?
It's probably not a good idea.
- Louise.
- No, probably not.
But I appreciate your time.
You all have a good day, all right?
Drive safe.
Louise?
Did you see how polite he is?
He was real sweet.
- Thelma.
- What?
Hey, cheer up, now. All right?
Fill her up.
Sure wish we could have
brought him with us.
What'd Darryl have to say?
Oh, he said, okay, Thelma, I just wanted
to make sure you was all right.
I sure hope you're havin' fun.
You deserve it.
After all, you put up with me.
I love you, honey.
So, how long
before we're in goddamn Mexico?
I just didn't think it would hurt
to give somebody a ride.
Did you see his butt?
Darryl don't have a cute butt.
You could park a car
in the shadow of his ass.
I'm sorry. I'm just not
in the mood for company right now.
Here. Take this map.
I need you to find all the secondary roads
to Mexico from Oklahoma City.
I think we should stay off the interstate.
We're too conspicuous.
Looks like we could get
on this Road 81 here
and head down towards Dallas.
I don't want to go through Texas.
Find some way we don't have to
go through there.
Wait. What?
You want to go to Mexico from Oklahoma,
but you don't wanna go through Texas?
Thelma, you know how I feel about Texas!
We're not goin' that way!
Yeah, I know, Louise,
but we're running for our lives.
I mean, can't you make an exception?
I mean, look at this map!
The only thing between
Oklahoma and Mexico is Texas. Look!
Thelma, I'm not gonna talk about this!
Now, you either find another way
or give me the goddamn map and I will!
- You understand?
- No, Louise, I don't.
Now, how come you never told me
what happened to you there?
Look, you shoot off a guy's head
with his pants down,
believe me, Texas is not the place
you wanna get caught.
Now, trust me.
I told you,
I'm not gonna talk about this anymore.
Happy birthday, lady.
You coulda been a cool crook
And, baby, you're so smart
You know you could have been
a schoolbook
Well, you could have been anything
that you wanted to
And I can tell
the way you do the things you do
The way you do the things you do
Is the manager in?
Marian, there's a police officer here.
All right. All right, Thelma. All right.
Okay.
The other night there was a murder
out at the Silver Bullet.
A man was shot.
And we have some witnesses
that saw a 1966 T-Bird convertible
leaving the scene,
sort of speeding
out of the driveway there.
And that vehicle is registered
to one Louise Sawyer.
And we have reason to believe your wife
was the other occupant of that car.
What?
Excuse me.
You're standing in your pizza.
Oh, shit!
So tell me something, Miss Thelma.
How is it you ain't got any kids?
I mean, God gives you somethin' special,
I think you ought to pass it on.
- Well, Darryl... That's my husband.
- Darryl?
Yeah. He says he's not ready yet.
Says he's still too much of a kid himself.
Kind of prides himself on being infantile.
He's got a lot to be proud of.
- Louise and him don't get along.
- That's putting it mildly.
- She thinks he's a pig.
- I know he's a pig.
Did you get married real young,
Miss Thelma?
Well, I guess 18 is kind of young.
But we'd already been going out four years
when we got married.
- How long?
- Four years.
I never been with anybody but Darryl.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Well, if you don't mind me saying so,
he sounds like a real asshole.
It's okay. He is an asshole.
Most of the time, I just let it slide.
You better slow down there, Miss Louise.
That's a cop up ahead.
- Shit.
- Yep.
Maybe you got
a few too many parking tickets?
We'll take you to Oklahoma City.
Then you best be on your way, all right?
All right.
Prints on the trunk of the car
match those of Thelma Dickinson.
Well, I'll be damned.
Isn't that strange?
And the husband says a gun is missing.
She took a lot of stuff.
It looks like she maybe planned
on being gone a while.
The strange thing is, her husband said
she would never touch that gun.
He got it for her
'cause he's out late a lot,
but he said she'd never touch it,
wouldn't learn to shoot it.
Just kept it in a drawer for years.
- What kind of gun was it?
- .38.
Right. Where are they?
They were on their way to some guy's cabin
and they never showed up.
All right.
Now, I'm gonna go and... Listen up.
I'm gonna go in. It's gonna take a minute.
You two better say your goodbyes,
you understand?
All right.
Okay.
- Hi.
I'm here to pick up a money order
for Louise Sawyer.
There's nothing.
How about Peaches?
Could you try code word Peaches?
Did I hear somebody say Peaches?
Oh, my God. Jimmy.
That's the secret word.
Show the lady what she's won, Don.
- What are you doin' here?
- I just came to see you, baby.
Can I have another room, please?
Put it on my credit card.
Thelma. Get your foot down.
Look who's here.
Oh, shit! Jimmy. Hi, stranger.
What in the world are you doin' here?
Ask me no questions
and I'll tell you no lies.
Good answer.
Same goes double for me.
Who's the cowboy?
- Oh, this here... this is J.D.
- How do?
- He's a student.
- He's gone.
We're just giving him a ride to here,
then he... he...
- Louise said that he would have to go, so...
- He's gone.
- I guess that's what he's doing.
- Yeah, I reckon that's what I'm doing.
- He's gone.
- Like the wind.
- Have a good trip.
- Okay.
Thank you.
Nice to meet you.
Yep. Yep, that's him goin'.
I love to watch him go.
Thelma kind of took to him.
Yeah, well,
I got you a room there, Thelma.
You can go on in and take yourself
a nice, cold shower.
Well, you know me, Jimmy.
I'm just a wild woman.
It's our future.
What are you gonna tell him?
Nothin'.
I'm not gonna tell him a thing.
Least I can do is not make him any more
of an accessory than he already is.
You are so sweet to that guy.
You know, you really are.
Imagine not wantin' to drag him into this.
I didn't ask him to come.
He's no different than any other guy.
He just loves the chase, is all.
Well, he sure got his work
cut out for him now, don't he?
Thelma, just put a lid on it!
Now...
I want you to just...
You guard that money.
Okay.
And if there's any problem,
then you call me in Room 211.
Okay.
I won't wait up.
- You want a drink?
- No.
Why don't you tell me what's going on?
I'm not gonna tell you what's goin' on.
Someday soon
you'll understand why I can't,
but I'm not goin' to,
so don't ask me.
- Can I ask you one thing?
- Maybe.
You in love with somebody else?
Does this have somethin' to do
with another man?
No, it's not anything like that.
Well, then what is it, goddamn it?
Are you just gonna leave for fucking ever?
What, did you fuckin' kill somebody?
You start this shit, I'm out of here.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You wanna come back
over there and sit down?
I wanna give you somethin'.
I'm fine right here.
- I wanna give you somethin'.
- Give it to me here.
Here.
Why don't you try it on?
Well, you didn't see
that one comin', did you?
Why, Jimmy?
Why now?
Try not to get too excited, Louise.
I just flew across two states
with that ring in my fuckin' hand and...
You know I hate to fly.
You came all this way
because you thought...
you thought I was with somebody else.
No, that's not why I came.
Because, you know, I...
I don't want to lose you.
And I get the feeling like
you're gonna, like, split permanently.
That's not a good reason to get married.
Well, I thought that's what you wanted.
I did.
But not like this.
Cooking methods.
Questions are encouraged.
The Fort Reno Days Festival highlights...
settler, Indian and military
lifestyles of years past.
And the military contingent boasts
an actual member of the 5th Cavalry.
- Louise?
- No, Thelma, it's me.
Surprise.
I was just out there
and I was thinkin' that...
Well, I know I'm supposed to be gone
and all, but...
You know.
And I'm not havin' a turd's luck
getting a ride out in this rain.
I was just thinkin' about you.
This... This is crazy.
This... I'm...
I'm gonna get out of your hair.
All right? I'm gonna...
Well, wait, wait.
Where you goin'?
I don't know. You know. Nowhere.
You think I'm happy playin'
my one-night gigs in Ramada Inn lounges?
You think you're the only one
with dreams that didn't work out?
We both got what we settled for.
I think maybe
you just don't love me anymore.
No, I do love you.
But I think it's time to just...
let go of the old mistakes.
Just chalk it up to...
bad timin'.
I think it's time to let go.
- Look out. Look out.
- Don't... Don't do it.
Come on.
- What are you doing?
- You're too... Come on. Here.
- All right, all right. I'll do it.
- Your turn.
- Oh, shit. Here we go.
- Come on.
- Well, don't just leave 'em there.
All right.
God. What are you...
You see, this is an unfair advantage.
You got too much metal goin' here.
You wanna lighten the load a little bit?
Yeah?
Yeah.
I think that's better.
What do you think?
- Yeah. Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Take me, break me, make me a man!
- You're gonna hit your head!
- Watch your head! Careful.
- Oh, my head's fine.
Who are you anyway?
I'm the great and powerful Oz.
Who do you want to be?
Come on, tell me.
I know you're not just some schoolboy.
- Nobody ever tells me shit. Tell me.
- Oh, I'm just some guy.
A guy whose parole officer is probably
havin' a shit fit right about now.
What do you mean, parole officer?
Wh... Are you a criminal?
No. No, not no more, Thelma.
Let's see.
Besides bustin' parole,
I haven't done one wrong thing.
- What did you do?
- I'm a robber.
- You're a bank robber?
- No. No. I don't rob no banks. Come on.
What did you rob?
Well, let's see.
Let's add it up here.
I robbed a gas station,
a couple of convenience stores,
liquor stores.
Oh, my God.
How?
- Come on.
- Okay.
First you pick your place, all right?
Then I just sit back
and watch it for a little while,
wait for that right moment
to make my move, see?
That's somethin' you gotta know up here.
That shit cannot be taught.
Yeah, then...
- Oh, shit, I don't wanna talk about this.
- Come on. I do.
All right.
Then I'd waltz right in. Yeah.
And I'd just kind of waltz on in
and I'd say, ladies, gentlemen,
let's see who wins a prize
for keepin' their cool.
Simon says,
everybody down on the floor.
Now, nobody loses their head,
then nobody loses their head.
You, sir. Yeah, you do the honors.
Take that cash,
you put it in that bag right there,
you got an amazing story
to tell your friends.
If not, well, you got a tag on your toe.
You decide.
Simple as that.
Then I just slip on out
and get the hell out of Dodge, yeah.
My goodness.
You were sure gentlemanly about it.
Well, now, I've always believed that,
done properly,
armed robbery doesn't have to be
a totally unpleasant experience.
What?
You're a real live outlaw, aren't you?
Well, I may be an outlaw, darlin',
but you're the one stealin' my heart.
- Oh, smooth.
- Oh, yeah.
- Isn't he? Isn't he?
- Oh, you're smooth.
- That's right.
- Yeah. How did you get that way?
All for you.
Remember when we first met?
Yeah.
What happened? Tell me what you said.
I said you had a nice pair of eyes.
And what'd I say? You remember?
Yeah, you shut 'em.
Asked me if I knew what color they were.
And what did you say?
I didn't know.
Jimmy, what color are my eyes?
They're brown.
Wait. Wait.
Y'all want some more coffee?
Thank you.
Anything else?
Look, I don't know
what's goin' on with you,
or what happened
or what y'all did, but...
I'm not gonna tell anybody anything,
and I'm not gonna say that I even saw you.
Okay?
Damn, Jimmy, what did you do,
take some kind of pill,
makes you say all the right stuff?
Yeah, I'm chokin' on it.
You sure you don't want me
to go with you?
I think it's probably not
a real good idea right now.
But I'll catch up with you later
on down the road.
Yeah.
Well, my taxi is here.
So why don't you just keep that?
- Okay?
- Thanks.
I just want you to be happy.
I am happy, sweetie.
Happy as I can be.
All right.
Well, why don't you give ol' Jimmy
a kiss goodbye?
And I'll be gettin' out of here.
Come here, ol' Jimmy.
I'll be seeing you, Louise.
You have a safe trip.
It's a good thing he left when he did.
We thought we were gonna have to
put out a fire.
Hi.
- What happened to your hair?
- Nothin'. Got messed up.
Thelma, what's wrong with you?
Nothin'.
Why? Do I seem different?
Well, now that you mention it, yeah.
You seem like you're crazy
or you're on drugs.
Well, I'm not on drugs,
but I might be crazy!
Thelma, what happened?
- What happened?
- J.D. came back.
- Oh, my God, Louise. Oh, my God.
- No.
- Oh, no!
- I can't believe it.
- I mean, I just can't believe it!
- No!
Oh, my God, it's like...
I finally understand
what all the fuss is about!
Now it's just like
a whole nother ball game.
Oh, darlin', I'm so happy for you.
That's great. I really am.
You finally got laid properly.
That's so sweet.
- Where is he now?
- He's takin' a shower.
Thelma, you left him alone in the room?
Where's the money?
Oh, my God. Thelma, where's the money?
It's on the bed table.
It's okay.
It's on the nightstand!
Oh, goddamn it!
I've never been lucky! Not one time!
Shit! That son of a bitch burned me.
I don't believe it. I don't believe it.
Louise.
You okay?
I'm sorry. I mean it.
Louise, it's okay.
- It's okay.
- No, Thelma, it's not okay.
It's definitely not okay.
None of this is okay.
I mean, what are we gonna do
for money, huh?
How we gonna get gas?
I mean, tradin' on our good looks?
I mean...
Oh, goddamn it, Thelma,
it's not okay.
Louise.
Hey, now you listen to me.
Don't you worry about it.
You hear me?
Come on. Stand up!
Louise, just don't you worry about it.
You hear?
Come on.
Come on, damn it!
Get your stuff and let's get out of here.
Move!
Jesus Christ, come on. Come on.
Oh, take your damn time.
Come on. Here we go.
Damn, damn.
Afraid of a little rain, Max?
Well, come on in.
Wipe your feet.
As you know, we've tapped your phone
in the event that she calls in.
Wh... Is that gonna cost me?
Excuse me. May I?
Hey, live it up.
That's what it's there for.
We're going to have someone here
at the house on the phones
until we find them.
The important thing is not to let on
that you know anything.
We want to find out where they are.
I don't want to get too personal,
but do you have a good relationship
with your wife?
I... I love Thelma.
I don't intend anything by that, sir.
It's just a question I have to ask.
- Are you close with her?
- Yeah. I guess.
I mean, I'm about as close as I can be
to a nutcase like that.
Yeah, well, if she calls,
just be gentle.
You know, like you're really happy
to hear from her.
Like you really miss her.
Women love that shit.
Okay. If you say so.
I'm sorry. It's just...
Oh, cool. Can I wear these?
Want anything?
Drive, Louise! Drive! Drive the car!
Go! Go! Go, go, go, go, go, go!
What happened?
You robbed the store?
You robbed the goddamn store?
Well, we needed the money.
It's not like I killed anybody,
for God's sake.
- Thelma!
- I'm sorry.
We needed the money.
Now we have it.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Oh, shit, Thelma!
- Louise. Louise.
- Oh, shit!
- Come on, get a grip.
- Shit!
- Drive us to goddamn Mexico, will you?
- Okay.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Well, how... how'd you...
I mean, what did you say?
Well, I...
I just waltzed on in there and I said...
Good mornin', ladies and gentlemen.
This is a robbery.
Now, if nobody loses their head,
nobody will lose their head.
Simon says, y'all lie down on the floor,
please. Right away.
You too.
Ma'am, would you get down?
Not you, sir.
Let's see who will win a prize
for keepin' their cool.
Sir, would you do the honors?
- Take all the cash, put it in a paper bag.
- Yes, ma'am.
You're gonna have
an amazing story to tell your friends.
If not, you'll have a tag on your toe.
You decide.
Hurry up. Let's go.
Ma'am, would you be quiet?
Sir, get down, please.
Thank you. Just stay there.
Just get real comfortable.
Hey, throw in some bottles
of Wild Turkey too, will you?
Yes, ma'am.
- Now, you get down too.
- Yes, ma'am.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I want to thank you all
for your cooperation.
Now, stay down on the floor till I'm gone.
Have a good day.
Jesus Christ!
Good God.
My Lord.
Hey, Louise, better slow down.
I'd just die if we get caught
over a speeding ticket.
You know, for the first time in my life,
I wish this car wasn't green.
You sure we should be drivin' like this
in broad daylight?
No, we shouldn't,
but I want to put some distance between us
and the scene of our last goddamn crime!
Oh, man!
You wouldn't have believed it.
It was like I'd been doin' it all my life.
I mean, nobody would believe it.
- Think you found your callin'?
- Maybe. Maybe.
The call of the wild!
You are disturbed!
Yeah, I believe I am.
Thelma, don't you litter.
Wait a minute. Oh, shoot.
God, I hate when y... This always happens
when you're in a hurry.
Damn. What are you gonna do?
Just stay drunk all day?
Try to.
Oh, isn't that nice?
Truck drivers are always so nice.
Best drivers on the road.
Oh, Lord. How original.
Thank you.
Ew, man. That's disgustin'!
He's a pig! He's a fucking pig!
That's gross!
- What's he gotta do that for anyway?
- I don't know.
They think we like it.
They think it turns us on or something.
Shut up!
James Lennox?
- Yeah. Who wants to know?
- Arkansas State Police.
Hi.
Thelma.
- What?
- I want you to call Darryl.
What for?
I want you to find...
I want you to find out
if he knows anything.
If you think he does,
you gotta hang up the phone.
That means the police have told him,
and the phone's probably tapped.
Tapped the phone?
What are you talkin' about?
Come on, Thelma.
Murder one and armed robbery?
Murder one?
- We can't even say it was self-defense?
- It wasn't.
- We were walkin' away. We got away.
- Yeah, but they don't know that.
It was just you and me there.
I'll say he raped me
and you had to shoot him.
That's almost the truth.
- It won't work.
- Why not?
Because there's no physical evidence.
Can't prove he did it.
We can't even probably prove by now
that he touched you.
God.
The law is some tricky shit, isn't it?
Hey, how do you know
about all this stuff anyway?
Besides, what are we gonna say about
the robbery? There's no excuse for that.
There's no such thing
as justifiable robbery.
All right, Louise, will ya!
Where'd you get this?
Stole it.
Hi.
Hi!
Who's the nut?
- That's Mrs. Dickinson's husband.
- Excuse me.
Well, shit twice and fall back in it.
God.
Where'd you get the $6,600 in cash?
A friend.
We spoke with a gentleman today
who says he delivered very close to
that same amount to a Ms. Louise Sawyer.
Do you know her too?
Yes, sir.
Yeah, I believe
she's the woman drivin' the car.
He said he took it to a motel
in Oklahoma City.
He also says that, at that time,
he met a man.
He identified you
through a series of mug shots.
He also told us
that you and Mrs. Dickinson seemed close.
Is that true?
Well, sir,
you might say we had
a meetin' of the minds, yeah.
Are you aware
that Mrs. Dickinson and Ms. Sawyer
are wanted in connection with a murder?
Murder? What, Thelma? Well, damn!
Did they ever indicate that they might be
on the run from the law?
Well, you know, sir,
now that you mention it,
they might have seemed
a little bit jumpy.
- You know what?
- What?
You're starting to irritate me.
Yeah, me too.
Well, that'll happen.
You two boys have a lot in common.
Maybe I should just step
out of the room for a sec.
I got a better idea.
Do you mind if I speak to him alone
for a minute?
What? What'd I do?
Nothin', that's what.
Tell you somethin',
this is a crock of shit,
Mr. John fucking Law.
Son, I got a feeling about something and...
- Yeah?
- I just wanna ask your opinion.
Do you think Thelma Dickinson
would have committed armed robbery
if you hadn't taken all their money?
Get your foot off that table.
Cat got your tongue?
No. No, I...
Well, how you know I took it?
How you know they didn't...
Don't you fucking lie to me!
There's two girls out there
that had a chance.
They had a chance.
- And now you've screwed it up for them.
- No.
And now they're in some serious trouble.
And I'm gonna hold you
personally responsible
for at least part of it
if anything happens to them.
I got no feelin' for you.
Now, you're either gonna tell me
every damn thing you know,
so there's a small chance
that I can actually do them some good,
or I'm gonna be all over you
like a fly on shit
for the rest of your natural life.
Your miseries
will be my goddamn mission in life.
Yes, sir.
- Okay?
- Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
- We understand each other?
- Yeah.
Okay.
- Mr. Dickinson?
- Yeah?
If you'd just hang on,
I want a word with you.
I like your wife.
- Hey, come back here!
- Hey, hey!
Come back here, you little shit!
I'll...
Come here!
All right, all right, all right.
Come here! Come here!
- Come on!
- Come on, now.
- I'll kill him!
- Come on, now, Darryl.
I'll kill you!
What will it be, ladies?
Fill her up. There you go.
Excuse me. Do you have a phone?
Thank you.
Thelma, listen up, now.
If you even think he knows...
Even if you're not sure,
I want you to hang up.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
Hello.
Darryl, it's me.
Thelma, hello!
- He knows.
- Shit.
I need more time.
What? All I said was hello.
Yep?
Darryl, this is Louise.
Let me talk to the police.
- Hey, Louise.
- Hi.
Let me talk to the police.
There... What do you mean?
There's no police here.
Hey, where are you girls anyway?
Just wait... Darryl, will you let me talk
to whoever is in charge there?
How do you know there's...
Hello, Miss... Miss Sawyer?
I'm Investigator Hal Slocombe,
Arkansas State Police.
- How are you?
- Well, I've been better.
- You be careful with that gun.
- Yes, sir, I know.
You girls are in some hot water.
You both okay? Neither one of you hurt?
Oh, yes, sir, we're... we're fine.
We're both fine.
Good.
- You want to tell me what happened?
- Sure. Over coffee sometime. I'll buy.
I want you to know neither one of you
are charged with murder yet.
You're just still wanted for questioning.
Although now, Mrs. Dickinson is wanted
in Oklahoma for armed robbery.
No kiddin'? Look, we gotta go.
I'll call you back, all right?
I don't think you all
are gonna make it to Mexico.
We should talk.
Please. I want to help you.
Shit.
God, that J.D. kid is a little shit.
What? What?
Thelma, how did they know
we're goin' to Mexico, huh?
How did they know that?
You told that thievin' little shit
where we were goin'?
I just...
I just told him if he ever got to Mexico,
he should look us up.
But I... I just...
I asked him not to tell.
I mean, I... I... I thought
he would not tell anybody, you know.
- Why?
- I didn't think he'd tell anybody.
Why? What's he got to lose?
Except my life savings, of course.
Oh, shit! Thelma, goddamn it!
Look, I'm... I'm sorry.
I mean, I...
Oh, goddamn it, Thelma!
Look, up until now,
we had only two things going for us.
Nobody knew where we were
and nobody knew where we were goin'.
Now one of the things
we had goin' for us is gone!
Look, Thelma,
you just gotta stop talkin' to people.
You gotta stop bein' so open.
We're fugitives now. All right?
Let's start behavin' like that.
- You're right.
- Thank you.
Okay.
I was wondering...
Listen, little boy,
of course I want you to go.
If that's what's worrying you,
please don't think...
No, I wasn't worrying about that.
I knew you'd want me
to take the job, sure, but...
Sorry.
Judy, let's get married.
My God, this is beautiful.
It surely is.
I always wanted to travel.
I just never got the opportunity.
You got it now.
What's going on?
Nothin'.
Shit. Well, we don't need
the East Coast anymore.
Hey, look!
Look who it is. It's that guy.
I'll be darned.
Ignore him.
Hey, baby!
I'm your Captain Muff Diver!
Your storm trooper of love!
Hey!
I ignored him.
What?
- What?
- Harlan.
What about him?
Nothin'.
Just...
Just the look on his face
when...
What?
He sure wasn't expectin' that.
Suck my dick.
Thelma, it's not funny.
I know.
It happened to you, didn't it?
What? What are you talkin' about?
In Texas.
I mean, that's what...
that's what happened, isn't it?
You was raped.
Hey, now, look. I'm warnin' you.
Just drop it.
I'm not gonna talk about that.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
- I'm not talkin' about it.
- Okay.
- You understand?
- Yeah. Okay, Louise.
It's okay.
Oh, shit!
Thelma, we're getting pulled over.
All right.
Shit! Shit! What do you wanna do?
What should we do?
I don't know. I don't know. Oh, shi...
All right, we'll play it by ear.
Maybe he doesn't know.
Maybe he's gonna give me a ticket.
Oh, God.
Oh, God, please don't let us get caught.
God, please, please, God.
Don't let us get caught.
I'm just gonna pull over.
Turn off your engine.
Putting on his hat.
Oh, my God, he's a Nazi.
- What's he doing?
- He's kinda walking this way.
Hello, Officer.
Is there a problem?
You want to let me see
your license, please?
Right.
Here it is.
- You wanna take it out of your wallet?
- All right.
I told you to slow down.
Officer, I told her to slow down.
She did.
- How fast was I goin'?
- About 110.
Fuck.
You wanna get out of the car, please?
Yes, sir. Sure.
Come with me, please.
Yes, sir.
- This your vehicle?
- Yes, sir, that is.
You wanna get in the car, please?
Yes, sir...
- Front or the back?
- Front.
You wanna take off your eyewear, please?
Yes, sir.
Am I in trouble, officer?
As far as I'm concerned,
yes, ma'am, you're in a lot of trouble.
Hello, this is 9-8...
You wanna step back
and get in your car again, please?
Officer, I am so sorry about this,
but would you let go of that?
Now, I really, really apologize,
but would you put your hands
on the steering wheel?
See, if you get on that radio,
you're gonna find out
that we're wanted in two states
and probably considered
armed and dangerous.
At least I am.
And then our whole plan's
just gonna be all shot to hell.
Louise, take his gun.
Take his gun, Louise.
- Right there.
- Right.
I'm real sorry. Excuse me.
You want to step out of the car, please?
Now, I swear, three days ago,
neither one of us would have ever
pulled a stunt like this,
but if you was ever to meet my husband,
you'd understand why.
Wanna put your hands on your head, please?
- Louise.
- What?
- Shoot the radio.
- Right.
The police radio, Louise.
- Jesus Christ!
- I'm sorry.
- Got it.
- Okay.
You wanna step
to the back of the car, please?
- Louise, get the keys.
- Yeah.
What happened?
- What...
- Air holes.
Open the trunk.
Shit, Thelma.
Who would've thought it?
Wanna step into the trunk, please?
Please. I have a wife and kids.
Please!
You do? Well, you're lucky.
You be sweet to 'em,
especially your wife.
My husband wasn't sweet to me.
Look how I turned out.
Now, go on. Get in there.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Wait a second. Excuse me.
Wait a minute.
Officer, could I have your belt, please?
- Extra ammo.
- Good idea.
And... And could I trade glasses
with you maybe?
Thanks. Okay.
Okay. Is that it?
Right.
Officer, I'm real sorry about this.
I apologize also.
Go.
- You ready?
- Hit it.
Now, I know it's crazy,
but I just feel like
I got a knack for this shit.
I believe you do.
Drive like hell.
I can't figure out
whether these girls are real smart
or just real, real lucky.
It don't matter.
Brains will only get you so far
and luck always runs out.
- We still going to Mexico?
- Yeah.
Then aren't we going
in the wrong direction?
Well, I figure
if you take a state policeman,
shoot up his car,
take his gun and lock him in the trunk,
it's best just to get on
out of the state if you can.
I heard that.
Hey! Hey!
Don't dent my car!
I think I fucked up.
I think I got us in a situation
where we both could get killed.
I don't know why I just didn't go
to the police right away.
You know why. You already said.
- What did I say again?
- Nobody'd believe us.
We'd still get in trouble.
We'd still have our lives ruined.
- You know what else?
- What?
That guy was hurting me.
If you hadn't come out when you did,
he would have hurt me a lot worse.
And probably nothin'
would've happened to him
'cause everybody did see me
dancin' with him all night.
They would've made out
like I'd asked for it.
My life would've been ruined
a whole lot worse than it is now.
Least now I'm havin' some fun.
And I'm not sorry
that son of a bitch is dead.
I'm just sorry
it was you that did it and not me.
Hello?
Let me talk to Slocombe.
She wants to talk to you.
- Hello, Louise.
- Hey.
- How are things going out there?
- Weird.
We got some kind of a snowball effect
happening here or somethin'.
You're still with us though.
You're somewhere
on the face of the earth.
Well, we're not in the middle of nowhere,
but we can see it from here.
I swear.
Louise, I almost feel like I know you.
Well, you don't.
You're getting in deeper
every moment you're gone.
Would you believe me if I told you
this whole thing was an accident?
I do believe you.
That's what I want everybody to believe.
Trouble is,
it doesn't look like an accident,
and you're not here to tell me about it.
I need your help here.
- Did Harlan Puckett...
- I don't wanna talk about it.
- You wanna come on in?
- Don't think so.
Then I'm sorry.
We're gonna have to charge you
with murder.
Do you wanna come out of this alive?
You know, certain words and phrases
just keep drifting through my mind.
Things like incarceration,
cavity search, death by electrocution,
life imprisonment.
Shit like that.
You know what I'm saying?
So do I want to come out alive?
I don't know. I...
I don't know. I think we're gonna
have to think about that.
Louise, I'll do anything.
I know what's making you run.
I know what happened to you in Texas.
Come on, Louise.
Don't blow it.
We got it!
Give it to me.
God...
Max, you gotta take me there.
No, Hal, cannot do. Sorry.
- I'm the only one she's ever spoken to.
- You've done a good job.
You're no good to me now.
There's nothing you can do for me now.
I don't want anybody losing their heads!
You know what happens.
The volume gets turned way up,
and the next thing you know,
these girls are gonna get shot!
What?
You're not gonna give up on me, are you?
What do you mean?
You're not gonna make a deal
with that guy?
I mean, I just want to know.
Thelma, I'm not making any deals.
I mean, I'd understand
if you was thinkin' about it.
In a way, you got somethin'
to go back for, Jimmy and all.
Jimmy's not an option.
But...
I don't know, you know,
something's, like, crossed over in me,
and I can't go back.
I mean, I just couldn't live.
I know. I know what you mean.
Anyway, we don't want to end up
on the damn Geraldo show.
Yeah.
They're charging us with murder.
Yeah, they say that we gotta figure out
if we want to come in dead or alive.
Gosh.
Did he say anything positive at all?
You awake?
Guess you could call it that.
My eyes are open.
Me too. I feel awake.
Good.
Wide-awake.
I don't remember ever feeling this awake.
You know what I mean?
Everything looks different.
You feel like that too,
like you got something to look forward to?
We'll be drinking margaritas
by the sea, mamacita.
- We could change our names.
- We could live in a hacienda.
I'm gonna get a job.
I'm gonna work at Club Med.
Yeah.
What kind of a deal is that cop
gonna have to come up with to beat that?
- Have to be pretty good.
- Have to be pretty damn good.
Oh, my God, Louise! Look, look!
Think that's him.
It's him. It's definitely him.
Pass him.
Hey, baby!
You ready for a big dick?
- Hi.
- Hi there. You all right?
We're fine. How are you?
Great!
You girls about ready to get serious?
I think so.
Follow us.
- Where you going?
- Fresno.
We've been seein' you all over the place.
Why don't you take off those shades?
I want to see your eyes.
Yeah, I been seein' you too.
We think you have really bad manners.
Yeah!
Where do you get off behaving like that
with women you don't even know?
How'd you feel if somebody did that
to your mother? Or your sister?
Or your wife?
What are you talkin' about?
You know good and damn well
what I'm talking about.
I mean, really.
That business with your tongue.
What is that? That is disgusting!
And that other shit, pointing to your lap.
What is that supposed to mean exactly?
Pull over. I wanna show you
what a big, fat slob I am?
Or does that mean, suck my dick?
- You women are crazy!
- You got that right.
We think you should apologize.
I ain't apologizing for shit!
You say you're sorry.
Fuck that!
You say you're sorry,
or I'm gonna make you fuckin' sorry.
Oh, Jesus.
I'll bet you even called us beavers
on your CB radio, didn't you?
Yeah. Sure did!
Damn. I hate that.
I hate being called a beaver. Don't you?
You gonna apologize or what?
Fuck you!
Goddamn, you bitch!
- I don't think he is gonna apologize.
- Nah, I don't think so.
You bitches!
You bitches from hell! Goddamn it!
You're gonna have to pay for this!
You're gonna have to pay for that!
I'm gonna make you!
I'm gonna make you pay for this!
You hear me?
Oh, my God!
- Where'd you learn to shoot like that?
- Oh, off the TV.
How about you?
Where'd you learn to shoot like that?
Texas.
Hello! Hello! Hello!
Hello? Hello?
I'm in the trunk. I'm a police officer.
The keys are over there.
D-I-D-10-17-55.
Red hair, brown eyes, 5'7" tall,
120 pounds.
Suspect, Thelma Yvonne Dickinson.
White female...
We got this guy running
around a burning truck.
Red hair, green eyes,
5'10" tall, 130 pounds.
Both subjects armed
and extremely dangerous.
Approach with caution.
New Mexico and Arizona on felony warrants
for armed robbery,
kidnapping a law enforcement officer,
assault with a deadly weapon.
Suspect driving,
Louise Elizabeth Sawyer, white fe...
Think they saw us?
I don't know. I don't think so.
We better get off, just in case.
You got your seat belt on?
This is 1-12. I am in pursuit.
Green Thunderbird. Requesting assistance.
Oh, shit.
We have the suspects in sight.
Continuing pursuit.
Stay in position!
I know this whole thing was my fault.
I know it.
Damn it. If there's one thing you should
know by now, this wasn't your fault!
Louise, no matter what happens,
I'm glad I came with you.
Shit.
Oh, shit.
Did you see that guy?
He was right in the middle of the road!
Hold on!
I guess everything from here on in
is gonna be pretty shitty.
Unbearable, I'd imagine.
Everything we got to lose
is already gone.
Oh, God.
How do you stay so positive?
Get him outta there.
- You're a good friend.
- You too, sweetie. The best.
How do you like the vacation so far?
I guess I went a little crazy, huh?
No, you've always been crazy.
This is just the first chance
you've had to really express yourself.
Good drivin'.
Thanks.
Oh, my God.
What in the hell is this?
I don't know. I think...
I think it's the goddamn Grand Canyon.
Isn't it beautiful?
Yeah. It's something else, all right.
Oh, my God. It looks like the army.
All this for us?
Hey, don't let them shoot those girls!
This is too much.
They got guns pointin' at 'em!
These women are armed, Hal.
This is standard.
Now, calm down.
These boys know what they're doing.
Place your hands in plain view.
Any failure to obey that command
will be considered
an act of aggression against us.
I repeat, turn your engine off
and place your hands in plain view.
What are you doin'?
I'm not givin' up.
Max, you gotta do something!
How many times, Max?
How many times has that woman
got to be fucked over?
Hey, listen!
Will you pull yourself together?
Now, listen to me!
You calm down.
Don't make me sorry I brought you.
Damn it!
I repeat, cut your engine off
and place your hands in plain view!
Okay, then, listen.
Let's not get caught.
What are you talkin' about?
Let's keep goin'.
What do you mean?
Go!
You sure?
Yeah.
Hit it.
Hey!