No!
There she is.
Ladies and gentlemen,
I've traveled over
half our state
to be here tonight.
I couldn't get away sooner
because my new well
was coming in
at Coyote Hills
and I had to see about it.
That well is now flowing
at 2,000 barrels
and it's paying me
an income of $5,000 a week.
I have two others drilling
and I have 16 producing
at Antelope,
so, ladies and gentlemen,
if I say I'm an oilman,
you will agree.
Now, you have
a great chance here,
but bear in mind
you could lose it all
if you're not careful.
Out of all men
that beg for a chance
to drill your lots,
maybe one in 20
will be oilmen.
The rest will be
speculators,
that's men trying
to get between you
and the oilmen
to get some of
the money that ought,
by rights, come to you.
Even if you find
one that has money
and means to drill,
he'll maybe know
nothing about drilling.
He'll have to
hire the job out
on contract,
and then you're
depending on
a contractor,
who'll rush
the job through
so he can get
another contract
just as quick as he can.
This is the way
that this works.
What is your offer?
We're wasting time.
Please!
I do my own drilling.
And the men that work
for me, work for me,
and they are men I know.
I make it
my business to be there
and to see their work.
I don't lose my tools in
the hole and spend months
fishing for them.
I don't botch
the cementing off
and let water in the hole
and ruin the whole lease.
I'm a family man.
I run a family business.
This is my son
and my partner,
H.W. Plainview.
We offer you the bond
of family that very few
oilmen can understand.
I'm fixed like
no other company
in this field
and that's because
my Coyote Hills well
has just come in.
I have a string of tools
all ready to put to work.
I can load a rig onto trucks
and have them here in a week.
I have business connections,
so I can get the lumber
for the derricks.
Such things go by friendship
in a rush like this.
And this is why
I can guarantee
to start drilling
and to put up
the cash to
back my word.
I assure you,
ladies and gentlemen,
no matter what
the others promise to do,
when it comes
to the showdown,
they won't be there.
Sit down! Sit down,
you have no right...
Let us discuss
what the man has to say.
Prescott, do you
trust this man?
Let's discuss
what he has to say.
There's logic
to what he's saying.
How does he know?
My lot is there!
Two or three years,
it could be ten years!
We gain nothing
by losing our heads!
Look at that
well out there!
Nobody's
losing their heads.
You have no business
being here!
Sit that woman down, sir!
You can sit down.
Mr. Plainview!
Please, Mr. Plainview.
No, Mr. Plainview!
No, where are you going?
I don't need
the lease. Thank you.
But we need you.
Too much confusion.
Thank you for your time.
No, no, there's
no confusion.
I wouldn't take
the lease if you
gave it to me as a gift.
Mr. Bankside,
I'm not going to
waste your time.
I'd certainly appreciate it
if you didn't waste mine.
Now, if you wish to sign with
me, we can have a well
drilling within 10 days.
Your lot is
further north from
the discovery well up here.
That means
we'll probably
have to dig deeper.
And if there's as much oil
here as I think there is,
it'll be harder to reach,
but once we find it,
we can take it right out.
We have to act quickly,
because very soon
these fields will be dry.
I need you to know
what you want to do.
Now, because of the distance
from the discovery well,
I'll pay you
a smaller royalty
than you'd get down there
but I'm prepared to give you
a $1,000 bonus on your lot.
What kind of royalty
are you talking about?
One-sixth,
plus a guarantee to start
drilling within 10 days.
Now, that's something
you won't find
anywhere else.
What age are
your children, ma'am?
Ten and twelve.
Mr. Plainview,
a question, sir.
Where is your wife?
She died in childbirth,
Mrs. Bankside.
So it's just me
and my son now.
It's coming in, boss!
Hear it?
Mr. Plainview?
Yes?
Are you Daniel Plainview?
Yes.
What can I
do for you?
You look for oil.
That's right.
What do you pay for
a place that has it?
Well, that depends.
What does it
depend on?
On a lot of things.
If I told you I knew a place
that had oil where land
could be bought cheaply,
what do you think
that would be worth?
Oh, I think that
you should let me know
what you know
and then we'll try
and work something out.
Can I sit down?
Please.
What church
do you belong to?
I...
I enjoy all faiths.
I don't belong to one
church in particular.
I like them all.
I like everything.
Where are you from?
That would be
telling you.
That's what I
want to sell you.
What are you
doing in Signal Hill?
We have oil,
and it seeps
through the ground.
Do you want to pay me
to know where it is?
Just 'cause
there's something
on the ground
doesn't mean
there's anything
beneath it.
Why did Standard Oil
buy up land?
Is it in California?
Maybe.
How much land
did they buy?
I'd like it better
if you didn't think
I was stupid.
Why did you
come to me?
You just brought
this well in.
That's right.
Yes, so just give me
$500 in cash right now
and I'll tell you
where it is.
I'll tell you
what I'll do, son.
I'll give you $100 now,
and if it proves to
be a promising lease,
then give you a $1,000 bonus.
Six hundred dollars.
Tell me one thing
to help me decide.
What else have you
got up there?
What do you grow?
We have a big ranch,
but it's mostly rocks.
Plant things.
Nothing will grow
but weeds.
What makes
you think it's up?
Is there sulfur around?
Or alkali deposits?
Alkali nearby.
I don't know sulfur.
Is that your son?
Yes.
Hi.
Who are you?
I'm Fletcher Hamilton.
Nice to meet you, son.
What's your name?
What do you do?
I work with
Mr. Plainview.
Here's $500, son.
You tell me
something worth hearing,
this money's yours.
I come from a town
called Little Boston
in Isabella County.
This is us, here.
Spur station here
at Little Boston.
The Sunday ranch
is what you're
looking for.
There's a sheep trail
that takes you there.
It's a mile out of town
headed west, not far.
Just through a small pass here
near the base of the hills.
You'll pass a church
and just follow
the sheep trail.
Where's Standard
buying up?
Here and here.
Your family name
is Sunday, yes?
That's right.
How many's
in your family?
My father and
mother and sisters
and my brother Eli.
How many sisters
do you have?
Two.
What's your name?
Paul.
Does any of your family
know about the oil that
you say is there?
I don't know.
My uncle always said
there was oil there,
but I don't know
what they heard
or what they think.
What do you grow?
It's goats.
It's a goat farm.
I told you,
nothing grows
but weeds.
Is there water?
It's salty.
You drill a well,
it's hard not
to get saltwater.
The oil is there.
I'm telling you.
I want to go now, so...
You can stay tonight.
No, I want to go now.
I want to leave.
Listen, Paul.
If I travel all the way
out there and I find that
you've been lying to me,
I'm going to find you
and I'm going to take
more than my money back.
Is that all right
with you?
Yes, sir.
All right, then.
Nice luck to you.
God bless.
And to you,
young man.
- There's someone coming.
- Thank you, Mary.
Good evening.
My name's Daniel Plainview.
This is my son, H.W.
Are you hunting?
Hunting for quail.
We're told there might be
a good place to camp up
near the Sunday ranch.
This is the Sunday ranch.
You can camp here.
Thank you.
Do you have water?
Yes.
We heard
there was an earthquake
up here a few days ago.
Is that right?
Yes.
Your family?
Yeah, all fine.
Thank you.
We have goat's milk,
if you'd like.
That would be fine.
Now,
if we set our tent
away over there,
we'd be out of
your way over there.
That's fine.
Ruth! Help these men
and bring them some water.
No! H.W.
Mr. Plainview,
would you like
that milk now?
That would be fine.
Thank you.
Mary! Bring them
some milk.
My family will
help you set up
your tent.
No, please.
We set ourselves on
this camping trip.
We have to do
the camping.
Hurry up!
Do you have bread?
We have potatoes.
Potatoes would be nice,
thank you.
I'll have them
boil you up
some potatoes.
That's all right.
I thought maybe
we'd make a fire.
I wanted to work
with my son on
making a fire.
All right. My son,
Eli, will bring you
some wood.
Thank you so much
for your hospitality,
Mr. Sunday.
Yes.
And we'll be
out of your way.
We're just hunting
for quail.
Yes.
I'm sorry we
don't have any bread.
No, no, no.
Corn doesn't fill out
in the hills here.
It's mostly rock.
We don't have room
to raise the grain.
Thank you,
young lady.
My name is Eli.
Yes, you're Eli Sunday.
Welcome.
H.W.
Eli.
You're hunting quail?
That's right.
We will bring dinner.
Thank you.
Thank you so much.
Dad!
Dad, look at my shoe.
That's earthquake oil.
Set loose.
So...
So?
So, so.
If there's anything here,
we take it to the sea.
What we do is we build
a pipeline to Port Hueneme
or Santa Paula,
it's about 100 miles,
and we do a deal
with Union Oil.
This is what we do.
Then we don't need
the railroads and their
shipping costs anymore.
You see?
Yeah.
You see that?
Then we're making money.
We're making the real money.
What we should be making.
Not just...
Not just throwing it away
on shipping costs.
Otherwise,
it's just mud.
How much are we
going to pay them?
Who's that?
The Sunday family.
I'm not going to
give them oil prices.
I'll give them
quail prices.
If we could
take a few minutes,
there's something
I'd very much like to
talk with you about.
Mother, would you
take the girls
outside, please?
I believe in
plain speaking, so...
This is a beautiful ranch.
I love hunting for quail.
My boy has been sick,
you know.
He needs fresh air.
Doctors all say
he needs plentiful
fresh air.
So,
what would you say
would be a fair price
for this lot, Abel?
To buy this place?
That's right.
Take a moment.
I'm sorry.
I don't know.
Six dollars an acre.
Six dollars?
Thank you, Eli.
And then with
the improvements
to the ranch over
the years at $500...
I'd like to offer you
$3,700 for this ranch.
That's $3,700.
No.
The Lord has sent
this man here, Eli.
Yes, I believe He has.
My offer to you
is $3,700.
What is it that
brought you here, sir?
The Good Lord's guidance.
Now, of course, within that...
What about our oil?
...we're going to
develop a lease.
What's that?
What about our oil?
Uh, what about it?
We have oil here.
That's worth something.
Oh, do you have someone
who can drill for it?
Do you think
there's oil here?
I know there is.
It's very
expensive to drill.
To get it up and
out of the ground.
You ever tried that before?
How much is it?
Costly.
Well, our oil sits right up
on top of the ground.
I believe that's
called seepage.
Doesn't necessarily mean
there's anything underneath.
What would you
give us for it?
I don't know.
Something you don't know.
That's right.
What would you like, Eli?
Ten thousand dollars.
For what?
For my church.
That's good.
That's a good one.
Well, uh...
If we decide to drill
for oil and if the well
begins to produce,
I'll give your church
a $5,000 signing bonus.
Ten thousand.
Do you want to find
someone else that's going
to come here and drill, Eli?
Make the investment
and do all the hard work
that goes into it?
I can just as easily
hunt for quail on another
ranch as I can here, so...
Though I'll happily be
a supporter of your church
for as long as I can.
For the bonus only.
Now, as it happens,
I do have some connections
in the drilling business
who might help
get us started.
How do you feel
about this, Abel?
Yes. What Eli says.
Well, good! Let's draw up
some contracts and let's...
Let's give it a try.
Appreciate your help
with this, Eli.
-         Good afternoon.
- Good afternoon.
Real estate?
Yes.
Yes, I'd like to
talk to you.
I'm looking for
some land.
I just bought
the Sunday ranch.
And, well,
where's the map?
Where are the hills
behind the Sunday ranch?
That's here.
It's the Bandy tract.
He has over 600 acres.
Bandy, 600.
What about this?
A.C. Maude, Blodget,
Redlick, Carr.
What's it held at?
Six dollars an acre.
Six.
What about this?
That's the Belvins,
and that could
be got, I'm sure.
Can everything
around here be got?
Sure.
Paul Sunday turned out
to be a good friend of ours.
That's right.
Well, you get here
just as soon as you can.
Bring Fred English.
Good enough.
Thank you, porter.
H.W., how are you?
Fine, and you?
Pretty good.
Where's your dad?
He's inside.
You fellas are
a long way from
Signal Hill.
Hello, Plainview.
Hello, Gene.
Good to see you.
Charlie.
On your way
somewhere else?
Passing through.
Looking around.
Funny to see you.
Funny, isn't it?
You boys are a regular
family business.
You boys are
a little late.
What did you find?
I found some
interesting prospects.
Hmm.
Did you hear
Standard bought up?
Mostly in the north, so far.
That's what I hear.
I'm gonna tell you, Gene,
if you're gonna
make a play, look east.
I'd rather it be you
than someone else.
This mud around here
has been taken.
It must be easy when you
have such a cute face
to carry around with you.
Telling me how
handsome my son is?
Well, that I am.
That's very nice.
Thank you.
Good luck, Gene.
Take care.
Like I said, go east.
H.W.
I'll be your lawyer
if you need to
draw up a contract.
Make sure you don't
get swindled, boy.
Get half what
your dad's making.
How's that?
What are those men doing?
They're just guys
that are working for us.
They're just
looking around.
How much money
can we make?
I don't know.
It depends.
One thousand dollars?
Mary said that
her father beats her
if she doesn't pray.
Mary, she's the, uh,
smaller one?
Yes, she is.
Everyone here?
Very successful.
But?
There were a few
vacant lots and
one holdout.
Who?
William Bandy.
...eight. Who's he?
He's an old man
who homesteaded here.
Lives with his grandson.
He said he'd like
to speak with you.
Is he here?
No, he'd like you to
come visit with him.
He's boosting his price.
He said he'd like to
speak with whoever
is doing the buying.
Well, let him wait.
He'll come around.
Let's go.
Ladies and gentlemen?
Ladies and gentlemen.
Thank you so much
for visiting with us
this evening.
Now, I've traveled across
half our state to be here
and to see about this land.
Now, I daresay some
of you might have heard
some of the more
extravagant rumors
about what my plans are,
so I just thought
you'd like to
hear it from me.
This is the face.
It's no great mystery.
I'm an oilman,
ladies and gentlemen,
I have numerous concerns
spread across this state.
I have many wells
flowing at many thousand
barrels per day,
so I like to think of
myself as an oilman.
As an oilman,
I hope that
you'll forgive
just good old-fashioned
plain speaking.
Now, this work that we do
is very much
a family enterprise.
I work side by side
with my wonderful son, H.W.
I think one or two of you
might have met him already.
And I encourage my men
to bring their families,
as well.
Of course, it makes
for an ever so much more
rewarding life for them.
Family means children,
and children means education.
So, wherever we set up camp,
education is a necessity,
and we're just so happy
to take care of that.
So let's build
a wonderful school
in Little Boston.
These children are
the future that
we strive for,
and so they should have
the very best of things.
Now, something else,
and please don't be insulted
if I speak about this. Bread.
Let's talk about bread.
Now, to my mind, it's an
abomination to consider
that any man, woman,
or child in this
magnificent country of ours
should have to look upon
a loaf of bread as a luxury.
We're going to dig
water wells here,
and water wells
means irrigation.
Irrigation means cultivation.
We're going to raise crops
here where before it just
simply wasn't possible.
You're going to have
more grain than you'll
know what to do with,
and bread will
be coming right
out of your ears, ma'am.
New roads, agriculture,
employment, education.
These are just
a few of the things
we can offer you,
and I assure you,
ladies and gentlemen,
that if we do find oil here,
and I think there's
a very good chance
that we will,
this community of yours
will not only survive,
it will flourish.
I'd be happy to
answer any questions
that you might have. Yes?
Will the new road
lead to the church?
That'll be the first
place that it leads.
Thank you, Eli. Anyone else?
Well, if anything comes up,
I'm pretty easy to find.
You just come visit with me.
Thank you so much
for your time,
and good night.
♪ What a privilege
to carry
♪ everything to God
in prayer!
♪ What a privilege
to carry... ♪
Just follow the new road
right to the church.
The new road
will lead you there.
Hello, brother,
my name is Eli.
The Church of
the Third Revelation
welcomes you.
Hello, brother,
my name is Eli.
The Church of
the Third Revelation
welcomes you.
Just follow the new road
right to the church.
♪ Jesus knows our
every weakness
♪ Take it to the Lord
in prayer
♪ Are we weak
and heavy-laden
♪ Cumbered with
a load of care?
♪ Precious Savior
still our refuge
♪ Take it to the Lord
in prayer... ♪
Daniel, may I
speak with you?
Yes, come in.
I'll bring them up
when they arrive.
Good morning.
How is all
the work coming?
Everything's good.
All the men are
provided for?
Of course.
Spirits seem high.
Is there anything
that you need from me?
Anything the church
can do for you?
I don't believe so.
No. Thank you.
I understand you've
asked the people
to gather around
and watch the well
begin tomorrow.
Is that right?
That's right.
I will bless the well.
Before you begin,
you should introduce me.
You'll see me walk up
towards the oil well,
and when I...
The derrick.
You'll see me walk up,
and then you could
say my name.
When you walk up?
Yes. You'll see me walk up,
and then you could say,
"The proud son of
these hills who tended
his Father's flock,"
and then you
could say my name.
That's fine.
And what happens then?
Well, then we start the drill.
It's a simple blessing,
Daniel, but an important one.
It's just a few words.
It won't take long.
What time?
What time's
good for you, Eli?
4:00.
Well, let's make it
4:00 then.
My thanks for your visit.
Good day. Thank you.
Afternoon,
everyone.
Come with me.
I thank you all so much
for visiting with us
at this time.
I've had the pleasure of
meeting some of you
and I hope very much in
the months to come,
I'll be able to visit with
each and every one of you.
I'm better at digging
holes in the ground
than making speeches,
so let's forget the speech
for this evening,
just make it
a simple blessing.
You see, one man
doesn't prospect
from the ground.
It takes a whole
community of good people,
such as yourselves,
and this is good.
We stay together.
We pray together,
we work together,
and if the Good Lord
smiles kindly on
our endeavor,
we share in
the wealth together.
Now, before we spud in
Mary's Well Number One,
named for the lovely
Miss Mary Sunday,
here by my side,
a proud daughter
of these hills,
I'd just like to say God bless
these honest labors of ours,
and, of course,
God bless you all.
Amen.
Now go.
Won't be a minute.
Fast as you can, H.W.
Are you ready
to do this?
That's it,
ladies and gentlemen!
Al Rose has very generously
provided some refreshments
for this occasion
out of his own pocket.
Thank you, Al.
If you'll all just
care to help yourselves,
I'll be back in a minute.
Mary. Oh...
Mary Sunday.
Do you like
your new dress?
Yes. Thank you.
You're welcome.
I thought you'd like it.
Are you happy
I came here?
Yes.
Your daddy doesn't
hit you anymore,
does he? Does he now?
Better not, right?
I'll take care of you.
No more hitting, right?
No more hitting. Now go.
Go and play some more
and don't come back.
Daniel?
It's okay, H.W.
Go back to sleep.
Go on. Go back to sleep.
Daniel.
Daniel!
What?
Lost a man
down the well.
What man?
Joe Gundha.
Did I know him?
No.
What happened?
Pick it up.
Set the brake.
Tie it down.
Tie it on.
Shit!
God damn it.
Where's the body?
They're
fishing it out now.
All right.
Where's the bit?
It's on the deck.
Clean him up.
Put some clothes on him.
And...
Set up a tent.
Anyone goes down
into the cellar,
you tell somebody. Yes?
Yes, sir.
Shut down till midday.
And I had a vision.
Yes, last night,
I had a vision
and I felt God's breath
move through me.
And it rolled down
into my stomach.
It sloshed around.
And my stomach
spoke in a whisper,
not a shout,
"Touch this woman
with your hands
and caress her." Yes.
My dear Mrs. Hunter,
you have arthritis,
don't you?
Yes, I do, Eli.
Yes.
The devil is in your hands,
and I will suck it out.
Now, I will not
cast this ghost out
with a fever
for the new spirit inside me
has shown me I have
a new way to communicate.
It is a gentle whisper.
Get out of here, ghost.
Cast out.
Get out.
Get out of here, ghost.
...and enter this
woman's body now.
Get out of here, ghost.
Get out of here.
Don't you dare turn
around and come back.
For if you do,
all the armies of my boot
will kick you in the teeth
and you will be cast up
and thrown in the dirt
and thrust back
to perdition!
And as long as
I have teeth,
I will bite you,
and if I have no teeth,
I will gum you!
And as long as
I have fists,
I will bash you!
Now, get out of here, ghost!
Get out of here, ghost!
And it left!
- Hallelujah!
Praise the Lord
and his holy days!
Praise God!
Amen! Thank you.
Thank you, Jesus.
Thank you, God.
My dear Mrs. Hunter.
Dance with me.
Aw!
Dance.
Thanks for coming.
It was a wonderful sermon.
Will I see you tomorrow?
Yes.
Eli.
Had a tragedy at
the well last night.
Yes, I heard.
Joe Gundha was a man
of considerable faith.
So if you wish to
say a few words,
his burial is
at noon tomorrow.
Daniel, this accident
could have been avoided.
It is terrible to
think of that well
working away out there...
These men work
in 12-hour shifts.
...unblessed.
They need their rest.
If they don't have it,
they start to make
stupid mistakes.
I've seen the men drinking.
Don't you think that has
something to do with this?
We need these men
well-rested to
bring in this well.
They can't get that
if they're up here
listening to your gospel,
and then the well can't
produce and blow gold
all over the place.
I wish I had more time
with Joe Gundha.
More could have been done.
Then the well can't
produce and blow gold
all over the place.
Now, would you see to it
that his personal possessions
find their way
back to his family, please?
Thank you.
Heard you were planning
some renovations.
Yes, our congregation
is growing strongly.
We need more room.
That was one goddamn
hell of a show.
We were happy to
have you, Daniel.
Gas, gas, gas!
Lights out! Wait here.
Wait here. Lights out!
Put that fire out!
Is he hurt? H.W.!
Hand him down to me!
Hand him down!
Here.
Got him?
I've got him!
Oh, God.
Come on.
Open the door.
Let go. There you go.
You're safe. You're safe.
You're safe now.
I got you here.
You're safe. Let go, son.
Tell me where it hurts.
Tell me where...
- Did you see this?
- No.
Tell me where it hurts.
Where does it hurt you?
I can't hear my voice.
Were you hit
in the head?
in the head? Tell me!
You have to tell me
if you were!
I can't hear my voice.
I have to go and
deal with this now.
You wait here for me.
You understand?
I'll be back.
I'll be back
in a minute.
Wait here.
Don't leave!
I'm going to
take care of you. Wait.
Stay here, son.
I'm going to fix this.
Don't leave!
You're going to be fine!
Wait for me here!
Hold him down.
Don't leave!
Got to break
the cables, Daniel!
Get me a hammer!
Here you go.
Get back!
Michael!
Sir!
Take Dave and two
of the fellas,
pick up some hoses...
Billy, protect the roof.
Don't wait before
it gets too hot.
What are you looking
so miserable about?
There's a whole ocean
of oil under our feet!
No one can get at it
except for me.
H.W. okay?
No, he isn't.
Where is he?
Mess room.
Ah.
That's enough now.
That's enough, H.W.
That's enough.
Do you hear me?
Can you hear me in there?
That's enough.
- Grab his legs.
- I have his legs.
No. Nope.
No, lad.
Give me that.
Steady. That's it.
Easy, boy. Easy.
Soon be over.
Yeah, and that's good.
Now the other side.
Turn him over.
Almost done.
That's it.
Come here.
It's over. It's over.
Who do we know
in San Francisco
or Los Angeles,
who could work with...
You know, we could...
Someone, a teacher for H.W.
How could you
figure out that?
Now, call...
God damn it,
what's his name?
Bob Brody
in San Francisco?
Call Bob Brody
and get someone
down here.
I'll do it right away.
When do we get
our money, Daniel?
Aren't you a healer?
And a vessel for
the Holy Spirit?
When are you coming over
and make my son hear again?
Can't you do that?
If you had let
me bless the well,
this wouldn't have happened.
Daniel.
You shouldn't have
done that.
You owe the Church of
the Third Revelation $5,000
as part of the arrangement
that we made!
Don't even try it,
you little runt!
You splash around in here.
That's it,
that's it.
I'm going to
bury you underground, Eli.
Oh. Oh.
I'm going to
bury you underground.
You are a stupid man, Abel.
You've let someone
come in here and
walk all over us.
You let him in
and do his work here,
and you are a stupid man
for what we could have had.
I followed
His word, Eli.
I tried.
You didn't do
anything but sit down.
You're lazy,
and you're stupid.
Do you think God
is going to save you
for being stupid?
He doesn't save
stupid people, Abel.
I will tear you apart
for what you've done,
you stupid man!
How did he come here?
Do you really know? I know!
Son, don't do this, please!
Be quiet!
Shut your mouth, Abel!
It was your stupid son!
It was Paul who told him
to come here. I know it.
He went to him and he said,
"My stupid, weak father
will give away his lots.
"Go and take him."
And you let it happen.
A stupid father
to a stupid son.
Get out of there!
Can I help you?
Daniel?
Who's that?
My name is Henry.
Yeah?
I'm Henry.
What can I do for you?
I'm Henry Plainview.
I'm from Fond du Lac.
I'm your brother,
from another mother.
Ernest is my father.
Who are you?
Henry.
Mary Branch?
Is that your mother?
Yes, sir,
that's right.
I read about your
gusher in the paper,
about your success.
You heard
about my strike?
You just show up?
Our father's dead.
Ernest died, I heard.
I wanted to find you.
When?
Three months ago.
I got a letter
from Annabelle.
My sister,
Annabelle?
Where is she?
Still at home.
Fond du Lac.
You came all the way
from Wisconsin to
tell me this?
I'm coming from
New Mexico.
I've been there.
I came to find you.
Did you know about me?
Do you have
identification?
this letter?
Where are you
coming from?
From New Mexico.
Yes, I know,
but from where?
Silver City.
I've been there
for two years.
I was trying drilling
of my own for years.
Getting leases in Texas.
Louisiana.
Anything that produced?
No.
Not like your success, no.
Are you married?
No.
I spent time in jail.
I had a stretch of
very bad time.
I had nothing.
I was picked up
in Louisiana.
I worked on a chain gang
for six months
building roads.
That was a very hard time.
Are you married?
What were you
in jail for?
Believe it or not,
for all the terrible things
I've gotten myself into,
when they picked me up,
I hadn't done anything.
But I've done
my share of things
that shouldn't
be talked about.
Drink it.
Drink it!
Come on.
So...
What do you want, Henry?
Nothing.
If you can
spare something,
I can work for
you in any way.
I know I'll keep moving,
before long, to get back
to Fond du Lac.
Do you have
any money?
Some.
Not much.
Just answer me directly.
You say "nothing,"
then you say you'd
like to stay and work.
And it's better, I'd just
like to hear you say
you'd like to be here.
I'd like to be here.
I'm a good worker.
I worked cable tool rigs,
built railroads.
I won't need any favors.
Good.
What did
my mother know?
I don't know.
I don't know if she knew
and looked the other way,
if she never knew.
Why did you leave?
I know you didn't
get on with our father.
I worked for
Geological Survey
and went to Kansas.
I couldn't stay there.
I just couldn't.
I don't like to
explain myself.
Are you an
angry man, Henry?
About what?
Are you envious?
Do you get envious?
I don't think so, no.
I have a competition in me.
I want no one else
to succeed.
I hate most people.
That part of me
is gone.
Working and not succeeding,
all my failures
have left me...
I just don't care.
Well, if it's in me,
it's in you.
There are times when
I look at people and
I see nothing worth liking.
I want to earn enough money
I can get away from everyone.
What will you do
about your boy?
I don't know.
Maybe it'll change.
Does your sound
come back to you?
I don't know.
Maybe no one knows that.
Doctor might not know that.
Where's his mother?
I don't want to talk
about those things.
I see the worst
in people, Henry.
I don't need to
look past seeing them
to get all I need.
I've built up my
hatreds over the years,
little by little.
Having you here gives me
a second breath of life.
I can't keep
doing this on my own
with these people.
Daniel! Daniel,
wake up! Daniel!
Uh...
Just have to go
and have a word
with the conductor.
I'll be right back.
You stay here.
You understand?
I'll be right back.
H.W.!
No! No!
No!
Tilford!
Plainview.
This is my brother,
Henry Plainview
from Fond du Lac.
H.M. Tilford.
Pleasure.
Henry Plainview.
J.J. Carter.
So...
Shall we?
Yes.
How's your boy?
Thank you for asking.
Is there anything
we can do?
Thanks for asking
is enough.
So what are your plans?
Is this about buying up
my tracts here?
Yes.
The cable was about
my Coyote Hills lease.
We'd like that, too.
What's your offer
on Coyote Hills?
We'll offer
150,000 for
full title.
That's a deal.
What's next?
You have 11,000 acres
in Little Boston.
You have one proven well
that was damaged...
I have three wells proven.
You haven't been
paying attention.
That's three proven wells.
We'll make you a millionaire
while you're sitting here
from one minute
to the next.
And what else
would I do
with myself?
Are you asking me?
What else
would I do
with myself?
Take care of your son.
I don't know
what you would do.
If you were me
and Standard offered
to buy what you had
for a million dollars,
why? So, why?
You know why.
Yeah, you fellas
should just scratch
around in the dirt
and find it like
the rest of us,
instead of buying up
someone else's hard work.
I've scratched
around the dirt, son.
You going to change
your shipping costs?
We don't dictate
shipping costs.
That's railroad business.
Oh, you don't
own the railroads?
'Course you do.
Of course you do.
Where you going
to put it all?
Where?
Build a pipeline?
Make a deal with
Union Oil? Be my guest.
But if you
can't pull it off,
you've got an ocean
of oil under your feet
with nowhere to go.
Why not turn it over to us?
We'll make you rich.
You spend time
with your boy.
It's a great discovery.
Now, let us help you.
Did you just tell me
how to run my family?
It might be more
important now that
you've proven the field
and we're offering
to buy you out.
One night
I'm going to come to you,
inside of your house,
or wherever you're sleeping,
and I'm going to
cut your throat.
What?
What are you talking about?
Have you gone crazy?
Did you hear
what I said?
I heard what you said,
why did you say it?
You don't tell me
about my son.
Why are you acting insane
and threatening
to cut my throat?
You don't tell
me about my son.
I'm not telling you anything!
I'm asking you
to be reasonable.
If I've offended you,
I apologize.
You'll see what I can do.
This parcel here is
the 3,000-acre ranch
owned by B.L. Harper.
This is San Luis
Obispo County land.
And from here to the coast,
it's all Union Oil.
What's this?
Why don't I own this?
That's the Bandy tract.
He was the holdout,
when we were
doing the buying.
He had hoped to
speak with you.
Can't you just
build the pipeline
around this tract?
Can I build around 50 miles
of Tehachapi mountains?
Don't be thick in
front of me, Al.
I can go to him again.
No, I'll go and talk
to the man.
I'll talk to him.
Show you how it's done.
All right.
Pack it up, Henry.
How big is his room?
He's sharing
with another boy.
Who?
An older boy.
About 12.
He's been there
for a year.
Named Ballard.
How big is the room?
Oh, it's a fair size.
Got enough space.
Are you taking Henry
with you to meet Union Oil?
Are you the son
of William Bandy?
Grandson.
Is he here?
No, he's out.
Where is he?
Told you, he's out.
Now, what do you want?
I'm Daniel Plainview.
I want to talk with him
about his property.
About what?
I believe I'll talk
with him about that.
You're that oilman,
aren't you?
That's right.
We don't want you
drilling out here.
I don't want it either.
Now, when will he be back?
Few days.
Tell him I'd like
to speak with him.
Not about drilling.
And I'll be back
in a week.
Put that in a glass case.
Here's to Union Oil.
Hundred miles of pipeline,
and all the independent
producers of this great state.
Cheers.
There's that house
in Fond du Lac
that John Hollister built.
Do you remember it?
Mmm.
I thought as a boy
that was the most beautiful
house I'd ever seen,
and I wanted it.
I wanted to live in it.
And eat in it.
And clean it.
And even as a boy,
I wanted to have children
to run around in it.
You can have anything you'd
like now, Daniel.
And you should.
Where are you
going to build it?
Here, maybe.
Near the ocean.
Would you make it
look like that house?
I think if I saw
that house now,
it'd make me sick.
We can eat and
get some women.
Take them to
the Peachtree dance.
I say get liquored up
and take them to
the Peachtree dance.
Yeah.
Can I have
some money, please?
I want you to
tell me something.
What?
What's the name of the farm
next to the Hill House?
What was the name of the farm
I can't remember...
Who are you?
I'll leave, Daniel.
I'm no one.
Just let me
get up and go.
Do I have a brother?
I met a man
in King City who said
he was your brother.
We were friends
for months.
Working in King City.
And he wanted
to make his way
to you, Daniel.
We didn't have any money.
He died of tuberculosis.
He wasn't harmed.
Wasn't killed,
nothing bad.
But he told me about you,
and I just took his story,
used his diary.
Daniel.
Daniel, I'm your friend.
I'm not trying to hurt you.
Never.
Just survive.
No!
Who is it?
I'm Bandy.
Yes. Yes.
Um...
William Bandy.
Yeah, I'd like to
lease your land.
I had asked for you
to come and talk
to me before.
When you were
leasing land.
That's right, yes.
My boy's been
very sick, you know.
This was before
your boy got sick.
Now, I know that
you would like to
build a pipeline
through my property.
Is that right,
what I've heard?
It's absolutely right.
And, uh,
well...
Eight inch pipe.
It could be buried
with your consent.
I guarantee you
absolutely no disruption...
God.
God has told me
what you must do.
And what is that?
You should be washed
in the blood of Jesus Christ.
Oh, but I am.
I have been washed,
Mr. Bandy. I have been.
It's your only way
to salvation.
And your only way
for what you want.
You can take it
at the Church of
the Third Revelation.
I'll pay you $3,000.
I'd like you to be
part of our church.
I'll pay you $5,000.
Be baptized.
Be forgiven for the sin
that you've done.
What sin are you
referring to, Mr. Bandy?
My sin of drilling?
I truly wish
everyone could be
saved, don't you?
Yes.
I am afraid that's
just not the case.
The doctrine of
universal salvation
is a lie, is it not?
It's a lie.
I wish everyone could be
saved, but they won't.
No, they won't.
You will never
be saved if you...
Reject the blood.
Good.
Now, is there a sinner here
looking for salvation?
A new member?
I'll ask it again.
Is there a sinner here
looking for God?
Yes.
Oh.
Allow me.
Thank you for coming,
brother Daniel.
Thank you, Eli.
We have a sinner with us here
who wishes for salvation!
Daniel, are you a sinner?
Yes.
The Lord can't
hear you, Daniel.
Say it to him. Go ahead
and speak to him.
It's all right.
Yes.
Down on your knees.
Pray to him.
Look up to the sky
and say it.
What do you
want me to say?
Daniel, you've come here
and you've brought
good and wealth,
but you have also brought
your bad habits
as a backslider.
You've lusted after women,
and you have abandoned
your child.
Your child,
that you raised,
you have abandoned
all because he was sick
and you have sinned.
So say it now.
I am a sinner.
Say it louder.
Louder, Daniel!
I am a sinner!
I am a sinner.
I am sorry, Lord.
I want the blood.
You have abandoned
your child.
I have abandoned my child.
I will never backslide.
I was lost,
but now I am found.
but now I'm found.
I have abandoned my child.
Say it.
I abandoned my child.
Say it louder.
Say it louder!
I've abandoned my child!
I've abandoned my boy!
Now beg for the blood!
Just give me the blood, Eli.
Let me get out of here.
Give me the blood, Lord,
and let me get away!
Do you accept Jesus Christ
as your Lord and Savior?
Yes, I do.
Get out of here, devil!
Out, devil! Out, sin!
Let me feel the power
of the Lord, Eli.
Do you accept
the Church of
the Third Revelation
as your spiritual guide?
Get out of here, ghost!
Where is your Lord, Eli?
Get out! Go back
where you belong!
Where is he? There he is!
Do you accept
Jesus Christ
as your Savior?
Yes, I do.
♪ Would you be free
from the burden of sin?
♪ There's power in the blood
♪ Power in the blood
♪ Would you o'er evil
a victory win?
There's a pipeline.
♪ There's wonderful
power in the blood
♪ There is power, power
wonder-working power
♪ In the blood of the Lamb ♪
Praise the Lord!
Welcome to the fold,
brother Plainview.
Welcome,
brother Daniel. God bless you.
God bless you.
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
Welcome home,
brother.
That's enough.
That's enough, now.
He must take the spirit
in on his own.
We have a new member.
Yes, brother.
Hallelujah.
- Hallelujah.
- Amen.
My sweet Mary.
Mr. Plainview
has been generous
enough to make
a $5,000 donation
to the church
which we are
still waiting for.
Oh, that does me good.
That does me good.
Welcome home, son.
This here's
George Reynolds.
Teacher from the deaf school.
- Mr. Plainview.
- Fletcher.
You're
too heavy for me.
Do you
want to get something to eat?
That's the pipeline, see?
All the way to the sea.
Come here.
I love you, son.
Let's take
a look at you.
All right. That's it,
that's it. That's it.
Uh...
Let's get some
decent food
inside of you.
That's all we need here
is a good, strong,
expensive meal.
You hungry?
Waiter?
Yes, sir.
Two steaks, a whiskey,
and water for him.
And goat's milk.
Very good, sir.
We're going to have
this teacher help you.
He's going to help take care
of all of this. Understand?
'Cause I need you.
Need your help.
Got everything we need now
to build this company.
Come here.
Good afternoon.
How are you doing?
It's nice to see
you again.
We need four.
I'll have them
right up.
Good afternoon, Daniel.
Oh, Tilford.
Good afternoon.
Hello! H.M. Tilford!
You don't have to shout.
Pleasure.
Ah,
it's good to be
in Little B.
Could use some
rain out here.
Yeah, we could.
There we go.
R.J., how's
the London broil?
Believe we ordered
these drinks before
those people.
R.J., tell us.
How's the London broil?
Excuse me,
gentlemen. Sorry.
I am sorry about
that, sir. I'll have
your steaks right out.
So that green
turtle soup is fantastic.
Is it?
It's delicious.
Sounds good to me.
So Standard offered us
a million dollars for
the Little Boston leases.
I told H.M. Tilford
where he could shove that.
And we made a deal
with Union!
On the pipeline!
And that whole ocean of oil
underneath our fields.
...$150,000.
Yes.
We needed
the money to drill.
- Who is this guy?
-        I go out       to meet him.
He's getting oil
on the property.
We're trying to
make a claim on it.
Offered him
a million dollars.
Turned us down flat.
Well, I'm hungry.
Orange fritters,
mashed potatoes, green peas.
All the way around?
All right.
Hold on.
I want you to
look over there.
Daniel, let me introduce...
Look over there. You see?
That's my son.
See him?
Yes.
Do you see?
I see him.
You don't tell me
how to raise my family.
I told you not to tell me
Daniel...
So what do you see?
I'm very happy for
you that the deal...
Yes, I made a deal with Union.
My son is happy.
He's safe.
Congratulations.
I'm taking care
of him now, so...
Excellent.
You look like a fool,
don't you, Tilford?
Yes.
Yes, you do.
Excuse me,
gentlemen.
Oh, excuse me, gentlemen.
Excuse him, gentlemen.
I told you what
I was going to do.
My son.
Mr. Sunday, I understand
that you're leaving
our fair community.
Yes, I'm going
on a mission.
Where you going?
Oildale, Taft,
and then on to
Bakersfield.
Well, I want you to know...
Three quarters
of an hour.
...you done
a great job for us.
Thank you.
You will be in
my prayers.
I thank you very much.
Union Oil Company,
Santa Paula, California.
"The woman saith unto him,
'Sir, give me this water
"'and I shall thirst not,
neither come hither to draw.'"
Come in, come in.
Can we be alone?
This is my closest associate.
He hears everything.
I'd prefer
to speak to you in private.
You can't speak.
So why don't you
flap your hands about
and have what's-his-name
tell me where you've been.
Or do you think
I don't know?
This is hard
for me to say.
I'll tell you first,
I love you very much.
I've learned to
love what I do
because of you.
I'm leaving here.
I'm going to Mexico.
I'm taking Mary,
and I'm going to Mexico.
I miss working outside.
I miss the fields.
It'll only be for a time,
for me to do
my own drilling
and start my own company.
It's time to
make a change.
This makes you
my competitor.
No. No,
it's not like that.
It is like that, boy.
Your own company, huh?
That's right.
In Mexico?
Yes.
You are making
such a misstep.
So, what are you doing?
I know you and I
have disagreed
over many things.
I'd rather keep
you as my father
than my partner.
Then say it.
If you've got something
to say to me, then say it.
I'd like to hear you speak
instead of your little dog.
I'm going to
Mexico with my wife.
I'm going away from you.
That wasn't so hard, was it?
Killing us with
what you're doing.
You're killing my image
of you as my son.
You are stubborn.
You won't listen.
You're not my son.
Please don't say that.
I know you don't mean it.
It's the truth.
You're not my son.
You never have been.
You're an orphan!
Did you ever
hear that word?
Tell him what I said.
You operated here
today like one.
I should have seen
this coming.
I should have known that,
under this all,
these past years
you've been building
new hate for me,
piece by piece.
I don't even know
who you are because
you have none of me in you.
You're someone else's.
This anger.
Your maliciousness.
Backwards dealings with me.
You're an orphan
from a basket in
the middle of the desert.
And I took you for
no other reason
than I needed
a sweet face to buy land.
Did you get that?
So now you know.
Look at me!
You're lower
than a bastard.
Mmm-hmm.
You have none of me in you.
You're just a bastard
from a basket.
I thank God
I have none of you in me.
Not my son.
Just a little piece
of competition.
Bastard from a basket.
Bastard from a basket!
You're a bastard
from a basket!
Get up, Mr. Daniel.
Mr. Daniel.
Mr. Daniel,
you've got a visitor.
Wake up, Mr. Daniel.
Sir?
You can leave us now.
Daniel.
Daniel Plainview,
the house is on fire!
Brother Daniel,
it's Eli.
Yes, it is.
I'll make us a drink.
Oh, your home is a miracle.
It's beautiful.
God bless it.
I've been spreading
His word far and wide.
Far and wide.
So much travel for Him.
I've been working in radio.
Yes, so much...
So much has been happening.
To be here and find you
and see you well is wonderful.
And we have
a chance to catch up.
No. Thank you so much.
Oh.
My brother.
Daniel, my brother
by marriage.
We're such old friends.
So much time.
Things go up,
things go down,
but at least
the Lord is always around.
We've seen ups and downs,
haven't we?
Are things down
for you right now, Eli?
No. No.
But I do come
with some sad news.
Perhaps you remember
Mr. Bandy?
Mr. Bandy has
passed on to the Lord.
He lived to be 99 years old,
God bless him.
Mr. Bandy has a grandson.
Have you met
his grandson,
William?
William Bandy is one of
the finest members we have
at the Church of
the Third Revelation.
He's eager to
come to Hollywood
to be in movies.
He is very good-looking.
And I do think
he will have success.
That's wonderful.
Would you like me
to speak with him?
Daniel, I'm asking
if you'd like
to have business
with the Church of
the Third Revelation
in developing this lease
on young Bandy's
1,000-acre tract.
I'm offering you to drill
on one of the great
undeveloped fields
of Little Boston.
I'd be happy to
work with you.
You would?
Yes, yes, of course.
That's wonderful.
But there is
one condition
for this work.
All right.
I'd like you to tell me
that you are a false prophet.
I'd like you to
tell me that you are,
and have been
a false prophet.
And that God is
a superstition.
But that's a lie.
It's a lie.
I cannot say it.
When can we begin to drill?
Very soon.
How long will it take
to bring in the well?
It shouldn't take long.
I would like
a $100,000
signing bonus,
plus the five
that is owed to me
with interest.
That's only fair.
I am a false prophet,
and God is a superstition.
If that's what you believe,
then I will say it.
Say it like you mean it.
Daniel.
Say it like
it's your sermon.
Don't smile.
I am a false prophet.
God is a superstition.
Why don't you stand up?
Put your glass down.
I am a false prophet.
God is a superstition.
Eli, stop.
Just imagine this
is your church here
and you have a full
congregation, so...
I am a false prophet.
God is a superstition.
Say it again.
I am a false prophet.
God is a superstition.
They can't hear you
at the back.
I am a false prophet.
God is a superstition.
Say it again.
I am a false prophet!
God is a superstition!
Say it again.
I am a false prophet!
God is a superstition!
Those areas
have been drilled.
What?
Those areas,
they've been drilled.
No, they haven't.
Yes, it's...
It's called drainage, Eli.
See, I own everything
around it, so, of course,
I get what's underneath it.
But there are no
derricks there.
This is the Bandy tract.
Do you understand?
Do you understand, Eli?
That's more to the point.
Do you understand?
I drink your water.
I drink it up every day.
I drink the blood of Lamb
from Bandy's tract.
You can sit down again.
Oh, Daniel.
Daniel.
Please.
I am in desperate times.
I know.
I need a friend.
Yes. Of course, you do.
I've sinned.
I need help.
I'm a sinner.
I've let
the devil grab hold of me
in ways I never imagined.
I'm so full of sin.
The Lord sometimes
challenges us,
doesn't He, Eli?
Oh, yes, He does, Daniel.
Yes, He does.
Yes, He does!
He's completely failed
to alert me to the recent
panic in our economy.
And this...
Oh, dear.
I must have this, Daniel.
I must, I must,
I must have this.
My investments have...
Daniel, I won't bore you,
but if I could grab the
Lord's hand for help I would,
but He does these
things all the time.
These mysteries
that He presents,
and while we wait...
While we wait
for His word!
Because you're not
the chosen brother, Eli.
'Twas Paul
who was chosen.
He found me and told me
about your land.
You're just a fool.
Why are you
talking about Paul?
I did what your
brother couldn't.
Don't say this to me.
I broke you
and I beat you.
It was Paul
told me about you.
He's the prophet.
He's the smart one.
He knew what was there
and he found me
to take it out
of the ground.
Know what
the funny thing is?
Listen, listen.
I paid him $10,000
cash in hand.
Just like that.
He has his own company now.
Prosperous little business.
Three wells producing,
$5,000 a week.
Stop crying,
you sniveling ass.
Stop your nonsense.
You're just
the afterbirth, Eli.
No.
That slithered out
on your mother's filth.
No.
They should've put
you in a glass jar
on the mantelpiece.
Where were you
when Paul was suckling
at his mother's teat?
Where were you?
Who was nursing you,
poor Eli?
One of Bandy's sows?
That land has been had.
Nothing you can
do about it. It's gone.
If you would just
take this lease...
You lose.
Drainage!
Drainage, Eli, you boy.
Drained dry.
I'm so sorry.
If you have a milkshake
and I have a milkshake,
and I have a straw,
there it is.
That's the straw,
you see?
Watch it.
Now my straw
reaches across the room
and starts to
drink your milkshake.
I drink your milkshake!
I drink it up!
Don't bully me, Daniel.
Did you think
your song and dance
and your superstition
would help you, Eli?
I am the Third Revelation.
I am who the Lord has chosen.
Daniel!
Because I'm smarter
than you!
I'm older!
I'm your old friend,
Daniel!
I'm not a false prophet...
Help me! Help me!
...you sniveling boy!
I am the Third Revelation!
I told you
I would eat you.
We're family!
I told you
I would eat you up!
We're brothers!
Daniel, please forgive me.
I beg you.
That's it. That's it.
Mr. Daniel?
I'm finished.