ASHLEY BLAKER: Ashley, live on BBC One.
Merry Christmas!
Now, an after-dinner snooze
should always be followed
by a plate of cheese, a cupper,
and a new adventure for Wallace & Gromit,
as a feathered foe seeks revenge.
- [DISTANT THUNDER RUMBLING]
- [RAIN PATTERING SOFTLY]
[RAIN PATTERING SOFTLY]
[♪ Suspenseful music]
[♪♪]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[LINE RINGING]
MAN [ON PHONE]:
'Ello, 'ello, 'ello?
Oh, is that the police?
We've got someone here
you might be interested in.
- [WALLACE CHUCKLES]
- [CLINK!]
I think we just
foiled a robbery.
[SIREN WAILING]
- [REPORTERS CLAMORING]
- [CAMERA FLASHES CLICKING]
[HEAVY DOOR SLAMS]
[ITEMS CLATTERING]
[CELL DOOR CREAKS,
SLAMS SHUT]
[♪♪]
[NECK JOINTS CRACKING]
- [CAMERA FLASH CLICKING]
- FEMALE JUDGE [VO]: Feathers McGraw,
you have been found
guilty of the attempted robbery
- of the Blue Diamond.
- [CHAINS RATTLING]
If not for the actions of two
- upstanding citizens,
- [DOOR SLAMS]
you would have succeeded
in your wicked plan.
Therefore, it is the decision
of this court...
that, for the rest
of your natural life,
you be removed
to a high-security institution.
[CHILDREN LAUGHING]
GUARD [CHUCKLING]:
There's no escape from here,
so don't even think about it.
[BOTH GASP]
[ENCLOSURE DOOR CREAKS,
SLAMS SHUT]
- [PIPE CREAKING]
- [♪ OMINOUS MUSIC]
[♪♪]
[♪ "WALLACE & GROMIT" THEME]
[♪ MUSIC STOPS]
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
[♪ PEACEFUL MUSIC]
[MOTOR WINDING UP]
- [LOUD WHIRRING]
- [EARS FLAPPING]
- [FWHOOMP!]
- [BEEPING]
- [RATCHETING]
- [MACHINERY WHIRRING]
[BEEPING INTENSIFIES]
[THWOMP!]
[♪♪]
[EARS FLAPPING]
[BUZZER SOUNDING]
WALLACE [OVER INTERCOM]:
Get me up, Gromit!
Another great day
of inventing beckons!
[CHUCKLES]
- [LEVER RATCHETS]
- [MOTORS WHIRRING]
Oh-ho-ho!
Oh, top dog!
[♪♪]
[BUTTON CLICKS, BUZZES]
Here we gooo!
[WATER RUSHING]
WALLACE: Away-hey!
- [DOING!]
- Ooh!
[SPLOSHING]
- Oh, lovely!
- [WHEELS SQUEAKING]
[MOTOR WINDS UP,
WHIRRING]
[FWHOOMP!]
[BRUSHES RASPING]
[BEEPING]
[MOTOR REVS]
- [WATER BURBLING]
- [GIGGLING] Tickles!
- [THUNK!]
- [GRUNTS]
- [SQUEAKS, THWACK!]
- [EXCLAIMING]
- [WALLACE EXCLAIMING]
- [SKIN SQUEAKING]
- WALLACE: Whee!
- [METALLIC THUNK]
- [METAL HATCH CLUNKS]
Woohoo!
- [GRUNTS]
- [METAL SQUEAKS]
- [CHUCKLES]
- [METAL RATCHETING]
Hup!
[GRUNTS]
[STRAINS]
- [LIGHT WHIRRING]
- Ah!
- WALLACE: Hit it, Gromit!
- [BUTTON SQUEAKS]
- [RATCHETING]
- [SPROING!]
- [HISSING, THWOMP!]
- [EXCLAIMING]
[BELL DINGS]
- [GRUNTS]
- [CHAIR RASPS]
- 'Morning, Gromit!
- [THUNK!]
- Ooh!
- [POP!]
How's my favorite pooch, hmm?
Oh, you do
look after me, lad.
[WOOD RATCHETS, RASPS]
- [WHIRRING, CLINKING]
- WALLACE: Very interesting. Oh, I must say.
- [TICKING]
- WALLACE: Hm. Oh, yes.
[SPROING!
SPROING! SPROING!]
- [RATCHETING]
- [GLOOP! GLOOP! GLOOP!]
- [SPLAT! SPLAT! SPLAT!]
- Mm. Hmm. Hmm!
- [WHIRRING]
- Mm-hmm.
[CRUNCHES]
Mm. Mm!
Cracking toast, Gromit.
WALLACE:
Mmm, mm-mm-mmm.
WALLACE: Mm, mm.
WALLACE: Oh, dear. More bills?
[FEIGNED SOBBING]
Inventing doesn't come cheap,
does it?
WALLACE: Maybe I'm just
making too many gadgets.
[SPLOOSH!]
[GROMIT SIGHS]
Oh, don't worry, lad.
We'll think of something.
You look like
you need a good pat.
Come here...
[♪ PLAYFUL MUSIC]
Heh, that's it, lad.
- My new Pat-O-Matic will oblige.
- [BUTTON CLICKS, BEEPS]
- [TRILLING]
- [MECHANICAL WHOOSH]
[CREAKY RATCHETING]
And if you think
that's progress,
wait 'til you see the next thing
I'm working on.
- Mmm!
- [CREAKY RATCHETING]
Ooh!
[CHUCKLES]
- [METAL LATCH CLICKS, SQUEAKS]
- [CHUCKLES GIDDILY] Oh.
- [ELECTRONICS BEEPING, TRILLING]
- [EXCITEDLY] Ooh!
[BIRDS SINGING]
- [LATCH CLICKS]
- [HINGES CREAK]
- [♪ TRANQUIL MUSIC]
- [BIRDSONG]
[TAKES DEEP BREATH]
[DIRT SHUFFLES]
[WATER CAN THUNKS]
- [WATER TRICKLING]
- [WATER CAN THUNKS]
[LEAVES JOSTLE SOFTLY]
[SIGHS]
[LOW RUMBLING,
CREAKING]
WALLACE:
Ha! Look out, lad!
- [CREAKING, THUMPING]
- WALLACE: Coming through!
Phew!
[CHUCKLES]
Oh, don't think
I haven't noticed, Gromit.
You spend ages
toiling away in this garden.
Well, no more!
- [WALLACE CLAPS]
- [THUD]
[THUDDING]
[CREAKING]
[HEAVY THUD]
[FROM BOX] He-hey!
[WHIRRING FOOTSTEPS]
WALLACE: This is
my latest invention--
a smart gnome.
Hi!
I'm your
Nifty Odd-jobbing Robot.
Call me Norbot!
WALLACE:
Norbot, meet Gromit.
Pleased to meet you,
Master Gromit.
WALLACE:
He's very friendly.
[MOTOR WHIRRING]
WALLACE: Whoa-ho, steady on, Norbot!
[CHUCKLING]
Well, go on, chuck.
[CHUCKLES] Why don't you put him
through his little paces?
- He's voice-activated.
- [CROW CAWS]
[GIGGLING]
A bit shy, are we? All right.
Norbot, make Gromit's garden
neat and tidy.
Neat and tidy.
[WHIRRING]
- Yes, Mr. Wallace.
- [TARGETS BLOOPING]
WALLACE:
I've pre-programmed him for you, lad.
He's watched every episode
of "DIY Garden Squad" there is.
Only two hours to go, and they still
haven't got the patio down!
Just watch him do all those
tedious gardening tasks.
[TRIMMERS SNIPPING]
- [RAPID SNIPPING]
- Chop, chop, chop!
[♪ RAPID MUSIC]
- [RUMBLING, RATCHETING]
- Mowing!
WALLACE:
Oh-ho-ho! Wa-hey!
More mowing!
WALLACE [CHUCKLING]:
Oh-ho-ho, don't forget the edges.
Strimmer!
WALLACE: Careful, lad.
[BLOWING]
[MOTOR RUMBLING]
NORBOT: Pointlessly
blowing leaves around!
WALLACE:
Oh! Whoops-a-daisy.
Hedge trim.
- NORBOT: Last bit of mowing.
- [BUZZING]
[♪ MELANCHOLY MUSIC]
[BEEPS]
♪ I'm a happy nifty Norbot
♪ I love to do a job ♪
[STING]
NORBOT:
Neat and tidy!
- WALLACE: Oh, oh!
- [APPLAUSE]
- [WALLACE CHUCKLES]
- [NEIGHBORS EXCLAIM]
He's a little treasure,
that one.
Amazing job!
And very convenient.
Well, well,
looks like you've
"made the cut," Norbot.
Better take a bow, hmm?
- [WALLACE CHUCKLING]
- NORBOT: Bowing.
- Bowing again.
- Where did you get him from?
- NORBOT: Thank you!
- Well, actually, I made him myself.
What fun! [CHUCKLES]
Is he for hire?
[CHUCKLES, STAMMERS]
- Oh...
- [TING!]
Come on.
I need your help.
Not you, lad. Norbot.
NORBOT [BEEPS]:
Yes, Mr. Wallace.
How may I assist?
Come along, Norbot, lad.
We've got work to do.
- [GATE CREAKS SHUT]
- NORBOT: Righto, Mr. Wallace.
CHIEF: It's a crime.
That's what it is, a crime...
that you and I
can't be together.
Mwah!
Not yet, my sweetness.
Soon, though.
- [KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- [EXCLAIMS] Eh?
Got a mo', Chief?
- Wha--?
- I've just finished my investigation
- into that missing bike saddle.
- [HEAVY THUD]
I've got witness interviews,
crime scene
- reports, full forensics...
- Mukherjee!
...and I checked the National
Bike Saddle database.
There isn't one,
apparently.
- Mukherjee!
- Chief?
[SIGHS]
How long have you been
with us now?
Since 9:00 a.m.
this morning, Chief.
Well, you can forget what
you've learned at training college,
because,
at the end of the day,
there's just one thing
that matters in this job--
- a copper's gut.
- Copper's gut, sir?
Instinct!
The important stuff's
not up here...
it's down here.
Yeah. I've got quite a copper's gut
meself, actually.
Oh, I can see that, Chief.
I mean, I... [STAMMERS]
[LAUGHS NERVOUSLY]
I didn't mean I can see...
...it.
Oh, is that
Feathers McGraw?
Ah! What?! Where?!
Oh... [CHUCKLES]
...that.
Well, there you go--
a copper's gut.
He stole
the Blue Diamond, right?
Oh, he tried,
but he couldn't escape
the long arm of the law.
CHIEF [VO]:
Oh, yes. I played my part.
[PHONE RINGING]
'Ello, 'ello, 'ello?
WALLACE:
Oh, is that the police?
[VO] The Blue Diamond ended up
back in the museum vault.
- [LID SLAMS SHUT]
- [VO] I locked it up meself...
well out of harm's way.
- [HEAVY METALLIC THUD]
- [TUMBLER RATCHETS]
Oh, I'd love to crack
a case like that.
You must be
dead proud, Chief.
It's not-- It's not
about pride, Mukherjee.
It's about duty.
Which is why
I've accepted one last task
- before I hang up me truncheon.
- Oh?
The new Blue Diamond
exhibition.
The diamond's going
back on display?
CHIEF: Oh, aye.
I've designed all the security
arrangements meself.
Foolproof.
Yeah!
Well, not unless Feathers
cuts a hole in that
- skylight...
- Skylight?
...or he removes the back plate
off the aircon.
- Air what?
- Oh! Actually,
he could just get in
through the gift shop.
There's a gift shop?!
Look, Feathers isn't
gonna get in, is he?
CHIEF: He's safely
banged up in the zoo...
literally doing bird.
CHIEF: Now, I've got
a grand opening to prepare for...
so get out there on the beat,
burn some shoe leather.
Yes!
[CLEARS THROAT]
I mean, yes... sir.
- Hrmph!
- [DOOR SLAMS]
WALLACE: Oh, yes.
That's it, Norbot.
Make the letters
nice and big.
WALLACE: Oh-ho!
Oh, that's just smashing!
WALLACE: Mm! I think you're
going to like this, Gromit.
Ta-da!
Gnome Improvements!
A gnome-based garden
and maintenance service.
[CHUCKLES]
I told you
we'd find a way
to pay the bills, lad.
- [WALLACE CHUCKLES]
- [DOOR SLAMS]
[RATCHETING,
FOOTSTEPS]
Uh, Norbot...
haven't you missed
something?
NORBOT [DINGING]:
Oh! Yes, Mr. Wallace.
[STING]
Oh, yes, very good.
Oh, good job, Norbot.
WALLACE [CHUCKLING]:
Oh, yeah.
- [HORN HONKING]
- WOMAN: Yoo-hoo!
WALLACE: Hm?
Ooh, it's "Up North News"!
Maybe they've
heard about our Norbot.
Ah, this'll be great
for publicity.
WOMAN [ON TV]:
And now, "Up North News,"
presented by Anton Deck.
Good evening.
Now, we've all heard
of cutting-edge technology,
but how about
cutting hedge technology?
[GIGGLES]
Onya Doorstep has more.
Meet Norbot,
the latest thing
in gnome help.
He's the brainchild
of a smart-thinking local inventor.
Oh, uh, "smart-thinking."
Oh, thank you very much.
So, Wallace,
what can Norbot do
around the house?
Oh, well, pretty much everything,
Ms. Doorstep.
- No job is too small!
- [TRIMMERS CLIPPING]
♪ I'm a happy nifty Norbot
♪ I like to trim the hedge ♪
NORBOT:
Ta-da! Artistic!
I've been testing him out here
in my own garden,
and he's done a cracking job,
as you can see.
He certainly seems
very user-friendly,
to use the jargon.
So, what's inspired you to create
this handy device, Mr. Wallace?
WALLACE: Oh,
I've always loved inventing...
making things
that help people...
and Norbot is
so very helpful. Mm.
I'd say he's my
greatest invention so far.
We charge him up
every night,
and the next day,
he's raring to go again.
ONYA:
He seems very obliging.
WALLACE:
Oh, whatever your problem...
he's the answer!
ONYA: Well,
sounds like this little gnome...
is going to make
a huge difference around here.
This is Onya Doorstep,
for "Up North News."
GUARD:
Cage inspection!
[ENCLOSURE DOOR CREAKS OPENS]
GUARD:
Move aside, jailbird!
GUARD: All clear!
What a deadbeat.
[CHORTLES]
Don't know why
everybody thinks
- he's so clever.
- [DOOR SLAMS]
[RUBBER SQUEAKING, SNAPS]
[HOT WATER WHOOSHING]
WALLACE: AI, lad.
See how embracing technology
makes our life better?
WALLACE [SLURPING]: Ahh!
I mean, thanks to that handy device,
we haven't had
to use the old teapot
for years.
WALLACE [CHUCKLING]:
Oh, yes, tech--
that's the thing.
WALLACE: Uh, so long as it knows
who's boss, of course.
- [NORBOT WHIRRING RAPIDLY]
- WALLACE [CHUCKLING]: Oh, look at him go!
Ta-da!
Oh-ho-ho!
A Wallace onesie!
Oh, that's champion,
that is, Norbot.
[WALLACE CHUCKLES]
NORBOT:
A Wallace onesie!
[WALLACE CHUCKLING]
WALLACE: I think
this'll fit perfectly.
NORBOT: Perfectly!
[CLOCK TICKING]
[♪ CLASSICAL MUSIC PLAYING]
[CLOCK TICKING, FAINT]
[♪♪]
[DOOR OPENS,
HINGES CREAK]
- [NORBOT SCATTING]
- [FOOTSTEPS]
[DOOR CREAKS SHUT]
Evening, Master Gromit.
- [NORBOT HUMMING]
- [WHIRRING]
[MUSIC STOPS ABRUPTLY]
[BUTTON CLICKING]
[WHIRRING]
[WHIRRING, CLICK]
[TRILLING]
Norbot recharge time.
[MOANING]
[NORBOT GURGLING]
[GURGLING INTENSIFIES]
- [LIGHT SWITCH CLICKS]
- [GURGLING CONTINUES]
[GURGLING CONTINUES]
[GURGLING CONTINUES,
RHYTHMIC WHIRRING]
[POWERS DOWN]
[CLOCK TICKING, FAINT]
[GROMIT SIGHS]
[GURGLING,
RHYTHMIC WHIRRING RESUME]
[GURGLING, WHIRRING STOP]
Recharge, nearly 1%.
[GURGLING,
WHIRRING RESUME]
[DOOR SLAMS OPEN]
[CLATTERING]
[THUD!]
[ELECTRONIC TONES
FROM SURROUNDING EQUIPMENT]
Recharge time reactivated.
[GURGLING RESUMES]
[GROMIT SLAPS HANDS
TRIUMPHANTLY]
[DOOR HINGES CREAKING]
[GURGLING STOPS]
Recharge, nearly 2%.
- [GURGLING RESUMES]
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- [NIGHT BIRD CALLS]
- [EQUIPMENT DRONING]
- [GURGLING CONTINUES]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[♪ OMINOUS MUSIC]
[MONKEY HOOTING IN DISTANCE]
[CLATTERING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[SAW RASPING]
[METALLIC CLANGING]
[♪♪]
[RATCHETING]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[BRICK SCRAPING]
[RATCHETING]
[RATCHETING CONTINUES,
HANDLE SQUEAKING]
[GUARD SNORING]
[SNORING CONTINUES]
[RATCHETING STOPS]
[♪ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[RATCHETING CONTINUES]
- [SNORING CONTINUES]
- [ARM LATCHES]
[BUTTON CLICKS,
LEVER SLIDES]
[KEYS CLACKING]
[♪♪]
[SNORING CONTINUES]
[KEYS CLACKING]
[RAPID BEEPING, TRILLING]
[SNIFFLING,
SNEEZE BUILDING]
[SNEEZE BUILDUP
INTENSIFIES]
A-ch--
[♪♪]
- [GUARD SIGHS]
- [ARM RATCHETS]
[RATCHETING]
- [SNEEZE BUILDS]
- [RATCHETING]
[MUFFLED SNEEZE]
[PERSPIRATION SPLATTERS]
- [RATCHETING]
- [GUARD SIGHS]
[SNORING RESUMES]
[♪♪]
[RATCHETING]
[RASPBERRY ALERT]
[BUTTON CLICKS,
ATTACHMENT WHIRS]
[ATTACHMENT SQUEAKS]
- [HEAVY LOCKS ENGAGING]
- [COMPUTER TRILLS]
- [ATTACHMENT WHIRS]
- [CLICKING]
- [KEYS CLACKING]
- [RASPBERRY ALERT]
[♪♪]
- [KEYS CLACKING]
- [RASPBERRY ALERT]
[♪♪]
[TAPPING SOFTLY]
[THWACK!]
[KEYS CLACKING]
- [COMPUTER CHIMES]
- [SIMULATED SLIDING]
[ALERT TRILLING]
[BLOOPING]
[♪♪]
[♪ DESCENDING 8-BIT TONE]
WALLACE [IN 8-BIT VOICE]:
Welcome to my top-secret Files!
[♪ 8-BIT
"WALLACE & GROMIT" THEME]
[BEEPING]
[TRILLING]
[♪ OMINOUS MUSIC]
[♪ MENACING MUSIC]
[BEEPING]
[NECK JOINTS CRACKING]
- [THUNDER RUMBLES]
- [LEVER RATCHETS]
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
- [COMPUTER THRUMMING]
[RISING ELECTRONIC TONE]
[TRILLING]
[DESCENDING
ELECTRONIC TONE]
[STING]
[KEYS CLACKING]
- [CONTROLS CLICKING]
- [KEYS CLACKING]
[BEEPING]
- [BEEPING CONTINUES]
- [KEYS CLACKING]
[BUZZING]
[BABBLING, WARBLING]
[CHITTERING]
[WARBLES]
[SILENCE]
- [CLICK]
- [POWERS OFF]
- [PLUG CLATTERS]
- [THUNDER RUMBLING]
[WHIRRING]
NORBOT:
New instructions received.
[THUNDER CRASHES, RUMBLES]
NORBOT:
No job is too small.
[TOOLS WHIRRING]
- [SAW BUZZING]
- [METAL TUBE CLANKING]
[METALLIC BANGING]
[TOOLS WHIRRING]
[THUNDER RUMBLES]
[THUNDER RUMBLING]
[♪♪]
[THUNDER CRASHES]
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
[MECHANICAL CLANKING,
WHIRRING, RATCHETING]
[RAPID BEEPING]
[RATCHETING, WHIRRING]
[EARS FLAPPING]
[RATCHETING]
[LIQUID POURING]
[WHIRRING]
- WALLACE: Get me up, Gromit!
- [REPEATED BUZZER]
We've got a right
busy day ahead.
[BUZZER CONTINUING]
[LEVER RATCHETS,
BUZZER STOPS]
WALLACE [DISTANTLY]:
Thanks, lad! Wheee!
[DOOR CREAKS OPEN]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
[WHIRRING,
FOOTSTEPS]
[WHIRRING, RATCHETING]
[SPOON CLINKS]
[♪ FOREBODING MUSIC]
[WHIRRING, FOOTFALLS]
[WALLACE GRUNTS]
- [CHUCKLING]
- [POP!]
'Morning, team.
- [WHIRRING]
- Mmm.
Ooh!
Loads of new messages.
- [MACHINE BEEPS]
- WOMAN 1 [ON MACHINE]: Gnome Improvements?
I saw you on the telly.
Could Norbot come and mow my--?
- MAN 1: New lily pond--
- WOMAN 2: With a stump-grinder--
- MAN 2: And put well-rotted manure--
- WOMAN 3: Inside my conservatory?
- [MACHINE BEEPS]
- Talk about celebrity, lad.
He's a household gnome!
[WALLACE CHUCKLES]
At this rate, we'll need
a whole army of Norbots.
[WALLACE CHUCKLES, SIGHS]
- [NORBOT CLAPS TWICE]
- [RHYTHMIC THUDDING]
- [THUDDING CONTINUES]
- Hmm?
Eh?
[THUDDING CONTINUES]
[SPOON RATTLING]
[SPOON CLATTERS
ON TABLE]
[THUDDING CONTINUES]
[NORBOT WHIRRING]
[THUDDING RATE INCREASES]
[THUDDING INTENSIFIES]
[NORBOTS CLOMPING]
[CLOMPING CONTINUES]
[♪ OMINOUS "WALLACE & GROMIT"
THEME IN MINOR KEY]
WALLACE:
What on earth? The--
[NERVOUS WHIMPER]
More Norbots
for Mr. Wallace.
Uh...
[LAUGHING NERVOUSLY]
WALLACE [CHUCKLING NERVOUSLY]:
Huh.
Well!
That is smart.
It's like he knows what we need
before we even know, ourselves.
[CHUCKLES]
The more gnomes, the merrier!
Right, Gromit?
The more gnomes,
the merrier.
NORBOTS [IN UNISON]:
Yes, Mr. Wallace!
WALLACE [CHUCKLING]:
What could possibly go wrong?
[♪♪]
- [HATCH CLUNKS]
- [RATCHETING]
WALLACE:
That's it, up you go.
- [RATCHETING]
- [THUNK, SQUEAKING]
WALLACE: Aha!
A bit of fine tuning...
WALLACE: Oh, that's good.
[CHUCKLES]
Uh, no need for us
to go with them, Gromit.
I just track them
with my new gnoming device.
- WALLACE: Mm.
- [DOOR SLAMS]
WALLACE:
Ah! Lovely tea.
All we have to do
is sit back
and let the machines
take the strain.
[SLURPS]
Right, Gromit?
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- WALLACE: Gromit?
- [CAR STARS]
- WALLACE: Gromit? Gromit!
WALLACE [OVER INTERCOM]:
I said we don't need
to go with them.
[CHUCKLES]
Don't you trust
my inventions, lad?
[WHIRRING, RATCHETING]
WALLACE [OVER INTERCOM]:
[SIGHS] I don't know.
Hmm. Never mind.
- Time to unleash the gnomes!
- [CLICK, BUZZ]
Go! Go! Go!
- Wahoo!
- Ha-ha!
Whee-hee!
Sick!
- Yeah!
- Rad!
- [PINGING]
- WALLACE: Oh, yes.
All present and correct.
WALLACE:
Mm. Uh, remember,
- I want you all working
- [KNOCKER RAPPING]
- like a finely-tuned machine.
- [DOORBELL RINGS]
[♪♪]
- [THUNK!]
- Ow!
NORBOTS [IN UNISON]:
♪ Ohhh...
♪ We're happy, nifty Norbots
♪ We love to do our job
♪ When we come round
and fix your house
♪ We make up quite a mob
♪ We dig and paint
and plant and snip
♪ We break our little backs
♪ And we never stop
to have a brew
♪ 'Cause we got battery packs ♪
This is the police!
Come down quietly!
You're only making this
harder on yourself.
[CAT WHIMPERING]
- NORBOT: Beep, beep!
- [WOMEN GASP]
- Beep, beep! Coming through!
- [HORN HONKING]
[WOMEN EXCLAIMS]
[WOMAN MOANING]
[WHIRRING]
Patio chop!
NORBOTS [IN UNISON]:
♪ Oh, we're jolly useful Norbots
♪ We do all sorts of stuff
♪ When we get asked to do a task
♪ We can't work hard enough
♪ We push and pull and saw and chop
♪ We think our chores are fun
♪ We won't delay
♪ Keep out our way
until the job is done ♪
The Norbots are
a triumph, Gromit.
We'll soon have
those bills paid off.
[♪♪]
- [ROPE STRETCHING]
- [WEATHERVANE CLANKS]
[♪ NORBOTS WHISTLING]
[WOOD CREAKING]
- [DOING!]
- [THWUMP!]
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- [HANDS CLAP]
NORBOT:
Neat and tidy.
[DOOR RATTLING]
[THUDDING]
[NORBOTS HUMMING]
- [HUMMING CONTINUES]
- [BANGING AGAINST GLASS]
[WHIRRING]
[STING]
[BANGING ON GLASS]
Oh, happy birthday, Mavis.
Oh, smashing!
[KERPLOP!]
[GASPS]
What happened to me glass table?!
[DOOR CREAKS]
- [GASPS]
- [MUG BREAKS]
Where's me tools?!
[DOOR CREAKS]
- [GASPS] Where's me shed?!
- [POT BREAKS, CLATTERS]
Where's our drainpipe?!
- [WATER SPLOSHING]
- [WOMAN EXCLAIMS]
- [TIRES SQUEALING]
- [POTTERY CLATTERING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[THUNK!]
[METAL CLATTERING]
[WHIRRING]
[PHONE RINGING]
- Hello, police?
- [PHONE RINGING]
- Another burglary? What's the address?
Hello? Police?
- A weathervane? When did it go missing?
- [PHONE RINGING]
Hello, police?
[LAUGHING]
Someone's pinched your big butt?!
Oh!
Water butt.
[CLEARS THROAT]
I see what you mean.
Uh, hang on.
[PHONE RINGING]
[CLEARS THROAT]
[ROBOTICALLY] Hello.
- You have reached the Old Bill...
- [PC SHRIEKS]
We're experiencing a high volume
of calls at the moment,
so please leave your crime
after the beep.
- [IN HIGH VOICE] Beep!
- [HANDSET CLUNKS]
What's going on here?!
Oh, Chief!
It's a spate of burglaries,
like, a proper crimewave.
I can't be dealing
with a crimewave.
I've got enough on me hands
as it is.
What do you think,
blue or black?
For the grand opening.
Uh... blue?
Ah, yeah.
See what you're saying.
Matches the diamond.
Any road,
about these robberies--
I've been building
this crime wall,
trying to find
common themes and such.
Never--
Never mind crime walls.
What's your copper's gut
telling you?
Well, all the clues
seem to point
to this man,
a local inventor.
Wallace?
The upstanding citizen who helped
put Feathers behind bars?
Yeah, hey, why not?
You catch one
super-villain,
doesn't make you a saint,
does it?
Oh, should we say
he's a suspect, then?
Just bring him in
and book him.
- I've got a speech to write.
- Really?
PC:
Don't we need...
...evidence?
Oh, I don't know.
All these fancy ideas you get
from training college.
[SIGHS]
Right. Come on, then.
[♪ NEWS JINGLE]
News just in.
We're getting reports
of a crimewave
affecting gardens
across the region.
- Onya Doorstep has more.
- [DIAL CLICKS]
[CHANNEL CHANGES]
WOMAN [ON TV]: The robots,
they're taking over the world!
They'll destroy us all,
I tell you!
- [DIAL CLICKS]
- [TV POWERS OFF]
Oh, that's
a bit hasty, Norbot.
I might have been
watching that.
Time to relax,
Mr. Wallace.
WALLACE: Oh, yes,
I do like a bit of relaxation.
- [FLAMES WHOOSHING]
- [NORBOT GURGLING]
Eh?
[RATCHETING,
WHIRRING]
[♪ PLAYING LULLABY]
- [STAMMERING] Ooh!
- [POWER TOOLS WHIRRING]
[♪ LULLABY CONTINUES]
Oh, what's all this
in aid of?
- NORBOT: Massage, Mr. Wallace?
- [♪ LULLABY CONTINUES]
Oh...
Oh, yes... Oh!
- OOh! Oh, that's lovely.
- [♪ LULLABY CONTINUES]
[♪ NORBOTS VOCALIZING]
WALLACE: Oh, dear,
you are spoiling me.
Snoozy Choc?
[CHUCKLING]
I don't mind if I do.
- [SLURPING] Mmm.
- NORBOT: Come along.
[CHUCKLES] Steady on!
[SLURPING]
- NORBOT: Drink up, Mr. Wallace.
- [WALLACE GULPING]
Mm... mmmm...
[HICCUP]
[SNORING]
[METALLIC CLATTERING]
[METAL CLATTERING]
[WHEELS SCREECH]
[♪ SUSPENSEFUL TONE]
[MUFFLED WHIRRING, BANGING]
[WALLACE SNORING]
[WALLACE MOANING]
[CRACKLING]
[STING]
[DOORS CREAK]
[WELDING, BUZZING,
TOOLS BANGING, WHIRRING]
[♪ DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[JACKHAMMER RATTLING]
[MOLTEN METAL BUBBLING]
[♪♪]
[HAMMER CLINKING]
[TOY SQUEAKS]
[WHEEZING WHISTLE]
[♪ ANTICIPATORY DRUMBEATS]
[TOY SQUEAKS SOFTLY]
[TOY SQUEAKS SHARPLY]
[SINGLE WHIR]
[SQUEAK!
SQUEAK! SQUEAK!]
[GROMIT'S SOFT FOOTFALLS]
[GROMIT'S FOOTSTEPS,
RUNNING]
- [WALLACE SNORING]
- [WATER SPLASHES]
[WALLACE MOANS
INCOHERENTLY]
Hmm.
[SNORING RESUMES]
- [WALLACE SNORING]
- [VASE CLUNKS]
[WALLACE MOANING]
- [DIAL RATCHETS]
- [POWER WINDING UP]
- [DEVICE THWACKING]
- [WALLACE GASPING]
- [STAMMERING]
- Gromit!
- [THWACK!]
- [WALLACE GRUNTS]
- [GRUNTING] What on earth?!
- [RECLINER RATCHETS]
What?
Is something wrong?
Is it the Norbots?
Well, this had
better be important, lad.
I don't know what's got
into you lately.
[GROMIT HUFFS]
[DOOR CREAKING]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
Well, I'll go
to the top of my stairs!
That's absolutely...
spotless!
- [NORBOTS HUMMING, WHIRRING]
- WALLACE: Oh, look at them.
WALLACE [CONTENTEDLY]:
Oh, yes.
WALLACE: Oh!
You are good gnomes,
doing all these chores
at this time of night.
[NORBOT EYELIDS
CLACKING]
I don't know why
you were so keen
to show me, though, lad.
Couldn't it have waited
'til the morning?
NORBOT: Ahh-hh.
[WALLACE CHUCKLES]
Daft pooch.
[YAWNS]
Well, I've got a nap
to finish before
- I turn in for the night.
- [NORBOTS WHIRRING]
WALLACE: Oh, yes.
Norbot, my best invention ever.
[NORBOTS WHIRRING]
[♪ FOREBODING MUSIC]
- [KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Oh!
- Uh, did you order a pizza, lad?
- [KNOCKING CONTINUES]
All right, all right,
hold your horses.
- Police!
- [WALLACE GASPS]
- [CRASH!]
- [PC SHRIEKS]
- Ooh!
PC [MUFFLED]:
Oops! Sorry!
- Oh, give me strength.
- WALLACE: Huh?
Right!
Let's get this over with.
Get what over with?
- We have a warrant to search your premises.
- WALLACE: Hm-hmm?
- Mukherjee, read him his rights.
- WALLACE: Huh? Eh?
[PC CLEARS THROAT]
Anything you say may be taken down
- and used as evidence against you.
- But I haven't done anything.
We believe you to be guilty
of theft by gnome.
I'm guilty of theft
by gnome?
Ha-ha!
There you go!
He admits it!
Write that down.
[STAMMERING]
This is ridiculous.
My Norbots aren't thieves.
They're down in my workshop
right now...
- doing a bit of spring cleaning.
- [PC GASPS]
There's our evidence, Chief.
All right,
check 'em out, then.
[DOOR SLAMS OPEN]
[SWITCH CLICKS]
Well, I don't see any gnomes.
WALLACE: Eh?
They were here a moment ago.
WALLACE:
I don't understand it.
WALLACE: Uh,
they must have just popped out
to finish a job.
Look, sunshine...
I have not got time
for your games.
Eh?
What--?
Where are you going, Chief?
I'm off to get
me 'tache trimmed...
for the big day.
Anyway, l-look...
if you need evidence,
Mukherjee...
find some.
I don't care
what it takes,
get this man behind bars
- where he belongs.
- [GULPS]
I want this case
wrapped up pronto.
- Understood, sir.
- [DOOR OPENS]
- [DOOR CLOSES]
- Right.
Evidence...
E-Evidence?
This is PC Mukherjee
calling for backup.
We'll need a van...
...a big one.
Uh?
[ALARM CLOCK RINGING]
[♪ MELANCHOLY MUSIC]
[♪♪]
WALLACE [OVER INTERCOM]:
Uh, Gromit? Get me up, lad.
There's a good pooch.
- [HOLLOW THUNKING]
- Oh, wait a mo'.
You can't, can you?
They've taken
all me inventions away...
...for "forensic examination,"
or something.
Outrag...
- ...eous!
- [THUNK]
PC [VO]: We believe you
to be guilty of theft by gnome.
WALLACE [VO]:
They were here a moment ago.
CHIEF [VO]:
Well, I don't see any gnomes.
[DISTANT THUDDING]
[GRUNTING]
Who needs technology, anyway?
Pah! Not me.
- [BUCKET CLATTERS]
- [WALLACE EXCLAIMING]
- Whoa!
- [WATER SLOSHES]
[SHIVERING]
That's nippy!
- [EXCLAIMING]
- [TUB CLUNKS]
- Whoa!
- [WATER SPLASHING]
[WALLACE GRUNTS]
[WEAKLY] Ooh!
Me begonias.
- [CAN CLATTERS, THUNKS]
- [JARS CLINKING]
[SIGHS]
WALLACE [DISTANTLY]: Ah,
I think I need a cup of tea, lad.
[FOOTSTEPS]
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- [JARS CLINKING]
[JAR SHATTERS]
[WATER BLOOPING]
[WATER SLOSHING GENTLY]
[WATER RUNNING]
[DRIPPING ECHOES]
[TEAPOT SLIDES]
[WALLACE GRUNTING]
[WALLACE STRAINING]
Oh, ooh, right. Tea.
I suppose we'll just
have to make it the old way.
[GRUNTS]
Ouch!
Oof!
[GROANS]
How do you do
in this pot?
[CHUCKLES] I haven't used
one of these for so long,
I've forgotten
how they work.
[WALLACE GRUNTING,
STRAINING]
- [STRAINING]
- [TEAPOT CLINKING]
- It's broken!
- [CLATTERING]
There's clearly been
a mistake.
My Norbots are innocent.
You believe me,
don't you, lad?
[CLOCK TICKING]
Don't you, lad?
Oh.
Well, I think you've said
quite enough, Gromit.
You've never trusted
my Norbot, have you?
And I made him
just for you.
Mark my words,
the police will be back
soon enough
- to apologize.
- [KNOCKING ON DOOR]
Aha!
What did I tell you?
[CHUCKLES]
There they are now.
Everything will be
right as rain
- before you can say--
- [DOOR CREAKS]
Nasty, crooked,
thieving, little toe rag!
- Huh?
- Scoundrel!
- Where's our stuff?!
- I want a refund!
What have your gnomes done
with me bath tub?!
And where's me glasses?!
Oh, they're on me head.
Sorry!
WOMAN:
Where's my big butt?!
I'm live outside
the West Wallaby Street house
of the evil inventor,
Mr. Wallace.
Evil?
Uh, don't you mean
"smart-thinking"?
Oh, you think it's smart
to teach gnomes to steal?
No!
But if only
my gnomes were here,
maybe I could
clear my name.
[CHUCKLING]
Well, where are the gnomes?
For the last time,
I don't know!
Oh, yeah.
Very convenient.
CROWD [CHANTING]:
Where are the gnomes?!
Where are
the gnomes?!
Where are the gnomes?!
- [STICK RASPING AGAINST SKIN]
- Where are the gnomes?!
Where are the gnomes?! Where are
the gnomes?! Where are the gnomes?!
Where are the gnomes?!
Where are the...
- ...gnomes?! Where are the--
- [DOOR SLAMS]
[WALLACE PANTING]
This is a nightmare, Gromit!
The police want
to throw me in jail,
the neighbors
all hate me,
and the press think I'm evil!
And how am I supposed to find
my gnomes
if they've taken
me gnoming device?
[FIST SLAPS]
[CAR DOOR
CREAKS OPEN, CLOSED]
[STARTER MOTOR
STRUGGLES]
STRUGGLING]
[LID LATCH CLICKS,
SQUEAKS OPEN]
[ELECTRICITY CRACKLES]
[♪♪]
[♪ DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[MOTOR RUMBLES
TO LIFE]
[MOTOR REVVING]
Wha--?
Never mind Scotland Yard,
looks more like
a scrapyard in here.
It's Wallace's stuff, Chief.
You told me to find some evidence.
I didn't mean take
the whole flippin' house.
I mean,
what's this in aid of?
- Oh! Chief, I wouldn't...
- [CHIEF EXCLAIMING]
Ow! Get off!
That gizmo just assaulted
a police officer.
Add that to the list
of charges, Mukherjee.
But that's just it, sir.
There's nothing here
to pin Wallace to the burglaries.
Oh, they're his gnomes,
aren't they?
I'm just-- I-I'm getting
the feeling that, well...
he may not be our man.
CHIEF:
That Wallace is a wrong 'un...
- ...end of story.
- [MOTOR PURRING]
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- [MOTOR STOPS]
CHIEF:
Now, if you don't mind,
we'll deal with
that villain later.
Right now we've got
important duties to attend to
- up at the museum.
- But, sir, I--
It's my big day,
Mukherjee--
the culmination
of 40 years of service.
- Nothing can go wrong.
- [GENTLE SQUEAKING]
PC:
Uh, no, sir.
We have to stay focused.
Watch like hawks.
Absolutely, sir.
Miss nothing.
[COUNTER FLAP SLAMMING]
- PC: Huh?
- CHIEF: Eh?
- PC: Hmm.
- CHIEF: Oh.
[PINGING]
[PINGING CONTINUES]
[♪♪]
[MOTOR REVVING]
[PINGING]
[PINGING CONTINUES]
[MOTOR REVVING]
[♪♪]
- [MOTORCYCLE TIRES SCREECHING]
- [TRUCK HORN BLARING]
- [TIRES SQUEALING]
- [HORN CONTINUES]
- [WOOD SMASHING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [MOTOR STOPS]
- [PINGING CONTINUES]
[PINGING CONTINUES]
[PINGING]
[♪ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
- [LOW RUMBLING]
- [PINGING CONTINUES]
[PINGING FASTER]
- [RAPID PINGING]
- [SOFT BURBLING]
- [RAPID BEEPING CONTINUES]
- [METAL ANTENNA SQUEAKING]
[♪♪]
- [METALLIC CLINK]
- [LEASH WHOOSHING]
[LIGHT FOOTFALLS
IN BRUSH]
[ELEPHANT TRUMPETS]
- [LION ROARS]
- [MONKEY CHITTERING]
[CHAIR SQUEAKS]
[STING]
[SEAL PUP PURRING]
[PUP SNIFFS]
[PURRING CONTINUES]
[PUP SIGHS
CONTENTEDLY]
[WATER BURBLING]
[DUCKY SQUEAKS]
[♪ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[♪ OMINOUS MUSIC]
[WATER SLOSHING]
- [HANDWHEEL SQUEAKS]
- [HATCH CREAKS OPEN]
[WHIRRING,
SYNCHRONOUS FOOTSTEPS]
[♪ SOFT, DRAMATIC CADENCE]
- [LIGHT PATTING]
- [PUP MOANS]
- [♪ BAGPIPES DRONING]
- [PUP WHINES]
[♪ BAGPIPES PLAYING]
[♪ BAGPIPES CONTINUE]
- [THUMP!]
- [GNOME SCREAMING]
[SPLASH]
[FOOTSTEPS RECEDE]
- [WHIRRING]
- [RUBBER GLOVE SNAPS]
[RUBBER SNAPS]
[STING]
[FOLIAGE RUSTLING]
[♪ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[SAW RASPING]
[BRANCH CRACKING]
[♪♪]
- [RASPING CONTINUES]
- [BRANCH CRACKING]
GROMIT [WHIMPERING]:
Aah!
Ah!
- [WOOD CLUNKING]
- [HAY RUSTLING]
- [THUDDING]
- [BUTTON CLICKS]
Reset mode activated.
- [TRILLING]
- [GURGLING]
[WATER BURBLING]
[WATER SLOSHING]
[DEEP GROWLING]
[LION SNORTS]
- [GROWLING]
- [ROAR]
[CRUNCH!]
[LION STRAINING]
Huh?
[CHEEKS FLAPPING]
[GRUNTING]
[MOANING]
[ELECTRONIC TRILLING]
[DING!]
[TRILLING RISING]
[DINGS]
[ELECTRONIC BLOOP]
Restored to inventor settings.
NORBOT: Hi! I'm your
Nifty Odd-jobbing Robot.
Call me Norbot.
[GROWLING, SNORTS]
[WHIRRING]
- [TRIMMERS SNIPPING]
- [BLOOPING]
NORBOT:
Initiating pruning process.
[RAPID SNIPPING]
Neat and tidy!
[LION GROWLING,
ROARS]
Hmm? Huh? Hmm!
[♪ BACH'S "TOCCATA AND FUGUE IN D MINOR"
PLAYING ON ORGAN]
[♪♪]
[MUSIC STOPS]
- [SONAR PINGS]
- [CHAIR CREAKING]
[SONAR PINGING]
[SLURPING]
- NORBOT 1: Set coordinates.
- NORBOT 2: Target located!
NORBOT 3:
Two degrees west. Tracking.
[MOTOR RUMBLING]
[PINGING]
- [SQUEAKING]
- No job is too small.
Neat and tidy!
- [TIRES SQUEALING]
- NORBOT: Wa-ha-hey!
CHIEF:
Right. Here we go, then.
This is it, Mukherjee.
- Are we ready?
- Couldn't be readier, Chief.
- [RATCHETING]
- [METALLIC THUMPING]
[METALLIC THUMPING]
[DEEP, METALLIC CREAKING]
[♪ OMINOUS VOCALIZATION]
- [MOTOR RUMBLING, TIRES SQUEALING]
- ♪ I'm a happy nifty Norbot
♪ I love to do a job ♪
CHIEF: It's been my great pride
over the years
to serve this community...
knowing there's nothing
more reassuring than the sight
of an uninformed
police officer...
- CROWD: Huh?
- [PC CLEARS THROAT]
Sorry?
Oh! "Uniformed"!
Uniformed police officer.
Can't read me own writing.
Anyway, now I have one final,
happy duty to perform.
Contact imminent.
[WATER BURBLING]
[SONAR PINGING]
[WHIRRING]
Going up.
[FLUSHING]
- [MOTOR RUMBLING]
- NORBOT: Coming through!
[RATTLING]
[NORBOT GIBBERING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
Ladies and gentlemen,
shall we?
[TUMBLERS RATCHETING]
[DOOR RATTLING]
[♪ VOCALIZATION]
[SQUEAKING, SNAP!]
[CAMERAS CLICKING]
CHIEF: And there we have it,
ladies and gentlemen,
safely on display
for all posterity...
- the Blue Diamond!
- [CAMERAS CLICKING]
- [PC GASPS]
[CAMERA CLICKS]
[SILENCE, CLICK!]
It's not as shiny
in real life, is it?
- You what?
- [CAMERA CLICKS]
[EXCLAIMS]
That's a flipping turnip!
[CROWD GASPING]
You didn't check
inside the sack, Chief...
before you put it
in the vault?
Uh...
Ohh!
[CAMERAS CLICKING]
[LID, DOORS SLAM SHUT]
Right!
Anyone fancy a pint?
- [CAMERA CLICKS]
- Ohh.
So, if you've been guarding a turnip
all these years...
then where is
the Blue Diamond?!
[PINGING]
- [♪ "WALLACE & GROMIT" THEME, OUT OF TUNE]
- Oh, gnomes have gone, gadgets have gone...
- even me dog's gone.
- [♪ MULTIPLE DISCORDANT KEYS]
- [RUMBLING, RATTLING]
- Huh? What on earth?
[RUMBLING CONTINUES]
[WALLACE GASPS]
- [METALLIC LATCH CLICKS]
- [RUMBLING CONTINUES]
I didn't know
it could do that.
What the Dickens?!
- [MOTOR SLOWING]
- [TIRES SCREECH]
[MOTOR IDLING]
[DOOR SLAMS OPEN]
[DOOR CREAKING]
WALLACE'S VOICE:
Come in, Gromit. Everything's fine.
Just come straight in.
- [SOFT FOOTSTEPS]
- [CLOCK TICKING]
[MUFFLED]
Oh, you're here! Gromit!
[AS WALLACE] Everything's fine.
Just come... [AS NORBOT] straight in.
NORBOTS [DISPERSED]:
Everything's fine. Everything's fine.
Everything's fine.
This is a disaster!
CHIEF: This has made me
the laughing stock of the town.
Uh, sir, are you okay?
[COUGHS] I'm fine!
Just got an allergy to turnips.
Should we haul Feathers in, sir?
He had the diamond last.
No...
No, he didn't.
What--?
You mean...?
Exactly.
Come on!
[NIGHT BIRD CALLS]
[WALLACE GRUNTING,
MUFFLED]
[WALLACE GRUNTS, PANTS]
Sorry I couldn't
warn you, lad.
I got grabbed
by the Norbots--
a very unpleasant
experience.
Turns out
they are bad after all.
I just don't get it.
Why would me own gnomes
turn against me?
[WHIRRING,
HEAVY FOOTFALLS]
[STING]
A chicken?!
Behind all this?!
[RUBBER SQUEAKING,
SNAPS]
Good grief!
- It's you!
- [STING]
- Again!
Uh, but you're
supposed to be locked up.
Well, you won't get away with it,
you know...
whatever it is you're
trying to get away with.
- [POT CLINKS]
- WALLACE: Eh?
[WHIRRING]
WALLACE:
Wha--? Why're you--? Wha--?
WALLACE: Huh?
Oh! Fancy a cup tea, do you?
[SCOFFS]
The cheek of it!
Well, I wouldn't bother
with that teapot--
it doesn't work.
Eh?
[♪♪]
[POT SHATTERING
IN SLOW MOTION]
What?
[♪ MYSTERIOUS MUSIC]
Well, butter me crumpets!
It can't be!
It's the Blue Diamond!
He must have switched it
all that time ago.
WALLACE [ECHOING]:
Oh, is that the police?
We've got someone here
you might be interested in.
[WALLACE CHUCKLES]
He's a slippery one.
WALLACE:
Oh, so that's your plan.
You get away scot-free
with the diamond,
and everyone thinks
I'm the evil inventor who stole it.
Why, that's-- that's--
vengeance...
most foul!
[DOOR CREAKING]
- [DOOR SLAMS]
- Huh?
- [LOCK ENGAGES]
- WALLACE: Uh...
Oi! Let us out!
[STARTER MOTOR
STRUGGLES]
NORBOTS:
Vroom! Vroom, vroom!
NORBOTS: Vroom!
Vroom, vroom!
[NORBOTS IMITATING
ACCELERATING MOTOR]
[NORBOTS SCREECHING]
Vroom, vroom!
[IMITATING ACCELERATION]
I can't believe
someone's nicked me bike saddle!
I know, sir.
Sorry, sir,
you took me off that case.
Still, we've got our culprit.
[CHUCKLING] Yeah.
All this time, Wallace just
wanted the diamond for himself.
Ah, so you were right
all along, Chief.
- [SIGHS] He is a wrong 'un.
- Aye, too right.
And if he thinks he's got away with this,
he's got another think coming.
WALLACE:
Oh, this is all my fault, lad.
I only ever meant
to invent good things...
things that help people.
I never imagined
they could be used for...
- wrongdoing.
- [DOOR OPENS]
[HEAVY FOOTSTEPS
APPROACHING]
Oh, heck.
It's the law.
- I'm done for now.
- [DOOR CREAKING]
'Morning, Mr. Wallace,
Master Gromit.
Norbot!
Where have you been?
- No job is too small.
- [WHIRRING]
Sounds like he's back to his
nifty, odd-jobbing self.
We're saved! Ha-ha!
Neat and tidy!
- [DOOR CLOSES, LOCK ENGAGES]
- Huh?
Wait! Norbot!
Come back!
Ah, don't worry, lad.
He's voice-activated.
- Mm. Norbot!
- [VACUUM WHIRRING]
- ♪ I'm a happy nifty Norbot
- WALLACE: Norbot!
- ♪ I love to clean the house ♪
- Norbo-o-ot!
Norbot!
Norbot! Norbot!
- [CHAIR THUMPING]
- [WALLACE GRUNTING]
- Steady on. Huh?
- [BLOWER CLATTERS]
What are you up to, lad?
- [BLOWER THUMPS]
- WALLACE: Huh?
- [MOTOR RUMBLING]
- Hardly the time
to start leaf-blowing.
- What on earth!!
- [BLOWER REVVING]
- [SLAM!]
- [WALLACE EXCLAIMS]
- NORBOT: Whoopee!
- [BLOWER REVVING]
- WALLACE: Gromit!
- NORBOT: Collision warning!
Right!
Someone's got
a big surprise coming.
- [KNOCKING, CRASH!]
- WALLACE: Sorry!
Chief, they're getting away!
Chief?
[DOORBELL RINGS]
[DOOR CREAKING]
Did we get 'im?
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- ♪ Born free
♪ As free as the wind blows
♪ As free as the grass grows... ♪
[LEGS THUNKING]
WALLACE: Careful!
- [WOOD CLATTERING]
- There's Feathers!
Nice work, Gromit.
Let's get after the bounder.
More speed, Mr. Wallace?
- Eh?
- [SWITCH CLICKS]
- [MOTOR REVVING]
- WALLACE: Whoa!
WALLACE: Steady, Norbot.
Take her up, Gromit.
[METAL RATCHETING]
Hand over the diamond,
you little tyke!
- Norbot, fetch!
- Righto!
WALLACE: That's it!
That's it, Norbot!
- [TIRES SQUEALING]
- Whoa! Gromit!
NORBERT:
Banana alert!
Skidding!
[WALLACE SCREAMING]
[NORBOTS SCREAMING]
- [SQUEALING]
- [SCREAMING CONTINUES]
[METALLIC THUD]
- NORBOT 1: Ow!
- NORBOT 2: Ow!
- NORBOT 3: Ouch!
WALLACE:
There he is! After him!
[WALLACE SCREAMING]
[WALLACE WHIMPERING]
[WHIRRING, RATCHETING]
[RATCHETING]
Norbot,
stop this thing!
Yes, Mr. Wallace.
Not like that!
WALLACE [YELLING]: No!
[LOUD THUNK]
NORBOT:
Emergency stop complete.
[WALLACE GROANING]
[GROANING]
[♪ DRAMATIC MUSIC]
- [ELECTRICITY CRACKLING]
- [WATER BURBLING]
- [INTENSE CRACKLING]
- [MOTOR RUMBLING]
- [LEVER SQUEAKS]
- [MOTOR REVVING]
[♪♪]
- Gromit...
- [SHIFTER CLANKS]
- Whoa!
- [MOTOR REVVING]
[MOTOR RUMBLING]
[CHUGGING]
[WATER SLOSHING]
- [BOATS SILENT]
- [BIRDSONG]
[DOG SNIFFING]
[WOMAN HUMMING]
[SOFT, RHYTHMIC CHUGGING]
[RATCHETING]
Ha-ha-ha-ha!
PC [GASPING]:
There they are, Chief!
CHIEF: Ah.
Nice-looking narrow boat, that.
Bit like mine.
Hang on a sec...
That is mine!
[ECHOING THROUGH LOUDSPEAKER]
Hey! Stop in the name of the law!
[CLATTERING,
SPLASHING]
- [NORBOTS YELLING]
- [INCOMING PROJECTILES WHISTLING]
- [WATER SPLASHING]
- [CLUNKING]
- [POTTERY SHATTERING]
[WALLACE GRUNTS]
It's no use, lad.
If only there were some way
of rebooting them.
- [POTTERY SHATTERS]
- [RUBBER PLUNKING]
- [RUBBER PLUNKS]
- [WALLACE GROANS, GRUNTS]
♪ I'm a happy nifty Norbot
♪ I like to clean the boat! ♪
- [THUNK!]
- Ah!
[PLATE SHATTERS]
[GRUNTS]
- [METAL HINGES SQUEAK]
- Huh?
[METAL CLINKS]
Another invention?
Are you sure, lad?
[HEAVY THUD]
- [HEAVY THUD]
- [POP]
Right, then!
Technical assistance is on its way.
Can't believe
he nicked me boat.
And you thought
he was innocent!
PC [GASPING]:
I think...
I think that's
Feathers McGraw, Chief.
- They're trying to stop Feathers...
- [CLICK, LOUDSPEAKER FEEDBACK]
- [AMPLIFIED] ...McGraw!
- [AMPLIFIED] Feathers McGraw?!
Don't be ridiculous.
He's banged up
in the zoo.
- [♪ ANGELIC VOCALIZATION]
- That's just an innocent nun,
out for a pleasure cruise.
I just think maybe
Wallace has been
unfairly portrayed
- as a crazed inventor...
- [WOODEN CLUNK]
- PC: Huh?
- [WALLACE LAUGHING MANIACALLY]
[WALLACE CACKLING]
- [RATCHETING, CLUNK]
- Oh, this'll work a treat!
- CHIEF: Huh? What the--?
- ...to a certain extent.
CHIEF: What's he doing
with me vintage boot collection?!
[SQUEAK!]
Okay, Gromit,
let's give those gnomes
- a good reboot up the backside!
- [WHIRRING, RATCHETING]
[TUBULAR CLUNKS]
[BOOMING]
[WHOOSHING]
- NORBOT 1: Ha-ha!
- NORBOT 2: Missed!
[RATCHETING]
[WHOOSHING, WHISTLING]
- [THWACKING]
- NORBOT 1: Bull's-eye!
NORBOT 2:
Reset mode activated.
WALLACE:
It's working, lad!
Ha-ha!
Give it more welly!
WALLACE: Take that!
- WALLACE: Hoodlums!
- NORBOT: Reset mode activated.
[BOOMING]
- [THWACK]
- Reset mode activated.
- [SPLASH!]
- This has gone far enough.
Chief Inspector Mac.
- All units, pursue and arrest Wallace--
- [WHISTLING, THWACK]
- [CHIEF EXCLAIMING]
- Sorry, Chief!
I'm using me gut.
Calling all units.
Head to the border.
Suspect is not Wallace,
but a small nun in charge
of a canal boat.
You're in big trouble,
Mukherjee!
Yeah, this is going on your
assessment report, this!
[GURGLING]
Reset mode activated!
NORBOTS [SCATTERED]:
Hi! I'm your Nifty Odd-jobbing Robot.
- Call me Norbot.
- Pleased to meet you.
- [GIBBERING]
- Caught a few tiddlers, have you?
Good lad.
Now we've got 'im.
Eh?
WALLACE:
Where's he gone?
[MOTOR REVVING]
- [WOOD CLATTERING]
- [MOTOR ROARING]
- Huh?
- Hi! Call me Norbot.
[MOTOR ROARING]
NORBOT: ...Norbot.
[NORBOTS CHATTERING]
- [WATER SLOSHING]
- WALLACE: Well done, lad.
We've got hiiim!
[SPLASH!]
Grom--
[GURGLING]
--mit!
Don't let him
get awaaay!
[WALLACE GASPING,
WHIMPERING]
Whoooa!
[♪♪]
- [METALLIC THUNK]
- [RATCHETING]
[♪♪]
[KNIFE RASPING]
[RATCHETING]
[RAPID RATCHETING]
[WATER SLOSHING]
[WHIMPERING,
EXCLAIMING]
[WALLACE GRUNTS]
- WALLACE: Sorry!
- Huh?!
[GASPS]
[HIGH-PITCHED] Mm!
- [KNIFE RASPING]
- [STRAND SNAPS]
[WATER SLOSHING]
- [KNIFE RASPING]
- [ROPE SNAPS]
[♪♪]
WALLACE [WHINEY]:
Oh, Gromit!
[WALLACE WHIMPERING]
[MUFFLED SCREAMING]
- [THWACK!]
- [WOOD CLATTERING]
- WALLACE: Oh, lummy!
- [VEGGIES THUDDING]
Huh?
Why, ya...!
[♪ DRAMATIC VOCALIZATION]
[♪♪]
[WALLACE YELLING]
[WALLACE EXCLAIMING]
[GRUNTS]
Ouch!
[VEGGIES THUDDING]
[GROMIT THUDS]
[SLAP!]
[SIRENS WAILING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[BIKE TIRE SKIDS]
[GASPS]
I knew it was Feathers McGraw!
Quick!
Close the gate.
[HEAVY THUD]
[LEVER SQUEAKS]
[BRAKE RATCHETS]
[METAL CLUNKING]
[BOAT HULL
RASPING, GROANING]
[WATER SLOSHING]
[RAILING CLANKING]
[CLANKING CONTINUES]
[♪♪]
- [GROMIT CLUNKING]
- [PAWS SQUEAKING]
[METAL THUNKING]
[WHIMPERING]
Gromiiit!
[GENTLE CREAKING]
[WHIMPERING]
[FEET FLOP DOWN]
[FOOTSTEPS APPROACH]
[CREAKING]
[♪ SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC]
[FOOT FLOPS SOFTLY]
[CREAKING]
[♪♪]
WALLACE:
Give him the diamond, lad.
I can live without inventing,
but I can't live without...
[GULPS]
[GENTLE CREAKING]
...me best pal.
[♪ "WALLACE & GROMIT"
THEME VOCALIZED]
[♪ VOCALIZATION]
[WIND WHISTLING SOFTLY]
[GENTLE CREAKING]
[WIND BLOWING]
[WALLACE GASPS]
[THUNK!]
[TRAIN CHUGGING,
WHISTLE BLOWS]
- [CHUGGING CONTINUES]
- WALLACE: Wha--?
[WHEELS CLACKING]
[♪♪]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
[METAL SCRAPING]
[METAL GROANING]
No!
[♪ DRAMATIC MUSIC]
[IN SLOW-MOTION]
Gromiiit!
[STING]
WALLACE: Nooo!
- [EXPLOSION]
- [CLATTERING]
[♪♪]
[FLAMES CRACKLING]
Hi! I'm your Nifty
Odd-jobbing Robot.
Call me Norbot.
- [WHIRRING]
- [IN UNISON] How may I help you?
[RATCHETING]
No job is too small.
ALL: Aww!
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY] I knew
you would embrace technology
in the end, lad.
Thank goodness
you're safe.
- WALLACE: Awww.
- All right, break it up!
This is a crime scene now.
Chief! Chief!
I haven't got time
for your apologies, Mukherjee.
Just arrest Wallace for...
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
- CHIEF: Flipping Nora!
- [TRAIN CHUGGING]
CHIEF:
It is Feathers McGraw!
And he's got the diamond.
Aw, that's ruined me
retirement, that has!
- Wait! What?!
- [PC, CHIEF LAUGHING]
He-hey!
The old turnip switcheroo!
Oh, cracking move, lad!
- NORBOTS [WHOOPING]: Bravo!
- NORBOT: Cracking move, lad!
WALLACE: Ha!
That told him, Gromit.
He's a bad egg, that one,
- and a scoundrel to boot.
- [TRAIN CHUGGING]
[TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWS]
I think you should
have this, Officer.
Well, considering what
I've just seen,
it looks like Mukherjee was right
about you being innocent.
You mean...
I'm not going to jail?
No... thanks to the instincts
of a fine young copper.
You're a natural,
Mukherjee.
Aw, thanks, Chief.
That means a lot.
- Happy retirement, sir.
- [WALLACE CHUCKLES]
Well, this is a turnip
for the books, eh, lad? Hmm.
[NORBOTS LAUGHING]
NORBOT: Oh, yes!
Very funny, Mr. Wallace!
[♪ "WALLACE & GROMIT" THEME]
[CHUCKLES]
Huh?
Ooh.
Hm.
[CHUCKLES]
[SIGHS]
[♪ THEME CONTINUES]
MAC: Ah, yes.
Ahhh.
- [MAC SLURPING]
- [BOAT APPROACHING]
Oh, oi!
Hey, watch that blasted wave!
Can't you read,
Sonny Jim?
- Maximum speed: four miles per hour.
- [SIREN BLARING]
That's three points on your license
for a start!
WALLACE:
'Morning, Gromit.
How's my favorite pooch, hmm?
Oh, I've got something
for your garden, lad.
[STING]
- I've repurposed the Pat-O-Matic.
- [BUTTON SPROINGING]
[PUTTERING,
SQUEAKING]
WALLACE: After all, necessity is
the mother-in-law of invention.
[WALLACE CHUCKLES]
[WHIRRING]
[WATER TRICKLING]
Ta-da!
WALLACE: Awww.
But there's some things
a machine just can't do,
eh, lad?
Aww-haa.
Aww-ha-haa.
Awww. Aw, yes!
[CHUCKLES]
Cheers, me old pal!
[CUPS CLINK]
♪ I'm a happy nifty Norbot
♪ I like to trim the hedge ♪
[WHIRRING]
Ta-da!
[♪♪]
ASHLEY BLAKER: Check out
a flock of films on iPlayer,
including the hens hatching
an escape plan in "Chicken Run."
Press red.
Possibly the biggest
cliffhanger in TV history:
What did Smithy say?
"Gavin & Stacey," the finale,
a festive farewell at 9:00.
Unwrapping secrets,
lies, and a few pressies,
the first of two unmissable
episodes of "EastEnders," next.
[♪♪]
[♪ VOCALIZING]
♪ We're happy nifty Norbots
♪ We love to do our job
♪ When we come round... ♪