That Was the wrong bus
What
Is this the bus to Wulagai
That was in 1967
the second year of the Cultural Revolution
City students were sent to the countryside
The Great Wall
The Great Wall, look
I volunteered
I was among the very first to go
I picked Inner Mongolia
Wherever that was
It was so exciting to escape
the hard life we had in Beijing
during that troubled period
Don't forget my books
Goodbye
See you
Look, so beautiful
Which is the brigade leader's yurt
The one with the Wolf totem
Welcome
Hello
We are students from Beijing
My name is Yang Ke
That's Chen Zhen
Hello
Welcome
How are you
Are you the leader
Yes
Alright
My name is Bilig
I am Bao Shungui
I am the new head of production for your area
I bring
Come, come
These two students
will stay here for two years
You will take care their living
and give them Work
They will teach the kids
to read and Write mandarin
I am going now
Goodbye
See you
What's inside
Books
Only books
That's my son's yurt
Yours is over there
This Will be your home
Here
This is for your protection
Protection against What
Mosquitoes
Wolves
You city boys
What did you learn at school
Serf)'
late again
Easy, Stop
Give me
Did you see the gazelles
Hard to miss them
I Wonder
What they were running away from
Do you have your club
I've forgotten it
Take this one
Okay
Take care
Sure
It's okay
E215)'
Did the awe that the Mongolian Wolf inspired
come from a cult deeply entrenched
in man's brain since time immemorial
My heart filled with gratitude
for the secret forces that came to my rescue
I had the feeling
that I'd started t0 open the door
on the spiritual World of the grassland people
What happened
Gasma
You alright?
"Riding this vast, deserted land
he could not stand
Walls, barriers or borders
He'd never surrendered to anyone
he'd rather die than be taken prisoner"
What means "never surrendered t0 anyone"
If not free
better dead
And then?
"His dream was t0 be free as the wolves
He would only answer to Great Tengger
His one and only Master"
Chen Zhen
who do you answer to
I'm loyal t0 my parents
my superiors and people I respect
I hope that includes me
To be honest
there Was one instruction I did disobey
I left the path
on the Way home
My horse and I were surrounded
by a pack of Wolves
But
I remembered that you told me
Wolves were scared of the sound of steel traps
So
I banged my stirrups
You saved me
You're not entirely stupid
A'ba
Wolves fascinate me
I am thinking
in the spring
I would like to capture a cub
t0 study it
What
You Want t0 study Wolves?
Look
What do you think they'll do
What are they Waiting for
They have been waiting for this moment for months
The desire t0 kill tortures them
But they
are not going to Waste it because of haste
How do you think Genghis Khan defeated
the great armies of the World
with so few mounted Warriors
He learnt the art of War by studying the Wolves
that you have in front of you
Wolves are smart
and organized
They Work together
and obey their leader's decision
More than anything else
they have patience
Life is about choosing the moment
Wolves and Mongols understand that
A'ba
Yes
After I escaped from the Wolf pack
I saw something in the sky
A smiling face
Of course. That was Tengger
Do you imagine
you'd still be alive without Him
See that?
The gazelles are too full t0 run fast
That's What Wolves were Waiting for
They are on the move
Look, they are about to attack
Get your horse. Let's go
Aren't We following them
Too far, too dangerous
Anyway, it will all be over
when We get there
You will see the result tomorrow
You see
the problem for us Mongols
is that our history
Wasn't Written by us
but mostly by our enemies
You speak Mandarin
Maybe one day
you'll Write about who We really are
I'm a reader
Not a Writer
There's a difference
How do you know
Have you ever tried
Look at our son
now a real man
Chen Zhen, follow me
You understand What the wolves have done
A great Mongol general
did exactly the same thing
a few centuries ago
Mugali drove the cavalry of the great J in Dynasty
into this snowdrift
They're probably
still buried there
Welcome t0 Wolves' fridge
They store their meat here t0 next spring
for their newborn
Take your carpet
if you don't Want to be changed into Wolf food
Be careful
Are you alright
Here is one
Pull hard, son
Pull it. Bravo
Pull. Pull
Pull it hard my son
Pull it hard
Bravo
Bayard fished one
I got one
Let's go
A'ba, this one is still alive
Let it go
If it gets stuck again
it Will be the Will of Tengger
Let go the live one
These gazelles are such pitiful creatures
Wolves are evil, killing the innocent
oblivious t0 the value of life
No
gazelles are the cruel ones
They eat all the grass
Out here, the grass is life, the Big Life
All else is little life
that depends on the Big life for survival
If gazelles are so horrible
Why do you rescue and free them
This time the Wolves killed too many
We have t0 keep enough gazelles
for them to eat next year
If not
they Will attack our sheep
To the Venerable Tribal Leader
When Will you marry a Mongol girl
and father a Mongol brat
Then you'll be one of us
Especially our beauty Gasma
She howls at night
What are you talking about
Bullshit
We can't sleep Well
Be quite, be quite
She is
the Wolf
and you are
the sheep
She sticks her teeth in your neck
Shut up! You will pay for that
You always say bullshit
Dare you say that again
I am gonna teach you a lesson
Batu, did I say anything wrong
Lamj av said the same thing too
You have t0 blame yourself
You deserve it
You such a bad guy
Dare you say that again
You deserve that
Help
A present for you
Here you are
This is Yill, it is my dog
Yill
you stole my meat
What's up
Shartseren
Let's go
Let's stay
We can take more gazelles tomorrow
We have enough
What's left is the Wolves' share
Tengger is telling us to leave
OK
We have more than enough for ourselves
You'd never see this much meat in the east
Have you heard of
the famine there
So Where's this big snow lake of yours
There's no such place
One hundred and twenty yuan
Yes
Let's go
Bye
I don't have enough money
How much you've got
Eight)'
Bring us more gazelles, then
and you can pay for it
Cheers
To the grassland
It is forbidden t0 say
Hurry, dad is Waiting us for dinner
Thank you
Huffy
Load them all
Pack them fast
Let's get out of here
Hurry UP
One, two, three
Looks like
you've settled right here
We like it here
Don't get too comfortable
You're here
t0 pass on your knowledge
and change these primitives
Your Brigade has been chosen
t0 look after those horses
It's an immense honor
It shows how much the Superior Level
put its trust in you
These horses
are the cream
of the People's Liberation Army's stables
They are a national treasure
Brigade leader
who do you think
could look after these horses
Batu, my son, will be in charge
He is our best herder
Shartseren Will assist him
Thank you
Great
I received this directive
t0 rid the w01ves's lairs of their cubs
I know
it is your custom
You do it every spring, don't you
The wolves' meat storage has been looted
They're already hungry
That's not my problem
Killing the pups
will make them vengeful
They will hit back
and hard
Killing the cubs will reduce their numbers
Less Wolves
will mean more ground squirrels and rabbits
which destroy the pastures
That's an order
Shout if you see a lived one
This one is abandoned. No puppy inside
Over here
Here is a cub
Be careful
So cute
Here you are
Bayar, look
There is another one
It's so cute
Don't kill it
The wolf puppy belongs to Tengger
Tengger is calling him
We are helping him on his Way
It's alright
Don't cry my son
His soul will live forever. He will never die
Tengger, this newborn is Yours
Tengger, please
accept his soul
I love coming here
Sixty centuries of history under our feet
Incredible
What a madness
I still don't understand
Why did We build that Great Walls
in the first place
For thousand years
millions of Han Chinese
were frightened
by a handful of unlettered Mongols
They ride horses
We go on foot
They grow on meat
We grow on rice
Herdsman versus farmers
Wolves versus sheep
A Wolf
She dropped the lamb t0 run faster
Where has it gone
Over there
For sure it's a female
that protect her litter
Right
Come out
I've got an idea
Where did you get these
We'll smoke her out
There is another exit
Bravo Yill, good dog
They are very lovely
Want one?
But that little female, I'll keep for myself
Jealous of your friend?
I am just thinking
that she-Wolf fooled us
She hided her babies
They often do this
They lead us t0 an old lair
but hide their babies elsewhere
It's not the right place
We have t0 look somewhere else
No
she runs away this way
Hey hey
What did I tell you
Here she comes
Where
Look, she has black legs
That's the one
Come
Look
See that
Food scraps
see that?
And cub droppings
Don't touch it
Taste it
They are inside
Quiet
I am going t0 get it
Take this
What
Leave me alone
Not Without dogs
The male may be inside
You moron
the male never stays with the cubs
Let's come back tomorrow
Chen Zhen
I have to do it right now
While the she Wolf is hunting
Tie up my foot
Later
pull me out
Give me the flashlight
Quick
the crowbar
Chen Zhen
don't go further
If the hole collapses, I even can't save you
Chen Zhen
don't go further
Are you OK
Come out
H%OK
Chen Zhen
can you hear me
Pull me out
OK! Let me pull you out
Quickly
Pull me out. I got them
Be quick, pull me out
You're insane
Look, you see, so adorable
I told you that they were here
It's so cute
Hi chaps
How are you
Everyone says you city guys
can't catch cubs
But you did great
You Want t0 sell them t0 me?
No, no, no
Show me
Excellent fur
It's cute, isn't it
Bravo
It Will sell Well
t0 make stoles for foreign ladies
May your soul fly to Tengger
Give me the other ones
Give me
Hand me the bag
May your soul fly to Tengger
Lamj av, no
Chen Zhen
It's for their salvation
Tengger will grant them eternal life
You sure you don't Want to sell them to me
No
our brigade need them to reach our quotas
Too bad
Never mind
Be careful when you skin them
Don't rip the pelt
or it'll be Worthless
Why didn't you stop him
Stop him?
Then we'd have had to kill them ourselves
Chen Zhen
What are you doing
the rope
Chen Zhen
are you insane
How can I pull you out if you don't have the rope
I've had enough
Stroke her, keep stroking her
Don't let her see the cub
Or she will kill it
Good
Good Yill
Will it Work
How could you know if you don't even try
Your babies are hungry
Good Yill
Good. Good wolf
Yill, don't move
Good Yill
Good Wolf
Good
Nurse your babies
Yill
you are the best
Look at him
A real bandit
Do you think this is right
To raise a Wolf in a shepherd's village?
You should have thought about that
before We brought the Wolf back
Me?
As though this Whole mess Was all my idea
OK
my idea
My idea, alright?
It is too much of a risk
t0 keep it here
Then What do you suggest
We should do
What the Mongols do
Kill it and be done
Good night
public enemy
Anticipated gale force Winds coming from Siberia
have moved down t0 the south
This cold front will bring
moderate gale and heavy snowfalls
in the border area
Shartseren, the day shift need help
OK
Hold it tight
The White hair blizzard is coming
Go fast t0 the army horse pasture
don't let anything go Wrong
Give me two Winter coats for the day shift
Come here kid
Be a good boy
Yes, dad
Be careful
Got it
I'm gOillg
Anyone there
Shartseren
Where are you
Can anyone hear me
Batu
Shartseren
Is it you
Are Def) and Qaokt with you
What? Aren't they with you
You're alone?
Yes. Where is the day shift
I can't find them
They have no rifles nor flashlights
They might have gone back to camp
Forget it, let's steady the horses
My horse is out of control, fears something
We may have wolves around
Then we need t0 move fast
Batu, let's gather the horses together
t0 deter the Wolves
OK
Wolves!
Damned Wolves know the lake is dead ahead
Bastards
Push the lead horse t0 the east
Get them away from the lake
To the left
Wolf! Help!
Somebody comes
Chen Zhen, come out! Wolves come
Hurry UP
Gasma
Chen Zhen, stay away
Stand back or the Wolf will bite you
Push the sheep aside
to let the dog through
Here, Bars
Send Bars over
Gasma
Let the dog come
Mama, mama
Let me help you
Move
Shartseren
Get up! Get up fast
Damn it! Go away
Go away
My horse is panicking
Batu, I can't control it
Batu
You damn Wolves
Go t0 hell
I'll kill you all
Sharsteren
Stop them
Stop, you dumb horses
Don't go toward the lake
Stop please
Tengger, help me
This is a disaster
Your brigade is t0 blame
I will report your
gross negligence and disrespect to the leaders
You'll pay for this
Each of you will take responsibility
for failing to protect state property
You especially
Deserted your post
You will be sent t0 quarantine
Do you have anything t0 say
I lost control of my horse
It was bitten by a wolf
And then
then I fell off
I think
You're here t0 Work
not t0 think
Take him away
We are still missing two herders
They probably froze to death
and were eaten by wolves
Incompetent bunch
Shut up
Forget it
Director Bao Shungui
I must beg t0 differ
Our brigade did the best they could
Batu fought t0 death
He died a hero
A hero is someone Who succeeds
to keep those horses
What kind of hero is he
The culprits are those
Who stole all their gazelles
caused the Wolves to starve
and took their revenge on us
Enough
Let the authorities decide who the culprits are
I'll help you
Leave him
He chose t0 get off here
This place is suitable
A'ba
It's too rocky
to bury him here
Let's find another place
Mongols don't bury their dead
We grasslanders eat meat all our life
for which We killed many creatures
After We die
We donate our meat
back t0 the Grassland
I stitched it up
Here you are
Thank you
Yesterday
You were very brave
My man says
thank you
He told me last night in my dream
Gasma
Thanks for your dog saving my life
Who is this meat for
You were right
I was jealous
I took one of Yill's puppies
Add millet in it
Wolf mothers chew meat and bones
for their babies
We use
porridge with meat
and milk in it t0 feed little dogs
The authorities
has completed its investigation
on the army horses disaster
All charges
are dropped
The authorities regret
the heavy losses your brigade suffered
Batu's
Work points
will be transferred t0 his Widow
As head of production
I entrust Bilig
with taking over
Batu's duties
But I Won't tolerate any more mistakes
All charges against Batu's assistant Shartseren
are dropped as Well
Set him free
Chen Zhen
do it now
What
Free your Wolf cub
I can't free him right now
He has the smell of man now
The pack may kill him
Chen Zhen
What's this
Open
A Wolf cub
Chen Zhen
What's this
I confess
I'm raising it
This is just an experiment
Chairman Mao says:
Study your enemy to defeat him.
So I thought We should observe wolves
more closely
I say No
We could protect our herds
by mating him with our dogs
That can't Work
At university
I taught the improvement of species
That is my goal
Bullshit
Chen Zhen
your idea is good
You have my approval
Director Bao
the Wolves are all over the place
They heard the cub
and will come for it
Good! Let them come
Your Wolf cub
Will lure them
Did you hear me
Leave it alone
Get back
Go away
This is madness
Lamj av
take him away
OK, OK
Back
Hurry, go back
Hurry UP
Got it
Brothers, this is Tenggefs Will
Wolves Won't come tonight
Brothers, let's go
Let's go
The little wolf doesn't speak the pack's language
Waste of our time. Let's go
They Won't attack for a puppy
they are not sure about
Bayar
come here
Are you mad
Let's go
A'ba
Please forgive me
You captured a god to turn it into a slave
What you are doing is an affront
to our ancestors and t0 Tengger
You will pay one day
And so Will this old man
A'ba
Don't call me that
I was Wrong
You're right
I offended you and the Mongols
Tell me how do you Want me
t0 dispose of this poor little Wolf
Look
that's the border
This is
the last piece of Chinese grassland
that has not been plowed
the last untouched lake
As soon as lambs are strong enough
to make the trip
We will set our summer camp out here
You say I treat my Wolf as a slave
In fact, it is I who am his servant
I Wait on him like I Would a Mongol Prince
I give him my ration of meat
I can't sleep Well at night
I Worry about him being cold, or sick
or bitten by dogs, or carried away by an eagle
Yang Ke says I am the Wolf's slave
Wolves Want the dignity to earn their own meat
They don't Want to be fed
They want to kill at the risk of being killed
They are Warriors
What sort of Warrior will he be
if you take his pride away
if you forbid him to kill
if you teach him to fear death
A'ba
I think here is a very good place
for the Wolf cub to live
Give me a few weeks
t0 grow him stronger
When We come here
I Will set him free
I promise
As the old saying goes
"it's easier t0 climb on the tiger's back
than to get off it"
Chen Zhen
What's going on
Just a second
What are you doing
I'm getting angry
You can't stay here you know
Dogs and eagles would eat you
Understand?
Don't you understand
Don't be silly
You are smart
We are going t0 a great new place
You'll be happy there
Come on
You have...
no choice
I'm angry with you now
Hurry UP
Go
Let's go
StOP
Stop the carts
What's going on
Let him go, for God's sake
Once and for all
How can he survive if I let him go
He can't hunt
What Will he eat
Will the Wolves accept him
I have to take care of him
What are you doing
Are you crazy
What's Wrong
We need dry dung
for the journey
How are We going t0 cook
I'll take care of it
I'll pick up more on the Way
Pick up more?
What if it rains
What are you thinking? Let him go
I've had enough
This is my Wolf, not your Wolf
I am the one who loves him
You don't understand. Go away
Go away
HEY
How long didn't you eat meat
I don't need t0 eat meat
Is he sick
He is punishing me
Yang Ke
Look
Behind this mountain it is the Swan Lake
This is the place I told you about
that looks like heaven
Look
look at the swans
There, do you see it
Here come the nomads
Bilig
Welcome
I didn't think you would come here, too
Did you see
These people will be you new neighbors
Just like me
they're Mongols from the east
Very experienced
in farming and agriculture
They come here
because they've ruined their own land
Our soil is too thin
It's not suited for plowing
Old Bilig
there are people starving down east
They have no choice
but making use of lands like this one
Look, We'll build a school here
a dispensary there
We will use traps and poison
t0 eradicate all toxic plants
Pests, mosquitoes
rats
and wolves of course
Stop shooting
Let's find somewhere else
Director
t0 settle down
The swans are so beautiful
Stop the shooting,
I beg you
Have you seen Swan Lake
What are you doing
Want to run away?
Don't tell me
this one was killed by an eagle too
No?
By lightning, perhaps?
Do you know
What our parents would do
for a piece of meat like that in Beijing
Little Wolf, time t0 eat
Time t0 eat
Grow up quickly
You have t0 become stronger
Stronger than foxes, eagles, and Wide wolves
Got it?
Watch out
See that?
Wolf trap
Remember it when you're free
Get it?
Don't be afraid
You know you have t0 learn how t0 swim
You are a real Wolf
Come on
Bravo
In the grassland, the mosquito season came
As Bilig A'ba predicted
mosquitoes that survived the Winter
in marmot holes
invaded the grassland
in larger numbers than ever
Cattle withered
Unable t0 hunt
starving and scraggy
Wolves moved closer t0 populated areas
They preyed on cattle
The new settlers retaliated
Where are you going
Where are you taking me
What's that
What's that smell that makes you so happy
Slowly
What's up With you
Come back
I said come back, did you hear me
Back
Come back
You monster
How dare you bite me
Sorry, I am Wrong
You are a real Mongolian Wolf
I am proud of you
What happened
Nothing
Your Wolf did it?
You are mad
It's 0k
Just a scratch
I told you
they have poison in their teeth
They don't
That's just superstition
You don't get it
How do you think Wuli lost his leg
or Bayin his arm
It's like a snake's bite
Your arm will fester and they will cut it off
Without a injection, you will die
I don't need your help
Where can I get an injection
At the hospital
But
all those new settlers are using everything up
Maybe there is nothing left
It Will hurt a bit
You have t0 be careful
Does Batu
still come in your dream
Sometimes
Is he happier now
No
What does he Want
None of your business
I know one thing
He Wants you t0 remarry
Nothing strange about that
His son needs a father
His woman needs a man
She doesn't
She's too busy
He Wants you to choose me
Why would he Want me t0 choose you
You are a Han student
Because he knows I love you
You know it as well
Maybe you feel the same
Gasma
Stop it
You Won't stay
Who said I Won't stay
Your home is Beijing
There is no future for the two of us
Everybody knows how these things end
They don't know me
Here is my real home
My life before was meaningless
What can I do
t0 make you trust me
There is no need
My new man has been chosen
By Whom
BY you?
He is Bao shungufs brother
Have you already met him
Have you
His wife's dead
He is a peasant
A Mongol from the east
It will help national unity
Nonsense
If you Want national unity
marry me
It's ridiculous
Does A'ba know
I am going to ask A'ba
He gave his approval
He said We should keep up with the times
Lock them in the sheep pen and We can go home
Lock the sheep
Seal the door, there are wolves outside
Little Wolf, little Wolf, time to eat
Eat the bowl While you're at it
Bayar
I am off to my shift
Could you look after the little Wolf
Make sure that no one bothers him, 0k?
See you later
Hurry UP
I Want to see the wolf
No, you can't
Let me go inside, I will give you two candies
Here you are
What means
Well?
Can't open it
OK, no touching
Let's go inside
Do you understand
Let me go first
Leave him alone
Don't pull the chain
He will bite you
Stay away
There may be either bomb or poison
Yang Ke
Why is he here so early
How can I know
I am here
What are you doing
Just had a nap
I am coming
Stay here. I will deal with him
Anyone there
Your mother
No, it's not
Hide yourself anyway
Crawl. Crawl
Yang Ke, where is my belt
Bayar has been bitten
By What
Your stupid friend's Wolf
Hurry up! Come with me
Hurry UP
We can't sew up his Wounds
Better t0 leave them open
I gave you the last shot of penicillin
and rabies vaccine We had
Without it, it's going t0 be touch and go
You can Wait here
I am sorry
Get out
Out
If anything bad happens t0 my son
I Will kill your Wolf
then kill myself
Nurse, is the doctor here
Sit and Wait
It's urgent
For the others too. Just wait
Doctor
Doctor! Doctor
What are you shouting for
Doctor
Stop shouting
Are you the doctor
Are you the doctor or not
Don't you see the operating room
Where is the doctor
Go sit there and Wait
Doctor
I told you to go there t0 Wait
Whose horse is biting the tree
Hey, your horse! Go look after your horse
What are you doing? Wait your turn
Doctor, I need penicillin
Penicillin
What penicillin
I don't have Penicillin
Don't go in there
Why do you need penicillin
A child has been bitten by a Wolf
The doctor in the county-town said that
Without Penicillin
the Wounds will get infected and he will die
I rode for twenty hours to get here
Do you have Penicillin here
Well
Where is the Penicillin
Stop that
You Won't find Penicillin here
Alright
Wolf teeth, Wolf claws
and
Wolf heart, Wolf kidney
Can you get me those things
Then we could make a deal
I just Want Penicillin
Then it's a deal
Give me Penicillin
Wolves are attacking the sheep pen
Let's go kill the Wolves
Chen Zhen. Come out
Chen Zhen
Chen Zhen, come out
Is it the right place
Anyone there
Chen Zhen
Come out
What are you doing
What is going on here
Come out
Where is your Wolf-loving friend
He is not here, he went to town
That was five days ago
Why's he not back
I don't know
There was an emergency
It is your Wolf cub
who called the flying Wolves t0 attack
What's flying Wolf
Wolves don't fly
They do
My grandpa saw it With his own eyes
That's right
It's not here
Then where is it
Tell me the truth
Where did you hide the Wolf cub
He's on his chain
Let's go
He's been on his chain
You damn Wolf
Get away from it! Drop the chain
Move, move your ass
Don't beat it
Beat the Wolf Beat the Wolf
StOP
What is going on here
I'll kill you
What's all this
Let it go
Wolves massacred our sheep
Idiots
It's the Wild Wolves
that are your problem
And I am here
with the solution
Are you alright
Where is Bilig
He is not well, he's been injured
A'ba
Tell me
What happened t0 you
Chen Zhen
It's important to keep one's appointment
I have heard Tengger a lot recently
He's calling me
Don't be silly
We are going to hunt Wolves
Revenge for you
Your Wounds will be recovered soon
Chen Zhen
I have to talk t0 you
You are the Wolf expert now
Follow me
Let's go
It is OK
Don't be afraid
The bad guys are gone, promised
They won't bother you anymore
I'll be right back
Get in
The grass is too tall here
Why did you bring us here
Go north, that way
Did you do it on purpose
to stop us finding the Wolves
Most of them have already been killed
Our jeeps make too much noise anyway
Maybe We should
Look
On the hillside t0 the left!
Two Wolves, over there
Try t0 follow them
Stay parallel
Ready
Fire
Two down
It is just a start
Let's go
Go fast! Go!
There! Take the pack down slope
This is an old couple. They Won't go far
The wolf jumped
What the
Their fur is Worthless
Better die than get skinned
Mom, is it healing
It's alright, it's fine
Mom, then Why are you crying
Bring the jetty can
Bartel, come
Block their escape t0 the West
This Way
Don't let them escape
Go! Spill the fuel
StOP
Fire is forbidden in the steppe
So are Wolves
The nomads will hate you
They hate me anyway
Even more so
since I helped you
keep your Wolf
Being a leader
is not about being liked
Sometimes, you have t0 obey orders
that your heart resents
Save your bullet
their fur is Worthless anyway
The pack leader
Don't shoot
We need his fur intact
Without holes
Try t0 exhaust it
Good, good
I need it alive, don't be rush
Bravo
Go faster
No shooting
How long has it been running
About 38 kilometers
It will be done soon
Now What
Chen Zhen
Chen Zhen. Come back
Have you lost your mind
Chen Zhen
Come back
You spared my life a year ago
Go away
Quickly
They can't follow you
in those rocks
Go away
Leave it here
He belongs to Tengger
Do What he says
I fed your Wolf
His appetite is good
Let's unload these dead Wolves
How is Bayar
Fine
But A' ba is not good
The wolves are all dead
Serf)'
Not all of them
Yours is still alive
I promised A'ba
I'd set the cub free
The hunt is over
It's the best time of the year
He'll be safe
in the Northern range mountains
I have to do it
Because I love him
But I lack courage
Little Wolf
Little Wolf, time t0 eat
I'm sorry, I'm late today
Little Wolf
Where's little wolf
I returned him
to the grassland
You killed him?
I should have
But I couldn't
I freed it
You had no right
He is my wolf
He is Tenggefs Wolf
I owned Him
a life
Two actually
Bayar is saved then
Almost healed, it's a miracle
It's the power of modern medicine
it's the future
You Han people
With Bilig's death
it Was the grassland I knew
and I loved that was dying
Time had come for me
to become again
the young city man I'd never ceased to be
Little Wolf
The memory of the little Wolf
haunted Chen Zhen forever
He devoted his life to Write a book
in the hope that the Wolves' long-songs
will be once again
over the restored splendor of Mongolians grassland