Dear sister and brother-in-law,
thank you.
From here on in, it's your show.
Isn't it our turn for photos?
Where are the kids?
Grandma...
Iook.
It was on the tree.
Anything wrong?
You know that strange woman?
Can I help you, Miss?
-Looking for someone.
-May I ask who?
Mind your own business!
Yun-Yun!
Ting-Ting...
you look so pretty today!
Where's your grandma?
I'm so sorry!
It should have been me
marrying your son today!
I let you down, I'm so sorry.
It breaks my heart,
I'm not worthy of you!
-Don't push me around!
-It's not that bad!
Where is she?
Where is that pregnant bitch?
Dad...
Grandma wants to go home.
Go home?
She doesn't feel well.
And tonight?
Where's Xiao Yan?
Show your face, Xiao Yan!
Give A-Di back to me!
You'll face retribution
for this!
Sorry about the mess.
We're the Jiangs...I'm Lili.
I'm Ting-Ting.
This is my grandma.
We're the Jians.
See you later, bye!
Ting-Ting!
Take out the garbage
before we go.
I'm doing it.
It's starting to smell.
There's some on the balcony.
I know.
What was I getting?
How did you find me?
Followed the removal men.
Mother will be livid!
I miss you!
Don't I call you?
Can't see you on the phone.
Come.
Sorry, I'm in the middle
of moving house.
It's a huge mess!
Call me on this mobile number.
I'll have a phone line
in tomorrow.
No problem.
Ready, Ting-Ting?
What's on your mind?
I feel sorry for Yun-Yun.
If it's not Uncle's fault,
it must be Xiao Yan's.
Don't say that.
We hardly know her.
I think Grandma's right.
We can't accept her.
Did Grandma say that?
No...
but she's been unhappy all day.
Did she say anything else?
No, but she said
she feels really old.
What does she mean by that?
The groom is right behind me!
Put your hands together!
Your wife's brother is some guy!
Not many weddings
with the bride so very pregnant!
That's the way he is!
He put off the wedding
for months...
because this is the luckiest day
of the year in the almanac.
Take his shoe!
Don't mess with girls!
Pregnant brides
aren't unusual these days.
We had
"bus rides without tickets"...
in our day, too, you know.
Sorry, Yang-Yang,
this is your seat.
Girls teased him again.
Never mind, have some food.
So, did you and NJ?
Guess.
No, thanks!
You women always
trap men that way.
It still works.
It worked on your brother.
NJ would be a pushover.
So?
Here's the bus-rider!
What? I drove myself here.
Drink!
It's on my brother-in-law.
Why aren't you eating?
Those girls teased him again.
Try this new toy!
Just let him be.
Is it really you?
You're still in Taipei?
I live...in the U.S. now.
Your son?
So cute.
This is my number.
Call me.
Why didn't you come that day?
I waited and waited...
I've never got over it,
you know.
Sherry!
How many years has it been?
Almost thirty!
Not that long!
It hasn't been that long
since we graduated.
Didn't know you two
were still in touch.
We just ran into
each other by chance.
Good to see you still get along!
My namecard.
My husband does business
in China...
so I'll be in town quite a bit.
-Stay in touch, OK?
-I sure will.
Sorry, I've run out of
namecards.
I keep forgetting to...
Sorry, I must go.
-Remember, stay in touch!
-Promise!
It really is a lucky day.
I've forgotten
my own first love.
Why do I remember yours?
What did I come down for?
Some tea?
No, thanks.
-Something wrong?
-Nothing.
Dad, your cigar burst it!
See what happens when you smoke
those disgusting things?
It wasn't...
Then who was it?
Er...Whatever.
Quiet! Shut it!
Now the elders are involved.
Fair enough.
They must both drink.
One each!
What the fuck is this?
It's called a "depth charge."
You'll both have
pot bellies after this!
Beer!
Plus fruit juice!
Chewed betel nuts!
Eggs and salt!
Drink up!
Applause!
Is it raining?
Can you manage
the stuff in the trunk?
If not, ask Dad to bring it in
when he's parked.
Don't forget the big bag.
Mrs. Jian! Why are you so late?
Get to the hospital!
Your mother's been rushed there!
My mother?
Wait!
I'll go in to see her first, NJ.
Wait here for A-Di.
He'll be here soon.
Tell Ting-Ting
to put Yang-Yang to bed.
I did. You go ahead!
What does the doctor say?
She's had a stroke.
They need to operate.
I saw her lying in the driveway
by the dustbins.
Did she fall over?
Was she hit by a car?
Why was she downstairs?
You drove here drunk?
The cops drink, too!
Don't worry, NJ.
Sister called
and told me what happened.
Mother will be fine. It's
the luckiest day of the year!
-She'll wake up in no time.
-A-Di, it's not that simple.
Maybe you don't trust me.
Things are different now!
I was unlucky, so I borrowed
from you and sister.
Now my luck has turned!
I'll be repaying you soon!
-There's no rush.
-Trust me!
You saw my partner
Piggy tonight.
He'll pay me back tomorrow,
and I'll pay you back next day!
Ting-Ting took out the garbage
in the afternoon.
What was Mother doing
down by the dustbins?
We don't know if she fell
or was knocked over by a car.
My brother says
she'll recover quickly.
It was the luckiest day
of the year.
He put off his wedding
for this lucky day.
Nothing unlucky can happen.
Otherwise,
Mother would be dead by now.
That's one way to see it.
How else?
Don't complicate things!
How's this, Min-Min?
Didn't I say
it goes to City Hall?
How does your Master see it?
You should ask him yourself,
I think.
I spent two weeks
at the temple with you.
But I didn't understand
his teachings.
I don't think the Master
would take me as his disciple.
Two weeks may not be enough.
Look how busy I am.
How can I find the time?
Maybe you need
a bit more humility.
Are you saying
there's something wrong with me?
Look at Yang-Yang!
My auntie was like this
at her wedding.
So fat?
No. Guess why.
What's under your shirt?
A balloon!
One inside the other!
She's coming!
Concubine! Concubine!
Is she the Concubine?
Shut up!
Stay there!
Get on with your work!
What's that in your hand?
Nothing.
Better watch yourself!
Yang-Yang, she likes you!
Her old man will be jealous!
Who's her old man?
Today...
one of you has brought
something bad to class.
Who is it?
Who has brought a condom?
Stand up!
If he won't admit it,
I'll name him.
Jian Yang-Yang, it's you!
Stand up!
Hand over your condom!
What's a condom?
Playing dumb?
Don't laugh! You're shameless!
You can't hide it!
I know everything!
Who's telling lies about me?
Never you mind!
You just heard something,
you didn't see it.
So I'm wrong, am l?
You think I need
to see it to know?
I even know
which pocket it's in.
Your left pocket. Come on!
What's this?
A balloon.
Quiet!
I'll let it go this time...
but you'd better watch out!
Finish your milk!
We both will be late.
You'll never grow tall.
Good morning, Mrs. Jiang.
First Girls' High.
Great school!
You are good.
So is Lili!
I hear her playing every day,
so beautiful.
I hope it's not too loud.
Do you play an instrument?
Yes, but I'm not very good.
Better to be good at books,
anyway.
What's the point?
Last year's profits are gone.
Everyone does computers now.
Remember how
the garment business crashed?
The more orders you fill,
the more money you lose.
Instead of cashing in...
you blew it all
on lavish expansion plans.
So, what can I do?
You screwed up real bad.
What can I do?
We do have a strategy,
one step at a time.
There's always ups and downs
at a time of transition.
I warn you...
one more negative review...
and we'll pull out.
So, what's this strategy?
Moving into software?
Or into...content?
Damn right!
It's still hush-hush.
Heard of a Japanese named Ota?
Computer games?
-That surprised you, right?
-Promising...
Go on!
We're always cutting-edge!
Sure you are!
But you're down the tube
if we pull out.
Why "cash in"
when we were ahead?
"No prisoners" was our policy.
Remember?
He better shut up!
Why should he?
You were too honest
and told him everything.
I'm not like you.
We don't even know this "Ota."
And we're going bust!
He doesn't come cheap.
He's a brand name!
We buy his name
to attract investors.
Brand name? What if it
costs too much to recoup?
It's our neck. I'm against it.
Taiwan has the best copycats.
Are they ripping off
Ota's stuff?
I'll check.
What will you guys do
if we go bust?
I know. You'll retire,
stay home, and smoke your pipe.
Da-Da, you'll move
to San Francisco?
And you, NJ?
All your money's in the company,
isn't it?
He didn't hear me.
He doesn't want to answer.
He has other things on his mind.
I'm going. Uncle is here.
Ting-Ting! You're leaving?
Yes. You two enjoy yourselves.
I didn't know
she was meeting you.
She and I are still very close.
Hey, everything's fine now.
I even urged Ting-Ting
to be kind to your new wife.
We didn't marry,
but we're still friends.
All these years!
Yes, many years.
You're so calm. I'm surprised.
Let's get to work.
Everyone was stunned by what
you did at the wedding banquet.
Don't get me going again, OK?
Here, look.
I've transferred part of
our savings to your account.
We cleared twenty million
on Yahoo and AOL.
Part of it is in a mutual fund.
The documents here
need your authorization.
And find me a boyfriend.
I'm alone now. You know that.
Figures give me a headache.
Lili!
I heard your grandma
is in the hospital.
Yes.
Is it serious?
She's in a coma. She fell.
I love your grandma.
She's so elegant.
She was a teacher.
It's your boyfriend.
Right.
Why don't you go over?
I'll see you later.
You should move her
every hour or so.
Like this.
A different position every time.
First one side, like this...
then the other, like that.
And put a pillow under her back.
That's the way.
And pat her back often.
Do it yourself
if the nurse isn't here.
-That's for her circulation?
-Exactly.
I think that's all.
Doctor...
how long before Mother
regains consciousness?
It's hard to say.
Treat her normally.
Open her window in the daytime.
Take her out in the wheelchair,
turn off the lights at night.
Most important, talk to her.
It stimulates her senses.
But I'm not optimistic.
You should prepare
for the worst.
Sorry, brother-in-law,
I haven't repaid you yet.
Never mind.
If I forget again, remind me.
I'm thinking about the company.
Bad mood?
More financial problems?
You're not going bust, are you?
I'm thinking about the meeting
with the Japanese tomorrow.
Fuck! Are you in debt to Japan?
No! What are you saying?
Of course not!
Yang-Yang...
it's your turn.
From now on, we'll take turns
to talk to Grandma.
It will make her wake up sooner.
Ting-Ting hasn't done it.
She played the piano,
didn't she?
I could show her my drawings,
but she can't see.
But she'll hear you.
Didn't the doctor say so?
There's lots to tell her.
Like what happened at school...
or some little secret you have.
You can tell Grandma anything.
What's the matter?
Why that grumpy look?
Don't want to talk to her?
What's the point?
She can't see what I tell her.
What?
Are you trying to get out of it?
That's not nice!
How can you let Grandma down?
You're making me cross!
Don't they teach you
anything at school?
Grandma loves you so much.
You can't just ignore her,
can you?
You just can't!
You take a break.
I'll talk to her first.
It's my turn.
Ma, I'm good at talking.
Luck's on my side now,
don't worry.
I'm rich now.
People come to me for loans!
Not like the old days when
my borrowing made you worry.
I've made lots of rich friends.
And...
Don't you worry about Xiao Yan.
She's a nice girl.
Really...
And...what else...
The other stuff...
I guess you know.
If you have questions,
you can't ask...
Today...
Iet's call it...
You must be tired...
I'll try, and tomorrow...
That's for...today...
Grandma.
Did I forget
to take the garbage out?
I can't remember.
If you forgive me, wake up.
Please?
Because I can't sleep
if you don't.
Survival instincts
are all the same.
Overfeeding may not
improve growth.
It may diminish
evolutionary impulses.
So, the drive
to reproduce declines.
Some of you
can't bring them into bloom.
You're overdoing the care.
Like, say...Jian Ting-Ting.
Jian Ting-Ting!
She stays up all night
nurturing her plant.
The others must be slacking.
See how they bloom?
It begins to acquire
signs of human life.
It begins to think...
then matures
into a living entity...
and becomes
our most devoted companion.
That's the limitless future
for computer games.
We haven't yet surpassed...
fighting and killing games.
Not because we haven't fully
understood computers.
But because we haven't fully
understood ourselves...
human beings.
Our future collaboration can be
based on these objectives.
This is the way forward.
These are uncharted waters...
so I understand
your hesitations.
But this cutting-edge approach
puts us well ahead...
of any future competition.
So there are ample grounds
for optimism.
That concludes my presentation,
thank you.
Wonderful!
We learned a lot today!
Really good.
No one's dared try it before...
but we have to pay for it?
I thought we were just buying
a brand name, pure and simple.
I liked what he said.
It's a risk worth taking.
Shit, you were
against it before!
He's too expensive,
not worth it.
I found a local copycat of Ota.
Calls itself "Ato."
Close enough?
Forget the names!
What about performance?
Small return on small risks.
Big deal!
It beats big losses
on big risks.
Let's not sign with him yet.
Find an excuse
to send him back to Tokyo.
That's not nice!
Who has to tell him?
NJ, take Mr. Ota
to dinner tonight.
Tell him we're keen to sign...
but play hard to get.
Let's buy some time.
-Why me?
-You look honest!
So? Am I pretending?
What's wrong
with a little acting?
So honesty is an act?
And friendship? Business?
Is anything real left?
Don't mind
what I said about acting.
We've been a team
since schooldays.
Sure, why else
do I stick around?
By the way, Sherry's husband,
Rodney Breitner...
He's from Chicago,
big in insurance.
Good reputation.
I had a long talk with her
on the phone.
She asked me to say "Hi."
Give her a call sometime.
Just as a classmate,
not an ex-lover.
It's not locked.
You're home early.
I was next door.
Hello? Dad!
Yang-Yang hid the phone.
I couldn't find it.
It was under the seat cushion.
We're cooking a health-food
dinner and you'll miss it!
OK, next time.
Yes, I'll tell Ma.
That was my dad.
He's going to miss
my masterpiece.
Well, that's his loss.
So, what's next?
Check that page.
We're out of carrots.
We have some.
Next time, I'll show you
my pad in Shanghai.
My daughter's in.
My daughter Lili.
Call him Uncle.
Call me Allen.
You're cooking?
Nice place you have here.
Hi, Mrs. Jiang.
Ting-Ting, you're cooking too?
Big job, isn't it?
It's fun!
Join us for a health-food feast!
We're going to the movies.
That's nice. Hold on.
Allen, make yourself at home.
I'm fine.
We're going to the movies?
It's on me.
Treat Ting-Ting to a good show.
Your daughter is a musician!
She certainly is.
She's won prizes.
Lots of comedies.
Which one do you fancy?
We can do something else
if you'd prefer.
Welcome.
Can I help you?
Our friend is...
They're my friends.
Hi, Fatty.
I thought you were cooking.
What are you doing?
Checking these.
I don't come here every day.
Wait for me
at the usual place, OK?
"Fatty"? He's so thin.
Maybe he used to be fat.
You shouldn't mind waiting.
He's often waited for you.
It's not that.
He'll be here soon.
Want to be alone?
I can go home.
OK.
Don't worry. He'll be here soon.
Keep it down!
This isn't your own place!
Hey, you seem
to be disturbing her.
Cool it.
It's not our fault that
your boyfriend stood you up.
Leave her alone.
Been in the army too long.
I'm not used to this.
Don't worry.
I may look rough,
but I have a heart of gold.
Let it be, OK?
This must be fish.
Where's he from? He's good.
Japan. I just met him.
He plays well
for a computer guy.
Bring more friends like him.
Great for atmosphere.
Times are hard.
We're in trouble.
Come more often.
Sherry? It's me, NJ.
I'm glad it's the machine.
Otherwise, I'd be tongue-tied.
Da-Da said he spoke to you.
He says you're doing well.
I'm so glad.
Before, I'd heard
your life was tough.
I felt it might be my fault.
You asked why I vanished
without a word thirty years ago.
There were many reasons.
Now they all sound stupid.
I'm glad that
you have a good life.
I'm really happy for you.
All my best wishes.
I have nothing to say to Mother.
I tell her
the same things every day.
What I did in the morning.
In the afternoon.
In the evening.
It only takes a minute.
I can't bear it.
I have so little.
How can it be so little?
I live a blank!
Every day...every day...
I'm like a fool!
What am I doing every day?
If I ended up like her
one day...
I'll ask the nurse to read
the newspaper to her.
She'll have something new
to listen to, OK?
I was busy!
So was l! Why should I wait
all day for you to call?
-Where were you last night?
-Why should I tell you?
You think I'm some dumb bitch?
Why should I wait for you?
Give me back the cell phone!
What are you doing?
You asking me?
Get the hell out!
Fuck you, you nosy bitch!
You're a fucking joke!
Yang-Yang, the lift's here.
Don't stare at people like that.
It's rude.
People will be cross.
I wanted to know
why she's unhappy.
I can't see from behind.
How do you know she's unhappy?
She had a big fight last night.
I could hear from my room.
Really?
Daddy, I can't see what you see
and you can't see what I see.
How can I know what you see?
Good question.
I never thought of that.
That's why we need a camera.
Do you want to play with one?
Daddy, can we only know
half of the truth?
What? I don't get it.
I can only see what's in front,
not what's behind.
So I can only know
half of the truth, right?
You have
a lot of questions today!
Let me ask you one...
Where shall we take Mummy
this weekend to cheer her up?
You can decide.
Min-Min!
Still here?
Nancy...
Where can I go?
What are you doing?
What are you snapping?
I want to show Mummy
the mosquitoes.
Mosquitoes? Can you snap them?
Daddy said so,
or people won't believe me.
That's not our place.
I know.
Your Mum and I both think
they are strange.
Is Mummy home?
I haven't seen her lately.
My boss is here. Bye.
Your partners are in a meeting
with Ato Company.
They want you to join them.
Ato?
Isn't it Ota? I wasn't told.
No. Ato is Ota's copycat.
Confusing, isn't it?
General Manager's office.
The President's in a meeting.
May I say who called?
No? Thank you.
General Manager's office.
My boss is here.
I'll call you later.
General Manager's office.
Hold on.
NJ, long-distance from the U.S.
I knew it was you.
You take care of the company.
I'm staying home.
Call me when you need me.
Seems I'm the only one left
to keep you company.
When Min-Min was home,
I thought...
she'd solve
all the problems around here.
But now...
there's no one to do it.
And I really don't know
when she'll be back.
It's hard for me
to mumble like this.
I hope you won't be offended
if I say...
it's like praying.
I'm not sure if the other party
can hear me...
and I'm not sure
if I'm sincere enough.
Frankly...
there's very little
I'm sure about these days.
I wake up feeling unsure
about almost everything.
And I wonder
why I wake up at all...
just to face the same
uncertainties again and again.
Would you want to wake up,
if you were me?
Maybe Yang-Yang's right.
You've lived so many more years.
Other than these questions
we can't answer...
what is there to tell you?
Anyhow, I guess
you don't blame Yang-Yang...
for not talking to you.
In many ways, he takes after me.
Really.
Which brand do you want?
The same one.
Which was that?
This one.
Right, hold on.
Shida Road Art Portraits.
Can I help you?
And the surname is...?
OK, I'll check.
What the...?
What the hell are all these?
Oh, I get it.
This is what they call
avant-garde art!
Amazing!
Class,
time for some art appreciation!
What's it for?
It's art! Expensive art!
Why is art expensive?
Why take so many?
Look at him!
Our newfound maestro!
A rare genius in our school!
Didn't you love to talk back?
Take after your father, right?
Tell him you are caught
in the act.
Call him...
and ask for help!
Scared?
Stand there until he comes!
Don't pull that face at me!
Turn around against the wall!
I dare you, do that again!
How was it the other night?
Isn't Lili home yet?
Could you give this to her?
Uh...nothing.
This...
is for you.
-It's...
-I know.
"Wen-Ho Lee,
originally from Tainan...
"was found to be
in breach of Security Codes...
"and dismissed from his post
at Los Alamos Research Lab.
"To date,
the Federal authorities...
"do not have enough evidence
to prosecute him...
"as a spy."
"Taipei City
Rapid Transit Commission...
"has lost its lawsuit...
"against the French company
Matra..."
Let's eat.
You don't like my cooking?
Been to McDonald's again?
Why so moody?
He got picked on.
Girls, right?
Master wants to see you.
Please come in, Master.
Ting-Ting, Nancy is here!
Will you make some tea?
Have you eaten?
We just did.
First, Min-Min
is doing well in the temple.
Master wanted to visit you...
so as to know
Min-Min's family better.
Mr. Jian, most people
neglect spiritual disciplines.
So you missed Min-Min's signals.
Yang-Yang,
don't run around naked!
You should join us
on the mountain.
A purified soul helps the gods
to answer prayers.
Nothing would help
your wife more.
Like everyone, my wife and l
need help from others.
But maybe I'd anger the gods
by making too many requests.
If I turn to them only for
the big things I can't handle...
my sincerity
may impress them more.
But...
I haven't yet had troubles
I couldn't handle myself.
These thoughts
seem interesting...
They do this work voluntarily.
Your encouragement
means so much.
I see.
Do you take checks?
Of course.
Thanks, NJ.
Your wife is in good hands.
Thanks for all the help.
It's our pleasure.
Lend me $300.
I have nothing on me.
A cab driver's waiting.
I owe him $300.
You'd die without me!
Aren't you lucky?
The clothes you left
are still here.
Do they still fit?
How did you get into this mess?
She went crazy and threw me out.
I went to NJ's place...
He threw you out, too?
I still owe him money.
I was ashamed to borrow...
from him again.
Didn't I give you nine million
to clear your debt with NJ?
I let Piggy invest that.
He says it's tripled in value.
Piggy?
I hear he's on the run in China.
Bullshit.
I won big on mahjong
at his place last week.
Cash?
I see.
Let's visit him tomorrow
to check.
OK?
Thank you so much.
It'll only take a minute.
No problem, just shut the door
when you leave.
Don't tell anyone I let you in!
Trust me.
Fatso, learn from your wife!
See how easy she handles me?
Thanks a lot.
They're no slouches,
cleaned the place out.
How much money have I got left?
Barely!
Didn't we just make ten million?
Values can go down, too!
Shit, what are these?
You mean...
I'm broke again.
Why did you trust
a guy like Piggy?
Come here.
Remember this:. Trust no one!
It's just junk.
Fucking useless!
Are you skipping
audio/visual class?
Buzz off!
Here she comes!
Quick!
Good morning, Dean.
Lovely new outfit!
You little fuckers! Don't run!
I'll get you! You fuckers!
"Warm, damp air rises
as the earth heats up.
"At high altitude, it condenses
into small droplets..."
Get in, quick!
"This creates
these beautiful clouds."
"To the quiet rhythms
of nature...
"they dance silently
above our heads.
"Often we overlook
their beauty."
"As they dance higher...
"they silently turn into hail...
"and return to earth
through the clouds.
"During their plunge...
"they shed
their positive charge...
"and form a negative-charged
front."
Close the door!
Don't just stand there!
Find a seat, quick!
"The two opposing forces...
"are attracted
towards each other.
"lt grows irresistible.
"ln one flashing moment,
the two violently reunite.
"That makes:. thunder."
"It's believed that thunder
created all life on earth.
"Four hundred million
years ago...
"a bolt of lightning
created the first amino acid...
"the origin of life.
"That was the beginning
of everything."
I can't help you!
You two can't fight like this!
Everyone envied you!
You can't do this!
I'm very disappointed!
What sense does it make?
I haven't seen her in ages.
Of course not!
You mistreated her!
Lili is so lovely!
How could you?
Is she seeing other guys?
I didn't say that.
You should know better.
Tough lady!
How can this be?
Open the door!
Why is it suddenly locked?
Not ashamed, are you?
How can this be?
Lili, it's not how it looks.
What is it, then?
Listen to me.
You're my teacher!
You're my mother!
You should be teaching me
English!
Teachers are human, too!
I'll tell the principal!
Listen to me!
Listen to what?
Excuse me.
It's not what you think, Lili!
Look this way!
Let Daddy videotape you.
Still crying...
Look this way.
The eyes...
What? You're moved?
Suddenly it all seems...
so cruel.
What's wrong?
Is his horoscope really so bad?
Didn't you say...
we can counter it
by giving him a lucky name?
It's all right.
A-Di!
Congratulations!
You're the first!
Let's see the baby.
Like you, but more handsome!
So they say! I can't tell.
To wish you luck...
How's his horoscope?
What's his name?
The name is crucial.
I'm still working on it.
Right, it's for life!
Have some tea.
Congratulations!
Good job, A-Di!
Migo!
I hear you've set
the world to rights!
Made peace between
your wife and Yun-Yun!
Let's drink to that!
Here, some expensive red wine!
All your old classmates
are relieved!
Lovely little baby!
Looks more like the mother
than the father.
You sure?
Go fetch the baby pictures.
What pictures?
Behind the screen!
Had a good eye, didn't l?
I hired Xiao Yan
fresh out of school.
See what happens?
You should thank me, Xiao Yan.
Right, you should.
Get Migo in here.
Why is that bitch here?
Did you invite her?
Of course not!
What the hell is going on?
Why did you bring Yun-Yun?
She said you invited her,
and we brought the wine.
You didn't invite her!
You think I'm nuts?
What a letdown!
We all thought you two made up.
We were so glad to hear it.
That's what she told you all?
Weren't you so friendly
to each other just now?
Forget the past,
make a fresh start.
Let's be happy.
Fuck, it's a setup!
What?
It's a fucking setup!
Look! Throw her out right now!
Come now...
Harmony is a precious thing!
Think of
our classmates' feelings!
It's for everyone's good.
Bullshit!
For everyone's good?
What about me?
Where does that leave me?
Your behavior isn't helping.
Yun-Yun is our old friend.
Your wife
is out of line here.
What the fuck?
What the fuck are you
playing at, Yun-Yun?
She doesn't mean that!
Trying to wreck the party?
You're wrecking it, not her!
Xiao Yan, don't get me wrong.
I'm sincerely happy
for both of you, believe me.
So I'm the villain?
What did I do to deserve this?
Xiao Yan! Take some advice!
You should repent! Our
friendship doesn't deserve this!
Don't leave! Stay here!
Long time no see! Don't go!
Classmates, calm her down
or Yun-Yun will leave!
This is not right!
Xiao Yan invited us!
We are her guests!
See? I'm the host!
You're full of shit!
This is not fair!
Who asked your opinion?
You lowlife!
This is all your fault!
Xiao Yan and the baby
are coming with me.
You'll never see them again!
I'll cut off your dick
and feed it to the pigs!
Let's get Xiao Yan and the baby
out of here!
Named your baby yet?
His horoscope's bad?
Why was Yun-Yun there?
It was a setup.
You've been seeing her?
Not exactly.
Xiao Yan's been pregnant.
Yun-Yun and l
go back a long way.
I've helped her out a little,
out of courtesy.
Paging NJ Jian,
you have a visitor!
How courteous.
You're one lucky guy.
A nice home and a colorful life!
I'll take a shower.
Help yourself to a drink.
Give me a break.
I have to drive home.
Sleep it off.
Start afresh tomorrow.
I wish!
Go to bed.
A bad day's over.
It's all over.
Fuck!
Look at this mess!
Thanks.
All these empty bottles,
damn it.
A-Di!
Can't you answer
while you're running your bath?
Still mad at me, you bastard?
What are you doing in there?
I smell gas!
What happened?
Open the door!
Telephone!
Where's the damn phone?
Open the door, A-Di!
What were you doing?
Why did you close the window?
Why didn't you open the window?
Why was the window closed?
Why didn't you open it?
I won't fight with you again.
What happened?
You seemed fine last night.
Don't scare me.
I'm fine.
What did I do?
I just took a bath.
Go ask the gas company.
Check my pager for me.
What a time to page me.
2773-7557.
That's my office!
Why are they paging you?
I tried all your numbers!
Lucky we had his pager number.
What's the rush?
We have serious interest
from this guy.
But he gives us only one hour.
What guy? Interested in what?
Get in.
You need an "honest-looking" guy
again, right?
Why come to me?
You've sewn it up!
Get on board.
Mind if I don't have a ticket?
Boss Huang knows all about Ota.
You've signed with him...
and Boss Huang
wants in at whatever price.
Today,
we'll finalize the details.
NJ is Ota-san's very old friend!
Right, NJ?
Boss Huang was drinking
with the President all night.
He's resting now.
Time is tight.
Wait here a moment.
Fly to Tokyo and sign
with Ota right away!
Get on the next flight.
Huang used to run game arcades.
He knows Ota's stuff well.
As a legislator, he now supports
women's rights and quotas.
Is this gonna make money?
This is a long weekend in Japan.
The noon flight is full.
You're wait-listed.
Shall I book a later flight?
You'd get in quite late.
Why not? Go ahead.
International call on line two.
This person has called before.
I was away,
running around on business.
I'll be in Tokyo tomorrow.
Are you sure?
Hang on, I'll check.
Which hotel am I in?
I won't be your go-between!
Why come to me again?
What did I say last time?
This is for you, Ting-Ting.
I have to go to Tokyo tomorrow.
The nurse will come in
every day, but...
You'll be on your own, OK?
You got here so quickly!
So many flights every day
from Chicago to Tokyo.
Shall we visit
your father's school?
We'll change
from the green line to...
the blue.
That's the exit.
But the map says this way.
No, that's the way out.
The blue line is this way.
That's the Chuo line.
This reminds me
of our first date.
I was so nervous,
I had the hiccups, remember?
I've had hiccups since I was
a kid whenever I'm nervous.
I was too nervous to ask why!
You were too nervous to breathe!
I sweat when I'm nervous,
my palms...
even my feet!
Excuse me.
Rodney and l
don't have children...
but he loves kids.
He's on business a lot.
We're thinking of adopting
so I'll have company.
-And you?
-Two.
A girl in high school
and a boy of eight.
I love my daughter.
She's growing into a woman.
I get jealous...
knowing eventually
she'll be with someone else.
My son?
I want to be his friend...
The relationship I always wanted
with my father.
What time is it?
Nine.
It's almost ten.
That's eight a.m. in Chicago.
Nine p.m. in Taipei.
Let's find a place
for the night.
Look, this is like
the crossing near our school.
That's gone now.
The first time
I held your hand...
We were at a railroad crossing,
going to the movies.
I reached for you,
ashamed of my sweaty palm...
Now I'm holding
your hand again.
Only it's a different place...
A different time...
A different age...
But the same sweaty palm.
Did you like the movie?
A bit too serious.
You prefer comedies?
Not really,
but it didn't have to be so sad.
Life is a mixture
of sad and happy things.
Movies are so lifelike.
That's why we love them.
Then who needs movies?
Just stay home and live life!
My uncle says...
"We live three times as long
since man invented movies."
How can that be?
It means movies give us twice
what we get from daily life.
For example, murder.
We never killed anyone,
be we all know...
what it's like to kill.
That's what we get
from the movies.
What good is it to me?
If life's so horrible,
why live at all?
If we're nice to people,
they'll be nice back.
Who needs to kill anybody?
It's only one example.
There are other things.
Like he also said...
"There's no cloud...
"no tree...
"that isn't beautiful...
"so we should be, too."
I found that very touching.
It changed me in many ways.
You make it sound tragic!
Shouldn't it sound cheerful?
Later I married
and had a child...
didn't you hear?
But I divorced within a year.
I went to study in Seattle,
married a Chinese-American.
I had to run away.
That day...
I waited and waited.
You never showed up.
I waited because I knew...
I'd be ruined
if I didn't see you.
I wouldn't know how to live on!
I'd fall apart!
Waiting was my only chance.
I waited for one day.
Then for another day.
I asked friends to find you.
There was no response.
You just vanished.
I left without a word.
Aside from silly excuses,
I had nothing to say.
I was so angry!
You pushed me
to become an engineer.
Did you ever ask what I wanted?
You and my parents were so happy
the day I graduated.
But me? I was so sad.
You can't run
someone else's life...
dictate how he spends
his days...
That's sad, you know?
And the one doing it
was the one I loved most!
So...
Do you know
how that hurt inside?
Do you?
How funny.
I'm doing exactly
what you wanted me to do.
And you have a better life
than I could ever give you.
You were so naive.
I thought we'd end up penniless.
What? You were always after me!
Nonsense!
You were just standing there
looking at me.
I couldn't stand it any longer.
Remember what I said?
"lf you want to talk to me,
get a move on!"
Why did you...
suddenly fall for me
in high school?
It was much earlier.
In primary school.
That's when it all started.
Strange, I just wanted
to see you every day.
If I missed seeing you,
I'd feel bad all day.
That's why you gawped.
We all wore uniforms,
but yours looked different.
In what way?
A very special way.
Yang-Yang...
You've been in there
a long time.
What are you doing?
Say something!
Why don't you answer?
Hurry up! Come out!
What are you doing?
What are you playing with?
Did you fall into the toilet?
What are you doing in there?
May I use your mother's
bathroom?
Of course.
That'll be from the hospital.
I'll get it.
Tell me the truth.
What?
Are you seeing Fatty?
No...
We're just friends.
Don't be like this, Ting-Ting.
Of course she spoke to me, too.
You have known her a long time.
That's how she is.
You should know by now.
What is she to you now?
Nothing.
In my heart...
there's only you.
Is that true?
You don't believe me?
It's...
not right.
One of my aunts
got married here.
Which one?
It was that summer.
They still dance the twist
around here!
"Good morning."
Good morning?
It's almost bedtime!
It's the only Japanese word
I know!
The clerk
gave you a strange look...
when he handed you two keys.
Who sleeps
in separate rooms these days?
To sleep with someone
means nothing now.
You're off again.
But it's true!
You dragged me to a hotel first,
remember?
I was scared, I ran off!
I used to think you'd vanish
if I just looked away.
If you gave yourself to me...
you could always hold me
to account for it later, right?
Not at all.
But when you left the room...
I knew you didn't love me
anymore.
You still feel that way now?
You know how I felt...
when you turned away just now?
It felt as if l'd
never see you again!
I don't want to go on like this.
I have everything.
What am I afraid of?
If I divorced Rodney...
I'd be well off for the rest
of my life.
We could start over.
How about it?
I was too insecure.
It was my fault.
Now I have nothing to fear.
Let's start a new life,
shall we?
You're tired, Sherry.
Don't change the subject!
You're scared, right?
You never loved me!
Admit it!
Sherry!
Why do I behave like this
whenever I'm with you?
Why do I always do that?
I'm sorry.
Why do I always
make the same mistakes...
when I know I'll regret them
for the rest of my life?
Don't feel sorry.
Who understands you
better than I do?
I think of you...
every day of my life, you know?
Think?
Think...
We all need time to think.
Carefully think.
Come on.
This is my business trip.
You've handed me
a huge workload.
It'll take several trips
to deal with.
Give me a break.
This is a big job.
I'm so tired.
I have to crash.
I'll pick you up for breakfast.
Have a good meeting tonight.
Sherry...
I never loved anyone else.
Can you bring me
a pack of cards?
Yes, but Morita-san
prohibits gambling here, sir.
I won't gamble.
Morita-san knows.
Then why do you need them?
Two warm pots of sake.
Yes, sir.
You're not gambling, are you?
Who won?
I tried to reach you
all day yesterday.
Relax, I talked to Mr. Ota.
Listen, we've signed with Ato.
That's what I wanted
to tell you yesterday.
Ato? Why?
I thought Boss Huang--
He's into quota-representation
for women, I told you.
And Ato is a woman?
A 34E-cup!
Make an excuse
and come back home.
What do you say, NJ?
Nothing! I get it!
NJ, what's wrong?
Don't get emotional.
This solves our problems.
We should celebrate!
We didn't promise Ota anything.
You...
You know that hurts!
What hurts?
Mr. Ota is a good man!
Where's our dignity?
What's that got to do
with business?
I'll ride pillion!
I just got back.
Where's my cup? Can't find it.
Fatty, don't feel this way
because of me.
It's OK. We can still
be friends. I'm still--
Still what?
Still cheerful, right?
It's all crap!
Life's not like your dreams!
If it was, you wouldn't need
those love stories...
to kid yourself!
Get lost!
Never bug me again!
Stay away from me!
Believe it, these things happen!
When the stars are in alignment,
the gods smile on us!
How old is hi-tech?
Twenty years?
Horoscopes are thousands
of years old!
Ting-Ting must be back.
Here's the bank draft.
That clears my debt.
That bastard Piggy
is on the run in China!
So I rushed to his place.
It was crawling with cops!
The place was empty
and sealed off!
So I found this one cop.
Talked him into letting me in.
Shit, the creditors
had cleared the place out!
Only junk left lying around.
Still, I found
this funny piece of rock.
Nobody had seen what it was!
How did you get so wet?
Is it raining so hard?
Get out of those wet clothes.
I had it valued,
and the guy's eyes lit up.
It was antique jade!
An 8,000-year-old
national treasure!
I kept my cool.
I asked for what Piggy owed me.
The guy wrote out a check
on the spot!
It must have been worth
a lot more.
We shouldn't be too greedy!
Get out of bed!
Just lying there
will make you sick!
I'll pick you up
at seven tomorrow.
Stick with me, your horoscope
will improve no end!
What's this? For me?
This is me!
The back of my head!
What's this for?
You can't see it yourself,
so I help you.
So that's why!
That's why what?
I've done nothing bad.
Why is it so unfair?
Unless...
you haven't forgiven me.
Why don't you wake up?
Please wake up, will you?
Nobody's home.
His daughter must be at school.
-Which school?
-First Girls' High.
I'll send a policewoman there.
Mr. Jian is usually home
these days.
This front passed us
yesterday afternoon.
We should now have clear
weather until Thursday.
Next up, City News.
There was a murder this morning.
It happened in
the Da-An district of Taipei.
The suspect is a teenager.
We cross to the murder site
for a report.
This is the suspect.
Nicknamed Fatty, he's a pupil...
at a posh school.
The victim was an English
teacher named Chen Lihua.
We are reliably informed...
the suspect's girlfriend...
had a sexual relationship
with the victim.
The police confirm the victim...
was also involved
with the girl's mother.
It complicates the case.
The mother works...
for a well-known American bank.
She had no comment today.
The security guard
recalls the suspect...
was seen loitering
near the building yesterday.
As the victim left the building
early this morning...
the suspect took a knife from
his satchel and stabbed him.
It was reportedly
a grisly scene.
I thought it was the nurse.
It's 2:30. She's still not here.
I was at the police station.
I can't face going back
to school.
I haven't slept for so long.
I'm so tired, Grandma.
Now...
you've forgiven me...
I can sleep.
Grandma...
Why is the world so different
from what we thought it was?
Now that you're awake...
and see it again...
has it changed at all?
Now...
I close my eyes...
the world I see...
is so beautiful.
Migo, this isn't a joke.
Why would I kid you?
Yes, Migo.
I'm not kidding.
Migo...
calm down!
I feel it's my fault.
If I'd come earlier,
this might not have happened.
It's all my fault.
Don't be so upset.
It's my mother's funeral.
Money is not a problem.
Unfortunately,
I was out all day today.
It must have been
a peaceful end.
Even if someone were home,
they wouldn't have noticed.
Listen, stay in your room, OK?
Good boy.
It was about 3 hours ago,
around 2:30 p.m.
Nothing's changed here.
The kids are both fine.
How was it up the mountain?
It was fine.
Actually,
it was much the same...
Just like...
talking to Mother.
But with the roles reversed.
I was like Mother,
they were like me.
They took turns to talk to me,
the same things every time.
Several times a day.
I've come to realize...
things aren't really
so complicated.
Why did they ever seem so?
Right.
How can I say this?
While you were away...
I had a chance to relive
part of my youth.
My first thought...
was that I could...
make things turn out
differently.
But...
they turned out the same,
or not much different.
I suddenly realized that...
even if I was given
a second chance...
I wouldn't need it.
I really wouldn't.
Why did you have to leave us?
How could you leave us?
A-Di and l
can't go on without you!
Come back to us!
You were right again.
It was a waste of time.
Ato's copies were terrible.
Buyers are too smart now.
No one buys cheap imitations.
Boss Huang is no slouch.
Ato is now his mistress,
surprise, surprise!
She just sits
by the pool half-naked...
and the cash comes rolling in.
One smart lady!
Come back, NJ.
Rejoin the team.
We go back so far.
Staying home all day
is no solution.
I've worked my butt off
all these years!
I didn't do it for fun!
You know, NJ, I'm never happy.
When you don't love
what you do...
how could you be?
Can I speak to Grandma?
Of course, go ahead.
"I'm sorry, Grandma.
"lt wasn't that I didn't
want to talk to you.
"l think all the stuff
I could tell you...
"you must already know.
"Otherwise, you wouldn't always
tell me to 'Listen!'
"They all say you've gone away."
"But you didn't tell me
where you went.
"l guess it's someplace
you think I should know.
"But, Grandma, I know so little.
"Do you know
what I want to do...
"when I grow up?
"l want to tell people
things they don't know.
"Show them stuff
they haven't seen.
"lt'll be so much fun.
"Perhaps one day...
"I'll find out
where you've gone.
"lf I do, can I tell everyone...
"and bring them to visit you?"
"Grandma...
"l miss you.
"Especially when I see...
"my newborn cousin
who still doesn't have a name.
"He reminds me that you
always said you felt old.
"l want to tell him
that I feel...
"l am old, too."