Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull
Okay, which one is he?
I don't know
if he's gonna be here or not.
- Are you kidding me?
- I think I should go.
Um, I should probably go.
Aw, but we didn't even make it
to the bed, freshie.
Oh, are you quarterback?
Hey um,
have you seen my brother?
Nah.
We didn't have to go,
I was just seeing what was up.
I just can't watch what
you're up to with that guy.
There was nothing to watch!
We were just hanging out.
Man, he's like,
Justin like that guy
that'll give like everyone else
a bad name.
Oh, yeah.
Like remember when he told
Stephanie P that she should...
I don't...
I don't wanna say it actually.
He's just trying to get
in your pants,
- I can tell you that much.
- Ew, Adam!
Besides, you're...
you're too young
to be going to parties.
I don't know
what you're thinking.
Dude, you are nine months
older than me.
...opportunity.
Wardrobe infraction.
Can we speak alone?
Freshman.
Hey.
Uh, some of us are going
to Ethan's after school,
and you should totally come.
- Um, yeah, I can probably go.
- Dope.
See you there.
Cool.
What?
A sophomore, just like came...
Yeah, it was really cool.
- What?
- I know!
You're so close.
I just got him.
Damn it!
Got him, I got him.
Hey.
Does Adam know you're here?
Adam?
Adam, yeah no, um, I doubt it,
but I did see him this morning,
so that was...
Or no that was last night,
it was definitely last night.
Maybe it was yesterday.
I don't remember
maybe we should call him.
Yeah, um, I'm good.
Damn it!
What's up, Watson?
- Do you know each other?
- Yeah...
- We're neighbors.
Cool.
Well, I was thinking,
because you're like,
the smartest girl
in the history class...
Um.
No, it really only seems
like that,
but it's just 'cause I'm like
one of the only freshmen,
I'm not that smart.
Yeah, well,
I think you're smart.
Dude!
- Don't you forget.
- Okay.
It seems like he was gonna
ask you to do
his homework, right?
Yeah, it totally did.
If I were you, I don't know I...
tell him you were blind
or something.
Yeah.
Actually though uh,
I have to get going,
but it was good talking to you.
Uh, can I come?
I have something to do later.
Yeah, yeah.
Uh, hey Justin,
I'm gonna get going,
I have something to do
for my mom, so...
Gotta help your mom.
Kidding, freshie, see ya later.
Okay.
- The leaves are like...
- You two...
- Sorry.
- Um.
No, no, you can go.
Shoot.
I was just gonna say,
leaves are like really cool.
Yeah.
So, um, what do you think
of high school so far?
Um, it's okay,
it's pretty much like
Hosford but bigger.
I have classes with my friends
which is nice.
I like my English class.
I don't like that
they are making me take
Spanish too,
but the counsellor says
I have to try, so...
What about you?
Uh, I don't know.
It's alright.
I'm kinda used to it by now.
I like drama.
Oh yeah, you're supposed to be
like...
I just mean to say,
you're supposed
to be really good.
Shit.
Hmm.
What?
I don't know, it's just...
it's just weird.
I don't think we have
ever really talked before.
I don't totally know you.
Oh.
Um, I have this thing,
in my room,
I don't know
if you'd want to see.
Really?
Yeah or not, I mean.
No, um, yeah,
yeah, that sounds good.
It's my little leaf collection.
Oh, wow.
Yeah.
I mean I'm kinda seeing
how shitty they look
after some time.
But you know,
once they were all bright
and beautifully colored.
Like this one, I don't know
it's probably from like
the fifth grade.
Really?
Yeah.
Wow.
So, now you know.
I like leaves, too.
Um, do you wanna smoke?
Oh, I...
I didn't realize you smoke.
Oh, yeah, I mean
I like to sometimes,
'cause just around people,
I don't know, I feel weird.
But like I only have
a little bit.
I got it
from my sister's friend.
Uh, I don't do it that often,
so...
I've only smoked like twice,
and once was today,
and one other time.
I don't really even know
if it counted.
Um, yeah actually I'll...
I'll take some more.
Thanks.
Okay.
Would you like to do the honors?
Yeah, sure.
Okay.
Thank you.
I'm... I'm good.
You guys look
pretty funny there.
Oh, yeah, that was like,
a year ago.
Wow.
I should've been nice to you
All this time
Um, I should probably go.
Yeah. Yeah.
- I'll see you tomorrow.
- Yeah.
Uh, I don't know I
mean, it's an amazing photo.
Yeah, what kinda class is that?
We just take fucking photos
you know,
it's kind of like
a college level class.
Like a college level class?
Yeah.
For a sophomore year,
it's pretty good.
Hey, so is it lasagne night
tonight?
Is it lasagne night tonight?
Okay, fine, don't tell me
if it's lasagne night.
Oh, um, I don't know.
Later.
I'm just not really sure.
Harper!
Harper! Harper!
It's trash night.
Yeah.
Hey.
Oh, hi.
Um.
So how are you?
I'm... I'm good.
Uh, I was just, you know.
Uh, do you...?
Yeah. Yeah.
Umm...
What... what have you been up to?
Um, I mean, just like stuff.
Homework stuff,
basketball stuff.
What about you?
Yeah, you know like
theater things.
I had a rehearsal yesterday.
And that's about it.
Oh yeah, you're um,
you're playing Duke Fredrick
in As You Like It, right?
Yeah, yeah, I'm kind of excited,
'cause I didn't really have
any big parts last year.
Well, you're gonna be
really good.
I mean, that's just...
that's what everyone else
is saying.
So did you end up doing
Justin's homework?
What?
Oh, um, no actually.
He asked me about it yesterday,
but um, I just told him to ask
Mr. Summers for help,
think he might.
Really?
I mean, that's what he said.
I had Mr. Summers last year
and I really liked him.
- Oh really?
- Yeah...
I had him for English.
The triumph
of the South Atlantic system
changed the politics
of the empire.
British would pretend to rule
the colonies with a gentle hand
and the colonists were in
a position to challenge...
In England glorious
revolution strengthened the powers
of the colonists
at the expense of the Crown.
American representative
assemblies also wished to limit
the powers of the Crown,
grab the one control...
Um, is... is Adam home?
He... he has my math notes like,
so I came by to...
Yeah. Yeah.
Adam!
Um, you can just come in
actually.
- Oh!
- Um.
I... I forgot my...
I was just, uh...
Um, but I... I can get it.
Or I can get it for you,
if you want.
Yeah.
Um, why... why were you out here
anyway?
Um, it's trash day, so.
What?
We should hang out sometime.
Okay.
Um, well,
I should probably go, so.
- Yeah.
- Um, okay.
Hey, um, did you come out here
just to see me?
Yeah.
Did you?
So um, what do you think
about politics?
What?
Sorry, I don't know.
No, no.
Um, let's see,
I don't know it's all pretty
crazy and terrible, right?
Like my dad, he says
it's a shitshow.
Mine, too.
I don't know for me,
I think it's more about like,
women's abortion rights.
Yeah?
Yeah, I mean not like for me
personally, necessarily.
I just think,
where I come from it's so much
more complicated.
And people die every single day
just trying to do it themselves,
so I just think that like...
I just think that sometimes
women deserve more
than they get.
Yeah.
Sorry, what part of India
are you from again?
Uh, Kanar.
In like this little village
actually.
So um, my birth mom, she had me
and the guy who was my dad
left right away, I guess.
And um, she couldn't afford
to keep me, so when I was 3
she moved me to an orphanage
in Delhi,
and so my parents now
Jocelyn and Bob,
uh, they found me through
an online program and here I am.
I remember the day you came.
No, you don't.
I was 3, so you would
have been 4.
- There's no way.
- Okay, yeah.
Maybe not, but I do remember
being really little
and playing with you, and...
oh and then I do remember
when Adam came, yeah.
Yeah, yeah,
no, you guys were 6
I remember that.
- Hey, you know what's crazy?
- What?
My parents just went to India
and Saint Paul
and got some children.
Yeah, I guess.
Yeah.
So, like do you ever think
about your family?
Like your old family?
Yeah, sometimes.
I mean, sometimes this lady
who says she's my cousin
sends me letters.
They're kind of funny
and kind of weird.
- Woah.
- Yeah, I don't know.
- Um...
- Well, it was fun hanging out.
- Yeah, yeah, um...
- I...
Are you going that way?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
I should probably cross it, so.
- I'll just...
- Yeah.
I almost told the guy
to step the fuck away
I was so pissed!
Mom, you can't talk to the mayor
like that.
It's not normal,
but in this case
he would've deserved it,
that piece of sh...
Oh, so how's school, Adam?
Um, it's okay.
I mean, you know
the treasurer and I have
a lot of good ideas, but I wish
she was vice president.
She's a lot easier to deal with
than Jonathan.
Well, you just need to give
Jonathan some time.
They elected him for a reason.
Harper, how are you doing?
What?
What do you think of the school,
sweetie?
- It's big, huh?
- Yeah!
It is big.
Um, it's pretty cool.
I like it.
I'm doing very good, thank you.
There's Mark.
You know, we really should
have him over soon.
Feel bad, it's been a while.
Yeah, me too, me too.
How's Tilly doing?
Does he ever talk about his mom?
Uh, not really.
- I... I think he's okay.
- Hmm.
It was really sad
watching her go like that.
I mean nobody should have to go
through something like that.
Especially not Tilly
And they were sparkly
and gorgeous.
How was your day?
Are you dating Luna Douglas?
What?
No.
Um, do you like her, though?
No, no, no.
We just hang out
with the same people.
So we're around each other
a lot.
She's nice.
Yeah.
Are you dating Joey Gomez?
What?
I mean that was in like
the sixth grade,
so it was a long time ago.
I guess I was going out
with Owen McDonald,
but whatever that's...
Hey, do we think anything about
um, about Adam?
Yeah, I do.
Me too.
I mean I don't know,
this is cool.
This is weird.
You know what I hate?
When I'm trying to perform
my summer dance routine
- and I go...
- Oh my God!
No one will ever let me
forget about that!
You guys chose the block party
to premiere
your world famous dance.
It would've been world famous,
it literally would have been!
- Who's playing Rosalind?
- Oh, um, my friend Luna.
Guys, how's school?
It's good, Mr. D.
- How are you?
- Oh good, good, good, good.
Make sure you try
some of the sauce, Bob.
- It's my grandma's recipe.
- Okay.
Mark, it is so nice of you
to have prepared all of this,
although when we said
we should have dinner,
we didn't mean that
you should have us like come...
Oh yeah.
No, no, no, no,
don't worry about it, I...
- I love cooking.
- Okay.
It's fine, yeah.
I do, Tilly.
Yeah, yeah, I mean we have like
frozen burritos
like every night.
Yeah.
Mark um...
Hey, uh, how's...
how's Carol doing?
Good, good, yeah.
I think she's not crazy about
being on the same campus as me,
but I told her that's
what you'd get for choosing
the old hippie school, right.
Yeah, I kinda wouldn't mind
going to an old hippie school.
Or at least I'm starting
to think that.
Last week I got in trouble,
because a teacher thought
my shorts weren't inappropriate.
What he was saying was just
shaming the way our bodies look
or the way our clothes fit.
It's just, isn't it society
that's telling us to wear
these clothes
just so we fit in?
I don't know,
it just kinda sucks.
Yeah.
Harper, I couldn't agree
with you more.
I was having
this exact conversation
with my students
just the other day,
- about that double standard.
- Oh.
It's... it's just so
backwards, you know, all of it.
And you two, it's time to start
standing up for women, okay.
It's not like it used to be,
at all.
It's not like uh,
"Oh, uh, happy to make
more money" or whatever, no.
You see something unfair,
you fucking change it.
You say something
and you change it.
Okay, so...
I went into professor mode
for a second there.
You did!
Okay, go to the one with
the pig, that's the wrong one.
This is like three summers ago.
Well, it's still funny, so.
- No way!
- This is...
- I love this one.
- That's mom's panda, show her.
- Mom!
- Mom, look, it's your panda!
Mom!
It's your child, the panda...
Thank you so much, thank you.
Yeah, it was nice, really nice.
- Bye for now.
- Bye.
- Thanks for dinner.
- Yeah.
- Bye.
- Adam, see ya.
- That was nice.
- Yeah.
So loved it.
That was good.
Hey.
Hey, so what do you wanna do?
Um, I don't know. I think...
It should be an adventure.
I think it should be a date.
- What?
- Nothing.
Hey, can you believe that
I would never, ever,
ever wanna go...
Hmm?
To the moon.
- Why?
- 'Cause you can't breathe.
Like literally think about it.
Well, I feel like you would have
some way to breathe
if you ended up finding a way
to get to the moon.
No, this is like you going.
Okay, okay, okay.
Continue.
Um, probably North Carolina.
No, no, no, no, no.
- I don't eat...
- What?
It's veggie.
Vegetable!
Okay.
I don't eat meat either.
Since when?
You know, I've been a vegetarian
since I was 8, right?
Yeah.
I remember we would always go
to the beach
and you'd make a really big deal
out of when my parents
made hot dogs.
But I don't know,
it's been like, a few years
after my mom got sick,
so she stopped eating,
so I stopped as well.
And then after... it just like,
seemed weird to go back.
I'm sorry.
No, it's okay.
It's not.
Real emotional, huh.
Sorry.
Very sincere.
I'm sorry, Tilly!
Well, um,
I think that was a success.
A success?
Um, what do you wanna do now?
I mean, we should probably keep
hanging out, right.
I think my dad might have
a late class, um,
would you wanna come over?
I mean I should probably
text him,
but what do your parents think
if you're galloping around town?
You mean gallivanting?
But no, yeah, they're cool
with it.
They trust us.
They're trying to be
so progressive that
I have nothing to rebel against,
so.
Um, but actually,
I'll them I'm going to Zoey's.
I'll be right back.
- Hi.
Dad late indeed.
So, um, what do you wanna do?
- Um, we could eat.
- Yeah.
Or I guess, we just ate already.
Um, we could smoke?
I don't know, sure.
Or we could, drink a beer.
My dad has beer.
Yeah, yeah.
I like beer.
Or I'm... I'm starting to.
My mom actually drinks a lot,
of beer, nothing crazy.
She's just...
she's very Portland.
She gets mad about politics
and stuff.
So, that's where you get it?
I mean, that's an
interesting way
of thinking about it.
I guess.
But doesn't everyone get mad?
I guess so.
Um.
I guess
I don't really need a beer.
Okay.
Do you want to?
Yeah.
This is fun.
Um, should I?
I mean, if... if you want to.
Yeah.
I haven't done it before.
I mean me neither.
Really?
Yeah, I mean like,
we don't have to.
Go, go get a condom.
Wait. I... I don't have one.
Do you think my dad would?
I don't know, go check.
Okay.
Is... is this crazy?
Yes!
Uh.
Well, I'll see you later.
Yeah. Bye.
Can I come over later?
Oh, uh, I have... I have
rehearsal in an hour, so.
Wait, so we can't do it again?
No, I mean we're definitely
doing it again.
When though?
Not... not till tomorrow?
I think we should do it
all the time.
You wanna?
You were looking at me!
No! You were looking at me!
Oh my God!
I was gonna come over
and I was gonna say something,
but then Madison
looked at me weird.
Okay, well,
Madison looks at everyone weird.
It's so weird not seeing you
during the day.
I know.
You know that day you
texted me at the food carts?
I didn't know if I should come
or not.
I am so glad you came.
Me too.
Although I'm pretty sure
that day we just talked.
No, that day we...
No.
You are remembering wrong.
You are remembering
incorrectly.
No!
I disagree!
Is this better
than what Madison likes?
No.
My dad likes it, and it's...
and it's cool.
Um, that's because he's 40.
- So when I'm 44, you'll be 45?
- Yeah.
And when I'm 52,
you're gonna be 51.
And when I'm 81,
you're gonna be 82.
We're gonna be so happy.
We're gonna be so old.
Hey!
- Is it okay that I decided to?
- Yeah.
I'm so happy you're here.
Struberry.
Strawberry.
It's struberry, it sounds
like January.
Struberry.
Yeah, struberry.
Harper Ann!
Mom!
Harper Ann, are you having sex
with Tilly Dodson?
We're just friends, mom,
that's it.
Yeah, you've become
more than friends
and you know it.
Well, kind of,
but yeah, kind of, but...
Yep. No, you were over there
yesterday, too.
- I thought you trusted us, mom.
- Trust?
Look, kids spending
every day together
in unsupervised rooms
are having sex, Harper.
No, they're not.
Look, I would know.
Uh.
I just don't want you
having sex.
Why not?
Because you are too young.
No, I'm not.
Turney, what do you think?
Him?
Definitely like her.
Him for sure.
Virgins.
Her too.
Probably.
Probably?
Definitely.
Probably never had a guy
who'd check her out on accident.
Um, hey, do you know what
we're supposed to do
for this essay?
What?
Um, do you know
what you're doing right now?
I heard it was in a tree house.
I heard she was on her period.
And apparently, she asked
to wait till she was,
so she wouldn't know
if the blood was from.
Oh my God.
- Guys, this is kinda gross.
- Yeah.
No, like,
that we know this stuff.
Are you just saying
that, 'cause you're getting
all the action now?
Yeah, maybe.
Why did you say it like that?
It's just gross.
Oh my God!
So what is it like?
Um, I guess it's just kind of
like knowing someone
really, really well,
but differently
than everyone else you know.
Yeah.
I wish my first
sexual experience wasn't having
hands stuck down my pants.
He should've been expelled,
really.
It's okay, I mean, I just Tiger.
I just felt stupid mostly.
Uh, I never should've told
my mom.
Well, he shouldn't have assumed
you wanted that
just because you shared
a locker.
Yeah, well, see you in history.
See ya.
What's up with you
and Adam Turney's sister?
Woah, you really like her.
Yeah, I mean, she's super funny,
and smart,
and like really into government,
and like she has all these ideas
about how school should be run,
and she's like... I don't know,
she's really into basketball,
so I get to watch her practices.
She's just kinda awesome.
Nice.
How are you?
Good, how are you?
- I'm good.
- That's cool.
So what do you wanna do today?
I don't know,
I think it's up to you.
You probably haven't
really been in here before.
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't think
I've been in here since...
I don't know when
I would've been here actually.
For a basketball, maybe?
Yeah, I feel like me and Adam
might have come in here
once when you were gone.
I'm sorry, look,
I would never do that now.
We might have looked
at your dolls
without their clothes on
or something really weird.
Yeah, that is pretty weird.
Well, we should probably do it.
I mean, my mom's working late
and my dad's to uh, Lake Oswego.
Adam has a
student council meeting.
So...
Yeah, but I should do
homework after.
Mhmm.
Hey, do you ever wanna like,
do it differently?
Yeah, how do you mean?
Like, like this?
Like this?
- Come on, come on.
- Hey, cradle-robber.
Hey, do I need to hide
my sister?
You eat more bagels
than anyone I've ever met.
I love bagels.
Hey, um, Abby got
her tooth pulled
and I was thinking after school
we should all go over
and bring her homework.
Mom said we can watch
Super Bowl there.
Oh, um, I actually was gonna
watch Tilly's rehearsal
- after school today.
- Oh.
- I'm sorry.
- No, it's fine.
See you later.
Hey.
I think he might have said
something to my mom,
if it makes you feel better.
Really?
Actually, I don't really know.
But he's ignoring me too, so.
Yeah, I mean,
it's just different.
Um, but, thanks, thanks Harper.
Yeah.
Did you hear what
happened in Geometry class?
No, what happened?
Okay,
so the projector stopped working
and we gotta be in our phones,
all class.
Oh, lucky!
- Hey!
- Abby!
Um, how's... how's your tooth?
Um, it's fine I guess,
I mean I can't really tell
now that it's gone.
Um, kind of hurts now.
Actually, talking about it
right now kind of hurts more.
What's Sam Pierson like, Tilly?
Yeah, is he always
running around
with his shirt off, like ugh,
look at how sexy I am.
I mean, not really.
He's... he's really nice.
But what's he like?
I don't know.
Just normal, I... I guess.
I remember that cheer
you guys used to do
at basketball games
when you were younger.
That was... that was cool.
That's weird.
Yeah, isn't that like sexist?
Yeah.
They're just joking,
you're fine.
You guys are joking, right?
I think I'm just gonna do
homework today.
Yeah, me too.
Hey.
Oh, hi.
So I was thinking
maybe after school
going to hang out with Ethan
and like, some of those guys.
Oh, cool, yeah.
Um, you know what,
maybe I'll hang out
with Zoey and Madison,
I think they're going
Halloween shopping, so.
Okay, um, text me
when you get home.
I can run out or something.
- Yeah?
- Yeah.
Okay, cool.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
- Okay, okay, okay.
- You got this! You got this!
Wait, wait, wait.
Hold on, wait.
- You got it, you got it!
- I know.
You're so close!
I'm going off.
- Wait, wait, wait, wait.
- Wait, no!
No! No! Ugh!
Nice try.
Well, new government awaits.
Hey, bro.
Hey.
Um, I could not figure out
that thing in math today, uh.
Oh, shit.
Is this what you're doing
to Adam's sister, Dodson?
Dude, I... I just meant like,
I mean,
you should it,
you should see this shit.
Plus, I hear that girl's a slut.
I mean you would know.
And you.
Hey, um, so did you want me
to come to your rehearsal today?
I know you have your big
homeless wanderer scene.
Um, yeah.
Yeah, I don't know,
it might take a little bit
before I have you seeing me
as a hermit in a cave.
Well, I think you'd be
a great hermit, you know,
you'd stock up on bread,
and Pop Rocks,
and you'd have your little radio
playing jazz.
Yeah, yeah, and you'd like,
sneak in 50 cucumber rolls
and like a YBM poster.
Okay.
Okay, so he's like this
uptight king, right,
and he's like, "No, you can't be
with my niece",
and then he meets this
homeless wanderer,
but that's the scene
he's doing today, so tomorrow...
Okay, I don't mean to be rude,
but I like don't care.
Okay, that's fair,
but you have to come
to his opening day with me.
There's no way I can make Adam.
Yeah, fine.
Hey, you know who's kinda cute?
Uh, that guy Eli, he has
the locker like really close
to mine.
Or him.
Hey Harper.
Hey?
Abby.
What's going on?
Nothing much, we're...
we're pretty good.
Cool.
Well, say hi to your brother
for me.
Okay.
And your boyfriend.
I will!
Why are all your brother's
friends hot?
Why?!
What?
You're like stalking me now?
You're my best friend, Adam,
and... and I don't wanna
bum you out.
Then why are you doing something
that's bumming me out?
Whatever, man.
What did you think would happen
when you decided
to lose your virginity
to my sister?
That we'd still just hang out
and watch The Flash?
It's not happening, dude.
Hey, what's up?
I can't.
I just I can't.
Adam...
Tilly, what's wrong?
It's like we're all hanging out,
you know playing video games
in the basement,
Dodson and Turney were there,
then all of a sudden,
Turney was like,
"Fuck you, dude!"
and he was like flippin' out!
Hey Justin,
what are you talking about?
I mean I... I heard Adam's name,
so I was just wondering.
Look, Liam's the one who called
you a slut.
- That wasn't me.
- What?
You know, 'cause, you've had sex
with like three dudes.
And Liam was just telling Adam
what he already knew.
And so I was like, I was
like, "I don't even know you",
you know?
Like there was no,
no possible way
that I was gonna...
So he's just like,
he's getting like
way up in my space.
I'm like, "Who you tryna fight?"
You know, he's tryna fight,
bro.
Hey Liam!
Yeah?
What makes you think
if you can tell someone's
a virgin or not?
Well, I mean, I heard you
talking about
how I'm not one and we all know
you make a game out
of pointing out everyone else.
Is it if someone's throwing
themselves at you or not
or maybe it's the way
their makeup is
or how they dress.
Maybe it's their shorts.
Or is if someone's had
hands down their pants or not.
You have no idea
what you're talking about.
See you in history.
Um, what do you wanna do?
I don't know.
Liam's such a dick.
I'm sorry Liam
said those things.
Yeah, I mean, it's...
it's complete bullshit.
Anyway, what's going on
between you and Adam, though?
I don't know.
I mean, he's really pissed.
He's never really liked this.
Us, you know.
Yeah.
But whatever.
Yeah, it's whatever.
Um, do you wanna keep
watching this?
Um, not really.
- Wait, I didn't know that.
- Really?
- Yeah.
I thought I told you that
earlier.
Oh my God, what instrument?
Uh, a trumpet.
Okay, bye.
Bye.
Hi.
I heard Henry's throwing
a party tonight,
are you gonna go?
If you do,
please don't bring him.
Uh, well...
What's up?
Um, we haven't talked about it.
But if Tilly wants to,
then maybe.
Oh my God, do you even listen
to a word I say?
Wait, how are your parents
letting you go?
- Maddie, your mom is...
- I'm sneaking out.
I have my story straight
and everything.
I'm super ready.
Are you guys dressing up?
MADISON and ABBY:
Yeah!
So what's up with
your girlfriend
and Liam Erwell?
Why are you always asking about
my girlfriend anyway?
I don't know.
Plus, I mean apparently
she grabbed his dick yesterday.
I just thought
there'd be a story.
What?
Oh, are you going
to Ben Linkson's party tonight?
Sorry, Tilly,
I thought you knew.
I'm... I'm gonna go to class.
Okay.
Bye.
Is it weird to be
in your dad's bathroom?
Um, I mean not really,
it's kind of both of ours, so.
I don't know.
Well, I meant like,
here with me.
Oh, no, it's fine.
Okay, cool.
Are you ready to go?
Are you sure you wanna go?
Yeah.
Yeah, why?
Why wouldn't I wanna go?
Why wouldn't you want me to go?
No, that's... that's not
what I meant.
I just... never mind.
Okay, let's go.
Trick or treat.
Um, so.
Hey guys.
Holy shit,
it's the dick grabber.
Hey, man.
How's Harper?
Oh, she's... she's cool.
So my brother dropped my ball
yesterday,
it went everywhere.
I wanna go to my mom about it,
but then she'll be like,
"Hey, this is good for you."
Oh it's fine,
she doesn't like him anyways.
What?
You just need to chill, Tilly.
Harper is an independent woman.
She just needs
her butterfly time.
'Cause, she's a
beautiful butterfly, you know.
Why are you telling me this?
Look, Turney.
I'm not mad about what you did.
If you weren't with Dodson,
I'd ask you to do it again.
I think you're dumber
being with him anyway.
We told her that, too.
Dick grabber!
Where's Dodson?
Harper!
Harper! Harper!
Hey.
Do you wanna go?
Yeah, yeah.
You're right.
Yeah, Dodson.
Dude.
- What gives?
- What?
You've been in a shit mood
all night
and I'm the one who has...
- You're the one who what?
- Nothing.
Just I'm the one who has to deal
with Liam
and all those other jerks.
So I don't understand
what your problem is.
Yeah, well, then why were you
even hanging out
with Liam anyways?
It's not like I wanted, too,
he just kidnapped my friends,
okay?
Yeah, and I...
I bet you didn't wanna
touch his dick either.
How do you know about that?
Tilly!
I like you.
And I've never said
anything to you about this,
but I hear stuff about you.
Stuff like... like you're a slut,
or...
This is what I'm talking about,
Tilly.
You have no idea.
You're so busy feeling hurt
about Adam,
that you don't bother
to think about
what it's like for me,
for girls.
I have sex with you, only you.
And all of a sudden,
I'm like this slut.
And you have sex
and you're part of
some cool boys club.
And you're the one
who touched Liam's dick,
so just fucking tell me
what that's about, and wait,
don't actually.
Abby pretty much told me that
you already had feelings
- for someone else.
- What?
I don't.
I don't know, Harper.
Part of me just thinks that,
that we should...
That we should what?
I don't know, break up.
Okay.
Wait, what?
You wanna break up?
Yeah, sure.
I mean if you're gonna keep
freaking out about Adam
and my friends are gonna think
I'm lame for hanging out
with you
and everyone is gonna have
something to say about it,
then yeah, why the hell not?
Harper, I...
No one likes us together,
don't you get it?
So neither do I.
Just leave me alone.
Give me my own block,
I deserve at least that.
Don't say that!
I can breakdance,
did you know that?
It's more of a pop and lock
situation.
- See that so?
- Nope.
Did you see that?
Woah, woah!
Woah!
Sup Dodson?
What are you, gay or something?
I don't think so.
Are you?
Not me.
Hi.
Um, I thought it'd be less weird
if... it's just if you came over,
it'd be like... I thought
you would need these,
especially this.
How... how's it going?
Honestly, I don't even know.
Me neither.
Are you okay?
Yeah, I... I don't know.
I'm still...
Yeah.
- Thanks for...
- Yeah.
For these, yeah...
Yeah um, I should get going
I have homework anyway, so...
How dare ye?!
Did I offend your highness?
Thus do all traitors
if their purgation
did consist in words,
they are innocent
as grace itself.
Let it suffice that
I trust thee not.
Yet your mistrust cannot make me
a traitor.
Tell me whereon
the likelihood depends.
Thou art thy father's daughter,
that's enough.
Halt!
O excellent, young man!
If I had thunderbolt in mine eye
I can tell who should down!
That's enough.
No and yes, and no and yes,
and no and yes,
and no and yes, and no and yes,
and no and yes, and no and yes.
That was so fun.
Yeah, that was really fun.
I can't wait until next year.
Yeah, what are we gonna do
next year?
- What's...
- Maybe Romeo and Juliet.
- That would be...
- That's so awesome.
Yeah.
Dude, you were...
you were so good!
- Good job!
- Thank you.
Yeah.
You were really good, Tilly.
Thanks.
You were great.
- Isn't he good?
- Yeah.
Yeah, super good.
- Go, go, go.
- Yes, yes, yes!
- Come on, no!
- Yes!
- Go!
- No, I!
- Yes!
- Go, Go!
No! No! No!
- I won!
- You cheater! You cheater!
- How did I cheat?
- I won! I won! I won! I won!
I won! I won!
...this one graphic novel.
But my teacher said that
there's too many vicarious
to account for my...
Hey Harper!
Hey, Josh.
How's it going?
Sing!
Sing me a song!
Sing us a song, Adam.
And that's why racial tolerance
and inclusivity
are important parts of feminism.
Actually, most.
Because, without them,
women will never truly be free.
You know, I agree Harper, but...
Personally, Mr. Sloan,
I don't think there's any room
for buts.
Our generation isn't gonna
tolerate buts when it comes to
equality for women
regardless of race.
I mean, just ask the internet.
Yeah, I... I think she's right.
Harper, we... we have
a few minutes.
Do you have any thoughts
you wanna share about why
you think women of color have
traditionally been oppressed?
Um, yeah.
Yeah, I do.
Hey.
Are you walking to school?
Um, are you sad the play's over?
Yeah, I mean, it's always
really hard working on
something for so long and then,
I don't know.
It's just... it's just over.
Thanks for coming by the way.
Yeah, I mean I was glad to,
actually.
Um, I guess, just to finally see
all the hard work pay off.
But I don't know, I mean yeah,
everything's...
everything's going good.
I'm starting a debate club
after Christmas break.
So...
I don't know.
It's just something
my teacher recommended, really.
But it will be cool to try.
I got another letter from India,
from my cousin or whatever.
Yeah?
What did it... what did it say?
Well, apparently
there was a storm.
And her goat died,
unfortunately.
Um, the power went out,
but it's back now.
Sometimes I... I reread
these letters and I just wonder
if... am I really related to her?
Or is she just some woman that's
tryna mess with me, you know?
I don't know,
you could write back
and like, pretend to be someone
completely different.
Um, but then again
don't take my advice.
Maybe...
maybe you like the letters.
What do you... what do you have
for lunch today?
Well, my dad made me
a sushi wrap,
but I think I'm gonna go with
a burrito today.
What about you?
I kind of want a pizza.
Provided by explosiveskull
https://twitter.com/kaboomskull