One can prevent mildew
by spraying with copper sulfate.
There are 2 classic solutions used,
one from Bordeaux,
the other from Burgundy.
Burgundy being a region in France
which is reputed for its wine.
Three sprayings a year are required.
The first when the shoots reach
two or three centimetres long,
the second just before or after
the flowering,
and the third a month later.
The treatment is preventative
and must not be neglected.
Gentlemen, I'll finish my speech
on mildew prevention.
I remind you
that as in previous years,
airplanes and flyers will be placed
at your disposal
to remind the farmers that mildew,
a disease that destroys vines,
appeared simultaneously
with that other ideological disease
which has devastated men.
But the Chief of Police
will develop this point.
Any similarity to actual persons
or events is deliberate
As the Under-secretary
of Agriculture said,
3 treatments are necessary.
An ideological illness
is like mildew
and requires preventive measures.
Like mildew,
it is due
to septic germs
and various parasitic agents.
So the treatment of men
with appropriate solutions
is indispensable.
The 1 st stage occurs
in the schools
where,
if you'll pardon the metaphor,
the sprouts are still very young.
The 2nd treatment
occurs when they begin to bloom
as college students
or young workers.
The draft is the best time
to spray and save the sacred
tree of national liberty
from the disease
of ideological mildew.
Air-dropped leaflets are telling
our peasants of a new kind
of ideological mildew
beginning to ravage our land.
This new variety
is spreading insidiously.
It's a sly enemy
pushing us away
from God and the Crown.
It's against this enemy
that our action is aimed.
Don't take notes!
It's all in our pamphlet.
With the outbreak of isms,
Iike socialism, anarchism,
imperialism or communism,
sunspots start to multiply
on the face of the golden orb.
God refuses to enlighten the Reds!
Scientists forecast
an increase in sunspots
due to the arrival of the beatniks
and pacifists from certain countries
such as ltaly,
France and Scandinavia!
As head of Law and Order
here in the north,
I wish to tell you,
who are high civil servants,
we must preserve
the healthy elements
of our society
and heal those that are ill.
Tonight the enemy's holding
a meeting on our city.
But we are not an ism!
We are a democracy!
We won't forbid the meeting.
Nor will we forbid
the opposition from demonstrating!
With these healthy anti-bodies,
we must fight all diseases
of both the vine
as well as Society!
That's all I have to say.
Bear it in mind
during the days to come!
- Having lunch?
- Rapidly!
I'll take you to your plane.
- Thank you!
- It's my pleasure!
Tell my wife
I'll pick her up this evening.
An excursion
for the Bolshoï ballerinas!
From Moscow?
The Bolshoï Ballet is here
for 4 days. They open tonight.
- Stay over! You can sit in my box.
- I must return to the capital.
Ah, the capital! The palace!
The Palace thinks well of you!
What if one of them
chose freedom here?
Like that famous dancer...
No, none of that!
For freedom they pick London
or the US where the money's stable!
We have enough hot-heads in town!
Enough problems!
Stop! Take that down!
No permit's needed
for a meeting indoors!
I don't want any trouble!
Get a permit to use the hall!
Do as I say!
Bring me your permit!
Or meet elsewhere!
Take it down!
How can we find
another hall now
and tell 3 or 4 thousand people
about it?
- It's a rally!
- You signed the receipt!
Now it's unsigned! Here's your check!
I'll pay you compensation!
You got threats!
I don't know what you mean!
You don't cancel a rental
unless you're pressured!
- You lawyers are...
- Bozini, you're an honest man.
Who's behind all this? Why?
I don't want you in my hall,
that's why!
If you don't like it, lump it!
There must be a reason!
My father died today! OK?
I'd gladly let you see it
but the city inspector came by.
When?
Yesterday.
The seats must be specially set.
We can set 'em up this afternoon.
No, fastened to the floor!
It'll take a week at least.
Since when!
We cancel or meet in the street!
And without a permit!
That'd mean instigators and cops!
We won't find a hall.
They'll all refuse!
I say we have to cancel it.
He'd never agree!
We cancel it
and go quietly off to bed
or better yet,
to the Bolshoï opening!
And we take him there too?
And send his audience there?
- You got a hall?
- The Bolshoï!
A plot on the doc's life!
- Says who?
- My wife.
Who told you? None of my business?
What'll we tell the police?
Don't hang up!
She won't say. The guy didn't know
the doctor's due today.
This is George Pirou.
You must tell us who...
Certainly not!
I trust him. He didn't know
about tonight's meeting.
He overheard a discussion.
He won't tell you. Me neither!
He's had enough trouble!
He has a family!
Now they know!
Now you know. So do something!
It's for you.
I know, darling. See you later!
What do we do?
Call the Red Cross!
Attorney-Gen.!
It's all quite vague.
An anonymous witness.
An overheard conversation!
Maybe it's a hoax or a chronic liar!
Like those who
phone there's a bomb in a plane...
Who'd want to kill your president?
Marie, open the door!
Shall we go?
I'll call the Head of Security.
He'll provide protection,
unofficially!
We've no basis for any action!
Yes, I'm interested
in the Paris Commune!
- I'm late!
- You'll come to the theatre tonight?
As for a hall, I can do nothing.
The colonel!
Property rights
can't be infringed upon,
even though
some may want to change that!
- Yes, Papa?
- Niki, see to our guest.
In 2 seconds!
He's a fine magistrate!
He's out? Give me his duty officer.
You know about tonight?
Not the Bolshoï!
Yes! The Doctor's life
has been threatened.
- No, but he's due to arrive...
- Shortly.
He'll arrive shortly.
No... on the phone.
Like you say...
Tell the Col. I phoned.
"All quite vague"...
"No basis for any action".
The Doctor'll be mad when he hears
we asked those puppets for help.
- Puppets?
- Of the USA!
What can they have to do with it!
Always blame the USA!
Even if you're wrong!
Cut it out! You're not always funny!
There they are!
The police?
They've tailed me for 3 days.
Everything's set?
No. We lost our hall
and no one knows it!
They want to sabotage the meeting.
Who can fix it?
Only the Head of Security.
We'll see him after lunch.
Let's go now!
Then, to the hotel.
Your life's been threatened.
A guy overheard some talk about it.
- We'll ask the cops...
- For nothing!
Just for a hall, that's all!
This hall does not meet
safety regulations.
It was in use 2 weeks ago!
Here's the report.
- It has no emergency exit!
- It never did!
With a normal show
there's no danger.
Your rally might excite people.
It's in no way dangerous!
I've no reason
to hinder your meeting.
My decision is based
on reports.
I'm neutral in this affair.
Then why're we being tailed?
For your safety! The Minister
of lnterior ordered us
to protect your committee members
from any possible extremists.
Whom you are using!
Other halls meet
the safety requirements,
Iike the Employees' Union Hall
opposite your hotel.
You simply cross the square!
I'm neutral in this affair!
Alright, Col.
There, on the 1 st floor! Not room
for over 200 people!
We'll look stupid! In a city
of 500,000, only 200 would hear you.
The rest'll be outside.
Ask the Col. to let us hang
loudspeakers from the trees.
Permit or not, people'll be here!
We'll go now...
...and try to alert people.
Print posters
with the rally's change of address!
Manuel, come discuss my speech!
George, you too!
I'll hold on.
Hello, darling! How are you?
Fine... yes.
Problems with the hall as usual!
Why should there be any fights?
Why any fights?
Yes, tomorrow.
George sends a kiss.
Till tomorrow, darling!
The kids?
Fine, but I don't see them enough.
Helen?
We're not always eye to eye
but it's not serious.
They say a hungry bear
won't dance!
The bears are going to read that!
Your pen!
Go!
Hold your meetings in Russia!
We'd rather stay here!
Do as you're told!
Hey, you!
What's the idea!
- Never mind!
- Better than the Bolshoï?
- I only came to please you.
- Your dancers are old-hat.
Except when one chooses freedom!
And the Warsaw Pact?!
We're against the bomb,
Russian or American!
Disarmament!
Long live the Bomb!
You could sell 'em
to the "Daily Worker"!
No more NATO bases!
Calm down!
No fighting! No provocation!
Ya just ease 'em away!
Ya don't push!
Leave 'em alone!
Calm down!
Don't provoke 'em!
Mr Lawyer!
Start now!
There's no more room up there!
Squeeze 'em in!
Get the speakers.
Ready?
I'll get 'em!
Go on in!
Let 'em in!
- So that's it!
- What?
The new opposition!
Women go for him!
Communist?
Never! He's anti-foreign!
Next elections, he'll win!
Good-looking!
Ex-Olympic champ, doc,
college prof and honest politician!
Perfection!
He's at the Bolshoï!
- He must cancel it!
- We back down!
To avoid provoking the crowd.
The students could maintain order.
- A free-for-all!
- You and your non-violence!
We must respect the law!
The law of the jungle!
They stuck us in that hall.
It's a trap!
Set by whom?
The ClA! We want
the foreign bases to be dismantled!
You think too much!
There are some stubborn extremists...
The threats?
It's not the 1 st time.
We've all taken risks.
They're all at the Bolshoï!
Keep trying.
The police must face
their responsibility.
We're going to our rally.
Rotten politicians!
We'll put ya in your graves!
We'll kill ya all!
Stay outside!
- And you?
- I'm a mason.
OK, let's go.
They hit me.
Why?
Why do our ideas
provoke such violence?
Why don't they like peace?
Why don't they attack
other organisations?
The answer is simple.
The others are nationalists,
used by the government
and don't upset
our Judas allies who betray us...
General, they're getting out of hand!
I'll have the loudspeakers cut off!
It'd excite the others.
Don't do that!
Where's the Chief of Police?
I was told he's here!
Really? He must be over there!
We lack hospitals and doctors
but half the budget
goes for military expenditures.
He's the one!
A cannon is fired
and a teacher's monthly salary
goes up in smoke!
That's why they can't
bear us or our meetings
and use hired thugs
to jeer and attack us!
Around the world. too many soldiers
are ready to fire
on anything moving toward progress.
He's your guy?
- You sure?
- I think.
An Olympic champ?
Stop!
Finish him off!
Shit! It's not him!
- I told ya it wasn't!
- They said it was!
Take off!
I'll go around to avoid the cops.
Tomatoes out of season!
They cost a fortune!
Fix your muffler!
I can't even make
the monthly payments!
Shit! The cops!
But our fight is theirs too!
We live
in a weak and corrupt society
where it's every man for himself.
It's blocked off here too! Hide!
Even imagination is suspect
yet it's needed
to solve world problems.
The stockpile of A-bombs is equal
to 1 ton of dynamite
per person on earth.
Horny again?
Yeah!
They want to prevent us
from reaching
the obvious political conclusions
based on these simple truths.
But we will speak out!
We serve the people
and the people need the truth.
Send them back to the Bolshoï!
The truth is the start
of powerful. united action.
Get those hoodlums out of here!
Down with the police state!
No more foreign bases!
Inspector!
Chief!
What're you waiting for?
Watch out!
Throw him off!
It's my cousin. He fell off!
By his feet!
I saw you hit him!
- What?
- What's going on?
I hit the brake
and my cousin fell off.
- He's bleeding and needs care.
- Your papers!
Just a moment...
Here they are!
He's bleeding! He needs care!
He hit him with a club!
See? It's nothing!
This is nothing?
- He tried to kill him!
- Dummy!
- My truck?
- lt'll be OK.
Call in for a patrol car.
Sure, call the station!
Stay there!
Look...
I'm goin'.
Pretend to try and stop me.
I can't explain but I gotta go!
Just play dead!
One move and I'll slug you!
What time is it?
I got a date I can't miss!
The regime can't change that!
All the Russians want
is to live like Americans!
Quick, sir, it's serious!
Come with me!
The Attorney-General!
We'll talk later.
And the ballet?
I had to miss it!
Why wasn't I told?
During the performance? How?
- What is it?
- A stupid traffic accident!
The culprit?
We'll have him soon.
- The victim?
- The hospitaI'll tell us.
I'll go there in your car.
Certainly!
Have the papers heard about it?
I doubt it.
I must call the Ministry!
Editorial room!
What on earth's wrong?
There was a demonstration.
We taught the bastards a lesson!
They hold a meeting?
Well, we can demonstrate too!
It's like a biological reaction.
Society's healthy elements,
the anti-bodies...
We beat the hell out of 'em!
What do you want from me?
Write...
...that I was there and beat 'em up!
What for?
So my pals'll know!
OK, if you want.
Get fixed up at the hospital
so they'll know
both sides were hurt!
Go now and I'll put
your name in the lead!
We warned you
but you said it was a hoax
- or a crackpot!
- Please!
This attempted killing
is your responsibility!
The police has proof
it was an accident.
Go easy! We need their help!
Such unfounded accusations!
They're blind... or worse...
accomplices!
They've no proof!
Assassination?
I was there taking pictures.
You got the truck?
No, I missed it!
The cops chased us away.
Such cynicism!
They'll use the incident politically!
- Surely!
- They know how to make martyrs!
Death-lovers!
Let's hope he doesn't die.
That would suit them!
The brain is damaged
in 2 or 3 spots. We're operating.
His heart is fighting hard
but it's too soon to say.
- But you must!
- He can't hear you.
You realise the political aspect?
But the other victim
is out of danger.
Other victim?
Senator Pirou.
He was found in the street.
It's serious but he's alright.
2 senators hurt!
Such incompetent police!
I must phone
the Minister in private!
His wife knows?
I don't eavesdrop!
I'm sure!
When's she coming?
Tomorrow, 1 st plane.
Tomorrow is today!
It's for my paper.
What did she say?
Nothing. I heard her breathing.
Then she said Will he live?
The director couldn't answer.
And she said
So they finally did it!
Were you there?
I'm a reporter...
I'm afraid the police bungled it!
I wanted no one hurt!
2 senators hurt... 1 critically!
We have the culprit!
Where? I want to see him!
He's in the canteen.
- The canteen!
- The cells are in poor condition.
No electricity!
So we use them for storage.
The Minister says this is serious
and a political catastrophe.
If the papers knew
he's in a canteen...!
The Minister wants
to be kept fully informed.
No handcuffs!
- His son?
- No, a street pedlar.
- Was he alone?
- No, 2 of them.
We have the end man's address.
It seems
he slept through the accident.
He gave himself up?
He was arrested for drunken driving.
You'll get a report.
Breathe!
- No alcohol!
- It's the stew.
Mutton stew kills all smells.
What have you been doing?
I made the stew!
He made it?
And you hid this from me!
I didn't know. I found out later.
You weren't told? Since when?
Since about 1 0:30 p.m.
That's harboring a criminal!
You knew about it, Col.?
I knew but...
...I hadn't had time
to tell the General.
Then you arrived.
The Gen. said
we didn't have the culprit
and I couldn't contradict him.
Fine!
I'll take his statement myself.
Get the 2nd culprit!
Eat!
They're at the presses!
Now what? You wear glasses now?
It's a disguise. Take my name
off the list. The guy's dyin'!
What's that to you?
Nothing! It was an accident!
2 drunks in a pickup truck!
If my name's in the paper,
I'll be questioned!
I'll remove it!
Are you free now?
No, I can't. I'm busy.
You'll have to go.
That way!
No one is to move!
What do they want?
To start trouble. We refuse!
But how do you explain
it's always ours who are killed?
- He's alive!
- Clinically he's dead! Why dream?
Clinically dead!
The brain's destroyed
but the heart's beating!
It won't quit!
One word
and they'll tear up the town!
Why hold them back?
I wonder if we've any will to fight.
He had! That's why
they killed him! Not us!
Come on!
It's all I could find.
The papers!
The cops put the blame on us!
Coffee?
"The broadcasting of the speech
was a provocation.
"The anti-national tone
"of the attack on foreign policy
aroused the crowd at once.
"Hence the violence.
"The police handled
the situation efficiently
"yet 1 3 policemen
were injured in the course of duty."
So said the Gen. to the Press!
We must answer that!
Yes, and stress
the pacifist nature of our rally.
We had permission...
So the cops
could do a better job on us!
But we have no proof!
Nothing valid!
We can only deplore
the police's passiveness.
Later we'll underline
all the contradictions.
Why not call the Red Cross
or the Rights of Man Commission?
You're making a cry-baby defense!
We must attack
and expose those responsible!
- Take up arms in the streets?!
- Why not?
Anything goes?
We can consider...
Nothing at all! It must be legal!
- We've been legal for years!
- This is no time to change!
It's our only way!
Or the affair could backfire!
Aren't you ashamed?
He's dying in there!
We've no case against them!
And the threats on his life?
He too ignored them!
But that was yesterday!
Will your guy talk now?
Statement to the Press?
I doubt it.
He was scared then of reprisals.
- And now, even more so!
- Try! Can you find him?
Not before noon.
We'll have to be careful.
We're being watched.
It's them!
But they're protecting us!
We're as safe as the doctor!
What was your reaction to the news?
The US President sent you a telegram?
Saying what?
Happily wed?
Was he threatened?
You'll let the Reds exploit this?
Was it an attempted assassination?
Why'd you send for a British surgeon?
Did you want a divorce?
Was it an accident?
They're operating...
for the 3rd time.
Here's the hospital director!
Your husband's had an accident.
I knew your husband.
We were at school together.
I wanted to go
to his peace marathon
but it was forbidden.
It's serious but he'll make it.
Prof. Dodd from London is here.
He's one of England's best surgeons.
Want to tell them the truth?
They'll live the truth later.
The fall broke
the dome of the skull
and no doubt
the brain has been affected.
The shock was very violent causing
an explosion inside the skull
Iike an earthquake.
I can't evaluate the aftereffects
of the concussion,
even if the operation succeeds.
The 3rd operation has just begun.
His heart
is the only positive factor.
We've massaged and used adrenaline
and its resistance is amazing.
It's beating regularly...
Come in.
Gen. Missou.
A stupid accident!
I'm deeply sorry...
Head of the Police...
We have the culprit.
Attorney-Gen.
My sympathies...
The inquest judge...
Well...
...certain areas of the brain
have been affected
but the lesions can't be defined.
But the surgeons are optimistic.
We must await the end
of the 3rd operation.
Your husband's heart is exceptional.
If it holds, he'll live!
We have every hope...
The capital is on the phone.
The Ministry!
They'll try to use his wife!
They'll use people's emotions!
The files!
Their committee secretary.
I want résumés on each.
Details of their private lives
and jobs too!
For this evening!
The injured senator.
The other lawyer.
And his? Have it?
It just came.
Any love affairs?
I don't know, but there must be!
Break his halo!
Does he get along with his wife?
- Watching her?
- Like the others, General.
- 2 of our men...
- I don't want to know that!
They met this morning,
picked up his wife
then separated.
Some took his wife to the clinic.
As for this one...
He took a statement
to the Press. You have a copy.
Then he saw some university students.
Students!
Call our students!
That one's a mad dog!
He wants to make the most of it!
- A Jew!
- Only half.
They think they're superior
even to other Jews!
- The Att.-Gen.!
- Good!
Stay on him night and day!
We were expecting you!
- The 2nd culprit?
- We have him.
He turned himself in.
Come into my office!
Please sit down.
He's boss now, officially.
So you're to give him
your initial findings
and then follow his instructions.
- My deputy'll keep me posted.
- The Col.'s men have checked...
Can I see the 2nd culprit?
Whenever you want to!
It seems he was asleep
on the truck, dead drunk.
So he's innocent,
if it all checks out.
Their whereabouts earlier?
The driver's statement and photo.
They'd been drinking
at the Chinaman's bar.
We have Chinese tradesmen in town?
The owner was in the Korean War
and now he's called the Chinaman.
He backs them up.
I'll read his statement.
"l, Bertrand... alias the Chinaman...
etc... bar owner... etc...
"do state
that on 22 May of this year,
"Yago and Vago
came into my bar at 7 p.m.
"and stayed until 1 0 p.m.
"They were drinking Pernod."
It's not allowed, Madam.
1 3th witness, a docker...
"l saw Yago and Vago
drinking Pernod all evening.
"They left at 1 0 p.m. drunk.
"The Chinaman said
Not in the Kamikaze!"
Kamikaze?
The pickup truck. It's Japanese made.
You'd think we're in the Far East!
I think it's clear.
Though we lack some details
on the culprits,
- it's obviously an accident.
- I agree.
Besides, the Minister phoned
and wants this settled very quickly
to cut short
political speculation abroad.
I think the prosecutor
must make a statement
about the accident today
and say the culprits are caught
and accused of drunken driving
and assault and battery.
And wilful flight.
Naturally!
And the man
who took him to the clinic?
It's for you.
He just died.
That doesn't change the statement.
Instead of "assault and battery",
say "manslaughter".
Go away, Shoula.
I'll wait for you.
Who are you?
An admirer of your husband.
A reporter.
No photos!
Only a few questions!
The public has a right to know!
Was it an accident?
Or not at all?
Yesterday his life was threatened.
Did you know?
You expected it?
You said So they finally did it!
What did I say?
To the hospital director
you said So they finally did it!
Who're they?
Go away!
The culprits have been arrested.
You thought of them?
Go away!
They know already?
Yes, and it's only beginning!
Unmask the killers!
The police is an accomplice!
Wait, I don't understand!
The fall didn't kill him?
Not at all.
The skull fracture
was due to a blow
struck on the head.
That's our conclusion.
The fall caused minor bruises.
You're sure?
A blow? You mean by the truck?
The truck hit his body.
It wasn't serious.
The death blow hit his skull
and was made by an instrument
such as a club,
an iron bar or a gun butt.
But no one's mentioned a weapon.
Continue, Doctor.
The skull fracture can only be due
to a weapon that struck from above.
That's the sole condition that causes
symmetrical lesions on the brain
touching the subjacent area
and the area opposite the wound.
An autopsy showed the lesions,
the right cerebral hemorrhage
and the fracture of the left temple.
In the case of a shock
due to a fall
on a hard surface like the street,
such lesions couldn't exist.
Why didn't you tell us sooner?
Yesterday!
Mr Deputy, he was still alive!
We needed an autopsy.
Time for other tests
would've shown the same facts.
Another hypothesis is
if the truck dragged him,
his skull could've hit the curb.
It's a fact that he was hit
in the middle of the street.
Then a fall couldn't cause
such lesions.
- A phone?
- Next door.
Yago was driving.
The 2nd man was drunk
and couldn't have been so precise.
A demonstrator.
Their story's odd.
- Know them well?
- Very well!
Political?
Maybe.
- Communists?
- Not if they work here!
The opposition?
One never knows.
The General, please.
I wanted to see you
to clarify a few points.
It all seems clear enough to me!
A new fact has come up.
It's stuffy in here!
You saw the accident?
How did it happen?
In what respect?
When the truck arrived,
what happened?
The Col. and I were there
when he walked out
waving to the crowd.
They didn't applaud him either!
He didn't see the truck
zigzagging toward him
and he was hit!
The Col.'s men ran after the truck.
2 men drew their guns
but, due to the crowd,
they didn't fire.
The truck zigzagged
and finally got away!
The police cleared the square
and helped put the victim
into a VW to go to the hospital.
No trace of the VW driver?
Not yet but he must be
a friend of theirs.
He helped them at once.
When the victim was run over,
could his head
have hit the curb?
No, it occurred in the square!
- You're sure?
- Positive!
But what's this new fact?
The autopsy says
he was killed by a club.
A club? Why did the doctors
do an autopsy?
It's the legal procedure.
Yesterday it was all settled!
Now you'll foul us up...
A new witness.
He claims he has proof
the senator was assassinated.
He'll be here today at 2 p.m.
There you are! An assassination!
Soon they'll say it was a plot!
I saw him! He's drunk!
He nearly fell in front of the truck!
What happened? You saw it?
Yes, he slipped and fell.
Anybody here?
I'm the Chief of Police.
I was on my way to testify
and as I walked along...
You fell and hit your head.
You suffer from epilepsy?
Someone hit me!
I was on my way to testify
the senator was assassinated!
It was no accident!
Yago told me so himself!
I was gonna testify!
But someone hit me on the head...
from a truck... with a club...
...to keep me quiet.
They tried to kill me!
I don't know who told you
to say this, or why.
I don't want to know.
We can forget all this.
Let's say you were influenced.
You're almost one of the family.
Your cousin's a policeman,
brother-in-law's got
a government job. Forget all this.
They're coming!
If you need anything,
come and see me.
I'll drop by again.
I'm a bachelor and live with my ma.
- Profession?
- I got a varnish shop.
You know Yago?
Sure! He makes
deliveries for me!
The other 2 I don't know.
The killing...
The accident.
...was the day I phoned Yago
about a delivery.
Varnished coffins! And I can't
even pay off my Kamikaze!
Come back this afternoon.
I'll be busy.
- Tonight then.
- I'm busy too.
I'm gonna make a real big mistake.
It'll be a murder.
Next day I learned
he'd killed the senator.
Yago told you all that?
You belong to the party?
I never belonged to any party!
I like soccer!
What is this?
The Gen. says I'm epileptic!
- General?
- The Chief of Police!
- He was here?
- Just before you came.
But I'm no epileptic
and never belonged to any party!
- Go on about Yago.
- That's all. He left.
He's the lucky one!
What about the delivery?
I tried to set him straight
but he does as he pleases.
Who told you to call
the inquest judge?
No one! I saw Yago's picture
in the papers!
On the front page,
like a Minister!
- Jealous?
- You made up this tale.
No, someone advised him.
Even Ma was against it!
She said to keep quiet!
- Come and eat.
- He killed him.
- Who?
- A senator.
- In the government?
- No, a leftist!
He did right!
What's it to you?
His picture too!
- Eat and let 'em kill each other!
- Not hungry!
Later my sister came.
So you wanna be a big shot?
Just doin' my duty.
Your duty's to see to your family!
I always have!
Ya got an idiot who sees to you!
Don't call my husband an idiot!
Ya think they'll give ya a medal.
I came anyway. Or I would've
if they hadn't slugged me!
You didn't fall?
I'd have to be an acrobat
to land on my head!
You can sign a statement later
if you still want to.
Of course! I'm not crazy!
1 st witness for the prosecution?
They lost no time!
Tomorrow you'll have 1 0, then 1 5.
They'll say Yago did this or that...
anything!
Vague, worthless statements
that'll create unrest!
They sent him
and beat him up
to turn a witness into a martyr!
They left him hospitalised
yet able to talk!
You admit I was beaten
and didn't fall?
You realise what perjury means?
It's not perjury!
I wanted to help, but if I'd known...
Told ya so! Why'd ya get involved?
Weren't ya alright at home?
Eat!
Suppose you say
you slipped on an orange peel?
I didn't slip!
Why're ya so pigheaded?
Listen to me for once!
The 1 st and last time!
- Like always!
- Really the last time!
Say you slipped and we got
no troubles. You won't go to prison.
I'll send others to prison!
I got 'em!
Yago and his picture!
Who sent ya?
The cops or your daughter?
Yes, it's me!
Ya wanna ruin my home?
Mama, leave!
Leave us alone!
- Don't argue!
- Go outside!
Ya hate me
'cause I've succeeded in life!
You and your husband hate me!
Never mind him!
You've caused him enough trouble!
Ya wanna ruin my life!
When Papa died,
I hoped you'd take his place.
I needed protection. You neglected me
and never took me anywhere!
You preferred soccer... and slobs
like Yago! See what it's got ya!
Prison, maybe... for perjury!
And my husband'll lose his job!
Come here... Listen!
You hear a guy's gonna be killed.
Ya don't believe it.
Then ya hear he's dead.
Would you tell the cops?
That's all I did, to help them.
Help who?
To help the cops find the murderer.
You're helping the others!
What do you want?
Your mother sent me. I'm a reporter.
I'll tell you what truly happened
'cause you print just anything!
Sure?
He wasn't hit. Either he slipped
or felt dizzy and fell
or else leftists hit him
to create trouble.
So say the police!
They say he's crazy
but can't prove it. Can you?
- No, I can't!
- Then why try?
I never said that!
He's stubborn as a mule!
He never changes his mind!
If he doesn't,
the inquest'll continue!
What if he is crazy?
And had epilepsy as a baby?
Tell him you and your husband
are rightwingers
and how ya got your jobs!
Yes, I do belong!
The cop!
- She woke him.
- Sleeping?
Pictures?
For the Press?
That's no good!
But that way people'll see
you were slugged
to keep you from saying
something important. See?
They'll beat me again?
They won't dare!
You're famous now!
But the Press must talk about you!
Tell me who saw you here...
your sister, the judge...
The General! He can't stand me!
I wanted to help
and got a cold shoulder!
They asked if I was a Commie!
- Are you?
- No! I only like soccer!
We'll be on the front page
for a week!
Sorry!
Who was it?
I know him!
And you're a cardiac case?
It's an old fracture!
Name and profession?
Any convictions?
- 4 times.
- 4!
Yes, 4!
Carrying arms illegally,
public outrage,
theft... and rape.
Rape?
Not really!
I was counselor at a boy scout camp.
Why were you in the hospital?
The Head of Security put him there.
My client has a weak heart.
The police doctor certified it.
I know but why the plaster cast
and a cane like a club?
It's 'cause of an old fracture.
I was broke when it happened.
I needed X-rays and 1 0 days in bed.
2 days of no work
and I starve!
It was a rich man's fracture!
The rich get a cold.
A week in bed!
For the poor, a fracture means
work or the grave!
So I had it seen to
while I was in the hospital!
Where were you that night?
At the Chinaman's with Yago till 1 0.
You see Yago often?
We're friends and cousins.
Was he drunk?
Yago drinks a lot!
The Chinaman told him
not to take the Kamikaze.
I got in back and fell asleep.
The shock and the yells woke me.
I thought we were in a ditch
but we were still going!
Then a guy leaped onto the Kamikaze
as lithe and fierce as a tiger.
He grabbed me and threw me off!
In the street!
He leaped like...?
- A tiger.
- Before that?
Lithe and fierce.
Yago used the same words.
Yet he didn't see him.
A simple coincidence!
They haven't met since the accident.
The police can swear to it.
Continue!
I was in the street
and almost got run over!
Then?
I went home.
Next day when I read the papers,
I went to the cops
who put me in hospital.
There he got lost in the halls
and met that reporter...
...by accident.
That agrees with the other testimony.
Yet one phrase makes me wonder.
It could change my investigation.
You're a Red!
You and Yago too!
Something you said
makes me think so.
"The rich get a cold. A week in bed!
"For the poor, a fracture
means work or the grave."
You gave yourself away.
I hate the communists!
Words! I want proof!
Only a Red would say such a thing.
I belong to an anti-communist group.
Yago too!
What one?
CROC! Christian Royalist
Organisation on Communism!
You created a storm!
Vago's jailed for collusion
and that means premeditation!
The judge believed you
and found out...
Vago and Yago belong
to a secret society!
- Secret?
- Yes, the CROC!
Anybody knows that!
The cops use 'em
to keep order at parades!
You've nothing to fear now.
But in a year I'll be forgotten.
No one can touch you.
Know anyone
who'd show me CROC members?
I'd pay.
- Sure, it's them!
- So help me!
Know anyone?
Yes.
But don't say I told ya!
It's Dumas!
He was born in Russia.
CROC's got a hold on him
'cause of trouble with his brother.
He'd like to get to Germany,
so if you can get him
a passport...
I can get one through my newspaper.
- Pictures?
- Here.
I've kept my promise.
Now it's your turn.
Don't like it?
Sure!
The questions?
Does CROC meet regularly?
Where?
At a guy's place on the edge of town.
Are there many of you?
Sometimes.
- What goes on?
- The boss talks.
Religion and the monarchy are
the 2 pillars of our eternal land
and Western Christian civilisation.
If ya don't listen, ya get no work.
What else?
In Russia a worker can't strike
or believe in God
or have his own house and garden.
He's crushed
by a totalitarian regime.
You agree?
I even read it in the papers.
The individual belongs to the State.
Yago went to the meetings?
Always.
They'd talk about capitalists.
No more capitalists or workers
or Left or Right.
A unified people is what we need!
We need a clean sweep!
Starting with the intellectual scum!
The bookstore next door!
He'd talk
about political youth groups.
What'd he say?
Unite the youth...
And give them a common ideal!
Abroad, some say
"Make love, not war!"
We say "Make war
"on corruption and on liberalism
"and on indiscriminate liberty!"
I say OK, but I don't give a damn.
And Yago?
He agrees 'cause he wants
to pay off his Kamikaze.
Now he'll be able to. Easy!
He killed the senator?
You said no accusations!
No, I'm paying!
Never!
But you can point 'em out to me
for some photos!
That's what you wanted?
The 3 on the pickup...
The butcher's involved.
The fat guy owns the bar
where we meet.
The barber.
The mechanic and the 2 in black.
- In khaki...
- Him?
An ex-boxer
who lived in the US a while.
In the yard, the boss... an officer
during the German occupation.
The fig seller, a loud mouth, always
up in front for the rough stuff!
Some figs, please.
He sells his blood and gets
a good price in case of emergencies.
He got rich selling
one of his eyes to an American.
He doesn't attend meetings anymore.
His sight's bad so he sells blood.
Not him?
Him?
Them?
No?
It looks like him...
He hit me twice!
Even in the ambulance!
Write that in the margin!
Publish it in your paper!
Sign the caption!
Publish it!
But not in your paper!
In a big daily paper!
For more readers...
- And money!
- Money!
In my paper tomorrow! I'll give
the inquest judge my photos.
Don't you want to be efficient?
In a local leftist paper,
no one'll see it!
In mine, it's sensational news!
Ya recognised me?
Ya dishonored me!
Ya made me out to be a gangster!
I wasn't at that demonstration!
I got nothin' to do with politics!
Politics are a lot of crap!
Let him be!
Leave!
I'm the judge.
Well?
I'm on the front page!
Mr Pirou says I hit him
at the demonstration!
I wasn't there! I got witnesses!
Politics are a lot of crap!
I was at the market with my figs!
Your picture's in what paper?
I forget! It arrives
from the capital at 1 0:00!
I can't read... very easy.
The news vendor showed it to me
and read it to me!
At the market
they think I'm a hoodlum!
I wanted an explanation, man to man!
From the capital?
Still recognise me?
I said, what paper?
The papers that arrive
from the capital at 1 0:00.
This morning they didn't.
The mail plane was fogged in.
Who told you to say all this?
Yes...
I hit him.
But...
...I had to!
Somebody forced me to!
Who? His name?
I can't tell you. He's too big!
Too important! I can't!
He told me about it.
Barone, your picture's
in one of the capital's papers!
Mine?
One that arrives at 1 0!
So at 1 0:45
you go see Pirou at the hospital.
Raise hell! Say you're innocent!
Scream and shout!
Reporters'll be there.
Now tell me again?
I rush to the hospital...
Get outta here!
...to see Pirou.
But tell me his name!
I can't! He's too big!
Alright. Follow me, please.
I'm innocent!
I only wanted to testify!
It's all leftwing politics!
This important man...
He helped you?
Yes, in my work and for my birds.
They wake the neighbors.
I was gonna have to move!
But my birds are pretty!
You should see 'em, Judge!
He helped me in my work too.
My market permit and all that.
The day of the accident
you saw him?
Yes, Jimmy said
"The head's downstairs."
He was in his car.
Get in!
You know it's tonight?
Impossible!
I got some figs due in!
They gotta be uncrated.
To sell them, you need a stand?
I got one.
And you need a permit?
But for how much longer?
- 6 months.
- And who renews permits?
He does?
Yes.
Then he dropped us off.
Do a good job tonight.
I'm counting on you.
You'll get a permanent permit and
maybe a new house, for your birds!
I said "Colonel, I'll do my best."
The police colonel?
Yes!
Let's start at the beginning.
Can you come in, Deputy?
Prolonging the inquest
gives the opposition
fuel for subversive action.
- You've sided with them?
- It's not a prolongation.
It's a totally new case.
Some points are awkward
but the case is clear!
On the contrary.
We began with an accident
and 2 drunks...
Some ice, dear!
Their testimony
coincides in detail.
Confirmed by the Chinaman!
Next day, the autopsy says
death was due to a blow by a club.
A 2nd autopsy will say no,
and a confirmation'll disprove
the initial autopsy!
I'd had no time
to examine this new theory
when a witness says
it was an assassination.
Based on a vague discussion!
On his way to see me,
the witness is clubbed
- and is still in the hospital!
- What do you mean?
I'm only stating facts.
Then comes the reporter. He's not
a militant and that's important!
I learn
Yago and Vago belong to CROC,
the Christian Royalist...
I know, I know...
...along with the assailant
of the 2nd senator
and most of those
at the demonstration.
It seems the police know
and use them as auxiliaries
to maintain order for state visits.
That's yet to be proven,
Iike the fact
that the Police Col.
drove this man
to the demonstration.
Really!
He wouldn't be involved
with such a person!
Not openly! No one'll believe it!
My conclusion is this:
As a case of drunken driving,
it's simple
but impossible.
If we accept
the premeditated act of a group
aided or simply abetted
by the police,
it all becomes clear
and fits together.
This is serious!
I must phone the Minister!
I favor the accident theory.
Premeditated, if you wish
by 2 drunken fanatics.
Yes, you don't smoke!
You must settle this quickly!
The country, even the whole world
is watching and waiting.
Our country's honor is at stake!
Don't bother with these fools!
Your future lies before you!
This case can either make...
...or break your career!
Trust in my experience!
My group is authorised by the State.
We are honest citizens,
healthy elements of Society,
anti-bodies
in the fight against infection.
We want to protect
Western Christian civilisation.
But it is a moral struggle.
No members of my group
were at the demonstration.
Where were you that night?
I was at the Dockers' Union.
Alibi confirmed.
I was playing cards with my dentist.
Confirmed.
I'm a baker.
I slept till midnight at my shop!
Alibi confirmed.
I was at the Chinaman's.
Confirmed.
At the Chinaman's.
I played cards with my dentist.
Confirmed.
That's not you at the demonstration?
It does look like me.
Indicted for perjury...
...along with those
who confirmed his alibi!
Plus obstructing justice!
Take him away!
Witness 27 has died
of a heart attack.
He owned the CROC meeting hall.
Earlier you stated Yago
hit you with a club
Iike a police billy-club.
- Do you maintain that?
- Yes, Judge.
The Att.-Gen. says he phoned you
that the senator's life
had been threatened.
Your superiors
never got his message.
Yes, I forgot to tell them.
That's a serious error!
I'll answer to my superiors,
not to you, Judge.
That morning,
you were warned of death threats
against the senator.
Who told you about them?
A colleague's wife.
She can't tell us the name.
She'll have to.
The man says I can tell you.
He's waiting in the hall.
Bring him in.
His name's Coste.
- On the assassination day...
- The incident!
...he came to my office
to tell me of a conversation.
But he'll tell it to you better.
Don't mention me in the papers.
Not my name!
Why? Isn't your story true?
Yes, but I want no trouble.
If you do, come see me.
Wait in the hall, please.
Name and profession?
Ilya Coste, deliveryman.
On the assassination day...
Day of the incident!
An assassination's not yet proven.
The day of the incident was rainy...
I work myself to death
and the bank gets
half of what I earn!
Someone's calling you!
Again!
Which one?
That one!
Go on!
I heard Yago say...
- If it rains?
- So?
- We'll skid!
- It won't!
It won't rain!
But I got payments due!
We'll cover you.
All the payments!
The varnisher phoned!
He wants ya this afternoon
to deliver some coffins!
It's a good sign! See you tonight!
Then he came over.
I'll buy you a drink!
As he sat down I saw the club.
What's that for?
Tonight! A delivery job
that'll take care of a lot!
What kind?
A delivery into hell!
A senator from the capital.
A dirty job!
No one knows.
If they do, it'll be by you!
Later, the same man came back.
He's different in civvies.
You knew him?
I'd asked for a truck permit.
Every 6 months I went to him
about it. He was always in uniform.
But why pick Yago?
He's the best driver in town.
You should see him
with his Kamikaze.
He has a political record.
He was in the communist
underground in the war
- then deported to the islands.
- His testimony...
...is suspect, of course.
I wouldn't use it.
Never mind.
They want to eliminate
all troublesome witnesses!
They just tried to get me!
What?
Attempted murder! Just now!
The plot continues!
And will continue!
I don't need your advice!
This involves the top brass!
The police's their toy!
And cops haven't the possibility
to commit such a murder
without being protected!
The guilty ones are
in the government or at the palace
where the General
is head of the guards.
And the palace
takes orders from abroad!
One more word
and I'll charge you
with defamation of the State!
This isn't a rally!
What happened?
They tried to kill me! They knew
I had important info for you.
So a car tried to run me down
on my way here!
Any witnesses?
Here are 3 honest,
God-fearing housewives
who'll testify, plus a park guardian,
a war vet with medals!
What's this information?
The police own the VW...
That took him away to the hospital?
But no cops were allowed
in the car to finish him off,
so the driver took
the longest route. I know!
I was there!
But the car belongs
to one of your friends!
He must be a friend!
He helped them at once!
Who told you such a tale?
The car disappeared!
No trace of it at the hospital!
The page was torn out
of the registry!
Don't you find that odd?
I think you did it
to add grist to your mill!
Is this the car?
Yes.
Find the owner of this car!
If you wish to wash...
Thanks, I'm alright.
Sit down.
Tell me what you know.
But I warn you,
you risk indictment for perjury.
Go ahead.
The car was waiting there,
hidden by the police.
And when the truck came?
He came forward.
Inspector!
Chief!
He wanted the General
to clear the square.
Come on!
What're you waiting for?
I saw the truck arrive.
Watch out!
The man in back was standing up?
Did he hit him?
I dunno. It happened too fast.
And then?
He fell to his knees.
His knees?
His head hit the pavement?
No. he was on his knees
surrounded by the demonstrators.
The police did nothing.
Which demonstrators?
Impossible to say.
We pulled him free.
Then he collapsed.
A VW arrived
from where, I don 't know.
,
Finally,, the cops intervened
and tried to get into the car.
Come on!
Get to the hospital!
Get going!
Faster! Honk your horn!
Is it broken?
Turn right!
This way avoids traffic!
He did it to waste time.
Then, he hit another car!
,
Keep going!
I need a damage report!
A man's hurt!
It's a matter of life or death!
OK, go on!
He did it on purpose!
And the cops would've
killed him in the car!
On purpose?
I did my best! They were upset,
I can understand that.
No one noticed me at the hospital.
I'd rented the car
for an afternoon date
and was on my way home.
Roadblocks were up.
I must not have noticed the police.
At the hospital I washed
the seats of the blood.
You said "I'm a part-time chauffeur".
But you're a serviceman!
- I'm doing my military service.
- What branch?
As a policeman.
You're a police chauffeur!
What section?
One close to the General.
How close?
Personal.
Since when?
1 year.
The General's driver for 1 year.
You were at the scene
of the murder by accident.
Shall I write "murder"?
You said "murder".
Do you know who has arrived?
The Nat'l. Att.-Gen.!
Leave us alone.
The Nat'l. Att.-Gen.
has come to talk to you...
...totally incognito.
Yes, he's here.
I'll bring my files at once.
So it's you... Sit down.
You're ready to indict
the Chief of Police?
It's inevitable.
My friend,
only Divine Will is inevitable!
Proof is overwhelming, sir.
Proof? Hearsay!
So-called proof
by so-called pacifists
who want to create a hero!
That's certain, sir,
but police complicity
with the demonstrators is certain.
Those 2 men circled in red
are plain-clothes men.
They admit being
in the demonstration.
We also know
the Police Chief met Yago that day
plus other demonstrators.
The General said
he didn't know the driver of the VW.
But he's the General's
personal chauffeur!
I won't mention
the police's passiveness.
Then comes
the intimidation of witnesses.
Vago is hospitalised secretly
with a police medical certificate.
He's found near the room
of a major witness, with a club!
Then there's Yago's club
during the demonstration.
Several witnesses saw it.
It disappeared when he was arrested.
But the agent admitted
rewriting his report.
You shouldn't mention
the club in your report.
But it's done, sir!
I'm the Police Chief General!
At ease!
Don't worry. You did your duty.
You've been a policeman how long?
6 years.
Just rewrite your report.
Ah! The Att.Gen.!
And then you arrived, sir.
He couldn't lie. On the contrary!
His confession'll cost him a lot.
There is a case for indictment,
but not enough for a jury
to condemn the police.
The jury'll do its duty.
I've done mine.
You'll discredit the police
and the court
who will be blamed
for absolving them.
As if it's not enough
our country's been invaded
by long-haired atheists and addicts.
Now you want to cast doubts
on our armed forces,
the sole healthy elements
in our country.
We dream of a renewal
of a land with no parties,
left nor right,
obedient to God.
You want to ruin it.
Listen...
I have a proposal for you.
I understand your scruples.
They honor you.
My idea should suit you
and the government and the palace.
We'll divide the case in 3.
1 st, the trial of the 2 criminals.
Let justice be done!
2nd, the police authorities.
Their negligence is evident
but can't be tried
by a circuit court.
It's strictly
an administrative matter.
3rd, an action
against the rally organisers.
They and their loudspeakers are
responsible for the ensuing violence.
An old rule of thumb
is to always look for those
who benefit from a crime.
The Minister of Justice
thought you're a Leftist.
I formally denied it.
Here's a list of helpful witnesses.
It seems no one wanted to kill
the senator. Just intimidate him.
I trust I've convinced you
to save the honor
of the forces of law and order.
But you're the sole master
of your conscience, after God.
I won't be disgraced!
Indict me and I'll commit suicide!
Dishonor is unbearable!
My blood'll be on your hands!
Name and profession?
You must answer.
Sign your statement.
You are indicted
for premeditated murder.
The law allows 24 hours
to superior officers
before their imprisonment.
To avoid the reporters,
use that door.
You're indicted
for premeditated murder.
It's unbearable!
You've no right!
I've been thrown to the hounds!
Name and profession?
You're indicted
for premeditated murder.
Sit down.
For me there's no choice!
Either I'm cleared
or I'll commit suicide!
Name and profession?
It's routine, General!
What did you do that day?
I was to attend the Bolshoï Ballet.
Not out of love for the dance!
I'm not one of those perverts!
But it was a chance
to spot some Reds.
The day of the assassination
you were told
his life was threatened.
No one told me about it!
I'm sure it was only a tactic
to justify any incidents.
My men couldn't stop the truck
but a man leaped
on the rear platform,
Iithe and fierce as a tiger.
I know no one in that organisation.
I've had no contacts
with this... CROC.
You're seen here at a banquet
you gave for them.
To thank them for keeping order
during a state visit.
Is he a Red? Why's he after me?
His father was police chief.
The photo's phony! It's not proof!
You're indicted
for premeditated murder!
Are you a martyr like Dreyfus?
Dreyfus was guilty!
Helen! They're all indicted,
even the General!
The judge didn't back down!
Helen, it's like he was still alive!
It's a real revolution!
The government'll fall
and extremists'll be wiped out!
Elections'll be a landslide!
THE TRlAL
The Deputy was not at the trial.
He died of a heart attack,
according to the coroner.
7 other witnesses died
before the trial.
A car accident,
a gas explosion,
a suicide, a drowning,
a work accident,
a 2nd car accident
and a heart attack while driving.
"Foul play is doubted"
says the new Chief of Police.
Vago was sentenced
to 8 years in a farm prison
where 1 year equals 2 years.
Yago got 1 1 years of the same.
1 0 months for disturbing the peace.
1 year with a possibility
of paying it off.
The 4 indicted officers only
received administrative reprimands.
Yet the government had to resign.
After the trial, the Leftists
seemed certain to win the elections.
Prior to the elections, the army
seized power and dismissed the judge.
Senator George Pirou died in a police
car of a clot on the brain,
said police officers.
Deported to the islands.
During questioning,
fell from the 7th floor
trying to escape,
said the police.
3 years for revealing
official documents.
Also. the military regime banned
Iong hair,, mini-skirts.
Sophocles,, Tolstoy. Euripides.
Russian-style toasts. strikes.
Aristophanes. Ionesco,
Sartre, Albee. Pinter.
,
freedom of the Press. sociology,
Beckett. Dostoyevsky,
modern music,, pop music.
new math
and the letter "Z" which means
"He is alive " in ancient Greek.
Subtitles: Jaib Warner
Subtitling: ECLAlR VlDEO