Madam.
Your glasses fell off.
Madam, can we swap places?
Can we swap places?
You're sleeping and not looking anyway.
Say thank you.
Thank you, madam.
This route through Belarus
is a gift from God.
It's a thousand times better
than the one over the sea.
Otherwise I wouldn't have come here.
With children?
Never in my life.
In Harasta we lost everything.
Our home and our store.
We escaped the siege
and went to the camp.
For five years.
Sorry, I didn't understand...
what you said now.
What did you say?
So... lady...
She said...
war in Syria is very strong, very bad.
Tell her the kids couldn't go to school.
And that you used to teach them.
No school in the camp.
I teach my grandson, my granddaughter.
Ah, okay, I understand.
Grandpa, I can't see anything.
Yes, darling, because we are
in the middle of a cloud.
A cloud is water, right?
Of course, where does rain come from?
Grandpa, we're getting close to Sweden.
No, darling, this isn't Sweden.
- How do you know?
- Because first we are going to Belarus.
From Belarus we go to Poland,
and then to your uncle in Sweden.
Nice stay in Belarus.
Look, look, this is Belarus.
Give me the phone, darling.
Nice stay in Belarus.
- Nice stay in Belarus. It's for you.
- Oh, thank you.
Dear passengers,
this is your captain speaking.
Shortly, we are going to commence
our descent and approach to Minsk airport.
The weather down there is quite good,
but it's partly cloudy and
the temperature is minus two degrees.
And it was my pleasure
to have you all on board
and we wish you a very good day.
- Abu Bashir?
- Yes, my darling.
- Did you write it down?
- Yes.
It should be there by now,
a light-colored minibus.
Don't move, he knows where to find you.
Remember, everything is paid for
and he'll take you to
the best border crossing.
- Ok?
- Ok.
Uncle, did you buy me
that game you promised?
Of course, here it is.
It will be waiting for you
when you get here.
Thank you, uncle.
You're welcome, my darling.
Where is Bashir?
Bashir! Your brother wants to talk to you.
- Hi.
- How are you?
- Alright.
- You'll be in the European Union soon.
- Then a quick drive to Malmö.
- Alright.
- Amina?
- Yes?
- Once you get to the border...
- Yes.
send me your location
so the driver can pick you up.
Ok.
Thank you.
- Here it is!
- That's our minibus.
Sir?
- Are you going to the border?
- Yes.
Can I come with you?
- What does she want?
- She wants to come with us.
But we don't know her.
- If there are seats, let her come.
- There are, and why shouldn't she come?
- Yes, madam, okay.
- Okay.
Thank you.
Oh God!
$300 now.
He said he wants $300.
$300!
No dollar, no dollar.
Wesam paid him everything.
Sir, please don't get angry.
I'll give you 300 euros.
It's more than dollars, okay?
- Ilya? What's going on?
- Everything's fine.
- Come on, come on.
- Wait.
Wesam paid him everything,
why is she paying again?
Let her give it to him,
we don't want any trouble.
What's wrong with them?
Wait here.
- Have we made it to Sweden yet, Grandpa?
- Not yet, my love.
- Mama, I need to pee.
- We'll find a toilet right away, sweetie.
Me too, but I'm not complaining.
- No coverage.
- No coverage?
Why don't you try?
- What was that?
- What is it?
Is here the state border?
It's the border, out, out.
Come on, come on.
Come on, Ghalia!
Is here the state border?
- There's the border.
- Yes, go, go.
Move it, move it.
Run, run, run!
Go, go. That's the border.
Go, go, go.
Go, go, go, faster. Go!
The bag!
Run!
Fucking run!
Run, I said!
Run!
You have to run now. Run, run!
Come on, Dad.
Run into the forest!
Give me a second.
Take your backpack off.
Mama... I peed my pants.
Don't worry, I'll change them.
Come with me.
Nur, darling, what happened?
Why is your hand bleeding?
Poland | Belarus
We're in Poland.
We're in Europe.
We're in the European Union!
We made it!
She said we are in Europe.
We've reached Europe.
Show me your hand.
- It hurts a lot?
- Yes.
Let me clean it for you.
Enough! Be quiet!
I'm...
I'm cold, I can't help it.
We know!
But...
I'm really cold.
Good morning.
I bear witness that
there is no deity but God,
and I bear witness that
Muhammad is the Messenger of God.
God is the Greatest.
In the name of God, the Most
Gracious, the Most Merciful.
All praise be to God,
Lord of all worlds.
Guide us along the straight path.
Damned fucking mobile.
Dad.
Let's try from your phone.
The path of those you have blessed,
not those you are displeased with.
God is the Greatest.
Dad, let me try to text Wesam
from your phone.
Glory be to my Lord,
the Most Magnificent.
God is the Greatest.
Glory be to my Lord, the Most High.
I seek forgiveness in God!
What's wrong with you, Bashir?
Let me send him a pin.
Instead of praying with me?
The phone's dead,
Ghalia had it on the plane.
She was playing with it
until the battery died.
- What's wrong with you?
- I just want to send Wesam our location.
Bashir, my darling, put the cigarette out.
Come pray with me.
I don't want to pray.
I won't pray.
I seek forgiveness in God,
I seek forgiveness in God.
God is the Greatest.
Nur! Ghalia! Get up!
It's pouring.
It's ok, sweetheart.
It's okay, it's okay.
Come on, come on.
Come on, my dears, come on.
Bashir, Bashir.
Hold it up with me.
Nur.
Thank you.
Amina.
Mama, look! Nur looks like a girl.
And you look like a grandma.
Nura, lovely Nura.
- I don't want to wear it anymore.
- No, no, no! Nur!
Nur, keep it on.
You'll get sick. Enough!
- Nura, lovely Nura.
- Nur, look at me, you're the older one.
- Stop it, Ghalia!
- You'll be sorry.
Nur, that's enough, son.
- Amina.
- Yes?
Give me the powerbank.
Take the powerbank from the bag.
That was the only thing
I asked you to do!
Bashir.
Thank you.
Thank you, madam.
It's wet.
Water.
- Water.
- I have a phone.
What will we do now?
There's a road there.
What?
What did she say?
She said there's a road there.
Mama, I want to drink.
Sweetheart, we'll drink
when we get to the car, ok?
- So when?
- Soon.
Just stop whining!
Nur, Nur!
In a moment, not long.
You look lovely. Come on.
Open your mouth, there's more.
Good girl! Want some more?
Here, open your mouth.
- Amina!
- Mama!
Help me!
- Amina!
- Bashir!
Dad! Hold him.
Bashir!
It's ok, sweetheart, don't worry.
I've got you.
Nothing happened.
Don't be scared, sweetie.
It'll be fine.
Shhh, it's ok, sweetheart.
Mom, are you ok?
Yes, sweetie, I'm fine.
Slowly, slowly.
I think he is hungry.
There, there, darling.
I've got you now.
Come over here, my darlings.
Let's try.
Mahir!
I don't have milk anymore.
Can I help?
Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday,
Thursday, Friday...
Saturday...
- Sunday.
Yes, bravo.
You can speak English!
What's your name?
Kylian Mbappé.
I don't think so.
My name is Leila.
What's your name?
Nur.
Say: My name is Nur.
My name is Nur.
Bravo. Where are you from?
Harasta, Syria.
- Say: I'm from Harasta.
- I'm from Harasta.
Yes, I'd like to stay in Europe.
I'd like to stay in Europe.
Hello, sir.
Sir?
Water?
Can you spare me some water, please?
Water.
Water?
Okay.
Thank you very much.
- No, keep it.
- Thank you.
Keep it.
Okay.
Do you have some food?
Food?
Thank you.
Want them?
Try over there.
Try there, yeah.
Okay, thank you so much.
Thank you, thank you, sir.
Stop!
Wait!
Don't shout! Be quiet!
Leave her alone!
Leave some.
For the kids.
Leave some for the kids.
- Stop, stop.
- The soldiers will come.
What soldiers?
Let's go, let's go!
Please, please, help.
Help, help, help.
Stop, Border Guard!
- Mom, what's going on?
- Grab the old one!
Please, please, I...
Please.
Backpack!
Stand there!
Hands.
Dad! Dad!
Bashir!
Don't do anything!
- No, no, no, I'm not doing anything.
- Are you Polish?
I'm from Afghanistan.
- They're clean.
- Ok.
Easy. Stand up.
Stand up. Easy.
- Reporting a group, zero zero two one.
- It's ok.
Forest road 4.
One mile east of base,
we need transport.
Okay.
We'll pick up some tourists
and come to you.
Oh, no!
Very nice these guys.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
- We can see you.
- Over here.
We're approaching.
Okay, let's go.
Get them loaded up.
Go on, get on the truck.
To Sweden, to Sweden?
Yes, that car goes to Germany.
Then Sweden.
You're a lucky man!
Don't worry, it's alright.
Get on the truck.
Get on, Bashir. Take the kids.
He said they'll take us to Sweden.
Mama, what are they going to do with us?
Don't worry, sweetheart, I'm with you.
Everything is going to be alright.
Come sit next to me, darling.
Nur.
Hi, what's up?
Working.
What the fuck do I mean?
I'm escorting some darkies, aren't I?
And you?
They stink so bad, it's unbearable.
Yeah.
Two, three hours.
We're heading back to base.
Tonight? Sure, we can meet.
Does anyone have a powerbank?
Battery?
Powerbank?
- Okay.
- Telephone?
Quick.
Yeah.
Nothing really.
For real, man...
It's alright. What can I tell you?
Please, no Belarus! Please!
Please, no Belarus!
No Belarus.
Hey, get out, get out.
Go, go, now.
Move it!
Come on.
Let's go.
Go, go, go.
Turn the lights off
or the Belarusians will see us.
Get him across right away.
Fucking move it.
Go, go, go.
Push him down.
I escaped from Afghanistan.
My brother worked with
the Polish army in Kabul.
- I want asylum in Poland.
- Go. Go!
Go, go, go.
Grab that phone off her.
- Grab that phone off her.
- No!
You're not allowed to do this.
- It's illegal. We're in Europe!
- Mister, she's a lady, mister!
We'll report you!
The damned dog...
Someone left a thermos.
It's not deep.
Whose is this?
Hey!
Catch!
Cheers.
Karim! What happened?
- Are you fucking nuts?
- Why?
- Are you not human?
- Have you never eaten glass before?
If you came to our town,
we'd invite you in.
- You would be our guest.
- What?
I don't understand.
We would welcome you into our homes.
Why?
Why are you doing this to us?
We need your help!
Ahmad Dia!
- Ali!
- Dad!
Excuse me, sir.
We need water.
Can you give us some water, please?
The children need to drink.
- Water.
- Yes, please.
- Give me money.
50 euros.
50 euros?
Yes, yes.
Yeah.
Give it to me.
Give it back, please.
No!
- Dad! Where are you going?
- Why, why, why, mister?
Why, mister? Why? Why?
Dad!
Grandpa! Grandpa!
Nur!
Enough, enough!
- Enough, enough!
- Stop, stop, please.
God!
May God punish them.
Wait, Bashir.
- Why?
- Let me check the mobile isn't broken.
I hope it isn't.
Thank God it's ok.
- Listen.
- Yes?
There is some battery left.
Text your brother,
tell him they sent us back to Belarus.
- Just hide it somewhere.
- Ok.
Are you hurt, my dear?
No, and you, Grandpa?
I'm fine.
There's blood on your face.
Are you ok?
Yes, yes, I am ok.
I'm fine, I'll just go and sit there.
Let the kids drink.
Do you want some water, son?
Nur?
No, I'm fine.
Ghalia.
My sweetheart.
There's no signal here,
don't waste your battery.
And hide your mobile.
You'll need it later.
Look what they did to mine.
Look what those motherfuckers did.
Listen. The Belarusians
will send us back to Poland.
They already sent me there
five, six times.
And every time, the Poles catch me
and send me back here.
The motherfuckers.
Beating and kicking us.
Let's stick together, but in case
we get separated, take this number.
- Ok.
- Take it quickly.
- Faster.
- Ok, ok.
When you reach Poland,
send a text to this number.
They'll get you whatever you need.
They're good people.
They're good Poles.
Go! Go!
Nabil! Nabil!
Nabil! Where are you?
- Nabil! Nabil!
- Amina! Amina!
Dad!
Amina!
- Don't shoot!
- Come on, quick.
Bashir!
Move it, move it!
Go, go, go.
Dad! Let's go!
Dad, let's go!
Faster!
Don't stop!
Come on, faster!
Come on!
Bashir!
You have to show professionalism.
Because if you give them an apple,
they'll just say it was poisoned,
and then what?
This isn't propaganda,
it's a real threat!
One mistake, and in six months we'll have
an attack on the Warsaw subway.
Did you hear what Minister Kamiński
and Minister Wąsik said?
They were found with terrorist,
pedophile and zoophile materials!
Have you seen the phones they have?
- You couldn't afford...
- What should I do?
- ...half of what they have.
- Pick it up.
And I don't want to hear about their kids!
[Got pains. Come here. I have to go to hospital.]
They hire or buy children,
and then blow smoke in
their eyes to make them cry.
I saw the footage myself.
We're saving them.
You have children of your own.
What father would take
his child down this road?
Well?
They want to play on our Polish compassion,
while Lukashenko rubs his hands.
Remember, this is classic hybrid warfare.
They aren't people, they are weapons
of Putin and Lukashenko.
They aren't people...
they are live bullets!
You've all had first-aid training
at some point.
Now listen up.
No one is to be found dead
on your watch, ok?
There are to be no dead bodies
lying around.
If you see one, it shouldn't be there,
is that clear?
They say you don't get psychological care,
but that's not true.
This officer here...
- Daria Schitz-Lis.
- Diarrhea Shitless.
Schitz-Lis.
Daria Schitz-Lis.
She's a trained psychologist
whom you can make an appointment to see...
in the usual way,
by the hour, at our expense.
All right, joking aside,
I was sent here to build up your morale,
but I don't care about that.
If you're not ready to wear the uniform,
you now have the chance
to consider it all
and leave the room if you want.
Anyone else?
It's ok, I just forgot to drink water
so I probably had colic.
But my movements feel normal.
Ok, so drink plenty of water,
and lie down. Ok?
- Don't worry, I'll be at home.
- Ok, I love you.
Bye.
Miss Indecisive?
- No, no, I just had to...
- Sit down.
Learn the grace of God.
There you go, a beautiful femur.
What a pretty face.
After daddy.
Come on, show yourself.
Look...
the foot is moving.
- What's going on?
- Why isn't there any sound?
They should pay me extra for working
with equipment like this. It's ok now.
Don't worry, it's fine.
Come on, baby girl.
A girl?
One hundred percent woman, sir.
Daddy's little girl.
Klara?
Or Zosia.
Lewandowski named his daughter Klara.
All right.
And when's the baby due?
Well...
- It looks like around the end of January.
- Ok.
And more precisely?
Medicine isn't an exact science.
A full-term pregnancy runs for 37 weeks.
- That's all I can say.
- Yes, but in your experience...
Geez, Jan, I'm not an incubator
that you can just program.
Get the renovation done
before Christmas, ok?
After you.
You were meant to move out
of our place by Christmas.
But now you'll still be with us at Easter.
It would be even sooner
if you helped with the floor panels, Dad.
Flooring isn't really my thing.
Plumbing, yes.
Well, if you helped us with the pipes,
we'd move in quicker.
Janek, look.
Someone's fucking been here.
Maybe it's mine.
Right then.
Ok.
No, look, someone's fucking been here.
Are you alright?
Does this state of emergency
allow you to use firearms?
In self-defense.
Self-defense! But you have clearance,
I take it?
They count every fucking bullet we fire.
Come on.
Fuck, our moronic boss
really screwed up the rotas.
And now I've got the day shift
with some old fossil.
And one more bottle, please.
Did you know the chief's coming to see us?
- Yeah, I heard.
- Could I also have...?
Our friend wants to buy condoms
but is too afraid to ask.
Fuck off!
Emel cigarettes, please.
Red or blue?
- Slims! The slimmest ones.
- Shut your mouth.
- Fuck off.
- Fuck off yourself.
Gentlemen, maybe you noticed
there's a pregnant woman standing here?
I know it doesn't matter to you,
but you should let this lady go first.
How do you know
what matters to us, huh?
But I've already entered these items.
Just cancel them.
Apparently, you push pregnant women
over the wires!
My husband works in the Border Guard
and he certainly doesn't do that.
You have no idea about anything!
They are Lukashenko's weapons. If we let
them in now, thousands more will follow.
I'll take it.
I understand it's difficult for you,
and I do sympathize.
I'm very proud of my husband.
If you're so smart, you take them in.
A bag, please.
I'm here, I'm here.
Quick, so we can still
give you a ride home...
What's wrong, Kaśka?
Hormones.
It's ok.
Yesterday, I even cried at
a commercial for soap powder.
Ok?
Come on.
- Get up.
- Thanks.
Do you know her?
Quiet!
Careful over the branch.
Is this dog bite?
- Yes, yes. Dog.
- Ok.
How long?
Many days, many days ago.
Dangerous, doctor?
It looks like a
bacterial infection in here.
Dangerous?
It could be dangerous, yes.
My God.
You need to change
the compress every day, ok?
- Every day.
- I'll give you some.
My God.
Alright.
Thank you.
My wife came back to her parents.
But I couldn't take any chances.
I have to have asylum.
- Here, and sign.
- I give you this, please.
- No, I'm good, thank you.
- Please, please, you take.
Please, please.
It will be good for me
when you take this.
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you for your help.
How are you feeling?
Is the baby okay?
I'll bring you some soup.
And paperwork.
Marta, give me some shoes.
- Smaller ones.
- There aren't any others, just these.
No others?
Okay.
Take them.
- What did she say to me?
- Huh?
What did she say?
Put on.
She said put them on.
Then she won't have shoes for herself.
I won't take them.
You don't have.
No, no... I'm close to my house
and there is a lot of shoes.
She said she lives nearby.
It's ok, take them.
Come on.
Put on.
Thank you.
Yes.
Ghalia...
Do you want chocolate?
You want some, Bashir?
Try to eat, ok?
Tell them, Bashir.
ISIS caught him and flogged him.
Just because he was smoking.
Before sunset, during the month of Ramadan.
I swear to God, look.
Show them what they did to you.
- Enough, Amina.
- Please, Bashir.
Enough!
Don't bring up this topic again.
Why should I show them?
They've been watching our stories
for the past ten years.
Nobody did anything.
Don't bring up this topic again.
That's enough, man, stop recording.
Honestly, I don't know
if I'm still human.
They made me an animal here.
My only sin
is to have the world's worst passport.
ISIS came.
A bad neighbor reported me for
allegedly living with another man.
They push people off roofs
or stone them for that.
My wife and I fled to the mountains.
My wife came back to her parents.
But I couldn't take any chances.
I have to have asylum.
I can't go back there.
They will kill me.
The Belarusians beat us
and shoot at us.
Go Poland, go Poland.
And you have to be careful
with the Poles near the barbed wire.
They treat us like footballs.
We just want to have
a normal life... to live.
I could stay all by myself in Kabul
and wait for the Talibans.
Or I could run away.
I'd like to stay in Poland.
You know, my brother worked
with you Polish people
and praised you so much.
I also want to file a complaint
against border guards.
They don't respect our human rights.
Have you seen any animals in the woods?
Have you seen any animals in the forest?
Yes, I have.
Can you remember
which animals you've seen?
Yes.
Gazelle, antelope, and giraffe.
Are you sure you saw a giraffe?
Giraffe? Are you sure you saw a giraffe?
Yes, I saw a gira...
Yes, I saw a giraffe, with my own eyes.
What's your giraffe with my own eyes?
I saw a giraffe with my own eyes.
I saw it through the eyes of my giraffe.
Ok, everybody, listen to me
for a moment, ok?
Come closer, please.
We want to tell you something important.
I'm now going to tell you
what your current situation is.
We want to tell you about
your situation in Poland.
Poland is the first EU country
you have arrived in.
You have signed powers of attorney
and asylum applications.
Now our attorney will support you.
Maybe the applications
will be accepted, maybe not,
but until they are reviewed,
you can't leave Poland.
And you'll have to stay in
prison-like refugee centers.
The Polish government
doesn't want you here.
It's telling the Polish people
that you are evil.
The border guards have orders to throw you
over the wires back into Belarus.
No, no, Belarus.
The dictator of Belarus cheated you.
He invited you on purpose,
to use you as a weapon
against the European Union.
And now nobody wants
to take responsibility for you here,
neither Belarus nor the EU.
If you apply for asylum,
we'll bring the Border Guard here.
And... even though it's against the law,
they can use pushbacks.
I can't tell you what to decide,
as there are no guarantees.
If you decide to apply
for asylum in Poland,
we'll be forced to call
the Border Guard.
But if you don't want to
apply for asylum, then...
We'll patch you up and leave you here,
as there's nothing more we can do for you.
Because it would be dangerous for us, too.
Please, please.
We want asylum here in Poland.
She has a massive hemorrhage
from the genital tract.
- Let's see the ultrasound, okay?
- Okay.
Sara, stay with me.
Stay with me, stay.
Relax, relax.
Take it easy.
We're with you, sweetheart, I'm here.
My darling, shhh.
The kids are here,
we're all praying for you.
Not all of the placenta is here.
Ok.
Stay with her,
I'll call the ambulance.
- Sorry.
- Yeah, keep calm, ok?
Doctor. Hospital.
She will go to the hospital.
The doctor is calling the ambulance.
What is it?
She has a massive hemorrhage
from the genital tract.
Possible placenta detachment,
we need to call an ambulance.
Ok.
- Guys...
- Everyone, one second, please.
This woman has to go to hospital.
Ambulances are always accompanied
by the Border Guard.
Those who don't want to apply for asylum
have some time now to get
as far away as possible.
Those who don't want to
apply for asylum in Poland
must take their things
and leave right now.
Hello, this is Dr. Paweł Kwieciński.
I have a patient here with...
We want to go to Sweden.
We don't want to stay here.
We don't want to go back to Belarus.
Take the first turn after Brzózki village,
towards the border.
What do you mean, you don't go to illegals?
Can you hear yourself?
Sir, I have examined the patient,
and her condition is unstable.
She needs to be taken to hospital.
Do you understand?
Sir, I'm a doctor.
If you don't come, she will die.
Ok, with the Border Guard...
Where? I can't walk.
My leg is very painful.
Excuse me, my wife is
seven months pregnant.
Her belly hurts.
She fell. The Belarusians beat her.
Can you check if she's ok?
Do you speak English? Yeah?
Can you translate? Ok, thanks.
I want to stay in Poland, you know?
Ok, so we have to wait and we are
waiting with you and your family now.
Mikołaj...
I have no one.
The ultrasound?
- Belarus.
- Belarus, yeah.
What happened there?
Did you have a hit?
- She fell over.
- Ok.
Hello?
Hi, honey.
Hey.
I'm still at work.
With mom?
Well...
just a few more days.
There's the head.
And the heart.
Beating.
- My wife! My wife!
- Hey, it's his wife.
Female, 27 years old,
a massive hemorrhage
from the genital tract.
I'll get the car, I'll be right back.
- That's his wife! Going to hospital!
- Fucking shut up.
What the fuck are you guys doing?!
Careful, there are kids here.
Ghalia!
Nur!
Belarus? Belarus?
- Ghalia!
- I peed my pants.
I peed my pants.
- Nur! Ghalia!
- Mom, Ghalia peed her pants.
Please be careful.
What's wrong with you?
Couldn't you say you wanted to pee?
Where am I going to get you
clean clothes from?
They've signed the papers
for asylum in Poland.
Kaśka?
Fuck!
Can you all shut the fuck up?
Do you have to yell like that
in front of kids?
They don't understand you at all!
Everyone onto the truck. Now!
I want asylum in Poland.
Go inside!
Please step back!
- What are you going to do with them?
- Stand back, please!
They signed the asylum papers.
You can't use pushback against them,
do you understand? There are procedures.
I know the procedures, they're none
of your business. Step aside, please.
All we need is the address
of the facility you're going to.
We'll take them to the
nearest Border Guard station.
- Please step aside.
- What's the address?
- I'm not talking to you, step aside.
- I am the attorney for these people.
You have to talk to me,
I am their attorney.
Please don't obstruct our work,
or I'll be forced to resort to force.
- Everything is being recorded.
- Please step aside.
- Turn off the camera.
- Please stand back.
- I beg you.
- I know who she is.
Address.
I'm under no obligation to provide that.
You can check it yourselves.
- The address.
- The nearest Border Guard station.
End of discussion.
Marta!
Damn, stop the car.
The exclusion zone!
Stop! Can't you see
we can't go any further?
Fuck!
[AREA UNDER A STATE OF EMERGENCY]
Hello, hello, are you there?
Dinner's ready.
We've got a load of
fucking tourists to deliver.
Get the parcel locker ready, ok?
- Over.
- Ok, standing by.
Now focus, this turn is easy to miss.
- I fucking know where to go.
- Just drive.
Why are you so uptight?
Is your wife giving you a hard time?
- What's so funny?
- All right, all right.
Do you know how much guys like us
are getting online right now?
One has already brought me
three dinners on duty.
She was a little fat,
but she had great boobs.
Make the most of it while you can.
Now.
- I know!
- I didn't know if you did.
Of course I fucking know.
The shit we have to do!
There they are.
You just get pissed off all the time.
Stop!
- Ok, ok.
- Stop.
- Go, go, go!
- Come on, go, go.
- Move.
- Move it, move it.
- Move it.
- Faster.
Get the fuck up!
- Faster, faster.
- Come on, fucking grab him.
Come on, move him along.
Go, go, go.
Fucking tell him.
Faster, grab him.
Watch out for those kids.
Go, go, go.
Run, run, run.
Take the brats.
Now, go.
Go, go, go.
Off you go.
Auntie, wait!
Nur!
Quick!
Stop!
Shut that kid up over there.
- To Sweden.
- Wait, wait, wait!
Come on, my dear!
Faster, move it!
Ok, grab her.
Nur! Where is Nur?
My son is on the other side.
I beg you, my son is on the other side.
My son is on the other side. Nur!
Back the fucking truck up!
- Back it up!
- Fucking back it up!
- My son is on the other side.
- Nur, my son! Where are you?
- My little boy!
- Nur!
Quiet!
One - two - three!
Nur! I'm here!
Pull back or we'll open fire!
Fucking Poles!
We'll start shooting!
Come on, let's go.
Get the fuck away, Poles!
Shoot them!
It's over there!
And this one?
Some jerk from the
Territorial Defense Force...
Come on! You want it
to blow up in your face?
So your father-in-law doesn't know
you're desecrating his sacred spring...?
My father-in-law and I are pals.
And him?
He's a Russkie.
- Is he?
- Let me see.
He's short. You want to have
dwarf kids with ginger hair?
Here, might as well throw the phone
out of the window.
Oh, what are you guys up to?
Nothing.
We had an arm wrestle... and he lost!
Screw you.
- You better get me a beer.
- Let's have a rematch.
- ...with a girl and she was pregnant.
- Now they are all pregnant.
Excuse me, excuse me.
Guys, over here.
The match of the night!
Pour it.
Don't you fucking dare lose.
Ready?
Three, two, one, go!
Go, go!
- Janek, Janek, Janek!
- Ola, Ola, Ola!
Jan?
Hey.
What is going on?
Nothing.
You never drink like that.
Everyone drinks nowadays.
The female guards too? Ola?
- Kaśka, go to sleep.
- Then tell me why.
Believe me, you wouldn't want to know.
Nur! My son!
Zero zero fifty-four.
You know how I recognized you?
By the patch on the jacket,
I ironed it on myself.
Here.
What the fuck do you think
we're doing out there, huh?
Knitting?
Jan, you don't have to do this.
After all, Wojtek earns
five grand at the supermarket.
It's my duty.
I'm sorry.
Come on.
Come to me.
Maybe Laura?
Lewandowski's second daughter
is called Laura.
Ok.
Hey, honey, what's up?
Baśka, look!
I see, a moose, a real moose.
I've never seen a live one before.
And you've been living here for six months!
Ok, don't worry. I was the same
when we moved here in the '90s.
Sorry, Baśka, it's the police.
I have to go.
- Good morning, I just...
- ID, please.
- But I live nearby, I'm going to Rysiówka...
- ID.
...what's going on in the exclusion zone.
Dramatic news has reached us...
I'm going to the pharmacy!
As initiative coordinator Jakub Sieczko
said on TokFM,
the crisis needs a systemic solution.
We need several ambulances...
- Please turn around.
- What's going on?
I told you to turn around.
Shouldn't you identify yourself first?
Please show your ID...
You have a fine of 200 zlotys.
Sign it, please.
A few days ago, three adults
were found near the border,
accompanied by children,
wandering about the forests...
What a bitch!
They came to share their know-how
and skills with those...
in the greatest need of help.
It's just one kilometer
from the exclusion zone.
Ten minutes on foot.
We know these people
are suffering and dying.
Fiona, Lapi, I'm back!
Yes, come here!
First, Anka got upset that I didn't clean
the air conditioning in the car.
And you had said you would?
Yeah but...
is it really so important now?
It's autumn,
and we don't use it now anyway!
Never mind.
Something made me turn on the TV and...
fuck me!
Have you heard?
I don't watch TV, I only use
the internet for running sessions.
I only know what I need to know.
[Mom]
What you need to know is that our state
has taken patronage of a Nazi rally.
You understand?
A fucking fascist march in the capital,
in Warsaw,
under the patronage
of the fucking government!
Providing therapy for the nation
is beyond me.
We shouldn't address issues
beyond our control.
- For fuck's sake!
- Let's talk about your problems.
That's just it, they are my problems.
We have racist fuckers
in the government.
I can't eat, I can't sleep, I can't think.
My libido is below zero.
Ask Anka.
- Bogdan.
- I'm fucking sick of it all.
When I see that crooked
little shit's mouth,
a guy who can't even put words
together in any human language.
Where the fuck do they get them from?
Do they breed them?
- Bogdan!
- Fuck me! What?
What did you take?
Bogdan?
Braxen... one pill.
It's a breach of abstinence,
and you know the consequences.
If you have any benzodiazepines
at home, get rid of them immediately.
I'm suspending you from the group
until we've worked through what happened.
We have to finish now.
4pm tomorrow, is that ok for you?
Fuck!
Hi, Mom!
I was just about to call...
I couldn't say that because
I have a patient at six...
Lapi, Fiona...
Nothing's going on, don't worry.
You remember about that
medical examination tomorrow?
No, I can't call back later.
I want to go to bed early.
I'll call you tomorrow night.
Okay, bye.
Sleep well.
Help!
Lapi, Fiona...
Back inside.
Help!
Hello?
Hey?
Help!
I'm here.
I'm coming.
Help!
I'll call for help.
I'm calling for help.
Hello? We need help,
people are drowning in a swamp...
Yes, right now, I'm here...
can you trace me?
The forest by the road to Bednarka.
Yes, now!
No!
And?
The firefighters fished out the body.
I'm sorry.
You'll feel a slight scratch.
You should stay in for observation
until tomorrow.
No, I have to get back to my dogs.
- And does she know?
- Yes.
Can I see her?
Yes.
To the left.
She is extremely hypothermic,
exhausted and dehydrated...
That's all, I'm finished.
Thank you.
We'll be on our way.
They're friends from a
humanitarian organization.
They brought you both dry clothes.
They'll take you home.
The pigs are standing by...
Let them stand there,
better here than at the border.
You have to sign here, okay?
Thank you very much.
They found it in the boy's pocket...
Nur...
Bashir, Amina... I tried.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry.
I know you won't forgive me.
My phone didn't work.
I was calling out.
I was calling for help.
I don't know why it's me who is alive.
Nur...
was unconscious
when he drowned in front of my eyes.
He didn't suffer.
He was so beautiful, a sweet boy.
I'm so sorry.
I hope you will forgive me, please.
Forgive me.
I'm so sorry.
What now?
We've got the signed powers of attorney,
we'll get the interim relief tomorrow.
What's that?
The European Court
of Human Rights prohibits
Poland from expelling foreigners
for a certain period of time.
That should keep her from being deported.
The pigs still respect it, for now...
- Fuck me...
- Hey, can you not make such a mess?
Are you from that "Border" group?
I'm Marta, group coordinator.
Julia.
Maciek.
Żuku is a bit eccentric,
she takes after dad.
But she knows her stuff.
Fuck off, Marta.
Hiya.
- Sisters?
- Yeah, I can't believe it either.
Yes, Marta.
And the next right, thank you very much.
Turn around.
- She'll die.
- Hey!
Do you hear?
She'll die in that forest!
- Move, I said.
- I need my glasses!
Please step back.
This is the doctor's discharge form.
Step aside!
- Give her the coat.
- Step back, I said.
Give her the coat.
Please step back.
Get in.
- Julia! Move it!
- Get in!
Get in, come on.
Hold this.
Shut the door!
Go, go, go.
Fuck!
You think that'll scare them?
- At least I'm fucking trying.
- Calm down!
- Drive around it.
- How?
Fiona, relax.
You can't let them get away with it.
You have to shout about it.
Where are the politicians?
And what about the EU?
You think that's funny?
Don't worry, Żuku is sometimes...
Do you know how many people have died in
the Mediterranean trying to get to Europe?
Since the beginning
of the crisis in 2015? Well?
- I don't know exactly, but...
- More than 20,000!
You probably haven't heard about the boats
being turned back, the Frontex actions...
So yeah, I laugh when someone bullshits me
about the sacred EU...
I'm sorry.
- What?
- No, wait.
Fiona, Lapi, come on!
Bravo.
Wait.
You're right, that's how it is.
I'm sorry.
Look, I want to help, too.
I'm sure I'll be useful,
I can do anything...
I'm in pretty good shape.
Go on, you're doing fine.
I'm a psychologist!
A shrink!
Anyway, I have the tools
to help people in a crisis
and I know first-aid.
- Do you have a driver's license?
- Yes, and a car.
And look, quite a lot of free space.
It's much closer to the border here
than your base in the town.
You wouldn't be so conspicuous.
There are two rooms upstairs,
with three beds.
The whole house is at your disposal...
except for my bedroom!
If you have to, please smoke outside.
Look...
It works just like Messenger.
This is Honza, our homie in Czechia.
He helped us once, and his number
has been circulating online ever since.
Now lots of people
crossing the border know him.
If they need help,
they send a pin to Honza
with their location and what they need,
and Honza sends it to us. Got it?
Alright...
now the most important thing.
If you want to work with us,
you have to accept the rules:
we give food, water, medicines,
clothes, powerbanks, phones.
We don't give lifts or guide anyone.
And we don't enter
the exclusion zone, ok?
We can't give the pigs any excuse,
or they'll hit the whole organization
and those people won't get help anymore.
You understand?
Get the boxes.
So funny.
- Tea?
- No, thanks.
God!
My son!
Nur, my sweetheart.
Nur!
She said he didn't...
suffer...
He was unconscious,
he didn't feel any pain...
You said the way would be.
quick and easy. You said!
God predetermined it, and did his will.
Pray for him, pray for his soul.
I killed my own son, I killed him.
Amina, Amina.
- I killed him.
- Amina, calm down.
Calm down, Amina, you'll scare the kids.
Come here, my darling.
Take care of the mobile, ok?
Without the mobile, you won't get here.
As soon as you get into Poland
and cross the exclusion zone,
send me your location right away.
There'll be a man waiting for you.
- Then wait for a signal from me, ok?
- Ok.
May God be with you.
Go, go, go.
The first one has already gone!
Run! Run! Don't stop!
No stopping!
Move it, bitch!
You're all moving like
it's your grandma's funeral.
Come on, come on.
Move it.
Faster!
Hey, move it, don't you understand?
Move it, go on!
No!
Go on!
Dad! Dad!
Dad!
- Dad!
- I'm not going!
- Come on! Dad!
- Grandpa!
- Come on, Dad!
Hello?
Anybody here?
THANK YOU, SORRY FOR
THE TOILET. BABY IS SICK.
Fuck!
I'm fucking sick of all this patrolling.
Hold on.
- What are you doing?
- I got something good.
Local quince liquor.
To warm us up, here.
How do I know
you're not the commander's snitch?
What the fuck are you on about?
- Here.
- I don't want it.
Ok, give me your phone.
- Why?
- Just give me your phone.
Here you go.
Alright now?
Hello?
Is everything ok?
Polish, English?
Are you ok?
Fuck.
Eternal rest grant unto her, O Lord.
We have to toss the body over.
It's not far away.
Oh shit.
Hey, man, let's leave her.
Look, I didn't see anything,
and neither did you. Come on.
What the fuck are you on about?
The Russkies threw her over to us.
They're us, and we're them.
No fucking way.
Holy shit!
Leave it, leave it.
Check for Belarusians.
And turn off your flashlight.
Hey, Russkies, Russkies.
Hey, Poles!
Holy shit!
Tension on the border
with Belarus is rising.
Aggressive assaults are on the rise,
along with physical attacks on
Polish soldiers and officers.
A group of about 100 people tried
to cross the state border by force.
They behaved aggressively,
throwing stones
and tree branches at the officers
on duty...
Polish soldiers, police
and Border Guard officers
continue to firmly and professionally
thwart further attacks,
refusing to submit to provocation,
for which they were thanked in person
by President Andrzej Duda,
who visited the soldiers and
officers monitoring our security...
- Just in time for soup.
- Pour it into the thermoses.
Because I just got a pin.
- Maciek, clothes.
- Wet stuff straight to the bathroom.
Maciek, can you sort it out?
- Later, ok?
- What do you have there?
Let me see.
How many people?
Four men.
One sick, something wrong with his leg.
Painkillers, anti-inflammatory pills,
dressings...
- Kids?
- No.
Shoes.
- What size?
- 41 and 44.
And dry clothes for everyone.
Julia, about that Afghan woman...
Leila? We still have no news.
No one's seen her, and she's not responding
to our messages. She's disappeared.
But we're in touch with
her brother in the US,
so maybe that will help,
I don't know.
Thanks.
Shit, not good.
They're inside the zone,
they'll have to move.
See?
- Fuck, it's only a few hundred yards.
- It'll be easier for them to get through.
Fucking hell, are you stalling on purpose?
We have no time. If they move,
we'll be looking for
them all night...
Spare us your words of wisdom, ok?
They don't help.
I'll wait in the car.
Watch where you step.
Yeah...
- Watch your step.
- Ok, come on.
It's here.
Shit, we're late.
I can't walk.
The taxi is there.
My friends left me.
Please, I don't want to die.
It's ok, it's ok.
He's all wet, he needs to get changed.
It's ok, I'm gonna help you.
- It's ok, it's ok.
- I don't want to die.
- They left me.
- You won't die.
I don't think it's broken,
more like sprained.
Look at me, what's your name?
- My name... Ahmad.
- My name is Julia.
- Everything will be ok.
- Don't let me die, please.
His details for the interim order.
Do you have a passport?
Where is it? In your pocket?
It's ok.
Please let me call.
Please. Please.
- Please let me call.
- No.
No.
Thank you.
Let me put the jacket on, ok?
Where are you from?
Morocco.
How old are you?
- 25.
- Are you here with anyone?
- They left me.
You mean your friends or family?
You have to be silent, please. Okay?
I think it's for you.
Sabih?
This is Ahmad.
Thank God, thank God.
Listen...
Those people came to help, they're here.
Where are you?
Send me your location, please.
Sabih, don't leave without me, please.
Ok, ok.
I have to hang up now.
Send me your location, Sabih.
Thank you.
Look, they are not far.
Just one hour.
The taxi will come, please.
Please, I have money, I can pay you.
- I have money.
- No one wants your money.
Please take me there.
Don't leave me here.
- No one will leave you, ok?
- Julia...
- For sure we will...
- Julia!
We will do whatever we can, ok?
Give us a moment.
Look, you can't promise him
things like that.
- It's only a few miles.
- You can't.
They're bound to find us here.
We'll have to go around.
It's only a few minutes by car.
And how do you plan
to get him to the car, huh?
If they saw us, we're fucked.
Fuck.
- Ok, stay with him, and I'll drive closer.
- Are you crazy?
Have you seen how many patrols there are?
- They'll throw him over the wire.
- Ok, listen up.
Let's try to move him,
it might work.
Have you ever carried someone
without a stretcher? Because I have.
We barely got here on our own...
- What if we take him on a sleeping bag?
- No.
We have his details for interim relief,
we can come back in the morning.
- But it's freezing at night.
- You know the rules, you agreed!
If we go to jail,
we can't help anyone, right?
- Go to jail? For what?
- Violating state of emergency rules.
Even just entering the exclusion zone.
We can't give them any excuse...
those are the rules.
You think they need an excuse?
- Ziobro will snap his fingers and...
- We have to leave him here, end of discussion!
Then you go and tell him.
Go on.
Right then.
There's your passport.
We have to leave you now, but...
Thank you, ok.
Ok, thank you.
Give me a sleeping bag.
And a roll mat.
Thank you.
The roll mat.
Julia!
Where are you going?
Let me go!
Fuck!
Go!
Ahmad?
Ahmad...
Hi, Mom, everything's all right.
Do you have a date for the second dose?
Mom, I have to go now.
Don't get upset, I'll call you back.
- Police, get out of the car!
- Yes? But what are you doing?
Hand!
The other one.
Your other hand.
- You entered the exclusion zone.
- I don't think so.
If you admit to it, the prosecutor
will drop the sanctions...
Are you kidding? What sanctions?
Even if I entered the zone,
it's only a misdemeanor.
Then how about assisting
with people trafficking?
Article 264 of the Criminal Code,
with up to eight years in prison.
I want to make a phone call,
it's my right.
Spread your legs.
I have to call my seriously ill mother.
She won't answer a strange number.
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
Hello, Mom, I'm sorry.
I was out of range...
For a walk...
Yes, at night.
Mom, honestly, I'm tired
of checking in every night!
Just tell me,
did you go for those tests?
How am I supposed to take care of myself
when you don't do the same for yourself?
Time to wrap it up.
Yes, you heard right,
it was a man's voice!
Mom, Szymon's been dead for over a year!
I have the right to my own life!
That's enough.
I'll call you back, ok? Bye.
Now you've done it.
I'm a shrink, a psychologist,
and I need to protect my patients' data.
Iza!
Come and do the full body...
Take your clothes off.
Strip.
- You must be joking!
- Quickly!
Come on, quickly!
Our commander is on leave.
That son of a bitch has got
under everyone's skin here.
- And no one revolts?
- You know, it is what it is.
Over there.
I can notify your foundation's lawyer
that you are here.
- I don't know the number.
- It's ok.
Thank you.
We will file a complaint
against your detention.
Thank you.
- Sign here, please.
- Here?
- Goodbye.
I'd change your phone, just in case.
And the sim card.
Fuck!
[FUCK OFF!]
I'll get a tow truck for you.
No, thank you, I don't have the strength.
I'll take care of it later.
He's a good friend of mine.
I'm sure he won't charge you anything.
- I'll send you his number.
- Thank you.
- Could you give me a ride home now?
- Sure.
Yes, here I am.
Come on, Fiona, come here.
Everything's ok.
Żuku, can you not fucking smoke
in here? It's too much.
Ok, sorry.
- Whose car is that?
- Mine. I mean, partly mine.
A few of us bought it together.
Come on, come here.
I already gave them some.
Oh, thanks.
So they can get a second helping, ok?
I thought they'd locked you up.
They did.
...border guards supported
by Polish soldiers...
Thought so...
...police officers...
Marta and Maciek have gone back
to the old base.
I see.
You know I have to apologize again?
- You don't, just smoke outside...
- Not about the cigarettes.
I thought you were just
a common, petty liberal,
looking to boost your self-esteem...
I was wrong, respect!
I have good self-esteem.
Apart from that, I agree with you.
They are supported by troops from the
18th Mechanized Division.
The soldiers carry out their difficult
service on a daily basis...
Indeed, as the President says,
it is demanding work.
Bastards!
I take it that since you stayed,
we'll do it together, our way?
Sure.
Great.
I'll never leave anyone
in the woods again!
Wait, wait!
Fuck, Żuku, how many times have I said
that no one should sleep in my bedroom?
What's wrong with you people?
This is Sasha...
And that's Ula.
Julia. Look, nobody sleeps in my bed,
or eats out of my bowl, ok?
I invited them because
we'll need support...
Alright.
You have two bedrooms upstairs!
We have to use two cars.
One in front, as the lookout,
to spot the checkpoints.
I saw that some guy gave you a ride.
What happened to your car?
I don't have a car for the time being.
Ok.
And we can't bring them here.
- You know they're keeping an eye on you?
- I know.
They'll track us.
Handsome.
- He died of Covid.
- Fuck, sorry.
It's alright.
- Hello?
- Hi, Baśka.
Geez, I thought it was Szymon calling.
Listen, could you lend me your SUV?
My car's off the road...
- I can.
- As soon as possible would be best.
- Could you come now?
- I'm on my way.
Thank you so much. Thanks.
Sorry, give me a moment, will you?
I have to speak to a patient.
Sure.
You can go upstairs.
Thanks.
Hi.
Hi Bogdan, how's it going?
Do we have a session today?
No, the day after tomorrow at 4pm.
It will be free. Interested?
Well, at your rates, of course.
I'm glad you appreciate the gesture.
I have some business, we need to meet.
And by the way, how is your outrage
at our reactionary regime?
You've got half a tank of gas.
It's an automatic,
but that shouldn't be a problem.
- Thank you.
- You always did drive like a lunatic.
It's good that you're ok.
I said my car's off the road,
it doesn't mean I had an accident.
- Oh hi! Julia, we got a pin.
- Get ready, I'm coming.
What is really going on?
We want to take people out of the woods
and put them up somewhere in the area...
What?
- You mean migrants?
- Refugees.
They need to get themselves together,
somewhere safe.
- Do you have any AAA batteries?
- Bottom drawer of the desk.
Holy crap, what a cool car!
And local plates!
We can take it to the forest
and use the Opel as the lookout!
Let me have a minute to talk, ok?
I'll show you something.
No, I'm sorry, I can't watch things like that...
It just gets to me and...
This is the woman I dragged out
of the swamp...
Julka, my dear, you know me...
I always voted for Civic Platform.
I stood outside the courts with a candle
when it was necessary,
but this...
I have to make a living, work,
you know?
Everyone has to.
That's easy for you to say,
you have no family.
Yes, my husband died.
I'm sorry.
I have a mother, and my dogs.
Baśka...
Will you lend me the car or not?
What if they catch you and tie it to me?
Helping is not illegal!
What world do you live in!
I'm sorry, but I can't.
No.
And don't ask me for such
things again! Understand?
I don't understand, but I heard you.
Bye-bye.
So much for the SUV.
All right, let's go.
It's good they're close to the road.
Damn.
My car is really close.
It makes no sense to me.
It just sucks, it's a disaster.
When I used to drive,
they never wanted a ride.
- Because we didn't ask.
- What do you mean?
- Those Kurds said they already had a taxi.
- Did you ask everyone?
This is no time for squabbling.
We have to consider every option.
We can put them in the back
and cover them with blankets.
I'll take them away
and come back for you...
- Or not.
- Ok... I'll drive, it's my Opel!
- It's a Toyota!
- I think I know what I drive.
- So what do you think you drive?
- An Opel.
What model?
Opel Toyota.
But the car is registered to me!
- I did my part, didn't I?
- Calm down, now!
I'll drive.
I'm the oldest and, with all due respect,
the only one
who doesn't look like an anarchist.
- The old lady will drive.
- That's right.
Well, I've managed to lose the police
in a chase a few times.
Really?
Geez...
Fuck!
- What the fuck?
- What are you doing?
That was a portal.
Pull over!
And keep calm.
Stay calm.
Where are you all heading?
We're out of the exclusion zone.
Can't we go where we like?
You could at least say
you're going to the store.
Ok, we're going to the store.
Is that better, sir?
Yes.
And the lady next to you,
with the dark face...
Does she speak Polish?
She does.
Then why doesn't she say something?
Our Father, who art in heaven,
hallowed be thy name
Thy kingdom come,
Thy will be done,
on Earth as it is in Heaven...
Ok, on your way.
Give us this day our daily bread
And forgive us our trespasses...
as we forgive those
that trespass against us.
And lead us not...
- Fuck off, I said!
- We are.
Sons of bitches!
Hello?
Yes, thank you for calling me back.
I'm a friend of attorney Jankowski.
Yes, it's about picking up a broken-down
car and taking it to the workshop.
It's on a side road,
I'll send you a pin. Hello?
That's great, thank you very much.
Thank you.
35.2 degrees.
Here.
Super, ok.
There are dry shoes
in the backpack.
- Get the tea.
- Here.
- There's soup too.
- In a moment, tea first. He is weak.
Here.
It's ok.
Just a second, then we can pick him up.
Ok, now...
One, two, three.
Perfect.
You can give us that soup now.
Oh, great.
Soup?
Very good.
- It's 11pm. What do we do?
- We stick to the plan.
I'm staying till morning.
- Don't go.
- Keep calm.
Take my backpack, leave me
the sleeping bag and a powerbank.
Let's get going.
Flashlights.
This is me.
And this is my little brother.
- I miss him.
- Very beautiful.
Thanks, I hope they'll come.
Hey, look! Record it!
Fuck!
- Say goodbye to the little girl.
- Goodbye, little girl.
Let's go.
Give me a piece.
Don't eat it all.
Mama! Mama!
Mama!
[The taxi will be here!]
We should get going. Let's go.
We should get going.
Give it to me, Ghalia.
Ghalia...
No need to be upset.
You can buy the headlamps and
windows at a salvage yard.
It's just the paintwork,
and that'll be covered by insurance.
So you'll still come out ahead.
Please get in the front, madam.
We're just about to set off.
Take care, please.
Hold tight.
Let's get the fuck out of here!
Show me your hands,
show me your hands.
Get out.
Alright!
Gently, I'm a lady.
Ula, Ula, Ula!
Good morning.
- How did it go?
- Hi.
- Alright?
Boys, come on.
Right here. Inside.
- Hello.
- You too?
Come on, come here.
- Franek, thank you very much.
- Where should I drop your car?
Could you take it to the workshop?
Sure, but it'll be 200 zlotys then.
I can't do too much for free.
What are you doing? I was kidding...
Quick, get in... let's go.
See you online on Wednesday.
Thank you!
You know, Julia, my wife and I
have been thinking. Whatever you need...
I'd always be happy to...
I can give lifts, pick people up...
You know what I mean?
Aren't you afraid they might
shut your company down?
No... I get on very well with the guards.
I went to school with the chief.
And the police? With all the patrol cars
I've hauled out of ditches?
You'll sleep here.
These are your beds.
Here are towels and some clothes.
The bathroom is through there...
And the laundry basket.
I wrote down the wi-fi password.
And the network name.
You have Canal Plus.
So, if you want to watch something,
feel free.
Thank you.
Can... can the military find us here?
Mom doesn't speak French.
But you are safe here, I swear.
- I'm going, see you upstairs.
- Ok, thanks.
What a room!
Great room.
Really cool.
Guys, I think this is going to be my bed.
- What are you doing?
- Lying down.
- But I'm the tallest. What are you doing?
- A room at last, our own room.
The bath is super nice,
good temperature. Perfect.
I am so good.
- I am so good in here.
- We were smelly.
- What did you say?
We were smelly!
- What?
- We were smelly!
Give me the baby.
Don't be scared.
Help me with the other one.
It's heavy.
Move in, move in.
Go, go.
The supervisor is screwing me over,
giving that bitch all the night shifts.
You don't have anything to do at night?
I prefer daytime patrols,
at least the sun is shining.
Alright, let's go.
- Papers, please
- I knew you'd stop me.
Papers.
Here.
Log book.
And this is... for the goods.
My two loves.
Check him.
I know how I must look...
I don't fucking believe him,
but the papers are in order.
Let him go, or he'll drop dead
from a heart attack.
Clear.
On your way.
Thank you very much.
Want some?
- Mom, will you pour him some?
- Sure.
Excuse me... I...
Miss...
We are Muslims.
I know, Mom prepared chicken because...
she thought it would be ok.
Is the chicken ok?
- Yes, it's delicious.
- You didn't even taste it yet.
- Miss, it's halal.
- Stop calling me miss.
If you continue, I'll call you Mister Alan.
- That would be a bit weird, no?
- Yeah, don't...
- See, so stop it.
- I'll try.
- What's up?
- Nothing, everything is fine.
Mom, help yourself to something.
It looks weird,
like you poisoned the food.
- Would you like more?
- No, thank you.
Give them more, they need to eat well.
Serve him some rice and salad.
Don't give him more,
he can't eat any more now.
He hasn't eaten anything
for a couple of weeks, so...
- He'd get sick, I read about it.
- So maybe...
- Mom, why do you force people to eat?
- Calm down, sweetie, hey
Just offer more.
- Can you stop?
- Ok.
Everything good?
- Good.
- Ok.
Cheers!
Na zdrowie!
- Salut!
- Super weird, Dad.
You know Papa Wemba?
Koffee?
No, but Papaoutai. Stromae?
- Stromae.
- Stromae is well-known.
It's old but we used to listen to it.
Wojtek makes music, but Polish.
Oh really? You rap?
Will you do it?
- Go on.
- Sure, if you want.
I'll beatbox and you go, ok?
- Now?
- Sure, now.
- You're good?
- Yeah, ok.
Three, two, one...
Yo, check it out
One, two, three -
everyone did time in the woods
But don't worry about them,
they're safe now
White and black, like yin and yang,
that's our new gang
Us and the beatbox, us and the hip hop
Wow!
- It's phat.
- He's really not bad.
He's phat! You know how to do that?
We know how. Let's play together.
Guys, do you know "Dying a Thousand Times"?
- Of course.
- It's really good.
It's on my playlist.
- I don't know it.
- Stop it!
Everybody knows it.
"Dying a Thousand Times"
It sounds familiar,
but I don't know the words.
"I fold when you fold,
I cry when you cry"
"I pray when you pray,
your grief is my grief"
"I vibrate when you live,
a heart for a heart"
"As I shine when you shine,
so I die when you die"
"Between the stage and the mosque,
I carry a lot of remorse"
"I lead a double life,
would I have a double death?"
"People only believe in
what they can see"
"I lost so many people,
I feel like I'm dying a thousand times"
"Dying a thousand times"
"Let me believe that
'Goodbye' will never separate us"
"Dying a thousand times"
"And we go again,
without time fixing us"
"Dying a thousand times"
Excuse me?
Everything will be fine.
Easy!
It's going to be ok, Maria!
I can't cross, I have to stay.
Go! Hurry up!
Everything will be fine!
Hold on a second! Take care!
- Are you crossing?
- No, I'm staying!
Why are you crying, auntie?
God! Help us, God!
We have no home, my dear!
What should I do? I don't know what to do.
What is it?
- To Warsaw.
- To Warsaw? This way.
Come on, I'll show you.
Don't worry.
As soon as we get to Warsaw,
we'll let you know.
- We crossed without any problems.
- Katowice? That way.
Katowice.
Come forward, please.
I've got a little kid, excuse me.
Hop on.
Next, please.
Everything will be fine.
Too bad you weren't such a caring dad
to those kids on
the Belarusian border, you dick!
I was never there.
On you get, please.
Where are you going, madam?
Sorry, my bird's freezing.
It can't bear the cold.
- You're going to Warsaw?
- Yes.
Ok, get on.
Katowice?
That way, over there.
- There you go. Warsaw!
- Warsaw?