The dream...
always ends there.
BOX
You still don't trust me, do you?
The box is too small...
I can't breathe.
I finished it.
Thank you very much
I'll go to the office and read it over.
Your handwriting is almost
as neat as typing.
I don't mean it should be typed, either.
I have to write by hand.
I can't type...
You're left-handed, aren't you?
I've read so many manuscripts
I can tell
I'll be in touch then...
One thing...
I mean...
Your novels are doing very well.
Here, a small token.
Sis'?
Sister, dear?
It's you, isn't it?
It's me.
Kyoko...
Say something.
Sister!
It's hot... I'm burning...
It wasn't what you think!
It really wasn't!
It wasn't!
Shoko...
you did well today.
A little reward.
Keep up the good work.
Kyoko, keep trying!
You'll be rewarded too.
Sensei.
I was looking...
looking for someone.
Someone?
Who is it?
Can't I be him?
At least...
I'm here for you.
You do look like him.
Bear it for one night.
I want to be you...
to sleep like you
to have nice dreams.
What's going on?
Shoko, don't worry.
Shoko...
Sister...
I'm sorry.
I didn't do it out of hatred.
It wasn't the necklace, either.
I loved you so much, sis'
I looked for you everywhere.
It's true.
I loved you more than anyone in the world.
More than anyone.
Help me...
So beautiful.
I can't decide...
which one of you is more beautiful...
Shoko back then or you right now?
Oh, Kyoko...
Why did you do it?
Don't...
You thought I only loved your sister?
Poor thing...
The heat was unbearable...
Don't!
She couldn't get out...
- She's trapped...
- Don't!
In that tiny box!
Look.
Look!
If you hadn't done it, she'd be here now!
I'm sorry... I'm sorry
I'm so sorry...
I saved one for you too.
Can't have one without the other.
Shoko and Kyoko...
Together, a perfect pair.
You're one and the same to me.
The dream...
always ends just there.
Good morning.
In reality...
we've been together since birth.
I had a weird dream.
Me too.
But then...
our dreams...
differ slightly.
Mrs. Li? You're so beautiful.
They say your dumplings
are the most expensive.
Of course! Please come in.
You've come in the right time!
The water is just boiling, waiting for you.
Actually, I know who you are
I watched you on TV very often
when I first came to Hong Kong.
You were the best!
I quit acting a long time ago.
Please, have a seat.
Mrs. Li, guess how old I am.
I suppose...
you're in your thirties at most
I'm much older than that;
everyone calls me Aunt Mei.
But you don't have any wrinkles.
And I have fair skin, too
I'm my own best advertisement.
Your skin is great; I'm impressed.
My dumplings are worth it.
You get what you pay for.
Mrs. Li...
Want me to put in more cabbage?
It's up to you.
The Northerners always say...
"Good feeling comes from a nap,
good taste comes from a dumpling."
Dumplings have existed in China
for more than 1400 years.
But the Southerners still say...
they're just dough stuffed
with meat, nothing special!
I use high-gluten flour...
for texture and chewiness
I knead it fine...
until it is like a peeled egg.
Smooth, translucent, and soft.
There's a secret to keep the
filling from leaking out.
So that the juicy flavor
explodes in the mouth.
Eat while it's warm
I eat these often.
Sometimes in soup...
sometimes minced and steamed
with citrus peel.
Just think of the results, not what it was.
For women to rejuvenate...
you must start from the inside
for the best result.
Only my secret formula can do this.
Let me sing for you.
Well, it's kind of a custom of mine
I often sing songs from my youth
after my customers eat.
Take it as an entertainment; listen:
"The water of Hung Lake is rough."
"My home is on the shore."
"At dawn, boats go out with nets."
"At dusk, they return loaded with fish."
"Wild ducks and lotus roots are here."
"Autumns are bountiful with rice."
"They say heaven is beautiful."
"How can it compare with Hung Lake."
You were already on a trip last week.
You promised to stay for
our 15th anniversary
I'm just going for a few days
I'll try to come back early.
It's boring here in the hotel.
We'll move into our new home as
soon as the renovation is over.
See if there's anything else
we need in the new house.
So many "zeroes"?
You used to laugh a lot.
Now even a big fat check
can't make you happy.
You're not taking me along.
Why should I be happy?
I'll be gone for only 4, 5 days.
And if more?
I'll write you another check as a fine.
Fines are for mistakes.
Whatever.
About that contract,
if you don't send over soon...
I'm going to change my mind.
Shenzhen, China.
I went through so much to get these.
- They're stepping up the surveillance.
- Because some paparazzi have come
Hong Kong media is so nosy.
Just don't show up in the next two weeks.
Even the locals can't get
a hold of the stock now.
We'll see.
- Thanks -This is for you
China-Hong Kong Border.
This way, miss.
- Put it through - Over there?
- The lunchbox - Okay.
Mrs. Li.
Ever consider having children?
We just can't; don't know if
it's his problem or mine...
Don't worry, you'll soon
regain your youth...
so as the heart of your man.
Do you have more potent stuff
for faster results?
The best are those in the 5th or 6th month.
Have to remove it only by breaking
the water sac, then sliding it out.
It's covered by a layer of creamy fat.
The colors are defined;
you can even see the cranium.
Its tiny limbs would still be moving around.
It's only this small in the 1st trimester.
But the meat would be too tough
by the third trimester.
The 5th month ones are perfect, kitten-like.
So cute and so nutritious.
Let me show you
I'm serving it pan-fried this time.
We can always try some
other styles next time.
What's this crunchiness about?
It's okay, they have hands
and feet already, you know.
And ears, too!
Those were bones?
Nah... their bones are hardly hard
I'll just chop finer next time.
Simmer in broth next
time; taste less greasy.
Broth is good; it keeps all the juices.
Are you done?
This can't go on.
Pardon?
My skin is still flabby.
No! It's much better!
I need your most potent stuff.
Trust me, I'll find it.
It's time for me to sing.
Suit yourself, but I must go.
Bye, Mrs. Li.
This way!
Don't worry, I'll find it for you.
Call me when you do.
Trust me.
Aunt Mei?
You are...
I'm a friend of Mrs. Kam.
Oh, hello dear, c'mon in!
From now on, you don't have to work anymore.
And live off you?
I can afford that, given you're
so slim and eat so little.
- Not true; I love to eat.
- And you love to laugh, too.
Relax.
You're almost there; it's
been 18 hours already.
Relax.
You must try to relax, dear.
Will she be all right?
Of course.
Try to relax.
Your cervix has not fully dilated yet.
Poor girl, you're not even fully grown.
We women must protect ourselves.
Don't let others bully you again.
The water broke!
It's okay.
Don't be nervous.
I swear it will be over in 10 seconds.
Breathe deeply!
Work with me, okay? Relax.
Hold on...
Relax...
Cry if you want to.
It's fully dilated!
Stay calm! And on my count...
One, two, three!
Where are my tongs?
Relax!
Try to relax.
Beautiful.
Don't be sad, my dear.
There's no more life in this baby.
Want some snacks?
I'll do steamed dumplings this time.
Need some wine, too.
It was a boy.
A boy?
See that little thing?
So beautiful and rare.
Boys don't get aborted in China
I didn't use any oxytocin, just a catheter.
Drugs make it inedible.
It will damage your nervous system.
It's a first-born, the most nutritious.
Nothing in this world
can beat this nutrition.
The mother's a schoolgirl.
Young and healthy.
Then get working!
What's the style today?
This will make you feel like new.
Hello?
My husband broke his leg.
Now you need me.
Normally you wouldn't care where I go.
You smell nice...
look nice.
You haven't touched me in ages.
Thirsty? I'll get water.
It's so hot in the street.
And we must go to Mongkok next.
Darn! I forgot about that.
Two more trunks to move.
- Woe is me -Big trunks, too.
What's wrong?
- What is this?
- What is it?
- It's blood -My goodness!
Here's a tissue.
Whose blood is this?!
Kate? Are you all right?
Kate... What's going on?!
Answer me, Kate! Answer me!
Kate? Are you all right? What's going on?!
Something is going on here.
- She must have taken something.
- Definitely.
Mrs. Li.
You look fabulous! Absolutely radiant!
- Talking behind my back?
- No!
Just praising your look
I'll catch up later.
You're so late...
Perhaps she finds herself a guru.
Or better, "voodoo".
That's scary!
Mrs. Li, stop busying yourself, join us.
- Bon appetite -Thanks.
The food smells kind of fishy.
Yes.
Is it the beef?
The beef?
It's the fish, I think.
Really?
I don't think so.
There is a strange smell here.
Something wrong with the food?
God, the smell is horrible
I've forgot to check something! Excuse me.
Why is she so tense?
Aunt Mei?
What was this "best stuff"?
What did you feed me?
The fetus was sick, wasn't it?
Or, poisonous?
This baby was hard to find.
Available only because his father
is also his grandfather.
One in a million, you know.
A child of an incest?
A cursed child turns me to this?!
A cursed child has extra
potency, I tell you.
Hey! Mrs. Li, Hurry!
Turn on the TV! Channel 2
is rerunning your series!
"Heard you have a crush on
the baby face next door."
"No..."
- "You sure?" - "No..."
"The one you said looks like Alan Tam."
"I never said so!"
Mrs. Li, you crying?
Don't be sad; be strong.
Good night, Mrs. Li.
Headaches? And rashes?
It's just nerves! You
should be happy instead!
You're 2 months pregnant!
We've confirmed it.
- You sure?
- Absolutely
Peter, you told me I couldn't conceive!
Not anymore! Now you can!
- You sure there's no mistake.
- Not a chance.
This is the best news
for both Mr Li and you!
I'll prescribe something
to ease your tension.
You'll be fine in a couple of days.
- Nurse - Yes, Dr. Wong.
Mrs. Li's chauffeur will come
pick up her medication.
How many days' prescription?
- Give her a week's worth - Okay.
Don't move!
Dispatch, we've arrived at 2103.
Victim is male, badly cut;
we need an ambulance.
We have his wife under control.
Tell them to hurry.
The victim is alive, please hurry!
So much stuff left.
What are these... so well-hidden?
Shenzhen, China.
CUT
Hello?
Just a minute.
There, alright.
No, I'm not busy... I
was just having dinner.
Have you eaten?
I can't finish it.
Yeah, I've left it frozen.
My stomach doesn't feel so good.
Anyway...
It's been 3 months since I moved here,
aren't you going to come over?
How about tomorrow?
We can have breakfast together...
if you don't mind cold leftovers.
You really want to hear me play?
My stomach is really bothering me!
I feel nauseous!
Perhaps the food is past
its expiration date.
Darling, it's killing me!
And...
What's scene 29 again?
- Good-bye, sir -Good-bye!
Scene 29 is where Young-Chae
draws blood with a water pump.
Right...
- Good-bye, sir!
- Good-bye!
If we push it back to the 13th...
Shoot the remaining inserts
during the morning of the 8th...
and I'll finish editing
before the night shoot.
Then the crew can catch
some sleep in between.
But you won't get any sleep at all!
Better just one, than all sixty
of the crew losing sleep.
Quite true.
- Take care, sir!
- Yeah, you too!
Kyung-ah, get the guys
to do the heavy work!
I heard you're going to Seoul.
- Could you drop me off at Hanam City?
- Good-bye, sir!
- Good-bye!
Sir... the daggers we talked about.
Good work!
Good work everyone!
I ran over from Studio 3 as
soon as I heard you're here.
Did you read the scripts I sent you?
What do you think? Which one should I do?
"Pink Panty", go for "Pink Panty."
They say director Jang is
the John Waters of Korea.
Still... don't you think his
film is a little sinister?
- Kim Chang's film seems better.
- Director Kim Chang...
His film only makes the director look good.
The actors don't get noticed at all.
Just don't waste your time on him.
What about this...
Trying something other than Mr. Nice Guy?
Like a psycho-rapist-killer thing... huh?!
Huh?!
Don't worry, I ate already...
Just go back to your work.
We can have breakfast together tomorrow
I'll take care of it if you
don't mind cold leftovers.
You should have come to see the set!
It looks just like our house...
Hey, I got the music for the film!
Listen to this...
The rehearsal will end late!
Don't forget your veggie diet!
You've got...
such pretty hands, ma'am.
There's jewelry in the bedroom!
Take it all! Just don't hurt anyone!
Please, let us go!
Darn...
You're not supposed to start
off with this kind of talk!
You shouldn't have started begging
until... like 20 minutes later.
"Wait"... till things fall apart first!
You are, after all, the head of the house.
If you're only capable of "begging"
from the onset...
who else could your wife count on?
Remember what happened when you
shot "Uninvited Guest" in 1998?
When those gangsters
busted in on the shoot...
"Stop it!"
You shouted at them boldly!
What happened to your guts now?
Who are you?
Who, me?
Maybe you'll recognize me like this...
Nope?
Red Hunt! Huh?
Water!
Water...
What the hell!
Ready, huh?!
Action, huh?
And... CUT!
She's a pianist...
I know that of course!
I've done my research.
Got to be the pianist's fingers
for the "cut" to mean something.
Only an idiot would want her toes instead!
Honey!
Honey, I'll... take care of this somehow.
Honey, are you alright? It
hurts a lot, doesn't it?
I still don't know what's going on...
But I'm sure... we can
get out of this somehow.
Just trust me, okay?
Does it hurt a lot, honey?
Try and bear it a little longer!
Do that for me, okay?
It will be all over soon
I'll... I'll make sure you can play again
I love you, honey.
Let's be strong.
One way or another, I'll...
I remember you now!
Yeah?
An Extra.
I was in all five of your films, sir!
You were such a kind man...
unlike any other directors
I've ever worked with.
So kind, no matter what mistakes I made.
Remember the mob scene in "The Desert"?
You were shooting the crowd
running in the distance.
Some moron knocked over
a hornet's nest as we ran
I got stung, I freaked out
and I ruined the take.
Naturally...
The damn assistant director gave me hell.
But then you said...
How about using the time to set up
another take instead of yelling?
It's not like he wanted to get stung.
Is your neck okay?
You were so sweet.
But what's the use of all that?
You don't even recognize me!
Why are you doing this to me?
What do you mean "Why"?
"Because" this world is so fucked up!
That's why!
Look at this, look!
I didn't even know there are
houses like this in Korea!
Lots of people are better off
than us! This house is merely...
The rich people I've ever met...
They're all scumbags, no respect for people.
I don't even consider them as human beings.
But you, you are a good man!
That's so fucking unfair!
You're rich, handsome,
educated in America...
a genius director, and
you have a pretty wife!
If you're also a "good"
man on top of that...
what are guys like me supposed to get?!
You know on TV shows...
Only the poor folks are good people!
Never the rich!
You've already got everything!
Why do you have to corner us too?!
Why are you a good man, too?
You live well in this world and
you'll live well in heaven.
Our lives suck and we're going to hell!
This is totally outrageous!
That's not true.
"It's harder for a rich man
to get into heaven..."
"than a camel to go through
the eye of a needle."
It's in the Bible!
Bullshit.
It's easier for a rich man
to get into heaven...
than putting a needle
into a camel's nostril!
Face it, you've got no cause to sin.
Of course I have.
Then, prove it!
What persistence
I'm sorry...
for being a good
person -Look at that!
Look!
What a good man?!
I can let your wife go.
On one condition...
You have to kill someone right here!
Can you do that?
I'll do as you wish.
Let her go and I'll die in her place.
You don't need to die.
You just need to strangle
the little kid over there.
If you don't, in every five minutes...
I'll cut off another one
of your wife's fingers.
Let's see how good you can stay!
Ready...
Go!
Who is this kid?
I don't know her either!
Met her on my way here!
She looked bored so I brought her along.
Guess what
I've been dirt poor ever since I was a kid.
My bastard father was always dead drunk.
He beat the hell out of
us day in and day out.
Needless to say my grades were bad.
And this ugly face of mine could
get me nowhere near stardom.
So you see, now I'm the one
who always gets drunk
I go home and I kick my boy's ass.
And, I beat my wife, too!
When I sober up in the morning...
and see that beat-up face of hers.
Guess what I think of?
Your face!
Your nice handsome face overlapping hers...
It makes perfect sense for a poor
kid to grow up to be a bastard...
and a rich kid to grow up
to be a good man! That's fate!
Damn it!
Hell, no!
No...
Time flies.
What should I do, honey? Whatever you say.
Should I kill her?
Don't kill her?
What a decisive man, my goodness!
What a decisive man!
Listen to me, life has many stages
I went through many difficulties
before getting this far.
It wasn't as easy as you think!
I didn't get it for free.
Someone once said...
"No time to blink, keep striving for..."
Fuck that! I ain't stupid!
It's a line from your own film!
Jin says that to Rose in "Last Wish".
Want me to follow suit?
Remember the cabaret scene
in "Dancing Factory"?
You wrote the song lyrics as well
I did some dancing there, too.
"I'm not going to listen
to your words anymore."
"All are a pack of lies!
All out of hypocrisy!"
"We'll make our own words."
"We'll make our own truth."
"I'm not going to listen
to your words anymore"
I'm sorry little one.
I really can't hold out
I'm sorry!
I ain't a good man...
You don't even know me!
How can you prove that I'm a good man!
The truth is...
Whenever an actor ask for my advice
I always persuade them not to
work with Director Kim Chang.
Because...
He's my sole rival.
I can't stand that jerk having
any good actors in his films.
You call this shit a confession?
Do I look like an idiot to you?
I've never said that you were a saint!
Who the hell hasn't done a thing
as tedious as that?
Give me a break.
Let me show you what a confession really is.
For example.
Before I left home this
morning, I killed my wife
I must have strangled her
for over 30 minutes.
Her tongue hung out all the way
and she shitted everywhere.
I was going to finish my son too,
but it was not that easy...
I just couldn't do that...
Now, that's what I call a confession!
Your turn! Give me something nice and juicy.
Wait! I'll talk! I'll talk!
There's a wardrobe called Kyung-Ah.
I offered to give her a ride home one day.
I lied that her home was on my way.
And then I drove her to a motel...
We've been doing this for 3 years
already since "Bluebird".
Love isn't a sin.
We dropped by a motel tonight, too.
Lakeside Motel, room 304.
We did it twice in three hours... No
three times in two hours
I'm really sorry, honey.
Shouldn't have told you this when
you're already suffering so much.
It hurts a lot, doesn't it?
But then...
You shouldn't mind this.
You've never had any real pains in
your life, and no worries either.
Know why I like Kyung-Ah?
Unlike you, she's smart and
we can talk about many things.
As for you, I'd rather you
not to talk to me at all.
All you care to talk about are
clothes and plastic surgery!
When I make love to you...
I'm not sure whether I'm holding
a woman or a bag of silicon.
Guess how old my wife is.
Just one year younger than me...
but already a Botox junkie.
Now her expression doesn't
change even if she smiles.
What she has is not a face but a mask.
And that mask yelps at me everyday
"I love you, honey!"
Mi-ran, be honest for just
this once in your life.
Do you know what love is?
Don't pity yourself for losing your fingers.
They don't deserve any tears.
Because you can play shit.
Plus, you don't cook and you never clean...
You hands have no use anyway
other than wearing jewelry.
Listen.
What is an artist without talent?
"Nada."
Not existing! A "nothing".
Like a ring without a hole
or a square ball! Get it?
If you can't play, it'll
be nice and quiet here.
Also...
It's so much lighter for
you to wave "Bye-bye"!
No, no, no, not yet.
There's something else
I've been trying to say...
I've been holding it back
for a whole 10 years now.
Curious?
Screw you, bitch!
Truth is, she has an affair too.
Know the tenor she plays accompaniment for?
He's her lover! Do you know?
I saw it all when I was
following her around.
Am I wrong? Speak up for yourself.
Oh, I forgot you're gagged.
But you can nod, can't you?
Do what you should do!
Ah... You already knew!
Didn't you? Didn't you?
How about this
I'm kind of depressed.
So if you really want to buy some time...
you can try to make me laugh.
Every time you succeed, I'll extend
the deadline for another 5 minutes.
You've made good comedies.
Now, you can try your hand on acting in one.
Okay.
Ready and...
You son of a bitch!
You... you've never seen me
losing my temper, right?
I'm going to show it to you now.
You son of a bitch.
Your dad was a moron and
he made you a loser.
Is that my fault?
Did I rob your blank?!
Did I steal your wife?
What do I have to do with
your unhappy existence?
Shame on you, moron.
Why don't you just kill yourself?
Your life is a waste of time anyway.
Want me to make you laugh?
Do you know who you're talking to?
I'm Ryu Ji-ho, "the" Ryu Ji-ho!
You're merely a lowlife extra!
Want me to make you... what?
Get the hell out of here.
Just untie me and go home!
Go fix your son some
instant noodles, okay?!
You've freaked me out and corrupted me!
Your mission has been completed!
I'll never mention what happened today.
If you want her fingers this much...
cut them all off!
Or better, just cut off her hands!
Why bother cutting off
her fingers one by one?
Just finish it quickly and
get the hell out of here
I want nothing more.
No, wait!
My closing statement.
You've never gone for cheap laugh
like this in your comedies.
You're so disappointing!
Wait, wait!
I was too wound up and... I made mistakes
I swear I didn't mean to do so...
Wait! Wait!
What are you doing now?
What are you doing?
Wait, wait, wait.
Give me one more chance.
Just give me one more try!
Please! I beg you!
My pose was bad, and I couldn't
help making that kind of mistakes.
Don't be so inflexible!
Just once more chance...
Damn it.
I shouldn't have given
you any false hope...
Nowadays, if you get to
the hospital within 10 hours...
they can reattach the fingers neatly.
No! Wait! I'll do it! I'll kill her!
Look, I'm doing it now!
You bastard!
I said I was going to do it!
Why didn't you wait?!
You saw it too! You know I have no choice.
Honey, I'm going to do it, okay?
That was three... Three, so, seven...
You'll keep your seven, honey!
I'm not doing this because
I hate you, okay?
You think I'm doing this
because I hate your wife?
"Hate" is nobody's fault.
For example, who do you think
she hates more right now?
Me or you?
Let's hear it!
Kill her!
Kill her! What are you waiting for, idiot?
Kill her! Kill her!
You see?
Easy, ma'am.
You probably will get one
finger left on each hand.
He's got to give in by that time.
You can still become a percussionist.
No law against playing drums
with "Chopsticks".
Common folks like me prefer
drum beats to music.
No! No!
You're right, better to
just cut off her whole hand.
Damn time flies...
47 seconds...
46 seconds...
- No!
- 45 seconds...
44 seconds, 43 seconds
42 seconds, 41 seconds
40 seconds, 39 seconds
38 seconds, 37 seconds
36 seconds, 35 seconds...
34 seconds, 33 seconds
32 seconds, 31 seconds
30 seconds, 29 seconds
25 seconds...
22 seconds...
20 seconds, 19 seconds
18 seconds, 17 seconds
16 seconds, 15 seconds...
14 seconds, 13 seconds
12 seconds, 11 seconds
10 seconds
9 seconds
8 seconds.
- No!
- 7 seconds!
6 seconds!
5 seconds!
4 seconds!
3 seconds!
Mr. Director...
How about this?
For example...
You scumbags...
I'll take revenge!
I'm sorry
I'm sorry; it can't be helped.
I tried my best! You saw it all!
Yes, you did!
I have to do this for my wife, you know.
I really love her.
It's hard for a kid like you to understand.
The world is filled with things
you can't get away from.
No matter how hard you struggle...
there are things
you're being forced to do.
Dear...
Alright, honey! Just wait a bit!
I'll take care of it!
I'm sorry... really sorry...
- I'm sorry...
- Ple... please!
Don't rush me! I'm trying!
It'll be over soon!
I'm sorry I shouted, honey;
you know I love you!
I don't believe you have another man!
I don't care even if it's true!
I'm going to forget it all.
After all, I'm the head of the house.
I must forget everything happened today
I'll just think of it as a dream
I love you, honey!
I'm so sorry, kid! I'm truly sorry.
Please forgive me.
I love you, Mi-ran!
Please forgive me, this grown-up...
this old man...
Forgive me, you have to forgive me!
Honey, I love you!
Forgive me... I'm sorry, sorry!
Forgive me...