Watch Online Movies and Series for FREE
www.osdb.link/lm
Until that day when the
waters of the East Sea run dry,
When you see this ocean,
what comes to mind?
Eternal...
Forgiveness.
The boss...
is infuriated.
1,200 kilometres of splendid
rivers and mountains
covered with mugunghwa blossoms.
Is this real gold?
Yes.
And what's this?
A four leaf clover.
Don't use English, you arsehole.
Why you wearing that Rabbit Grass?
You really don't know?
You being clever?
One day,
while Napoleon was on horseback,
he saw a four-leaf clover...
I mean Rabbit Grass.
Intrigued,
he got off his horse to pick it.
And narrowly, a bullet just passed him.
Why did the bullet pass him?
Don't you know?
Obviously, it was shot at him.
'Obv..'
'Obviously'?
You getting cocky, you little shit.
And you! Can't you sing something else?
That dumb ass.
Please forgive me.
For what?
For being arrogant.
For that?
And then?
Then what?
What piece of shit fired the bullet?
You're so frustrating.
That's not important.
Napoleon's life being
saved because of a four
leaf Rabbit Grass
is what's important.
I know, I get it you shit.
Did your girlfriend give you this?
Yes.
Is it a sign of her love?
It's a symbol of luck.
She gave it to me on Valentine's Day.
Valentine.
It's good.
Don't you think?
Ah, this arsehole,
keeps using English.
This is made in Italy.
If buying new,
it's at least 3000 dollars...
This guy!
Who are you trying to scam!
Can't fool me.
Just even at this place alone,
I've been specialising in
instruments for 20 yrs.
There's no way a horn is 3 grand!
It's not a horn.
It's an alto saxophone.
Don't like it?
Forget it then.
'Blessed are the merciful,'
'for they will be shown mercy'
Gospel of Matthew.
Chapter 5, verse 7.
I'm sorry to say but
That cross and those pictures
were all made from money.
You're not a believer?
I believe.
That's why I bought these cheap
artefacts to help out.
The church I used to go to closed down.
Please add 100 dollars more.
I don't have medicine
money for my child.
You should pray. Pray.
Okay.
Fine.
Then,
just play me a hymn
gracefully right here.
Here.
Are you really a musician?
Sure you didn't just steal that?
You ordered food again?
Why are you still here?
Please.
Just for one day.
How are you trying to borrow an
instrument that's for sale?
You.
You too.
Excuse me.
No sax player?
Since Bong-Ju Lee passed away,
no one has looked for a sax player.
I put her in your hands,
mother-in-law.
Wake up and say goodbye
to your father.
It's been awhile.
How you like the place?
I found it recently.
The girls are hot here right?
Look at them there.
I called your house but...
Who calls the pager of a man
attempting to commit suicude?
Brother,
you haven't broken that habit yet?
Van Gogh had a suicide habit too
you brat.
Next time you try it,
turn off your pager first.
Is Bong-Pal treating you well?
How dare you call the
Chairman by his name.
I don't know.
School is more boring than I thought.
You know we can't endure boredom.
Just think this will be your
life long organisation
And dedicate yourself.
They won't let me grow my hair.
I can only wear black.
Fuck, are we wearing uniforms?
How long are you
going to live like this?
You know,
I'm really trying hard
to be a good person.
So don't be like that.
I'll have a coffee too dear.
And what will you do now?
Where was I?
I said, what will you do now?
Fuck, I'll do what I wanna do.
Even if I'm starving,
I won't eat rotten meat, and
live like the Leopard of Kilimanjaro.
As it's a life of getting fucked anyway,
I'm gonna do one big job
and live a long life.
Brother, your IQ is 150
Mine is 80.
I'll do all the dirty work.
Just lend me your brains
and skills brother.
That brain of yours.
Where are you going to use it.
Honestly, why you're so smart now is
all because of me.
When you were in the joint,
how many books did I send you?
Three.
Hyun-Sae Lee's comic 'Pongjjak',
vol. 1,2,3
Is that so?
I've graduated.
In life,
there's no graduating.
I've dropped out then.
Oh really.
Should I make you return to school then?
This arsehole,
singing in English.
What's this.
You pieces of shit.
Stop whining and hand over
all the money you have.
Fuck. Look at them cower.
Brother, get up.
Brother.
We're going turn this fucked up
world upside down.
Take it.
Take it!
Do you know what the meaning of life is?
You can't come in like the wind,
and then leave like the dew.
That's life.
Look at these arseholes.
You're not gonna get up?
You're not? I said get up!
You have to realise how lucky you are.
Lift your heads up!
Don't look.
If you look, they'll kill you.
If we look,
he said they'll kill us.
You, get up.
Don't regret it while
watching TV later.
I said, lift your head up!
Move your hands away you bitch.
Move. Move.
Open your eyes. Open your eyes.
Open your eyes!
What?
That's it.
That's the way.
They all should be more like you.
Don't you think so brother?
What the fuck's up with him?
Well, well, well.
Leave the ones that love
music and books alone.
Even if that's so...
I'm going to strip search you later.
If I find that you're hiding something,
you'll be sorry.
You're not the only
smart one here brother.
You've now been surpassed.
Stop.
Damn. I just oiled this.
Don't get your spit on here.
Disgusting.
Honestly, I hope he doesn't return.
I heard he stole the guns.
Wasn't he a sniper for the paratroopers?
No, he was in the special forces.
Assassinating figures from Pyongyang.
I doubt he'll come to the baths
carrying a gun though.
He's not stupid enough to come to
his regular sauna while we're after him.
I wouldn't be so sure.
You heard what his IQ is.
Ouch.
Be gentler.
I just want you to exfoliate me.
Not rip off my skin.
Damn.
I thought they looked alike.
Take it off.
Your pours are open now.
Okay.
My muscles are burning.
I've changed baths recently.
What do you think?
Isn't it great here?
Why is there so much
doodling on your body?
These tattoos?
These are nothing. There was even a guy
in the marines who tattooed his dick.
It was of a girl.
Usually it looked like a
wrinkly grandma.
But when he got erect
it turned into a tight young woman.
Even her eyes opened.
Like this.
Fuck.
Brother, let's rob a bank.
Or a Mint.
Can't you ask me what I want to do
with the money we steal?
What will you do?
Well...
That's a real hard question to answer.
I'm going to bribe a TV producer,
and work for a broadcaster.
And why a broadcaster?
Because getting on TV once
in my life is my dream.
Maybe as a comedian.
And what would you do
if you become a comedian?
Make money.
So your reason to make money,
is to make more money.
You think you can make people laugh?
Didn't I tell you that
I got letters of encouragement
after entering a
military talent competition?
I have so many good stories.
Have you heard the story about
the turtle that jerked off?
When I was younger, I had a turtle.
One day, the baby turtle said
to its mother,
"What's jerking off mean?"
I know that one.
Don't you have another joke?
Don't dent my gun.
That crazy idiot.
I'm not going to steal anymore.
Have you seen my pager?
Miss Ma Ri-Ah.
Is your surname Ma?
Yes.
You're the only witness
who saw them.
Did you take a good look?
Of course.
And what did they look like?
Please give me back my pager.
I don't have it.
What?
A friend has it.
Where is my pager?
If I don't call her by tomorrow,
she will take it to the police.
There are a lot of
numbers on that pager.
If something happens to my kid,
I'm meant to get paged.
We've given back your things.
So what more do you want?
You have to go somewhere with me.
What did I tell you.
A bitch like this
talking is useless.
You won't know because
you haven't been in the army,
That thing before,
it's a real gun.
It's known to be a very powerful gun.
I think.
To summarise,
I'm not some petty
person that robs empty houses.
You understand?
This is why, these days
you gotta send broads to the army
Let's split it 8 to both of you,
and 2 to me.
The owners of the house
are really wealthy
If you count their wallets,
the safe and cash,
it's more lucrative
than robbing a store.
You think Jazz is the only art?
Fuck, what you're doing now is art.
Hey.
Hey!
What the hell are you doing!
Who are you people?
Us?
Brother.
This is real art right?
When we came in, we were burglars.
But when leaving, we could be robbers.
I think these two are actors.
He could be her teacher.
Porno actors.
And how old are you kid?
Seven...
Seventeen.
Seventeen you say.
You think this is okay? At your age,
you should be at junior athletic meets.
And you!
She's old enough to be your daughter.
What are you doing?
How many times have you done it?
Tell me!
It makes sense when I say
you're old enough to be her father.
Why are you taking off your mask?
- We're fucked.
- Hey, you're...
What's going on here?
Where's my child?
That child shouldn't
have been born.
- Child?
- Just tell me where my child is?
There's nothing that
can be done now.
Just tell me where my child is!
"My child?"
The baby is dead.
What are you doing?
- Let go.
- No.
- Get out of the way.
- No I won't.
I'm going to get the videotape.
We've been filmed too.
I know the baby is alive.
Where's the baby?
Teacher, your eyes see me.
But those eyes are of someone
itching to kill me.
What time is it?
7 a.m.
These incompetents.
It's been daylight for a while.
There's not an ounce of a DIY attitude.
Yeah what?
That's my phone.
You called just for that?
You crazy fuck.
My girlfriend saved money
for a year to buy that gift.
If I don't get that back...
I'll be dead soon.
You idiot. Just buy the same phone.
I can't replace that sticker
though you fucking arsehole.
Fine. Fine.
I'll return it
after I use it for a bit.
Don't get too excited.
Go home and rest.
But doesn't it hurt where
I hit you?
It really fucking hurts
you fucking arsehole.
How old are you to
be swearing all the time.
Either way, I'm paying
that phone bill.
You better not make
international calls.
Also,
Use 'collect calling' when phoning
interstate, when you can.
If there's nothing to be done,
use 0-8-2 before calling.
You understand?
Alright. Alright.
Not that expensive anyway.
Just do it you fucking arsehole!
This dickhead.
What's wrong?
My dream was so boring,
I decided to wake up.
What did they look like?
The small guy...
had short legs and red socks.
He had beady eyes.
He was very clumsy.
And the tall one...
He had slanted eyebrows and tired eyes.
Whenever he opened his mouth,
a lot of spit came out.
You're not getting out?
You know where I hate
going most in the world?
Do you always have to make
it obvious that you were an orphan?
It's not like you grew up in
a harmonious household.
Anyway, all humans are orphans buddy.
Because God has discarded us.
I don't know about any god,
but what I know is that
my mother discarded me.
You want to die?
This is our turf.
We're busy kid, so go over there,
chew some gum and play.
Move your car.
There's a lot of space here.
What's the matter?
Could you play somewhere else please?
You go somewhere else lady.
Why I oughta...
Just wait a moment.
Do you live here?
Don't you have a mother?
For fuck's sake.
Hey kid,
where's the director's office?
It's over there.
Thank you.
So,
first, write an application,
then until it's approved,
visiting will be possible.
Well,
She's wanting to take her baby,
so what's this about visiting?
You fucking arsehole.
Fucking arsehole?
You orphan bastard.
How dare you cause a scene!
What are you doing?
You're lucky Pigface.
God.
As I was saying before,
you should adhere to this
rightful legal process.
We can't give this child to just anyone.
Is the mother of this child
just 'anyone'?
Why are there so many
people giving up babies?
Should I just raise this
one myself?
All humans are orphans anyway.
Have a nice day.
It's just a toy.
Robbers!
They're robbers. Robbers!
We're police. Put your hands up.
I'm...I'm a mother.
Put your hands up.
Where did our bikes go?
Hey kid.
Have you seen our motorbikes?
Tell the baby to be quiet.
Why is she crying?
She's met her mother.
She must be hungry.
But she's not sucking on my breast.
What are we to do...
She's probably had powdered milk,
so won't want breast milk.
Why isn't she sucking on
such a great thing.
Me, I can't understand it at all.
This Mr Elephant's nose are his hands.
When you give him a snack,
he eats it with his nose.
Why did you steal this too?
When my daughter
sees me playing the saxophone,
she thinks it looks like
an elephant's nose.
That's why she loves
elephant stuffed toys.
Don't be like that.
Just give it to me one time.
I even found your child.
In good conscious, shouldn't you
be giving me something like this?
Just once.
C'mon, let's just do it.
Just this once.
What you glaring at?
You think if you glare at me like that,
I won't be able to stick it in?
What are you going to stick in,
you idiot.
Hey!
Are you a person!
How can you do this to me!
Just take it easy.
It's not what you think.
If a baby doesn't breast feed,
the breast can get stiff and painful.
If not careful, women can get mastitis.
- Therefore...
- That's why?
That's why Ma Ri-Ah
asked me for this favour.
Ma Ri-Ah.
Let's do the left one now.
Mastitis...
Me too. Me too.
Hear me out.
If we suck each breast,
it would be quicker. Right?
70 cents plus 45 cents,
times three.
That will be 5 dollars and 55 cents.
Wait a minute.
Why is it so expensive?
70 cents times three.
Isn't that 2 dollars and 10 cents?
It's 18 dollars and 50 cents
times three.
That will be 5 dollars and 55 cents.
What times three?
Like I said, It's 18 dollars
and 50 cents times three.
Why are you charging $18.50
when the sign says 70 cents?
That says the coffee price is 70 cents.
Then the cup price is 45 cents.
But in those cups,
the capacity is 2 cups of coffee.
So I'm right.
Fine then.
So let's say 6 cups of coffee,
then 6 times 7
equals 4 dollars 20 cents.
But charging for cups,
what's that about?
Isn't 6 times 7 isn't 47?
Just stay out of this you idiot.
Mister, just stay out of this.
Miss. You seem not to know,
but these 'Slushy' cups
are expensive to begin with.
And also, in our business,
we see how many of these cups
are used, then calculate the price.
You understand now?
Brother,
'slush' is English right?
That's right.
2 times 9 is 18 you arsehole.
So you're saying that this
piece of shit cup is 45 cents each?
Ridiculous.
Bring out the manager you arsehole.
What?
What? 'Arse..bitch...'
What did you say?'
You prick, do you have
a death wish?
Prick, I'm the manager!
Now what?
You really want to die, don't you?
This is hilarious.
Stop talking shit.
Many people are going home for
New Year's Day.
Fuck, if they loved their hometown
so much, why did they leave.
Let's go to my hometown.
Where's your hometown?
Ah, my hometown smell
's like shit.
Isn't the day too nice to
be so poor.
I'll stop giving the baby
powdered milk.
After a couple of days, the
baby will have to have breast milk.
Do you know the feeling of a mother
who can't breastfeed her child?
Being breastfed is so
important for a baby.
I thought that someday,
I would hold my baby in my arms,
and look into her eyes,
I waited for that day.
Her 100th day.
That's right.
You said, it's the
baby's 100th day anniversary.
Make sure you write it's
the baby's 100th day anniversary.
What you think?
Don't I look like him?
Okay. Let's quickly shoot
while the baby's in a good mood.
Assemble!
Please look to the front.
Hey Moustache! Not so close.
Look at me and smile!
Thank you.
I feel like a real mother now.
Did my mother have my 100th day
party before dumping me?
If she were in circumstances to
have a party,
you think she could abandon a child?
And what did you do Brother?
For my kid's 100th day party,
I was in jail.
Cheese.
You trying to make your kid
into a chain smoker?
This is my last one.
Brother, have you quit smoking?
I haven't seen you smoke recently.
Smoking is a slow suicide.
Oh, suicide?
That must mean you have to smoke a
fuck ton then.
A life has to burn bright.
Anyway, you are a fearful person.
You always say you will kill
yourself but you can't.
It's all because of that.
Crazy fool.
Okay, let's say goodbye now.
Don't live in an
orphanage again kid.
We were fortunate to
find your kid again,
so raise her right.
What do you mean by all that?
We're going to the next job.
And you're going to go
raise your kid.
Bye.
You think you can raise a kid for free?
Take me with you.
Let's say at the very least,
we rob a convenience store.
One person takes the
customers and staff.
One goes to the cash register.
Then who's on lookout?
If the cops swarm in,
you wouldn't know.
Let's say that's the case
for convenience stores.
What about banks?
One person for the security guards,
and one to collect the money.
And then when a cop storms,
you get into a firefight. Then what?
Well, well, well.
Look at these audacious fools.
How could you rob
a bank with only two people?
Should I go on?
Stop it!
Why are you suddenly wanting
to rob a place like that?
Our objective are banks!
Banks! Banks!
There's always an order to things.
You need to put underwear
on first before your pants.
Are you saying we should
rob an underwear shop?
This idiot.
Firstly, it's a cash business.
Secondly, Saturday and Sunday sales
are always kept in the safe.
Thirdly, security is low.
Something definitely is in there,
seeing these men struggle so much.
Here.
What did I say, don't
look over that way.
What should we do brother?
Lay it down.
Go over there and
put your heads to the floor.
Now it's time to show us
your skills, Brother.
What's that?
Is this a specialist skill too?
I could do that too.
You start at the simplest
place when cracking safes.
Take note.
These models of safes
have a weak back plate.
What's this?
You had a lot of customers before.
We had a lot of invited guests,
so there won't be a lot of cash.
But you have two cinemas here.
One cinema is for art films.
Thank you very very much.
The golden bell was rung
on table eight.
Which means, what you've drank
until now will be paid by the table.
Also, we will have a special
performance from table 8 as well.
Please come to the stage.
A round of applause.
I have a younger brother.
We met at the 'Beehive Club' Cabaret.
There, I was playing alto saxophone
in the band.
And he was
a tout.
From the first moment we met,
how should I say this,
there was electricity between us.
And he's sitting...
right there.
To be honest, I never
wanted to perform again.
But for his family,
I want to perform.
Hey Ma Ri-Ah.
Do you really not want to give it to me?
In that case,
what if we do this.
You can have me. I'll give you
my body.
Oh that stupid bitch.
She's learnt something
important today.
Isn't that right?
Let's get some ramen.
We're nearly at the hotel.
Let's just eat there.
You're not eating?
Nope.
I'll just sleep here with the baby.
You do that then.
You're not eating?
If you drink then have ramen,
you gain weight.
I'm starving. I can't resist.
- Where's the baby?
- The baby?
She's sleeping soundly.
Stop you thieves!
We've been robbed!
It's all my fault.
Shoot.
Do something. She says she's going
to find the baby herself.
Fuck. How did I fuck this up.
Hey Ma Ri-Ah. Wait.
We'll find the baby for you.
Right Brother?
- Just relax and have a cigarette.
- Get lost.
Because all I want is to kill you.
Brother.
Wait in the car.
Yeah, that's probably better.
Hey Ma Ri-Ah.
Listen to what he says.
I'll wait in the car, okay?
I think I've done enough
finding your baby once.
I can't always take
responsibility for you and your daughter.
Just leave.
I'm going to go my separate
ways with him too.
Because I've had a realisation.
Music, I can't give up yet.
Where is this place?
Where are we going?
Brother!
I'm here to collect something.
Wait a minute.
Go back.
What's wrong?
- You thug.
- Put your hands up.
You okay?
Brother, I said are you okay?
I'm okay.
Fuck, what kind of granny is this?
Put that down.
Now!
You think I haven't been
fooled by a toy gun before?
You have no chance.
This is real.
You'll die really well if you get shot.
If you don't scram,
I'm going to shoot again.
Look at this old bat.
Don't you watch TV these days?
You haven't heard of the
armed robbers 'the Trio'?
I don't watch the news!
In Korea, only 'the Trio' carry guns.
What trio?
There's only two of you!
I mean...
We were previously three.
But Ma Ri-Ah has left.
Drop the gun!
You say it's a fake,
so why are telling me to drop it!
You see.
It's real.
Are you okay?
Move.
Give me my saxophone.
- I sold it.
- What?
This says you couldn't sell it yet!
I told you.
I thought it was stolen
Take one from over there.
There are a lot of horns.
Relax.
You going to kill an old person?
Get the money.
I said, get the money!
No you can't!
You don't know how hard
I worked for the money.
Be quiet!
There will be no more
scenes without tears.
Run!
Those sons of bitches!
I'm tired. Should we just fight?
No we'll get caught.
Then what do we do?
My stomach hurts. I can't run anymore.
Just follow me.
Hey.
Are you okay?
Hey!
Get a hold of yourself.
- Get a hold of yourself.
- Hey Mister!
You fucking arseholes.
How's your head?
My head has always been really hard.
I'm worried because you don't have
external wounds.
Later, if you feel drowsy or
you bleed from your ears, tell me.
Because then it will be
really serious.
What's wrong?
Are you getting drowsy?
This is the first time in my life,
someone's cared about me.
What are you doing?
Is this the right one?
They're quick.
Get in.
It stinks in here.
Out of all things,
why did you steal a garbage truck.
Do you believe in God?
A little bit.
This table will be perfect to play
cards and drink soju.
Good carpet here too.
Hey lady.
Is there a TV or a deck of cards here?
We don't have such things.
Whatever then.
No convenience store here?
You should have gone to a hospital.
You'd find a doctor, TV,
and store all there.
And you can play cards in the mortuary.
Is that so?
You want my phone?
Do you know Ma Ri-Ah well?
You think I could become a nun
without knowing Ma Ri-Ah.
I guess.
Honey?
- Is something wrong with our daughter?
- She's sick.
Even the hospital
doesn't know what's wrong.
I don't know. She keeps
asking for you.
Darling.
I miss you too. Come back quickly.
Put whoever is next to you
on the phone.
Put on the men sent by
Bong-Pal!
Did Bong-Pal send you?
I'll go.
Just don't lay a hand
on my daughter.
My interest is not in you.
For my boss, the guns are important.
And to me, that arsehole that
killed my brother is important.
So, if you do as I say,
I won't even touch a hair
on your daughter.
Of course,
even the hairs of your wife
If you arrive alone,
then, you could see this house
go up in flames.
"He that is without sin among you,
let him first cast a stone at her".
There are these words in the bible.
My dear.
Those words don't fit this situation.
And also, those people are men.
Actually...
Can you tell me why
you abruptly left us then?
I was pregnant.
I only found out while I was here.
However...
It's fortunate you found out
during your training period.
Who's the father?
Hey Mister.
Who? Me?
Put it out.
This?
As Ma Ri-Ah asked a favour,
I'll give you some time.
I'll report you at exactly midnight.
So leave by then.
When our saviour was on the cross,
two robbers were crucified next to him.
The robber to the left,
blasphemed against Christ until
the end and was abandoned.
But the robber on the right,
repented and was given salvation.
You...
You told them we were robbers?
Brother, we've been exposed.
Where has this guy gone.
What's this?
- Is this where you take a dump?
- No, it's where you dump your sins.
Brother, are you dumping your sins?
What wrong?
That's where you confess your sins.
It's somewhere that has
nothing to do with me.
Wait a minute.
Have I sinned?
Have I?
Oh Sin.
No I haven't.
Leaving a baby in the car,
does that count as forgivable?
Shut the door.
What?
I said, close the door you arsehole!
Do you know who took the baby
and the money?
If I knew that...
You think I'd be here.
When we went into the convenience store,
Ma Ri-Ah and a women made eye contact.
She wore a red dress.
She stole the car.
Ma Ri-Ah purposely left
the ignition on in the car.
I only put it together later.
She worked together with
Ma Ri-Ah at the cafe.
So what you're saying is...
The one who stole Ma Ri-Ah's
baby is Ma Ri-Ah.
No way.
Can't you use that thing
attached to your neck for once.
You don't remember her
shooting at your dense head.
If she had the money,
you think she'd be back here?
Her kid she can pick back up from the
orphanage. She's been double-crossed.
When we said goodbye, they
probably were meeting at the bus stop.
But her friend disappeared.
With just the money.
What are you doing?
Why are you packing the bag?
Brother!
Do something. He's going to leave.
Brother.
Shouldn't you listen what
Ma Ri-Ah has to say too?
You can't go by yourself.
We're a trio. Right?
A trio?
A trio of a suicidal man, a moron,
an unmarried mother.
Brother.
There's no such things
as friends or salvation.
This is cowardly.
Why are you suddenly using me
as an excuse to run away?
You got your sickness from your father,
and my daughter from me.
It's now time to erase
these original sins.
To let go of all the sins.
Brother!
Don't follow me.
What are you both doing?
Are you all crazy?
Don't go.
Should I tell you a funny story?
One day a masochist said,
"I beg you please, please torture me."
And then the sadist replied,
"No."
You can't shoot me.
Because that would be such
a great gift to me.
Would killing a suicidal man
be a blessing?
Or a curse?
Fuck, what did I do wrong to you?
I believed in you. That's why I'm here.
And what she did that. She came
back to save us. That makes it even.
How righteous are you?
You think you're that great?
Sure.
I'm an orphan and a moron.
So what?
Now, even you will le...
Even you will...
Even now you will throw me away.
Fine. Leave.
Leave. You think I won't shoot.
I'll shoot and kill all those who
betray me. Leave.
I'm different from you two.
I've got a home to return to.
Did you just shoot at me?
You shot.
I'm going to kill you.
If you follow me
you'll be killed, you idiot.
Where will you go now?
Aren't we going to get your fucking kid?
How can you say that about
your daughter?
Your faces are in newspapers and
on TV. How will you travel?
Here. Take this.
You fucking arsehole!
These fucking arseholes.
I'm so hungry.
What the fuck is all this?
I want fried chicken.
And roast sweet potatoes.
Ma Ri-Ah, I'm hungry.
Hey.
I'm not doing this. I'm not doing this.
What am I doing.
Why did you tell me to cut my beard.
What a waste of my beard.
I'm not doing this anymore.
I'm not doing this anymore
Is this your car?
It's her dad's car.
And what does her dad do?
He's a monk, so that's why
he chose the colour grey.
If her dad is a monk, then
I'm Mother Teresa, you fuck.
You're about to find
Śarīras from my body soon.
You're not taking it off?
You want me to sing more?
It's probably best to stop.
However...
You will talk now about how painful
it was when you lost your virginity
What's this?
You haven't done it yet?
You saying you're a virgin?
Want me to check?
Hey you.
If we take it off, it will reveal all.
Now begin.
It was Year 9 during summer vacation.
That's good.
And how old are you now?
Twenty.
You probably fooled around
plenty since then.
Did you know about that?
- You said I was your first.
- Go die somewhere you retard.
How can you trust anyone
that sits down to piss.
Can you die by getting
hit by a tear gas gun?
Why do they use this,
when there are guns?
A quick inspection please.
- Honey.
- You must be tired.
All's good at home?
Cops.
Fuck off.
Soon the road splits into two.
Turn left.
You piece of shit.
Put the boss on.
We've caught the horn blower.
No. It's a horn. A horn.
Yes.
He's alone.
But I think he's brought the goods.
Yes.
Anyhow, let's wait
a little while longer.
Wait a little longer please.
- Hey.
- Yes, brother.
This prick doesn't seem to know.
Bring the bag, the bag.
It will be in there.
Yes, brother.
Here you are.
What's this?
That's an alto saxophone.
Be quiet!
I'll kill her.
Don't move. I'll kill her.
Don't come closer.
I'll kill her!
Have you been well, mother-in-law.
Who are they?
They're here after
hearing over the police radio.
He's been wanted for crimes
committed for a few years.
They're here
wanting to arrest him first.
- Alright.
- Yes sir.
Who the hell is this guy?
At least his name.
Don't talk to me so casually
just because you gave me a cigarette.
You look younger than me.
Why don't you like it?
You won't be able to find him ever.
I don't really care if you
escape or don't.
My concerns are for the
people in there.
I like you mister.
Chief, we're getting into position.
How about this.
Bring me a helicopter
and I'll let go of the hostages.
When it arrives and we lift off,
if I see any of you rats
within a 50 metre radius
It all fucking ends.
Please keep talking.
If you escape,
send me a postcard.
How about a lottery ticket instead.
If anybody is lucky enough to
escape this situation,
it's obvious that they will win.
Is Ma Ri-Ah going too?
Please delay for longer.
I have a personal favour to ask.
Could you listen?
Ma Ri-Ah has lost her baby.
Find it for her.
A mother's pain is something,
being an orphan,
is really fucked up.
To your left.
Please keep talking.
Yes.
I think another person like
you entering the world
is fucked up too.
More to the left.
I'll now count to three before shooting.
Starting now. One,
- I like you.
- Two, three.
Crouch down.
- Have a good one.
- Crouch down.
Crouch down!
Hey Jae-Mi.
Jae-Mi.
Daddy's here.
Open your eyes.
Hey Jae-Mi.
If you tell the police,
your daughter dies.
Now go.
It's time to divvy it up.
Here.
Aren't you coming
for me later?
You can give me the money then.
They'll confiscate it if
I take it with me anyway.
What's wrong?
It's the first time,
anyone's trusted me
with money matters.
I trust you.
That you'll find me again.
Turn your head away.
You're going to come find me right?
Right?
If you have this, I can find you.
It's a good luck charm
Also,
And lastly
There's something I want to say
and something I want to hear from you.
Tell me what you want to say first.
Until two minutes ago,
I was a virgin.
What?
You're my first.
Fuck sake.
Now it's my turn to ask.
The thing that brother said at the
cathedral. That's all rubbish right?
Isn't it?
It's not.
Just in case my
mother tries to find me.
I'm an orphan.
Fuck, I can't do this shit.
Fucking hell.
Don't swear on tape.
How many times do I have to say,
I'm selling this to the TV stations.
Fine.
Talk to me informally then.
Respect the TV stations.
Let's start again.
Fine then.
Shall we get going.
They've changed. It's not him.
Fly you son of a bitch.
Daddy!
Daddy.
Production: Lee Chun-Yeon
Director: Park Chan-Wook
Producer: Lee Mi-Young
Script: Lee Mu-Young, Park Chan-Wook
DOP: Lee Eun-Gil
Lighting: Shin Jun-Ha
Editing: Park Gok-Ji
Music: Jeon Sang-Yoon
Watch any video online with Open-SUBTITLES
Free Browser extension: osdb.link/ext